good afternoon thanks for staying so
late for the talk glad to be here I'm
here to talk about the rolling the root
zone Dina psyche signing key the
motivation for this talk is that I can
is about to embark on a project to
change a configuration parameter in DNS
SEC for operators out there this may or
may not be something that is going to
affect what you have to do in operations
but I intend to do here is to inform you
what's going on give you an idea what's
happening when it's going to happen why
it matters and in particular we're
highlighting that we have some
documented plans available on the web
for you to consult so to give it back
round twos told this is more of a
general audience on a DNS crowd do a
little bit of background of what this
matters and why this matters and what
where this fits in the scheme of things
dns for those don't like protocols you
ask a question and an answer comes back
and for DNS SEC a digital signatures
added to that response and the idea is
that de stijl signature now can let the
receiver do some verification or some
validation of what they received what is
d a sec validation it's taking this
digital signature looking at what's in
the signature deciding whether that
signature is valid invalid or so on and
from that being conclude whether the
data they receive you've received is
genuinely what you're supposed to have
been receiving now cryptic the
validation process we talk a lot about
the cryptography part of this the
digital signature is a digital yep it's
a cryptographic piece of data that gets
checked by a key and that's a very big
part of this work but keep mine there
are other factors in here is the answer
related to your question as part of this
is the answer fresh is it just has been
replay from the past or is it new is in
there I'm going to stick to just the
cryptography side of this because we're
talking about the key the key management
is going on so before I go further to
the one of the obvious questions is why
should I bother with this validation why
is the dance like verification or
validation something that is interesting
but the Dinah's protocol
all is easily fooled it's constantly
asking questions getting back answers
and if it's not careful it can be very
gullible and pick up bad data be
redirected to places all over give you
the wrong responses for addresses for
machines and so on so validation is
basically a form of self-protection
anyone you running a DNS server out
there a caching server the servers ask
questions if you want to make sure what
you're caching what you're answering
your clients with is right you really
want to go out and do this form of
self-protection there are other ways we
can use the in a second of the future
which I won't spend much time on but I
have listed their help now before I go
through much of this talk i can have to
step into a puddle of detail in within
DNS SEC we have roles of keys and we
have different records that are involved
here and I need to explain a little bit
about this for the talk to make a little
bit of sense up we have a key signing
key that's a special key that only signs
other keys it just does don't ask why ah
there's a zs k which is a zone signing
key which signs all the zone data all
the data in DNS that's not keys up these
are conventions for operating this and
then we have a third thing it's actually
a record not a key so much is called the
d/s and it's a pointer to a key that
lets us link up the security throughout
the tree now this setup was supposed to
make operations simple and it doesn't
hurt operations but it makes it really
hard to explain everything so going back
to the the boxes here when you want to
crypto check the signature you take the
data which is the blue on top you take a
digital signature which is in the middle
which has information about who signed
this and when they sign it and whether
what the checksum should be basically
and you combine it with this key on the
bottom as esk his own signing key is
what's going to be at the bottom of this
picture and the operat the output of
that operation is either thumbs up or
thumbs down there's no almost maybe
either yes or no because cryptography is
that is an exact hit or not now this key
at the bottom of the CSK the bomb in
this chart is what we're starting to
link in to the topic here it's actually
backed up by a
a chain of other keys and then a show on
the top down the route KS came with a
black arrow down of the route CSK to the
column d as the comm KSK and so on this
is a chain of keys that gets involved in
DNS SEC and we talked about DNS SEC
validation you get the data you get the
key you validate that that that little
three those three boxes work together
but you have to make sure the key is
reliable and that's why you're chaining
back up to some point you can play some
kind of trust in now the reason why this
is a little hard to explain in a few
slides is that in reality that simple
chain downwards just one way down to the
data that was involved in this example
in the reality today the root zone KSK
signs the root zones esk which then
science about 1300 to 1400 des records
pointing to all the TL DS all top-level
names out there that's right away a fan
out of 1300 dot-com itself also has 500
DS records within it so it goes out even
further and dotcom isn't it
representative it's just the biggest one
out there of course and 500 k is way
more than any other of the TL DS out
there so getting back to the topic of
this talk this talks about the root zone
dnf set KSK roll over this is the root
zone KSK pictorially it's at the top of
these chains it's a thing that sits on
top of all the dsx operations that are
done in normal use they're there
exceptions but this is the normal use so
this top key means something special
from the operator end of this we need
for the receiver the one running a DNS
server we talk about trust anchors a
trust anchor is the top of the process
it's what an operator pulls full full
faith and trust in this key is a special
key this key is going to be a key that
you trust it's like the certificates in
the web browser that then gets that then
sign other certificates when in web
pages this is a key that you have to
have trust and now the trust might be
implicit it might be that you just
download mind you download unbound and
you roll it out there powered in s
whatever and they have some copy of this
key sitting somewhere and you just trust
it because I code was also trusted or
you could be a much more likely to be to
do an explicit check of this
by taking these keys comparing them on
your desk doing other cryptographic
checks that are available out there but
whatever however it is it's up to you
decide how you trust something this
trust anchor is a thing that you're
hinging all of your decisions on if
you're running DSF validation a first
question here is the root zone KSK the
key that I'm talking about the trust
anchor and the answer is it depends it's
up to you the trust anchor is something
you choose locally to run your recursive
servers for validation and so on it's up
to you to decide whether you trust that
but the by convention the root zone KSK
KSK covers just about anything that's
operationally hooked together right now
in DNS second there are holes in the
tree right now where things aren't
signed properly this you can add other
trust anchors in your code if you feel
like managing it that way but if you're
doing that scale you probably aren't
going to have too many of these turnkey
or extra aquis ins installed but tools
can allow you to use that so and also to
give you some more background of how the
DNS SEC is operated the roots done it's
done a little speck it's another special
way of course there are two bodies
involved right now as I can we rely on a
functions and part of that is to run the
root zone KSK verisign is the roots on
maintainer they've been producing the
root zone for years they've been sending
it out to the root server operators as
part of that function they operate their
root zones esk the zone signing key
that's why I bothered to explain the two
differences the KSK means we take care
of the KSK we created it once we're
going to roll it we're going to manage
the security of it pop publish it and we
use it to sign the CSK once a quarter
every of so four times a year operating
the CSK verisign does this work they
they manage this life cycle of it and
they also sign the root zone with it
every time they send out a new copy of
the root zone the to our two
organizations do these functions
separately but we're also very
coordinated we talk all the time but
we're doing separate jobs and this helps
up make sure that we're securing the the
root zone d ina sec properly now the
current KSK the current root zone KS
k was created in 2010 and put into
operation back then it has not been
changed since then we keep it secure
insecurity h SMS in two locations in the
East Coast and West Coast the United
States it's tempting to go into a bit
background there i have a whole 45
minute talk about that but that's not
the towns that the time for that but we
have a lot of information about how we
run this we were very happy to go with
it if you really want to see how we do
the operations I well we will talk about
that we try to expose as much as we can
for those of you who want to get a copy
the root zone ksk there are a couple of
ways of getting the key the key is in
the dns and you can actually grab it
from the dns if you do that beware that
if your d s is being attacked at the
moment you may not be able to trust the
key that way it's kind of hard to convey
to you a key securely in the system i'm
trying to secure with the key but you
can get it that way you least get the
data fright we also publish it on a
website we have a I have a file their of
XML file which has the the trust anchors
inside of there and there's some more
security behind that you can again
verify this but there are other means
out there software distributors have to
have the key in there it's in
presentations we talk about I've
mentioned the key places different
t-shirts printed with this and so on you
can also check other operates and make
sure you have the same kind of key the
it's one thing to get the key syntax
correct it's nothing to begin to trust
it and you may have levels of trust that
you have that you want to meet trust on
first sight trust on far you first use
or you may want to do some more due
diligence it's all up to you to do that
it's it's whatever you fits your needs
so changing the root k sk we have a plan
in place to change the cake the key and
in fact the plans have been out there in
eight days we start the process by
creating the new key and that's gonna be
the first thing we do but it won't be
visible to the public so you can look at
the plans and have some chance look at
this still so got quite some time to
prepare for this though up what's really
precedent-setting about this plan is
this project is that on one end i can is
going to do something we're going to do
a few commands we're going to create a
new key and we're getting ready to sign
with it the problem is is that everyone
else out there who wants to
set up a trust anchor based on the key
has to get it and in and then also
configure it we don't know who that is
there's no roster of who needs to get
this key we have to talk to everybody to
make sure if you need to know about it
here it is that's the best we can do and
that's why we're going around and making
sure we you know about this project it's
there were no analogies I could find in
any other projects that hit the scale of
it's me and everyone else or at no one
else I don't know anything could it go
out here so the the one thing to keep we
keep mind is that there really isn't a
need to change the key right now because
we have a problem it's there's no
emergency going on the key is not
wearing down it's not losing bits over
time it's not losing air or whatever but
the change is being done first of all
because cryptographic assets don't live
forever at some point they will become
not unworkable e not secret um and
secondly though it's for operational
hygiene we want to make sure that we can
change the key in normal situations
without an emergency with level heads
and planning before we try to have to do
is in an emergency we don't have the
boat sinking we have to start figuring
how to use a life preservers but so
we're going through this process of
doing this just to make sure we can do
it it's an operational best practice and
why not do this privately why not test
bed this because part of what we're
learning is it's the elements outside of
our control outside of our operations
area that need to be updated we're
making better contacts with software
developers with this distribution chain
of DNS out there with operators we're
trying to make sure that we know who
needs to know we're getting a better who
need to know this and how and why and
when now so the bottom line is if for
all the root the root KSK change will
impact us about aldi is like validations
if if someone out there is validating
today and they don't update their trust
anchor in time the entire internet will
go off for them they'll get surf fail
for everything not just things that are
signed everything because you can't
prove anything if you expect security to
be there you get no security data DNS
second say something's going on it drops
everything now so this time trust anchor
maintenance is going to be as something
that we want to start building some
awareness of and it's a good time to
start thinking about
how do we trust any of the cryptographic
assets we have in our operations is a
good time to look at that so the project
the project is meaningful if you're
doing gesek validation Jeff Houston's
measurements indicate about fifteen
percent of resolvers out there actually
doing some dns sex so it's not zero it's
not a lot somewhere in between people
need to hear this the whole process of
signing is not affected since all about
validation running recursive service
serving users out there and if you're
validating it's a time to begin to think
about preparing for this role out there
and Frank you still have quite a bit of
time but this is the first warning I
want to get out there this is the first
time we rolled the route KSK it's going
to be it's kind of unprecedented so we
all have to be kind of on the ball for
this up we have some documents out there
that if I want to make you aware of I
the documents listed here they're
available at that URL on top up there we
encourage you to read these we're not
looking for formal feedback we don't
have a formal feedback mechanism but if
you see something wrong in them please
let us know we're not perfect but we've
gone through a lot of process a long
process to get to hear listen to it but
we're not setting aside a special time
to get more feedback on this according
to the plans big holidays on october
eleventh in 2017 which is about 51 weeks
from now we will we plan to start using
the new key and getting rid of the old
key in operations ah so we have 51 weeks
to get ready for this event right now
there are other significant events along
the way that we're going to talk a bit
about but in the plants we're using for
those you're curious we're going to use
the same kind of key we're using now
we're not changing the cryptographic
algorithms out there the libraries and
all be the same we're following
something called the automated updates
or dsi trust anchors this is RFC 50 11
if you know those numbers that's a way
in which we publicize the key you can
look at the key and decide whether you
want to use or not up this is taking a
quite a while because we're not in a
rush there is an emergency we don't have
to but so we're doing this at a slower
pace and we're fitting into existing
events that we have right now so there's
no extra cost in operations to doing
this the way we're doing this right now
we're also beefing up testing and
monitoring of the systems involved
see if we can detect stress on the
system so we can also help operate
prepare for what's coming up I in doing
this work we had a few concerns and I
want to let folks look at this and you
might wanna consider this as things that
look out look look for it during our
plant during the plan roll the DNS
response is some of the responses that
are going to matter i'm not quantifying
which ones may grow as high as 1425
bytes some experimentation with ipv6 is
that might be kind of interesting on the
network to see if it goes that big
before fragmentation kicks in up the odd
thing is though empirically people have
we have we know of many examples of tlds
running with very large key sets even
larger than that and we've never had
anyone cry foul or error or a problem
out there so we're we're done we don't
see that there's actually going to be a
problem but we're just we're watching
out and that's the thing that we are
trying to design around for operators
out there anyone who's running DNS
servers things to look out for is one
thing keep tcp open for you for the dns
services it's nowt the DA's protocol
natively will fall back to tcp if it
can't get it through UDP and keep that
open and really try to restrict
filtering based on dns message size that
used to be a big problem less so now but
just make sure that you let dns
determine what size message it has to
pass back and forth i I've use ipv6
fragmentation where that why that's an
issue is in v6 that would network no
longer fragments so you have to send out
things according to the maximum transfer
unit to begin with if you don't you get
back in error message saying this was
too baby dns has no memory so once it
sends a sense of message and it's told
that was too big it forgot what its
scent and it's not going to doing any
good so that's why dns is kind of
feeling the pinch in this area but Jeff
Houston has an article which I would
love to summarize in the talk but don't
have enough time to do that it's at the
URL there is from May of this year was
in his up on his pottery dotnet account
is P column I think it's called and he
talks about the MTU settings in the
information behind that
there were some good informations in
there and I have a button quotes on my
slide because that would have taken
three or four slides to explain and I
don't have the time for that but I would
courage you take a look at that article
if you have an interest in v6 and what's
happening with this and look at some of
the MTU settings you have on the
computers that you have a server so
dates to watch the first date I'm
actually going to mention is not on here
in eight days we're going to create the
key the new key will be created in eight
days from now at a key ceremony in
culpeper West Virginia that's not going
to be visible event so we don't have it
on the slide but since it's eight days
away it seems kind of interesting to
talk about um in September 19th and 2017
we're going to put some of the keys into
the DNS or put the keys the DNS actually
it's a role as it's a long story but
remove it more information of the DNS on
that date and the first week in the
response size will grow to 14 14 bytes
which is above a threshold as some of us
are concerned about we're going to watch
what happens there if nothing goes wrong
we is acceptable we keep rolling on for
the next 20 days we have a very large
set of compared to today today it's
about maybe eight hundred bites i think
or 1100 bites of the highest it's going
to go to 14 14 then we have to watch out
for that operators will price may see
that more than anything else on october
eleventh we change the keys and that's
basically swapping the new key in for
the old key coming out and if you
haven't kept up don't have the keys
configured everything goes dark I
January 11th we go through the process
of revoking the lp formally and that's
when we go to 1425 bites again another
new high at this point for the potential
fragmentation exists so those are the
three main dates for operators looking
out there you can see these dates are
nearly a year into the future so we're
we have some time to prepare for this
still but what are you doing the
meantime look at how you do trusting and
configuration how do you trust and
configuring trust and your DNS servers
and probably other places too how do you
do configuration control do you how do
you manage your DNS servers out there
the reason why I mentioned that is the
automated updates of DSi trust anchors
the middle bullet there which is RFC 50
11 assumes that you let your your
servers self-managed
these servers will go out there and
they'll do some queries and they'll see
Oh a new trust anchor in Allah adopt
that by myself if you do centralized
configuration management you may not
want to have that happen to your network
so you have to you might want to account
for that some way you may want to have
another server do that and then tell
your centralized servers that push
things out we have to maybe some
preparation in pushing this out there
because the alternate to that is you
don't need to use the automated updates
you can do it all manually push it out
yourself but then you have to be more
aware of what you're trusting also a
newer feature of the DNS out there is
called negative trust anchor management
this is now appearing in more and more
of them more recent versions of software
out there it's a way of saying ignore
others trust anchors nor other other
zones DNS like mistakes by putting in a
don't trust this key area to help block
office on the errors that is a that is
an outcome of one of the frames example
of nasa.gov screwing up or messing up
the the d/s record change a couple years
ago and it impacting one of the ISPs out
there so that's finally made it into
commonplace software uh so tools and
test beds that are out there I can is
working with software developers and
tool developers to look at having better
tooling out there for this we've talked
with a lot of the operators already who
thought the opposite software developers
that produce the DNS out there we're
making them aware of this we're also
making sure they know of the new keys
when the keys are available so they can
put it in their software there are tests
fits for code developers that exists now
co-developers not operators these two
URLs have sped up versions of the RSC
5011 automated updates protocol to run
them you have to change critical
parameters and you probably don't want
to do that in operation so we don't
consider that to be a this one operator
friendly testbed we are constructing a
test bed for operators use it's going to
do the RFC 50 11 change in a certain way
so that you don't change any critical
parameters in the code you can try that
in the background to see if your
software that you have out there is
actually following this and whether or
not those trust anchors actually going
to be managed through your configuration
management system out there
so that's the end of my slides my
information elides there's some contact
information here we have a mailing list
for the KS k rollover that you can join
and you can hear some the announcements
out there there's a Twitter thing and we
have a webpage off of the ik net org web
page there's a KSK roll a selection you
can get information about what's going
on there with updates on the process of
this