hi everyone I'm David huberman I am a
network hopper
part of the team that run Oracle's
bare-metal cloud similar to Amy's
presentation i'ma talk about buying IP
addresses in the market but this is
going to be a walkthrough for anyone
here or anyone watching it needs to buy
IP addresses it's funny because you saw
Amy's pricing slide everyone thinks
they're buying and selling at the right
time it's funny how that works alright
basics we all know this there are buyers
and sellers there are brokers there are
operators of the exchange there are
lawyers I'm going to talk a lot about
that and there are IRS and national
registries especially if you're in AP
Nick my pricing looks a little different
than Amy's right now IP addresses in the
small range can be up to thirty dollars
an IP address and it's wholly dependent
on supply there are times there are
months where there's nothing to buy
you're going to pay more and there are
months where there's a lot to buy and
you're going to pay less it's a little
bit slower less volatile in the medium
range today if you were to buy space
right now in October 2016 you could get
a / 16 for about 10 or 11 bucks if you
are dealing with a very seller with
desirable space who's very astute you're
going to pay more and then there's a
large blocks large blocks eight to ten
bucks right now fourteen fifteen dollars
but look out because I'm seeing the
prices rise very very fast in the large
blocks so before you get to the market
you need to know before you go you know
how much you want to buy and how long
it's going to last right model it out
figure out what you need because then
you got to go to your company and you
have to secure your capex and the capex
is not only your purchase price but it's
two things you're not going to know
which are your transaction fees with the
registry with escrow agents which costs
money and fees that you may be paying to
a broker or to an exchange and after you
get your capex the most important part
of this whole process is if you've got
to find em na lawyers this is not going
and buying five hundred million dollars
worth of
infinera gear okay nobody in your
company knows what you're talking about
when you say I need counsel for buying
IP addresses they don't know what that
is and what you tell them is its M&A
activity you're making an acquisition of
somebody else's intellectual property
purchase price seems to matter a lot but
it's actually one of the least important
parts of the deal the terms and
conditions the covenants the
representations the warranties are the
most important part when you're a buyer
you need to purchase an asset and you
need to protect your company while
you're doing this and by the way that
costs money you're going to need
significant operating capital to pay for
these M&A lawyers as Amy said just keep
in mind what's going on in the rirs you
cannot buy space and lack nique or
AfriNIC and move it out of the registry
nor if you're operating in those regions
can you move space you purchase an
errand ap Nick or ripe into lac Nick or
AfriNIC and if you have to do that which
some of us do that's just going to add
complexity into the terms and conditions
of your contract have your RA our
account ready to receive the addresses
Amy talked about that I'll move on the
regulatory framework and the reason I
put this in here is the very first
paragraph of an asset purchase agreement
the lawyer needs to know what words to
use what is it you're buying well if
you're buying IP addresses in Aaron land
you're not buying an asset you're buying
a license for a slot in a database okay
in right you're pretty much buying an
asset as far as that legal regime is
concerned and a peenics very clear they
don't care but it's probably an asset to
be bought and sold in LAC Nick and
afrinic to the best of my knowledge
these are undefined terms um I work for
big companies so I wanted to put in some
interesting notes for buyers who work at
typical big companies you need to teach
finance how to book it these are
intangible assets they go on what's a
called an amortization schedule it'll be
amortized for a certain number of years
which is dependent on the accounting
practices of your finance department
they'll
let you know transactions are not closed
with a p.o you're not going to go get a
purchase requisition and turn that into
a p.o you have to do it with a wire
transfer I don't know about you but
figuring out how to do a wire transfer
at a big company for the first time is
not the easiest thing so you go make a
friend over in corp dev and the MA folks
and you learn how they do wires or you
go out and find people in the Treasury
who control the cash in your company and
you make a friend and they help you and
they're ready to initiate a wire when
you're ready to send one so now you got
to go find a seller brokers are not your
friend brokers and exchange operators
are very valuable as a buyer and as a
seller this is a silly market buyers
don't talk to buyers sellers don't talk
to sellers the sellers don't know who
the buyers are and the buyers don't know
who the sellers are think about that you
want to go buy a / 18 right now you
don't want to deal with a broker where
you going to buy it from how do you know
who's selling nobody talks to anybody so
the broker is an exchange operator
hugely important but understand they're
not here to help your network operate
they're here to make money they want the
prices to rise over time you want to pay
as little as possible so your interests
are not aligned keep control you're in
control if you let people tell you what
to do and how to do it and it doesn't
work for you you're the one who's on the
wrong side of the transaction
deal-making is about people this is just
like peering and transit people will
sell to you and accede to your terms if
they like you and they like you if they
know you and if they know you it's
because you've gone to them or you've
met with them and your face to face I
mean think about how much we get done
here at an an ugh because we talk to
each other and we see each other email
doesn't work for this stuff a lot of the
time and you have to be cognizant that
it's not just North America in some
cultures around this world email is not
an acceptable medium for business you've
got to do it face to face the more money
you spend the more time you need to be
on a plane when you get to the deal it's
about price it's about the timing of the
delivery as Amy was talking about and as
I've been harping on it's about the
terms and conditions of the contract
there's a bullet point here we can give
you ninety percent of the space now but
we're going to need a few months to
finish cleaning up the other ten percent
you're going to see this a lot a lot of
blocks of IP addresses they're not quite
ready to go so protecting your company
when you're doing your due diligence
there's technical due diligence ripe r
is the routing information service is
the best tool you will have during this
process it tells you about the history
of the routing talks about block list it
talked about registration history the
last point there is the seller routing
the block internally you'd be surprised
how many people sell IP addresses from
the CFO's office without actually asking
the ops folks and the office looks like
dude what are you doing we're using
these it happens a lot the legal ones
we've talked about make sure the IP
addresses aren't under contractual
obligation I mentioned this because this
keeps happening to me because I keep
buying from defense contractors defense
contractors have some contracts that are
really really old and it's some military
division way far away from what they can
see and that division is using the IP
addresses so you really want to make
sure that your seller doesn't have
obligations to the IP addresses that
they may not even know about until you
ask the question
the last thing I want to talk about is
fraud I've been doing this for three and
a half years I have bought a lot of IP
addresses from a lot of different
companies through brokers through direct
and I'm going to tell you thirty percent
of this market is fraud there are two
types of fraud we're going to talk about
today wilful fraud where they're trying
to screw you and unwitting fraud were
they completely trying to act in good
faith and they're just messing up
willful fraud is pretty upfront they're
selling space that's not theirs they're
selling non-registered space you get an
exhibit it's got ten blocks on it not
all of its actually registered they're
selling space that they hijacked from
the RIR jamie talked about or the worst
kind which is there intentionally
selling space that they had to lie to
the RIR to get when you're buying a big
block from a company you've never heard
of from a person you've never met ask
yourself why are they selling how did
they get this large block and why are
they selling it then there's the more
interesting unwitting fraud there's a
lot of merger and acquisition activity
especially in North America and you'd be
surprised how many folks think they have
space but they don't they're selling you
space that's in their name but as
actually through mergers and acquisition
belongs to a different company this is
where your lawyers and your due
diligence are very important and then
there's big corporation problems three
times I have bought IP address space
from employees that tried to buy space
from employees at a company who we're
selling it through a broker and it turns
out that department didn't control the
IP addresses a different broker and a
different set of employees in a
different department actually have
control of the IP addresses and that's
really annoying when that happens fraud
is can be avoided by counting on your
lawyers and by using your common sense
as a network operator and as an end
near rigorously vet your seller do not
buy from any company or any party that
you don't already know where you can't
easily find out about there are two
countries where I'm going to advise you
not to buy address space from for two
very different reasons do not buy
address space from Romania ladies and
gentlemen it's fraud okay tell you that
right now not going to sugarcoat it
there's a lot of space for sale it's all
it's all space you don't want anything
to do with if you want to protect your
company which is our responsibility the
second for very different reason be very
careful if someone if a Chinese company
is offering to sell you IP addresses IP
address is in China sell all the time to
other Chinese companies bigger Chinese
companies China Mobile has eight hundred
and eighty million handsets you think
they need some IP addresses when IP
addresses go for sale in China they buy
them or companies like them buy them
they're not going to sail to come
companies outside of China so someone's
trying to sell it to you it's probably
not real Amy talked about escrow agents
they're very important brokers and
exchange operators like to tell you who
to use as an escrow agent only use a
major bank police don't use an escrow
agent you've never heard of it's all I
got thank you thank you
thank you very much Amy if you want to
come join us we're going to open the
microphone to questions we have quite a
bit of time so don't be shy if you have
any statements questions if you think
there's an experience that you want to
share that actually help enrich the
conversation thank you teddy bear teddy
vandenberg from softlayer what control
has an individual lost due to the
marketplace taking up all IP address
assignments and sales what control has
an individual lost right because the
rirs we used to be able to actually
dictate how IP addresses were used in
the past and now it's not as much not as
much control um can you be more specific
because i'm not i don't understand the
question so the rirs have their policies
right and later this week starting
tonight aaron has been reading and we
the community we set the policies right
and we all have to live under those
policy regimes there's what we've
created individuals never had control
over that um corporation you know the
network operator does the IP address has
always belonged to the operators yeah
some old some really old ones belong to
you know Carl our back or an individual
like that but for the most part they
were always registered to companies and
they were an asset of the company you
know ignoring the asset stuff so what
kind of control were you looking for I
guess I was wrkn cerned about smaller
corporation to being or not having the
same access as the larger /
you mean to the rer policy development
process is that we're so small cutting
small companies I mean that's where most
of the market is right mostly market is
in the buying and selling of /
twenty-fours and these are with
generally smaller entities and they
don't have any different control than a
large company bite so I feel like I feel
like it's I feel like the market works
for the sellers and it works for the
buyers because we're able to do these
transactions and you know while we stood
up here we were giving you things to
look out for and things you want to be
careful of it really does work and if
you have a / 24 that you have control of
it is really rightfully your the
registration of you can sell it to
whomever you want and I as a buyer can
buy from whoever I want and the rirs
aren't in the way of that at all as far
as I can see sure so I handle a ton of
really small sales I run an auction
platform specifically aimed at small
buyers and small sellers where we
automate the contract process to get a
lot of the hurdles that the big guys
have to deal with and all of the lawyers
out of the way for these smaller deals
and they still have to go through the
Aaron transfer process and it's a little
bit more difficult for them sometimes
because they tend not to have as much
experience as the operators handling the
larger companies they haven't gone
through the process of getting face
directly from Aaron so sometimes that's
an extra hurdle for them to have to deal
with but they can still participate in
the policy development process like
anybody else can you can participate on
the pp ml you can come to the meetings
and talk if you have a problem with the
policies and how they're applying your
organization so I don't see there being
a huge difference between me between the
large guys and the small guys other than
you know the extra hurdle of getting
your head around going through the
transfer process that you might not have
done before okay thanks Kevin Bloomberg
the wire
question for you first two quick things
first one is the aaron who was service
it wasn't really mentioned there have
either of you use that service as a way
of looking back at the last 25 years of
history related to blocks is that within
the terms things like that because it
was a little ambiguous to me if as part
of a transfer a buyer could look at the
who was data if that's allowed in the
terms and if you've used it in the past
i really be curious about that and so i
don't believe it's technically allowed
under the terms i've seen who was used
for slightly different purposes and then
people that had gotten approval for a
slightly different purpose use it for
that purpose as well i'm not sure you'll
probably better in that vein I used to
tools as I talked about i use right bar
is because i don't look at the routing
history I want to see which a asses
originated routes for the IP addresses
I'm buying for as far back as history
goes and Ras goes back like you know
decades it's wonderful who was as you're
alluding to is great because in Aaron it
shows you the registration history at
each step which you can match up to the
routing history so you put those two
tools together that's a fantastic tool
for seeing the big picture on the block
thank you and the i guess the second
part is a little bit of a statement just
to be aware that within the air and we
do have reserved blocks and there is a
policy right now that would lock those
up and prevent them being used in the
Trina in part of the transfer market so
it's also very important to know if a
block is part of a lockdown so in TP is
an example you weren't allowed to
transfer for three years but there's no
way to necessarily know that without
really digging into it yeah and that and
that's as buyers as engineers as
operators we can't be expected to know
every little detail about every our IRS
rules in every blocks history and that's
where as Amy was saying in a
presentation it's all about protecting
yourself in the terms and conditions can
you get your money back if something
went wrong
I jean-christophe at DePaul University
two brief questions he can choose who
wants to answer this the first you
mentioned thirty percent fraud no
wondering if there's any additional
pattern to that like should I be more
leery of fraud occurring with a / 16
versus a / 24 or not or or does it not
really necessarily matter second
question is if I'm from a one-man shop
but I've got a need for just maybe a
couple of / 24 zits few hundred bucks it
just based on my quick judgment of what
it might cost me at least just for the
address space lawyers that sounds really
expensive for just those two small
relatively assets you still recommend
going through an elaborate lawyer
process or how involved do i need to get
legal rep not a lawyer but how what
might you i expect for legal
representation even for relatively small
purchase purchases in that space um
alright so your first question was about
the fraud in big versus small Amy sure
so I'd say for the most part with a very
large blocks I see a little bit less
fraud especially if it comes from a /
date holder because there are pretty
clear records there and the holders a
very large amounts of space tend to be
very large organizations where you can
do a bit more diligence with ICT I see
more frog going on with the smaller box
especially smaller than a / 16 um it's
yeah I'd say this once you get slashed
Lonnie and small you see you see quite a
bit more so you just need to be careful
about who you're dealing with make sure
that you get you know chain of title
history where it's there and just make
sure you use escrow in other ways to you
know make sure your phones don't go over
a ahead of time and as far the so with
the very small sales I I don't use
lawyers which I don't really see a lot
of organizations using lawyers with a
really small tells just because the
dollar amount is so low that it's just
not reasonable for them to do so
whatever money they would lose from
doing that is typically less than the
cost of
he's being involved in that again just
use escrow yeah it's better tolerance
for risk you know no one here is going
to tell you what when to use and what
not to use a lawyer that's up to you but
it's what your tolerance for risk at 15
bucks an IP address it's over four
thousand dollars for his last 24 does
that four thousand dollars plus the time
you put in is that is that mean a lot to
you if it does then you spend a little
bit more and and protect yourself more
if it's negligible then you are open to
more risk this in the very small in the
scenario you've outlined this is where
brokers and exchange operators are very
very helpful because their interest is
in just moving right volume and they
want a successful market because it's
good for their business this is where
they can really be a help but the small
for the small / 24 transfers once you've
agreed on price and you're okay with the
price you're paying your brokers and
exchange operators have done this
they've iterated it over and over and
and I'm feel pretty confident saying
you're probably in good hands if you've
picked a good broker or exchange sure
and our reputations are at stake with
these two cos we do so many of these
it's not this is a one-time deal where
we're in and out so we so we do have
quite a bit of vetting that goes on
before we even engage a seller because
we would hate to be in a situation where
we perpetuate some sort of fraudulent
activity because you know where
reputation is high to what we're doing
here I had a statement in a question
using my own mic Donnie roizman with
softlayer just two statements I want to
echo a bit once they've on Deko a bit
the value of brokers or exchange
operators is definitely huge these are
experts in the market many companies
maybe would complete one two three
transactions over a multi-year period
these exchange operators and brokers are
moving a multiple per month so they're
there they're really tapping your
tapping into a good resource their one
recommendation I would make is if you
are being solicited by a broker and
exchange operator which you have never
bumped into a tan a nog
or an errand or ripe or an AP Nick
delete the email hang up the phone I you
really want to be working with people
who are active in the space who know the
business know the industry and know the
players in the space i would say your
best bet is look look at one of these
conferences and talk to the broker so
you can actually see in person that
you've seen coming back again and again
one question I had is you'd mentioned
even in your slide that there are some
cases where you might be speaking to a
seller and they'll say well I have
ninety percent ready now and the rest of
the ten percent might be ready in the
future what would be your advice or
recommendation if you find yourself in
that position so I mean it depends on
your situation if you don't need that
ten percent it's a good it's a good
transaction it's a qualified seller it's
someone you're comfortable doing
business with the price is right go for
it you you structure the terms and
conditions of the contract to ensure
that there are penalties or there are
motivations for them to follow through
and deliver future tranches as they're
clean you follow up engineer to engineer
people generally act in good faith if
you found a good buyer and if you're a
qualified seller you know people are
just trying to do business right so it's
increasingly common as far as I can tell
that you're not going to get all the
space right away so you have to be
flexible and you have to be flexible in
your terms you have to understand the
seller is trying to make a sale so you
need to work with them and put yourself
in their shoes and say well what would
you do and go with it I would just sort
of preface off I think that's very much
true for large sales if you're looking
fine a / 16 are smaller and the entity
you're working with can't get off of the
space all at once keep looking there's a
ton more space out there especially if
it's less than a 16 so that's really
just that's a large pyre problem it's
been surf from google a couple of
questions first one is is there any kind
of a reputation system that would help
someone figure out if they are speaking
to a reputable broker or agent not that
I'm aware there's no gossip sheets over
you can become a registered facilitator
with the rirs f transfer policies in
place although I when we sign up I'm
pretty sure we just had to sign a
document pay five hundred dollars i'm
not sure it didn't there wasn't a ton of
vetting going on there yeah it's a it's
a very young market and the opaqueness
sometimes works against us yeah so maybe
ask for references and look at the types
of organizations that are giving you
references from are they organizations
that you've heard of so the second
observation is when I hear terms like
purchase and asset that makes me nervous
some of you will have watched the iono
transition debates and actions that were
taking place very close to the
transition point an argument was being
made that an asset of the government was
being transferred this is not helpful I
gather it's almost impossible to stop
but we have the same problem with domain
names people speak as if they owned them
but they really only have a license to
use I noticed that you were careful to
say that Erin refers to license there
are good reasons for that to protect the
whole system but I gather that our
friends outside the US don't have the
same litigious concern is that we do
yeah I'll share something with the
audience I john curran the CEO of erin
has been very loud and upfront over the
last year and a half that IP addresses
are not an asset as far as Erin is
concerned they are a license
and this didn't sit all that well with
me so mmm the company I work for is
spending a lot of money so I wanted to
make sure we got it right so we invested
some money in some time then a lot of
lawyers to do months of research and
really look at this and in the United
States and under US law we came to the
conclusion that Aaron's position that
Vince is expressed very well as one
hundred percent backed up by the law
these are not yours these are not assets
and that's where you got to be really
careful in that first paragraph of that
contract that asset purchase agreement
it's not yours you're gonna use it
basically going to think about it like
yours because we're you know they're on
a network and hopefully they're going to
be there for decades but it's not an
asset then vintage saying software is
starting to turn into that as well just
a minor language point there's a
difference between an asset and property
so you can have a contract right that is
an asset but it doesn't mean you own it
like property but I think that what
we're getting at here is the property
question yeah and in North America they
treat it as a contract right but there
are all sorts of contract rights that
you can buy and sell that doesn't make
it your property it just means you're
assuming somebody else's position within
that contract but it's still you know an
asset of your organization Kevin Kevin
Bloomberg so thankful even brought up
the regulation and of the brook get of
brokers where there really isn't any and
just to add to the concern I have seen
brokers at multiple conferences Aaron
and nanog and Barnum & Bailey would be
proud
just because you've seen them in the
halls the stuff that they're selling is
ridiculous so what I'd actually like to
ask each one of you is can you sort of
point out the best not even fraudulence
the wrong word the biggest exaggeration
the biggest crap you have seen from
pseudo brokers in our industry something
that really stood out and I'll actually
start with you my favorite was the
broker who tested his sellers space and
in doing so got it listed on every
blacklist out there and made it
unsalable that stupidity not malicious
but stupidity so do you have any good
stories in that regard um I I recently
had a fun fraud case I'm helping
somebody get some space back that was
Friday lately taken from them there is
another broker I'm still working out the
details i'm not going to assign any
blame or name any names but it looks
like there is a broker that was involved
with submitting some fraudulent
documentation that included a notarized
signature from somebody that had been
dead for 20 years yeah yeah the stories
I could tell I spent 10 years of Aaron
fighting fraud I've seen a lot of it
when I had a broker this week offer a
tranche of a / 12 to me for fifteen
dollars an IP address but it's a no it's
an opening number it's fine it's not
that irregular today and they said but I
have a different seller who has 40
different blocks that together comprise
almost a / 12 and he's willing to sell
them to you for nine dollars gosh why do
you think that is
why when a broker comes to you and has
to what they think of as equivalent
block sizes and two completely different
prices one of which is completely below
market you got to ask yourself why and
that really looked at that email from
the broker and he and I known each other
a long time so emails fine I said you
know why would this guy doesn't get it
God doesn't realize that we're dealing
with these people who are just scamming
for box you're not helping anybody hello
one thing I'll say in defensive brokers
that will give you two different prices
sometimes we do have clients that have
different timing requirements or
suchlike you're with me look like a
bankruptcy estate or something where
there's a limited time period where they
need to get those funds and sometimes
they can provide you with a credible
back story of why one seller might be
willing to sell for below market value
it's probably upfront about yeah yeah
they should tell you about how to write
and if they don't ask about it make sure
it makes them that's one cuz i know are
realistic stories for what something is
priced it below market ah i see someone
at the microphone john curran CEO aaron
if you're uh there's a lot of reputable
useful brokers out there if you're a
emerging creative broker was attempting
to make a quick money by getting people
to send it to you don't start off by
putting an offer together to sell an IP
address block that's not registered to
you and then spamming me with your offer
not productive
hey Donny
there we go thank you very much Amy and
David that was one of them
for guitar it's my pleasure