she won't get filling out your surveys
days hi everybody good afternoon my name
is Ron when we
evangelist for radware for North America
and prior to joining rad where I was at
server central an end layer for a very
long time where I learned a whole lot
about how to handle volumetric DDoS
attacks I learned a whole lot from this
Community I've been a member of the
mailing list for eight or nine years now
it's an honor to be here and to talk
with all you today so thank you at
server central as I said and an end
layer we were really good at being
creative about handling volumetric
attacks and how to handle big attacks
inside of our network but there were
other needs that we had and why we
looked at some solutions out there and
ultimately chose radware to help with
some of those and specific examples of
attacks and Here I am almost almost a
year now at radware so what we're going
to talk about today is the D dots
marketplace we're going to talk about
I'm going to start off with a little
story to kind of set a framework for us
and I'm we're going to talk about this
hacking pay we're going to present both
sides of that does it pay for people to
attack our networks how are they
attacking our networks what are the
tools that they're using how are these
available to them there's a whole
marketplace that we're going to talk
about some of its dark net some of its
clear net and we're going to wrap up
within and a review of maybe a different
look on the ROI on protecting our
networks so so we'll start off with that
story in 1886 a gentleman named Frank
Doria attended a oh hi oh state fair and
he found a one cylinder force four
horsepower motor that he thought you
know what this is probably strong enough
to power my horseless carriage so
Charles Doria was an accomplished
bicycle mechanic with his brother Frank
and they went to work and in five years
after five years of work they came up
with their first version of the
horseless carriage the powered horseless
carriage of their first automobile and
then advanced five more years by 1896
they became the first commercially
produced automobile manufacturer in the
United
it's a for 1,900 I didn't know that
didn't many of you probably didn't know
that and a lot of us think that Henry
Ford is the person who who we attribute
to the automobile but Henry Ford didn't
even actually get into manufacturing
automobiles until 1901 and the ford
motor company didn't start till 1903 so
we've got a couple years of good you
know maybe 15 years of good experience
in in the market and developing cars and
but Henry Ford is the guy who we think
of right and so we attributed that to a
lot of different things we attribute
that to advancements in manufacturing
and Henry Ford is attributed to really
economizing on the assembly line we have
advancements in infrastructure roads
Henry Ford made took their other that
recipe and took the recipe of the right
price and the right product and combine
that with the right economic situation
we had the roaring 20s world where one
had ended and and we have the right
recipe for Henry Ford to be the guy who
we think of with with automobiles right
so this story is a little bit familiar
we kind of see us in a similar type of
situation happening right now with how
people attack us we'll talk about a lot
of examples today we're going to show
you real examples of how the data that
is out there screenshots of things for
sale everybody in this room knows what's
happened in the last month in terms of
the volume of the you know the
volumetric attributes of attacks we are
seeing things change very very fast
right and we are at this tipping point
of cyber security or cyber attacks in
our networks and we think that there are
three interesting aspects that make this
up we have more resources so the people
who are attacking us have access to
better tools many many options for tools
we have more targets for us as people
who operate networks we have a lot of
things that are valuable on our network
maybe it's you know digital assets maybe
its intellectual property maybe it's
customer records we're going to talk
about some of those too and we have more
maturity we have
we have been dealing with DDoS attacks
for a very long time the people who have
been doing DDoS attacks have been had a
lot of years for for getting better at
it so it's it's a pretty similar recipe
I think so we think that hacking has has
turned the corner right so take a kind
of a step back here Hollywood
romanticize is hacking and hacking is
there is an interesting attribute to it
to you know there's somewhat of a
romantic attribute to it I happen to
watch these are a bunch of movies that
happen to watch sneakers again this
weekend and I've gone through some you
know some some interesting things there
swordfish is the movie where the
reference a ds3 connected to a computer
that allowed seven network set wants to
be accessed and that was just amazing we
joke about the IP address is being wrong
in this stuff so that to us this is kind
of funny and in jest but it's also
Hollywood sets a picture of hackers for
us this last one we are legion if you
haven't seen it it's on netflix and
youtube and yeah it's a good one to to
see because it's more of a realistic
documentary of of what is what was
happening with anonymous recently but
the reality is that the people attacking
us probably look more like the team on
the left then the gentleman on the right
now this again is just imagery and and
put out there but the reality is that
the gentleman on the right is probably
working in the cold aisle in the data
center and in fact i think you can see
the cold air blasting on to him there
but the point of this is that there is
organization in the network and the
people that are attacking us and the
let's talk about this set this is a
slide from hewlett-packard a
hewlett-packard enterprise that was a
study that showed there are structure
organizational structure attributes to
networks and people who are attacking us
right we have employees we have paid
employees who are people whose job is to
do recon in a network we have bonuses
for good work we have obviously a big
take on bounty or things that were taken
out of a network here we see different
these this graphic shows different
functions that a person might play in an
organization that is that is
perpetuating crime and we think that
because increasingly the answer is that
crime is paying right let's take another
look at this dr. Larry Ponemon in his
group the Ponemon Institute has done
some of the best work on quantifying the
impact of attacks on two networks this
is very hard thing to do and and they've
done a great job with it this is a
report that ponymon Institute has done
with palo alto networks and there were a
couple good bullet points that I wanted
to pull out of here most interesting to
me the their study says that the average
hacker or attacker earns approximately
one-quarter of the salary of the average
IT employee so that swings the pendulum
in the other way right part of that what
they found is that the cost and time to
to complete attacks has decreased
because of better access to better tools
and you know better things out there but
the one point that I would make is that
in contrast to that first point nobody
goes into this being average wanting to
be average nobody plays high school you
know plays football wanting to stop in
high school every kid dreams of being in
the pros and taking that big hall and
that I think is why people you know
continue to do that this graphic also
comes from that HP a document it's a the
business of hacking it's a pretty good
document if you were interested in
reading it but it talks about the
valuable the value of certain assets and
their their ease or difficulty of
attaining them right so credit cards
which were once the most sought-after
asset are really not as valuable anymore
and I'm sure just like me many of you
have changed your credit card numbers or
re-issued your credit cards this year or
last year because this is the world we
live in today right so the the longevity
of these assets is not as attractive to
two people not to people taking them but
in contrast medical records are hugely
profitable medical records are ever all
of the PII information that you need for
identity theft and there it's a lot
harder to to change your address and and
all of the things that come from medical
records intellectual property is up
their credentials has been found to be
even you know a lot of us are used to
credential breaches and so we are aware
as users that we have to use diverse
passwords and you know change them
frequently I think we're although it's
still a problem we're more and more
educated so that the value of them has
not become a an increasing or decreasing
kind of thing this era says
vulnerabilities are pointing down they I
believe are pointing up we're going to
talk about some vulnerabilities and
exploits the same there was a company
called zero diem who was offering a 1.5
first a million-dollar bounty for
exploits on an iPhone on iOS and then I
read that it was increased to 1.5
million dollars and then I read that it
was paid but there's some skepticism in
the in the community that says where's
the proof you know this is potentially a
a publicity stunt but you know an
interesting attribute so we have a
million dollars that you can make with
exploit I'm going to go through some
examples these are screenshots of actual
attacks a hacker this summer called the
dark overlord
gained a lot of popularity for Tim
taking information from big breaches and
posting them for sale online I don't
list this to point out anybody who was
affected by this just the reality of
what's there so in this first example
the dark overlord had he breached three
healthcare networks with a remote
desktop protocol vulnerability rdp and
and three separate networks was able to
gain some of this information the first
auction that was listed for sale was
four hundred thousand or so wreck
healthcare records of customers in
Georgia listing them for just over six
hundred Bitcoin that's three hundred and
fifty thousand dollar central Midwest
same attack two hundred and ten thousand
records 303 Bitcoin about 175,000
dollars 48 thousand records in Missouri
151 Bitcoin or about eighty seven
thousand dollars so if the dark overlord
sells this one time on the real deal
which we'll talk about the real deal he
stands to make six hundred thousand
dollars seven hundred thousand dollars
maybe with some other stuff and just by
selling at one time right this crime
pays right here's another example
bitcoin bitcoin is a legitimate currency
right there was an attack on bitfenix
which is the third largest bitcoin
exchange in the world based in hong kong
a gentleman were an attacking party
breached the exchange stole 119,000
bitcoins 72 million dollars of take from
breaching tiffanix so much so that i
hope that you can see this in the back
this is a 30 day view of the value of
Bitcoin there was a twenty percent
decrease in the value of Bitcoin the day
that the news was released twenty
percent impact a financial impact from a
simple hack I'm not a simple hack I
don't mean to say that it's simple but
from a hack a twenty percent decrease in
the value of a legitimate currency and
now there's a new attribute to that
there's a 3.5 million dollar
reward for information leading to the
recovery of these bitcoins so you know
you could pay to steal that and it could
pay to return it and this graph may look
familiar to a bunch of us earlier in
about the springtime there was some
discussion in the mail thread about DDoS
attacks and a gentleman named gyre
Santana posted a response discussing
some of his research this is a graph
from his website called booter blacklist
and he has developed an algorithm that
has looked at some of the Alexa database
and and scraped information off of the
web to look for booter and stress or
websites now booter and stressors are
volumetric attack tools right booter
coming from the term of booting people
off of gaming networks and stressors
coming from maybe adding legitimacy to
the service of I'm stress testing your
network right so tired and his
colleagues work found approximately 400
may be more 430 or so publicly
accessible booter and stress or services
available on the clear net so back to
the story of the Ford and an automobile
you know between that time there were
about 200 or so startup via car
companies and we think about Henry Ford
right here's the another similarity
right we've got four hundred or so
booter and stress or services available
on the clarinet where any one of us
could go and buy an attack for very
little amounts of money in this example
where as little as six hundred six
dollars you can order a 5 to 10 gig
volumetric attack lasting 10 minutes or
more I pay more than that to ship a
return back to amazon right that's
nothing six dollars could really put
somebody's lights out for or you know
when they need it most more on the
economics ransom ransom was a big thing
in the past maybe year and a half two
years two year and a half where Armada
collective bless you automatic
collective and lizard squad were sending
emails that say i am going to attack you
Amy this many Bitcoin to this address
just so that you know
serious here comes an attack and forward
this to any decision maker in your
network who can pay us and they made a
good amount of money for a long time we
recently did a report at radware that
showed that one in seven people have say
they have been ransomed in the past year
and of the people that paid this is a
really big distribution a difference in
in what we've seen but in the US 75
hundred dollars was the average ransom
paid in the United Kingdom 22,000 pounds
was the was the average ransom that was
paid that's that's a lot of money though
on the success of these bought of these
ransom attacks we have copycats right so
this was this is pretty clever those
ransom emails were sent some of it had
kind of went quiet for a while and then
it earlier this year we saw copycats
people sending very similar type of
messages sometimes from domains that
were registered that same day and most
of these did not include the same letter
more or less most of them did not
include the volumetric attack that is
the what we call a warning shot but
think back to those stressors those
booters and stressors for six dollars or
whatever you can send that warning shot
for very little investment here so think
about what is what the economics of this
now right I've got maybe a VPS somewhere
that I get for a couple dollars for a
month I send an email and register a
domain name and I you know do some
administrative work and maybe if I want
to I add another six-dollar attack but I
send these fake emails going on the
coattails of what had happened in the
community and these guys reportedly made
a hundred thousand dollars in about six
weeks of of work for just sending email
it's crazy a different aspect of the
economics of attacks so this is a recent
one there are new updates to this just
as recently as this weekend but we have
the NSA hack that we know about the
shadow brokers an actor
said we have breached the equation group
the equation group being associated as
the elite hacking team for the NSA the
same team that did the Stuxnet attack on
Iran to dismantle or you know attack
their nuclear program so there was a
breach of their attack tools and the
shadow brokers released it to the public
and they put it up for auction and they
said the highest bidder will win the
tools but anybody else who bids is lose
lose they lose the bid they don't win
the auction and they lose their money
you don't get your money back and then
they said if a hundred RF 1 million
Bitcoin were raised which is seven 572
million dollars they would release all
of the tools to the public that's a
that's a that's a big that's a big hack
that's a big take and takes a little
huts but I kind of go out and do that
one to the update to this since the
slides were submitted was over the
weekend they have canceled the auction
and now they are crowdfunding is so to
the tune of 10,000 bitcoins which is
about six million dollars so hopefully
there they are hoping that they're going
to get six million dollars and just
about 10 days ago somebody was arrested
with the route correlation of some of
this so I wonder are they have they
changed their tune to try and get
something before the for the heat comes
on them as well again with the NSA
there's another side to this there's a
negative impact us in this room right so
we know about the NSA prism project
information that was leaked by Edward
Snowden but that is a head impact to us
as Internet operators and internet
businesses companies have started
avoiding the United States for for doing
business here Brazil has some pretty
important laws about or regulations
about not having certain content inside
of the US or even traverse the US brazil
is even building a submarine cable to
europe to completely bypass the US so
there's an impact for us the ITIF has
said that the loss of business from this
35 bill
in dollars to us and to related
companies right but then Forrester
Research came back and said you know
what we think this is going to be a lot
bigger we think it's a hundred and
eighty billion dollars so there's a
negative impact for us for this stuff so
all of this stuff we're going to talk
about how people attack us and how
what's there how they get access to it
and what we can do about it so this is
the guy from the men's wearhouse I
guarantee it the cyber attack
marketplace is a complete marketplace
for you know cyber marketplace for e
criminal or for criminals and e-commerce
mostly on the darknet some of it is on
the clarinet most places are available
for everybody but some places require
that you commit a crime to gain access
to them and some of them quite
interestingly show you you have to
they'll give you a target that you have
to hack and if you are able to do it
then you gain access to their
marketplace if not sorry the most common
current the you know bitcoin is the
other attribute to this you know I think
the Bitcoin has really driven the
success of these marketplaces as well
bitcoin is largely anonymous largely lon
durable largely easy to to to make this
all happen right it's not completely
anonymous not completely untrackable but
it's it's the fluidity has made this
stuff more successful I think so they
have a fully a full marketplace that's
readily available to them we'll talk
about some of these and some of the most
popular hell alpha Bay I've got some
alpha bay these are the real deal alpha
Bay vahala hansa the real deal the real
deal is actually now offline as of about
11 days ago the real deal gained its
popularity when peace of mind had
released all of his breeches or
downloads that were available for sale
so they were all
on the real deal is so it gained a lot
of popularity 10 days ago or so 11 days
ago it's it's now offline and
unreachable but you can buy anything
where you can buy much more things that
are outside of the realm of cyber
security but for us dee da services the
tools for hacking tools for for cyber
attacks pii lists and you don't need to
look for it on the clear net on the left
is an example that we're going to dive
into more but this was a company called
V das you can find auctions and listings
for things in real legitimate websites
and you can find you know people
advertising their information on hacker
forums in both the clear net and the
dark pen and people market their
services right just like real businesses
back to that model of business you know
for all of these people who are doing
this how do you become the next video
sore the next Shenron attack tool it's
it's it's you know be becoming the best
Adam right it's the best service its
customer service so here's an example of
people marketing poodle corp who
recently also got in trouble around the
same time of 10 days or so ago said on
Twitter these upcoming attacks are
coming courtesy of poodle Corp and then
EA Sports said so I folks were down and
then poodle Corp said yep that was us so
that was us what we call stunt hacking
advertising your what you're doing
social media net stressor in this
example had this was a Twitter post that
said we are responsible for taking down
this this bro Isis website so it's a
form of advertising right forums our
community we're used to forums to find
anything we
any research or information that we
might need but this exists on the
darknet to customer service again back
to that being a successful business this
is an example from somebody you know the
of what they offer there's professional
website there's client support auto by
you know all of these things that that
make it try to make a better user
experience to the person buying so that
they come back and then they get gained
the reputation of being the best
business the best service out there and
then there are also things that you'll
never find you and I will never find and
it just as a matter of how it's done
right a lot of it is rep you know
personal interaction and reputation and
things that will just never have access
to all of these things are available as
a service so I mentioned before the
Shenron attack tool Shenron attack tool
was one of the biggest it is the lizard
squads public stress or service that is
available on the clarinet there were
three payload attacks available I'm sure
that the people in this room have been
on the bad end of this either having a
transiting our network or perhaps
targeting our network but here in this
example they've got eight different
price points for different services that
you can buy and these guys were were
recently and again in that tent ten days
or so ago time frame these guys were
arrested now the interesting point here
is that these guys 19 year old men the
men who were taken into custody for this
19 year old men and had been operating
one of the best most well-known stress
for services at out there so don't make
the mistake that somebody who might be
that age has any correlation into
sophistication with this stuff and I
think it would be a mistake to do that
but so they were recently taken offline
vidas maybe about two weeks ago had some
maybe two to three weeks ago had some
attention these are 18 year old men from
Israel who were operating this site 13
different attack vectors we
are available for 1999 you could you can
launch a big attack it was one of the
most popular tools they had customer
service they had like if somebody needed
a question it would send messages text
messages to their cell phones and it was
really run like a real business right 18
year old men this site was running for
four years so the media says that the
first two years they cleared six hundred
thousand dollars us so we can deduce
that in the four years of operation
these 18 year old men probably cleared a
million dollars attacking us and beating
up our networks you can get anything
right here's somebody advertising email
hacking 4.35 Bitcoin that's about two
hundred dollars social media hacking 4.4
Bitcoin one of the things that's on here
that I love great changes for half a
Bitcoin for three hundred dollars is
that I have a Bitcoin yeah I can
potentially change your grade right I
think that we're going to see people
some of the stuff changing right over to
the point of I can you know for before
Bitcoin i can say that you went to
Stanford or you went somewhere right
there's what's to stop that I'm going to
dig into another example here there are
job boards right this is jobs for
hackers this is the craigslist of the
darknet where you can list your services
where you can request services like Mia
here who went to UC Davis and said I
need a great change ASAP I'll tip you
well please contact me at this gmail
account which I've done her a favor
maybe and blocked out or her wicker
account but this is real this is this is
happening right this is amazing to me so
everything that you need also right d
das has a service you can buy this is on
the real deal
an example from the real deal bot net
rental here's another example somebody
offering the pc machines mobile android
phones like a botnet of 40,000 devices
you know that can be used to i said i
think it's 500 SMS attacks per second
that would be a bad day for somebody who
had to deal with that here's a male of
malware ransom ad from alpha bay one of
the other marketplaces where somebody
can can buy a malware to attack your
network right these marketplaces are so
legitimate that they they offer escrow
services for payment though I want to
buy something I put money into escrow a
third-party escrow I receive the service
and then the payment is released as to
add legitimacy to the service that's how
I advanced this is this I thought was
very interesting here's a company called
serve net networks that there is another
server networks I don't believe it's the
same as on the clear net but this is
dark net hosting right this is for
eighty nine dollars you can get a
unmetered one gig server up completely
on the dark net right and up to this
example there's more there but up to 120
dollars and it's priced just like every
other legitimate service anyway very
well might be legitimate you know it
does just because you're on the dark net
doesn't mean that you're doing nefarious
things but it's interesting legitimate
business on the dark net here's somebody
offering a zero-day exploit a exploit
for for a telegram 11 Bitcoin again
escrow available wordpress accounts you
know data leak fraud leaked to admin
credentials it's all out there this is
one that i thought was very interesting
here is somebody advertising a
and exploit to a certain kind of router
they say that there's 250,000 of these
routers out there there are ce8 capable
so i can do remote code exploits an
execution on them and in the notes here
they say which you certainly can't see
there are 250,000 of these available in
China and 45 Bitcoin 35 hundred dollars
you can have your own mob botnet of
these machines so the economics of you
know what can we do moving forward all
of this and all of us us having to
defend this in our network has really
created a point of we have a lot of
spending right and and things change and
so we technologies change and and we
have spent a lot of money to helping
protect our networks right we have the
traditional stuff the firewalls web
application firewalls we buy more
servers and load balancers and ddos
protection and then on the cloud side of
things we buy cloud yeah instances for
replication or disaster recovery and we
buy dedicated links to our cloud and you
know we have business implications we
have SL a's for customers that we have
to meet if our service is not available
we have profits we have cyber insurance
that we buy for the people side we train
people we hire people we hire people to
do audits of our networks and pen
testing right it's very expensive here
so a lot of people we grunt when it's
time to say I gotta spend more money on
my or my security so the ROI for
security is really the holy grail for
for IT right if you can find the right
thing that is the right price point and
does everything that we need if that
exists that's our holy grail right
things have stood in our way of that
right so the definition of return varies
greatly by our role I have another slide
that will talk about how certain people
define the return differently right poor
visibility into our into an actual
attack until it's too late
a lot of times we get attacked and then
we we're reactive than we say oh I need
to I need to prepare for this one of the
it happens you know if it happens again
I'm prepared I need the right tools I
need the right tools to dissect the
information that happened I need the
right tools to protect my network a lack
of understanding of whether or not you
fit in attackers profile if not knowing
that you have something that is worth
taking we're worth attacking you for is
is one reason people don't understand
this overlooking the actual cost of
manual manual mitigation we'll talk
about that I personally have done a
whole lot of that and then the hidden
costs of processing this attack traffic
and we'll go through an example of this
but the business managers is going to
define the return very differently than
a risk manager will or a compliance
manager or you and I who are actually
driving the network and having to handle
what has happened right so we have
things right now that we think you know
it's maybe an even scale right I've got
compliance I've got revenue and brand
assurance and I've got job security but
I the investment I get security budget
is staff and management and operational
risk but if I can look at other things I
can maybe help help look at the cost of
this differently right and that's kind
of what we're talking about as somebody
who handled attacks we had a very big
network we had at server central and end
layer we were very good at handling
attacks volumetric attacks we had great
mx-9 60s that we could quickly do
firewall filters and fingerprints and
log traffic and very quickly identify
and then block an attack sometimes it
was flows back there to block traffic
transiting you know from from peering
ports in San Jose or something but we
were good at it but that's the
volumetric side of things and it's so
its network layer stuff and it's
reactive right I've got a fingerprint my
attack maybe I have some tools with net
flow
but I've got a fingerprint my attack and
then make their deploy the solution that
can take some time especially if it's
the middle of the night you're on call
right so we look to automation sometimes
to say well what can I do to make this
easier right maybe it's just the
fingerprinting of the attack that that
is a little bit easier maybe it's the
whole bit right so as engineers we
should be thinking of automation how
much do we spend about over-provisioning
for bad traffic at our networks at
server central and end layer we spent a
lot of money intentionally to be able to
carry traffic right and that was our
business model and and we were good at
it but not everybody has that you know
that came with a lot of optic costs and
dark fiber costs and cross connect to mr
c's and a lot of router real estate you
know the it was not it was not
inexpensive to be able to do that not
everybody can do that and then everybody
has that ability within their business
right and that's not their job to be
able to over provision for us a huge
attack right so one example of a
customer that we have gave they took
attack traffic a bogus garbage traffic
that was coming into their network and
they were able to reduce 100 terabytes
of traffic traversing their network when
is an operational cost of a million
dollars a year oh I don't mean to say
that you know we are the only ones you
know that this is not a product pitch
it'sit's to make you think about if you
can maybe reallocate certain money or
think about it differently maybe you
don't have to have have to carry that
traffic in your network right just as
something to consider so let's bring it
home again with Henry Ford Henry Ford
great man took advantage of the right
environmental conditions his own
ingenuity his own thinking of how to do
things differently and made a great
success with the automobile industry I
do not draw a comparison between Henry
Ford and cyber attack criminals one is a
great man one or felons and criminals
and
that's not what I'm here to say but the
similarity is is there right so our
security posture has to has to change
right we have more resources available
to us and they don't all have to be paid
right they don't often there are plenty
of good tricks and free ways to help
protect yourself there are more targets
we're putting more information out there
that needs to be protected and the
protections are more mature right so we
have advancements in an AI for
automation for for protection and
algorithms and protecting in algorithms
and people who are aware right and who
have dealt with the tax for a long time
so it might be tipping in our direction
as well as Network people so last slide
personally I love the idea of automation
it can help me either identify an attack
or let me know about it before my
customer calls about it consider
automation simplify with services maybe
you don't have the staff who who wants
to go in and do this or you know
sometimes these things plug along doing
their job and then you only have to look
at it once a month but then you forget
what to do you know at one time a month
so managed services are available from
companies cover your blind spots this is
a big thing attacks there are
smokescreen attacks right so that big
volumetric attack with multiple payloads
that's very complex might be just to
divert your attention from the small web
attack that's happening because all
hands are on deck trying to figure out
how the heck we're going to stop this
volumetric attack and we're going to
divert everything else right the other
side to that cover your blind spot ssl
you know if you have application layer
stuff that isn't encrypted you're going
to need a way to to be able to crack
open that payload and take a look at
whether something's good or bad and
visibility I'm a huge data nerd I
visibility there are plenty of free
tools there are plenty of great
commercial tools the more data to a
point right you know the more data that
you have to
be able to make an actionable decision
in your network the better you know I
I'm a huge proponent of net flow i love
the data that i can extract from the
network to see what has happened for
forensics and i love the idea of
automation to let me know when
something's happening in real time so
with that I opened up for any questions
and we'll we'll also be here throughout
the day as well okay well if you are shy
and want to talk to me independently I
look I look forward to it so thank you
so much it's an honor to be here I
appreciate that