foreign
[Music]
let me Jump Right In a theme of the
conference has been essentially wither
the rules-based order
who who's in charge how do we solve the
Cyber problem and there's been a lot of
pessimism about the role of treaties the
speed with which policy is developing in
an uncertain world where the rules-based
order is under challenge as one of the
foremost thinkers in the United States
about Homeland Security having served as
the the president's top advisor on Cyber
along with other issues and in your
current role overseeing the FBI the
justice department and prosecutors how
do you think about it well thanks so
much John and uh thanks so much for
having me here at the cyber security
Forum here in Munich look I think all of
the work that we are doing and that
conferences like this Advance when it
comes to uh policy issues and
multilateral approaches is absolutely
vital but I also think that we can't
wait we can't wait uh for that process
to move in advance before we uh
certainly at the justice department from
a law enforcement and National Security
perspective before we act which is why
when I came into this job nearly two
years ago I took a kind of wholesale
look at what we were doing in the
Justice Department conducted a
comprehensive cyber review which you
know John because you led that review
and what I determined was we were at a
pivot point and we needed to change our
orientation and we did that and we have
been doing that and we've been acting on
it for the last two years and what we
have done is change our orientation to
one where we're putting prevention first
disruption first and we are putting
victims at the center of our approach so
what do I mean by that I mean we are now
on our front foot and taking action
using an all tools approach a page we
have taken from the book that we use to
as all of you know except because since
it has required multilateral and
international Partnerships uh to beat
back the terrorism threat and to address
the terrorism threat and we're taking a
similar all tools approach to the Cyber
threat so that means we are trying to
break the business model when it comes
to ransomware actors and you see that in
the work we did in clawing back
ransomware payments in the call in the
colonial pipeline attack you see that in
the work that we did with very
importantly International Partners to
hack the hackers when we took down the
hive ransomware Network just a few weeks
ago and Laden wait in the network swiped
decrypter keys and gave them back to the
victims so they could protect themselves
and we are still doing the old-fashioned
work of and very important work of
working with our partners to arrest Bad
actors and you see that in the work that
we've done to arrest the soda nikibi
actors key actors when it comes to
trickbot and lock button I could go on
and on but the point here is we're on
our front foot and not waiting to take
action but importantly putting victims
at the center
and in order to do that uh Innovative
approach of putting victims at the
center you need information you need
intelligence and you need information
intelligence as the foremost law
enforcement action that you can lawfully
act on how do you balance that against
some of the restrictions on sharing
information that are done with good
intentions in the name of privacy what
type of new statutes actions policies do
you need to keep getting that
information so you've hit upon it John
it is vitally important our ability to
rapidly share information with our
partners consistent with legal
Frameworks and protections that apply
but I'm glad you raised this and
obviously this uh this audience knows
all too well the very complicated
environment we all find ourselves in
when it comes to information sharing on
this and a host of other issues and so
what we're doing is trying to put in
place new mechanisms that continue to
have lead legal controls in a framework
that we can all operate under as a as a
global set of leaders and people coming
in good faith to address these issues
and I'll take a case in point
um many of you know I'm sure are
familiar with the cloud act that passed
a few years ago in the United States we
in the United States have entered into a
data access sharing agreement with the
UK under the cloud act but this is
complicated because what we're seeing is
it's being misrepresented and
misperceived and I think there's a lot
of misperceptions about what it is and
what it isn't out there and so I want to
take the opportunity to clear some of
that up because it's a very important
audience to do so first there is a
misperception that the cloud act and
this agreement that we entered into with
the UK and that we hope to do a similar
agreement with other countries in the EU
there's a misperception that it gives
the United States States some new
Authority it does not it makes explicit
A widely accepted principle that a
nation can provide legal process to a
provider if that provider comes within
that nation's jurisdiction to compel
production of information again under
legal process no matter where that
information is held and I say this is a
widely accepted principle because it is
enshrined in the Budapest convention
that has been in in effect for over 20
years I believe and is signed up to to I
think 26 of 27 EU member states and I
say it's a widely accepted principle
because it will be enshrined in the
forthcoming e-evidence regulation that
the EU is promulgating so I think it's
exceptionally important that we be very
clear about the framework we're
operating Under And also the the final
point on this is this type of
arrangement this type type of agreement
is fundamental to our cooperation and I
would argue it is fundamental to cyber
security it's incredibly important that
people understand that the agreement and
the access to data comes with important
safeguards and in our system that means
a warrant issued by an independent judge
based on a finding of probable cause and
based on a very particular showing by
prosecutors in a criminal investigation
so it's incredibly important that we be
clear about the safeguards and the
framework that we operate under
so we've talked a little bit about the
the legal framework and then how you use
that framework to get information to do
things like hack the hackers steal back
keys so people can get access to
information return money to victims but
I know you've just spoke and made a
major announcement in uh in London at
Chatham House I think yesterday and
ironically no Chatham house rules at
Chatham House yes
to get a lot of a lot of press despite
the chatter Mouse rule uh the uh and you
talked there about using a lot of tools
in this space that aren't cyber enabled
using the information to use other types
of tools could you tell us a little bit
about that framework and how it relates
to cyber security sure and you know this
forum is a perfect place to discuss this
because what I talked about in London is
something we are all confronting which
is a era of great power competition
which of course describes a post-cold
war reality but it also describes an era
where autocratic governments are
acquiring using and abusing disruptive
Technologies and by that I mean
technologies that are accelerating
critical advances that give a
nation-state who's using them a military
and National Security Edge and what
we're seeing is autocratic gov
governments trying to acquire these
Technologies and accelerate their
development of them by any means
necessary listen and elicit and so what
I announced was a task force-led Strike
Force called the digital
um uh sorry the disruptive technology
Strike Force led by the justice
department and our Commerce Department
to pool our expertise and go after those
who are trying to acquire and abuse this
technology in violation of our export
control regimes and I think it's
critically important that we are using
these tools that we are doing so in
collaboration both in the United States
and with our International partners
because these Technologies are being
used by autocratic governments to
project power at home and abroad
certainly to make these National
Security advances but also to repress
dissent and engage in transnational
repression around the world and we're
seeing it far too often
if followed up you talk about autocratic
uh regimes I want to talk about one in
particular when it comes to technology
and restrictions on technology and
that's China and there's been a lot of
discussion here about what does it mean
to shape Behavior or use tools like
export control when the goal is not
decoupling but shaping behavior and also
for our German colleagues in particular
but EU how is this approach being done
multilaterally versus unilaterally you
uh you talked about your own personal uh
non-use of tick tock at the conference
for some reason that got a lot of news
who knows but tell us a little bit about
how this approach applies to China and
what's the perspective on the U.S on
working with with colleagues across the
Atlantic
it is vitally important there's not a
single thing that we do uh certainly in
the Cyber realm and in the types of uh
issues that I just described when it
comes to export controls sanctions uh in
sanctions Invasion uh enforcement all of
this takes uh critical work with our
partners every single uh notable cyber
disruption whether it's ransomware
networks that we've taken down whether
it's uh disruption of a GRU botnet as we
did with the operation Cyclops blink
last year all of these things the Hydra
darknet Marketplace that we took down
thank you very much with the help of our
German colleagues everything we are
doing in this space has an international
aspect we cannot operate in a single
Silo none of us can do any of this alone
so International cooperation is a
critical piece of everything we do you
know we say in the United States in
typical fashion using a sports metaphor
that cyber is a team sport well
sometimes the best athlete may be one of
our foreign partners and our goal has
got to be to use whatever the best tool
is to disrupt the attack to prevent the
harm from happening and to put whatever
the best athlete can be on the field and
sometimes that will be our foreign
partner and as teammates we need to
enable our partners just as we would
hope they would enable us so the
international cooperation is vital and I
don't see that stopping anytime soon
you talked about International
cooperation another theme of the
conference has been cooperation with the
private sector in the uh approach where
sometimes the the private sector is
viewed as the villain here and is uh
subject to Regulatory and other actions
saying you need to be more secure and
it's your fault and then others have
talked about them as uh as a victim and
said come in and we're we're here to
help and to use your team partner with
partner with you against the bad guy
what's your message to the private
sector
my message is we are all in this
together and the sooner we all recognize
that we in government and those uh of us
who partner with those in the private
sector uh the sooner we recognize that
the better off we'll be I've talked
about a number of the steps that we've
taken to address malicious cyber actors
the critical element uh to every single
one of these is also victim reporting
take the High
um uh take down uh just a few weeks ago
it was critically important to have
victim reporting there to enable us to
lie in wait quite frankly I described it
as a 21st century cyber Stakeout through
incredibly good work by the FBI and our
partners we literally were sitting
inside the network
and swiping to crypter keys and passing
them on to the victims before they could
feel the effect of the ransomware attack
so that was vital we did that for months
but as as good as it was and as
important as the impact that we had
which was to prevent over a 130 million
dollars in ransomware payments it was a
result of only 20 percent of the victims
reporting imagine the impact we could
have had if we had had a much higher
number so my messages were in This
Together the victim reporting is
critically important it certainly helps
law enforcement but I would argue it
also is good for business it is good for
the bottom line because it can prevent
you it can certainly lessen your loss as
Colonial found but it also can prevent
you from being the victim and also help
you prevent the next victim let me uh
open it up to questions from the
audience the in the role in the United
States at the justice department they
enforce
Behavior to prevent age discrimination
so unlike our esteemed prime minister
colleague any age is welcome to ask a
question although I had
guys hi thank you so much I'm my name is
Dr Jennifer Cassidy I'm with the
University of Oxford
and alongside
um increased information sharing with
your partners
um within the judicial null framework
would you agree that one of the greatest
challenges and something I think about
regularly of our time is the speed and
acceleration of the new disruptive
Technologies versus the length of time
that nation states and Regional blocks
have the ability to legislate for these
new disruptive Technologies and how to
balance that so I'd just be wondering
your thoughts on that and thank you very
much thank you for the um really
insightful question I I think you've Hit
Upon a huge challenge
um the the norms and the Frameworks that
we are all struggling uh to build as we
are flying the airplane of also trying
to ensure that we're developing these
Technologies to be put
to greater good use everything from
semiconductor chips to Quantum compute
shooting to AI but I think what is very
much at the Forefront even as we try and
run both races simultaneously we have to
recognize that China for instance is
doing that as well but from a standpoint
where they are trying to mold the use
and the Norms around these technologies
that privileges their view of the world
that privileges their values those
values are completely antithetical to
our own there those values are about
authoritarianism ours are about
democracy and alliances which this
conference so wonderfully showcases and
just to follow up on that because it's
where you started uh your remarks today
the question was really what do you do
when disruptive technology speeds past
the rate at which laws laws change and
you're known for being action oriented
how do you how do you use tools in that
framework uh in innovative ways with
partners well um we've got to be putting
them to use developing them in concert
developing the Norms around them in
concert but always mindful of our shared
values and doing so within a rule of law
framework because if we lose that I
think we have lost our ballast and we
can't uh we can't be dissuaded from that
and final question
thank you so much Alexander Martin from
the record again I'm sorry to everyone
for having to put up with the journalist
grabbing the microphone and the
Department of Justice has had a couple
of
um quite notable activities against
ransomware actors over the past few
weeks and months
um which of these do you think is going
to be the most successful the sanctions
against the trickbot group
or the kind of hacking the hackers as it
was against Hive and which should we
expect more of going forward
all of the above
so please uh join me in thanking uh Lisa
Monaco Deputy attorney general for
joining us today thanks very much
[Applause]