foreign
[Music]
panel over the years on a wide range of
topics but one feature has remained the
same and that has a panel in common with
some cyberspace that there are no limits
and No Boundaries so we talk about a
wide range of topics
and we tend to be on the gloomy side
normally we are largely focused on
threats and threats of Assessments but I
noticed that this year it's a little
more upbeat but we're also talking about
the next big thing in artificial
intelligence in other areas of cyber and
we would like to focus on that today and
I'm happy to announce a stellar cast
again of people with Sabine if you want
to might come up first hello nearby from
rhb Hello the first public illicit
company in Germany on space and Aviation
joined by Phil who is
I think uh it was coming that's good to
know hi Phil
um who is obviously with Google Cloud
but uh previously he was also uh working
for Goldman Sachs and basically
protecting our financial system hence
our money so that's good to know and
Christopher of course uh from recorded
future hello in Washington
um
which is uh simply is the largest
intelligence company which is pretty
cool to say actually yeah so even if you
are not focused only on threats but
let's start with you and I'm sure you
have discussed that incident today
multiple times but yeah yesterday there
was this Digger operator here in Germany
who
damaged a few cables and basically shut
down the entire airport for the entire
day so is that something you should
laugh about or is that something you
should be deeply concerned about because
it shows that there is still a lack of
understanding how vulnerable this
critical infrastructure is no but it's a
good
this works good so you know when we see
those sort of things we obviously always
go Cyber attack and in fact one of my
colleagues in the room uh I made that
point to oh Cyber attack and this person
said whenever it's this sort of stuff it
always turns out to be a cable and he
was very right so so um the and I think
also the so number one and then Sir Alex
made the point earlier about cables and
you know we talked about Russia a lot
here and googie and what is it 75 uh I'm
not gonna remember their unit number now
I should but um the the main director
for undersea research in Russia who
knows everything about how to cut cables
and so cables are important I guess
that's uh cables are important but isn't
it a little worrying that there wasn't a
backup system in place
um I think you know as we see our world
become more and more interconnected I
like to say that we're sort of at a one
percent of where it's going to get you
know many ways we may think that the
internet is sort of done no we're at one
percent we're at 1.1 percent of where
it's going to get and the sort of
criticality of
or lack of of dual infrastructure you
know the the single point of failure is
maybe it's the right word is is I don't
think we have any clue about how that
how bad that is Phil if we are
determined to look at the bright side it
was mentioned in the panel before that
the attacks from Russia that we're
forecasting our uh during the past year
of the or the year since the invasion
happened
um we're not as bad as as many people
predicted was that primarily because the
Russian attacks and Russian attackers
are not as good as we thought or is your
defense system just so good
well so I think you know we we
interestingly some of you may have seen
we've put out a report today between our
Google threat team and our colleagues at
mandian threat intelligence called the
fog of War which analyzes that situation
in fact you know the the the Russian
attacks did increase
um you know clearly against Ukraine and
against NATO
um I think also we've seen some
fragmentation of
um russian-aligned criminal groups that
are
um you know if one of a better phrase
breaking apart their allegiances because
um as we all remember attackers have
bosses and budgets as well
um and so there's only a finance of
resources to go around in terms of doing
attacks and actually achieving their
criminal goals and if the uh if they're
aligned Masters and not supporting their
profit-making objectives there's going
to be fractures in that and I think we
certainly see that but just on the more
positive note
um well I often describe myself as
short-term pessimistic long-term
optimistic short-term pessimist because
there's still a lot of bad things going
on in the world and there's going to be
a lot more attack and more and more
organizations need to definitely upgrade
their defenses
um one of the things we see a lot in
Cloud infrastructure is companies moving
to the cloud to tap into that higher
level of defense and resilience and
that's the reason I'm more long-term
optimistic is because we have a path
forward to raise the Baseline level of
defenses that adjusts the economic cycle
of attackers imposes cost on them which
starts to tilt the dynamic in in our
favor but interestingly just going to
the point you just made about resilience
is fascinating one of the things that I
I too was impacted by the flights
yesterday and it must be my luck I've
had a few similar situations yeah well
we have a few simple situations with
some of our nice friendly us-based
Airlines and the interesting thing is
it's one of the things that we've got to
think about is it's not just a question
of are those systems resilient enough
and are they capable of recovery but are
they also capable of operating in in
degraded States the thing that
fascinates me is you have a system
outage and it takes everything out and
why does it have to take everything out
you look at some of the some of the
ransomware events that have affected
energy companies they want ransomware
events in their operational technologies
that controlled refineries and pipelines
there were attacks that affected their
office systems so why did the office
systems have an impact on that
environment why why don't we have more
isolation and certainly something in you
know particularly hyperscale
infrastructure we're very very focused
on is how do we assign boundaries and
failure zones and security zones to
reduce the effect or the blast radius of
individual failures and as we improve
security we've also got to think about
how do we improve our ability to be
resilient in the face of attacks not
just how to deal with the attacks
themselves to be able to bring you in it
can be really annoying now to be stuck
at an airport and to wait for a plane
but if something happens in space it can
be really crucial and in the in the
run-up to the innovation rightly
afterwards there are many reports on
incidents in space and satellites that
were being attacked How concerned were
you and your company initially and how
concerned are you now
so luckily we haven't been really
concerned directly
but since we we have infrastructure or
we have our build Satellites by our own
by by our company and for our Engineers
it's a every satellite that we build is
a new kid of the family and we have to
take care of it until it leaves us
forever and forever is not going into
space it's uh it's more the time when
it's going back from space to if it's in
the Leo to Earth so becoming becoming
Starlight or if it's a Geo to go
somewhere else but it really showed the
the attacks on The Wire rights uh
satellite network but also on on on the
bright side if you can say it in in in
times of War
um
the uh the use of of styling it really
showed that um space-based
infrastructure is in not only talking
about resilience but really on talking
about the ability to communicate and we
cannot still we we are at a global
digitalized society and we rely on
cables and we have learned that this is
not a good idea
um we have also yes we have also seen
and learned that um being
uh all that uh
that the gentleman's agreements that we
all thought that everyone is relying on
like um we are not invading we are not
we are not having an Envision into
Ukraine it's not really something that
um is still a fact and therefore it's
also uh the outer space treaty saying
there's no militarization of space
um
I think that um I don't want to say that
we have to really overthink this but we
have to be
we have to stop being naive about it and
therefore we do not only have to think
about how to protect our Assets in space
we have to think about about also more
resilience in space and we have to think
about
um how to save the infrastructure that
is needed on the ground because uh if
you don't have access to space if you
don't have no interest to bring
satellites into space
there's very much emptiness in space but
also you cannot operate satellites if
you don't have a ground infrastructure
if Phil I was glad to hear that you're a
long-term Optimist is that partly
because after the violation of that
gentleman's agreement a year ago did we
see a new push for more uh cooperation
between private actors and and
government agencies to really invest in
cyber security
um so I think that there's been a a
long-term strong relationship in many
geographers between the the public and
the private sector to share information
about threats and vulnerabilities again
to work as fast as we can to resolve
these things based on observed
intelligence one of the things I think
that while we often talk about the
importance of the public-private
partnership between governments and
private sector I think we also need to
remember that most of the work that
happens every single day is private to
private relationships through constructs
like information sharing and Analysis
centers through various other things
that happened in and out of various
National and sector-specific certs and
the most important thing and I think
this is something that is is has been
transformed and continues to be
transformational is industrializing
information sharing there's a history of
where information sharing between
organizations and between public and
private sector was bit artisanal it was
kind of you know craftsmanship based and
individuals sharing information with
each other what we're driving towards
now is the industrialization of this
process so that we can make sharing and
the response to the sharing of those
threats more real time I kind of like to
think about what we're doing as well
wiring up the planet as a digital immune
system so we can detect one attack in
one place and quickly upgrade or respond
to that in all places again imposing
costs yeah no I would I would agree and
I would say you came from the financial
markets you know think about the way we
talk about public private information
sharing to be honest it's ridiculous the
way it works so it's it's I will say
that imagine if you're going on the
stock market and said I want to buy long
Google short Goldman and the way that I
would get the information that's exactly
what I did no so I would use price
inevitable or long long Goldman short
Google and I would want to get price
Discovery for that I want to get the
stock price and now I'm going to go out
and do some public private information
sharing to get the price do you imagine
how this sounds ridiculous and nobody
would be able to you know to trade on
that and number two it would be
incredibly dangerous from dangerous
actors taking advantage of this stuff
every single second and that's you know
what politicians have been talking about
for 30 years public private information
sharing boom no so you need principal
actors who take ownership of the problem
so in financial markets Bloomberg does
that then we model our company to be the
Bloomberg of cyber security so you know
and then now you could also Imagine you
had other sort of constructs it could
you know but but Bloomberg is a great
example of doing this in the financial
markets and they're similar examples in
Pharmaceuticals and how can that really
be because I mean largely uh Bloomberg
and even your company is still a profit
driven Enterprise I mean you're not
doing it pro bono right no but I think
it's a tough problem and so you know you
could imagine having governments doing
it so for example in so in
pharmaceutical Adverse Events to drugs
very important if you guys take a drug
and there's a problem that gets reported
the U.S government has take on itself to
develop this air system adverse event
reporting system and they will from even
if it happens in the deepest parts of
China they'll take that data aggregate
it and turn into a great data set that
any one of you can download and analyze
and so it doesn't have to be Bloomberg
it could be a government sort of thing
but the one thing it cannot be is public
private information sure is this stupid
so that is stupid but it's
public-private partnership particularly
and to be controversial no that's fine
in space security I mean is that
something that
um you have experienced over the past
years evolving or not yes yes it is
evolving um I
so from my perspective public private
partnership especially if uh if it's
taking place in Germany it's
um
if you have a little bit complicated but
um to be optimistic as well on short
term as on a long-term basis
um I think there's always room for
improvement so
um
especially in space I think that public
private partnership has more
opportunities because everything you do
in spaces do will use and therefore
um there are no borders and therefore
you can also share more information
because if you collect information
especially for example your Opera you're
a private operator of your own Earth
observation constellation like I don't
know we know all from from the news
especially since uh the Ukrainian the
invasion in the Ukraine
um from Maxa or from I don't know
other private companies and um
there the the public-private partnership
can also be that uh the the the private
company sells the information the
picture or the service to the government
and um
from my perspective this is uh this is a
good example of Public Partnerships
if you have uh
pop the private Partnerships already in
in building the hardware or then it
could be a little bit more complicated
because then you have always a
government or an Institutional customer
who is
is particularly touchy often in Germany
and that the partnership is more of
building this partnership is more
complicated than other countries have
you seen the uh often quoted Titan
vendor the the turning point in that
area as well now over the past year
um so what the the Titan vendor has
brought us
um is the Titan vendor and and the war
um uh that we are talking much more
about space as an infrastructure as a
critical infrastructure we are talking
much more as well in Germany as in all
other European countries and in
especially in the European Union about
um how do we have to build up our
military infrastructure in space
um we have more information and we we
see more upcoming business or needs in
terms of Safety and Security in space
and from space which is not only the
military use but also
um how to deal with space debris how how
can we how can we protect our
infrastructure and space and how can we
protect our planet Earth from from the
from from space as it's it's not so you
have asteroids you have uh not man-made
space debris
but
um
if you really want to break it down on
on what is written on paper about uh
about how to spend the budget that is
coming from the Titan land there it's
much more saved for other dimensions not
really space now we looked to the
challenges from the past but let's let's
look forward
um many people were in awe of what
happened recently on artificial
intelligence and it has really changed
the equation for many again when you
look at it Phil from your professional
perspective do you see the rice or the
the constant Improvement of artificial
intelligence as a threat overall or as a
real opportunity to improve things no so
so the the I mean we've been investing
massively in artificial intelligence for
the longest time and it's embedded in
many of our products and it achieves
great cyber security effect every single
day so for the uh for the nearly 2
billion people that use Gmail every day
artificial intelligence is protecting
you against malware fishing all sorts of
spam various different links that may
take you to to unwelcome websites you
know that's you know AI has been the uh
the engine behind that cyber security
effect for many years and I could talk
for five hours about all the places
we've applied and embedded AI
um I think you know over the past couple
of years with the research into
Transformer models that was created at
Google that led to the creation of these
large language models I think we're also
seeing the classic dual use issue where
these things are going to be immensely
useful for defensive purposes but
they're also going to lead to many other
consequences we have to deal with you
know one of the things we've been very
very focused on the responsible safe and
ethical use of AI and making sure that
we think about the consequences of using
this technology and introducing and
managing it in in appropriate ways but
we're very very aggressively look always
looking at the opportunities for AI to
act on the difference and it's just
proven highly advantageous on the
defensive front for the past many years
and it's going to continue to do that
but earned you a little concern that
artificial intelligence is going to help
a competitor to basically uh
compete with you in a much more
challenging way now we're always
observing competitors all the time and
everything so uh um I don't particularly
worry about kind of things that
hallucinate regularly so I mean I think
we have to think about how do we
continue to provide capabilities to
people that's the most useful for their
job at hand and delivering accurate
results that that they can rely on is
very important and similarly on a cyber
security front applying artificial
intelligence for a defensive mission to
keep giving us defensive advantage over
attackers and driving the accost costs
up for attackers is just part of the
equation we've been dealing with for the
longest time should Google be more
concerned because artificial
intelligence is going to change the
equation no you know look Google is
incredible at artificial intelligence
we've had a lot of fun with this so we
for example in Ukraine
were deployed in 12 or 13 agencies over
there and I think we get in like
hundreds of thousands of images every
day now sort of from and and not sort of
in the Cyber domain but more in the
physical domain and and so now you get
very interested can I beat a human at
detecting Shaheed 136 drones versus
Shaheed 131 drones versus these sort of
things and so we've been we've announced
a big collaboration with the Ukrainian
government on building uh called an
intelligence Dome around critical
infrastructure that has a cyber element
to it but also a physical element to it
and and you can imagine use these sort
of techniques there in in ways that
you're not going to have a human be able
to do it because of just sheer volume
and so you know and and then we should
be careful about you know dual use
absolutely but no there are some pretty
incredible stuff that you can do at the
same time
and it's exciting you know I'm a nerd if
that doesn't come true I'm a nerd and so
you get very excited about stuff you can
do at the same time you know it's still
data analysis I started doing data
analysis in 1991 and if you don't know
the problem you're going to solve it
doesn't matter which sort of technique
you pull out of there there's still no
magic you've got to know the problem
you're going to solve and all those sort
of things so it's been it's been
interesting as well I mean I think
people forget
um with the latest focused on these
particular generative AI models the AI
is just embedded already in every part
of every sector around the world we work
for example with a number of large
financial institutions where I was
successfully using AI
to apply for anti-money laundering to
mitigate terrorist financing to mitigate
many other things and it's enabling them
to have massive increases in accuracy
lower false positives and false negative
lives it increases the productivity of
their workflow that's just one we do
other things with pharmaceutical
companies on drug analysis we do things
with every research that's AI today is a
big part of the Machinery of every part
of society and the great thing about it
is that introduction of that has been
done in safe and responsible ways where
we're able to validate models explain in
many cases the results of what's
happening and be able to put them in the
constraints of the appropriate risk
managed structure of those businesses
and doing that going forward to get the
best out of AI in a responsible and safe
way is is the most important thing is
that to Rosie a picture of AI in your
point of view
to be honest it's not really my specific
field
um and uh of course we are
um we are also working with that and of
course AI is uh important for for space
companies but honestly I don't think um
that we are already on that level that
is discussed right here because I'm
really
exciting on what you are talking and
yeah it sounds pretty cool and it's very
much information on very short time
well we have time for a few questions so
who would like to to be first maybe you
can introduce yourself briefly and and
your question was a question mark
ideally
hi my name is Lucha I worked for the
United Nations for several years also in
cyber security so the question is why
was Starling so successful
in Ukraine and was it because it came
from a private partner because official
other methods of communications could
not be deployed and do you think musks
should continue providing it I think
Federal of the minister who bought it
was just all in he's great he's 31 years
old and just very like with him
procurement is fairly easy it's fast
it's like things walk and he just goes
and that sort of mindset to things plus
technology that is obviously good you
know you can imagine in pretty much the
other 199 countries on the planet that
would have taken about five years before
that got deployed so I will give a lot
of credit to the good Federal of vice
prime minister of Ukraine incredible guy
who we're about to respond to yes I
think that um one of the the key factors
were or was that um
it was there
and it was available
um none of the other telecommunication
constellations are um on that level of
of ambition right now
I also think that Elon Musk did a very
good it might be very good marketing but
he he was uh he has sent the terminals
very
uh very fast and very cheap to to the
Ukrainian user and it showed that um at
least it we have to have a resilient way
of communication and
although we have uh the opportunity to
have
um the classical satellite
Communications as we we know it from
military use
[Music]
um
the Starling idea or the idea of having
communication constellations in in the
Leo orbit that also provides broadband
and this is I think also one of the keys
it's no longer only or it's no longer
between Broadband for for broadcast or
do we communicate but it's it's only the
internet and therefore that's I think
also very important why styling uh has
has been such a key factor for how how
the Ukrainian were able to communicate
I don't I'm I don't think that it's it's
me to to say if uh Elon Musk should
um or what or if styling should be
provided to the Ukraine any longer or
not um but I think that um what what
really happened it it showed that
especially Europe has no no own
competence in that and this is why Iris
Square which is now um officially uh
also
um debate has been decided by the
European Parliament so this will be the
European telecommunication constellation
so from the institution and this should
bring the the service that styling now
provides to to Europe and to the world
since it's yeah it's a worldwide
consolation but it's uh it's yeah the
the customer or the service is provided
by the European commissioner and I'll
really emphasize I think it's great you
bring up the musk point to being sort of
the his he's a doer and then you're
Federal on the other end when you sit
down with him and he pulls up his phone
and says do you want to create a company
yeah I'd like to create a company this
is exciting and it hits his phone and
and boom you have a Ukrainian company
you create a Ukrainian company and
bypass you know lawyers and by the way
when we do this we actually remove a lot
of ability to for corruption blah blah
blah so it's like you know and you put
that obviously in the context of War now
they can move fast and and I think
probably for a lot of us in this room
this is a good good lesson
so I want to start a company or crane do
it now
um you're next
the microphone is coming that's maybe
easy
you you've been talking about
communication satellite Elon Musk when
it comes to protecting the communication
on those lines actually uh could you
give me your take on what the quantum
computer challenge or threat would be
and one little bit more specific on that
I would like to understand uh of course
also the U.S take when it comes to
Quantum key distribution against uh post
Quantum encryption if you could be more
specific yeah so just kind of a bit
background the question so you know
clearly you know everybody's watching
the development of of quantum computers
and the uh the real threat on the
horizon is the availability of what we
would describe as a cryptographically
relevant quantum computer that's of
sufficient scale to be able to break
much of the public key cryptography
that's vital for many of the the key
exchanges and other secure
Communications
um you know I I've no kind of crystal
ball as to when such a a computer will
come about but the one thing I would say
is it's moved from the domain of physics
to the domain of engineering and if
there's anything taught us over the past
few decades Engineers can always work
quicker than we ever expect them to do
so I think I would range the
availability of a such a quantum
computer to be in the in the 2035 range
but you know that could be more it could
be longer there's still some fundamental
challenges on Quantum error correction
and other things to be able to kind of
realize the uh such a computer but we
can't wait and so one of the things that
nist particularly in the US have already
announced the uh post post Quantum
cryptographic algorithms uh we're hoping
that the standards of how they'll be
used are released next year and we would
expect that many companies like us are
going to be fast implementers of that to
get ahead of the quantum threat we've
already been trialing quite extensively
these algorithms in our infrastructure I
I don't have I don't have objective data
on this but we think we're one of the
largest implementations if not the
largest of some of the peaky see
algorithms in our infrastructure layered
on top of the existing cryptographic
infrastructure to test performance but
one of the things I would say is we're
encouraging all organizations to start
planning for this transition because
it's going to take a long time and it's
a little bit like a Y2K problem you've
got to go find these things and fix them
and replace them on the quantum key
distribution piece one of the things is
we're not so positive on that I think
the the quantum key distribution itself
is not necessarily a viable replacement
as a tactic for mitigating the risks of
computers just because of deployment
challenges also there's been substantial
security weaknesses in its
implementation so we're all in on post
Quantum cryptography less so on Quantum
key distribution we have exactly one
minute left so one brief question to
each of you uh with the uh
and I'm asking for a brief answer uh
starting with you Phil um what keeps you
up at night now when you think of the
future of cyberspace so so there's
there's one thing and I'm kind of almost
phrasing it as a negative so I I think
the biggest opportunity for us all to
resolve cyber security issues is to
modernize our technology platforms I
think if we can invest as much in
modernizing away from Legacy systems
where the security isn't built in it's
bolted on after the fact if we can get a
modern more defendable architectures
where the security is built in not
bolted on that's our tremendous
opportunity and anything that gets in
the way of that modernization to get to
more defendable architectures is is not
a good thing the faster we can get to
that the better
Sabrina even briefer maybe
so for me I think that cyber security is
uh or it's very close to space and
security from space and Security in
space and therefore I agree with Phil
that we have to really look at our
Technologies we have to develop new
technologies and we have to be brave
enough to LeapFrog wherever it has to be
done and we we have to stop saying it's
all based on our experience
yeah so I made the point that we're sort
of 0.1 percent into connecting the
internet really into our lives and it's
going to get in here another one of your
Elon musk's companies for example is
working on getting a computer into your
brain so I think we have we know a lot
of software vulnerabilities like 300 000
of them let's start enumerating the
human vulnerabilities in the brain and
thinking about what it means to actually
attack those that will be a little bit
of a different challenge that's probably
the topic for next year thanks so much
to the Fantastic panel and thanks to you
for listening
foreign