foreign
[Music]
good morning everybody uh
it's uh not quite as nice of a day today
I didn't believe there was Blue Sky in
Bavaria in February but I saw it
yesterday
um today we're going to talk about cyber
crime lines of action which is but we're
really going to focus on cyber crime
ransomware and we're very fortunate to
have Decades of combined experience here
in the National Security Public Safety
and cyber security realm their bios are
all on the papers that you have so I
won't repeat them and we have short
times so we're going to do Dive Right In
and I'm going to ask the panelists all
to spend about a minute answering the
question of what are the current
shortfalls
in effectively fighting cyber crime
right now and how would you fix them if
you could
now for from where I sit and uh I've
been in the private sector on the vendor
side for over 20 years so spending
um literally decades with both public
and private sector organizations and
companies
really I think from my perspective it
comes down to two things one there's a
massive technology Gap that's uh still
sadly very prevalent in organizations
both from a software as well as Hardware
perspective and some of the biggest and
largest and most critical Enterprises in
the world today still rely on Antiquated
hardware and software and that presents
a you know a major opportunity for cyber
criminals nation state actors to exploit
those vulnerabilities inherent in Legacy
systems and in absence of a massive
forklift of Technology upgrades really
what what we see is a need to fill that
Gap with effective cyber security tools
the other important element is I think
um
certainly in the Western World there is
a real lag in terms of collaboration and
effective cyber security policies and
legislation in place and where we see
the biggest impact around that is um uh
a lack of carrot in the stick in terms
of enforcing proper cyber security
hygiene uh really encouraging
collaboration between
nation state and private Enterprises as
well so those two large elements are are
what I see
thank you Nick nixwood an advisor was
Sentinel one out of Boston Valerie
following up same question to you but
let's um in addition what are the
current shortfalls uh Nick mentioned a
stick why don't you talk a little bit
about what the scissor stick is
um hi good morning so sisa isn't a law
enforcement agency but we're an agency
that focuses in on how do we understand
manage and mitigate risks for the
nation's critical infrastructure and
especially when it comes to cyber
security and as mentioned by Catherine
earlier this morning we have a real
concern about small and medium-sized
businesses as well as state and local
governments that are as our director
likes to say Target rich but resource
poor every week in the US we've seen
ransomware attacks sadly ongoing against
our school systems against hospitals and
really so from our perspective what
we're trying to do is focus in on some
of those sectors that do need help they
don't have a lot of resources and
unfortunately they are targets for cyber
criminals and so we've in at cisa we've
launched an initiative to really focus
in and help on K-12 education as well as
the health sector and and the water
sector and we recently released a K-12
resource guide for educators to help
them to give them a tool kit on things
to look for to help Shore up their cyber
security we also have a grant program
that we were recently given where we're
trying to help our states better protect
themselves by having cyber security
plans for their states in order to raise
the bar really I think we've we've
talked about earlier today there's
probably no way to totally eliminate
cyber crime but it's really our
responsibility to make it harder to make
it more expensive for criminals to be
able to act
thank you and um Valerie spent years at
the FBI before she went to cisa as one
of their senior Executives the next
panelist John Carlin also was at FBI as
the chief of staff before moving back to
doj where a couple times so John why
don't you follow up on that
sure I I recently was at the Department
of Justice as we did the switch of
administration to the Biden
Administration and one of the first
things I started at the justice
department was a task force focused on
ransomware as many of you know I think
our statistics will show that 2021 was
the worst year in history in terms of
the damages caused by ransomware actors
criminal and nation state
I think we'll see a decrease in
ransomware this year partly because of
the distraction of the criminal groups
by the Russian aggression in Ukraine but
we'll see an increase of other types of
cyber-enabled fraud business email
compromise schemes in particular so
bottom line I think the threat picture
from Bad actors criminal groups and
nation states is bad and getting worse
0.2 would be on the back end as that
problem is getting worse we continue to
see the acceleration of a move now where
we've taken everything we value from
books and papers from analog moved it to
digital space to bits and bytes
connected it through a protocol the
Internet Protocol the tcpip protocol
that was fundamentally designed not to
be secure and interviewed the the those
who designed it uh book I wrote on this
and they said explicitly they thought
about designing it for security and
since that wasn't the purpose they
designed it so that it would be insecure
which will be a permanent jobs program
from my friend from uh from Sentinel
when I'm back in private practice now to
to Mark's Pro question and helping
private sector companies then where are
the gaps and what can we do to impact
them one I know we'll hear more about
this here is we need to be on offense
and make it for the criminal groups as
painful as possible for them to
effectuate their trade that means doing
things like the the justice department
just did in cooperation with many
countries throughout Europe and private
sector companies throughout the world
which is hack the hacker do things like
if they steal the
um uh if they steal data disable the
data so they can't use it and post it
for profit if they encrypt your systems
do cyber-enabled operations so that you
steal the keys back from the hacker when
they try to demand Ransom the uh they
don't understand why victims aren't
paying this is the hive case that Brian
will talk about more but secretly that's
because the government is providing all
the victims the keys and so the hacker
is out using a tool that doesn't work
and doesn't realize it if they steal if
they get a payment or extortion payment
steal it back like in colonial pipeline
where they're able to recover the
digital currency that was taken through
wallets the great thing about blockchain
for bad guys is you can uh anonymously
get the initial receipt the bad thing
for bad guys is that blockchain you can
follow the chain and see where the money
went and it is very hard to get it from
digital currency into fiat currency and
into the pocket of the bad guy so that
creates vulnerabilities for them if you
can't get the money back disable the
wallet so they can't uh enjoy the
proceeds of their theft if you see where
the servers are launching the attacks
seize and disable the servers this
cannot be a unilateral approach no
country can do this it raises important
questions of sovereignty for it to be
effective at the speed and scale of
cyber it's going to take groups like
this and the people who are here today
working across borders to effectuate
these tools at speed so that's one go
after the bad guy increase the cost and
the second really is on the victim side
of the house of both have addressed
which is when I work now uh even with
the largest companies in the world
because this technology is fundamentally
insecure it means not just focusing on
trying to prevent the attack from
occurring but this shift of mindset that
we're slowly seeing uh develop towards
resilience and resilience sometimes
means being able to use systems
particularly with critical
infrastructure in a way that is not
digitally enabled I think we've seen
actually some success in Ukraine and the
resilience of Ukraine against Russian
cyber attacks because they are able to
operate plants and others facilities
manually in the US that's an important
lesson I think in Germany as well and
across the country that you sometimes
the old-fashioned way works best this
was true with our election and to have
things like in the election context
paper ballots with physical Machinery to
maintain the skills and capabilities of
operating a plant manually are going to
be important to be secure at least over
the next five to ten years until we
innovate our ways out of this
thank you John that is a lot of good
info there the next person keeping in
the FBI theme was sent over specifically
to speak to this group because of his
recent leadership on the hive
investigation and takedown he's the uh
the FBI cyber criminal operations lead
I thank you very much Mark um and
pleasure to be here I always uh I'm
curious you know when people get out of
the government and they're more free to
talk about some of these things is how
they happen I just want to make it clear
that everything that we John said we did
is all with lawful authorities
um when we hacked the hacker and we
steal credentials and things like that
that's based off court orders and the
jurisdictions that supervise them so I
just want to make it clear that we're
not going rogue on any of you
um but if you need a lawyer I'm here for
you
the uh um as far as you know what do I
see out there and I was trying to keep
because I used to do Consulting so I was
trying to keep with the rule of three
and I just can't get there so I'm gonna
go with the rule of four so um if that
sticks then I'm going to trademark that
thing so the areas where I think we
really need help is on the victim's side
so John talked about that
um we are only getting about 20
reporting on victims and we can't do our
job and our partners law enforcement
can't do our job if we don't have all
the information coming into us they are
just like us they make mistakes the more
they do things they leave breadcrumbs
their VPN drops on things that provides
us opportunities to take advantage of so
the more reporting that we get the
better that we are
the second is the private sector we
can't do this we have great coalitions
and great Partnerships across the globe
that are working these problems but most
of the data most of the information and
a lot of the capabilities actually
resides in the private sector and so
we're having to partner more and more
with the private sector it's not an easy
thing and it's been alluded to up here
of based off privacy rules and things
that we have in the United States and I
know other places we have got to get
beyond that if we want to make a real
impact on this environment and see a day
where we see private sector and law
enforcement working hand in hand in the
midst of the trenches of these types of
things
um the uh the other part is that from a
victim side is looking at this it's not
a technical problem
um I was so encouraged earlier when we
heard about the thing about you know you
need process and people and technology
and I think that is so true these are
business systems and we need to start
thinking of this as a business problem
it's not an I.T problem that you
squirrel away to the guys down in the
basement who manage your servers
these systems are there to support our
business needs and so we need to get the
business Community to get more engaged
that this is their problem to help solve
and it's not something that they can
just uh push off to other people and I'm
going to save the fourth one for another
part of my conversation thanks actually
uh I'm going to go right back to you
with this next one about if you could
just tease out a little bit the
importance of international alliances in
the cyber crime ransomware fight I'm
going to go to you but then I'm going to
ask Sissa to follow up and then if our
other uh panelists want to jump into and
before we go to the next question so
maybe use some examples of your most
recent if that's uh appropriate yeah
happy too
um so certainly within the hive
investigation that we just had uh the
first announcement on um so I want to
make it clear that that investigation is
not over
um but that if you look at the uh press
release that we put out there I think
there's 11 different countries that were
involved in it as well as europol as an
entity
and that is pretty common that is almost
every single one I can't think actually
I cannot think of one of our major cases
that we have at the FBI that we do not
have international partners with and
particularly European Partners we were
talking last night about those are
really some of our closest relationships
and that comes from
uh you know where the servers are
located but it also comes from the
capability and so we have to make sure
that we're partnered up with entities
who have the requisite skill sets to
address this and I'm pleased to report
to people in this room that in Europe
you have very capable law enforcement
um things where as we talk about you
know when we talk about the hive uh
investigation
it's an example of what we call joint
and sequenced operations and that means
that if you look historically at how we
did things it would be you big a big big
take down at the end and you try and get
as much as you can within it and we're
recognizing that that model doesn't work
anymore we need to put pressure on the
adversary which means that we need to be
doing this an ongoing basis over a
length of time and put pressure on them
every day of the week because that's
what they're doing to us and so high was
an example of us and our partners taking
those sequenced operations and you will
see
things like
one country making an announcement on
something and there may not be other
countries on there but that actually may
be part of a joint and sequenced
operation because we are going to be
timing this over time and let the right
place at the right time with the right
capabilities address what those issues
are thanks and um so FBI has had
attaches around the world for decades
sisa is a relatively new agency in that
context so can you speak a little bit
about what you're doing to plus up the
international coordination for ciso yeah
no for sure so one thing that said if
you you are all aware of or not is that
sis a host U.S cert team so the computer
emergency Readiness teams and we
interface with over 150 different sir
teams around the country I mean sorry
around the world and that's really the
way that we engage internationally we
share information regularly on threats
you know with each other so that we can
see if there's a trend going on
somewhere else in the world that can be
shared back and we can share it through
that that certain Network I want to say
too that we team up a lot with the FBI
since they have a physical presence the
last time I was at the FBI I think in
over 76 locations around the world and
so even recently in the case where the
government of Costa Rica and the
governments of Montenegro experience
ransomware attacks
FBI was able to have people boots on the
ground to help those those countries but
we were able to remotely provide
assistance in cases like that
and if I could jump in Mark I think
that's a great example because we had
other instances like Montenegro and then
we're partnering with the Germans and
the Dutch and bringing their expertise
in where we may have one person on the
ground but we've got a whole Coalition
of international Partners who are
helping out
all right thanks next time John I I want
to go to you and then I want to go back
to Nick on this next one about hacking
back since you brought it up
um I know Brian clarified it but what
are you saying Wild West just you know
if you see something do it
yeah no it's I get this question a lot
and understandably because if you're in
a circumstance using the wild west
analogy where you don't feel like the
government is helping you and that
criminal groups where you know the name
of the criminal group you know the
location from the IP address of where
the attack is coming from you think you
do you think you do is attacking your
company can I go hack them back myself
and do can I go get my data back can I
go disable the data that they have taken
I think for the private sector uh as
you're outside uh Council or general
counsel will advise the answer is going
to be no that's not probably a good idea
and I know uh publicly traded company
should be doing that because of the risk
under U.S law uh there's the Computer
Fraud and Abuse Abuse Act and it could
be a criminal act that you are
undertaking when you go to do the attack
back I think there's two reasons why
that's probably sound policy as well one
that Mark was alluding to is it sure is
hard to get all the attribution right
and the way the criminal groups work is
they're often hacking someone to get to
you which means you may be going back
against a Vic another victim and
intruding upon their system and the
secondly as this group knows and we've
been discussing are the sovereignty
issues where that can cause escalation
between nation states and that
determination as to when the tools of
the state should be used in a situation
that can cause conflict to use one
example of colonial pipeline you had a
criminal group attack a private company
in the U.S for-profit and for criminal
gain and that caused a oil lines to back
up and essentially a national security
crisis
that group was located in Russia and the
solution of of the state involved
statecraft where the president of the
United States raised the issue with his
uh publicly raised the issue with his
his counterpart that said
you can do what's called active defense
it doesn't mean there's nothing that you
can do on your system and so the line I
would think about is the perimeter of
the your system or Network
you can do creative things like if you
know that there's no system that's
secure as we've discussed and that a bad
guy can enter the system maybe it's a
bad idea to put your crown jewels in a
folder called crown jewels don't advise
that but keep a keep a folder that says
essentially crown jewels and put
information in there that is fake use a
virtual uh environment so you can
monitor the activity of the bad guy on
your system you can also put information
in there that they can steal or
exfiltrate that will not work when they
try to try to develop it they'll waste
time and resources and you can study
them and gives your Defenders time to
response and I'm sure uh Chris could
follow up on some some of these ideas
finally and this is in I think a gray
space and one that warrants further
exploration or things like beaconing
back so if you apply that same principle
bad guy goes into the system takes
something from your system that they
believe to be yours and it happens to
Beacon back so that you can find uh the
location I think that's a gray area and
if that doesn't cause damage maybe
lawful don't recommend you rush it out
and do that but that's one to further
explore and then finally just to pause
what does that mean though going back to
to earlier comments if if companies
can't go and defend themselves by doing
the attack it puts even more pressure I
think on governments and policy regimes
to allow effective response by
government because what can't be
sustainable is that you know there's
this criminal group attacking you
constantly sometimes with the resource
of a nation-state and you on your own as
a company are left with nothing to do
about it it means you need to have those
Partnerships with FBI you're a pole
Interpol others to take action thanks
Sean now can you follow up on the
industry standpoint on that you know
echoing a few things that that uh Johnny
mentioned
the vast majority of of customers in the
private sector
um as well as the public sector
emotionally they would love to be able
to hack back
um that's not practical it's not
feasible in most cases it's not
technologically possible you're either
gonna end up attacking an uh a service
provider an intermediary
and I think what it really underscores
is Need for collaboration between
government law enforcement and the
private sector
um and to leave that element of uh
responding to the experts but you know I
think it's best summed up from some of
the things I heard yesterday which for
the vast vast majority of organizations
defense is the best form of offense so
building a resiliency as John had
mentioned building in even deception
Technologies within uh your own uh
corporate Network cloaking critical uh
data and building in a modern defense
against attacks because attacks are
going to happen as Valerie had mentioned
we're seeing it across I think a common
misperception from folks outside the
industry is that only the most critical
and largest companies are hacked and
what we've seen is in a just an
incredible Rise of opportunistic
ransomware and other types of hacking
attacks against libraries Community
Hospitals small organizations tax
offices with 30 40 50 people because
sadly they they're going for the week of
the herd and so uh you know I think it's
just incredibly important for these
organizations to drive best practice in
terms of having a really robust defense
but then also really um game play this
out understand how to respond to attacks
how to collaborate both within their
industry and partners and I think some
of the some of the encouraging things
I've heard uh both today and yesterday
is really and there is very much a need
for increased collaboration and
legislation around this because I think
a couple Folks up here have mentioned to
date there's a lot of like legislation
that actually discourages information
sharing in the name of privacy
protection Etc and that really
hamstrings responding in the proper way
to these type of attacks
thank you thank you Nick let's um let's
move more into the geopolitical realm
um the the founder of the Silverado
policy accelerator of which I'm a part
of has coined the phrase that we don't
have a cyber problem we have a Russia
China Iran and North Korea problem so
John I want you to put your hat on from
your second to last government
assignment when you're an assistant
attorney general for National Security
Prosecuting State
Affiliated hackers
what do we do with criminals supported
or tolerated by state actors
look and I I agree but fundamentally
with uh with his assessment these are
for a long time I think we thought of uh
hackers and if you ever look at news
reports about hacking it's often the
same uh old b-clip old video clip of a
pair of fingers typing on a keyboard
masked in Shadow but the fact is you can
put uh thanks to incredible work by FBI
Homeland Security by private sectors you
can put faces and names behind those
keyboards and so in that sense I think
the ransomware criminal problem is is
part of the broader problem of how do we
sustain a rules-based order that's under
threat as it never has been before in
the post-world War II uh or uh regime
and in cyber as in other areas actions
speak louder than words I think we've
tried for uh for years to do this
through policy negotiations but the
quest question I think is can we work
multilaterally in order to impose pain
impose consequences that can be through
the form just because it's a cyber
enabled attack doesn't mean the response
is through cyber uh I'll give you an
example a member responding to something
we wargamed out for a year what would it
look like if a rogue nuclear armed
Nation attacked the United States
through cyber-enabled means we always
thought it would be on the energy sector
or some critical structure we were
surprised when it was about a movie
about a bunch of pot smoking journalists
this is the North Korean attack on Sony
Motion Pictures so that was not the
scenario that we had War Games war games
for but if we had tried to respond by
disabling North Korea's access to the
internet I think they're probably the
combined IP addresses and connectivity
of the people in this room is greater
than the nation state of North Korea it
would not be an effective deterrent
that's why I think you're seeing the use
of of other tools lawful tools that
could be used multilaterally the use of
sanctions both against the criminal
groups involved but also the
nation-states that Harbor them to try to
deny them the access to the next Cutting
Edge phase of Technology through export
controls I'm going to interview her
later at this conference but the deputy
Attorney General of the United States
announced yesterday a new task force
with the Commerce Department in the U.S
working with Partners across the streets
going after those critical Technologies
you heard earlier today from Paul Rosen
overseeing the foreign investment inside
the United States denying the
opportunity through foreign investment
from those Rogue from countries that are
harboring Road Rogue actors to next
phase technology a discussion that's
quite live today is outbound
investment should there be rules that
limit outbound investment from
rules-based country trees two countries
that are not following the rules to
prevent them from developing
technologies that can be used for
offensive cyber attacks that approach is
sometimes called the all tools approach
meaning all tools all legally available
tools as Brian uh pointed out working
multilaterally and just before I ask
another panelists just follow up on that
one of the things about the outbound
investment is it's not just dollars
going to an entity it can be expertise
that goes with that from the Venture
Capital on how to make your business
better and I think the point is we don't
want to
create any more benefits for adversarial
or challenging Nations than are already
there yeah it's and I think it's these
are important and difficult issues that
we need to work through to give because
there's a flip side right you you want
to enable those who want to protect
themselves from autocratic regimes from
getting technology that for instance can
protect
Communications so it's going to take
conversations I think with particularly
transatlantic Partners but really
countries throughout the world and share
the the rules based order on what are
the most effective series of sticks that
we can use that will ultimately change
the behavior of states that are
harboring the these criminal ordination
states that are themselves attacking
private companies for the benefit of
their competitors overseas
okay anybody else want to speak on the
uh how to deal with the tolerated State
actors are we ready to go on
so that was the fourth prong um that I
was had mentioned earlier and it's a
real difficulty for us um when you have
people in countries that we can't get
access to uh you know we're all getting
attacked every day and there's certain
places where this is emanating from and
you know that's not law enforcement
problem but that is how do we put
pressure on those entities to make it
harder for them to do that and that's an
ongoing issue that we need to be
addressing okay so
um I'd like to go to you with reporting
victim reporting
um do we have any good estimates on
victim reporting whether Trends why
don't people report and what are we
doing what can we do to facilitate more
reporting I know there's the regulatory
side for certain critical infrastructure
that's going to kick in over a number of
years but can you just kind of run us
through where we are with that and then
I'd ask Nick to jump in on what he's
seeing and then if the other panelists
have anything they can add
well I think Brian mentioned earlier
we have a real dearth right in reporting
because it's all voluntary right now we
we were fortunate that in March of 2022
we were able to pass the cersea law so
the Cyber incident reporting for
critical infrastructure and we are going
through the rulemaking process as Mark
mentioned so it'll take a few years
before we see the fruits of that but we
are really excited to be able to when
that law does get enacted to be able to
better understand sort of the trends
that are going on when we think even
about the ransomware issue that we've
been discussing here it's hard for us to
all we know is that the reporting that
we have is underreported so what's going
on is probably just scratching the
surface of the about volume and amount
of activity there that's going on the
losses even that have been mentioned in
earlier panels are probably even sadly
more than than have been reported and so
we're we're really excited about being
able to have this data when it comes
online and being able to rapidly share
it with our
interagency partners to make sure sure
that we can get the intelligence that we
glean from the data out and be able to
really help protect us as we've talked
about already that really hardening our
defenses is really an important part of
being able to decide to fight cyber
crime Nick can you follow up
yeah I mean I think from my perspective
it is massively underreported one in 20
one in 30 or or greater and there's
several good reasons for that these are
solvable problems and they need to be
solved the first is
most organizations don't know how to go
about reporting they literally don't
know what to do next and what a lot of
them are doing is relying on their cyber
insurer which then brings in a breach
coach who by the way usually are
attorneys and attorneys are like don't
talk to anyone you know the typical
legalese
and related to that I think companies
are really concerned about reputational
damage business damage customer damage
and I think that these things need to be
addressed and mitigated with legislation
and processes where folks and companies
can confidentially and easily report
because I think as Valerie had mentioned
there's really good reasons for having
that data just to understand the scope
size and nature of the problem problem
but to date it's it's really a
combination of not understanding how to
do it getting advice from folks who are
you only report if you have to and
um I think that's all against the
backdrop of the chaos that's usually
unfolding during a breach situation a
company is just trying to get back in
their feet and go through business
resiliency and so that ends up taking a
back seat
um you know the reporting and
information sharing aspect so these are
these are things I think we're chipping
away at it's encouraging that we're
addressing it finally for critical
infrastructure but there's a real need
for that to be applied broadly across
all Industries I just want to Echo what
Chris said in terms of of the challenges
that private sector companies face and
that some of those challenges are placed
there by law and Regulation and
highlight a couple parts of that because
I think they're very relevant for policy
in the EU as they are in in the U.S so
one is right now our our laws are skew
around privacy how many of you uh by
show of hands have received a notice at
some time that your data was compromised
in an incident
so it's pretty much the entire room I'll
tell you my daughter was a first piece
of mail and she was very excited to see
her uh name was a notice that her
identity had been stolen in the in a
well-known breach of the U.S
government's Federal data databases so
look I don't think that's a very
effective approach we're all being told
I've got you get multiple notices what
are you supposed to do with the notice
uh at this point you just you know that
you're
information has been stolen multiple
times what's more important in a lot of
these incidents is that there's a
mechanism to get it to the right
government officials to act on it and go
after the bad guys who took the
information but quite to the contrary
because we have this
schizophrenic two-sided approach where
the FBI and some of the other agencies
saying and sister saying come in as
victims we're here to help you have
other agencies who are set up to punish
the company who is the victim of the
attack if we don't get that carrots and
sticks right when we have the internal
counsel they're making rational
decisions as private companies why they
don't want to go forward we have to
change that second and uh I'll say this
uh bluntly in this credit it is
Kafkaesque and absurd that for a period
of time there were harsher restrictions
on sharing data from Europe to the
United States than there were from
Europe to for instance Russia
how can that be the case but that is the
Privacy regime that has been set up on
data transfer
on data transfer between countries so
that means it's quite complicated if
you're bringing Chris or other or trying
to work with FBI and you're looking at a
breach that is a multinational breach to
get the information you need to
effectively respond to the attack so we
need to change that incentive as well
and third you're seeing the move and
just to lift up what value describing in
the U.S for the first time to have
mandatory confidential reporting to to
the government I know private sector is
quite worried about that that is going
to end up being used against them
instead of against the bad guy there's a
similar move happening in the EU and as
you uh you know leave and work on the
policy on this I think we all need to
work together to try to incentivize that
that information is shared for use
against the criminals and the bad
nation-states and not against the
victims who are trying to protect the
information in the first place thank you
John we have five minutes left
um and I do want to get the audience
questions because I do not want to get a
yellow or red card in our football that
means we have to go back five or ten
yards and that wouldn't end well so why
don't we go to some audience questions
and then we'll if we have time we'll go
to our last question here
um I if you get a microphone over to one
of those Gentlemen please
and a question please not a uh a speech
thank you very much do we have any
expectations from the cyber crime
convention which is negotiated in the
United Nations under the top committee
thank you
uh any particular anyone in particular
one
no not our stuff you know I mean I that
would be more of a question for State
um so I'm not sure we have a former
State Department cyber person in this
room that will hook you up with um right
after Harry's third row on this side I
don't want to put him on the spot though
I'll do it a two-second one which is
um it will have uh respond later it's
been as you know under development for a
long period of time and the interim I
think we need to continue to take action
and some of that action maybe through
bilateral Partnerships through law
enforcement to law enforcement or cert
assert Partnerships because it this is a
law of customary uh law and so you if we
don't take action to show that we find
unacceptable some of these incursions by
nation states through cyber enabled
space we're creating the norm in an
international law that says that that's
an okay use of your intelligence
apparatus that's why what the uh f FBI
worked with europol and others do is so
important to show even when you can't
arrest the individual because it's in a
state that will not uh extradite that by
publicly naming and laying out the facts
taking it out of the shadows in the
intelligence world and saying No this is
unacceptable just like also customary
law and easement if you let someone walk
across your lawn long enough they earn
the legal right to walk across your lawn
it's important collectively that we put
up a giant no trespass sign and say
that's not acceptable that's not a norm
that we want to live under thanks John
do you want you have anything to add or
should we go to the next audience
question all right we had another
audience question over here
gentleman with the blue name tag
thank you I'm uh customer from NTT so
you talked about the um
um this incentive or almost companies
not wanting to report issues right and I
think one problem is that law
enforcement is interested in collecting
evidence and the company is interested
in getting the systems back up so law
enforcement will probably keep the
systems for a while would it be an idea
to just as a as a government for example
offer an infrastructure to affected
companies trucks with satellite
connection whatever where you say you
can use that infrastructure immediately
to be back up and running within base
right and then we have time to do law
enforcement rather than kind of
collecting searching and holding up
getting back into operation so I'm sorry
what was the question who is it to did
you get that right yeah I can jump into
this um so as far as with the government
I'll actually defer on that one but what
I will tell you is that as far as a
company reporting and I can only speak
for how we respond in at the FBI is and
we've had a significant change over this
last year is we need to provide value
back to the so I came to the FBI because
I wanted to do good
um and I think you should do the right
thing for the right reasons and but I
also recognize there's also other
competing interests in this and there's
risk for the entities with regulators
and things like that so how do we
incentivize people so we've shifted so
that we're going to have value in that
first interaction when you call us what
I will tell you is that we're not taking
your servers we're not taking your your
information we don't want your data what
we want is we want the indicators to
compromise we want to know the we want
to get the logs we want to understand
the nature of the data because then that
helps us understand well what are they
going to do with it we don't actually
need the data so we shouldn't be
shutting you down in any capacity
the other thing is that we know because
how how we're structured is that when
you tell us hey it's it's Hive or it's
lockbit we've got information on those
groups and that agent who shows up on
the door either you call on the phone
they can give you right there to teach
the most latest ttps the iocs whether or
not the FBI has the capability of
decryption on it any intel products that
we've produced that is immediately
available to you so that should help you
get back up and running so that then we
will get the evidence later on on that
but that's the interaction so we need to
speed that up and Hive taught us that 20
and some people and I agree that may be
high is what reported to the FBI Ryan
thank you so much for that answer we
have we have no more time left so I am
going to ask and then answer the final
question what preventative measures are
needed to stop cyber crime happening in
the first place and the answer is none
you can't stop it so focus on resiliency
all right thank you thank you
[Applause]