work now but jokes aside we got a
prepackaged schedule and we decided to
experiment so we decided to start the
day - with what we call an anti plenary
session that's effectively a stand-up
comedy or a sit-down
tragedy format and you will see mostly
the people that presented yesterday in
them
someone actually presented so many other
events and we're asking them to actually
share with us some of their best B's you
know things that matter to them things
they care about and we hope that that
will pretty much guide you next year you
know they may set your sights and
something is really important
well as a person we actually proposed
the whole idea I think I should be the
one for talking it so naturally I am
personally thinking about these days all
the time I'll take this one for example
we started preparing it in June last
year premature right up to the end of
the phrase installation and we start
preparing it well actually still
preparing can you imagine that you know
we're still perfecting minor elements
the two nights session and there will
also be both paged even visible for the
whole year Lewis you know blue sky
castamere there is a more important
thing I wanted to share with you know
now that we are sort of monitoring those
heckard ins we can help wondering what
will be the evolution of this industry
so the first idea I have is at pH dice
is actually a strong community well you
can argue that you know lots of people
want to sell their services or products
here or you can argue with that point
this is the number and it's actually a
pretty convincing number right now these
are the people who decided to sense the
species take part of the contest
actually a big crowd we should just talk
on point eleven hundred companies have
sent in to their representatives and
only 250 out of 1,100 companies are
information security professionals are
you with me which means that everybody
else are effectively customers which is
good manager must be sad partner oh we
are safety partners ready
these are corporations that have
supported this forum with a hardware
their PR by buying tickets for their
employees
money-wise as well so these are all the
people or the companies the belief the
wording is good and they can send Alex
hey looky here the other the positive
country know what the oldest a is
positive had guys getting a good story
kid okay you know I've been following
hacker conferences since 2004 minutes
times great first of all I attended was
in 2009 so thinking back over all this
time you - I believe God you stupid
machine
you know we hackers believer there is a
kind of a system on there that rules a
set of constraints it could be the
hacker community or the researcher
community systems in a way right say a
researchers have a certain routine to
how they break things apart and how they
disclose stuff same applies to say
information security professionals is
also a system onto their own you may
remove the Hector manifests of 1986
so back down we saw the rules were sort
of unruly
rules were
Bard's we can escape the box outside the
box so quite often you will fear hackers
including hackers today here is saying
let's get outside the box let's think
racially smooth so every time we try to
transgress the existing boundaries you
know to check our assumptions to say if
there is a better approach and I think
that this kind of out-of-the-box
thinking is driving the quality the
content of this event is also assumed
number of other events as well so this
is how we are making our system a better
system it's a huge room I believe we
have about 100 people here it seems like
underpopulated because of the size of
the room and you know what last year
when we had a lot of well-known hackers
at 9 o'clock in the morning we have
pretty much the same number of people
which I think shows that so well this is
the kind of turnout we have in the
morning of day 2 I think it's funny
the super content itself is know the
person of your daily schedules are so in
conclusion of this Tokyo Tech speech I
like to say the folly we are a big
crowds lots of people lots of
corporations lots of ideas lots of ideas
in spacious lots of ideas in the
standoff these are the things that
nourishes that keep us going
actually we are going to see the
threshold of 5,000 people today I think
also we are in the process of creating a
very strong and healthy community which
is great so don't get attached to March
to your favorite holidays because this
is how we can actually make our current
system data what's the word of wording
there quite often we blame our existing
systems of arrogance and
narrow-mindedness
well this can happen to any system you
know quite often people do research to
show off or the you know hack systems
simply to prove their worth to show the
early worth your salt and this is a risk
and this is a risk we would certainly
want to avoid what you vegan German art
videos these videos so we believe that
development is great
to mislead you you community on a budget
bigger and please help us control for
that and make sure you know we don't get
arrogant you don't get arrogant cool we
can now give a round of applause to
Alexei