good morning and welcome to backslash
powered scanning automating human
intuition
imagine if you could conduct a pen test
and skip out all of the boring bits skip
over there hours of repetitive fuzzing
and trolling through meaningless results
and jump straight to that one input the
reacts in a mysterious way to your every
payload the one that turns out to be
vulnerable to code injection in a
language you've never heard of or sequel
injection behind the heavyweight filter
that almost stops you from cracking open
the database the kind of page the no
blackbox vulnerability scanner could
ever detect in this session I will share
with you the conception and development
of a new type of scanner that can find
research-grade fallibility this all got
started around three years ago I just
began a pen test and I had a problem
that's probably familiar to many of you
although I had started the test the
clients hadn't gotten around to given me
any login credentials so I was just
staring at the login page and this time
this was particularly upsetting because
from the 90s visual design of the login
page I could hear the vulnerability
screaming out at me but I couldn't log
in to get access to any of that attack
surface eventually when I did get some
credentials I logged in found some
sequel injection dumped out the database
including the all the user passwords
which were naturally stored in plain
text and found that the password of the
director of this company was market
either one so his password was actually
less hard to guess that his username but
I nearly missed this critical
vulnerability I so I thought next time
I'm not going to let this happen
and I wrote a tool called Let Me In
which will try a large number of
usernames and it will do statistical
analysis on the timing of the responses
and on the content of the responses to
try and see if there are any clues
that show which usernames of valid and
sometimes this tool works really well
but most of the time it fails hold me
and one day while trying to fix this
tool I realize that I could actually use
this technique to something far cooler
and that's what I'm here to share with
you today so first I'm going to talk
about the three failures of scanners
three huge blind spots
so all vulnerability scanners have when
it comes to finding server-side
injection issues and I'll show how
combines these form the million payload
problem and then I'll describe a new
approach to scanning which handles all
of these issues and can find research
played vulnerabilities and I'll look at
what happens when I run that scanner on
a bunch of real websites
after that I'll talk about ideas for
further research where else we could
apply these ideas and are finally I'll
take five minutes of questions so by the
end of this presentation you'll know why
scanner stopped how to build a better
scanner and how to use that scanner for
maximum effectiveness so I stopped a
little bit about me I work at a company
called port Swigert where we make a tool
you may have heard of called burp suite
and my role here is to design scanner
checks so now I'm going to spend the
next few slides sliding off
vulnerability scanners it's coming from
a position of respect I think
vulnerability scanners are great I
didn't know that they are and their full
potential at the moment something else I
do from time to time is research new
types of vulnerability so for example I
spoke a while ago at blackhat USA on
server-side template injection and one
of the personal objectives of this
scanner was to help find unknown types
of vulnerability for me just to make my
life easier so the first flying spot is
the scanners are really bad a dealing
with obscure technology security through
obscurity works against scanners for
example
how many types of service I attend play
injection is your scanner support
probably not all of those and that's
just a list of the most popular template
engines out there for example were arts
quite recently got code executions on
paypal using dos jeaious which is a
template engine not popular enough to be
in that elect list and in 2014
well your scanner didn't detect any kind
of server-side templating section
because nobody knew that it existed but
I know for a fact they're vulnerable
servers were being scanned so how many
other unknown vulnerabilities are out
there present in servers that are being
scanned regularly that the scanners has
failed to fight also using obscure
technology can lead to scan as missing
vulnerabilities in quite unexpected ways
for example scanners typically detect
local file include vulnerabilities by
reading in the contents of the et Cie
password file and if you happen to be
using selinux
on your server the web server may well
not have permission to read the contents
of the ATC password file and so scanners
will fail to find any local file
includes vulnerabilities on your system
basically as soon as you use anything
slightly non-standard scanners just
start to miss issues all over the place
so we're limited to languages that our
scanner explicitly supports so let's
take a really easy one let's take PHP
how well can a scandal scanner handle
that well it can handle the basic case
quite well so the payloads you see here
will fly and blind PHP injection by
making the server sleep for 10 seconds
if it's vulnerable but what if the
application is filtering out for
instance the scanners get a false
negative it won't find the issue the
issue is still exploitable but the
payload the scanner sends won't work and
if there's a web application file
looking for the sleep keyword it's
probably still exploitable somehow but
the scanner won't realize it and even if
the application is just filtered out
quotes it's still exploitable
but the scanner is not going to find it
and of those three examples to us um pen
test that I've done personally so
they're not uncommon things things as
basic as putting sequel statements
inside double quotes for Strings instead
of single quotes two-liter scanners
missing vulnerabilities just because
that behavior is a little bit
non-standard it's just not what stan is
expect okay so now we're going to assume
the vulnerability is in a known language
it's in PHP and there in those filters
so here all the scanner has to do is
figure out where to put the payload this
is an endpoint on the eBay that used to
be vulnerable to remote code execution
via PHP and the obvious place to put the
payload is in the Q parameter but that
doesn't work
and neither does putting it in the
cookie or the referrer or the user
agents or the past or even various
additional headers that you might think
of try in order to successfully exploit
the server he has to specify a second Q
parameter and put the payload there what
chances the scanner got of finding that
issue this issue was found by a manual
tester and he said he found it because
he noticed that the first Q parameter
was being spell checked and in his
experience he'd seen a lot of spellcheck
as being implemented in securely using
eval
so that's why he tried specifying a
second Q parameter just to see what
happened so the million payload problem
is simply put a scanner could
technically send every payload that I've
showed you and find all of those issues
but in order to find every possible
issue it would have to send a payload
for every request every input
vulnerability class technology variant
assaulter and that would mean sending
over a million payloads for a base
request these scanners simply don't have
time to do that so they're reduced to
sending best-effort payloads that work
reasonably well most of the time and
that's what leads to people saying
scanners are good for finding
low-hanging fruit which is a statement
that breaks my heart what we deserve is
the scanner that finds high hanging
fruit so if we want to find a make a
scanner that doesn't have these blind
spots we need to harness the intuition
that human testers have rather than
sending a highly specific payload that
says finally injection into a double
quoted string being evaluated in PHP
with no filters when you descend a
generic payload it says finally
something suspicious and then if we do
find something suspicious just like a
skilled Emanuel gesture we need to
investigate and try and figure out
exactly what's going on by gathering
further information so we're going to
dig begin with the payload that's about
as simple as possible we're going to
take the input and we're going to put a
single quote on it and as we can see
here this is called the server error so
the server might be vulnerable but we
can't be sure it might be saying you've
got an error in your sequel syntax or
might just be saying invalid input
please try again now as a human we can
read the response and decide whether the
behavior is suspicious but scanners
can't do that and what normal standards
do is they grep the response for certain
error messages like that one there but
that has two massive flaws if the server
is using some kind of unknown technology
the scanner won't recognize the error
message and also if application is
handling errors properly it won't work
so we need something better
well we're going to do what our scanner
is going to do is send a second payload
that is syntactically almost identical
to the first payload but it uses an
escape sequence to stop to avoid causing
an error on the server and if the
response from the application revert to
the original response that tells us
there's something interesting happening
here so just to give you a visual
overview of that last slide we're going
to start out by appending a single quote
to the input and if that response
matches the original untampered response
we're just going to give up there's
nothing interesting there but if it
doesn't match the original response
we're going to follow up with an escaped
quote and depending on whether that
match of the original response or not we
can tell what's happening and this
simple decision tree here is at the
heart of the strategy that I'll be using
for the rest of this presentation it's
really simple just bear in mind so using
this concept of probe pairs we can ask
questions of the application as you've
seen we can easily ask am i in a single
quoted string and you can do the same
with a double quoted string obviously
you can also ask am I in a numeric
context by taking the input divided by
one and doing the input divided by zero
if the input is really in a numeric
context there divided by zero will cause
some kind of error and cause a different
closed path which will be visible in the
response from the application we can
also ask if we're in a file path by
seeing if the influent normalizes by
supplying two inputs one that normalizes
to the original value and one that
doesn't and we can find some more
esoteric stuff to that manual test this
might even miss out on just because it's
quite rare for example maybe our input
is specifying the name of a function
that gets called on the server so by
trying a valid function name and an
invalid function name we could maybe
find out if our if this is happening and
if our works well we probably got remote
code execution and we can also ask maybe
I'm in a JSON value and supplies some
value that breaks to date on JSON data
structure
and something doesn't and just see what
happens so what we've got here is just a
tiny sample of the number of questions
that you can ask if you can think of any
vulnerability that you can express using
a probe pair like this because the
scanners open source you can add this to
the scanner yourself in about five lines
of code it's really easy and I recommend
giving it a go so that's cool but the
true power of the scanner is that we can
use the answer from these questions to
decide what to do next so while asking
those questions we can see what kind of
quotes women and now we know we're in a
double-quoted string so we can
efficiently try and find out what
character sequence the server uses for
string concatenation and once we know
that we can follow up and say well maybe
I can inject a function here I'm using
that a dysfunction because that's a
function that exists in almost every
programming language out there so I
don't need to know what the programming
languages for this follow-up payloads to
work and if that works well we know
we've got remote code execution more or
less but it would be nice to know
exactly what language of the server's
using and we can just follow up by
trying a bunch of specific functions
that only exist in one language so here
that is finalized function Corner's
works so that tells us that we've got
server-side JavaScript injection inside
a double quotes drink cool
and that's clinical but a normal stand I
could find that just by sending that
last payload straight away the power of
this technique is because of the way
that I've come to that conclusion I've
dealt with all three blind spots for
example if the server is actually
running an unknown language and not
JavaScript I'll probably still get to
this point and the scanner will still
report this to the human to the user who
can then investigate and figure out
what's going on and if the scanner
happens to be filtering out parentheses
to serve the scanner we'll still get to
this point it won't reject the functions
but it will find that it concatenates
dreams and it will tell the user who can
figure out what's going on
and finally if the application isn't
actually vulnerable to anything the
scanner only sends a tiny number of
payloads so it's extremely efficient and
that means that it can afford to do
things like put payloads everywhere
within a request even specifying
parameters multiple times to trigger
different code parts unfortunately I've
got ahead of myself slowly because I
haven't defined how to know when to
responses from the applications are
really different the obvious approach of
simply comparing the strings fail with
horribly in real life because many
applications like fulfill their
responses with meaningless junk content
that changes randomly on every page load
I originally try to solve this problem
and let me in by fetching the response
several times and using the longest
common common subsequence algorithm to
identify the static parts of response
and then stitching these together who
would a gigantic regular expression
however a lot of things went wrong with
this approach too many for me to
actually listen here but I've lived them
up in the white paper online what I
found actually works when I gave up
after a couple of years of trying to
make that work is viewing each response
as a collection of attributes actually
attributes meaning something like the
status code the Lion count the word
count the count of certain interesting
key words and so on and I'll let you
respond several times with each item in
a paper and I'll say I need at least one
attribute that has the following two
properties it needs to be consistently
different in the responses to the two
programs but if I send a single prepare
a single probe over and over it should
never change and if there's something
like that that tells us these profiles
are definitely triggering code pods that
meaning Italy different and that Singley
simple Reuters is actually really quite
effective and as such we've added an API
- burp suite so any extension can use
this technique the most important thing
to note from what I'm doing here is that
a no point am I trying to predict what
effect a specific payload will have on
the application I'm just looking out for
any clue that something is making the
application behave differently
so here's a simple example here we've
got one valid attribute the status code
never changes so that's no use and the
lion count changes on every page load so
that's not much you see there but the
word count always drops by one when we
send a none escaped single quote and so
the scale in the world will present this
evidence in a table as you see and this
scanner has found real live sequel
injection issues where the only evidence
is a single word vanishing here things a
slightly more complex so the code is a
reasonable attribute it just does what
we expect whenever he calls an error
it's 500 that's great but with the word
count it's a bit more complex so here
when we called an arrow the word count
is always 27 but the rest of the time it
changes randomly and that might be
because of some interaction between our
payloads and the system or it could be
just because someone's gone wrong so
prior to the update that I'm releasing
today this would not have been counted
as valid evidence but as of today this
is considered valid evidence but it's
listed in the table in italics with
stars around the variable attributes so
you know that this evidence is a bit
less strong it's more like
circumstantial evidence
this technique is still found real
vulnerabilities but just read more
carefully with that
okay so this different strategy is good
but regardless of what dissing strategy
we use we have to it will only work if
we back up the very carefully crafted
payload pairs so as I've shown if it was
response to size random content we can
just repeat folks and filter that stuff
out very easily some applications like
to alternate between two different
responses so if we alternate between the
two items in our post pair we might sync
up with the application and falsely
conclude that the different payloads
we're sending are caused are causing the
alternation of the response when
actually it's just bad luck so in order
to address that it's important to
shuttle the probe order instead of just
alternating between the two probes send
one twice in a row some of the time also
some applications that are particularly
nasty have deterministic random content
for example one side I tested likes to
list quotes about why you should buy
their products on their homepage and
this quote was randomly selected to fill
a pool of maybe five different quotes
but this selection was seeded with the
current URL so for a given URL the quote
you would see was always the same but as
soon as you changed your payload which
was in the URL you get a different quote
so my scanner originally falsely
concluded that this was vulnerable to
everything everyone ability out there
pretty much the way to address that is
to use probe batches take each item in
your prepare and make cosmetic
alterations to it and send those as well
so rather than just sending 7/0 also
send 7/0 zero if the application is
vulnerable this will have exactly the
same effect because the semantic meaning
is the same
but if your input has just been thrown
as a seed into a random number generator
or suchlike then this will cause a
different response for the application
and you won't get the false positive
okay that's pretty much all the theory
just to consolidate that I'll just show
a quick example of the scanner searching
for and finding a vulnerability so here
Shannon has sent an input of 221 and the
server has responded and there's a word
count of 965 so the standards going to
start out by saying a single quote and
that hasn't caused any change in the
word count so it's just going to give up
the bat and move on and try doing divide
by zero that does change the word count
to 327 so it's going to follow up and
try divided by one but that doesn't
revert to work out so it's going to give
up with that approach as well now it's
going to try injecting a function called
with a comma which is a technique that
typically works in sequel statements in
particularly in order by causes and here
injecting an invalid function tool has
changed the word count to zero so it's
going to follow up and try a valid
function call now the work out has
returned to the original value that
looks interesting but the scanner needs
to make sure this isn't is some kind of
deterministic random crap so it's going
to follow up and try another cosmetic
variation so here rather than calling
the function that doesn't exist it's
called in a real function but the number
of arguments is not valid so it will
still throw a syntaxerror
and now it's confirm the behavior so we
know we've got some kind of server-side
functional injection but it would be
nice to know what the server's running
in so it follows up and try the mode of
language specific functions and
eventually finds the current request ID
works which tells us this is running my
sequel server we've got sequel server
injection cool okay that's enough of the
theory let's see how a scanner works in
practice in order to find this out I
decided to run a scan on every server
that I could legally scan and that
effectively means every site that has a
bug bounty program that doesn't forbid
automated scanning and in order to help
out with that
I will at all called distribute damage
which implements a per host rate limit
so you can scale 30 hosts at the same
time easily using but but with this
extension that will ensure that each
host only thing only sees requests
coming in that may be one per second or
1 for 3 seconds
now the point of that is to be polite
but there's quite a cool side effect if
you disable over to normal Stan checks
and just on this run back slash powered
scanner and with this extension see the
service point of view you're sending a
tiny number of quite noxious payloads
very slowly and that means it's quite
likely to slip under the radar so if
you're on a red scene or you're trying
not to make a wast too angry this can be
quite useful the scanner is a little bit
like highly enthusiastic rookie security
desperate if you point it at something
that's really easy it will just tell you
exactly what's going on so here is to
found some my sequel objection I this
was in the use of agent on a server that
was running WordPress so presumably had
some terrible plugins and a school but
know better than any other scanner
really this gentle the scanner is that
it will tell you when it's out on an
interesting just like this rookie tester
they will try something they'll make a
bit of progress and then they'll get a
stock but they'll let you know so what
we've got here is the first critical
vulnerability the back slash powered
scanner ever found it was on a pen test
and I haven't found this issue while
manual manually testing so this is all a
extremely happy would anyone like to
take a guess as to what the server was
vulnerable to now ok it's vulnerable to
PHP code injection but the server is
filtering out parentheses so the
function call has failed and yeah I
didn't even find this issue in manual
testing and this application had been
tested by several other companies prior
to me testing it so it was a pretty hard
to find issue
the reason that I didn't find it is
because the input had to be placed in
the past and this was this was on a
household name website calling a PHP Evo
on the path is the kind of nonsense that
you expect an Internet of Things device
to do and not a real website anyway the
scanner found it because it's very
patient and try payloads everywhere
whenever you see a partial issue you can
be sure that things won't be entirely
straightforward so here the scanner said
it managed to inject a function call but
it couldn't figure out what the database
language was which is a bit odd because
it has support for all major database
languages so I took this issue to the
repeater and I investigated manually and
it became very obvious what the problem
was
regardless of what request I sent to the
application I go up for a three
forbidden back in other words I've been
IP banned quite a web application
violence and so I changed my IP and I
leave on the stand on that target and I
found my simple injection
it might soft signal injection so that
was nice that was really easy and that
was on a US Department of Defense server
and actually affected over 100 different
US military service I guess they were
all using the same lively or that had
some kind of shared code it raises the
question why did no other scanners
finest given that this vulnerability was
displayed on tons of publicly accessible
websites I think that's probably because
all the other scanners just got IP
banned before they go anywhere at all
if the scanner finds a partial result
like the last one and you spend hours
investigating probably the most
disappointing outcome its defined that
you've got regular expression injection
because typically this vulnerability has
pretty much most developed it like the
best it can be used for is normally a
denial of service and who cares about
that so it's important to try and
identify this one of anything as early
as possible so that you don't waste time
one of the ways that you can find that
is by trying to inject a bad Crescent if
you inject something like backslash 0
and it gets converted into another
string that tells you okay that's just
reg X injection and also if you notice
to come a different response from the
application when you inject slash 1 and
something like slash 1 1 1 once again
that could indicate regex injection
because slash 1 1 1 is too high to be a
valid regular expression group and it
will typically throw some kind of
exception where it slash one point also
is when using that slash power scalar
it's very easy to forget that actually
you are human and you could just read
the result and see that there's an error
that tells you exactly what's going on I
generally think of that some of the time
wedge X injection is quite possible
because on certain PHP systems for
example PHP myadmin
had this vulnerability you can specify
additional veget regex flags including
the e flag for eval and thus get code
execution so that's nice most of the
time that won't work and so to save you
from the effort of trying this backslash
powered scan I will try that follow-up
Talos for you automatically
other times the scanner will get false
positives now these are generally caused
by flaws in the probe pairs and the
copay is used in backslash powered
scanner by default have been refined
over the last year or so and so false
positives are going to be really quite
rare but if you add your own your own
experimental prophase you'll probably
find that you need to refine them to
avoid
certain false positives here we can
immediately tell there's something a
little bit weird because we're getting a
four a three when we call a valid
function it doesn't make much sense and
the root cause is actually that there's
a Web Application Firewall
grepping for the text substr so that's
all cause is that false positive and
that was easy to fix I just added a
variation that still called the
substrate function but used invalid
parameters to it so the Web Application
Firewall isn't smart enough to parse the
input and work out whether the arguments
are valid and so that resolve is false
positive in general this is why you want
your players to be as syntactically
close to each other as possible
other times the scanner will finds
things that aren't exactly
vulnerabilities but they're useful
pieces of intelligence so here it
initially looks as though we've got some
kind of code injection in a numeric
context but the scanner will now send
the follow-up payload and find that the
same thing works with HTML tags so now
it looks quite different the root cause
is actually that there's a web
applications rival again a different one
and it's rewriting requests in slights
to remove comments so the backend for
the first in the first case just be a
zero whereas in the second case that
seems a bunch of junk so that's why it
causes an error only in the second case
now that isn't a vulnerability by itself
but that is actually quite useful in
some situations because you can use this
behavior to bypass browsers cross-site
scripting filters their filters use
regular expressions and they can't
possibly account for requests being
rewritten in flight by intermediate
servers so if you just inject a comment
into your payload that will break the
regex and the browser won't catch the
cross-site scripting vulnerability other
times you'll find issues that are
destined to remain a mystery the scanner
found this one
couple of months ago and I spent about a
day trying to figure out what was going
on here and Gareth Hayes also spent
about a day trying to figure out what
was going on and there's some other
people in the office also he tried to
figure out what was going on
and none of us could could could do it
the behavior from the server here it
almost matches what you would expect
from a Jarvis from a Java eval on a
single closer to regular expression but
it doesn't quite match it so none of us
could escalate this and this is just
going to happen sometimes if you find
something like this and you're on a on a
client job please consider asking the
client what the hell is going on maybe
they can show you the source code even
and if you let if you let me know what
the behavior is I can potentially add a
follow-up test the back slash powered
scanner to try and classify it more
accurately as of the update that I'm
releasing after this presentation
backslash power planner will also find
server-side HTTP parameter pollution
just in case you're not familiar with
this vulnerability I'll just briefly
describe it so applications sometimes
take user input and embed this in a
query to a back-end server that isn't
publicly accessible and that's fine but
they may forget to URL encode this user
input and that means that the user can
specify additional parameters that will
get passed on to the backend or they may
be able to overwrite existing parameters
and that make time for some really
really interesting results because the
backend probably doesn't view the
additional parameters as being user
input and so it may trust those values
and yet as of today's update backlash
card scanner will find that issue so
this flow pair that it's using now this
is more of an experimental one so it may
get some false positives but I have
tested it on a digital language website
and it has found a large number of
legitimate issues in fact you found so
many legitimate issues that I got really
bored while manually trying to exploit
them all and so I've made that cash card
scanner help you out with that so when
it finds this
if you right-click on the response
you'll see an additional option in the
menu which says identify back-end
parameters and if you click that it will
send the top 2,000 most common
server-side parameter names to the
back-end server and use the different
technique to see if there are any valid
ones that cause a different response
from the application so here for example
I found there's a valid parameter called
City on the backend and it has the
evidence showing that this is causing
some kind of different behavior so that
sells you the city parameter is being
used by the backend and then you can try
and exploit that by scaling it we'll
just using the logic so what can we
maybe do in the future using these
techniques well one thing that backslash
card scanner is undeniably great for is
cold-start blue forces the tax attempts
to enumerate valid inputs when you've
got no prior knowledge for example the
original place that I've had was let me
in where I didn't have a single valid
user name so I couldn't identify the
response to a valid user name when I
started I was just looking for anything
changing and letmein hasn't be imported
to use this new technique that's
actually reliable yet so that's
something that I'm planning on doing in
the future and also you can use this
technique to brute force parameter names
as I do on the back end at the moment
also you can essentially try some really
quite advanced stuff with this for
example maybe you're doing a black box
test on an application and you find an
arbitral and object deserialization
vulnerability but because of the black
box you don't know what gadgets there
are available on the server well you
could use this different technique to
try to avoid force to automatically
identify valid ladders on a server that
would be nice and with the bit of
creativity we can go far beyond
injection vulnerabilities for example
take the simple here as a human you can
just read that and tell what it
and you know if you change the IV and
you can edit someone else's profile
you've got a critical vulnerability but
all the scanner sees is an application
that takes an input which is a number
that's about as much as it understands
but it can actually answer the question
is there's this number correspond to
something that we can enumerate on the
server site and it can do that by
incrementing the number one incrementing
it twice and confirming there we get
three unique responses from the
application if you only get to two
unique responses then that might just be
the application saying here's your
profile and saying you don't have
permission to view this profile which is
not much but if you get three that shows
you can enumerate this and that just by
ourselves we'll find some interesting
things but it will also find some quite
boring things like calculators in
calendars where your input isn't really
a numerating of fixed results it's just
doing some kind of calculation so we can
get rid of those boring outcomes by
doing the following up test which is to
see if there's a finite number of
entries we can do that by adding a huge
fixed value to the input so if you had a
hundred thousand to both of them we
should get the same response in this
example they should both say something
like this profile does not exist so
that's something that I'm planning on
adding recently sooner I've got a
working prototype of this it just needs
a bit of Justin okay you can grab the
source code for service online so it's
implemented as advert extension so you
need burbs to run it but the source code
is all available it's in Java if you
wanted to you could cause it to run on
SAP very very easily and you can also
grab the white paper online which has a
bit more details if you just want to run
this tool then this update will be will
be available in the back store so you
don't really need to look at the code
if you
wanting this is not one of those
security tools but gets released into
presentation and then never updated this
has huge potential and I'm planning on
continuing working on it for the next
few years on and off and as techniques
become stable and reliable stable stable
and reliable
I'll also port them to Burke core so
three key things to remember their
scanners can find research-grade
vulnerabilities provided they focus on
enhancing rather than replacing the pen
tester and this is still just the
beginning okay so I'll take five minutes
of questions now and then if you've got
any more questions just send me an email
or come up and talk to me at the back
toe forget to follow me on Twitter thank
you for listening
[Applause]
so any questions
what thank you oh wait no one bitching
the does you're gonna support automatic
change IP address for example if you
make some tries you look at a kind of a
locket and okay it doesn't currently
support that but that is a features but
I'm considering implementing in fact we
might even put that in core but just
some kind of something that identifies
when when you've been blocked by a by a
Web Application Firewall yelling thank
you
hi James thank you for call - I have a
question
what kind of injection vulnerabilities
you can find with your scanner is it a
sequel injection I you can find almost
any kinds of server-side injections so
you can find a lot like though it has
explicit support for sequel injection
code injection of pretty much any kind
really like I've added support for four
specific languages like PHP Java Python
Ruby pearl JavaScript etc but because of
the design of it if you want it on any
kind of language that is vulnerable to
some kind of eval then it will find it
like it's also for example I think it's
found solar injection it's fine it's
found a later injection I think so it is
capable of finding some pretty weird
stuff okay thank you very much
the distributor's colour is publicly
available yes or on don't shoot it's a
plugin yeah yeah it's a plugin you can
install it by the BAP store and the
source code is online - thank you
right Copland ation Thanks what did you
do what do you do with too many requests
problem how to detect it and my part is
the too many requests saying yes the
manna-fest problem
so because backslash powered scanner
uses at users a tree if an input is not
vulnerable to anything then it will
typically send maybe six requests like a
tiny number because for example although
it can find and classify maybe 30
different types of code injections they
all begin with a single quote or a
double quote or with a number and so it
will try each of those and so the three
requests it can vol out 30 different
kinds of injection vulnerability so as a
resolve that it's extremely efficient
well thank you how do you add a new
signatures to scanner so I you need to
edit the source code of theirs and if
you look in the wall do is are only a
link to an example signatures that's
very simple and then you can base it on
that is it is very very easy
thanks compiling the code is the hardest
part
okay thank you very much
[Applause]