and banks for example morning every time
urban contesting internet banking web
apps or apps the guys from my team they
have found at the internal pages some
Google Analytics they were surprised
they asked how come and it turned out
that this is the msconfig of a template
level and one of the problems there was
that the Google Analytics management was
conducted by the external team as
opposed to the organization to the
business and after that we have decided
to look into how often this practice
actually happens when web analytics is
published at the login page of the
internet banking apps and it turned out
this quiet come to come across lots of
eternally published their analytics at
the login page briefly why this is bad
first of all of us does not recommend
this and technically javascript plugins
which are connected to the page they're
being executed with a sob context of the
page so if those scripts have access to
all the data on the page including the
login so we decided to research this
thing and we have avert a tool which
uses the web client this very
lightweight browser called splash we
have decided to isolate the isolate the
objectives by launching a splash inside
of the docker we used the bank through
website we took the financial writing
other banks and I have decided to
create the automatic list are the pages
of login pages of the the aterna banks
of those Spanx but since there are some
banks that are not well known than those
listed Google and Yandex have been
giving us some pointless information and
we have decided to make the list
manually and after that the list was
giving - - and we have this tests as a
result the 56% of the bank's out of the
out of 600 banks that are in the list
they have the app for the internet Bank
for consumers about 30% of the bank's
the outsource riding that up or use Clos
like fucked or did ru or anyone that are
you
and those club banks the often as a rule
includes some kind of analytics of all
of all those apps that were exclusively
developed by the bank's they have about
although those apps you about fifty
percent of those apps use some analytics
in their login page and there was
popular plug-in there was Google
Analytics the newest versions are used
at 76% of the pages and if we look the
older version of Melinda's this is used
at 98% of their login pages of the
others apps so now let's look into this
thing in a more detail at different
kinds of analytics so say writing mail
are you it's used at the pages of login
pages of the apps of six banks in terms
of security this is the most secure of
all the Analects because this is a
simple script that just sends the in the
user info such as
such as the browser screen resolution it
takes two references of the HTTPS to
actually display how the user goes about
the app and of course all the logistics
of the tracker is at mail.ru servers
which determine based in the data where
the user is the age the gender and so on
Google Analytics is a bit more
interesting because and the newest
version of Google X they added some
extensions which can be connected from
external resources and if you want to
connect the extension the page the text
script should be added to the page with
the address from where this extension
can be connected so the hacker can
easily attack the host series hosting
where the extension is published and
replace the code of the extension to
execute that code on the client side but
this is quite hard to do because that
requires a certain way to enter some
external hosting Yandex metrics if web
visitor is switched off there it's not
so interesting because it's very simple
to writing Mallory are you but if web
visitor is on which allows the owner the
app or the person who manages the plugin
through their control panel to see the
video the actual video of what the user
was doing on the page how he was moving
about the app but was putting into the
spaces but there's no way to get
information about hidden fields and
password fields because the metrics
hides it the most peculiar tools
turned out to be a Google tag manager
testing BladeCenter plugin it's the
manager this plugin manager but after
having been installed at the web at page
there's no need to change the code to
manage this thing the entire management
is made through web interface of the
plugin so this thing has been written so
that any specialist any non technical
specialist can easily use this analysts
marketing specialists but backer there's
very interesting feature to add into the
page any random HTML tag that is why the
web interface of the control panel
there's a way to actually sue in the
script with some random GS code that
will be executed after having been saved
right away on all the clients and
there's a very easy way to collect all
that it's from the page and send to some
other remote server
the vendors that provide analytics they
do realize that there's a certain threat
to the security which can come out as a
result of getting access to the plug in
control panels so that's why they try
their best to isolate the X is there or
just use the counter ID or find out to
which email the plug-in has been
registered to and who manages the plugin
but more often than not co-ceo is SEO is
given to the outsourcing and that does
one and that is when people who have not
been checked ever can access to daytime
turns out it's the developers of the app
to themselves they hand out user
credentials to some other people into
malicious hence this is basically
everything they wanted to tell you about
any questions you might have
[Applause]
thank you very much the presentation so
here's the question dude those are these
conductivity polity she's being used to
protect from Scrubs whopping that might
come out or some inline scripts that
might come in have you ever noticed
anything like that
no we haven't looked at that because
when we were collecting stats on the
user plugins was automated but in the
case of for example Google tag manager
things like this do not save for the
plugins that can be uploaded because
they are all uploaded from one single
domain thank you very much for the
presentation I have kind of the parallel
to the presentation question the
question parallel to the presentations
I'm curious have you researched the
websites of the bank in terms of Robert
a text a file because there are some
particular pages to download like
blistery spendings de Janerio unique
address but those link address can be
sent for the analytics to Google through
the Firefox address aligned have you
been researching the bank's website from
that point we no no we have been
researching the login pages for the
internet banking because if you want to
test all those 600 banks we need to have
the account there it's quite problematic