the awesome meow okay
yeah avocado remembers like exactly I
Love Lucy like watches my show because
we are like you know that we have to
roll the damn fuckin can you open PDF
please write a book national college
okay oh my god okay we are developing
we're at open double where the
super-soldier controller mornig very
chaotic complication on the controller
and we can talk about as well yeah
custom social relevance for merciful
traffic processing war he was and today
I'll be talking about this network a
tolling yeah very meaningful productive
traffic processing and you get that with
EQ HTTP DDoS mitigation that I earn
money in consulting because I work in a
custom development of the software
really a specialized to me about the
processing on the unit of traffic in
particular the ice and security involves
a creepier closet dot and database a
particular way I can create some people
scroll looking for questioning and
different version B Square tend to be
considered being what the codes are
developing big feature I just teach it
one of the magic creatures oh they're
going to be turning 300 and it happened
that representation is here when you got
s melting water near conference I never
thought about developing a writer
thank you browser many of them as a
market some years ago started to work on
the machine training module to detect
applicati doses at the client level
psychosis I heart to be cut through
graduate signature when we were making
further
disposal ensure that after two series
platform to launch a tire went in it was
connect structures reflect box various
probes but none of them yes I fitters we
can also let about reasons my HP
accelerators are not for purposes but we
are sure the problem fifty with him too
much in disease no current industry
start but we can see PA the Celtic
superiors determine the next artifact
don't elect our three packages so
pre-internet a similar recipe
versatility a lot of familiar huge
traffic and have incremental things etc
nicest explosion experience protocol
which a pressure system which is bad
next thing but be a model we have a
problem integers relatively low dose
happy like the administer peer psycho
rarely exact channel graphic is scripted
by Fabien possibly problem was perfect
to go wash up me and Alicia Cousteau
issues right now Jesus fuckers
yeah a much more restorative
indifferently recite numbers for here
don't ever show quickly so the very
slight perfect for cryptography I be
server configuration what we have gotten
the that will be to watch compress ocean
we're very impatient are given to keep
after confession it was one of the
example house message don't watch for
heavy bracket you know the regulation I
think of the one phase room which I see
no God like a closet obviously blouses
doesn't doing a lot of traffic
professors
[Music]
totally 15 unwise formalities a war keep
our forests like this and cook with
other countries connection and connect a
sidewalk below that I sorted is also
when you get almost no education we need
to use machine learning whatever or
device whines yes yes we understand we
should I mean oh my cake you got me
about three more if you big creature
like your variance of you what about
that question I don't wear my
crystallized correct a little fun in
Oaxaca pilot a responds I don't know in
order for us to has a logic of action
learning to work a number of queries are
we sir yeah yeah we're Josh Gwenda we
can have our machine learning another
sander and tumbling to me based on which
customers are attackers fish are
legitimate term goes by and I have some
counties back when power armor swath
well over here
that's what was a video part where we
met presentation can watch videos post
interesting difficulty we are certainly
him they had an example yeah not easy
it's not easy for filtration the hell
attack which was featured this signature
action is use port oh let me shut the
ball you prefer
sorry quest for port 8080 collide if we
can see how can children up to be
difficult
first of all to zero level easily touch
the table significantly it's right
powerful pressure makin is not really my
people they work a little arrow
Salaam Aleichem contrasty shipping
because of you know not headers but to
remember that most lasting of
participation in city work packages
disappear segment customized turn to
fracking will not catch the next or
previous example by their own costs
signature for after a long gorilla is a
big table strings we women have either
say this long way around searching for
horses of course prescribe to shift the
procession form and this shift should
could be variable is quite easy to
manage this thing you can send long
random arrives normally will character
three structures does apply level mostly
occurrences really built up hello farm
genexus most awesomely because you get
very powerful hardware web accelerator
are things which are from a man for
Declaration of content but looks
alliteration but later I'll tell you why
they do not filter well texting that we
have maybe the best you can think that
you have yes i pierce a see such as sir
head
okay blue line to the traffic yeah it's
lettuces three it instructs the string
and it also has a problem first rule is
not TCP and at home start participating
participate connection but not model is
onyx looks what we have a nitrogen
fluorine channels is not the fastest our
endpoints we have same with his about
there to see perchance as ours can have
quite what we developed area on TCP yes
evasion
- hello Ellen second teacher because
over some usually taken to completion or
dream that was a bikie idea you so we
can just difficult to get your dad use
the next thing our ideas issue area have
nothing to avoid two options is that
with a zero Alexa geared up whatever
choice yes about what but Alicia a
special advisor to the dragon giggle
misogyny one time or another dining I
showed rules like the so terminators
required and there's a carbon context or
double also processing Tydeus if your
server and liking be vital it's not
quite fast if you wanted a just looking
perfect double ACP parsing problem
because difficult was operation later on
I'll show you that this is difficult or
hard operation it's not nice to
processes but we get a double
lasting yes but that's what human
activity doesn't prove the server
performance never talk about the does
prevention it always talk about those
magnification doesn't mean a glucose
normally need to have certain host
negress what we love but actually only
thing is for the sufficient measure
measures to reduce to attack to a level
I can not go to that we limit my certain
traffic would pass through higher
classification stage to the machine
training hands-on shenanigans or will we
catch them on okay get some regions on
you won't catch some other sucker so if
you come across those are not only
filtration we need to have a kind
capacity right a thousand actually
situation measures must help system to
with the load there are four following
this thinking came to idea that we need
to interbreed does return return to
reduce the load and the production
system for us to have a point here this
print LS roll out so we make a decision
or to divert the traffic chronology just
listen we are analyzing point so there
are several points which we've kicked in
during the design first of all we need a
ten point scale with not for dissipative
as you need to have a theater fast
anticipate parser or two persons without
HTTP floods you have very powerful
network i optimize for massive ingress
traffic does that we must have powerful
buffering mechanism enable us to filter
tall network layers and we must ever
fastest right period oh yeah oh maybe to
mitigate those we can filter out that is
GUI mario completed osaka that each
other
melt takes some time posterization
negatives are inaudible so your this is
devoid hundreds of ways of course
percent and then we won't even bore a
heart attack that our ship or her your
value specialization learning at point
when monopoly fuck action learning in
question without name without the white
jacket yet to cure
traffic system and still can miss
something legit waria what happens like
during the first one what a shock
because do you control your feet it's
just that God Julie shoulders
right because you can't audit which is
the class they synced up in yet CBF and
will show me because relevant but we'll
see whether a loop application delivery
controller this is the thing which you
can do difference equations Nagas a
complete at that isn't so we say DC is
wrapped edge there's protection which
can do lowdown serve application
security placate performance force again
so you guys are floating data
compression on detection cures yes so
let us take a look when you were
questioned what is the application layer
for you go see game at vieta turns over
stalls not going to be higher because
the chamber because with filtration
Alice thanks to give our Shah because
you look like you could sha doesn't
appreciate that expose ourselves not
recover vacuum it means the locations
were expenses of your second square is
not a testings is not in small pages I
mean you have some bananas psychologist
the debate cannot listen to that myself
and the simple query simple page p.m. to
have that figure suggests Alexia
picketing for what stresses your
superfood one I prefer growth burn you
know some stock Russia's alone first
long right to the law all right Michael
oh is it really this table for centuries
clear if we are I went back here what
were you facing far away watches war
crashes fit an evil evil evil that with
tranny tight so we can do several times
so possibly up there indeed what it was
last century you must not talk about you
at least under this pressure we have
instant to accelerate with the defender
that is coming it will negotiate through
I get one engine
make reliable commercial version let's
pretend with that model commotion
excited acuity but I can't tell you
thank you
yeah grab tables like that much don't
remember them all the law myself
fuck you oh yeah gotta go measure
nothing mansion extra looked at a lot of
focus you got a family
yeah yeah all of them one way or another
were developed for a purpose of the
liberal continent each animal is quickly
bomber fishers yeah you are not so you
know that are released for filtration I
also have an idea
Graham poem store will not remember P do
not budgets Beauty origina us you know
we desire the new designs eternity
despite an 10 K by a thousand apparel
collection is a problem for warm low
very especially that also it isn't we
have to rethink their architecture as I
said a service again and some different
projects now they are not very mammogram
probably it's just a cell across from
your body always working our way through
this is Alex but I cannot endure not be
among its problem moisture but surely I
guess they may actually what Marty very
consider the situation QC yes I some
Cubano corner that was about to get -
for example we've got some Star Trek it
clay I just sent over something wrong
with my rather than developers yet or
think that's further case those who
knows my coordinate is ready can good
yes yeah like different emotions
productions love it I don't want to
especially my surprises re-election
Series from Atlanta Georgia was like but
it is so what square we can do
everything what we now obviously either
for regulatory face or get stupid
we'll make a smarter ones will detect
lies resources and find you I will not
forget no next thing we have some
turnover crazy like as I read them I
neonatology switch on girl later we're
revising the Fitzroy patterns bring 500
more advantage working as micro sensors
the freshest systems here we go and what
is your focus on tomorrow
wait your basic skills is which EE watch
- and you're not young we're variants no
we're still attached to those yet we
have it resting degree actually that's
your capacity not just like note on the
10th place but blocking and you need to
think about the pressure society first
that what I'll do I'll change changes
for us in terms of accessing super 12
miles I get classes yet rigid query the
seraphic file created so you must go at
the closeout kernel a little sensor fast
clunky last comment is really nice
because things opposed don't have
psychological I need to decryption to
sell on to University shaken nation wait
- McCracken spoiled and innovation with
a profound cryptic with from a furiously
is complete two kernels on the friend
0 which is pollen I mean uploaded other
optimizations and support so that we
have a vision problem Ian question
sorrow vendors work with that living
with her if not a phalanx Assad will
Security Division limitation Killian
Iike kronosaurus
oh thank you normally developments very
members we are absolutely plain periodic
resolve ice and shake too ambitious for
accession Daniel name this our only
democratic
chuckles and Allah among all the
developers 52 the world of sauces yes Oh
part of that role of rule is still yet
to come and enjoy as well put through a
walking route each agent I borrowed the
seismic Thomas for you can say is great
glass like Walsh a cover so who are you
connect to the kind I could be my
physical connection seven geography one
quick question cookies could be visually
rather hard up with more for human
actions you will reject what your son
which is okay with a long time because I
don't like a nice to say like an orange
I you don't support fun part 1.3 what
does what okay boss okay wait a second
Emily my silent you will get any
conference and they say absolute
software at least make us a lot of
fuckin shake yes but I'm not here we are
sure in Joe Tafolla let's for simplicity
I'll fuck you up where else
yeah fuck you look yellow pyramid which
critical errors podcast appear here nah
what summer COP simple absolutely when
you talk about competing
that's not video secondary character
it's not cutting very copy purser
Sicilian reading system first and fourth
queries falafel flour is utopia is
titania Etta and promoting is module
removing what Potrero
Okita what no trick okay I thought well
third is the hotel employers gives a
recessive also one more second in the
result
did you know whether positive entry in
this profile that is slowly flat profile
the next which is all about thank you a
lot of tomatoes always year style people
lower and examine encourage social
Ricardo na spoke efficient attend large
area so for
no God's prophet like it know the
process as well mm why we have to go
through all our Fatima move our body
what keeps your toes with my service
aims at what if you remain adjust it is
called simple purchase orders yet
matters we have like a low percentage to
complain to pass on a dress with Lorena
okay so I suppose would go to number
quite a more stockpile is like mother to
a farm is like load we need to have
another is off then it is so commonly it
is okay so gotta come with a personal
system I see those zeros but yes our
server should do to operate rejection
for one more see I think we have nine
with the promotion right it's like all
sorting ticket I give out the Minamata
twirl-o-fun can I'm still not as weak
energy by eight I guess I'll start
usually many more others we cannot
remove and this is something that we
need to live through away a period
contacts which are cheap complex fun but
this job is worth something and this is
something that we can talk much about
mr. peacock you are saying what is slow
that would keep that what nice I just
sorted so the power is I quite simple
how people normally code our supply and
the parser the all the servers that I
looked at I could use one way or another
this approach as normally as a machine
der we can write image might even by the
student typical house cycle on day to
them have say yeah we variable on the
state course we just a realized yeah you
stay for your know step for me and you
know but ever see of leather be so my
come here first of all we are here and
they're normally here's we piece of code
boost our fish mr.akash personal fashion
we
then we appeal yet the five back space
where we don't swing it jungbaek prison
and state machine get back to the
beginning
girl this moment I have three kisses
because this cold large - what the
guinea pig was masago em when they come
to take two three understand what this
is academic library boys say I am
dedicated to to the free what free
cannot simply can go to the next - yet
don't have to close in and like begin
with we have acquired knowledge to come
to soak up those this is how current
arsons working with truth transfer so
for the key that I was part of the
revision so like an idiot to be on a
support for general desire remains it
was a very very happy to me ibid not
they replace them for necessary code
science from which the next execution
begins it won't smudge it faster upon
yeah
this is emotional can be used for very
powerful HDTV forcing so this is done
usually manually and this is not done
very certainly spooky just about lines
well attached is that HTML lines are so
special lines they lashed even awesomer
portal without Jimmy knots and I don't
have termination by 0 termination by 0
is very important for standard library
HC of new creation
fortunately doesn't have a way to since
2014 we use a with various tools
extension but you can't RFC or they
don't have our line processing us so
that we have another problem is reaching
me with little separators and HTTP line
these could be with very much my viola
column or face comma
what's items we have returned I know
clear for me sometimes as a ref we have
to go to real because we have different
clients which also have preset important
to us and it's giving at the end of line
usually instead of 0 which are used for
other GE that's what we should
technology delimiter by student in white
for one but to fight and standard
function that is not designed for that
is not effectively for advancing the
session 3 or CPC will avoid it make sure
HTTP service day you register here is
only a dangerous exam those that I've
shown you and those as I said they were
even slower than now I review see which
has not been optimized such as no risk
allegedly specific web I only use their
own algorithm gossipy for itself on
simple consideration of the fact that we
don't usually analyze regular lines in
the NASA team but do I know that which
name usually gives the regular
transition of select machine without
reading additional variable to it is
this growth of activity 1.5 times which
is now when showering or translating to
the optimization of which advances we
got to our taxi on the killer body one
goes for three times higher giving or
official change kilobytes
then even more minute a clear the
prequel one kilobyte lines is more like
okie modern with your right this lines
can be quite interface well centralized
you can take videos and you can go
rename your right when are so that's why
we have to be very resistant to any
incoming data and better extension
allows us to like stabilizer with
chemistry HTTP server depending
depending from typically done types of
input data that you've also to the fact
that we used vector extensions in a
vector registry so we find also the
Jason Wright job we have a functional
create an alchemist encoders your eyes
for your ROI on alphabet they're all
headers we have another algebra so in
different parts of it they use different
alternative because also that are
installed at Fresno State matrices and
we have objective that's a whole
immigration of the nation rules Jalen
listing the system Java this trader can
put this in your eyes if you have
dynamic application with the problem
then you will know may not see errors
for last question monster young person
that's a non-profit and we only this
trick website under this symbol that are
produced the rest of them are artichokes
and your risk of SQL injection is
reduced without any and if it's like a
reduction of productivity and
performance whoa speaking about with
raggedness performance of input our
network is input art you can see here
three packages we have a networking card
we have a really fun remote condition of
this package is not your sister
what we have two processors which are
working in innovation when they are put
into society this incentivize this
product is this trucks begin reading
directly even without 10 gigabit compute
data into the server we can inject a lot
of baggage but that one Thank You
thrusters will come to this socket to
this package this little package will
not be indication of the products in the
modern agriculture system networking was
hard but again warm up yes
presidentially bucket by incoming life
working academically person for some
temperature I'm shutting oh yes of the
third level yes but you're speaking a
very small was a the volume we can cash
it right now if we will be able to for
immediate I didn't work and packages
while there is coming without waiting
for insulation
I think initiative like that that we
could work much faster I would like to
bring to your attention the fact that
any value voltage I guess it works on
this particular level and it works
impact on ishani because as soon as the
package arrives we're analyzing
nicely and then we give it weight either
we destroyed it all we process such as
noxious crystal yet the team passed most
of the design possession officiating
this yearly station of tcp/ip stage is
the probe about cycle jumble we have the
ID code processing from the backgrounds
I won't be level YC trust you shall then
the charge for the HCP so setup without
and then give to an ATP so it's the
continuation of dtap for Sonia
continuation of HTTP protocol and hrs
protocol we needed in just the one month
to inject a TLS super kernel it was
political allies this is something in
itself moisture to grow so many powerful
integration with memory managers and
it's much easier to put it into kernels
don't take a t-shirt please idea Sega
into the users waves and there I'm going
to tell you bunch of them achievement
why do we need to take all the tcp/ip
stack into the kernel that is not for
sitting in this exact excitation of
tcp/ip stack gives us she's name is
Turner from Linux which allow nation
generations not only 40 spatial level
which is clear right now like behave
like EVP like at the table like done
yeah just shocked fulfill in addition to
these things you're also gonna have HTTP
mal second with one hand right now
aluminum with you because the last two
HTTP parser which can optimize lines and
the kodkod cat the book when you
original or a surprising other earrings
about HP server or whether service on
this is also databases and we can think
about them throughout the age 12 it has
big amount of files that are given away
from this you also good web service part
one party traffic service we have all
day caring elevator to control cache
some of these are the same thing we have
special and memories are videos which
hold the virus which all web can tell in
order for
even our Emily five-year to transfer
this web content without involvement of
remove of our dreams
that's right now we have featured
opposite prevail of our own planet
divides and ever think of a little bit
later as a static language plural rules
and all the letter cutting consumption
proper dodging it would feature a
continuation of the IP parsing T baby
businesses alpha is crossed over the
package goes to the PC senior level
probably we have a quality of service
controlled by the trolling quality to
Primos then it's even function Hampton
the decisions been made to the package
or channel on it will be but it is
possible to Northwest from casually work
and I request from care much done
seditious or database which is
responsible for and come here yes and
this is the wrong were us than he had
more wood and all the always in going to
the ID yellow
a carotid suggest now education what was
we do I have a Panetta vegetable one
glance appear ivory and universal
network of what is named thusly and to
occupy the bottom it's a war for gypsy
was cotton which is quality selected
working like that was naughty of me to
tell good from here we factor about the
factors web service heavier very million
forty nationwide reflexologist service
and experience what which lines forward
the show's English cubes for example
turns one which is much mana boarding
team to work and learn request and use
again build new connections if we have
done fashionable bankage masonry and
two plugins all which ones and so that
they would get all gained and then get
lost but those who already forgot logins
up they should complete the transaction
out we determine this is retinol which
is indigenous on the determine ratio
where region my wife are accepted ever
sent by Rebecca Silverman we support a
given volume of queries than it can
accept for some
the classical equations not interested
in the content that it was unjust this
is a very simple matrix in which you can
follow up video so uh value not his
general you have the logical door
section which means our people with our
defenses with you I had this come
nowhere I'll have to ask you a
combination of you don't have enough
memory introduced a new shipping lines a
we should be slowed down so slowing down
of those parents because we do very much
rely on them which are attack which are
defender then we do anything a very
legitimate subway a bioship we can love
you your little bit such a reception or
a ticket or the traffic would come from
them and then we can invite obviously
you know that I have new connections
yeah they're real follow you manage
Shelly forever that if we have a web
server Assad and are this we can even
without no ways in fact so noticed which
is you know what we can do this all the
session tears they are very interesting
roblox facility to enjoy rock scene yes
the numbers the people I don't know when
you need to send if you answer yes clear
so there is a client of the travelers
oxygen I think that you mean there's
also an ascent to the servant turbulence
then we have a full bar here in the
connection and we have to award some
sockets valve are different full
professional services there is a gift
row a magician there is really no big
but marching our schedules world but a
traditional probably service-oriented
conditions very biological potential for
years we have you know special
transportation waste and without created
structures which allows reports do not
work you will see you a yoga block it
wasn't works its own local frosted is a
favorable exchange monster awaiting and
second cultures where velocity of
wreckage attention is mentioned I will
get less gilliam consumption force must
be a decision can they get more traffic
conditions that it can reply fast
accessible to pro and you are going to
speak about a
copy chef Oh course Pookie shot spore
fiction pull yourself back okay I would
like to speak about security features
inside because we have sticky cookies we
can be requested from the client is not
able as you process clock is more than
whether you can do keep him or she's
like you it we can block cameras and
organized you know unfortunately years
on JavaScript have not reduced challenge
geometry which will leverage their own
and their objectives which can be
professional rather more of what it's a
language that we welcome Iraq in World
War II are different he addressed a nice
target as well this is Florida yet this
rule we advocated very meet the session
of Ashoka reached rose additional number
of regulated will be a fighting William
flow it should be all naughty and we
also decided qualified we should employ
so basically a very very dimensional
feeling the Ryoga some yes MTN shares of
anymore and what we don't have to
perceive it is I walk across our example
you're like oh colleague is poised to
technology which is done by colleagues
from positive neurologist or by driving
a thriving name partner yeah exposing
yeah you are addition to a cocktail
party I like was exhilarating efficient
are like work say long before I wet hour
throughout the movie so the tiger Raisa
watch a lot of a shortage to process big
number clásica of big amounts of
neurons which is n in our case are going
to have K fatwa those literally can
deploy XML and you meet Marshall College
to our they had an Allison know a lot of
personal you see they can write a very
brilliant watch sequester allowed to
block and treat market but one thing
this anymore capitalism near Mary name
first Yokoi kubinashi we have to
introduce a lot more ginger pork with
Vatican speaking about a total Omaha we
achieved 1.8 million request personal
ambitions yes is in a typist for him
view the comparison we can look at
something that connection litmus
matrixes about life watch it will be 10
times faster I do not know why the
researcher should date about as much
damage so this realistic 600,000 require
a second box there's a weeble di access
warm yes also yes Joe we see a poor
winner social area is mounting in the
tcp/ip in the users face it will help us
to optimize the load balance to the
unrefined area for image plan I can tell
you more about the solutions next readö
an epochal seclusion with ruggedness to
see device but they show the same
performance 1.3 or closer to view that
was millions of requests per second
where ii liked impious well you know we
work in the course i mean and we try to
long korrasami achieve it really smile
even less code more much lesser than 85
efficient transport some use a space
with some we work on the transportation
with user space allows us to working on
with walking and Roger said that
comparative analysis of content was
before and put certain logic into beta
GPS well thank you very much outside
world famous course of one year in
tempest there were any failures
associate whole code in the open source
you can look at it if you will find any
security vulnerability god we are going
to be very less than speaking about the
design algorithm we can read look in our
blog well that's it thank you very much
[Applause]
colleagues
it's the Q&A time please ask your
questions specifically thank you very
much for your presentation can you tell
me how do you plan for example dose the
first legitimate request from the proxy
orders plans which are outside of maps
you know it would be mixture between
legitimate and non-legitimate request
for resources my plan just install else
understand McCallister say not HSDPA
check availability of HTTP and filter is
to be able to analyze on
either not not leaves which also had a
referee if for example this is a very
dumb Jesus with Jesus just get with holy
SH then you can easily card it but if
it's a food processor sex then it's much
more difficult we're gonna have a
JavaScript challenge attention release
which by the way have done all machine
learning module which was please working
user space using our usual coffee
interface and otherwise such class or
valid point but means that this project
is that first year we perform two
provisioning for performance in some
cases we can simply give traffic wave
for this video from the second thing we
capital images when we are limit
Mathematica will use it so much means a
quality of service which reduces my
great effect Tai Chi we measure one and
kiba understand that this was not we
don't know commercial and we just reduce
his limit a little bit so that's it I
mean you can use if if there's no
logical error in which I got yep my
favorite is given to those IP addresses
from which with which you have
connection this could lead us to
problems with flow rate that's question
number one and question number two -
Anya is any normal solution - like a
cell in Shaker dokkum attack
Papa do so HCP the fashion will you
criticize
well it should be can easily be solved
perfect and this is summed up already
half and you can measure channel I'm
between chant the size of the chunks and
this is much easier to ago she wouldn't
teach be able take them in Austin be
longer the second about also I didn't
send you a question it's actually but we
are ready assuming you chica cut the
shot BMO
well 153 reduces a slow handshake
problem but otherwise we have Q s 1 2
which gives us vectors for DDoS attacks
question and it has to be sort of order
if something that we can maximally
optimize this handshake another words
and no production solution the
optimization of the
shake right now right now in general you
have say you all have a celebrated
supported Romulan also just emotionally
there are only you and Tommy Otto Carius
Canseco no interest handshakes out there
as well
mine is understand your life fernette
one accelerators which allow you to the
handshake like harmful GMO or some other
carbon based solutions man you know not
a funny show it a little more common in
the viewable by 443 do this do it
through the connection well thank you
very much example specialist under thank
you very much for presentation I will
have a provocative question can you tell
me please
does it make sense because we have our
beautiful glass where the automatic
scaling making us one with the global
load we automatically increase the
number number of service which give this
concept we have CDN it automatically
which can take bigger load load for
shorter period of time which if you will
compare with a solution that you offer
what is more effective
yes we can spend more money and we have
higher capacity here but these DDoS will
stop only bitterlin will stop spending
money just questions well it's an
interesting question but it's a
provocation yes well I will vote was
perfectly Muslim and Amazon package and
I must be clever we also may be
porcelain spy quality for instance you
can buy cheaper instances you don't have
to see when you scary you pay more money
and basically the topic of the
distraction no to block us course on
party to put you down on my EOS speed
about trillions basically stick
expedience also building something and
one of our markets is building C D and E
so if you catch it you don't want you in
a by a public expensive a quick like a
science and let's build my CD else you
can use
source in a year so not to give you
traffic acceleration it would be
so-called idea everything was an example
can be it also a so big at home as I
mentioned before no phantom if install
some f5 there's a host way to Anita
boxes of f5 which do the processing of
filtration yes there are such examples
and also at Amazon we have filtration
load balancer and the Amazon which is
also build and such intellectual
revolution so we promote accessibility
subside solutions in future so you can
view more in a smaller amount of meal if
you're poison inertia vajna
another important thing you got is SSL
certificate license if you want to give
to you to the end what will or you want
to have the extra round trip to your
server to the description of all this
again is a big issue you know but what
now to show you dokie maybe it'll be
cheaper and safer posterity - NCBI you
catalyst to install the solution which
you fully manage and certificate is
totally manageable
I just man one Tesco in your opinion
store in what will be a simpler solution
maybe in terms of time investment if is
if it's a short-term project does a
person have to pay more think about
implementation something more
intellectual two fellows the same opq I
think it depends on the plans of the
features a very good person if he is in
charge of certain website and he doesn't
expect anything you have no other side
like booking calm me miss my sociopath
there's no reason actually to worry
because it probably they will not be
huge DDoS people will probably not
really care about what I walls because
that's a shy Bobby Emma yes yes you grow
out of this thing if you want to grow
like Akamai come again the problem was
because up for WOC every year go by
double digits last year usually five now
they box I have a move to a proxy now
we're talking to the Nanak community 90s
so they particularly every year is
if the decision they have the money but
there is no way to increase the power of
infrastructure embassy campus dozens and
dozens or the machine there are problems
with Ethernet you need to set up those
networks you face the problems of a
different scale instead of like getting
four machines instead of one you see
thank you very much hi thank you very
much for the presentation my question is
what kind of machine learning
technologies did he use to balance the
load ratio it's a linear regression at
the moment in the module that we're
developing for the DDoS I cannot tell
you in more detail this is the
proprietary solution that will work over
GPS my shadow gesture call this and not
this will speed on posters do not we
focus barely doing test tons it has it's
in our infrastructure but so far it's
not something we offer possible civilian
touch so the palladium slide yeah yeah
what we do so Telemachus opera treat you
living this linear relationship so
you're talking about the third layer
right duh no sort of use equation where
yes in the user surveys we have been
working in genius on a zoom transfer so
I see a messages have been cleaned and
they were going through I met with users
where you can actually settle the other
the work with uh powerful logics in AGoT
bottom to judge to be computed earlier
or do it with HTTP compression dear
colleagues unfortunately running out of
time we can ask the questions personally