dear colleagues
you can handy
but no chemistry novel stupid I believe
this will be our first presentation done
to music I'm getting any sound away
could be nauseous a possibly change well
if I were you I wouldn't really put on a
lava body we are risking it
yeah I thought I would be number five in
terms of order of presentation
[Music]
I seem to have misplaced my clicker oh
right okay I am I Elmen be Botev anybody
here insanity yesterday's session on SOC
cold and I will continue the things need
you know I'm a big fan of this stuff
I've been asked to talk about things
that really care about and I want to
tell about thing I go really really into
last but six months so deep learning
okay Kimmy can you hear me well uh okay
I would do it here watch it stubborn Oh
since our audience that usually likes it
to be cross-platform and in different
languages I decided to ask you one which
completely and use nothing but pictures
my presentation so will be talked about
neural networks deep learning machine
learning now you can use them let me
start by signing without according to
some studs by 2035 it's one quarter of
all people who are currently working
will be replaced by robots
so all the professions that can be
formalized you know professions that
involve
looking for answers to some routine
questions well will be replaced with
robots you probably know that it's
already happening in the banking
industry there is for example a bank
branch that is stopped only with virtual
assistants notice single wetware
employee there so those server chill
assistants are prepared to you know
issue loans exception poses and so on
and so forth well the same naturally
will apply to
various institutions where example you
need to submit forms and declarations or
what have you
deep learning is a major subject so much
is happening there but reporters need to
understand these are computing
capabilities over our hardware have gone
up considerably lost 15 years in fact a
lot of processing is now happening on GP
years the Qt technologies are used for
that and the colossal number of cores
GPU Sparky is put to good use
at the same time artificial intelligence
is at the same level of development set
of ABI well the research this
classification we have we know frogs
Octopussy and bees in humans
this means that artificial intelligence
still has to go three notches up to
reach the level of humans and they say
that by 2040 we should expect the rise
of artificial intelligence that will
have human-like app abilities in terms
of understanding continent context which
is great and scary at the same time the
problem of artificial intelligence
covers several fatal first AI is a major
part of programming and mathematics it
seems like a simple picture however
Ratigan's minor out it is not that easy
well we see some cores and some links
between them but programming it all is
not that easy most difficulty is
actually training a system like this you
know the long I'm sorry the full cycle
of training filtration validation takes
a lot of time
ecology Dignitas technology however Big
Data technology helps us overcome those
difficulties now we shall discuss how
some of these difficulties have and
they've been overcome and how we can
already apply artificial intelligence in
our day-to-day operations anybody
recognizes to the screenshots o3 ends
well well ask the same question
yesterday yesterday whether people were
prepared to work with AI at all well you
have it in your pockets
I'm referring to your virtual personal
assistant Siri so why you got from Apple
so what it's worth well there are so
many question Siri can answer yes indeed
I am blogging for Apple when you might
in order to use to reflectively no you
need to understand what's here II can
and cannot handle
let me demonstrate the kind of questions
I can ask Siri your ad see we actually
every date okay I'll ask Siri for
starters to call me a cognitive Mary and
busting the oxide from known I'm gonna
call you that
that's a beautiful name thank you see
Siri do you think it will rain today no
it doesn't look that way should I dress
warm today well it won't be very hard
but well we'll catch a verse about 22
degrees centigrade well it's a very
special spring this time so these are
the two questions I asked Siri every day
and see if I good at answering them my
poem you put money now I can also tell
Siri to remind me to call a particular
contact when I'm in the office and Siri
will do that well this is good because
Siri knows when I arrived in the office
because he has a geolocation
capabilities and she can actually match
a particular name to particular no phone
number so these are the youth cases we
can actually is these are the use cases
a weekend
- these are related in another the
cobalt isolation the human and it's
actually great that you can have a
friendly chat with a virtual assistant
in your pocket let me ask you Seri this
particular questioner
Syria okay google oh that was very funny
he actually has got a sense of humor
within the limits of its understanding
now can you guess what I'm going to be
talking about now raise your hands if he
can right this is the service which I
started paying on a regular basis a
large corporation music I'm referring to
Google Play Music because in these it's
great when you get access to a treasure
trove of new music at a ridiculously
small amount of money
why is God artificial intelligence to do
that well the stuff you're hearing now
you're listening to is this selection of
tracks so I sit on the basis of my
preferences and you know what in 80% of
cases the cloud actually gets it right I
don't know those musicians have never
heard them before and I but the cloud is
good at predicting my life
so this is another AI technology that we
all rely on in selecting music books or
movies you should majima our ownership
with a fellow can follow me manage a
business on another application with a
huge business potential is chat box you
will find a chat boards now in so many
web development engine so you can
actually have these a chat bot sort of a
reminding you that advice is available
you know we've got our people who can
help you whenever you need help there is
a big industry now around programming
those chat boards and I think that chat
box will soon start replacing my front
line people call center operators
because well people who work in line
with a certain script will be the first
ones to be sidelined and voice
recognition technologists today are sort
of a far cry our others canalla JIT will
be our technologist three years ago our
far cry from what we have today it is so
much better than robotisized
the contouring of individual letters a
number of Russian companies are now
doing a lot of research and a lot of
development as far as smart box are
concerns well naturally our western
peers have been doing this all seasons
60s or 70s and and they have like I have
five minutes left
wow that was elegant no problem
what a mother though yes we are testing
you for this with my body I can put up
you know some music that resists tears
as they wanted now imagine you've got
700,000 EMRs Anna should be pretty easy
to predict say diabetes cancer who
rather is diseases for new patients it
does work
although requires a lot of knowledge of
medicine and mathematics and I should
also mention cars you know we keep we
all keep reading about them the
driverless cars again that's artificial
intelligence so because there is so much
they can do like measure distance we can
all it cost me and what about
information security well the reason
applies for AI unit information security
that's a logo of IBM Watson and Watson
is already available in Russia is
actually an application of this adviser
technologist so you can use Watson for
security purposes so again this
technology can be applied to help
frontline people or maybe engineers and
support better decision-making and I
think that this is where the digital era
or the AI ear insecurity style
can I have my Foreman no you don't have
it five more minutes
all right wrap it up the way is a space
seemed able to miss this pebble problem
or the key problem is a robot still
don't have a sense of purpose you know
you keep stuffing an infinite amount of
knowledge into Robert the robot doesn't
have a sense of purpose even if the
robot understands the point of the
knowledge you impart it with it doesn't
have a surface you know you don't have a
purpose of selling anything to you and
like a human we should actually find as
far as we are concerned but imagine now
that AI starts understanding context is
finally understand this is a pyramid of
human values goals objectives and
aspirations so when it finally reaches a
human-like level it will be actually
retained the pre dangerous by Robert
in a maze that several Isis you know a
robot can easily find one exit doesn't
really mean that this will be the exit
that human would prefer and we as humans
would like to understand why but we are
getting a base or that I believe just
like someone know you don't have more
time you know I will be the reigning
weird sheet of paper this will be much
worse your last thought a surgeon today
can save laws
thanks to advice from artificial
intelligence chilly pals the here save
human lives
now imagine that artificial intelligence
gets it's wrong well we remember those
tragic cases with Tesla so imagine that
AI gets it wrong you have a car crash or
you have a medical error well then a
developer assume responsibility that
doctors are relatively comfortable as
himming today and this is my concluding
thoughts humans in this ecosystem should
always remain the very center we
shouldn't rely on new technologists
exclusively we should remember that the
buck stops here the buck stops with us
thank you