well Jule well do what Dave you knew
beyond OWASP top 10 no sorry I'm not
gonna not gonna do this one in French I
apologize I'm from Canada
so I I do speak a little bit of French
but I won't embarrass myself by trying
so we'll do this one in English however
this one's going to be a little bit
quicker because I know that a lot of you
are still trailing back from lunch
because of the stringent Disney security
security just the always a pain isn't it
it's kind of ironic so welcome to this
talk it's called beyond OAuth top 10 and
let's get into it
people stream in the last minute all
right so first up this is me my name is
Aaron Natsu I'm a senior security
researcher at security compass it's a
company that does security testing of
all sorts and I'll be basing a lot of my
work on my research and on the other
work that our consultants and our other
my co-workers do as well so that's where
I come from my background is pretty
diverse in IT I was a software developer
professionally now I just do it for
hobby with a college professor and
application security security consultant
system administrator web developer all
that stuff basically I've seen a lot one
thing to note my twitter account is at
inspector it's pretty easy to remember
it's inspector with a three and an re
follow that because I'm going to be
posting my slides and everything later
on and a little bit more detailed
write-up about this so if you want some
more information
further on be sure to check that out
I'll be giving my email address at the
end so if you want me to send you slides
after you can use that as well so let's
dive in what is this talk about this
talk is about
but more specifically as this laser
pointer falls apart more specifically
it's about their top 10 project so the
OS top 10 project is a project by OAuth
which is the open web application
security project where they list out or
they try to list of the top 10 security
vulnerabilities in web applications so
it's kind of the de facto standard when
it comes to web application security
and it's often what we give developers
when when they ask us what do I do
for security what's the security thing
when I'm developing web applications not
only that when we're doing penetration
testing when you're actually doing
security assessments web applications
typically it's used as a category
categorization scheme as well so you say
this particular vulnerability falls
under you know the cross-site scripting
or it falls under security Mis
configuration which are different
categories of the AUSA top ten however
unfortunately actually going to cover
the next slide which is talk about
coverage as well this details this is
from the sans the sans 2015 state of
application security report basically
shows the top application security
standards or models that organizations
follow as you can see the top ten is by
far the most common one that
organizations follow this is great as a
first step however the problem with this
is that the top ten does not cover
everything it does not even come close
to covering everything when it comes to
web application security so this talk is
about those other vulnerabilities that
aren't covered by the OAuth top ten so
when you're looking at security
vulnerabilities and web applications you
need to be aware that there is way more
than that and there is it's something
you have to continue to learn so well
let's dive into the OWASP top 10 first
so I will cover this briefly but first
one is injection it's basically when you
can pass in user control data or an
attacker control data gets passed to an
interpreter as part of a commander query
so in example this would be sequel
injection second one broken
authentication session management this
is basically where any any issue where
there's like a session ID that can be
guessed or there's you know some way
that it could be you can grab the
session ID through you know a cookie or
whatnot that's broken off that education
and session management there's more to
it than that but anything to do with
authentication session management kind
of falls under there cross-site
scripting most people know about this
but it's where you can an attacker can
inject their own code into a browsers
session and in the context of their
client so usually JavaScript and
insecure direct object reference if you
ever see a website where you can
directly go to a
file or go to a page based on a unique
ID if you can browse to it and there's
no access controls paths are provided on
that
that's called an ID or next with
security miss configuration this was
kind of a bit of a catch-all but if
you're using a product that is not
configured correctly so for example in
the Java Springs framework they have an
option to enable cease or protection if
you disable that explicitly that would
fall under this so those are the first
five next one sensitive data exposure
basically you're not encrypting stuff at
rest or in transit next one you're
missing some kind of access control
around functions so before I talked
about authentication and session
management but this one is if you're
looking at a specific function in an
application so if you're calling out on
a slash admin / delete user that is a
function if you don't have the proper
control around that individual function
then it would fall under this cross-site
request forgery basically allows an
attacker to or an attacker can force a
user to make a request from their
browser and if they're authenticated
already it will pass their session
session token' in a cookie with their
browser request
that's a cross-site request forgery this
one using opponents of known
vulnerabilities basically just patch so
if you're using something that is not up
to date and has security vulnerabilities
that are known falls under this and last
but not least unvalidated redirects and
forwards and this basically is an
example there's be an open redirect so
if you have the option to pass a URL
that you can actually explicitly state
what URL you're sending them to an
attacker can basically send someone
wherever they want them to go so that
could be a MOS web site drive-by
download whatever so those are the off
top ten so that's just a basic overview
of what's covered in there which is a
decent coverage and it's a great place
to start so it's a great place if you
don't know anything about security and
your your web developer you need to know
what are the basic concepts that I need
to understand before building a web
application however as I mentioned
before there really is a lot more than
this because this is trying to cover the
most common ones and not necessarily
everything and not necessarily the most
damaging ones either if they occur and
they're more rare so let's get into the
first one that falls outside of the u.s.
top 10 and that is HTTP parameter
pollution try saying that 10 times fast
it has a cwe as well but basically what
it means on this is more of a being
aware of your underlying web technology
issue than anything and if you were to
see a request so the way this works is
if you send a request and has a
parameter in it somewhere so it can be
in the URL request so it can be actual
in the actual URL as let's say you do
example.com
slash you see the question mark equals
one two three
that's a parameter value so the
parameter name is a and the value is one
two three you can also see it in cookies
you can also see it in a post body so
when you're making a request you can
pass these parameters basically our
variables that you can pass to a web
application to do something different
based on what that variable is however
what you can do is if you send multiple
parameters of the same name but
different values so if I say a equals
one two three and a equals four five six
what happens is different web
technologies handle this differently and
if you're not anticipating how web
technology handles this then it'll
result in something happening in the
application you don't expect and this
can actually result in a security
vulnerability given the right
circumstances and I'll show you some
examples of exactly what that looks like
so remember how I how I mentioned there
were different web technologies that did
handled it differently here's a really
good starter grid that shows you all the
different ways that these common
technologies handle it so if you take a
look at asp.net it actually concatenates
them all the values with commas and then
it also if you look at PHP for example
it takes the last occurrence so it'll
ignore anything except for the last one
that it sees and then I believe Python
it makes it into an array so there's all
different ways that it's handled when
you pass multiple values and multiple
variables into an application with the
same name and if you're not anticipating
this then things can get ugly so let's
start with some exploits the way this is
commonly used is one example is to
actually leverage this confusion to
bypass some kind of access control
restriction to bypass firewalls web
application firewalls and specifically
when you're using it for other attacks
like you're doing a sequel injection if
you were to pass this string in or
passed this request to an application
that's using asp.net for example this
will actually result in this because
remember asp.net concatenates all values
with commas and if it's using microsoft
sequel in the back end which is very
likely because asp.net and microsoft
sequel are both Microsoft products and
they're often used together it will
result in this query and in Microsoft
sequel a comment actually adds a space
as well so this is a valid sequel
command that does a select for name and
password from the users table so this is
a sequel injection
hidden through HTTP parameter pollution
now this may not this exact thing may
not work anymore
I'm sure web application fire will catch
it now but there's all different
variations you can do because web
application firewalls are typically
signature based rather than heuristics
or rather than basically because their
signature based they can't catch
everything so if you find ways to modify
this you can probably get something like
sequel injection you can also do
something like bypassing web application
firewalls like I mentioned before but to
get a to get cross-site scripting so if
you take a look at this string stain
concept as before but this time we're
passing in a script tag with an alert
which can obviously be more damaging if
you do like steal a session token or
something but this is just a basic
example to show how you can hide what
the payload is through HTTP parameter
pollutions so let's see what the next
slide does so that first one would
basically give you a script tag the
second one is another way of bypassing
input validation remember how I said
there was three different places that
you can actually pass parameters in the
request this shows well not only that
you can pass it in three different spots
they are actually handled in a certain
order so if you know that order you can
pass variables in those different spots
to get them to join together at the end
so here's an example this request would
result in if you're using again it put a
asp.net where it concatenates and adds
commas this would result in a equals one
two three four five six so you can see
that the first place it takes the value
from or the variables from is the actual
URL so the URL variable takes first
second takes it from the post body see
if I can get this thing here we go
second one is the post body third one is
the cookies so if you can use them in
that order and you actually understand
the order that it's taken in that's
another way of bypassing info validation
because you can join them together not
just in one spot but across different
areas so again this is a tool is not
only a vulnerability in itself but it's
leverage to bypass often bypass any kind
of access control and get another
vulnerability in or exploit and rather
again here's another way of hiding
cross-site request forgery basically
makes it look like a post action but
it's actually a delete action I won't go
into that new further so here's an
actual example of this being used in the
wild if you take so this is so everyone
here should be are some people should be
familiar with OAuth a lot is basically a
way of authorizing an application to
perform actions on your behalf so with
Twitter if you if you use OAuth to
authorize an application that
application can usually read from your
timeline right to your timeline
basically do everything on your behalf
you're basically giving them permission
to use your account so it's very
dangerous when you have vulnerabilities
in that kind of framework however in
this case the vulnerability was in the
framework it was in the way that Twitter
was handling the authorization so let me
break this down here this is a a NOAA
request to basic to authorize periscope
TV to access your Twitter timeline
because the host is periscope TV and
digits is what Twitter at the time was
using I think they still do it's easily
the domain to do OAuth so what they do
in this case is it looks like periscope
TV is getting access to your Twitter
timeline and to use your Twitter account
however what the what the attacker
actually found and this is on a bug
bounty reports you can see the report
here but what the attacker actually
found was that if they pass the second
host variable with attacker com it
Twitter past periscope TV through and it
saw that that is a valid authorization
that it will allow or at least that this
application will allow however by
passing a second variable through with
the host set to something different in
this case attacker com
it would actually authorize attacker.com
but look like it was authorizing
periscope TV so someone who clicked this
link was would think that ok periscope
tot TV is is going to be using my
Twitter that's fine I use periscope I
want it to easily you know post things
to my Twitter timeline however what
really happens is attacker comm gets
your OAuth token and make him then do
everything on your account instead so
this is quickly patched but this is a
perfect example of HTTP parameter
pollution used in the wild which is
really interesting so I've showed you
some some ways that it could be
exploited I can show you with
vulnerability is how do you actually
test for it so let's go through this
really the way to test for this is is
the best way is to just kind of test
your applications as you use them so for
example if you get to your request with
parameters in it in your application try
changing the values of values try
passing a second parameter with the same
name different values see what happens
see what you get on the other end
remember that you can put into those
different spots in the request so see
what happens if you put it in either the
URL request the post body or the cookies
you can actually automate this as well
with burp suite and cruder this is
another example but you can pass in a
second parameter with different name it
intruder just makes it really easy to
automate stuff like this as well so you
can do it really quickly across all your
application so you want to look in the
following sources I think I get to
another point later that I won't talk
about so here's some common sources
you're going to find parameters passed
in form fields pagination so that's like
page equals one page equals two things
like that
I haven't page identifiers so if you can
access a page where the page is ID is
one and that's the admin page if you can
only access it as I'm and try accessing
a regular page with like an ID of one
two three four and then add another
parameter value with page equals one and
see if you can get to that second one or
switch it around so yes this is exactly
what I'm talking about and there's a way
you can actually intercept all post
requests and parameters but not just
post requests now
burp suite makes it really easy because
you can there's a setting to just
intercept all requests that have
parameters so that could be get request
post request it doesn't matter I mean
probably put requests maybe
and other ones but the most common ones
are going to be getting post requests so
so burps we make this makes it super
easy to actually do so try one time when
your browse with your application set
this on setup a burp instance setup the
proxy and then just enable this this
option and make sure to set it the last
option to that it's in your scope
it's your only testing your own
application but try seeing what
parameters you're seeing coming through
and try changing things as they go so
how do you actually defend against this
so let's take a look quickly through
here really the the key thing is dynamic
testing actually test your application
to see how it handles this because like
I said different application
technologies handle parameters
differently so the only way to really
know as these technologies change and
evolve and new ones get added because I
don't even think node was on that list
try to understand like test it in your
in your environment to see how it
handles it I take a look through source
code find where parameters are accepted
pretty easy validate how your last
handles is you will have application
firewall because if it's handling things
differently and passing things things
through to your application that you're
not expecting you may have tested your
application thoroughly but if you put
something in front of it that's
modifying those requests or stripping
out parameters if there's duplicate ones
whatever you need to know how that
reacts in your environment so you can
adjust appropriately and just general
good practice output encoding so if
someone does manage to get get through
your applications access control or get
through any kind of defense against this
this just makes it so that the ensuing
attack is neutered so you know they
can't get through with across that
scripting they can't execute JavaScript
if it's encoded properly again there's
ways around this but that's just general
good practice and best case be as
explicit as possible so strip duplicate
parameters or explicitly choose the last
one whatever it's up to you if you're
designing the application be as explicit
as possible always good practice so
here's some more further reading again
I'm going to post this afterwards so you
can check it out then overly permissive
regular expressions so I'm shorter on
time so I'm not going to go in depth
here but basically what this is is
regular expressions can be able their
source of vulnerabilities because
they're often you
is for access control and input
validation so if you're trusting your
regular expression that you wrote to
catch everything you're probably in for
a world of hurt because it won't so when
they're not tuned well it can result in
you know authorization bypasses it can
result in anomalies in your application
you didn't expect so here's a here's a
comics not really much to do with overly
for them permissive reg X's but that
thought you'd enjoy it
everyone likes xkcd so let's move on to
some common gotchas again I'll run
through this pretty quickly
make sure you caught the right character
case when you're using regular
expressions because it's by default is
case sensitive so check that you can
also use flash eye as a modifier to make
it insensitive weird boundaries
basically when you're looking at a word
you want to only accept to the point
where you're looking for so you don't
want to accept in your application admin
and administrative assistant probably
aren't the same role so use word
boundaries to delineate them which is
usually /b do you really need to use a
star so this is the wildcard that
basically accepts 0 or any if it's if
you're using an or condition especially
this is dangerous because if it's in the
first condition it will usually match
almost anything and then always allow
someone through so here's an example
this is a or condition where the first
match is always going to be true because
it's either zero digits or any number of
digits or really you know so it'll match
any of these things okay
so just be aware when you're going to be
using the star character special
characters special characters if you
actually need to special characters in
regular expressions use a backslash to
negate them and don't try to parse HTML
with regular expressions a is painful
and it sucks as a developer because it's
always changing and there's just so many
edge cases just ask cloud player just
because if you're trying to do this to
to parse things you're probably going to
miss something there's a lot of really
good libraries for this so don't try to
do it on your own just don't exploit so
let's look at some regular expression
exploits
so this was a case where what so you can
actually see that this is a thing as a
bug Danny what's basic multi line abuse
to remote code execution so they
actually got remote code execution do
this bla so if you take a look at this
regular expression it's supposed to
match for anything basically anything
dot R PT but the flaw here so it'll look
something like this will match the flaw
here is that because it's got this
character here there's two plus first
off its got the slash s character slash
s not only includes spaces but it's also
tabs line breaks and form feeds line
breaks can be used in malicious ways
when it's passed into a command so look
at this if you pass this line break
right here with the percent zero a the
next command execute will be cat SC
password which is not good on a Linux
system and then this so this would
actually match because it actually hits
be anything matches our PT however
because of this multi-line modifier here
the way that PHP handles multi-line is
that it not only checks on multiple
lines but it will look until it'll
accept and take anything the goal line
rather than the whole string that
matches and puts it into your output so
something like this would also work
because it takes this this matches but
it continues for the rest of the line
because of the multi-line modifier so
this will be completely valid it'll pass
this into the command in the backend it
accepts the file but then it also
executed this this actual command to
output your password file in Linux not
good
oh and interesting thing about this
vulnerability is actually a default on
Ruby on Rails for a while so by default
is do multi lines you could actually
pass something like this into a into
almost anything that was taking a
regular expression and if it was passing
it back to a back-end command then it
would execute a script or reflect back
or you could basically enter anything as
long as you use the line breaks and then
would execute that command so as long as
it was found somewhere and there's some
kind of valid match you could continue
it with the with the line break and it
would also use that it's pretty
interesting
so this left a bunch of websites exposed
at the time they're using Ruby on Rails
saying it was like WordPress tumblr
github bunch of them
next one blacklist bypass so this is
pretty simple essentially reading a
blacklist that this came out to this but
if you tried to do slash title it was
caught by the blacklist so for those of
you that aren't familiar there's two
concepts one is a block that's one is a
whitelist blacklist matches on things
that you specify whitelist basically
says sorry blacklist is usually used to
say don't allow these specific things
that you specify whitelist is usually
used in Reverse where it says only allow
these things that you specify which
means it catches a lot more things in it
so in this case we're doing a blacklist
so they were specifically looking for
the flash title in the input so you
couldn't then continue on and pass in
HTML or JavaScript and all you had to do
really to bypass this was something like
this where you would pass in extra this
looks kind of convoluted because of all
the URL encoding but basically what it
is is it's it would result in this so
bypassing and not just a flash title you
can also pass in an ID and then a bunch
of other things that doesn't expect that
are valid HTML because it wasn't
checking for them in the regular
expression and the blacklist for the
regular expression it got through and
then you got code execution or crossing
scripting rather so how do you actually
test for this really the thing that
comes to testing I'll kind of sum it up
right now it's most effective with with
doing white box testing because if
you're looking at if you're looking at
regular expressions they're hard to
parse if you don't see them so you can
try fuzzing things but really the most
effective way is to look in the source
code so you can use any of these tools
to check your regular expressions
they're really really good any of these
doesn't matter it's just kind of a
sanity check dynamically test them with
some fuzzy input so fuzzing is the
practice of sending in particularly
incorrect input to see what happens and
see how it reacts there's a really good
list here you look at sec lists they
have a whole section on fuzzing I would
highly recommend checking this
by the way because they have a whole
bunch of polyglots basically a bunch of
strings you can use in your testing for
cross-site scripting sequel injection
things like this so test with those in
your applications see what happens and
then try passing in line breaks as well
so how do you defend against this really
all of these solutions are just kind of
around best programmer programming
practices with testing sprinkled in so
keep it simple perform transformations
and stages again I'm going to rush
through this a little bit test a lot and
always try to have like a set of fresh
eyes on it because it gets really tiring
looking at regular expressions for a
long period of time I know I worked on
an application that was solely regular
expressions before taking data passing
data interpreting data it was a pain so
get another set of eyes to look at it
and it really helps because sometimes
you just get lost in the forest and use
proving regular expressions so here's
one that'll help you this is a IPV this
finds an ipv4 address so just really
best practices around using regular
expressions is be modular test it as
much as you can and have someone else
look at it and again use best practices
whenever possible which is similes oh
and really good practice everywhere
whitelist not blacklist here's some
sources and further reading if you want
to learn more regular expressions
there's actually a lot to it and I'm
sure if you're doing bug bounty hunting
if you are a security researcher if
you're a if you're developer there's a
lot to be found in regular expressions
because a lot of people don't understand
them and a lot of people don't want to
understand them so if you get good at
this I'm sure there's a lot of things
that you can find so here's some good
useful sources last but not least server
side request forgery
so SS RF because I'm not going to say
the forward the whole time SS RF is
basically when an attacker can force the
server to perform a request on their
behalf so instead of if I were to send a
request normally to a location and it's
blocked I can pass it to another server
it basically makes a server act on your
behalf which is kind of cool it has some
ability
cool for the attacker bad for the
defender but that's always the case
isn't it so how is this RF actually used
often it's used to bypass firewalls so
when you can force an application to
make essentially the application becomes
your proxy when you can force an
application to make a request in your
behalf
if there's a firewall blocking your IP
or any IP except for that server because
it's a trusted server then you can then
bypass those firewalls it's pretty easy
but not only that it gets more dangerous
when that server has has the internal
network interface exposed so most web
servers are really any server that are
supposed to the internet a lot of them
have some kind of way back into the
inside the internal network you probably
don't need that but if you have some
kind of weight inside the internal
network then you can then reach Network
a network and computers that aren't
accessible from anywhere on the internet
because of the stall owner ability so it
opens up a lot of vulnerabilities a lot
of further exposure to your internal
environment and it's really cool because
this allows when you find a necessary
foul nur ability because of the nature
of it it turns an application attack
into a network attack so it allows you
to essentially turn that host into a
port scanning bond or a bot on your
behalf and because of that is useful for
enumeration reconnaissance so you can
then perform a whole bunch of scans out
on the internet on the internal network
without your IP being exposed and I
think that's the next point yes
so because the destination actually sees
only the server's address not your own
attackers love this because then this is
another way of them hiding their own
source address so it's really handy to
attackers and this is how it's often
introduced so saint sop Aesop is stands
for same origin policy
it's a browser defense that is present
in really all major browsers that
prevents site a for example from
reaching out making a request to site B
and getting getting any getting some
content back unless there's unless you
have something set up which I will talk
about later to actually do this properly
developers find this bothersome because
sometimes they want to go to site B and
get content to return it back so one way
that they will get around this is by
potentially essentially turning their
server into a HTTP client for them to
make the request behind the scenes and
then return it back to the user in the
front end and I'll show you how this can
get dangerous later
actually I'll tell you right now it
actually can be leveraged to get
cross-site scripting by over the return
content so what that means is when if an
attacker can force a server to make a
request to their own server and then
return that content back if that content
is their own HTML that they've design
its scripted including JavaScript then
they just got control of your browser
because of that return content so it's a
way of chaining it's a way of using this
to get another vulnerability or another
exploit as well which is kind of cool so
let's look at some exploits so this
one's really interesting and for all of
you that are running on AWS pay
particular attention because you will
probably learn something that you may
not have known or you may know it and it
was just novel to me
so attack step what happened was the
attacker found this URL funny enough if
you ever see URL equals in the browser
or in the URL try passing in other URLs
and see what comes back because that can
be an open to redirect as well but
anyways they found this and they found
that it only loads images so you can see
it's a media preview function so that
kind of makes sense but it will only
return back images based on whatever URL
you pass into that parameter however if
you just passed it it's just looking for
dot PNG or another extension like that
which kind of relates back to the last
vulnerability we talked about where it
was doing a regular expression for a
specific instance and not checking other
things like content type so in this case
it was it was just looking for dot PNG
or something like that and by passing in
this parameter dot PNG it does nothing
you can just return back this was the
attackers website saya org and I left it
in there just kind of it was it was
there attack so I left it anyways so
they can return back their entire web
site just from this not even in an
iframe it returns back the whole web
site which gives you a lot of power
because then you could do something like
this
and return back your own cross-site
scripting payload that you want this is
what they did but not only that they
didn't stop here and and hey look an
overly permissive regular expression
they didn't stop here
after that they realized that because it
was hosted on AWS
there is a particular end point that if
you can reach that end point from a
trusted source gives you a lot of
information bonus points if you already
have that in your head and you know
exactly what I'm about to say so did you
know if you query this IP from an aw
instant AWS instance it will give you
back it's got it's basically has a REST
API where you can query a ton of
information about the server because
it's only only accessible from that
server itself it's only a local one it's
only internal behind it but because he
is the attacker was able to make that
server make any request on his behalf
including to that internal address he
was able to access this so for example
they did this and they got pretty much
everything so some of the metadata is
here I'm going to iterate through some
of them ami ID reservation ID local host
name public host name public keys open
SSH keys credential city credentials by
role security groups user data and on
and on and on there's a lot in there and
they basically found all of it
so here's a guy that you're going to
want to note down if you're running a to
the US this is some of the functions
that you can actually call from that at
that endpoint it's helpful it's really
valuable if you want to script out some
kind of information about especially if
you're in like a DevOps works workspace
where you need to get more information
about the at the endpoint or the the
instance itself this is gonna be really
handy for you let's move on Google Diggs
Google Google actually had a tool box
where they allowed you to do a whole
bunch of stuff you can just do on your
client anyways but do it with Google
because it's Google Apps so they have
this spot where was a they could you
could use a tool called Digg Digg is a
command it's usually built with most
Linux distros I don't even this windows
have it I don't I don't use my nose as
much so Digg basically it allows you to
make your request or music tool to check
a particular domain with a name server
that you provide and it will return back
the DNS information for that name server
or sorry for that actual ad domain so
they gave you a web interface to do this
because why not
Google Apps and it returns back the
information the interesting thing though
if you modify the request and change
that name server to one to seven zero
zero one that's the local host and
Google happen to be running a DNS server
on that web application so what they did
was the attacker could then just keep
making a bunch of requests to this to
this Google Apps this Google app and
then with that internal name server
specified they enumerated pretty much
all of Google's internal namespace they
could see every single instance every
domain every host name inside of Google
and fun fact about this Google is
actually running a minecraft server
inside turn internal network big
surprised so how do you actually test
for server side request forgery first
off if you actually see a URL provided
in a request try changing it and again
you can script this out as well with
with burp I change it to a few of the
following things one try google.com or
another remote URL see if it loads that
or your own domain see if it loads that
another one is the loopback address like
they did in that on that last example of
Google try seeing what else is running
on that local server because if you can
make requests on that server it's very
likely that there's other services
running on that server because most
people don't have the money to do a
dedicated instance for every single
service they're running so it's very
possible you're going to find something
else on that local server try local IP
see if you can get behind the server to
the local address or to the local
address space try a different protocol
this is interesting I will come back to
this in a little bit but basically when
you're in your browser if you look at
the URL most of them start with HTTP or
HTTPS but you can actually make requests
with other URL forms such as like file
SSH FTP File in particular will return
back a local file the contents of a
local file in your browser so it can be
particularly dangerous if you can if it
you is an attack or an attacker can
actually use your server to query the
local files there you can imagine
there's probably some files you don't
want them to see
same with SSH and FTP there's a lot
there just the different protocol URLs
is something that a lot of mobile
applications use as well so you'll see
like custom
some URL schemes for like for Spotify
for Twitter a number of other ones where
they little be like I don't know Spotify
: flash flash something and it will call
out their mobile application so there
may be other things you can do there if
you can find like a mobile app server
just thing it a lot try different port
similarly to if there's other services
running on the same box if you try to
report you can find basically enumerate
every service that's running on that or
if you find another domain or another IP
that's that's reachable from that server
then you can then find maybe there's
other services other than just web
services running so you can enumerate it
basically turns this server into nmap
for you but a much more dumbed down
version of nmap and like I said Bert
sweet and true to make this really
really easy if you sort by response
sizes it'll be a lot easier to kind of
catch which things are positive hits for
you continued if you have not going to
dive in this is gonna take too long but
if you have XML external entities
vulnera SEC's poit
then basically it'll allow if you can
make a request to an external URL that's
also server side request forgery you can
check this this one out for more
information on that after it's just a
way of using multiple exploits together
oh yes this is a key point here so if
you don't have your own server set up
that you're just just having there just
to listen for requests for dis
vulnerability you can use burps
collaborator servers as well because
there they will just provide your free
servers that will monitor for requests
to them with unique information and then
it will return back in your burp
instance anytime hears back from it even
if it's like way down the line let's see
if like the you get a vulnerability
where it's making a request out and it
comes back at the logs or something you
can still get a little er then so burbs
collaborator servers are really useful I
don't work for burp suite I promise they
just make really good tools so how do
you actually defend against herbicide
request forgery so I mentioned same
origin policy remember that it exists
for a reason I don't try to use JSON P
or server-side workaround so the
server-side workaround is basically what
I just described about making requests
with your server returning the content
back to the client from there however
you can use something called JSON P
which is having chase
with padding I came over anyways juice
um P what it does is basically it
exploits a situation in your browser
where your browser can make a request to
another domain for a javascript file
maybe not for other resources but for
JavaScript files they're allowed and so
what this other server will do is if you
call a javascript file at a particular
particular like you pass in like a
specific location it will return back a
specific function for you so it's a way
of calling a function a dynamic function
on another server and returning it back
to you in a more roundabout way don't do
it just like if you can avoid it it will
lead to things like server side request
forgery instead use cross-origin request
sharing course this was made just for
this reason so if you are able to
control server domain a.com and b.com
then you can set up a course rule which
will allow from vidcom you will allow a
comm to make a request for javascript
CSS whatever so you can actually use
cores to legitimately request resources
from another domain and bring it back in
the client so use that and whitelist
allow domains of protocols whitelist /
blacklist is important I'm going to show
you why in the next set of slides in
particular in PHP this is important but
when you're looking at domains of
protocols remember I said you can use
more than just HTTP when you're thinking
about what your whitelisting also think
about what kind of protocols your
whitelist saying if you only need to
make a request to http which is likely
or HTTP try weight lifting that as well
specifically and to prevent either ear
don't have an internal interface on your
your server your web server or whatever
servers expose the internet or have some
kind of firewall rules severely limiting
what can access from the server to the
internal network so that if an attacker
does get a necessary exploit they then
cannot enumerate and access your entire
internal network which would otherwise
be safe safely hidden from the dangerous
internet and so why
so I mentioned whitelisting protocols I
you get an idea why but in practice you
may think oh you know you can't do this
with most technologies well that's not
true because we have PHP so PHP actually
supports the
protocol URLs by default there's a lot
you can find more information there so
if you're using PHP be very especially
careful with protocol URLs that are
being used data seems and here's some
more
further reading for you I did a blog
post on I was doing a bunch of open
source security reviews recently and
found one where as basically a design
level SS RF vulnerability so if you
check this out I did a holdat write-up
on it this will give you more
information so let's review all off top
10 2013 now I'm not going to read this
to you you can read here's the top 5
there's the next 5 looking beyond the
OWASP top 10 we have HTTP parameter
pollution remember if you pass multiple
parameters with the same name different
values see what happens it could result
in anomalies because different web
application servers and technologies
handle it differently overly permissive
regular expression check your reg axes
because if you're using it for axis
control or input validation which is
very likely you've got to make sure that
it's tuned properly otherwise it can
allow for easy bypasses and server side
request forgery be sure when you're
making requests on behalf of users that
you whitelist as much as possible and
and really try not to allow access the
internal network because server side
request forgery basically allows an
attacker to make a request anywhere they
want through your vulnerable machine so
there's actually a release candidate for
a loss top 10 2017 because the last one
was 2013 there's a few changes made to
it right now it's still in public
comments so it's not like it's not firm
but that should be available in roughly
July or August because public comments
are closed the end of June so soon and
here's what the changes are basically
they added a a for broken access control
which which combines unsecure direct
object references and mixed function
level access control so it's a for now
means broken access control attackers
can bypass authentication and
authorization controls 87 is incident
attack protection this one's kind of
this one's got a lot of press negative
press really because people thought that
it shouldn't really fall into it it's
kind of a catch-all basically what a 7
insufficient attack
section is saying is that developers
should incorporate an automatic
detection logging responding and even
blocking exploit attempts I don't know
if it's necessarily a vulnerability so
I'm going to leave it up to you to
decide whether this should be in there
add your comments whatever look it up
online there's a lot of commentary on it
that's a seven and the last one eight
ten under protected EAP is basically
means that I protect your API S which is
weird because all the other off top the
off sub ten in the past has really
applied to API is just as well as web
applications so I don't understand where
they were going with this but moral of
the story
all of these vulnerabilities I talked
about still apply even to the new
version of the oo stop ten so final
message that I'm going to leave you with
is this the OAuth top ten really is a
good start for developers for someone
learnt new to security web application
security if they want to learn more but
there is so much more than just the off
top ten and it's really really important
that as a security professional is an
advocate for this you should always be
learning because there is constantly
going to be new things coming out there
could easily be another five
vulnerability types that I talked about
so moral of the story understand that
it's a good start but you should always
be learning more and I think this is why
we're all here we're all here because we
want to learn more about security keep
that up because that is what drives the
security industry that's what makes
that's what makes us good at protecting
our applications so you should always be
able trying to learn more and to help
you out with that I provided a few
resources you can use to keep learning
these are just some things I found
recently too that I use more often to
actually keep up to date on security
vulnerabilities and exploits one is the
Activity Feed so it's a bug bounty
platform they basically publish a lot of
bugs binary reports Twitter is a really
good place to this is where I get most
of my News to be completely honest if
you're following the right people you
can usually catch security issues and
vulnerabilities and exploits before
anyone else does if your the problem
with out is you have to kind of curate
who you're following to get that
information so my advice to you would be
to look at who is speaking at this
conference speaking at other conferences
follow them see what they follow see who
they like see who they retweet and
eventually you'll just start to build up
here who where you get the information
from
read it I don't really use this all at
often but it's especially beginner
friendly so if you're looking for
network security especially kind of
content check that out and hacker one
again they have a zero daily newsletter
which just recently came out I found
it's actually pretty useful so the point
here really is is that if it's a good
start but there's so much more and if
you need help understanding where to
start from or where to continue or you
need other resources or you have any
questions around the things that I've
talked about please feel free to reach
out I'm I'm always open I'm pretty
pretty happy to help
and if I can't help you then I can
always point you to the right person
that can so I think we're all in this
together we're all trying to learn more
and we want to advance the security
industry by learning more and
understanding that there is so much out
there that we still need to know so with
that I want to say thank you very much
and I appreciate you coming out
you