so before we get started
thank hacking pairs and systems for this
privilege it's a lot of fun and I love
coming here doing this so let's go ahead
and get started the internet of
vulnerabilities my name is Darrell
Hyland I work for rapid7
I am the research lead for IOT I've been
doing that for about a year-and-a-half
working on various research projects
helping with assessments around IOT and
that's just a general history of where
I'm at and what I do so let's go ahead
and get started great right there ok ok
ok so let's go ahead and get started so
when we get into IOT research and start
looking at i/o T almost always there's
this heavy focus on the hardware side of
it but we want to look at the overall
security of all of IOT or a particular
products IOT ecosystem we need to focus
on more than just the hardware for it to
be effective and the reason is as so
many of these components are interactive
if one fails outside of the hardware it
could lead to compromise or control the
system can also lead up to compromise of
various PII data control data over the
internet mobile applications and that's
kind of what makes up this ecosystem
this is a model that I try to focus on
anytime we're doing research or
assessing IOT and the fact that we have
three pieces specifically when you're
talking about consumer base IOT we have
the mobile the cloud the hardware and of
course the network communication which
is used to move commands and data back
and forth and it's important to focus on
all of these because each one of them
affects the overall security model of
that particular product when we get into
things other than consumer based there
may not be a mobile application aspect
to it but often there's some kind of
command and control structure which
could exist on a server consists on some
other kind of a control system a SCADA
system as an example human interface
Ace device and that also works within
this whole ecosystem so coming out of
there over the last year we've kind of
developed you know kind of an eight step
approach when we're looking at IOT
technology we get into the likely
functional evaluation and that literally
means I set up the equipment and I use
it figure out how it works why it works
if it's something I carry on me I carry
it on me for days or weeks just to get
used to how that technology works if it
happens to be some kind of home
automation solution I turn my house into
the lab and this is how I approach
looking at i/o t from there we get into
device recon we literally do historical
research on the technology or the sub
components or products are there open
source pieces within this are their
products white labeled as part of this
it's not necessarily their product if
some came out of China they put their
signature on it now it's part of their
IOT ecosystem so we do that recon that
recon would also looking at FCC of
information so you pull the FCC ID off
specific learned stuff in the US and
manufactured for the US and with that
information you can go to the FCC side
and you can get interesting information
you can get a complete breakdown images
of the internal of these devices you can
get RF testing results so you get a lot
of information about the RF on a few
rare occasions you can often come across
some schematics but generally that's
what we do we look at the all the device
all the information that we can farm on
that device and then we go off and we
focus on all the sub components that I
mentioned of that ecosystem we look at
the cloud and Web API as we look at the
mobile applications the control
applications we look at the network we
look at the physical embedded hardware
we break it down look at it what is it
made up of what are all the pieces does
it have USBs if I open it up can I find
landing points where I can hook up je
tags you arts so we map out the entire
piece of the hardware and then we do
physical attacks on the device what
level of access can we get to the device
can we get through it through the
Ethernet can we get to it through the
USB can we tack it by tapping actually
into the device itself
and of course then we also do analysis
of any RF communication comes out a
device often most IOT technologies have
various sub components as part of that
ecosystem that are communicated with
various protocols ZigBee z-wave
Bluetooth Bluetooth Low Energy and the
list kind of goes on and on and on of
all the different protocols you can
actually encounter even some proprietary
protocols so in this case here we try to
analyze those we set up like a hacker RF
we capture the data we try to decode it
we try to figure out what makes up the
pieces and parts of this we try to use
replay attacks if we can actually decode
it can we write programs to mimic it and
actually jet and Jack various attacks
into the device so these are kind of the
eight steps considered an effective
methodology for examining IOT and the
big thing is during this whole process
we look at the interaction between the
components an example if I enter a
command on the mobile application I want
to look at the effects into the cloud I
want to look to the effects from the
cloud to the device I want to look at
the effects from there to the sub
components that may be communicated via
RF and I want to do this
generally all at the same time so we
analyze the system and the results as we
go through each one of these pieces and
it helps us get in a very effective view
of the overall security of a device
besides vulnerabilities it also helps us
to make recommendations on various
improvements for security or
implementation methods around security
to make the product more secure so now I
want to get into IOT hacking because
that's what's fun so over the last year
I've worked on four general products now
as a research lead this is not the only
thing I do all day long
everyone thinks that Daryl sets at his
home and plays all day long with IOT
that is what I want to do but in the
real world this is a part of what I do
the other parts obviously working with
customers and manufacturers and various
government entities may be involved in
IOT and be in that voice within rapid7
for IOT but moving into this these are
the four projects that
worked on automated lighting solution
which will talk about Biello ble
tracking Bluetooth Low Energy tracking
devices those little devices that you
like hang on your keychains so you lose
your keys you can actually find your
keys
I actually got four of them for
different products that were on the
market at that time and started playing
with us see but what's the implication
because I saw people wearing these
things all the time and I was wondering
you know what is the is there any
security impact
what would the risk potentially be do
these things leak information could I
abuse them so we kind of looked it that
way and then the telepresence robot
robot which is really cool I don't know
if you ever seen these it's like a iPad
on a Segway they're kind of freaky
looking you know you can drive them
around the office and you can meet
various people and have these
face-to-face conversations well it
turned out rapid7 actually had one of
these because I started talking about
them with my boss he goes you know I've
seen those wandering around the office
so it took me about three or four months
but I managed to get my hands on one I
haven't given it back yet I've had it
for like six months and no one's asked
for it so I'll probably keep it and use
it to do something else evil I don't
know we'll see and then I looked at a
GPS panic button and this was kind of
interesting and the sad thing about this
none of these vulnerabilities have been
fixed on the GPS tracking device or BS
panic button we'll get into the story
deeper but basically his devices were
being recommended or issued by the
Colombian government to protect people
from potentially high-risk people from
potentially being compromised by
kidnapping and certain entities came to
us and asked us could we can we look at
this just as a research product and let
them know what kind of issues there were
so we'll talk about that in a little bit
too so let's kind of dig into this also
I came into Paris on Monday I still
haven't seen hide or hair my luggage
which is really bad unfortunately if
people know me and see me present before
I love live demos unfortunately about
$1,000 worth of equipment used in the
live demos is still in that luggage
somewhere in Paris so
so we had to compensate but it still
should be good good material so some of
the issues we see with automated
Lighting's that I looked at and these
are common some of these are very common
issues that we see on Io t technology
unencrypted storage of data and that's a
big one
poor encryption you know they're not
doing you know we know SSL is not the
end-all be-all but you know it's a
simple baseline that most products
should communicate in and finding in
cases where that's not happening
unaffiliated control ability to inject
commands into the IOT technology and
affect it without using the primary
control systems or having any kind of
security and of course we actually found
some embedded web vulnerabilities
actually on the devices the embedded
devices that have web servers they have
the same problems that every other web
server on the face of the earth
potentially has so we looked at a couple
of those so let's go ahead and dig into
that so the first one I was looking at
this this device up here the back side
of this is a asraam lie defy Sylvania
light a physis Tamizh for lighting
automation your home this one here
happens to be the home version I also
looked at the enterprise version which
we'll talk about also some of the issues
so looking at the mobile applications
I found out once you authenticate this
device and configure it what it does is
it set up to connect to your home Wi-Fi
but on the mobile application we found
out afterwards of a store and that
depreciated key in the SSID and yeah
that's that that's not mine at home I
use the test unit just in case you're
like taking pictures thinking you're
going to get date and HI and get free
internet but as you can see it actually
restoring this data it was actually
stored on a pee list this happened to be
iOS device the problem also exists it
also on the Android device the thing to
think about this is this is only used
when this device is initially set up
once it's set up there's absolutely no
reason for this data to be stored but
yet it was still being stored
and I see this over and over and over
and now if it's going to be stored it
needs to be stored encrypted it was
needed for future use in this case it
was not and like I said this is a very
common issue that I find on probably
more than 50% of the technology IOT
research that I do the mobile
applications aren't properly secured and
data that needs to be secured so what's
that mean well if you lose this device
and someone gets it in phones and you
know iPhones and and you know tablets
are lost all the time it's common to
lose this so if you lose the device
think about all the IOT or integration
you have on that device and if you're
not sure I would recommend changing all
your passwords it doesn't mean the
person getting is going to do this but
the potentials there so there's no sense
in take an unnecessary risk now that all
of my luggage is missing one of those
devices in there happen to be a Android
tablet containing a lot of stuff like
this so I know what I'll be doing when I
get home if I don't get it back at the
recorrect on my lab stuff so moving from
there we also looked at these devices
had Wi-Fi capability like I said when
you set the devices up they fire up a
Wi-Fi access point you connect to that
Wi-Fi connection you configure it to
make it connect to your home Wi-Fi
generally how it works and it turns out
I was interested in the keys the
passwords that are hard-coded
which is common on the Wi-Fi aspect to
these devices when this is the home as
you see it's ten characters uppercase
lowercase and numbers not the most
greatest address base but not horrible
you know it's not absolutely horrible
and then I start looking at the
enterprise the pro version this is a
unit that's not used in homes this is
used in places like this or office
buildings this product is actually for
sale in Germany so where it came out of
they actually had it shipped to me from
Germany for testing so when I first
looked at this unlike its eight
characters that in itself kind of caught
my attention
I notice it wasn't very verbose I didn't
have uppercase lowercase and numbers
showing up I ended up having the
manufacturer send me another one and I
looked at the password on it and it
finally dawned on me
they were only using hex characters 0
through 9 a through F that was it we
were able to fire up this device if
anyone was connected to it
throw me off capture the reconnection
and crack it in less than about two
hours and that was using a crappy GPU
not even a good one it took only two
hours
the interesting thing on these devices
from an attack perspective typically
these devices when you're actually
connected to your home Wi-Fi these
access points go away in this case it
does not you have to configure it and
this also has Ethernet so this can
easily be turned into an access point so
now you have a device potentially in a
business or organization that if it
isn't completely configured right and
these services are not shut off
it can easily be attacked and gain
access in turn you know game over
the other interesting thing that I see
on a number of devices when they when
you configure them up and they attach to
your home Wi-Fi that access or the
access point on it goes away but if you
send a million disconnects to the actual
home Wi-Fi connection for this
particular device when it disconnects
and can't phone home it instantly goes
into configuration mode bringing up that
access point giving you the ability to
literally connect into it and modify it
or do other attacks if you know the
password ten characters a little more
complex a character hex not so so we
were looking at the the home or the the
pro version this is the Enterprise
version and like I said when we go
through this we run it through all this
tests we use it like it should be used
so I go on there and you could log on to
this device via the web interface and
has a username and password which you
can change so it's not the default one
so that's probably good
thing but after going onto the system I
went into the security logs and in the
security logs I noticed my logon name
was there and of course what's the first
thing I think is what can I inject into
this and yes it was vulnerable to a
persistent cross-site scripting in the
security logs in this case this is
actually a laughing skull if anyone's
seen some of the stuff I do I like to
inject the Laughing skull from the movie
Independence Day in the systems when I
find this so the actual security logs
were vulnerable to a persistent
cross-site scripting making it possible
to carry out any number of attacks via
this method going on to that same
premise when we look at the actual Wi-Fi
configuration the device it shows
near-field earned near presence Wi-Fi
devices other SSIDs in the general area
and of course if anyone's seen the
research paper I wrote on SSID and
injection attacks this is another thing
I quickly check out we actually have a
video on that so I like videos
so this is logged on to the pro version
and if we come over to the Wi-Fi
configuration page we can see Wi-Fi
access points regional ones actually
showing up so we fire up our own access
point and give it its own little special
SSID not realizing this is a excellent
out-of-band injection into devices
that's often never tested by security
testers they see this stuff and go on
because they think it's not part of the
system I'm testing but it's an outside
out-of-band injection so a little bit of
humor we were able to inject a flash
into it
but we got to think about it from a
further security standpoint we no need
to just quickly get hung up on the fact
that all he just rickrolled them that's
all it was this is another persistent
attack the people logged on to this
system would be management administrator
on the device they would often have
administrative rights on their network
also this is something to critically
think about and then the fact that I can
execute
code on your device makes it possible to
carry out a number attacks in my
research paper is probably the research
I did a while back was probably one of
the best ones best examples that I put
out there it was in an Aruba wireless
access point in the rubra it actually
had rogue access point detection and it
was vulnerable to this so I could
literally set up a rogue access point
against an Aruba Wireless LAN controller
and when they looked at the screen it
would actually inject code it actually
created a root level ID password on the
device and then it would offload the
running config to a third party web
server or third-party ftp server
so this attacks is really critical some
of our
me water from over there start to lose
my voice
thank you so moving from there on the
home system as I mentioned I don't know
if I mentioned it but there is a a local
functionality so anytime we're testing a
device we were testing the entire
ecosystem not just the hardware what
happens when the cloud goes away on a
device so you have home automation if
the internet goes down can you no longer
control the heating air conditioning
ventilation the Lighting's in your house
in most cases the answer is no you still
can the devices if you have your mobile
app attached to your local network it's
going to go into local mode the question
is when it drops in the local mode is
there any security so in this case there
was not there was no security in 4,000
we actually mapped out the actual
command structure and in this case here
if this device was on a network that you
were on this port was open you could
actually inject commands in and
reconfigure the demo that I was going to
do that I don't have the hardware we
were actually going to make this device
jump from one Wi-Fi access system to
another Wi-Fi access system and it's
easily done by as a simple Perl script
you just send a single command to it
instantly it changes so got to get into
a little hardware not too much we'll get
a little bit here so on the home so on
the home device pop it open the first
thing I see in here is a couple landing
pads so it was like what do we think
these are you know and I'm hoping
they're like a simple you are connection
and they turned out to be so the next
thing we want to do is let's go ahead
and find some connectors these were
going connectors for connecting to it
that's just to give you an idea of the
size is really small was like one
millimeter pitch on these so then we go
ahead and solder them in place and it
turns out this side over here is
actually had a UART
to the main processor this one had a you
are too
the ZigBee z100 processor that was on
there so I actually it was kind of funny
I showed this to a friend of mine he's
like about my age I showed him the
device he's looking and he's like how in
the world did you saw to that on there
he says I can't even see it I cheat I
get a microscope and I do quite a bit
under a microscope
you know surface mount devices and all
that stuff there's a lot of things I'd
like to do the devices when I'm tearing
them down so having that ability to
solder at that level I think is critical
to being able to do some interesting
work so at that point we can plug into
it and this is a standard SheiKra that
does the JTAG spi and UART and I just
wanted to show real quick the actual
data so watch this see if you see
anything interesting there is some
interesting stuff it flows by we connect
off to the SheiKra we run screen and
then we power up the device the device
powers up hope this is the right video
there goes this device didn't have an
operating system on it I just had to
code and this gave you some level of
control over it one of the controls
there was some up let's keep watching we
see anything good there yet don't tell
me it's not good sure he may have
already flowed bought anyone seen
anything good go Wester well there was
actually a track ID in an actual
password it would buy if he didn't catch
it and that was used to authenticate
this device to the actual manufacturers
for confirming firmware yeah there we go
so the device the product key and
national password
I had several command structures they're
fairly simple maybe five or six command
you can actually do on the device this
is all you could do we pulled the
firmware off the device firmware came
down encrypted
but once it landed on the device so we
tried reading it straight off the device
failed on that so we disordered the ship
standard socket chip was able to
actually pull the firmware off of it and
look through the firmware again we
didn't find anything great other than
kind of what you already seen flow by
and that's the great thing about these
these logs these debug logs these are
great if you can get access to them
because now I can monitor the device no
matter what I'm doing to it so I can
send a tax to it I can watch how
commands go through the whole system
hitting this device and that way you can
evaluate the overall security of the
device
okay so now we move on to the
telepresence robot 15 minutes left gosh
I've been talking that long so it's time
for me to talk a little quicker so real
quick on the telepresence robot this is
what the device looks like I had it
shipped into my house now
I would love to done some serious
hardware hacking on this but taking a
hacksaw to a $3,500 device was kind of
like probably not good you know they
were nice to send it to me the last
thing I want to do is send it back to
them in a paper bag so what we did here
we found some interesting things
insecure cloudy ap is part of that
ecosystem information leakage and
bluetooth pairing it turned out you
think this iPad that's exactly what it
is it is nothing but an iPad you buy
this unit and then you go buy the iPad
put the iPad on it install their
software it's how it works
it has a cable running up here plugging
into it the cable is only use for power
no communication goes through it the
head actually pairs with Bluetooth Low
Energy
there is no in the pairing hair there is
no validation of the pairing process it
can only take one pairing but if
somebody in the office decides to shut
the iPad off it becomes an instant
target for anyone nearby you can
download the software throw it up on
your machine connect to the Bluetooth
and take over the device of course you
can't see where you're going but you can
still make a hell of a mess it doesn't
go super fast which is probably a good
thing or I would have destroyed it by
now when I first got it I ran it
straight into a wall in the house when I
powered it up so moving from there we
start looking at the cloud api's so it
turned out there was no authentication
and we had this offset what I did was
you put a high number in there for an
offset and it'll tell you what the max
offset it is what this is used is
tracking all of the session data for
every robot that is ever connected to
the system
ever so you basically take the limit
right here and set it to a high number
with the upper level I offset and dump
all the data out of the system and this
was all the session communication data I
blocked this stuff out because this is
potentially data that could be used to
take over a robot
and I don't want you taking over my
robot needs to be left alone sit in the
corner being nice at my house
I don't need it waking up some night
driving around so we found another one
here and this is with the installation
key when you set up a device it
registers an installation key you can re
register a device multiple times and get
different users is based on how what how
the robots logged in so in this case
here we can do the same thing with
offsets but in this case here we can
actually pull latitude and longitude so
we can pull all the offsets and then we
can use that to pull all the latitude
longitude for every robot on the face of
the earth probably not a good thing this
has been patched also this one here way
worst but somewhat mitigated turns out
and this has been fixed also turns out
the robot if you are can manage middle
the robot to the cloud or you can
actually get physical access to the
robot you can get this thing that's
called a robot key with the robot key no
authentication which everything I've
showed you is no authentication and you
send the robot key to the cloud it dumps
a list of every users that can remote
control that robot and a session driver
token that always stays valid that
driver tokens nothing but the web
management session token' every
connection to the robot giving you the
ability to completely take over the
robot over the Internet so disgruntled
employee you know he walks over the
robot you can basically pull this data
off of it now he can control every
control that robot no matter where he
goes until they D register the robot so
some interesting findings there so
moving on to the Bluetooth Low Energy
dongles this was kind of this kind of
interesting we found some interesting
vulnerabilities the demo I was going to
do is with a live device so but I don't
have a live device but I did film some
of it
I'm hoping everyone can see this okay
yes I too bad this happens to be my
Android tablet and what we're going to
do is as this is running we kind of
think about it if I'm a bad person I
come in here I can detect using you know
information on local devices this is in
our connect show me all the devices that
are in that location and I can find one
of these tokens in this case here we got
several different brands but the one I'm
talking about is the TKR which is the
tracker Bravo we can get information
down here like these IDs these IDs is
the actual tracker ID in Reverse it's
also that's the tracker ID it's the MAC
address in Reverse this is used to track
the device that identifies advice via
GPS so from here we're able to actually
connect to it so someone's in a room you
can fire that up you can identify the
device of the room you can connect to it
with your device because there's no
pairing and at that point it's
connecting we can get a certain amount
of information get information in this
case here we're looking at where is it
the one I'm gonna look at immediate
alert so now I can identify who's
actually holding that tracker by looking
for the person is trying not to look
like an idiot because the alarm would
often the tracker should be easy to spot
in here so I can set the alarms off in
these devices remotely so no alert high
alert or you can drain the battery on
them so it's pretty impactful so okay
now I get set I can identify device in a
crowd I can set off the alarm identify
the person that has it I identify the
tracker ID where it all kind of comes to
a head is when we get to the cloud API
is we take that tracker ID we pulled and
now I can get your latitude and
longitude so the ability to figure out
who you are figure out the device you
have gather your GPS coordinates
no matter where you're at as long as it
in close proximity to your phone because
your phones what's being used as a Tico
system to send up the GPS coordinates
now if you lose the device anyone else
walking by with that same application
will detect that device and send up the
GPS coordinates and that how you use
known as cloud or crowd GPS and it's a
common thing for these tokens okay so
now we get into the panic button and it
turns out that like I said the Colombian
government was actually issuing these
devices so the AP Sochi ated Press who
had people using these devices came in
and asked me if we would take a look at
it and it's like cool this thought it'd
be fairly interesting so we found poor
design like horrible horrible design
okay
non SSL communication GPS data being
sent up to the cloud without any
authentication the application running
inside had some bounced check issues was
it exploitable but we did identify it we
pointed it out and then of course their
web real time web interface total fail
so the first one to look at here is you
know like I said that whole recon part
and using the device the device uses SMS
messaging for configuration okay so you
can use SMS messages to configure it to
call any number to do all these
different features but what happens is
you can also set a password so you set a
password to protect it it's a pin number
okay so now people can pull information
or configure it with SMS messages but
they actually built into the product
that you can use reset which will set it
back to the factory without a password
so if this device is being used by
somebody trying to be protective or
being kidnapped by Colombian drug lords
and you have their phone number you just
send them an SMS message that the device
is rendered useless so pretty bad but it
shows that whole that whole recon and
testing the device from all those eight
pieces I was talking about
we found a vulnerability or a design
error just by reading the manual the
next one was if there is a password
devices could identify this device
setting at the end of the phone number
so if I had a phone number and I wanted
to know if one of these devices were
there could identify it
well the reboot command like they
mentioned before it could be done
remotely without a password
it's not true you actually had have a
password to set a reboot so what I did
was we pulled the firmware and I went
through the firmware and we found a
unimplemented command that was a reboot
exclamation point all it did was return
to form ed error in that case there you
did not have to have a password so you
can basically do like SMS war dialing so
if you know there's a range of these
devices by people in a certain country
in a certain city you could easily do
war dialing or SMS dialing and wait for
responses back and identify whether that
device is potentially one of these
devices and then the balance check this
was based on looking at information we
dumped the firmware or we dumped the
flash on the flash we've seen all the
configuration settings but I noticed the
spacing between all the configuration
commands seemed to be fairly narrow and
I wasn't sure where there's bound checks
so what we did here is this is command a
one is used to set the phone number for
the first phone number of dials so in
this case here we just made it longer
and when we run it it runs through okay
but as you see we ended up overriding
the second phone number that needs to be
written now I when I start testing for
this I was just like shooting from the
hip and freaking bricked one of the
devices so it overrode something but I
didn't think it was close enough to the
code so I'm not sure what got corrupted
in there didn't really get a chance to
follow up or see if it was could be
leveraged in any way I don't think it
was I just think I just screwed up the
whole structure associated where it was
reading to identify how to proceed in
the application okay and when we get
into the cloud part of this the web
service the real-time web server as part
of this this is sending data up from
this device to the cloud
we turned out that you see they have a
user ID that's basically every device
has been issued every one it says an
account there's no authentication to
this so I post this all tracker data I
get the e Mei number for the cell device
and I also get the that's just the Mei
number well with that data you could do
a lot more so with it I'm sorry
IME I always get that pass backwards but
with that there you could actually
poison turns out that the real-time
tracking system goes over port 50 50 50
50 and yet it's not encrypted so I
constructed a program to actually be
able to inject this data up there and
alter the GPS coordinates of the device
so making it possible to move it
somewhere so my test device which was
dayton ohio instantly jumped to moscow
by a being able to poison this data to
affect the actual data here so i'm not
sure if I have any more time left we
have time for questions so I hope you
guys liked that or found that
interesting
[Applause]
any questions yes yes sir
BG ABG a chips I have app to admit I
find to be okay so how do you
effectively root a device with BGA
processors on board it really comes down
to tracking out all the connectors on
there are there any connectors all the
wires coming off the BGA obviously I
can't hook into it
it's a BGA and if I disorder it's
impossible to do the ball grid arrays
back on unless you're like really good
and have the equipment and I don't so
often in that case is I'll flip the
device over and I have one at home right
now I'm actually working on it turns out
looks like everything's passed clear
through the board so that I scrape off
all the finish and I tap in freaking 50
million wires on the device and and and
then I pull down the the data sheets now
data sheets may give me a general idea
of layout so there's certain things I
can test on there to maybe get
orientation properly how it came to the
board and I literally try to map out the
structure of the BGA on the backside and
at that point I will attempt to test
into it is there any exposed J tags zero
are debug is have any s P is is there a
you are in there and then we'll go
through that process and try to test for
all those am i successful a number of
times in cases with those it gets real
frustrating real time-consuming but
that's the typical approach that I take
and like I said I got one at home I'm
doing that with right now so thank you
very much I appreciate you coming
you