good afternoon and a very warm welcome
to the fixed
munich cyber security conference
i greatly appreciate you're here today
the weather is so nice outside that you
could have done something different
i was hoping for bad weather but
typically during this conference we have
very nice weather
it has a downside because after two
hours we run out of oxygen
um but at the same time i must say we
always choose this location here
the buyer shohoff because tomorrow our
big brother the security conference
starts here
and we always feel we should stay close
to that
and we should make it a routine to have
the cyber security conference
before because it's very important
and it takes more and more space also in
the main conference
for good reason but let me not just
welcome all of you
but let me also welcome a very special
guest here
mr sheena's the vice president of the eu
commission
in charge of security and i'm not sure
whether they looked up the homepage of
the commission
very recently what you will find
is a very well and nicely described
vision of each commissioner
and all the duties
and responsibilities are described very
well
and when you read mr sheena's
vision and idea is promoting
our european way of life that includes
a security union and probably we're
going to hear
something after the after i speak from
you
so it's a great honor to have you here
thank you very much for coming
we also expect another guest to have a
little bit flight problems
uh mr jose angel guria the
secretary general of the oecd he will
come sometime
soon and he will speak later as well and
it's also a great pleasure to have the
oecd here because the ocd
is aiming for better policies for better
life
and i think nowadays it's not just the
sound objective
i think it's needed to make our life
better because the digital society
offers a lot of opportunities but it
also requires that we have the right
policies
behind and last but not least
i would like to welcome mr yeshuhida
nakayama
state secretary of the foreign ministry
of japan thank you very much for
for coming
so in that sense i would like to also
welcome you as
dear fellow colleagues dear fellow
colleagues
i'm speaking to all of you now
independent of hierarchy independent
from where you are
because we all have one and the same
object objective
that is to make this world a little bit
a better place
in particular with all the changes we
actually foresee
often driven through technology and
often driven through political change
that is the thing we have in common here
that's the reason why we are here that's
the reason why we want to have debates
that's the reason i want to hear
opinions new issues old issues but also
proposals on what we can do
in actually to pro promote that
objective
for that we also need to have capable
moderators they sit in front of me here
it's oliver roloffs oliver
is a
as a person with long experience in
politics and business and communication
you were involved in the main conference
for over 15 years so you know what's
going on
so we have a demanding
let's say audience here you have to do a
good job right tyson that's the same for
you
so we have a second moderator um tyson
barker
you are a managing partner you are a
deputy director and fellow of the aspen
institute in
in in berlin for three years now you
have speciality which is digitalization
and transatlantic relations which we all
observe very closely so i hope you bring
some input here too
so you will run the show later thank you
for doing that and thank you for being
here
so before we move on with the main part
let me quickly set the scene
for this conference here today we choose
the title
fail safe act brave building
a secure and brazilian digital society
for thousands of years
tangible things
assets have been the driving force
in our societies and that actually
drove the societies which were living in
protected by walls by borders
physically and the digital world really
has changed that
the technical innovation we saw over the
last three decades
created something which is virtual
values not just physical values
and these virtual values are not really
tangible
but we all go with the digital
infrastructures and with our digital
identities
into this world and that world
has not the same protection as the
physical world
it has a different kind of protection
and the vulnerabilities in this world
changes very fast
and as it changes very fast we have to
think hey what are the root causes
why it changes fast and b what we can do
that's what we hope for to find
input here today let me outline a few
reasons why i believe
it will accelerate even faster if you
look at the last decade from 2010 to
we saw a lot of changes i think
the time will never be as slow
as it has been the decade to 2030 will
even accelerate
just look at the global spend for
innovation
it is over 2 000 billion
2 trillion spent in innovation in r d
580 billion dollars come from the united
states
in the meantime 520 from china
followed by japan 180.
germany is the only country from the eu
under the top five with run
round about 120. so
having united states with 580 having
china with 520
europe altogether 400
actually it makes good reason that
europe cooperates
it makes good reason that europe
cooperates
and the technological race is on because
it's not just the race on having the
best technology
but it's also a race on who is having
the best technology
that makes it a bit complicated yeah
so if that span goes on and it increases
year by year that is one of the root
causes why it gets faster
a second point to look at is of how
policies are being made today
and what we see is that policy making
mr sheen as we just spoke about it very
briefly
of course can often only react it's very
difficult to be proactive in policy
making
but if the world is technology fueled
if it is not undermined with
technological competence
and input how can we be confident
that we see the consequences and the
benefit of certain technologies as we
move ahead
so we must enrich policy making with
technological
input i think otherwise we maybe fail
and if you think that a bit further down
the line
then we still are the same people
like 30 years back we still live in the
same governments we still live in the
same
infrastructures the rules are often
still the same
so how can we make sure that we actually
catch up with today's world
and that we make the policies which are
technology
in the technology driven world so that
it fits
to today's society so that we can fill
the objective we have built a secure and
resilient
digital world i would hope to see a lot
of input here today
because that's what we're here for i
think the audience is perfect for that i
like the small setup with content-rich
discussions
not the big shows here we have
content-rich discussions
so that we all contribute here today to
a better
resilient and secure digital world
i wish you all a good conference here
today
and i wish you good input and now i
would like to ask
our special guest of honor mr sheena's
to take the floor thank you very much
for being here
have a good conference