hi everyone welcome to my presentation
today here at nahang khan 2022 my name
is shabam shah and today i'll be
presenting about finding zero days in
enterprise software i'm the co-founder
and cto of asset note an attack service
management platform we often find
vulnerabilities in enterprise software
for our customers as well as generally
for the wider security of software
inventors
the first piece of software i'll be
talking about today is hcl digital
experience it's also known as ibm
websphere portal it's a piece of
software that's written in java and runs
on ibm websphere server
it's used by enterprises
and is a very flexible content
management system there's around four
and a half thousand instances on the
internet and it's self-hosted as i said
earlier on ibm websphere server
it's pretty it's got pretty widespread
usage amongst the fortune 500 and other
companies running bug bounties
so how do you get a copy of it
so it's not that difficult actually
whenever you're looking for enterprise
software one of the key things i can
tell you to do
is to look for it on
public services like docker hub docker
hub often has copies of enterprise
software that
either someone has pushed as they were
doing some sort of development or even
officially has been pushed by the
company
in this scenario ibm have pushed a
version of websphere portal at some
stage that we can download locally and
start running on our instance
this isn't always the case these days a
lot of enterprise software is locked up
behind sales processes and sometimes it
can be quite tricky to get access to
enterprise software
thankfully for websphere it wasn't too
difficult and we're able to get a local
instance running quite quickly
the next thing is
decompiling the jar files now this isn't
the same for every enterprise software
but we realized that websphere portal is
written in java and ultimately it's
deployed in a similar way to how you
deploy web applications through
something like tomcat except on web app
and websphere application server so what
we do is we ultimately find the location
of all the jar files and we
compress them into a tar file we get
that onto our local system and then we
use our favorite decompiler to decompile
all the jar files in this scenario i use
presion decompiler but ultimately you
can use anything you want like jdcli or
jd gui
this will end up with a bunch of source
code that you can start auditing
this is an easy way to get to a point
where you can start auditing source code
immediately but before you start
auditing the source code what i would
recommend is mapping out the attack
surface
so to find the attack surface
we can run this command which will
return all of the different mappings for
this application
obviously this is specific to this
application
because it's in uh it's using websphere
application server and it's mapped in
this way
each enterprise application is going to
have a different way of doing routing
and mapping and you need to determine
that before you can find what to run to
get the exact details you're looking for
in this scenario we can see that there's
quite a few mappings available and
there's a lot of attack surface for us
to go through
but as we started to progress down this
list what we ended up finding was this
really interesting file
called
proxy.config.xml
and it was really surprising because
when we found this file uh we saw that
there are a number of paths that were
defined and there were also three urls
that were whitelisted
www.ibm.com
www.03.ibm.com and redbooks.ibm.com
immediately this this sparked our
curiosity we thought to ourselves okay
this seems like there's some sort of
outbound proxy here
and it seems like these three urls are
whitelisted
some of the questions that we thought
about at the time were is this one
protected by authentication and two
is there any sort of uh
support for something like redirects
because even if there's a policy url
here if it supports redirects we might
be able to bypass these policies
one of the hard things about mapping
things when it comes from looking at the
mappings that we found earlier back to
endpoints on the system on the
application
is that that is the difficult part
sometimes knowing that there's a mapping
available isn't enough you need to be
able to know where you can hit the
application to reach that mapping and
that piece of code
so this one was pretty easy it was um it
was deployed under wps so we found that
those wps proxy my proxy common proxy
and so on
but the the proxy config file says that
we can only access ibm.com and
redbooks.ibm.com how are we going to
turn this into a full read ssrf
well this is where the magic happens
we realized that
redbooks.ibm.com runs a software called
lotus domino to deliver content to users
if we achieved a url redirect on this
subdomain we'll be able to achieve
ssrf on arbitrary hosts and after
researching the software lotus domino we
realized that there was some pretty old
documentation around the sign out
process
this sign up process allowed you to
redirect people to arbitrary locations
after signing out
so looking at this documentation we can
see that there's this simple command
that you this is there's a simple thing
you can slap onto a url which lets you
lets you redirect to arbitrary locations
in this example you can see question
mark log out and redirect to equals
http.www.sales.com for example
so it's actually quite straightforward
to understand that there is this
redirect gadget in lotus domino and we
can combine all of these elements
together to achieve full read ssrf
so you can see here
that we can reach redbooks.ibm.com
and we can add the
the query parameter logout and the other
query parameter redirect to with our
host and we can see the response from
this web server it's redirecting to the
location we're looking for
so ultimately we now have a redirect
gadget on one of the whitelisted hosts
that this proxy config has in its
policies
we can we can
pull all of this together and ultimately
achieve full read ssrf
so if we put it all together this is
what our final payload looks like slash
wps proxy
redbooks.ibm.com and then we've got the
log out and redirect two parameters at
the end and ultimately we're now
proxying to arbitrary locations on
behalf of the web server using this
redirect gadget
so this one's pretty exciting because
it's not just a straight ssrf we're
actually using a redirect gadget to
finally get to our location and this is
why often open redirects are more
valuable than most people think in
scenarios like server-side request
forgery and open redirect could be the
difference between a successful
exploitation of the ssrf versus
unsuccessful exploitation
the next thing we did was variant
hunting now this is a common technique
that vulnerability researchers do when
they detect a vulnerability they look
for all the different variants in the
code base that may also have that
vulnerability
so we ran the command this find command
to look at all the other proxy config
files on the system we found a number of
hits and we went through all of these
systematically
you can see here that i've highlighted
these two hits in particular that's
because these hits actually were the
most impactful in my opinion
if you take a look at the policy
um it allows you to proxy to any url
using all of these different methods
this is even worse than the initial ssrf
we found in websphere that we just went
through with lotus
domino
so it's really like a super ssrf um you
can hit this endpoint and ultimately you
can
send any request method and you can have
any body you can have any headers or you
can have these headers as well
and ultimately you can proxy to anywhere
on the internal network
using this
exploit
so variant hunting is very powerful and
something that i highly recommend you do
when you are auditing enterprise web
applications
once you find a single vulnerability try
and find all the different patterns and
locations in the code base that mimic
that vulnerability or that behavior
because you'll often find that a mistake
made once in code is made elsewhere as
well or in config
so you can see here that this ssrf works
really well we don't even need a
redirect gadget we can hit any endpoint
any url and we can also have any method
that we want in any body as well so it's
basically a super ssrf in websphere
portal
the next thing is uh i did look for more
variants and i found that there were
some other locations in the code that
you could
reach this proxy functionality
so these are some examples of how else
you could reach this proxy functionality
so really what it meant that you know
waff rules weren't really that effective
because there's so many ways to
ultimately reach the proxying
functionality
it was also possible to use the redirect
gadget in these two scenarios to achieve
full read ssrf as well
here's just an example of it running
locally
and
another variant that we found was inside
uh the quicker document picker
and they had an internal proxy as well
uh and looking at the internal proxy um
and also the common proxy is very
straightforward
you could just hit these two endpoints
and also proxy to any url any location
one with the read write gadget and one
without the redirect gadget
this is again a full read ssrf pre-auth
but it's limited to get requests
um
once we found the ssrf we wanted to see
if we could chain the vulnerability to
gain further impact and one of the
things we realized with ibm websphere
portal is that it has this software
called knowledge center that's running
on port 9043
we thought that throughout ssrf we can
access this port and hence this
functionality and inside the web.xml
file we saw this interesting route
called
jsonp callback filter which was that oh
sorry it was yeah it that's the filter
it was called api slash web feed which
we thought could have further
vulnerabilities inside
so naturally we downloaded the knowledge
center wall file and we decompiled it
and looked at it in our source code
looked at the source code and we found
that it's downloading a arbitrary url
and then it's performing
xml
parsing on that on the contents of that
url
and we thought okay this looks amazing
this looks like we can probably get um
xxe through this um through this gadget
but what we ultimately found is we tried
it on a bug bounty target and we just
got
it just returned forbidden and it didn't
work even though we could hit the
knowledge center port and the url and
everything it just returned forbidden so
it was a fail
but we had to work out why it was a
failure because everything in the code
made it seem as if it should work
and we realized that once we downloaded
an even newer version of this software
that this was basically patched
we downloaded a different docker image
that seemed to be a newer version of
websphere and it was effectively patched
because um you can see here it has a
and add deprecated um and essentially
returns a forbidden exception instead of
actually doing anything
the big lesson we learned here was make
sure you have the latest copy of code
before testing your vulnerabilities
this is often something that you don't
have access to in this scenario
we only had sparse access to websphere
and the copies on docker hub and things
like that so
i guess
if you can always make sure you have the
latest copy if you are looking at
targets in the wild but in many
scenarios i understand that it's not
going to be possible
we had another attempt at xxe so we
tried um
uh crafting a payload like this and uh
basics defouring it and then we tried
hitting uh this resource proxy portlet
which takes in xml
as a base64
and we thought maybe we can get xxe this
way and this was obviously found by
auditing the source code and what we
found was ultimately
it was well protected against xxe
none of the dcds were being resolved and
we weren't able to successfully achieve
xxe
now one of the things is i'm talking
about the failures here just so that you
understand that
source code auditing isn't always
glamorous and you're not always going to
find amazing vulnerabilities there's
going to be a lot of failures along the
way there's going to be a lot of time
spent on testing vulnerabilities even
when they might not account or they
might not amount to real
impact
we can see here that this failure at xxc
we can see that it's just not resolving
any of the dtds and digging further into
the source code we can see that they've
explicitly
disabled any of the dtd handling or the
resolvers
for external entities so ultimately it
was something that they had already
patched and it wasn't vulnerable to xxe
but yeah talking about failures is
extremely valuable
this sort of stuff happens all the time
on your source code auditing so don't
feel discouraged just keep on going and
find more vulnerabilities spend more
time on your target you will find
something eventually
one of the other vulnerabilities that we
found in websphere portal was post orth
rce via directory traversal so there's
this functionality to upload script
applications and it allows you to upload
zip files that can contain html css and
javascript
what's really interesting about this is
that even though it's post
authentication once someone does get
authentication it's likely that they can
get command execution through this
technique
so you can find it at this location that
i've got in this slide if you're looking
for it inside websphere
and essentially you click this actions
and import and you can import a zip file
what we found was we can simply
upload a zip file which has directory
traversal
inside it and it will let us upload
files to the local system at any
location
so we we can use the software called
evil arc which will construct zip files
with directory traversal and we can
create a file which has the following
contents here
this will lead to rce on reboot which
you know isn't too impactful but if you
are looking at this as an attack chain
this could be useful in the attack chain
um you might be wondering why this
technique works like why can you put
this file in this location and why will
it lead to command execution
so essentially there's this amazing um
full disclosure um exploit details um
where they talk about this technique
where for whatever reason if you can
write this file to etc sysconfig network
scripts
and you do a reboot um you can
ultimately execute arbitrary commands
based on the name attribute
um so anything after the first blank
space in the name attribute is executed
as root um or as whatever users are
executing this
so this is an interesting rce vector
something to remember that if you do
find a way to upload arbitrary files to
the system but you can't really get
command execution this is one of the
possible techniques to get command
execution by arbitrary file upload like
for example let's say you can't upload a
shell for whatever reason
and you can't nothing's really writable
except some directories if you can write
to the etc sysconfig network scripts
directory you can likely get a shell
anyways if on reboot at least
here are some references around
websphere and some of the things that i
was looking at when i was auditing
websphere i found all of these very
useful if you do look at this software
these might be useful to you as well
and lastly here's the exploit write up
for websphere you can find a lot more
details about this a lot more details
about the exact source code and things
like that in this exploit write-up in
the journey that that we had to go
through in order to find these
vulnerabilities
the next software that uh we're gonna
look into is solarwinds web help desk
and we're gonna see how we can hack solo
in web help desk which is another
enterprise software that's used by a lot
of large companies
so what is solarwinds web help desk well
it's essentially a central ticketing
management system free enterprise it
connects with solarwinds oreon it's used
by medium to large enterprises schools
government there's around 2000 instances
of it on the internet
one of the things i want to quickly talk
about is removing the stigma from huge
code bases
so solomon's have this helpdesk product
that is used by large enterprises and
the code base is absolutely huge there's
spring web objects traditional servlets
all sorts of different things going on
and initially when you look at this it
can be really daunting to take a look at
because of the scope however with some
intelligent analysis of sources and
syncs it starts to get easier my number
one advice when it comes to auditing
complex software is trying to map out as
much of the attack surface as possible
in forms of sources and syncs and then
do your auditing after you understand
this
one of the first things we found when
looking through the source code was this
uh concept of hard-coded credentials we
saw that there was some
there was some javascript that had these
hardcoded credentials in there and
immediately we started searching the
entire code base for these hard-coded
credentials
we found that there's actually
production hardcoded credentials as well
and you can see them being defined as
constants in the source code here you
can see that there's a login and a
password that's defined here
well the first thing we thought about
was what does this let us access these
credentials
seem to be a big part of the spring web
app app embedded into the software and
there seems to be this really
interesting controller which these
credentials let us access over here
surprisingly solarwinds were exposing
endpoints that let you run arbitrary
hibernate queries and hibernate talks
directly to the database based off
models explicitly defined in java
so what we found was these credentials
let us access a spring controller which
let us execute arbitrary hibernate
queries
so this is what the spring controller
looked like you can see that the
endpoint was slash raw hql
and it took in an arbitrary
string
that it would execute as a result
so the get string hql result would then
create a query using that string and it
would get the results
once we put it all together you can see
that the the
post request
actually needed a few things for it to
work
and we found this through the trial and
error but essentially it needed a csrf
token it needed the basic auth
credentials that we found earlier
it needed the csrf token again in the
cookie and very important it needed the
content type being text plain
and lastly in the post request the full
hibernate query
this took a really long time to figure
out all of these different elements
working backwards
but
one of the things that i was actually
stuck on was the content type and it
took me forever to realize that tech
slash plane was what was needed to
exploit this issue
but ultimately it responded with an
email address and a password hash which
is crazy there was an endpoint that let
you execute arbitrary hqr queries inside
solarwinds web help desk
and this was the vulnerability
what's not shown in this presentation
and something that i've kind of really
glossed over is the amount of time that
was spent mapping out sources and sinks
understanding the authentication flow
for some of the spring routes and how a
hard-coded credential is enabled with
this vulnerability
numerous failed attempts at exploiting
certain vulnerability classes in other
areas of the code the vast amount of
code in this code base causing auditing
fatigue and also shouting f yeah after
discovering the pre-orth critical bug so
these are all things that um during the
process of source code auditing you will
often come across and
don't be discouraged if it takes you a
long time to find these critical pre-ord
vulnerabilities but this is just an
example of finding a vulnerability in a
soft piece of software that's used by a
lot of enterprises
the impact of this was that an
unauthenticated user could run arbitrary
sql against solarwinds web help desk's
internal database and it would allow
attackers to obtain usernames and
passwords hash password hashes from the
database it also allowed attackers to
insert arbitrary data into the database
so an alternative vector is just
replacing the password hash with one
you've generated yourself or adding a
new user
but it is limited to hibernate sql
queries and these hibernate sql queries
will only work if there are models
defined in java for the most part almost
every table had a model defined in java
for hibernate so on you could access
almost any table and run almost any
query you wanted to
the exploit write-up for this issue can
be found here you can learn a little bit
more about the mitigations that were in
place that prevented mass exploitation
as well as some of the things that we
worked out when diving deeper into the
issue
as much as this presentation doesn't go
into the really deep
analysis of the source code you will
find that this exploit write up does and
it should be a really valuable resource
when you're trying to understand how
these vulnerabilities worked or how we
were able to discover these
vulnerabilities in the first place
another favorite piece of software that
i hacked uh last year was called
sitecore experience platform
and um this was one of my favorite
vulnerabilities that i found in the last
year just because of
one how widespread sitecore is used in
enterprises and also how simple the
vulnerability ended up being when it
comes to exploitation
and the impact it does lead to command
execution so it was one of my most
impactful bugs that i found as well
what is sitecore experience platform
well it's essentially a cms that's used
by large enterprises government banks
fortune 500 companies you can build a
lot of digital experiences through
sitecore's experience platform and
there's around 10 000 instances or so of
this software running on the internet
exposed externally it's a handful of bug
bounty programs that were affected by
discovering bugs in the software and
ultimately we were able to make a lot of
money through bug bounties through this
software but not only that a lot of our
customers that asset also ran this
software which was the most important
thing for us in securing them
so note on giving up
and this is something that
you know you'll often feel like doing uh
when you're auditing large code bases is
um you know throughout your source code
auditing journey um you'll like want to
give up all the time in fact when i was
auditing sitecore's experience platform
i almost gave up like five times it was
so tempting to walk away and not spend
any more time auditing this software
ultimately not auditing the software
costs nothing and it's something that's
really easy to do just walking away and
moving on to something else but you have
to be really motivated to find these
software vulnerabilities through source
code auditing and when the code base is
very large and complex this can be
pretty difficult but my best advice is
to take a lot of breaks so every time
you feel fatigued take another break
come back to the source code when you're
feeling better and this strategy has
worked really well for me
um what i will find is you know i'll be
auditing a piece of software and it
might take me a week two weeks before i
find critical vulnerabilities
and
honestly it's really tempting to just
want to give up and the key is
persistence the key is confidence that
you're going to find something and just
keeping at it and keep going without
giving up
so this is my note on giving up and when
it comes to source code auditing it's
particularly important um things will
get better over time you will understand
the code base better over time so just
don't give up keep on moving forward
the first step in auditing sitecore was
obtaining its source code now i obtained
the source code by looking at github
repos um where people had posted the
site called webroot to a github repo
and i was able to find one that was
relatively recent and looked like it was
really popular version of sitecore so i
downloaded it all to my local system and
i decompiled all the dll files i then
opened up the sitecore source code the
decompile dlls as well as the site
called deployment folder side by side in
sublime text this was pivotal to
understand the attack surface by looking
at the c-sharp source code and also
looking at the web route and
understanding what was exposed
again we have to map out the attack
surface like we do with any enterprise
software and you know sitecore is
complex it has a lot of attack surface
and a lot of this attack surface is
defined in the config files located in
the app underscore config folder
but sitecore also has a lot of aspx and
ashx files in the web root as well and
inside the web.config file we find the
following line which essentially says
that this virtual folder
is being mapped in the web.config file
and anything within this virtual folder
can be executed
so what we can see here on the left is
just the basic outline of the shell
folder and what was included inside that
folder
and we can see that
you know there's quite a few different
aspx files and folders and things like
that but really the journey in mapping
out the attack surface is not over yet
we still don't know what's
pre-authentication and what's post
authentication this becomes a little bit
clearer clearer as we iterate through
some of these files and read the source
code to see whether or not there are
authentication requirements but we still
need to do that in in this journey
discovering the vulnerable endpoint was
pretty interesting because inside one of
these folders i found a file which was
called report.ashx
and had the following contents basically
just referred to a c-sharp file called
report.ashx.cs
and since we've loaded up all of our
source code into our id we can check
that source code simultaneously
while looking at uh this asujx file
so we found that the source code was
located in this directory called
report.cs and we opened it up
this is what report.cs looked like
ultimately it was processing the request
and it was
passing it was processing uh it was
ending up at the sync report data
serializer dot to serialize query where
it took our input stream
as input
when we look at report data
serializer.cs we can find that our sync
here was ultimately net data contract
serializer dot read object
now for people that aren't familiar with
source code auditing or specific quirks
of languages
this is incredibly dangerous behavior in
dotnet
there's always been the issue of
insecure deserialization or at least
since the last four or five years that's
been more widely known and publicized
where if you're uh if this arbitrary
input from the user ending up at one of
these dangerous syncs for example net
data contract serializer.read object you
can achieve command execution
there are so many more syncs just like
this
and there are so many different quirks
inside languages that let you do
dangerous functionality or dangerous
things
thankfully
when i was auditing the source code my
understanding was
if something is being deserialized we
should check whether or not it is
happening in a safe way or not and
anything that looked like it was the
serializing i would investigate further
to see whether or not it could lead to a
dangerous uh
dangerous outcome
in this scenario we can see that the
sync
netdata contract serialized.readobject
takes in the input that we provide and
ultimately that data gets deserialized
so to craft the payload uh we used yso
serial which
thankfully has a gadget available for
net data contract serializer and we can
just do a simple gadget like this and
generate the base64 for that gadget
our final payload looks something like
this
which had query source parameters and
the parameter name and the serialized
xml object
this payload was crafted by looking at
the source code and understanding how do
we get to that sync what do we need to
do what do we need to include to get to
that sync
tech and really what we needed to do was
craft this specific xml file which would
lead to
the the sync inside the parameters tag
where the serialized xml object is
our final rce payload looks something
like this so you just send a post
request to report.ashx
with the xml payload and the serialized
xml inside the parameter tag
the exploit write up for this can be
found here it has a lot more detail
about the vulnerability how we found it
some of the things that we had to do to
come up with the exploit payload and i
hope that it's uh it's more insightful
for you to read this right up than just
this presentation because it does have a
lot more extra information as well
lastly i want to talk about vmware
workspace 1 uem which is also known as
airwatch
so workspace 1 uem is used for mobile
device management mobility management by
enterprises
it's for the administration of mobile
devices such as smartphones tablets
laptops and mdm is usually implemented
with
with the use of a third-party product
like workspace one uem
vmware acquired airwatch and then
renamed airwatch into workspace one uem
almost every large enterprise has some
sort of mdm solution and this software
is actually a really popular solution
that a lot of enterprises use
as usual we've got to map out the attack
surface
so one of the things that's pretty funny
is installing workspace one uem was
almost harder than discovering the
vulnerability which is
many times the case when looking at
enterprise software
these folders inside the website's uh
websites directory were deployed under
different virtual paths so you can see
on the right hand side there's all these
different um websites like devices
gateway catalog device management they
all have different virtual paths when
configured through iis
and there was some presence of some ashx
files which is what we focused on
initially when looking at the attack
surface
some of these ashx files weren't
protected by authentication
one of the ones that we focus on
particularly was something called
blobhandler.ashx
this file existed in multiple multiple
virtual parts however the ones that we
found that were vulnerable were only on
slash airwatch and slash catalog
the endpoint was accessible
pre-authentication and there was no
authentication logic that was found
within the code or the web.config files
and as you can see here there was this
function that we found within
blobhandler.ashx
called renderproxyresponse
it took in an encrypted url and then it
would proxy that encrypted url directly
this was incredibly interesting to us
the first question we had was how can we
generate our own encrypted urls
so the logic uh was essentially as long
as we provided an encrypted url
a http request would be made to this
encrypted url you could control the
method you can control the body the
headers and the full response would be
proxied back to the user this
functionality was not in use by
literally anything else in the code base
and it was a big question for why it was
implemented in the first place
essentially it's a full read ssrf with
full control over the request if we work
out this encryption algorithm
the encryption function looks something
like this it would obtain a master key
and then it would uh return a function
with that master key and encrypt using
that function
when we looked at the the function to
get the master key we realized that the
logic was actually quite flawed
and it would return the default master
key in most scenarios
so you can you can walk through this
logic pretty easily you can see that um
it uses the key version to determine
whether or not it returns the default
master key but you can see that it
returns a default master key in two
scenarios if the key version is empty or
it equals kv 0 or also if the master key
from the database is null or the master
d from the master key from the database
is not valid
um
but yeah ultimately this was the
functionality that was being used to
encrypt
arbitrary strings and also the
functionality being used when you needed
to encrypt the url to provide to
airwatch or vmware workspace 1 uem
we realized that the default master key
was just hard coded in the code base so
you can see that here's the key version
the passphrase the salt data
and at this point we were pretty
confident that if we were able to use
this master key to encrypt our own urls
we would be able to get full read ssrf
so what we did was we hooked into the
source code we hooked into the dll files
and we ultimately hooked into the
encryption functions defined in the dll
files in order to make our own encrypter
we leveraged the already existing
functions for encryption and we were
able to create a cli application that
was encrypted that was capable of
encrypting arbitrary strings
this allowed us to specify arbitrary
urls to be encrypted which could then be
used for when requesting
blobhandler.ashx this successfully led
to pre-auth ssrf
the final exploit looks something like
this um we had a python script that
would do all of the work with the
encryption calling out to the binary
that we created it will take in a url
and the ssrf target and then it would
generate an ssrf payload this is an
example ssr of payload that will request
example.com
the write up for this can be found here
this has a lot more detail on the
write-up and it explains the whole
encryption algorithm how we hook in the
poc and things like that so i highly
recommend you check up this write up and
see if you can
recreate this yourself
that's all i have for today thank you
very much for joining and watching this
session i hope that you learned a little
bit about source code analysis i know
that ultimately i was just explaining
vulnerabilities that we found through
source code analysis but i feel like i
had a few really important lessons
throughout this presentation
i hope that you can learn something from
my journey in source code analysis and i
hope that i helped you in some way have
a great day