[Music]
hi
my name is ian kenovic and i'm a tread
hunter director in micro
today my colleagues and i will discuss
the ransomware group which we call water
rock
we're going to show you why we believe
water rock is one of the most relentless
ransomware groups that we've seen today
but firstly let's have a really quick
recap of the last couple of years in
ransomware which has evolved in this
relatively short space of time but not
necessarily the ransomware itself but
rather in what happens before and after
the ransomware is deployed in the
network
in the years 2012 to 2017 we were
fighting mass male ransomware campaigns
these campaigns would infect
endpoints and they were capable of
identifying network shares and
encrypting those as well taking
advantage of companies who lacked
business continuity measures such as
backups at the same time businesses and
security companies were adapting and
working to improve defenses and
proactive detection capabilities for
ransomware
in 2017 we had two significant events in
the forms of wannacry and apetia where
the malicious use of encryption was
coupled with exploits and automated
propagation routines leveraging mimikatz
and ps exec
these catastrophic incidents put
ransomware vulnerabilities network and
system architecture weaknesses that
enable them in the spotlight never
before and this really did drive
improvements in companies that started
to have an impact in the volume of
successful opportunities to grants more
attacks we were seeing and this began to
change
in 2018 we started seeing attackers
pivot away from opportunistic attacks
and begin to pay real attention to
internet exposed systems they began
exploiting vulnerabilities in remote
desktop protocol services and they also
began leveraging weaknesses in
credential management
and that brings us to modern ransomware
today we have a combination of attack
vectors fueled by an underground supply
chain made up of access brokers
ransomware service providers and
affiliates then we also have malware
installation as a service this is the
cooperation between botnet operators and
malware as a service affiliates malware
installation is a service operators drop
second stage loaders that steal
sensitive data and place back doors in
compromised environments for further
attacks the now defunct imitech botnet
that dominated the space until its
takedown by law enforcement earlier this
year is a prime example of malware
installation as a service
we've seen others namely trick bot
icesteady and quackbot attempt to fill
the void left by emmitat in other words
this is a problem that is not going away
anytime soon
so this is where we are today
we have a cooperation between access
brokers botnet operators and ransomware
as service operators all working in
unison to identify weaknesses in
organizations networks globally this
mind map is non-exhaustive but it does
serve to illustrate the breadth of
different malwares groups and attack
factors aimed at companies today
the outsourcing model leads to a higher
success rate where the required skills
are offered and recruited in the
underground
so let's take a closer look at water
rock well we first observed this
intrusion set in 2020 when we analyzed
the nephilim ransomware as a service
when we took a look at the early victims
we found that they were generally one
billion dollar plus revenue
organizations
like other targeted ransomware attacks
the criminals leveraged double extortion
with ransomware for impact and stolen
data for additional leverage
as is the case with other targeted
ransomware groups such as ryuk
water rock victims were named and
chained on a leak site
with nephilim we observe similarities
with another ransomware as a service
offering an empty an empty was the
ransomware as a service offering which
we first spotted in 2019
and with no film we have obvious cool
similarities with an empty quote
we also know two aliases with this group
namely js forum and jingo at the time
nemti was shutting down the same actors
were actively recruiting for a new
private ransomware as a service offering
the adverts feature in addition an
initial profit split between operators
and affiliates of 70 30 moving to 9010
for affiliates who can bring a higher
number of victims this is similar to
that of an empty and we believe the
actors here are recruiting for nephilim
so let's talk about how water rock gains
initial access to the network
so we can think of modern ransomware
initial access techniques and our skill
sets to be at least on par with that of
professional penetration testers in the
case of water rock we observed that they
used a citrix vulnerability that first
appeared in december 2019
at that time on disclosure there was
approximately 80 000 organizations
running vulnerable instances
citrix disclosed the vulnerability with
mitigations on the 17th of december 2019
a first public proof of concept code
appeared on the 10th of january in 2020
but crucially the vulnerability was not
fixed until the 19th of january 2020.
the expectations are the gap between
vulnerability disclosures and the
availability of a fix the availability
of proof of concept code and then the
usual lag between the deployment of
mitigations has become a stable tactic
exploited by criminals in target
ransomware attacks we also believe that
there were other exploits likely used to
gain initial access to victims
for internet exposed systems this is
especially critical our advice to
customers is drop tools mitigate patch
and treat these vulnerable assets as
potentially compromised
after gaining an initial foothold in the
network attackers deployed
post-exploitation tools to begin
borrowing deeper into that network we
found the usual suspects cobalt strike
was used in every intrusion that we've
seen
in an early case we found that the
deployment of the cobalt strike beacon
didn't always go smoothly we found that
water rock deployed an unsigned cobalt
strike beacon that was detected by an
anti-malware software running on the
compromised server there were turns and
ten days later deployed a signed beacon
which was again detected but they
persisted until av was evaded a full 17
days after gaining the initial access
yes we have seen that ransomware
attackers go from initial access to
ransomware deployment in the same day
but if with effective monitoring and
instant response plan there is time to
minimize the impact and to boot the bad
guys out of your network
for defenders this also demonstrate the
value of monitoring certain noteworth
detections which may indicate a
particular attack phase what's more it's
worth pointing out that the attackers
persisted in the network of further weak
before deploying any ransomware at all
so let's talk about how water rock moves
laterally in the network using
vulnerabilities
critical bugs such as remote execution
vulnerabilities rightfully get the
attention that they deserve to gain
widespread coverage in the media but
with new vulnerabilities gaining
notoriety almost every month they
quickly get forgotten about patch
management for older vulnerabilities
continues to plague organizations
water rock for instance leverages
elevation of privilege vulnerability
from 2017 which was discovered by
researchers at google almost a full
three years prior to the water rock
intrusion the code used was the actual
proof of concept code released by google
other vulnerabilities are also used
namely eternal blue and smb ghost to
move laterally across the network let's
take a look at some of the tooling used
by water
from water rock we found a couple of
commonalities outside of cobalt strike
so process hacker
a tool that's used by defenders and
malware analysts and systems
administrators in this case uh it was
used to kill security software and
monitoring tools for credential access
we found the usual suspects with
mimikatz used for credential dumping but
we also found tools that we don't see in
many targeted ransomware attacks these
days such as nl brute which attackers
used to brute force rtp services
for discovery of other systems
bloodhound was used for attack pack
discovery sharpound was used to dump the
ad structure which was then analyzed
off-site adfind another ad enumeration
tool was also found in multiple
intrusions
smb tools additionally was used to
perform reconnaissance across the
network using smb this tool uses ntlm
hashes as well as domain credentials to
access remote hosts using smb so a wide
variety of tooling was used to achieve
their objectives
and that brings us to the ransomware
deployment so in the case of water rock
nephilim was deployed using a
combination of psx and batch grips and
brass scripts were used to kill
interesting processes to avoid things
like access violations or potentially
security software finally before
executing the malicious nephilim binary
so for data exfiltration the attackers
used two primary mechanisms in early
attacks we observed the water rock using
a combination of collection scripts with
ftp so these commands were executed via
cobalt strike
where 7-zip compressed archives were
uploaded to a remote host using ftp
but the attackers also leveraged mega
sync
and we noted that they used a mega sync
to exfoliate large volumes of data as
mega provides 20 gigabytes of free
storage the tooling to compress the
stolen data was dropped earlier on in
the attack phase
hello my name is fernando mercedes and
i'm a senior threat researcher with
trend micro we'll now have a look at the
inner workings of the
nephilim rancher itself
the main payload behind this attack so
let's start
so first i've prepared
two documents two files one is a
document.rtf
it's a text file
as a testing document
and we're going to use this first one
with the first
nafflin operation mode which is
basically providing
to the netherlands executable a file
path or a directory path
this is going to work this way
and
as you can see the file was encrypted
and the kiano extension was added
but there is also
a regular
working mode
which is actually just executing the
transfer
so just
the
binary
and then well before that let's look at
the image it's a test image
and it opens normally and then after i
press enter
well nephiline complains about a couple
of files and folders it couldn't open
because i didn't run it with elevated
privileges
but it actually worked encrypting
the bitmap file
you can actually
see this by trying to open it
it doesn't work
and it also creates the renson node in
this mode it creates the renson node so
you can see the
blog where they leak data
and yeah so that's
basically what happens
now let's debug it let's see how it
works i will first load a
map file
which i exported from ida
so i have
labels here
in the debugging session as well
especially the main underscore labels
for go programs are really useful so i'm
going to put a breakpoint on main
in the main function and also in that
unix file function you're going to see
why in a minute
so here we are at the main function
and the first interesting thing we see
is that ctr encrypt
call
so i'm going to break it here and
we note that there are actually
two parameters
uh to this function
uh among others actually
and uh it's
actually decrypting
uh something that looks like a
configuration
so let's copy this
whatever was decrypted here
it is
a bit lengthy yeah so we have b0a bytes
i'm gonna copy this data
as a string
and
i'm gonna use now
cyber chef
just because it's
a very nice tool
to do some beautifying of this json
output
that's it so i have a well identity json
file here
and we can add it as a note
in the debut key
then we see there is something
that
seems to be encoded in base 64.
the actually the field name is base64
note
so we can use cyber chef as well just to
see what's in there
and we get the ransom note
i'm going to copy that also
paste into the notes of the debuggie
so
yeah that's the rest of notes the email
addresses and the blog
so i keep it for later
now let's continue
with the debugging
we have some json parsing and then
go to other functions and i hit f9 and
we can see it opening a couple of files
let's look at this one
because it seems like it's a file it's
going to encrypt it's not a directory
so i'm going to copy the file path
and just to have a look at the file
first
okay seems fine so it's a text file
no problem with this so it's opening the
file
we can
have a look at what happens here
and then we see some interesting stuff
which is
this call to generate random bytes
so it's called once
now i later realized that in edx
you get the address where the bytes were
written to
so that's the first sequence of bytes
generated and then let's look at the
second it actually
right after this so i have two numbers
let's add a label to make things easier
this i'm going call rando number one
and the next one i'm gonna call it
rainbow number two
okay
so going forward
we see some
interesting
key handling here
so it's an rsa key this is actually the
rsa public key
that is present in the configuration
that was decrypted
before
so this key is actually used to encrypt
something here in this call and uh what
is this is going to encrypt render
number one
done so uh we can actually look at the
results
this
we can add a label
and because that's the encrypt
render number one so let's call it inc
render
one a similar structure
follows
next so that's again encrypting but this
time random number two
we
gonna add uh
another label
that's random number two
and then
we follow with the execution
and now it's easier to see in the
right column
when random number either render number
one or two are used
so now there's a call to read
and this is actually reading the
contents of the file we can see here and
dump
that's really the content
of the file that
we saw before
and
now
we have a call to ctr and crypt using
both window number one and two
this is actually encrypting the file
content
that's the encrypted version of it
okay so
this is now written back to the file
and then there is another
data being written which is actually the
encrypted version of random number one
and also random number two
afterwards so that's exactly how nafling
works
it
writes
the
generated random number
to
the end of the file then
it does the same for the second one
and finally
he also adds a marker
which in that case is kiano
and this is also written
through the file
now we can have a look at the file
it doesn't really exist
because it was renamed to dot kayano
and we see the file is now encrypted
okay so let's look at this file
in a
more interesting way maybe with a
hexadecimal editor
okay
so
we can go to the end of the file it's
actually
easier this way
because the two numbers are actually 256
byte
each so we can just
select uh 512 bytes
and then the rest
is going to be our
encrypted data
we can just use a cyber chef as well to
put that encrypted data here the idea is
to decrypt it so we're going to need
that previously generated random
numbers which are actually
the
aes
keys so let's copy the first one
and
we're gonna need uh recycle here for
hex
hexadecimal
so convert into raw and then an aes
decrypt reside
so we have the key
that's in hex
and then the second random number
it's actually the iv or in that case
which since it's aes ctr
it's also called
nonce
so here the iv we change the mode to ctr
we change the inputs for
role
and we have the file contents
and that concludes our
analysis of the main range for payloads
it's important to say though that the
decryption methods are shown here they
they were only possible because i was
debugging
a
particular session of the execution of
this ranger
while it was generating the keys
so this is not really feasible
for past
attacks so we are not aware of any way
of decrypting
files encrypted by nephiline rensser
to date
now i call my colleague fikey
who is going to give you even more
details behind this operation
hello everybody my name is feika
huckabout
my teammate fernando has just explained
the inner workings of the ransomware
binaries of the water rock actor
i will now talk about the victims of the
water rock actor
the victims of waterrock are distributed
over various industries
but most of the victims are located in
the u.s
this is consistent with postings in
underground forms we have been seeing
in these postings in underground forums
water rock related actors are
interested in buying access to
compromised networks of companies mainly
in the us and australia
they also request
a revenue
of companies of at least 200 million
dollars
this is also consistent with data we
have been seeing
the median revenue of the victimized
companies of water rock is about 900
million us dollar
once water rock starts to publish stolen
data on their tor hidden web server
the actor shows a rather relentless
behavior
for about 75 percent of these victims
this ransomware actor is leaking data
over a period of one to two months
but for the remaining 25 percent of the
victimized companies the actor is
leaking parts of the stolen data during
a period that varies from 4 to 13 months
for about all of the victimized
companies lead data remained online
from the first day the leak appeared and
there's no indication the data will be
removed from the tor hidden surfer of
water rock
we do not know what the rationale is
behind this behind leaking new data over
extended periods of times
for example from 4 to 13 months
we think victims will not be more
inclined to pay a ransom
but rather this is a message to future
victims
when they wouldn't pay a ransom
to our knowledge there's no other
ransomware as a service actor that is so
relentless in exposing new sensitive
data victim data over extended periods
of time
we will now talk about a study we have
done where we compared 16 different
ransomware as a service actors with each
other
there appear to be significant
differences between
different ransomware sa service actors
we have been looking at the median
revenue of different ransomware as a
service actors but also at the number of
victims it appears that nephilim has
relatively few victims on their
website on their website where they post
stolen data
about 30 early this year and in the
summer about 50 victims there are some
other ransomware as a service groups
that have far more
victims on their website
sometimes a few hundred but it appears
that these actors are not that selective
in choosing their victims
nephilim and other ransomware as the
service
groups are much more
selective as you can see on this slide
the median revenue of the victims of
water rock is almost 900 million dollars
and
for a lot of the other ransomware actors
the median revenue is much lower
basically
their victims is a mixed bag of
companies of different sizes and with
different
revenues
about all of the
ransomware as a service groups say that
they will
keep online the stolen data for months
but it appears that some of the
more infamous
rensover as a service groups
are not able to keep their data online
for a long time
because they are hosting
their
stolen data on file sharing platforms
that are usually quite fast in taking
down
the stolen
contents
we have seen that these ransomware as a
service groups
do not update their own website with new
links for example that links are not
removed nephilim however
so the water rock actor
is keeping online
victim data for a long time and they
have no issue
hosting their contents on their tor
hidden server
of course
the
usage of store hidden servers
has its negative size for example
it takes a long time to download huge
archives with stolen data it might take
days before you have the complete file
while ransomware attacks have an
enormous impact on victimized
corporations
both in monetary losses and reputational
damage
there are good opportunities
to defend and to fight back
the threshold for attackers can be made
significantly higher and there are some
points where
researchers or law enforcement can start
an investigation
for defenders there are at least three
points where alarm bells could ring for
a upcoming ransomware attack
first is the reconnaissance and
exploitation phase where an attacker
attempts to get access to the target
network
these attacks can be stopped
by a intrusion prevention system an ips
system
an ips system can shield a potentially
vulnerable system by using filters to
prevent exports to be used against that
network or system
an ips system can also provide virtual
patching
that is particularly important when a
patch is not available and ransomware
actors are known to be quite fast
in using newly discovered
vulnerabilities
second is the phase
when the attacker did succeed in getting
access to the target network
ransomware attackers often use a tool
called cobalt
strike
for the phase of a
lateral movement
faux cobalt strike is designed for red
teams and
penetration testers ransomware actors
are using it too
but in practice we see that ransomware
actors are not using this tool to the
fullest extent they are not using all
the evasion techniques that are
available
so a defender can potentially detect a
cobalt strike in a network
and
use something simple as a block list of
known
ip addresses known c c i p
addresses
whenever a defender detects a cobalt
strike in a network he has a small
window to
fight back to fight back against the
ransomware actor that window could be
just a few minutes
could be a few hours it could be a few
days but there is the opportunity to
fight back
then there's the data exfiltration phase
for double extortion
most ransomware attackers
will try to find sensitive data in a
victimized corporation network
and
they will try to exfoliate the data that
expectation of data can be detected as
well in a network
when
none of these
warning signs were picked up and the
attacker was able
to load ransomware binaries onto the
victimized system
then
well you would say it's too late but
actually there are still some points
where
corporations law enforcement and
researchers can fight back
for example in the double extortion
phase where a ransomware
actor is
making public some of the stolen data of
a victim
he can make mistakes opsec mistakes for
example
by uploading it to a third party he
might use a ip address that shouldn't be
in the hands of law enforcement
or when he is uploading it to his own
ransomware as a service website
he might have made mistakes in setting
up a tor hidden server
more than once we were able to determine
the real ip address of the tor hidden
surfer of a ransomware actor and that
includes water rock
i can explain this a bit further in the
following table
in this table you will see some ip
addresses that are involved
the bold ip addresses were
confirmed to be related to water rock
for example we found a few
cobalt
strike cnc servers related to water rock
but they also found the back end servers
of their
rent server as a service website where
they put stolen data
when we were looking in a neighborhood
of these ip addresses we found many
other ips's that could have been used in
other phases of the ransomware attack
for example the exploitation phase
uh the uh reconnaissance phase but also
in the data exfiltration phase
we are not
uh 100
percent sure that these appearances were
actually being used by water rock but
these ipads so this ip range is
definitely a good starting point
for researchers and law enforcement to
get
to know the actors better to
know more details about the actual
actors
then
there's still a opportunity to fight
back and that is the almost the last
phase i would say that is the money
laundering phase whenever a victim
pays a ransom to the rent survey actor
the ransomware act will usually receive
that ransom in bitcoins
but those bitcoins somehow have to be
laundered into real money because the
the actor wants real money in his pocket
then he can make mistakes as well
in the money laundering phase and that
is evidenced by a recent case where the
fbi was able to cease a significant
amount of the ransom that was paid by a
large u.s
company to
a ransomware actor the fbi was able to
seize some of the money that was
actually paid
um so this concludes our presentation
about water rock
i hope you enjoyed it and that you
learned something new water rock is a
clear example
of a
ransomware actor that was not very good
at its job a few years ago
but it has um
evolved into a well one of the most
relentless and ransomware actors
that is active
today and it is actually
attacking multi-billion companies
nowadays if you want to learn more you
can read our paper we have published on
our own website but we also have a
shorter paper with a bit
of new details on the website of
firespirit10 thank you very much and
thank you for your time
[Music]
you