[Music]
hello everyone my name is shankar i'm
working as a threat researcher at norton
lifelock
today i'm going to present my topic on
hunting analysis and detection of
android soccer let's get started
stockwear applications are primarily
used for tracking spouses friends
employees etc
the application would be installed on a
victim's device
it will gather
sensitive data like your whatsapp
message location details and transmit
them to a remote location
now
apart from transmitting the gathered
data
they also try to avoid attract
attracting users attention by using
different persistent techniques like
hiding icons prevent users from deleting
the app
where they can be found
stock aware applications are widespread
and they are made available to public
via play store third-party app stores
and directly sold from the vendor
websites uh play store remote most of
the stock wire application but
third-party app stores did not they are
still out there in the third party app
stores for anyone to download for free
and use it
for stalking the victims
the next slides let's see some of the
persistent techniques uh used to buy
those stockwear apps are taken from
different app stores
first one is apc tools it is a parental
control application from playstore
it can remotely track your location sms
and call logs the interesting part is
the persistent technique used in the app
any atoms to uninstall the app uh would
take you away from the app in full
screen uh thereby relate thereby
preventing the deletion of the app
this is achieved using the perform
global action method from accessibility
service class
the perform global action
with the method with argument one is a
back press event
second one is hands a location track
tracking application from third party
app store
it silently transmits your phone
location details to a remote ip address
of your choice and there are two
malicious behavior
the persistent technique is the
application launcher imitating the
settings icon uh moreover the
application menu can only be opened
using a secret code which is uh known
only to the stalker
more examples on launcher icons on
column one tracker is another location
tracking program
it transmits your location details to a
remote
dashboard
the malicious behavior is that the
application can hide the launcher icon
completely from the app drawer if you're
using android 9 or below
column 2 is an application from our
in-house database
and the suspicious behavior is that the
app goes unnoticed by using the
transparent icon
uh last example is a spycam application
from a third party app store it takes
pictures or videos on a regular interval
and transmit them to a configured email
address the pictures taken won't be
visible in the gallery this is taken
care by the dot no media file
no media file is a hidden file um the
file is created by the application to
avoid pictures or videos showing up in
the gallery
spy camps are still actively used only
in the last nine months we had close to
a thousand detections on different spy
cam variants
so these are some of the persistent
techniques used by the stock of our apps
in the next slide so you will see how to
hunt them using search engine operators
um some of us could have used the search
operators for debugging websites
penetration testing and os and hunting
we found that it can also be used for
hunting software applications
among the popular search engines google
provides the most number of search
operators followed by bing
here are some examples for hunting
potential stock of our applications you
may check them all
what do you need exactly to do the
hunting drive search operators and
keywords
consider including the protocol details
in your search queries file type can
also
come handy sometimes
if you're looking for iocs you may use
csv or txt file because usually they are
published in those formats
next you need to gather keywords
read application descriptions package
name
pay careful attention to the title and
the content of stalker wire vendor
websites
stock aware apps also available in
multiple languages so
consider using languages in your search
queries
no
after you after you have collected the
search operators and keywords uh we can
automate the hunting process uh wire
automation uh if you google uh for uh
alternative if you google alternatives
for uh play store you may spot five or
ten third party app stores but in
reality there are plenty of them
manually hunting stock aware apps in all
the app stores will be a time consuming
task
we need an approach to hunt them program
programmatically that's where serp api
comes in
let's see a couple of examples on how to
hunt stock over apps using search
operators uh use case one uh finding
stock aware vendor websites
the related search operator can be
useful for hunting stock aware
competitors for instance when related
search operator is used in combination
with the vendor url it presents us with
a list of stock aware competitors the
search results
taking each of those url and repeating
the same steps may reveal potential
stock aware vendors
the same technique applies for
collecting third-party app stores urls
second use case finding spy cams on app
stores
you can find potential app stores again
using the same related search operator
with an app store your urls input now
take each app store url and use it with
the site operator plus keyword related
to spycam it would get you the spycam
apps from
app stores
we did some experiments with the search
operators and serp apis we did see a
related search operator was useful but
there are drawbacks to it
the latest uh operator did not work for
uh new stock five vendors um google says
related
operator is not refreshed in real time
meaning um
new stock where apps may not show up but
we show up sometime later
i read an article that it works for
larger domains
and often vendor vendor websites go out
of business and the newer ones may come
up and they are not indexed by search
engine in real time
we also notice
spam urls popping up
after doing queries by combining other
search operators like index off
uh here are some hints that may be
helpful for hunting uh run a search on
google for keywords later to spy or
vendor name and sometimes it presents us
with the ads of popular phone tracking
vendors if you find the stock wire
vendors
facebook page scroll down to check the
related page it might link you to other
vendors pages
the related search lists at the end of
the search page can also be useful
if you're using search operators it can
help refine or expand your current query
searching for a vendor name sometimes
reveals just talk about competitor names
as well
right above that you may also support
the people also search for box that may
link you sometimes to other stock aware
vendors
so that's it about hunting let's move on
to detection
we have seen majority of the stock of
our apps in the market does not employ
any code protection techniques
most of the features like sms recording
clipboard etc
rely on the standard apis
offered by these classes that leaves
them vulnerable to static detection
social messaging apps are popular these
day stock web applications also target
target social messaging apps when they
do it they track multiple social
messenger applications there are two
techniques widely used to extract
messages from them
one is directly accessing the private
database files
the point to notice here is um
it is suspicious when any app uses two
or more database names of popular social
messaging apps moreover the messaging
apps database names
does not change often we also noticed a
similar implementation in cat watchful
sp app m spy free spy and other vendors
uh the second implementation is by
tapping the notification message uh by
tapping the messages from notification
instead of accessing the private files
just talking about apps extract messages
from the notification
similar implementation were also seen in
talk log flexi spy mm guardian and spicy
vendors
uh this slide contains some of the
sensitive and commonly used uh methods
constants and artifacts uh found in the
software applications um that primary
clip change listener is for clipboard
media projection for screen capturing no
media is usually used in spy camps
foreign artifacts we have database names
of whatsapp facebook and viber
we can combine some of them and use it
for detection
while using db names
use wildcard because implementation
implementations are usually like slash
data slash data com whatsapp and file
path
so to sum up
change the sensitive method names um
class names and when you include
forensic artifacts um
linux files constants used in the
application it would make the detection
stronger moreover the android api
constants and artifacts don't change
often
we have tested this method and it was
effective in detecting complex talk
about apps fuse spyware and rat variants
about drawback the technique does not
work for simple programs like tracker
it application
go it may cause wrong classification if
used and apparently the decay could fail
if the app use any code protection
techniques
let's see a quick demo uh using the
android python library
the pocs are quite straightforward
implementation all the indicators are
defined in a json file
the commonly used and sensitive api
calls artifacts uh linux files etc um
that
the classes methods uh constants used in
the application uh can be obtained using
the android analysis object
now all the indicators defined in the
json file
will be run over a loop
to check if they are presented app
they are found the next step is
evaluation
the logic class takes care of it it
checks for suspicious patterns like an
app cannot use two or more database
names of popular messaging apps and
others based on our guidelines and then
it locks the verdict on the console
i'm i'm going to use a
exynos stock web application for the
demo
okay
the cross reference for each method is
also locked on the console and finally
the verdict along with the stock wire
type
with that we come to the last section of
the talk
stockwear threadless is a platform for
sharing samples metadata related to
stock web applications
currently we have several av vendors
universities and independent researchers
contributing to this platform
of course they can all seat and download
the samples from the portal
if you are an av vendor or university or
independent researcher working on stock
by topic we correctly invite you to join
us
um
please follow the link we can we can get
in touch with you
we would also like to take this moment
and thank all the members and
contributors uh for your contributions i
it really helped us in the research
this was an uh interesting uh find
reported by one of our contributors
amrita university
it is a simple application that guides a
user to download a stock aware program
called mobile tracker
even though google remote stock over
apps from play store developers are
finding uh ways to spread stock wire
programs through play store and this app
is an example
play store has a huge customer base
the developer is using play store as a
platform for advertising stock of our
application
if you notice the comments
developer is requesting the user to
avoid using inappropriate
words in the comments because uh he
might get
uh the app remote from play store
up this is a general advice and with
this slide we will wrap up this talk um
if you have uh if you have any of these
apps installed on your phones pay
attention and learn the capabilities of
the apps because these apps can be used
for stocking purpose
if you spot uh two popular application
you know like if you have to place your
icons on your phone that's suspicious uh
take steps to remove them or contact
antivirus helpline
upgrade your android versions to 10 or
11 because icon hiding is not allowed
anymore and under an android version is
about it
make sure play protect settings are
enabled
often stock web application disable play
protect settings before they get
installed
make sure you have knowledge about the
apps installed on your phone
what permissions are given to them uh
stock of their apps target device admin
and notification access privilege
these are only limited advice but we
highly recommend you to install
antivirus programs on your phone
thanks for your time if you have any
question
questions shoot them away
[Music]