[Music]
i would like to present an interesting
story about the latest research which
involves was matrix thing and data
excretion in world of iot
i am gabrielle verhart senior security
researcher at searchtop focusing on iot
devices such as routers gnosis and so on
my name is robert neumann i'm currently
the head of the cyber protection
operations center at acronis
and
the story started with very strange
messages ah small business in hungary
received an unexpectedly high monthly
voice sometimes in 2016
and then they were reaching out to us to
figure out what was basically happening
with the device or with
their
company
first they were trying to figure out
what the root cause of the
high monthly invoice was
they could track it back to short text
messages
sent to a foreign country so at this
point we were expecting that those
messages would be coming from standard
phones but instead
we figured out that there was actually a
soho router sending out them and that
was later in identified as a tp-link
amar
the content of all those messages was
the same and it was rather specific
about football
before if we proceed further with the
research we have to step back and have a
look at the evolution of the
kind of whole router space
so
routers for whom and so use i
had a primary one connection for the
kids that was providing the internet
access and later with the birth of the
3g
standard
that was finally providing an
alternative method with acceptable
transfer speeds and also it was sort of
reliable it wasn't too fast but it could
be used finally as an alternative
solution
then companies started to build usb
modems using this 3g capability
and those were sometimes very useful for
places where traditional options options
were just absent
embedding these technologies resulted in
new devices such as the mr 6400
but before we we reached that
point
uh a step further step back
there were kind of mixed solutions where
the actually the vendor was providing a
compatibility list for the router and
you could buy a usb modem and you could
just plug that into the
modem
as a alternative way of connecting
finally these
new breed of devices were so kind of
combining the best of both worlds so one
was that
us the usb modems were just kind of
standard models they had no firewall
functionality
in the new there's you have finally
firewall
functionality and also there was a
fallback connection if the standard
broadband was not working for whatever
reasons
the investigation was started by
exploring
known vulnerabilities
we have found some of these
vulnerabilities such as
an authenticated local fire disclosure
which made possible to read out every
file from the device such as the
passwordify
and this issue was fixed in certain
tipling devices expect for the mr 6400
admission
we found that this
authenticated file disclosure
would be used
to read out the password hash of the
http
as in user
by reading out the adobe password file
and this password hash could be used to
log into the device without brute
forcing because
the authentication process required only
the password hash
we found an undisclosured sms related
vulnerability in one of the tp-ring
advisory
which was
pure then our investigation
we also found some
new ones
for example an authenticated information
leak the device info
page
post back a lot of sensitive information
about the device such as the mac address
the
pin code or the email address
and because this
device info page was
handled especially
it could be used to bypass the
authentication process
so
every get
request could be
accessed without an authentication and
because
settings were modified through get
request the authentication bypass could
be used to
modify any settings without
authentication
there is one
api endpoint which
could be accessed
with post requests it was the atf
config
which was responsible to
handle
modern specific commands
it required an authorization
cookie which was similar to the
authorization header
and
it
contained
the password hash in that
md5
password hash
encoded with 2bs 64.
the
mr
6400 root
two chipset one was a application
chipset responsible for
wi-fi and applications
and other was there the chipset which
handled the
modern related functionality
so when the
user
or the
admin side code ltlwebconfig
api handler handler
it was handled by the httpd
process in the application chipset it
verifies some
something in the
authorization cookie and send the
original json to their rtl chip set
which perform the
requested modem functionality
the
anti-web config
handler
verified whether the authorization
cookie contains
any string but
it doesn't verify the content of the
string
so
any content in the authorization cookie
could be used to
access the
api
which made possible
to send sms
changed sms settings
uh
read out
in
books and out books
messages and also to change
the time in the
chipset which was
contained
common injection vulnerability also
we have to note that
the wall up ui was rewritten
and the current firmware of the tp-link
disabling device
doesn't
contain this vulnerabilities
so
back to the football messages
there was a
long time until our honeypot device
was finally having different types of
organic messages
but the
football team advance
were still using the same
structure this focused on bigger ones
and top leaks
and all bets
aimed the win or drove situation
the
definition four numbers loot ordinary
phone numbers
and the
messages were sent
a day per the mesh day
this message is made before match fixing
but it would be some
conditions to met
and
because
the
bets aimed only for the win or joe
in case
it's a real bats
they
they should
bet the final results because it would
pay more
and also it
would be hard to monetize the what's in
this
attack because it would require much
more messages to send so we conclude
that
this may be
offering tips service
which
could be found on the indian tests
now also
we found that their message types
which were
which seems like an activation of
verification code
and
such as
form verification travel code
these messages seems to use the device
as an sms gateway
but the
content was repeating and four numbers
are only from a small batch
uh in some cases we found that
timestamps indicating
at least semi-automated processing in
one side because the
sending times
were very frequently
so at this point we found that there
must be money involved somehow
as no one was really just doing this for
fun or trying to bully someone into a
high monthly invoice and there were a
couple of trades so
by this time at least two dozen
different messages was discovered
and
the devices were versing all scattered
around the world so they were not
focusing on a specific location
the problem was that any verification on
the possible exploitation of any premium
rate services became very complicated
so we had no
further context for these messages but
then came up an idea as when we were
looking at the old going messages we see
[Music]
we have seen a small issue that
sometimes there are gaps between the
indexes they would normally just
increase by one but sometimes there are
bigger and smaller gaps and that was
indicating a kind of another side quest
to also check their inbox messages as we
originally didn't want to do that
feeling that it was something only
sending out mass amount of email must
amount of messages and there is nothing
really interesting in the inboxes for
sim cards which are inserted into
this type of routers
so the singapore case
this was one of those prime examples
where we could nicely see the indexing
gaps field on the upper part you see the
incoming messages on the on the bottom
you see the outgoing messages this was
one device located in singapore and
having incoming messages about completed
purchases on buku so boku is a big
e-commerce portal supporting mobile
payments
if you are adding up all the numbers
then the total amount is sort of 70 usd
which is not high but we don't know
whether that was intentionally low or it
was maybe just a kind of a test run
preparing something bigger
if we are looking at the outgoing
messages we can see that there are
domestic numbers being used for the
service so it wasn't an international a
short message in this case and also we
can observe
two numbers starting with plus seven
which are belonging to russia so those
numbers
seems to be
having a kind of um
kind of a dumb content just uh numbers
repeating so we were looking up the
number and
got sort of lucky as
this was pointing to a free sms service
provided on on the internet
for these services you can try to locate
local numbers in your country and you
can use them to send out
messages
for example if you don't want to use
your own phone number for registering
certain services per verification number
or response code or an authentication is
required you could use these services in
this case it was simply just used to
kind of test whether the actual device
is working and capable of sending out
messages
the irish case there was one device in
ireland which seemed to be receiving
multiple confirmations on weekly
donations so these donations were too
big basically varying between two and
four euros but they were coming back on
a weekly basis
we were trying to also locate that the
root cause of that in the indexing
but that was kind of problematic as when
we were looking at the index numbers
they already started at
so that was sort of indicating that this
device might had a complete reset thing
before probably due to the reason that
they wanted to get rid of these messages
and likely that that was a failed
attempt
if we were looking at the
ongoing messages in the same time frame
that was bringing messages into focus
where we could
see
at least three different countries used
for destination
and also some
other numbers it was sort of the same
just like in the previous case
sending out only numbers and with no
specific order or the content wasn't
revealing more so when we tried trying
to kind of match these against
any service that initially
became
kind of challenging
these numbers were first appearing on
fake dating sites that was a kind of a
dead end
and then at some point we finally found
the perfect match uh on one of the
premium ray of an sms series on the web
offering premium rate services
so when we were investigating a little
bit more that was also revealing that
there are similar services sometimes
it's only the
web ui changing and if you are going a
little bit deeper digging into the
company then you will see the very same
faces turning up as who is working for
the company
and nothing else is basically different
so just like kind of a rebranding of the
very same service
we were collecting all the numbers from
here and
try to kind of cross match with all the
logs we had so that was revealing a
couple of exact matches but beside those
exact matches there were a lot of other
cases where the numbers were only off by
like the last two or three digits
as the
by this time our looks were already
covering a time frame of five years
that was indicating that these services
are frequently changing numbers and
those could be very well belonging to
the same service just going back a
couple of years
then
previous cases were
mainly falling into the low volume
category so we had one in poland which
was
just a little bit higher in terms of
download the photography messages so
there was one device located in poland
having
a kind of an incoming message obviously
the first index which was resembling of
a proper monthly invoice coming from
t-mobile
so you can see that that's having the
index number one
and
if you are translating the message is
basically an invoice and uh
the whoever the owner of the device was
had to pay 202 zlotys for the services
so that's like this is as usual you are
buying a new device you are enabling the
services and this is the first message
message you receive
then just a month later
there are a couple of things happening
if you are looking at the index number
that's already over
1000 and if you look at the very same
message the amount of the monthly
invoice is much higher close to almost a
thousand zlotys
so let's have a look of what was
happening
with the ongoing messages at the same
time frame
so we have a couple of test messages
which are basically using
the you know the same phone number as
for the content or sometimes using test
or something else and then
you have your your phone verification
number and a constant number and that's
starting and there are over 1000
messages with the very same content
so we could observe the similar
campaigns where there are test messages
used sometimes
the content is the phone number
sometimes it's test or tst or asd or
something similar for this we can see
that the as a result of these messages
there is at least a damage of over 200
usd
for the owner of the device because
that's how much
he or she had to pay for that
if we were kind of going a little bit
further also looking at the next month
and the month after then the amount of
the monthly invoices were going back to
the very same 202 so it was business as
usual after that it was only happening
for one month probably because whoever
had this was reporting the incident and
then they were kind of just putting a
bearing on the sim card so there was no
possibility to send to foreign numbers
anymore
and then let's have a look at some of
the top guns
so out of a lot of cases there were two
which are outstanding
both these cases were having over 10k
messages sent out
there was one device located in
singapore which had
over 9 000 of the same message types
sent
to one phone number in russia the phone
number was never changing the content
was slightly changing
it was always send code is and then
a number
which was kind of different
we believe that that might be due to the
reason that they wanted to avoid throw
detection on the career side
but they weren't changing their content
or messages beyond that and due to the
massive amount of messages this whole
campaign lasted for
a couple of months
looking at the number we couldn't find
on the exact match with the some of
these premium red
sms services but this was also kind of
close enough and the format and
everything also indicated that it would
be probably belonging to the very same
category and then probably the most
interesting
case we bumped into that was
located in in israel
and it was containing
10k of what looked like grammatically
correct english sentences the only
problem with that was they made no sense
at all
so you can look at the messages
these were
perfectly fine sentences but the content
was off we were trying to kind of cross
match these with anything we could find
and a couple of youtube song titles came
up or also kind of quotes from movies
and books
the idea here was the kind of the same
that these were probably used to kind of
avoid fraud detection
for the previous cases where you have
kind of a simplistic message with the
send code and the code some rules could
be applied to detect those for these
messages all the messages are completely
different so it's kind of hard to
detect them
also something else to
notify about this case was
that that kind of the time
they were using for sending out the
messages if you look at the indexing and
also kind of the same time
they are all constant so that's also
kind of
interesting because this was the almost
the only time we've seen that someone
was ever of the vulnerability in which
could be led to changing the lte time
more than that
to achieve kind of this output
you would need to constantly send the
time after sending out one message
because if you are just sending the
setting the
system time then normally seconds would
increase as they normally should so for
these they were going back and setting
the system time every time prior to
sending out a new message
and then due to that reason we couldn't
really
estimate how long this campaign lasted
but probably it was similar to the
previous russian one
even if it wasn't a couple of months but
it was surely multiple weeks
then we were looking at the content of
the messages like what else we could do
with them
one idea was that these might be using
acoustic cipher
but unfortunately looking at
a couple of dozen messages wasn't
revealing anything else
not only that the
timing would be off and that would make
anything
much more
uh problematic from an accuracy cipher
point of view
but the the indexes were
never off on the device itself so we
could probably properly identify
the order of the messages sent out
when we were looking even further then
we were only kind of bumping into
one side that was
having messages
like exact matches from these at least a
couple of months so sites like course
hero or script are having documents
where you can locate the very same
messages there these documents are not
contained containing anything else but
that wasn't really providing any useful
additional context for research for this
typical this specific message type
the idea of data exfiltration was
constantly coming up and we were
dropping it multiple times during the
the whole research
the reason was that we felt that the
base idea of sending out smaller amount
of data such as login credentials or
passwords or access codes that was all
possible mastery was all possible with
these devices it wouldn't take too much
to use some symmetric uh crypto like aes
and also like this base64
and use the credentials password encrypt
them encode them and send out
also kind of the same way using for some
of the smaller document files you could
split them into
chunks which are
having the proper
character limitation of the sms messages
and then you could kind of just rebuild
the messages on the other side
also it's rather strange that endpoints
or servers in a company environment
would connect to external routers just
for proxying data to towards maybe a
burner phone
and in this case iit security people and
also people working in
security operations centers might not be
prepared for such a scenario when they
are looking at the logs
still we were not really having anything
closer to this
and
almost at the very last point when we
were concluding the research we were
bumping into one case
as you can see there it was very unusual
there seems to be a test message being
sent out and then there is another one
trying to access
a server by the ip address and also
using the login password which is admin
admin in this case
unfortunately we couldn't figure out
anything more about the server
as it was already offline the time of
discovery of this was a couple of years
of looking at the time of when the
messages were sent
and at the end we had to conclude what
we feel that we felt this
whole operation was for
so running football team campaigns for
over a year after the initial discovery
was happening without kind of any
additional message times
at the very same time the number of
exploitable devices were significantly
growing both in location and of course
in numbers
if someone wanted to create a service
focusing on
text messages like this
that was
providing a complete anonymity for the
senders as even if someone was kind of
gathering the device
itself
it would be unable to kind of verify who
the sender was as using the
vulnerability is acting the very same
way like someone would be sending out
messages using the the ui of the device
because it's using the very same api and
of course there is no uh ip logging
implemented because that would normally
makes no sense at all
also we had signs of implementation of
load balancing so unfortunately due to
the time restriction we couldn't
talk about all the different message
types and campaigns we observed
but for one we were
having a case where
we could identify the very same meshes
message types and the very same content
being sent out parallel on two
completely different devices that was
indicating that there is some kind of
load balancing implemented
likely due to have a loan low number of
messages being sent so one sim card is
not going to be easily blocked and if
there are a couple of thousand devices
up for take on the internet this
providing uh better use of such a
service and also the campaigns we
observed were very broad scale both in
numbers
of the outgoing messages and also in
content so what we found was really
happening here is someone slowly build a
service uh which could be uh rented out
for whoever wanted to use and send out
messages unanimously
thus for the conclusion
there are a couple of issues that the
general state of the security of
internet connected devices such as
routers or iot devices is only slowly
improving that's been a problem going on
for years but the current state is not
much better than a couple of years back
one of the main issues with that is that
there is unfortunately no properly
implemented auto update functionality
and that's only done by a selected few
vendors that rest are still using the
old-fashioned ways of them people would
need to download firmware files from the
internet and then login into the
web ui of the device apply the firmware
restart sometimes also reconfigure it if
something went wrong
and that's just something we cannot
really expect from
people at home or also sometimes it's
even problematic for uh servos and
kind of small companies
also there is a problem with hardware
versus software balance so
the vendors are mainly interested in
selling hardware and generating revenue
that would be of course no problem and
they are trying to make sure that
the
devices are working for an extended
period of time so for example in the
case of mr 6400
there there are like five different
hardware revisions up to date of course
that could be due to different reasons
like trying to change
internal components and reduce the price
everything else
but compared to the software side that's
still sometimes feels a necessary must
and
even though that there is a completely
new firmware for this device
in general the software size seems to be
lacking compared to the hardware one for
most of the vendors
also one big issue in specific case was
that
exploiting functionality which has no
noticeable effect on the device main
operation is making discovery very
challenging so in case if it was just a
standard coin miner then the cpu would
likely overload or if you had a mass
amount of oil going queries then it
could be adidas and there are ways to
locate those
for
on sms base functionality
uh it was very tough because everything
else was properly working on the device
and we could only kind of get involved
as someone was reporting the high
monthly invoice
as for the result this can be kind of
ranging from just an unexpectedly high
monthly invoice and that would be the
kind of the
the smallest issue especially that if
it's just a kind of a one-off then
usually carriers are resolving that
and
at the end the end user doesn't really
have to pay
because
it was something they couldn't kind of
prevent happening
the bigger problem is if for whatever
reason that the device is
participating in criminal activities
because then someone could end up in the
very same unfortunate situation than if
the home wifi was hacked and the
neighbor or someone else was accessing
web pages or services which are not
really on the legal side of things
and in general as for the main
conclusion
looking at this case it was also
making us
feel that the
boundaries of traditional and cyber
crime are increasingly overlapping
before this the kind of phone related
crimes were considered as a traditional
crime but since those services were
integrated into iot devices
that the boundaries are much more
overlapping than in the decades before
if you have any questions
please feel free to reach out to our
emails
and we would like to thank you for your
attention
and see you soon
[Music]