you
look good hello and welcome to this
week's serious security seminar from
Purdue University our presenter today is
dr. Jackie resole Murr a serious
affiliate affiliate Pro fessor in the
management information systems program
of krannert graduate school of
management here at Purdue University
Jackie thanks Joel well good afternoon
everyone I play you can all see in here
I'm Jackie summer and I'm an associate
professor over in the krannert school in
the Information Systems Group and my
research arian information security has
been primarily on risk management and
security policy so this talk I'm about
to give is pretty fresh it's some
extremely early work that we are doing
with the building security in maturity
model version 5 professor spafford first
alerted me to this a while ago while
chatting about something and it is
turned into a really rich research
opportunity particularly for us in the
business school because it really is
focused on the management of security
and technologies a huge part of that but
as you all know it's usually the people
that screw something up somewhere down
the line or allow something to be
screwed up somewhere down the line so
this is research so it's really early we
first presented this work December well
about a month ago December nineteenth at
the workshop for information
technologies and systems in Auckland New
Zealand and got a little bit of feedback
so this is the second time and this is
work that I'm actually doing with a team
of four undergraduate students over in
the School of Management we don't have a
course that's dedicated to information
security so I just got some that were
interested in interested in the research
process and they are Kyle Harris you he
Douglas head who just graduated in
december and wishy or emma song so they
get a lot of the credit for this what we
were
what some of my previous research has
done is we've looked at the things that
firms say when it comes information
security so we have looked at the
textural disclosures that firms make and
there's a whole literature behind what
firms say what they do there's a cost to
making a statement that may give away a
position that you have in the firm so
firms only do this if the benefit is
going to be greater to the cost and when
we talk about these costs we're talking
about the legal statements that firm
make in the United States to the
securities exchange commission so these
are the things that firms have to say we
face risk we face market risks we face
credit risk and we face operational risk
and this is so that the shirt
shareholders and other stakeholders can
make informed decisions now as a firm
you want everything to be rosy and
awesome so people will not only buy your
products and services but also invest in
your company in terms of equity and
bonds and things like this so you want
to present a really positive picture
however you also don't want to be sued
for not sharing all the information that
is reasonable to share so firms are
hesitant to say more than they have to
about the risks but we find that firms
actually kind of forward-looking firms
tend to disclose quite a few risks they
don't say that I think some hacker in
Albania is going to break in at ten
o'clock on a Thursday night but they say
things like our systems are at risk for
malicious activity and we actually did a
previous study with some former graduate
students where we did find that actually
firms that disclose information relative
to information security risks actually
tend to do better when there's an
adverse
event against their company in terms of
being hammered on their stock prices so
you know it's so basically you say hey
you know companies are made up of human
beings things are going to happen we're
prepared for it when they do happen so
we have good incidents response and
we're going to try to do everything to
protect but when bad things happen we're
going to rebound really quickly and the
stock market rewards that we also looked
at the options market and we got a
similar story where what we know to be
informed investors know these things
happen the company's going to manage as
well as I can you know it's fine we're
kind of your day traders you're naive
investors have trouble differentiating
these signals in the market but overall
things kind of wash out for these firms
which is good in that market so we were
looking at things firm say through text
analysis or text mining so in this
project the besom project we're thinking
well you know to participate in these
activities is quite a statement about
how you approach security these are
firms that you know are really willing
to do what they can to improve their
security posture so so we look at the
Texas well as some other numerical and
ordinal data so we're looking at
particularly at the building security in
maturity model version 5 there are
several previous versions and this is
all publicly available information and
it what's interesting to us it's really
an industry driven model these are firms
that come together and say hey you know
you know what are the best practices for
us how can we say that you know we're
really mature in the way we think and
it's real focus is on secure software
development but when we look at it as
managers we say this actually applies to
your entire security posture even though
that was not the original intent of the
of the model so we say really from a
research
perspective I could say that this is
really generalizable to other tasks and
we know nothing exists in a vacuum right
if you have secure software development
if you don't have strong network
security you know you're still at
substantial risk right so it's not been
studied academically at least from the
business school perspective previously
so this is pretty cool but it does share
a lot of similarities with other pretty
well study maturity models one that many
of us in the business school are
familiar with is the software capability
maturity model out of Carnegie Mellon
where they have the five levels of
process maturity from the you're flying
by the seat of your pants at level 1 to
level 5 where you are extremely well
focused on the process and you have
procedures in place to manage your
really truly focusing on quality
assurance which makes sense not only for
security but or software but also
security we see at the business school
in other ways too there's a new product
development model there's project
management maturity models there's you
know these are pretty well established
in the business school literature but
the idea is you may have and this
doesn't have to apply to every single
process you often will have some
processes that are at one level and
others that are at maybe a more advanced
or less mature level so this has five
levels the BCM model is going to have
three levels so it's a simpler model
which has a lot of advantages the
research that has come you know as
business people we tend to ask how much
is this going to cost and what is the
value I'm going to get back and going
you know from the lower levels to the
higher levels generally say if you're
going from a very low level to the next
level there's a huge payoff given the
investment required it becomes really
questionable going from say level 4 to
level 5 and so we want to ask the same
questions of the besom model
actually we won't accomplish that in
this research but is it worth being at a
level three in the BCM model versus a
level two given the cost it's going to
take to be there and that may not be an
answerable question even at the current
point in time so about the model we
mentioned that there's going to be these
four levels there are firms that
participate in the development of the
model and this is where we're actually
looking for a lot more information but
there is the option for anonymous
participation so we don't know the names
of all those firms which from a research
perspective makes things a fun and
challenging but there are 47 identified
firms including some very big players
and they're not all tech firms but all
these firms obviously are very reliant
upon technology for their successful
operations so we see insurance we see
financial services we see technology
systems and other processors these are
just some of the firms and so the cool
thing about these knowing at least 47 of
the firm's is we can collect a lot of
data about the firm's themselves and
just kind of look a bit into their
management so there are three levels of
maturity as I've mentioned across four
domains and these four domains are
governance intelligence secured
development software development
lifecycle touch points are kind of steps
along your development lifecycle and
then deployment so there's these four
domains and they each have three levels
of maturity and there's a bit more so
about each one governance is just the we
think of them as rules for engagement in
the firm but practices that help us
manage a security initiative including
staffing which is something that we're
also interested in the management school
how do you staff and not just stopping
your technology functions or IT
management network management functions
but what happens
at the high levels of the firm what
happens if your c-suite your CEO coo CFO
do you have the CIO do you have a CISO
do you have a chief privacy officer
firms that do you tend to do better but
that's something that we found
interesting intelligence are really your
knowledge management practices about
information security how do you maintain
the organizational memory because people
cycle through your organization that's
actually very healthy to have people
being promoted into new roles people are
going to come in and people are going to
be people are going to retire and how
accessible are people using those
repositories as needed and then SSD L
touchpoints these are your practices
your project management practices more
or less within these secure software
development environments and last but
not least deployment that is really you
know implementing and managing secure
software so those four domains each has
three practices so we're getting kind of
a cube like structure going here each
practice area has six to twelve
activities that are kind of clustered
into different maturity levels and we're
making an assumption and there's not a
really great way to test this yet but
something that my colleagues thought was
interesting is you know if you are at a
level three does that mean you're at a
level one or two we're making the
assumption yes because we haven't seen
any counter examples but they may be out
there and we just haven't found them yet
so this is a screenshot from just the
website that kind of clarifies how this
is structured in terms of there are the
four domains going across the top row
there and then there are the three
practice areas which within each of the
four domains so governance has strategy
and metrics it has compliance and
policies or security policies and also
training
than in intelligence these are things
from attack models to security features
and designs are standards and
requirements SS vo touch points
architecture analysis code review
security testing and then deployment
your penetration testing your software
environment and configuration management
and your vulnerability management
activities so if you were to go to the
website you can drill down and see each
of the activities which end within each
of the four domains and three practice
areas so just to blow up one box here is
the compliance and policy to always
think is an interesting thing to look at
within firms so you can see there's a
objectives activities for each
objectives and then a maturity level
whether these are in one two or three
and each one is nicely labeled which
makes us happy when we're doing data
analysis to see that each objective and
activity is nicely neatly rolled for us
so thanks be some people that's so
awesome for us but this gives you an
idea of some of the activities that
might be in each of these boxes so what
we're trying to do we're trying to do
everything but our broad goal is we want
to at least for now we want to see what
differentiates firms that we know are
really actively engaged in the bsm model
and those that are not so this trying to
answer this question is problematic for
a number of reasons we'll get into those
but we really want to know are their
managerial differences because we can
all by the same sets of technologies we
can try to hire people with the same
qualifications but it's actually hard to
do in practice but we can try to do that
but we know that firm a is probably
going to have or they're going to do
better they're going to suffer from pure
breaches fewer things that have to be
publicly disseminated versus firm B and
that usually we attribute to well
there's something going on in the man
men of the firm that's different so
that's really kind of what we're looking
at any advice we can give difference in
terms of hey you know you know this
practice will get you this this maybe
not so much so that's what we're really
trying to look at here and as I said
this is really early so we haven't been
able to answer all the questions yet but
you know in our initial kind of early
analysis we started that you will if
we're trying to get at that second
question now what do we need to start
looking at and in this first swipe at
this research the team and I we decided
okay you know we need to know who the
firm is and what they do because we want
to make sure that we can kind of you
know look at crosses they're an industry
specific affect things like this so we
captured the firm specific factors such
as number of employees because size is
relevant firm with 10 people just
operate a heck of a lot differently than
a firm with 10,000 people the industry
there in because obviously not only the
products and services that you deliver
but the regulation and compliance
requirement insurance healthcare
insurance providers have a whole set of
rules Financial Services has a whole set
of rules commercial banking has a whole
set of rules so we wanted to control for
that we also wanted to along with number
employees kind of get an idea of how big
they are in terms of assets so we looked
at the market capitalization and one
source and Hoover's were the places to
find that then we thought well who's
running the place and do people think
highly of them so we went to
glassdoor.com which is an interesting
site from a business research
perspective because you have firms and
you have people whose association with
the firm is not necessarily well
understood being able to provide ratings
of the firm so let's say I work for
company X I had an awesome time I did my
internship there in college and then
wait just time to move on in life and I
have very happy memories of firm X i'll
give it a great review and then there's
firm x that you know is the only offer i
got out of college and knows i had to
pay my student loan so i took the job
and you know i was just a number they
really kind of sucked and so yeah give
them a bad rating so there's no real
differentiating between current and
former rate or former employees and it's
not easy to tell if people were even an
employee so i could go to say a cable
provider who likes to be trashed in the
media and even though i'm just a
customer i can write nasty things and
that's something that's really well
known in terms of these review websites
or online review systems in general is
that you tend to only get the really
happy people or they're really cranky
people that are going to put things on
so but we thought well this actually
might serve our purpose because if the
firm is doing a great job we want to
know and if they're doing a horrible job
we want to know and if they're just kind
of like you're yeah you are the best uh
okay so that really kind of gives us
three clusters to work with so we
captured the CEO approval rating which
is a number it's a typical Likert scale
one to five where five is awesome one is
crappy that's not the word they use in
the label but you can pour and there's
also a number that captures senior
management approval and there's also an
overall firm rating now as you can
imagine these tend to trend together but
we do see some interesting differences
and again that's from glassdoor calm and
we also from some previous research knew
that firms that had IT executives in the
top six highest ranked executives tend
to do better in terms of information
security so we wanted to capture that
again for this data set so we wanted the
number of IT executives which at a lot
of firms is still zero that the CIO is
not even in the top six so but if
there were a firm that had a CIO and a
CISO chief information security officer
and maybe even a chief privacy officer
come in your top ranks we wanted to
capture that as well we want to make
sure that they were paid well or how
much were they paid because again we did
some previous research that says firms
do better when you pay your IT
executives better oh gosh you know
that's good news for all of us right
being an IT and also my research team is
half actually three fifths the female
and there is some interesting research
out of the finance literature that said
that female hedge fund managers actually
tend to get better returns over time
because they are risk-averse rather than
risk seeking as a populate or a sample
not every female is risk averse not
every male is risk thinking obviously
but you know their thing you wouldn't do
you funny if you know where we see a lot
of female IT executives that firms maybe
do better in terms of managing their
risk and we'll get to that punch line
but that data is all available through
the execu cobb database that we have
here at Purdue we also wanted to know
how does the firm formally communicate
to regulators and shareholders and
stakeholders about risk so the risk
factors that firms disclose and they
don't have to disclose everything but
they can choose to disclose ones on
their 10k if they're a US based firm
door 20 up form that's filed with the
SEC if they're in an international firm
and of course I can only collect those
for publicly traded firms because of
your not publicly if you're not a public
firm you don't have to disclose that
information but we were able to identify
234 relevant risk factors from 34 of the
47 publicly named burned firms and so
you can start to see the conundrum as
researchers that we faced with the
anonymous capability of the model
because now we know there's firms out
there that participate but we can't
capture
data and we can't add it to our data set
so that's a bummer for us it's probably
you're not there for the firm's so IT
related risk factors would be things
like our data center is located near
major fault lines in California or
Washington state are due to the nature
of our business special like financial
services you know we're kind of a hacker
magnet things like that and then we
wanted to know what has been the
exposure at least the ones we know about
to information security incidents or
events so and again my colleagues like
to beat me up because and the other
information security researchers and
management because you know everybody
knows that there's a lot more breaches
than or ever reported but we can't read
people's mind so we can't get at that
data we use at data loss DB org which
has become a much richer source of data
with the various data loss notification
laws and I think we'll see some more
activity on that front and then
incidents that may not be a data loss
incident or may have been outside of a
jurisdiction that has this type of
compliant or regulatory requirement you
know things like they stole some
important patent application or they
stole our strategy documents so we use
LexisNexis to search for incidents such
as that and as you might imagine there
were a lot more data loss incidents in
rather than intellectual property loss
events but there are some in there and
we included them in the data set so
those are the things that we're looking
at currently and of course we probably
can collect even more data about
different aspects of the firm but those
are the ones are kind of what we call
low-hanging fruit from a research
perspective they're pretty easy to get
either screens gray being or getting
from a data source here at Purdue so the
first thing we looked at was the be sown
participating identified friends
themselves and we thought well you know
what are these firms like and
are they similar in their thinking are
they different so the first thing we did
is we actually took a lot of that data
that was numeric or ordinal and did some
basic regression analysis to see if
things were different and these firms
are remark I mean they kind of even
though they're in different industries
and there's some big differences between
these firms you are pretty similar or we
can say there were not many significant
differences so what we did is we went
back and say well do they kind of talk
the same way and in order to do that we
ran a cluster analysis on the text and
what happens in a cluster analysis on a
text it's similar to when you cluster
numeric data but we're looking for
phrases sentences that are similar they
don't have to use the exact language but
they're similar semantically so if I say
the Apple is red and someone else says
the Apple is Rouge those two things
being the same thing basically so what
happened was first of all we had
convergence meaning it found similar
categories of text among these risk
factors that were disclosed and we
experimentally varied this to find the
the best or the least mean squared error
and we came up with the optimal number
is five clusters and the and these are
just ID'd by the we use SAS text miner
for this and it just applied a ID really
the the biggest cluster the the number
of phrases that was the most across all
the firm's participating that we know
about is cluster number three which is
timely development market these are
companies that have some sort of product
or service that they're offering and
they actually the market concerns them
very much and so
we thought well that's interesting that
you know security is not their top one
but as we go further and software is in
that cluster the next biggest one is the
cluster ID number one which is breech
personal attack security so this is a
big concern and there really wasn't that
much difference in size between cluster
number three in cluster number one three
four and five were together much smaller
but they were also significant cluster
the next biggest cluster was cluster
five which was intellectual property and
copyright and infringement so companies
are not only protecting their data but
they know it goes beyond that we have to
protect everything that makes our firm
valuable which is usually I mean value
data is important but if you can't come
up with the next iteration of your
product if you can't bring that drug to
market you're not going to exist as a
company much longer or at least not as a
very successful one so we thought well
that's pretty cool and that kind of
dovetails nicely with some previous work
and then cluster for is the fourth
largest and that is your natural
disasters your floods your interruptions
and then finally cluster 2 is we thought
this was kind of interesting that popped
up is the risk involved with using other
people's software as part of your own
products and services for example you
use an open source product let's say you
licensed MySQL for something okay if
it's a huge vulnerability is found in
that software that can impact your
operations and there's a lot of great
open source software that firms find
very attractive to use or it could be
that we have this software bended and if
our vendor goes belly-up or it turns out
there's things full of holes that we
didn't detect they can be in a lot of
trouble because the end customer can't
differentiate what
Microsoft's product versus something
they might have included as a third
party so like I don't care obviously you
can spend it all you want but the
customer is going to associate the brand
with the problem as opposed to a third
party so we thought okay that's a good
start then we want to see where the farm
is focusing in terms of those risk
factors the visa model includes 12 must
do activities and these are listed but
identify the gate locations gathering
the necessary or defector information
privacy culture of security which means
you provide awareness training create
your data classification scheme and your
inventory build and publish your
features security features create your
standards perform your future reviews
use automated tools along with manual
tools drive test with requirements and
features external penetration tests
these are things that most people know
that they should be doing but not all do
ensure that the basics are in place for
host and network security and then
identify the bugs during operations and
beat them back to development and that
is a big problem for a lot of firms
today but these are what the BCM firms
identifies kind of must do and so we
wanted to see okay are they practicing
what they preach or they preaching what
they practice and that's kind of a
chicken and egg question but we decided
well let's look at what they say in
their communications or risk disclosures
and you know once we we thought it was a
good idea at first and then we kind of
went back and said well maybe not and
the results kind of reinforced that that
what when we look at those beasts and
must do activities they're pretty
operational in nature and the risk
disclosures are meant to be more
strategic in nature so we kind of look
at the continuum from the strategic to
the operational these are really
capturing more the operational although
we do see so we see the
first must do activity which is
established those SSTL gates we find
that the number of firms participating
and this is data from besom not from me
is about eighty-five percent but when we
searched through the or basically we ran
another analysis using text miner
looking for any associations we don't
find anything in the risk disclosures
but you think well firms probably
wouldn't say anything that specific and
their risk disclosure so we're actually
collecting a whole nother set of data to
see if we can rerun this analysis on
something that's a little bit more
operational in nature but as we go down
we do actually see some what we would
call pretty good alignment privacy is an
important topic because you know firms
generally want to do the right things
when it comes to managing or engaging
with their customers and clients and we
do see that they're talking they're
saying they're participating at
seventy-eight percent and they do say
that into a small extent about 13%
within their risk factor disclosures as
we go down promoting a security culture
I thought that was interesting that that
even popped up because I thought are
they going to really talk about that but
they do seventy-five percent say they of
the besom firm say they do it in the
besom literature but twenty-seven
percent say they do in their risk factor
disclosures which actually thought was
pretty pretty interesting it's even
mentioned they're prioritizing that
actually picked up twenty-nine percent
in the risk factors versus sixty-four
percent saying actually do you practice
that creating proactive security
guidance thirty percent refer to it in
some way they don't use those exact
words but close enough semantically
versus any one percent say they do that
meet the demand for security features
and creating standards forty percent
disclose that in their formal risk
communications we thought that was
pretty cool and so you know they kind of
are practicing what we preach we
actually need a better data set to
to reinforce that so then we started
looking back at the numeric data and the
ordinal data and we did want to look as
I mentioned before we didn't see all
that much difference but my research
assistants really were curious about
this gender question and so we figured
well if there's more females on the IT
you know in the top group and more than
were female they should be less
risk-averse meaning they should have
reduced risk exposure and fewer security
breaches well it turns out that the
relationship wasn't quite significant in
the data but we do see the right
relationship so if we collect more data
we actually should be able to get
significant we should see significant
results but then take me to the bank on
that one of the problems was we don't
have any female executives in the sample
most firms had zero although Aetna not
surprising being a healthcare related
insurance firm did have forty-two
percent of top executives being female
top I'd keep that could it's being
female not surprising the bigger you are
just the more target you are so number
of employees was positively correlated
but we had a lot of multicollinearity in
the data which means we've got to kind
of do some feature selection to get the
the statistics actually make more sense
and we did find that again the
relationship was going in the right way
but the better people write you on
glassdoor the fewer number of reach
reports that were collected from the
media sources so again not significant
but you know that actually hang a better
run firm is going to be better run in
multiple dimensions not just the
security or not just you know how many
parties you throw for your employees so
that's good so the firm's themselves are
fairly consistent manager Lee from what
we can find and that kind of leads us to
you know these firms generally speaking
are going to have an overall higher
quality of management man
people and procedures and processes in
place so what we're currently doing
because I said this was really early is
we've collected a matched set so we now
have the set of firms that we don't have
any indication now that does again from
a statistics point of view it's a little
rough because they could be
participating in BCM and we just can't
find any public trace of it but we've
come up with a matched set so for each
be sunburned we've collected three to
five kind of control firms if you will
and we're starting to do the statistics
to see what the real differences are and
we already we don't have the gender one
but we already know that the glass door
ratings aren't quite as high on these
number of breaches it looks actually
there's fewer breaches but the types are
a little bit more concerning in the
number of records laws so so that's kind
of where we are oh and I'm early but we
would really like to well we're keep
going on that but any questions that you
may have yes so these are given IP
services ever do
this will be not for mature so you know
by the pc model good luck yeah but if
you were to look at we shall meet on one
side have you also looked at companies
that have the skin dreds akin to them in
terms of IT security for example who
were the ones who designed visa or make
a fake you know Google for example which
has a big security interest by the Sun I
mean it means the portion so for
security then the VC water might not
even apply right so that's a great
question about being able to offload
risk or firms that we know Google used
to protect their not listed currently
but we kind of took them out because
it's google no no that's that's a good
example the IT outsourcing question is a
very interesting one what we're seeing
actually and that's kind of a tricky one
for us because it's a really dynamic
environment we're seeing a lot of firms
in sourcing again and so I've got some
colleagues at UIUC in michigan state
that actually look at contracts
contracts and in sourcing outsourcing so
i might ping them and see what their
perspective is but we we're seeing that
a lot of this stuff's very fluid right
now so it's kind of hard to make any
useful statements one thing in the risk
factors that they disclose they disclose
when things are not specific systems or
processes but they talk a lot about
third-party vendors which we can kind of
take to be outsourcing firms for at
least some of them and and they're very
concerned about that because you can't
completely outsource your risk because I
still have you know if it's my product
that has you know a module that someone
else designed in it and it's bad I still
get sued so but that I think is an
interesting and a deeper perspective to
take thank you
if you ask questions make sure you use
the microphone freeze any other
questions yes as you look at
management's decisions in terms of this
is what we get this is what it costs us
is there anything that you crank in
there in terms of risk so it is possible
that you overspend on something it has a
highly unlikely possibility of happening
to the detriment of other things that
are more likely to happen that's kind of
the golden ring really because we know
that unless you're mcafee or a security
company every dollar that you spend on
security may be a dollar that you can't
spend on rd or compensation or market
development so it is a really tough
position for companies to figure out
what is that best balance and research
wise I think you're seeing people ask
the question but the only answers we've
gotten have been from game theory models
which we all know are so abstract they
don't really apply that much to reality
there's been some work out of Maryland
where which is really kind of what we
all side all the time where you know
there is what they call kind of a
classic smoke stack where you do have to
look at the marginal benefit versus the
marginal cost of every dollar invested
beyond what would bankrupt your company
so beyond the catastrophic but it's not
becoming you know I think the
catastrophic and the not catastrophic is
not clearly demarcated because something
that seems little we've seen really
snowball so I think in practice figuring
out what what is what can be very murky
at best but yeah that's that's something
that we're really really curious about
do you invest up to a level three or
maybe even beyond what does that got you
does that get you the ability to sleep
at night or does it take so much
resource away from other vital functions
of the firm that you go into the death
spiral so that's that's what we're all
interested in to a great question jump
yeah you are identify some of the yet
Detroit's a has been looked at tenure of
security employees and get that makes
the thing I'm making I'm making huge
assumptions here but I mean if you have
constant journal or even your painting
well maybe people leave other reason has
that been looked at in the research yes
actually two of my former PhD students
and I looked at that very question and
we found that there's kind of a golden
area if the turnover is really high
that's not good because nobody's paying
it there's a learning curve with all of
these things and you just you can't get
acclimated enough to make some decisions
that stick if you stay too long that's
usually not a really good fun either we
didn't we didn't have enough data
because there weren't enough IT
executives in our samples and we took we
had a pretty good size sample to really
tell what that old ideal tenure is but
we know that if it's less than I think
18 months that's not good i I'll have to
look back at the paper but you know be
kind of the usual rules of thumb applied
after five to seven years people kind of
get stale yeah but we did we looked at
yeah we just found so few firms had IT
executives in those top six we were
shocked because we thought we'd find
CIOs and CIS OS and chief privacy
officer zwi thought we'd have all this
data to look with and we went through
every
for us-based firms because we're also
looking at compensation they'd had to be
publicly available so we could get the
compensation data and we were sorely
disappointed by what we found or what we
couldn't find of those firms that did
have the information officer or a
security officer in the top six were you
does this look like this is a trend that
is increasing or or just look if it's
been a constant that either do here
you're done we didn't have time series
data so we couldn't look at changes over
time we took snapshots and we know that
just tracking the media that these we
are seeing more at the first PlayStation
hacked Sony didn't have a CIO and I'm
not sure that age there but yeah so yeah
that's just one firm but and they
actually weren't in our data's that we
just kind of looked at that on the side
but yeah we there's a lot more interest
and I think the law regulation is kind
of pushing this to firms attention at
greater levels and in the past we
thought tjmaxx with it then its target
was it home depot going on but it's it's
getting there it's improving we also
consider the mergers and acquisitions
and other research going to be different
say there was an example of say some
some of these financial light and saline
voltage which was taken over by MF
Global and then they robbed the
individual icons and then maybe they pay
it back on and you can do you consider
do a yes or no we don't consider that
but that's something that because we
didn't do we weren't trying to nail down
a specific change at one point of time
but that's like outsourcing or trying
doubts or service that's
thing that we need to take into
consideration because that could you
acquire a firmer you emerge because you
think there's some value to be gained
that's going to outweigh the cost of the
transactions but it's you know really
good question how does that change your
security posture and that's something
we'll have to look at that's a great
observation thanks have you have you
observed some kind of correlation
between companies moving their data and
competition to the cloud and a higher
risk factor that they have or is it
something that you observe in there
observe that they put in their
disclaimers just like the question about
having vendors and then so it's cloud a
factor that that is something that I
looked at or quarterly we didn't find it
but I think it's because we weren't
looking in the right place when we start
looking at the more operational
information coming from firms that might
be something we pick up that some people
very interested in that topic though
because you know that's kind of a big
question right now good tan gentle but
very useful thank you yeah you mentioned
earlier like target and home depot know
the these companies that have issues
have you done any look at to see whether
other companies are reevaluating their
processes when something bad happens to
someone else is that part of this
researcher it's not part of this
research but we know that that happens
we talked to our friends in the
consulting world may help companies do
that so yeah business for them is really
good great quick yeah I mean I think
that's you know pretty you know we got a
group of is researchers that look and
they call it fad in IT so it's like when
SI p you know are three first became a
real big thing you know firms were just
all jumping or bandwagon effect you know
oh I gotta have SI p why well because
that guy's got SI p and we saw firms
bankrupt it by trying to an aside
p it's you know it's just the nature of
the beast we saw firms fail because of
an ERP implementation gone bad it just
sucks so many resources in the firm
couldn't survive so there's negative
bandwagon effects and there's positive
bandwagon effect so this would be an
example where yeah I'm sure firms are oh
my gosh you know could that happen to us
and could be so yeah plus there's things
like PCI compliance you know the
regulators and auditors are going to get
feisty and you know look more closely
which is a positive thing okay anything
else well I really appreciate all your
feedback really useful I'm going to take
that back to the team and keep going so
thanks a lot everybody