good afternoon welcome to the serious
security seminar it's my great pleasure
to introduce today's speaker kami Vania
kami is the assistant professor in
school of informatics in Indiana
University Bloomington our neighbor and
she received her PhD from the Carnegie
Mellon University her research are in
human factors in security and privacy
and today he will tell us about her
research in understanding why people
apply or not apply software updates
thank you so uh as he already stated
we're going to be talking about software
updates today and I actually really
appreciate this XKCD comic which I will
note came out after I did this research
I did not base my research on the xkcd
comment to read it to you it says urgent
critical update available details fixes
an issue that was causing random laptop
electrical fires do you think might be
serious on hits this update will require
you restarting your computer and so of
course he clicks remind me later if you
measure put a mouse over this it says I
had too many windows open this is
actually a beautiful type of vacation
for why people aren't necessarily
installing updates and really people
aren't installing updates so most of the
people in this room probably recall the
heartbleed vulnerability from last year
Hartley was a very serious vulnerability
infecting openssl if few when said it
specifically crafted connection request
to a server it would start dumping parts
of its memory this is serious problem
and it infected 600,000 vulnerabilities
this thought our servers this kind of
has a nice story too though because
shortly after we found the vulnerability
we figured out what was causing it and
we fixed it right and we fixed it by
installing a software update patch which
is how we normally fix these things
unfortunately the story since then is
not always quite as good so 600,000
server is initially vulnerable after one
month we got to a half life we patched
half so 300,000 servers two months later
we still have 300,000 servers of
vulnerable and now a year later were at
200,000 servers we only managed to patch
two thirds uh I really like software
updates as a particular research
direction because they represent what I
like to think of as solved problems some
researcher out there some security
professional figured out how to fix
hardly this is a solved problem we know
how to fix heartbleed this is not a
mystery there is no concern about how to
do this and the patches are working on
very large servers out there the server
but the patches themselves are not
broken they function but we're still
looking at a third of the servers that
are still vulnerable and this isn't just
an issue for you know big servers out
there for as you'll about to find out a
majority of my research is actually
about individuals this is a study done
by Microsoft of 10,000 Windows computers
worldwide then statistic I'm kind of
kind of draw your your eye to here is
java and i'm going to picking on java
the length of this talk seventy-two
percent of java installations worldwide
are not updated for anyone who
understands where security
vulnerabilities tend to come from java
is really high on this list uh in fact
if we were to look at the list this is a
list out of microsoft security
intelligence report they ranked the most
commonly attacked pieces of software so
for when or for windows computers
they're running their protection
software these are the piece of software
that malicious code is attempting to
break into java is its own category by
itself and it ranks only below the
internet which is you know HTML and
javascript this is a serious problem
also note adobe reader or down on number
four accounts for ninety percent of that
category updates are prominent and and
they're solved in many ways i mean most
people actually get compromised by a
vulnerability for which Apaches this is
the most commonly attack method there
exists a patch you could have been saved
but you
why why aren't people install ea's and
because I do this presentation too many
audiences of many mixed backgrounds
actually going to take a my toes set
background it back and talk briefly
about why on earth these things matter
so bear with me for a moment if you know
this so a softer update at a very high
level does one thing and that's take an
existing piece of software you currently
have and change it into a slightly
different piece of software the one I
just demoed here is iTunes actually
before and after my study so before my
study it has the sidebar on the left
after or right before my study they
changed the entire user interface they
switched everything up these are in fact
the same page before and after an update
an update just effectively goes in and
takes this thing you had before throws
that out and puts a new thing in there
now sometimes what it throws out is very
tiny and sometimes when it turns out is
very large but effectively what's doing
is taking something you already had
running and changing very high level but
go one level deeper what it does is you
have many different programs on your
computer and some of those programs have
holes or issues with them and so when
you try and you say adobe reader to open
a file that is malicious and your
version of adobe reader is old then the
malicious software our target known
vulnerabilities and we use that to
compromise your computer's gain access
to being able to do things that you
don't necessarily want to have available
if you were to update it if you closed
those holes then you and you have to
open the same file what will happen is
either nothing or the file will just
crash because it's going to attempt to
do something that the hooks that the
piece is there that it's targeting are
missing i sometimes describe this to
people ask me why aren't we just using
anti viruses if you think of this as a
castle we can either start blocking up
all the gates so there's less ways to
even get into the castle or we can start
hiring more guards java adobe reader
these are the sorts of programs that
have a lot of open gates and every time
we find one we patch it we close it and
then we don't need as many guards
because there are less ways to get into
the system and so that's just that's a
really high level but what
we're really concerned here is why are
people not updating software why are we
having this problem and to answer that
this is research I did well still a
postdoc at Michigan State with Rick wash
and Emily reader we did a multi-method
study so what we did was we brought in
participants we ran a custom powershell
script on their computers to collect a
lot of information about settings
information about log files basically
being opportunistic about what's
typically recorded by the average
Windows machine we had them fill out a
survey in the lab to get some structured
information and then we did an hour-long
interview with them asking them about a
couple different scenarios and
specifically trying to get them to talk
about prior experiences they'd had with
updates and how they they frame
decisions involving updates we use 37
non-technical graduate students now keep
in mind this is graduate students this
is a convenient sample their age ages
are pretty good and we surprisingly got
a pretty good mix of male and female I
will however note that even though we're
looking at graduate students that
theoretically have their theses on their
machines and you know their research
data on their machines we were not
looking at in many ways this is a more
educated group this is a group that has
something that they want to protect and
tie their computer and we're still
seeing this many security issues so our
participants 15 of them had at least one
major security issues six had antivirus
installed or not installed or disabled
in some way to turn their firewalls off
seven had either completely turned off
user account control or change it to a
lower setting for those of you who don't
know what user account control is it's
the thing that makes windows ask you
before it installed software if it's off
windows doesn't ask you before
installing software six of them had
either turned off windows update or
unlimited it in some way so we're not
nests are perhaps a better sample we're
still seeing a fair number of problems
also I realize I probably have a lot of
mac users
in the audience you may not have had
this Windows Update experience happen to
you very often so I'm going to spend a
moment explaining how Windows Update
works this is a fairly complicated
graphic what we're going to focus on is
the three boxes that are colored so the
first box is as blue box entitled
scheduled so what windows does is it
goes out periodically on your behalf and
looks to see if there's any new updates
just checks for on your behalf it just
checks for them what finds one it
automatically pulls it down and then
creates a scheduled time period for it
to be updated and notifies you it puts
up a little dialogue in the corner that
just says their updates available you
should install them and then it moves
into the green box which I like to think
of as the hands-off box it just doesn't
do anything unless the user decides to
do something this is the moment in which
the user is given the opportunity to
find a convenient time to update their
software so you know if you were busy
this is when you have the chance to go
and pick that point when you're not busy
before you do the software update maybe
need to redo the reboot if you fail to
get this done before 3am the computer
will do it for you we move into the red
box the forced one so what will happen
is Windows is decided well this is a
major security problem we need to
install it so 3 a.m. or soon thereafter
it just starts installing all the
updates once it's finished installing
the updates it decides if it needs a
reboot by the way it doesn't actually
always need a reboot if it does need a
reboot it starts with I like to think of
as the countdown dialog where it starts
at ten minutes and if you don't catch
the dialogue before the end of ten
minutes your computer automatically
reboots if you do catch the dialog you
can't get rid of it all you can do is
delay it by a maximum of four hours at
which point it pops back up again and if
you miss it your computer reboots and
then obviously at the end of this
process you have an updated computer and
this is actually one of the outputs of
this research because this was very
non-obvious to our participants this
wasn't even necessarily obvious to me
beforehand how this structure works and
it's really interesting because in many
ways it's trying to be polite to
end-users it's giving you an opportunity
to determine whether or not you
want to install an update right now and
it's giving you that time frame in order
to figure it out I should note that this
is also windows 7 windows 8 does
something very similar but the time
frame is larger I believe it gives you
two days and through experimentation I
can tell you you can push that two days
to about a week before it starts having
a fit and it forces this reboot alright
so that I'm going to start by talking
about the log files so this is the the
more structured information we pull this
information almost exclusively about
windows itself because it's very verbose
in its logging and many of the other
programs weren't or were harder to
extract this login permission actually
backing up just half a second so our
participants actually had three
different possible levels for automatic
software updates so if I go back to the
prior box off is off it doesn't do any
of this if you have it set to notify
only it only does the blue box so all
it'll do is check for updates and let
you know that they're there but it won't
try to automatically do anything and
then the default setting is to do
everything on this graph where I
automatically spots them gives you a
moment to install them and if you fail
to install them it will install them for
you and as you'd expect we have this
sort of layout so the majority of people
had the default setting for participants
had changed its notified so it won't
automatically install it'll just tell
them to install and two of them had
completely disabled when looking at the
windows logs what we're interested in is
really two questions our users
installing updates and our users
installing updates quickly so if they're
not installing the updates they are
going to become vulnerable period end of
story if they're not installing the
updates quickly they're they're
installing them but they have this time
frame which they're vulnerable so again
if you're not familiar with how updates
work what tends to happen is Microsoft's
a pushes out an update all the bad guys
download the update they install it and
then they take the old version and the
new version and they say what's
different between these two versions
because what's different is where the
hole is as soon as they find the hole
they start writing malicious software
which means that
as soon as an update is published as
soon as it becomes publicly available be
a number of pieces of malicious software
targeting it skyrockets every paper I've
seen has a different number and it's
usually somewhere between like four
hundred percent increase in several
thousand percent increase so the faster
you install updates the safer you will
be and so it is important that not only
they are installing them but that they
are installing them quickly so I'm just
going to lean forward and see what
whether or not yellow okay good yellow
is showing up alright so what you are
looking at here is all of our
participants on each participant is a
dot green dots are the people who are
automatic yellow dots the people who are
just being notified and read people
weren't installing updates so they're
not on this graph I know it's a little
hard to see but I believe yeah so this
is 200 here people are installing a lot
of updates it's actually shocking the
number of updates Windows pulls down at
any given moment and it's installing at
all times but what you are seeing here
is a big difference between the yellow
and the green dots unfortunately we kind
of have too few people that have notify
settings to reliably do statistics on
this but we're not seeing a horrific
setting here in fact they are installing
these updates and they're installing
that it very similar time periods also
if you can't tell this is months own
this is at 20 months so a year is
sitting about here all right so if we're
not seeing many differences in the
numbers installed let's look at the time
to patch now we are seeing some
differences here again yellow is the
number of people are the people who have
notified setting in this case this is
dazed update so a month is sitting at
the center of the graph here the we're
looking at about a hundred and fifty
updates per person and the median is six
days for the notify condition and 2.6
days for the automatic so we are seeing
difference but keep in mind we can only
have four users so let's break this out
so you're looking at basically the same
graph here but I've sorted
it by the medians starting from the
lowest median on the left to the highest
median on the right what's really
interesting about this is that for the
majority of the notify participants the
median is actually sitting way down at
the bottom of these box and whisker
plots this person actually doesn't use
their machine a lots they have a lot of
variation same story with these green
ones nearby it isn't ah they told me to
do that all right so you can kind of see
here at the bottom of the yellow boxes
that the median sitting at the bottom
these people are actually installing
these updates most of the time fairly
quickly and then on occasional timeframe
there they're delaying it for a long
time now if you try to delay it and
you're on automatic the windows has a
fit and automatically installs it for
you and just forces the reboot which is
why we see most the green people sitting
down at the lower ends here if you don't
then you have the option to delay it for
longer but this is actually this is kind
of a mixed story because on one hand
it's actually really good we're seeing a
lot of people installing it quickly even
though they have notify and we're seeing
it work properly for the automatic
settings but you know we are also seeing
the sort of thing we're concerned about
which is this greater delay that's
happening so it's kind of a mixed bag
yeah why you have this long grain bars
so if it's automatic why up they take
that long they don't know the completely
time difference between when the patch
was published by Microsoft and one is
installed by the laptop Christmas
particularly for graduate students is a
time period where they might like close
the laptop and not open it again for two
or three weeks and that causes this
situation across both experimentally I
tried to figure out if I could determine
if the machines were on or off and then
subtract that time period but we didn't
have on/off logs for them for a long
enough time frame if you look at it for
just the time frame when we did have it
it starts looking a lot better but I'm
iffy on saying that because we don't
have enough
nation so another question is one of I
guess two slides back you show there's a
one yellow dot which installed more
updates than the other green one this is
because some of the if the update is not
critical than automatic update do not do
it well why so my best guess at this is
Microsoft does this behavior called
bundling of updates so what they'll do
is they'll release an update and written
up update and then when they hit this
the third update they go well really we
should just put all those those earlier
updates together into one update roll
them together and then just release one
forward and so what I did that the
number of updates or that it's possible
to differentiate this because they do
post the information but it is in a very
hard to parse movement saying and I
didn't want to throw enough undergrads
at basically reading through all of
these documents at figuring out which
thing can came to which one but that's
what causes it the other one that you
haven't brought up but you may have
noticed is I cut this graph off this
graph actually heads way the heck up all
the way up into past one year the other
cause for this is that sometimes I don't
need an update right away like this
device when i first plugged it into my
machine installed a driver automatically
and that driver may have had an update
associated with it which i did not need
up until the moment in which i plugged
it into the system and then i suddenly
needed it and so microsoft may have
released this two years ago and I just
now installed it and so you have these
long time theories that I haven't
figured out how to remove from the data
set yet mostly were removing them in
this case by just pulling them out
because they look like outliers all
right any more questions on this piece
before I kind of start moving into the
survey alright so that was entirely
windows logs when I start talking about
the survey we're going to start mixing
talking about windows and talking about
some of the applications install the top
of it I've just thrown this up here
again in case we'd spent a lot of time
before we don't really need to talk
about it all right so what you're
looking at here is the way people are
answering a survey versus the way our
log file parser determines what their
system is actually doing and the number
the fella teach group so the in the
upper left hand corner for example
is all the participants who all knew
that they were being notified before
installation and not if the system
wasn't in automatically installing so
they changed it so the system was not
doing an automatic installation and they
knew that if I color this graph for you
because okay good colors show up the
people in the green boxes are correct
the people in the red boxes are wrong I
want to distinguish between them being
wrong and being in the dangerous state
because that's two different situations
but the four people that change to
notify knew that they change to notify
which is perhaps why we're seeing them
updating things fairly quickly they know
it's their responsibility I should also
note that there should be two people in
the disabled category but one of them
indicated on the survey that they did
not have windows installed I swear they
had windows installed but it caused the
logic and the survey software to not ask
them this question which is why they're
not here so getting back to so one of
the reasons we're probably seeing the
the quick installation by the notifies
they know that they have to do this they
are aware that they change their
settings what's really interesting
actually is that 20 of our subjects that
have it set to automatically install
don't think that they think that Windows
asks them but then never automatically
installs anything they think it's their
responsibility to do this and when we
interview them we actually get a
consistent response here they think that
so just to back up two slides if you
went and you always took advantage of
that green box so every time it popped
up and said you have new updates
available you clicked yes I want to
install them you might never learn that
there is a red box uh and so a fair
number of our participants felt that
they were notified before an
installation but that no automatic
installation was ever done and it's
possible that for I haven't tried
pulling this out as much I catch I did
pull this out there they're a mixed bag
some of them are actually being having
forced installations happen on their
machines some of them aren't but they
the perception that situation is that
they actually are being asked and the
system is not necessarily
doing it on their behalf verses eight of
our participants that believe that it's
actually there that the system is
automatically forcing this situation so
we're seeing this is I realize not news
most users don't properly necessarily
understand how their systems are
behaving when it comes to software
updates but it is interesting to see
where they are falling and that a large
number of people believe that updating
software is with something that they
personally have to do and that the
system may not do for them I I promise
to pick on Java so let's look at the
same graph for java java is a little bit
different in that we can't reach in and
figure out what java settings are and at
the time of the study java was not doing
any automatic updates so the fact that
the row of automatic updates in the
survey is completely blank they're
correct there it's not automatically
updating and it's always asking them so
instead of looking at the setting we
looked at whether or not it was
currently updated the day at the date
then we ran this survey and broke it out
equivalently on the three people that
think it's not installed and it's not
installed or obviously correct what's
kind of terrifying here though is that
out of all of these participants only
nine of them have it updated I mean this
is actually fairly consistent with what
I showed at the beginning of the
presentation people aren't updating Java
they just don't and what's almost more
terrifying is that they know the system
will not update itself if you look at
the survey there's an option here auto
installs updates no one picked it they
all know that the system is asking them
to do the installation and that and then
they're not doing it this is a conscious
decision and so this isn't a mistaken of
understanding kind of what's going on
here so of course that leads me into the
next part which is well what happens
when we actually asked them this
question what do you think's going on
here and why are you picking these these
options in order to do this and we don't
necessarily
have enough time for me to dig through
all the details of how we did this
analysis but it's called a thematic
analysis we did interviews we went
through the interviews we coded up
particular concepts they're coming out
of it I'm going to be talking about
several pieces of software the software
i'm mentioning was actually not brought
up by us participants uniformly picked
these software's to talk about as a
common point of concern or problem and
when I hit certain ones of them will
explain why because sometimes particular
update happened right before our study
which caused the participant to be
irritated about that particular one and
mention it so the the first theme that
really came out here is this concept was
surprised you their interface changes
right before our study iTunes decided to
go from there prior interface where they
had a sidebar that showed music to a
interface that's modal so if you want to
go from books to music you have to click
on the thing that says books and then
select the drop-down item that says
music one of my subjects describe this
is oh my god where'd my music go there
was some distinctive concern about the
the updating behavior here and this is
typify din a quote so I always worry
that everything is going to get screwed
up especially for itunes updates or
things like that because they're always
reconfiguring the layout of stuff and
I'm like I don't want you to do that
just like leave it alone this is
actually a really common comment from
participants they're like I have this
thing it's working I liked the way it
was working and then suddenly you just
changed it on me and I did not like to
change 24 of our participants had iTunes
installed eight of them had actually
some in some way either stopped
responding to the update requests after
this or completely disabled and I can't
tell which one it is I can just tell you
the eight of them no longer had an
updated version of itunes so the first
question you might ask is who cares its
iTunes I mean sure maybe if they're
downloading really evil music mp3 files
off the internet maybe that's a problem
but it means in itunes who cares i
actually had this question personally
myself so i went and did some googling
i tunes like who the heck cares about
all the security I found that the the
update before the one that my
participants hated actually patched 162
security vulnerabilities including
remote code exploits serious stuff and
when you start digging into why it had
that many vulnerabilities you discover
this interesting though perhaps obvious
fact which is that iTunes runs a web
browser doesn't just run a web browser
it runs WebKit web kits the thing that
makes chrome run and it's the main thing
that makes Safari run so if you have
written a vulnerability and it works
against chrome or it works against
Safari there's a non-trivial chance of
the work against iTunes and I especially
had my students with Macintoshes attempt
this on websites if you craft a URL
properly it just auto opens a night in
iTunes right like it's an iTunes it
wants to open into the store just pulls
it straight up and so you have that I
really like this example mostly because
it's it's not obvious like you wouldn't
normally link iTunes it's a security
problem our subjects definitely didn't
like the guy turns to the security
problem but many pieces of software you
don't normally think of as security
problems on your system can in fact be
this way and it's a situation in which
decisions involving a user interface are
causing security problems these people
completely stopped updating to prevent
this user interface change they will
have security problems in the future
that are caused by the user interface
decisions that are being made and how
things are packaged so moving on to
another one again Java unused and
unrecognized software for those of you
don't know what Java is just in case you
don't Java is a pro or a broadly it's a
program that lets other programs run so
there's your computer there's Java
there's your favorite game so your
favorite game sits on top of Java which
since it's on top of the computer if you
remove the Java out of the middle your
game stops working this is important
because most people never hit Java when
they click on the something off the
start menu they hit my favorite game
and it's not necessarily evidence the
13th with Java and you can tell this
from the quotes from participants so I
don't know why the hell I need a Java so
I ignore it and I'm pissed off and I
think I have a tendency like when I see
Java pop up in the corner I'm like fu
java get off of my screen why are you
still here I very frustrated participant
on I will note the right before our
study Java had a string of security
vulnerabilities which is not an uncommon
event for java and this caused people to
have to hit you know the ok button or
ignore this Java thing a lot frequently
and so this was we did not actually ask
them explicitly about Java other than
the survey but they all mentioned it was
like yeah um and yes seventy-four
percent were not updated yes I remember
there was a period it seems java will
ask for updating every day even an
update today tomorrow it will show up
again so I actually ended up not not
responding to it so I guess maybe that's
a similar experiment here it's for some
reason just to frequent so I like I
don't know why I haven't actually asked
them is deep suspicion they're not
bundling the updates so you install
update 1 and then you've been ignoring
update 1 for so long there's now update
2 and then by the time you get around to
update to update 3 happens I can tell
you that your experience is not abnormal
I talked to people on airplanes and in
lines and all sorts of things about
their negative update experiences and I
have frequently heard this this opinion
like I just hit that button why do I
have to hit the button again is this a
virus is it broken that didn't come back
so much as much in this study but yeah
it definitely happens the other one
though I want to talk about is so if
you're familiar with Java there's kind
of two camps in computer security when
it comes to Java one camp is get that
thing off your machine it's really
dangerous you should uninstall it and
never use anything that involves jobs
this is one camp the other camp believes
you can't get it off your machine it's
needed for too many things you need to
update it and you need up in it quickly
so this
just to describe it one of our
participants was like oh there's all
these Java requests I should figure out
what Java is before I decided you know
should I be hitting this pattern out so
she did the rational thing she googled
it do I want to install the java update
you know some of the forums say you
should install the update because we'll
make it better other forms are like just
take it off your computer completely she
hit the end of this and she decided you
know that not to touch it because she
doesn't know what to do one half is
telling her to get through this Java
thing the other one is telling her to
hit the buttons like she has a vote for
both buttons what does she do and the
answer is don't do anything you might
damage it and and this is another reason
we're experiencing problems with Jabba
this is why Java is updated so poorly so
moving on to the third one that we
identified out of this research is
currently functional software adobe was
a beautiful example of this I also like
to refer this category if it as if it
ain't broke don't fix it it's working
don't mess with working things I I feel
like if I'm really used to software I'm
using it and I think it's meeting my
needs I won't update the software I just
don't see what an update to adobe reader
can do I mean it's PDF files it's
viewing them it's he wrong I mean when
he hits the PDF file button the PDF
shows up why would I need to do this I
nearly inserted this graphic I found
online that states on it you know it's
just it's the the logo for a dub ereader
it's like the same program for the last
decade needs to update every day this is
a why does it need to update everybody
it's working its functional I don't need
to waste the time on it and and this was
also heavily singh I'll also note that
when we presented the sakai we had
someone come up and explained to us that
they've had to have this conversation
with software engineers previously
before because this is not obvious and
the reason that is that many people see
this as you have this document it's
sitting
on your hard drive it's just sitting
there so what's the computer doing it's
picking it up off the hard drive and
it's showing it to you so how could this
have anything to do with security right
it's just taking a static thing and it's
showing it to you and that is not what
it's doing right it's doing a lot of
complicated things just like the
Internet has to do some things in order
to show display this concept content to
you also adobe reader has to do
calculations and it allows all sorts of
other things to run to in order to
display something to you so it can
actually be serious in dangerous all
right so that is the the work I did at
Michigan State talking primarily about
like just talking with this small set of
users so now the Indiana University
we're starting to try to move some of
this resource forward into new
directions and this is so what a might
reside is not finished work it is work
then which we are planning to hit the Go
button on soon but we don't actually
have the results of soon so I'm just
dating that up front part of the problem
here is we're looking a small set and we
we can see some of the problems people
are having but we're not really sure how
do you address them or how widespread
they are or even what's out there to
address them right now so what's out
there to address them right now is this
right this is like now every time I see
a software update pop up on my computer
I screenshot it it's an automatic
behavior at this stage I have piles of
screenshots of these things some of them
are really good like the one in the
middle here I this update addresses
customer issues and security
vulnerabilities Adobe recommends that
you always install the latest updates
all right so does this update change my
user interface I don't know ah watch I
might know what this software is that's
more likely but there's nothing on this
thing trying to explain to me what the
software is it's not trying to address
that concern and if it ain't broke don't
fix it well I don't even understand if I
am customer issues and if I don't think
it's broken right now then what customer
issues and this is a common thing so
what I talked about before is strong
things that came out of the research
what this list is is it's a longer set
of things that either came out weekly or
based on other research I think are
things that people are concerned about
yeah what happened when your creative
details what kind of detail do yoga
trying to member happen racket it wasn't
useful I think it shipped me over to the
adobe update webpage mm-hmm I know
though father like Java more information
I do not have the job and more
information is not particularly useful
oh sorry won't let me go back through
them one by one it's probably gonna
bring the back up honestly I think the
most useful one I've ever seen and I
perhaps you have screenshotted here was
Wireshark so if you look at this list
here and you look at a Wireshark update
they actually have a whole document
that's their release notes the on the
outline for the document basically reads
like this list starting with a
description of what's Wireshark which
theoretically you should know if it's on
your machine but they don't just even
assume that they start with a
two-sentence what is Wireshark and in
the bottom left-hand corner they even
have a skip this update option so if you
don't want this update you just hit that
button the next update will show up but
it won't bother you about this one
anymore it's probably one of the more
usable ones I've seen since I've started
screen shopping now admittedly I'm
screen shouting the ones on my machine
and we're looking at trying to do this
more broadly with a with different
groups but let me go through this list
quickly talking about some of the things
that are on it and why they are on it
the first one should be obvious from the
presentation I've done thus far people
are really concerned about whether or
not their user interface will change and
many update dialogues do not actually
address this topic which makes it very
difficult for me to tell the difference
between something that's just going to
make some changes underneath that I
don't see it's something that's going to
require me to relearn my entire user
interface or figure out where my music
one on the second ones usage and this is
something people brought up a lot was do
I use this program java fell straight
into this bucket am i actually using
this because if i'm not using it why am
i spending time updating it why am i
having to up really
boot my computer if I don't actually
need the update it's not going to be
valuable to me why would I waste that
time or take that risk and so my
personal usage of it actually comes very
strongly into this this includes whether
or not i'm using it right now whether or
not trying to update it while at fact
impact my ability to can keep doing
things the company reputation comes in
very strongly what happened last time i
had a lot of people talk about Java
updates and actually a positive manner
they're like oh a java update well when
i see one of those i know i'm going to
hit the box nothing on my computer is
going to like freeze up or cause any
problems it's just going to run and if
it asks for a reboot I can just tell it
know when it will respect that and
because of this opinion those people are
updating Java they're like this thing
doesn't get in the way it doesn't cost
me any grief that hasn't caused me grief
the last time compare that to the iTunes
quote I gave you earlier in which they
are going ja itunes apple always messes
stuff up when i hit that button they're
going to screw it up and when they have
that opinion their willingness just
update things is actually really low I
talked to Apple users and their odds of
telling me that they're going to
research an update is a whole lot higher
than when i talk to Windows users
they're suspicious they actually go out
there and look just figure out what this
update is going to do because Apple
might screw it up um computing resources
also a major issue if you're an Apple
user particularly if you're an apple
phone user they actually I talked to
ones all the time they won't install the
updates because the updates will
increase the size of the operating
system and will take away to space on
their hard drives of their phones and
they need all the space or they may not
even have enough space to pull down the
update this is a serious concern when I
was on the interview circuit I remember
someone actually showing me two versions
of Lightroom like it's Lightroom isn't
it that they use running simultaneously
because the new version apparently isn't
memory efficient enough to handle the
file sizes the old version was running
and so he had to keep the old version
around just because it couldn't handle
or manage memory properly so resources
are actually a major issue features
apple maybe I should have said I was
going to pick on Apple
um i have another quote from an apple
participant who basically said that well
you know the old apple devices sometimes
you just can't use them with the new
versions of itunes I actually talked to
a tech journalists once who is like I
have the virus ridden computer in which
that was in quotes by the way through ur
doing virus written computer that i have
for updating my old ipod because i can't
install any new versions on it because
if i do it'll no longer work with my old
ipod and so sometimes be sure show up
which is a really positive thing so like
some people are updating itunes because
they needed to work with their new phone
or because it had new new bell or
whistled that they really liked some
people were blocking updates because
they thought they would stop working
with an older file format or if they
would they lose the ability to interact
with a particular device monetary costs
come came up in some cat sometimes
though its most updates today are
typically free but sometimes they're not
so particularly an upgrade so if I'm
moving from Windows say XP up to Windows
8 that will cost me money and that might
make a serious decision point um
compatibility this came up actually in
reference to browsers more you've got
all these plugins and when the browser
rolls forward some percentage of them
just stopped working and if that was a
really valuable plug-in to me I will
block this update and I don't know if
that will happen or not a beautiful
example of this is actually screen
readers I was talking with a blind user
who had every update on her automatic
update on her entire machine turned off
because if one thing updated and
disabled the screen reader she would
lose the ability to even fix the problem
because she couldn't see it so unless
something was approved as working with
her screen readers she would not move
anything forward everything was blocked
and that I can't tell her she's wrong
like she's making a very rational
decision security is an interesting one
on here because I keep wanting to add it
and my participants don't keep not
adding it but the way that they do talk
about security is whether or not
something is a security related software
so people will talk a lot about updating
their antivirus they will update their
antivirus this is important for security
they will update their browser
bad things coming off the internet they
don't update iTunes what the heck does
that have to do with security so
something is perceived as being
security-related they are more likely to
update it because of that but they won't
necessarily update these other things
that might be security-related or they
might not believe it we had one
participant it expressed that um well
okay Matt we told them will imagine that
this the softer told you this was an
urgent security update and his
responsible how does the computer know
it's urgent and if we have lack of trust
in some of these machines i mean like
how does this person who's sitting all
the way over in Microsoft know what's
best for my machine I am the one sitting
in front of this I get to decide whether
or not something is surging and so
there's sometimes a lack of belief
there's also a lot of opinions about
bugs so issues involving that I think
I'm probably running low on time someone
want to tell me I actually don't know
when this ends so the clock in front of
me is not helpful okay is that before I
didn't start getting questions or shy
okay i will skip through this then i
just wanted to kind of point out that
there is a second round to this is
reasons people won't install and then
there's reasons people won't install
right now this is kind of different the
two difference i've talked about earlier
right are people installing updates at
all and why are people installing
updates necessarily right now and they
are different lists there's a lot of
similarities but a lot of them have to
do with things like budgeting time in
case one of those other things happens
so if I might not hit the Update button
right now on itunes I might wait to the
weekend when I know I have time to
relearn the user interface if it causes
that problem and if I know the user
interface not right not isn't going to
change maybe I will go and make that
decision maybe I'll do the update now
but if I have that risk I have to budget
for it and there's a lot of elements
active budget for like reboots can I go
back different sorts of things that
control whether or not i'm updating
right down i'm just going to skip
through the minor point i had there and
we'll skip to questions we still have
time for it so thank you very much
I have questions have you done any
research on these windows which comes up
and they ask you this version that you
are using is kind of odd would you like
to update and are usually very
apprehensive to do that because
sometimes i'm suspicious they're putting
something in that they can get in later
on so i have to go to the original
website to do it have you done any
research on that i haven't but i really
do want to this is kind of those spaces
we're moving into so we're trying to
look at two things moving forward 1 i'm
trying to do in a survey in which we
elicit experiences from users just
trying to get a broader sense of what's
going on the other one in which i want
to take a couple of these screenshots
like the ones I showed you here and just
put them up in front of users in a
survey format and ask them ask them a
pile of questions like do you think this
is valid or do you think this is a real
one do you think this is going to change
yours or interface like going down a lot
of elements of that list I can tell you
from not necessarily software updates
but just in very general users have a
lot of trouble differentiating between
like that pop up that came off the
internet and this incredibly important
security dialogue if you don't have a
lot of experience is difficult to tell
the difference between something
blinking and telling you who you have a
virus online blinking is starting to
become something that they've learned to
avoid but just something popping up on
line that says you have a problem and
something popping up in your computer
can be very different so something I've
specifically done but it is reasonably
well known at this point in the field
and yeah it's also particulars at this
domain many times you're dealing with
security the the answer is to have the
operating system show you the the
request but many of these dialogues are
actually designed by each individual
system one of the things I would really
like to move into and hopefully we'll
start doing is looking at mobile devices
and whether or not using things like the
app stores is actually improving some of
the issues you're talking about because
now you have an authoritative source
from which you can get the update
information you don't have to guess
if I was all four others included office
maybe in some kind of nice ones that can
or something that if your evenings are
gonna wear out there was something
automatically stop those things haven't
you will help you there over the wall
coming so it's a mixed Samantha sweet
this is not the focus of the study so I
only know it tangentially when we
identified an issue like that we tried
to make sure the participant knew before
they left they may have totally ignore
us one of the people that turn off his
firewall did so because it was
interviewing with some older game they
like to play and so he just disabled the
firewall antivirus is a couple of our
participants were actually on Macs in
which they had installed a vm and so I
would get this tone from them that
they're on a Mac they're fine and
they're not fine a vm is like they were
running an actual Windows computer
there's there's no strong
differentiation between because it's on
a Mac or it's on an actual Windows
machine but they didn't have that
opinion they were on a Mac similar
opinion might be that i'm on a mac and i
don't really have anything important in
here all i'm using this for is running
the you know spss you know stuff with my
research in it ah but sometimes that and
i also have had several participants
tell me that they don't go too dangerous
parts of the internet and because of
that they don't feel like they or that
they can differentiate between dangerous
and non dangerous things and so it's a
range of i've also had security
researchers previously tell me that
antivirus is actually don't do that much
which i have an entire opinion on that
topic they're not necessarily wrong but
it's only because so many people install
antivirus is that it's not worth making
viruses as many much nowadays and if
everybody had that opinion we'd probably
see a resurgence and the amount of virus
is used
but have a comment following which a
question you're talking about Java
earlier that you know Java is probably
one of the most widely unpatched
application that you think about but
isn't it justified that you know because
Java is one of the largest used
languages for web right now and it's
used on all the most largest number of
production machines patching is a bit
difficult with Java so having said that
have you looked at standardized data
with Java and that's a windows update or
adobe updates have you sign it as it and
seen how much of a difference it is I
know but that's because I kind of have
the wrong data set what's going on here
is so first off there's end-users
machines there's typically what I've
been showing out here which are not
production machines and typically the
most valuable Java related thing they're
running is either something from their
company or that game that they really
care about and both of those are equally
you know internally valuable to someone
so I don't think that's really
necessarily what you're concerned with a
more interesting statistic is the
heartbleed one or the one for a PHP
someone did a survey on that actually if
you look that one out they have a lot of
different languages and what whether or
not they're patched on servers they
found eighty percent of servers running
a version of PHP with a known security
vulnerability this is a this is a
problem and we don't it's not just Java
Java is the easiest one to pick on in
many regards but like adobe reader adobe
flash both of those have benefited by
the fact that the web browsers have
started bundling them so if you have an
automatic update in chrome or firefox
you have an automatic update of flash as
it's used i also want to just in case
here in the audience and you don't know
the difference java is not JavaScript
Java is very rarely used on the internet
anymore it's actually primarily
JavaScript which does beat out Java on
that list typically Java is for for
local machine issues all right there was
an hour question
and they did some encryption algorithm
within the software so like most of the
software's that use Java for encryption
purpose it would not function in Java
update it is that one of the reasons to
consider also it's actually just
slightly different so a question I got
from a prior audience was about these
emails they would get all the time from
their IT department and the email is
like update Adobe right now don't update
Adobe right now do update java right now
don't update java this version do you
update this one I and you get I don't
know entirely the answer to that I
suspect that fatigue about hitting these
stupid buttons and not knowing what Java
where are much larger reasons but
there's also the secondary level of
input people are getting from IT
departments it from other groups that
are trying to manage software
compatibility within organizations and I
don't know how much people are learning
from that and neither taking it home or
learning from that not to touch this
thing both of it both lessons I think
might be contributing to something like
this and causing that sort of trouble
the other thing I'll notice there's an I
haven't gotten into the economics of
this sort of a situation but there is a
lot of interesting economics if
everything is updating very rarely do
you write software that is the entire
stack nowadays typically you don't want
to reinvent the wheel you use a library
so you pull down libraries ABCD all the
way through Z and you use all of them in
your software if a single one of them
changes single one updates and isn't
compatible your entire software breaks
and when all of them are updating on
these tight update cycles the odds that
one of them is going to scrub your
software actually gets really high and
how much effort are you you're willing
to put out particular when we start
dealing with these situations in which
we have a lot of developers that are
developing for free they're doing
open-source development now how much
like maybe I wrote the most awesome
widget effort for Firefox but I did it
back in firefox 3 odds are my most
awesome widget no longer work
and I don't know what Firefox number
we're at now but it's a large one and
even if I fix it today the odds are
Firefox are going to mildly change their
their API and it will be broken tomorrow
and so I am partially curious how much
this updating this continual source of
change is causing a negative effect not
just for end-users and security and
updating but also for security of like
things like servers and all of these
other sorts of elements which are
specifically not updating their
libraries because updating their
libraries is so much work and one of the
things I would really like to see happen
in which I'm kind of working towards
with these questions is trying to figure
it out if you were to decide whether or
not you wanted to update a library what
are the most important facts to know and
how can we get the developer who made
that update to answer them and can they
answer them easily right if you make it
too hard for them they're not going to
answer them but if you can find easy
questions they can't answer that will
actually help facilitate this transition
to differentiate between update that is
likely to break your stuff and update
this is not likely to break your stuff
the odds of getting the they'll not
going to break your stuff updates
installed like I hope will improve