stand by 30 seconds
good afternoon welcome to the serious
security seminar today it's my pleasure
to introduce young-hee kwan-yuen he is a
PhD student in the Department of
Computer Science at Purdue his research
interests include but not limited to
dynamic and Static binary program
analysis reverse engineering and
assistant security and he's focusing on
solving security and debugging problems
using dynamic binary analysis
translation and transformation
techniques he's a recipient of the 6th
soft distinguished paper award and the
best paper award from ase 2013 that is
the conference on automated software
engineering hello thanks for attending
this talk today I'm going to talk about
a p2c understanding output data fires
we're on the fly transformation from
producer to consumer execution this work
is a joint work with sra international
and cisco systems and i was presented at
ndss this year and let me start with a
simple question what is the program and
what they do so it's simple and it's
easy question you can find the answers
from the slide very quickly so the
program just take inputs and process it
and outputs and the computer programs
generate a lot of outputs and some of
them stored on to the fires and some of
them are sent out to other computers
through the networks but here is the
question do we really know what kind of
data are stored to or send out to the
other computers the answer is
unfortunately no for example many of you
see these kind of windows in many cases
that is when some program crashed they
say that they're going to send some
information they're going to collect
some information and send
these two their servers to investigate
the crash later but do we really know
what kind of data they really collect
sure no so the understanding unknown
data virus or net on messages is a
prominent security challenge and let me
keep your concrete example so a user
download and install some few freeware
programs and use it for wire and weeks
later he found some mysterious binary
fires in his computer and sure
intuitively it is mysterious binary
fires you can think of they are
generated by this one of the pier
programs but you don't know really who
create these files so without audit
logging and monitoring systems is
difficult to answer these following two
questions first to create these fires or
whether do they contain actual private
data for example private personal
profile or content list or keystroke
that you don't want to share and again
these mysterious mysterious binary
buyers are just finery so without
knowing the data structures in the virus
if you can just open these files on the
hex editors or you can see it's just
sequence of the hex so you don't really
have chance to understand the data fires
this problem is actually has been there
for a long time so there are many input
format reverse engineering techniques
based on consumer programs such as a
prospect and chimney and the word and
here I want to first define consumer
programs and the producer programs
consumer programs are the programs that
we and understand the input buyers
producer programs are the programs that
generates such input fires so
the key idea behind the input format
reverse engineering techniques is that
they monitor the execution of consumer
programs and they analyze the execution
to understand how the fires or messages
are parsed in the consumer program so
let me give you an example we have fire
that we want to analyze on the left side
and the program the consumer program
they read and understand the file on the
right side so it the consumer program
first call every to read a field normal
file the field contains a string James
here and later at the program cause
string copy function and one of the
parameter is the proper we just read
from five so at this point we know that
the proper actually a string type and
then we propagate back this information
to the fire field so at this point we
know that the fire field that the field
from the fire is a string type so this
is how the existing input form a reverse
engineering technique works but here we
have the problem because they require
the consumer programs but unfortunately
we don't have consumer programs in many
cases in practice so what if we don't
have the consumer programs and we only
have the producer program let me give
you an example and in case of the
Barnett command and control protocol we
don't have consumer program on the
victim machine so we only have a
producer program on the victim machine
and the producer collects some of your
data and they generate some unknown
metal messages and send to the attackers
machine the consumer program that can
read and understand the network message
exist on the attackers machine
unfortunately we don't have the access
to the attackers machine so the problem
here really comes down to how to
understand such unknown network messages
without having consumer programs
before I talk about the p 2z program I
want to first talk about an observation
that motivated our work so paper
published it in FSC 2011 the tighter is
checking compliments of a producer and a
consumer they proposed us an observation
that a producer and consumer a symmetric
they use this observation to show that
the correctness of the producer can be
verified by checking its components to
corresponding consumer basically what it
means is if you want to check the
correctness of the producer you can just
monitor the execution of the consumer
and just looking for how it accurately
follows the corresponding consumers
logic if they are match it then we can
say that we don't have the bug here let
me give you an example here so we have a
pair of producer and consumer program
and the producer depending on the
predicate outcome at line number two it
may generate just one field output or
three build output so it may generate
the spooling or cooling doubling and as
you can see the consumer follows exact
same blue a line number eight I first
read the first view which is bling and
then it did determine whether it goes to
read two more views or not so as you can
see these two a consumer producer follow
the same rule which which means that
they are correct and there is no bug but
here still they require a set of
producer and consumer and we have in our
setting we don't have the consumer but
these were actually inspired us to come
up with a new idea which is how about
just one the producer to create consumer
if we don't have the consumer available
and now we try to run the program and
try to transform the producer execution
to consumer execution and now encounter
a huge problem which is you don't know
how to run these programs so as you can
imagine just executing the producer just
executing a program without proper input
images one and do something little seem
simple and the script and sure they
don't create a fire which we want to
analyze it and as you can see I I have a
picture of a simple abstraction of the
program and the program has sponsor
functions and depending on the input you
may execute few functions and just get
in here I mark redbox as one that
executed and it shows that without the
proper input we just execute one piece
of code and it does not execute the
produced fire function which we want to
analyze and this is actually a
fundamental problem of dynamic analysis
which is a coverage problem so here is
the big question how we solve this
problem anyone can suggest
so you may think of try to find like a
lot of different inputs to drive the
execution something like that all right
so this is actually a huge problem and
it's really so difficult to solve and
there are some static analysis to try to
find all kinds of inputs so that they
execute all kinds of the program code
but they are not as successful in
practice so here our audio 2 comes to
the rescue we have we have been
developed a first execution engine code
experts and the experts can explore all
the possible paths without inputs and
during the execution entering is during
its exploration of the all possible
paths it generates random inputs on
demand and also it recovers from any
folds during the execution so now as you
can see thanks to the experts we can
execute all kinds of D functions without
requiring any inputs all right now i'm
going to introduce beta basic idea of
the p to see here we have unknown
message or file that we want to analyze
and a set of potential producers so our
setting is we we have some messages or
fire that we want to analyze what we
don't know and it is previously
generated so we actually don't know
whether each program is generated and
the potential producer is should not I
mean it it does not need to be just one
program we can have set of programs that
as I showed the first example it could
be of you freeware programs and then we
feed the potential producer to the
experts and during experts explore all
the execution paths it try to find
the execution paths that contain file
open for write operation which
essentially means produced executions
and with these producer producer
executions and we feed the producer
executions and the unknown file or
message we want to understand to the pit
to see and Pete to see a trend generate
transform the consumer execution once we
have the transformed consumer execution
we can just use the existing 10 analysis
tools to understand the fire format as
well as the type information of each
field in the five so here I want to
point out that the pig is different
between our work and all the previous
work is that we just directly work on
the potential producer programs and we
don't require any consumers and any
input to drive even the producer
executions all right so let me explain
some how the pit to see actually works
in detail here we have a non binary file
we want to analyze as you can see is it
kind of contains some five integer at
the beginning and the next two fields
contains strings and integers game and
this is actually how this fire is
generated we have a producer program it
looks a little bit complex so I'm going
to explain it line by line so first
first line it tried to open a file which
is essentially the unknown vibe and line
number two it calculate the account
number and a line number three it assign
some constant value and a line number
for it try to write the magic variable
the magic video is actually the
the signature of the fire is as if if
you think about like PE fires at the
very beginning of the peopie it is
always MZ which is constant it's telling
that this file is a certain type and Li
number 5 you try to write the account
number that is actually calculated at
line number 2 and line number six to
eight also try to calculate some numbers
and the strings and a line number 98
rights right the size of the header and
line number 10 is just storing this D
header and but please see that the size
of that F write operation is stored
right people at nine number nine and
line number 11 we have a loop and the
loop depends on the account number and
it will store number of account
structures at the end so this part is
actually constructed the first it has a
signature and the second is the number
of accounts structures in this file and
the third field is the size of the
header right but the problem here is we
don't really know how to run the
producer so we use x-force to run the
producer execution but the first
execution does not really generate the
same unknown data file that is since the
x-force does not take any inputs it
generate it just randomly generate the
inputs on demand for example at line
number two instead of calculating the
account number it generates just random
number two and just assign it and line
number six seven eight it happens also
the same way line number six it
generates on random string and assign it
to the name field of the header
structure and line number seven it also
generates on random number two and
assign it so
this is actually the fire generated by
the first execution as you can see these
two unknown file and file generated by
the first execution are different and I
marked a different field of between two
fires with the red boxes so as you can
see it has to field the first field are
the same because it's just constant and
this next field the number of account is
different and the size of header is also
different and there's a strings are also
different in header structures and
account structures to in here the
biggest problem is actually we have
different size of the header because
that size of the header is used in line
number 10 to store the header and it
determines the size of the header in the
file we will have all like misaligned
account with misaligned account
structures in these outcomes so if we
use paint analysis to analyze that first
execution to understand your known file
all the type information we get right
after the header including some of the
field in the header are incorrect and
also we can see that the file generated
by the first execution is a little bit
smaller than unknown file so the last
view field in the unknown file does not
really have the corresponding part in
device generated by the first execution
so even again even if we just use the
hand analysis to analyze at the first
execution we don't have no idea how to
match this last few field in the unknown
part
so now I'm going to talk about how we
solve this problem we have we have the
producer program program on the left
side and the consumer program on the
right side the basic idea of the P to
see is we try to find all the write
operation and try to transform it into
this metric read operation so let's
beginning from the first line and when
the producer try to open a file to write
something we transform it to the
symmetric read operation which is f open
for read and the file that this F open
function will read is not if I generated
by the first execution is the file that
we want to analyze so it's going to open
the unknown file and see what happens
next and it executes line number two and
nine number three since we are using the
experts to drive this execution at line
number two instead of calculating the
account number we assign random variable
random random number two and line number
three is just constant so it doesn't
change and a line number four instead of
writing something to the fire we do a
symmetric read operation so it read the
first field from the unknown file and
since the first field is just constant
it doesn't really matter and I line
number five we do also this metric read
operation and now we read the account
number so let's see that a line number
two we actually assign a random number
two but here we read the second field of
the unknown part and then the account
number at right after the line number
five is becoming verified so this is
actually correcting the program state to
drive this consumer execution correctly
so let's see what this actually affect
to the rest of the execution
after that it also excute line number
six seven eight and during the execution
it generates some random values and
assign it like some random strings to
the Heather name and random number to
the account number two and a line number
nine we also do the symmetric read
operation and now it reads size variable
and this symmetry operation will read
the third field of the unknown file
since we just generate the random values
during line number six seven eight the
size is actually calculated hex hex
number a but this is incorrect because
in the unknown file the rear size of
that header is 15 so at the line number
nine the symmetric read operation will
correct this problem so it reads the
third field which is 15 and assign it to
the size variable and line number 10 we
also do the symmetric read and now we
try to read the header and since we have
corrected the size variable n nine
number nine now we can now the consumer
transform the consumer execution can
correctly read the header and after that
we have aloof and the number of
iteration of this loop depends on the
account number and let's see that first
the account number initially has the
random number two but a line number five
we have redeep symmetric read and
correct the account number and that
actually propagated to the line number
11 so we have now correct number of loop
and then line number 12 we're going to
iterate it and read the account
structures this is unkind of nice
example that we successfully transform a
producer execution to consumer execution
at the end of this execution where we
can see that
all the unknown fires are actually
consumed and we reach the end of the
file point of the unknown fire so any
questions so far all right but the life
is not that easy so sure there are many
practical challenges we have observed
many complex programs and here we
identify a bunch of programs and
formulate it as a one problem so we
found a lot of programs actually there
are some so many cases that symmetric
read operation do not really help that
is even though we do the symmetric read
operation to the every write operation
it does not help to drive the execution
correctly this is because the symmetric
read let's say that there are two
symmetric read operation they are
actually related but day since they do
not have explicit dependence it is
really really difficult to identify so
let me give you an example we have a
producer program here on the left side
and the transformed consumer program on
the right side let's look at the
producer program first it bursts open
the virus and try to calculate the
length of the string at line number
three and it stores the length of the
string to the to a variable and a line
number five is going to store but the
problem here is a line number six when
it's toward the popper contents it
recalculate the size of the string again
so just for human just looking at this
code you can see that I assured this
first store the length of the string and
then store the string according to the
code but for the program it is kind of
difficult to
come up with this idea because they
don't have explicit dependence between
line number five or six so let's see
what happens when we apply symmetric
read operation in this program so the
consumer program follows the same
sequence alignment is same and at line
number three it tried to calculate the
length of the string but since we use
the first execution the proper contents
is not the correct one it just have
random buffer so sure the length is
incorrect but align number five since it
tried to read the length of the popper
from the unknown file is going to
correct that variable mi number five but
this correction does not have a line
number six because because a line number
six at the symmetric read operation is
going to recalculate the length of the
string using string lengths with the
buffer so allein number six it will read
different number of bytes which is
incorrect and that actually makes all
the next symmetric read operation
incorrect so does anyone can can anyone
suggest how to solve this problem
alright so to solve this problem we try
to find the original definition of the
variables and when we need to correct
the variable from the unknown fire we
try to propagate try to correct the
original definition of the variables and
make it like make it propagating
naturally so we call this finding the
original definition and correct the
first definition of the variable
patching and we run the program like
several times and during the execution
of the Dead iterative execution we check
the consistence among the patches and
when the patches are inconsistent
between executions we identify that it
actually indicate the presence of
unexposed field correlation then if that
happens we try to backtrack to the last
patches and then try a different values
until we don't have inconsistent patches
so this is a little bit kind of more
tricky part so if you are interested in
you can refer the paper we have the
algorithms and the examples to these
unexposed correlations and now I'm going
to show how we evaluate 2p to see
programs all right we have evaluated
this system with nine programs five
programs generate files and poor program
generate network messages
and as you can see the program size
varies from really small and a little
bit large like two megabytes this
program size essentially does not
include all the library dynamic library
codes so actually when it closed in on
to the memory is way more bigger than
this one and the unknown fire size we
want to analyze is very from few bites
to a few megabyte and we have measured a
number of iteration and we have two two
parts the first one is method and not
match it this is the case that at the
matched cases actually if we can pick a
right function in the right program then
how many iteration we need to do to type
all the field in the file and your magic
part is we may pick a long program or
even if we pick the correct program
there are a bunch of functions that has
write operation so let's say we just
pick wrong program and wrong functions
then how many iteration we need to do to
know that this we're not going to help
us so as you can see the magic part when
is finish it successfully is usually ten
times or 20 times less always less than
50 times and your magic part is usually
zero because you can imagine that most
of the fires or most open it and let own
messages they have their signatures like
constant number telling that this
message is this type and when we compare
or try to execute and when we encounter
those kind of things and then we can
usually just immediately fail to
transform the execution so this is
mostly just zero means that at the first
execution we immediately know that this
function will not help us and the number
of type field or
out of number of field means how many
people can accurately type in the
unknown data file or network messages
and the less time means just running
time of our system and this running time
actually include all the iterations we
have so just running one execution
actually doesn't take a lot of time and
the coverage and the past number of
paths explored is like how many
instructions are covered by the first
executing x-force engine and the number
of paths explored by the export engine
too and as you can see we we can cover
like plenty of the instructions and
plenty of paths that can identify the
producer executions and here I let me
explain a few case studies we have gone
through we have a steganography program
that actually embed a secret text in the
image by changing the least significant
bit of the each pixel in the image so
here our setting is we have an image
that potentially or not potentially
contain a hidden message or not so we
don't know whether this is actually
containing a text message or not and by
just looking at is really difficult to
tell because even though the image
contains the secret image it does not
really change a lot it just change the
leasing significant feed
so all right and and also we have some
set of potential programs we don't know
what kind of program exactly can inject
the hidden message to the image so we
have set of programs that may inject or
not so we use these two one image file
and set up programs and feed them to the
pit to see and whether it can generate a
transform the consumer execution or not
here actually we can have two different
outcomes if that image has the secret
message then alright if that image has
the secret image and if one of the
potential producer actually can inject a
secret image to the image a secret text
to the image then we can we will get the
correct transformed consumer execution
otherwise we are not able to transform
the producer executions to the consumer
execution and once we get the
transformed consumer execution we can
simply apply the tane analysis
techniques to understand like first what
kind of texture actually hidden or and
how they hide the text and the their
internal structures and the types of the
internal structures all right so if
there is a hidden messages here at our p
2 c 2 p 2 c 2 can identify these hidden
images with data structures the mario
actually use as well as how they embed
the individual field type information
and if this image is just benign it
doesn't have the secret text then we are
not able to
drive I transform the consumer xscape a
produce execution to the consumer
execution so even though we are not sure
whether the image contain a hidden
message or not we are still we can still
get meaningful information out of the P
to see and hear another case study we
use the Z boat which is Mario that
communicate as through the networks and
it generate different messages depending
on the situation for example sometimes
he generated try to send local
information to other servers and
sometimes it just wait and doing nothing
so our goal is to understand previously
generated message by this program and
it's already sent to other computers so
we have we encountered the prop right
here we have two consecutive messages
that we want to analyze and we have we
encounter a problem that the program
actually does not generate messages
without input so when I try to just
execute this program this program just
run and keep doing nothing so we use
experts to try to try to make this
program generate something and we we
identify that it actually generates
something but it January different
messages so here we have unknown
messages we want to analyze and the
messages generated by the first
execution and I marked different part
with the red boxes and as you can see
all the strings are different and we
have one integer difference between
these two messages so we run DP to see
to generate a idea consumer execution
and this gives us to information that is
first the first message actually
contains the size of the second message
as you can see
a at the 25 actually meaning that the
whole length of the second message and
the second message contains computer
name and the operating system version
information and one key values from the
registry key so we type this information
by painting all the standard windows API
so after we won p to see this is kind of
what we get out of the program and so we
have observe some few interesting things
during our evaluation first of all is it
was actually quite interesting that the
number of iteration to find correct
transformation is not a large because
when I started this project I was
thinking that it maybe take a bunch of a
bunch of times it may run forever but in
most cases the program dependency is
already exposed and we don't see a lot
of unexposed weird correlations and the
second we can precisely identify all the
field in the Cuban fires or messages
with few exceptions first one program
code MD has a lot of floating point
instructions and the net or more is wind
peeing in fuji they have some
non-standard api uses and the fears are
tainted by these non-standard api's but
i want to point out that this limitation
is not actually from the pit to see
these are just imitating of
implementation of pain analysis engine
so we could improve cane analysis engine
to make it better and third we find
found out that transform the consumer
execution sometimes recognize more fear
than some typical consumers
for example mp3 gain is a program that
can calculate something and inject new
tag into the mp3 file and one of the
commercial famous m.tech reader mp3 tag
reader program which is mp3 tag cannot
actually recognize this field so I can
say sometimes it's even even though you
have the consumers it is better to
transform the producer execution to
consumer execution to understand what it
actually generated and to conclude we
have developed p to see which is an
output from a reverse engineering tool
and we it understands the structure and
meaning of the unknown failure messages
and we don't really require consumers
and any inputs to drive the producer
executions we just take the producer
programs and transform it to the
consumer we don't need inputs and the
kiai kiai kept it behind this tool is we
transform a produced execution to the
ideal consumer execution sometimes it
recognize more pure than typical
consumers and we show that it is highly
accurate and we don't need to know the
exact producers so you can just have
settled producers and you don't even
know how to run these programs to write
so any question
so if I said everybody get the idea