welcome to crack econ 2019
[Applause]
my name is Wade I'm one of the
co-founders along with Glenn in the
front row here Glenn some a lot of the
hard work to get this thing happening
we're really pleased to welcome you
today to what we think is gonna be one
of our best troika cons yet troika comes
a result in Glyndon of Glenda myself
catching up over a few beers and
wondering what we can do for the local
community how can we provide opportunity
to learn how can we provide an
opportunity to to meet up and chat about
stuff and InfoSec and hence Crockett
Khan was born I won't lie to you the
first few years were a bit touch-and-go
particularly the first one we weren't
sure whether it was just gonna be asked
to and a few close friends turning up
and that would have been absolutely fine
but very quickly we got a fantastic
dedicated bunch of people to come along
and Crockett Ron's grown year-on-year as
a result of it so since last year it's
been a pretty spectacular year in our
industry has been a whole heap of things
happening we've got even the morning
shows talking about cyber security we've
got so many different it's a new segment
every other day and probably some of the
biggest things for me that have happened
in the last 12 months are our Parliament
being compromised in some of our major
parties as well I mean it's one of the
biggest couple of the biggest things
that have occurred which kind of trusts
the people in this room and the people
with this skill set into the line life
not or into the front line so it's
really important for us to to have a
good kind of meeting area a good kind of
conference and that's why I'm really
pleased to see the lineup of speakers we
have today I've got a great bunch we've
got a whole heap aired including Justin
Stephen we've got Sarah young and we've
got somebody who really kind of just
needs one name bit like Beyonce
Silvio so but crikey comes more than
just about security it's about also
about giving back to the community and
we're pretty proud of what we've been
able to do in the previous years in your
behalf so last year on your behalf we
were able to donate twenty thousand
dollars to our charities
so the four worthy charities have got
the $20,000 were act for kids which
helps kids and families prevent child
abuse our knees and uncles which runs a
mentoring program for kids at risk we've
got the women's a community aid
Association which provides support for
women and a special school which assists
kids with special needs reach their full
potential and I think you should give
yourselves another round of applause as
a result of that well done a lot of this
great work couldn't be done without the
support of our sponsors and want to say
a special thanks to them today also
you've been with us for many years and
we're really really appreciative of your
support
they're just first in line to say will
sponsor each year they're out there our
Platinum Partner and they've got a
conference coming up later in the year
as well and our Gold Partner this year
f-five has come aboard and we're really
thankful for you and we've got some
silver partners who've been with us here
in year out just kind of just it's
really they're really easy to work with
and just want to say a special thanks to
our silver partners we've got insomnia
interlock humanised yellow eye T P SBA
and Korsak look these companies are
really happy to support these organizers
these these charities and our conference
they don't have sales teams waiting
lying in wait for you to walk around the
corner and thrust business cards into
your pockets they're here for the
community they're here to support
something like this and that's that's
how we know we've got the good ones so
thank you very much for your sponsorship
[Applause]
speaking of the good ones we've got a
whole heap of unpaid volunteers that
help us out they're just they're putting
in their spare time and really making a
massive effort just to just to help out
this conference I just want to say a big
thanks to them um you'll see you'll see
a lot of them around today in there in
the burgundy shirts but there's some you
won't see that really help us out on the
back end keeping things like keeping
organizations like the tax office happy
and there's people who volunteer to help
us in that space as well so I just want
to do a massive shout out to you thank
you for your help and this one group I
haven't thanked yet
you lot look cranky Kong gets bigger
gets better every year and it's only
because of your feedback it's only
because you come back to us and tell us
how we can do things better the
following year and we really want you to
keep that up for example we brought in
to do some feedback reporters from
coffee carts we've asked the speakers to
mostly keep it family friendly so you
can potentially bring your kids along
and in any of these videos will be
beeped out on YouTube if there's
anything that comes out and we hope that
conference is improving as a result of
it so if you do have any suggestions
please do let us know if it is a
different coffee if it's more speakers
or even a better opening speech it's all
the big help to us
to make this a better conference so
please please don't be shy in coming
forward once again I'd like to thank you
all for coming to croc econ and I hope
you enjoy yourselves and that's enough
for me I'm going to leave it to the
people that know what they're doing now
I'll pass you over to MC for today
Patrick great thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
hello okay how you going everyone my
name is Patrick gray you might know me
from such podcasts as risky business and
it's my job to basically just introduce
the speakers and keep things moving
which is going to be a hell of a
challenge this year because I can't
believe how much great content
crikey Kahn's been able to squeeze in as
Wade just explained the first one I was
there it was a really small little event
it was very informal and one of the
great things that happened at the first
crack econ was it really got quite
interactive there were a lot of
questions and answers coming from the
audience and it really felt more like
you know like a group chat it was really
cool and we like to try to keep that
vibe as much as possible so if you do
have questions assuming we have time it
would be great for everyone to you know
feel free to ask them and it's my job to
try to help help that process kick along
now
before we got get on to the next of the
first talk I should mention them you
know some of the speakers might use
swear words you know if this is likely
to offend you you might want to you know
see a volunteer about a refund you know
no harm no foul just warning you that
that's something that might happen we're
actually running 15 minutes early and
given the number of talks that we have
to squeeze in I think I might just
introduce our first speaker and we can
go from there if that's all right with
you Glen excellent so our first speaker
is your him Mets he is a Googler
technically a security engineer at
Google with a background in IR and he's
going to be talking to you today about
scaling defense you know we know
attackers scale in his talk abstract
you're here mentions that you know
botnets are a great example of how
attackers are scaling things but how do
we scale defense he's going to give us
some examples on that and I think you're
ready to go thank you very much MS
[Music]
[Applause]
yeah Thank You Patrick
so my name is yoga mats and roughly the
next 45 40 minutes I'm gonna talk about
scaling security from a defensive
perspective I'm not a local for for
those of you who saw my name maybe on on
on the agenda you might have googled it
and you might have you might have found
a couple of people that that were
mentioned as chemistry scientists
photographer or a scarf designer I can
tell you these are different people so
no worries the thing the thing the thing
let me before I go into the presentation
more about about scaling defense I want
to give you a little bit a little bit
about the background who I am and how I
came to information security as a young
young person I was always interested in
in tinkering with Hardware tinkering
with software and when you tinker with
hardware and software you'll you'll
notice you find your way around security
controls you like things like savegame
like tinkering with save games or
copyright protections in in in computer
games and I wanted I wanted to kind of
get a professional into that in at a
time but when I started there was no
there was no such thing like a security
engineer job role so I ended up doing
doing being a jack of many trades as
with a soft development a bit of
deployment engineering a bit of system
admin and eventually network engineering
and that was kind of one of the first
first roles that pushed me more towards
information security because as a
network engineer you were responsible
for dealing with the firewall when in
2005 one of my former colleagues came to
me and said like hey we're looking for
people that do that do digital forensics
in in in fraud investigations as
consultancy I thought why not that
sounds interesting
the the thing the thing is though if if
you if you have done consultancy for
quite a while you get a bit demotivated
the thing is that you go to you go to a
customer you help them out six months
later you're there with the same
customer same problem you have to tell
them the same thing maybe six months
later you have to help them again so so
unfortunately my experience with with
consultancy from an instant response and
IDO French perspective was the companies
are not changing during the information
security posture so that was kind of for
me a reason to look for something look
for something else and and I was playing
with the ideas like hey why not develop
computer games because I suppose so they
were so interesting to to
reverse-engineer them or or do some sort
of business for myself but
coincidentally I ended up at Google
Google Switzerland particular thanks to
one person in the room Michael Cohen who
was who we ended up there as well just
before me now what I what I started
there was do forensics and instant
response but you have to realize that
Google is a very non-traditional IT
environment if you see and console to
see a lot of Windows ad environments
Google environments completely different
and and and also just the sheer scale
scale of the matter kind of changed and
changes your perspective significantly
in how to solve how to solve problems in
I don't know of Australia privacy laws
are changing as well but in Europe
there's a GD P R and there was kind of a
strong push in 2017 to be ready for the
for the 2018 deadline my role changed
from not only dealing with security
incidents but now also dealing with
privacy incidents and and the TLDR of
privacy incidents is is it's the data
could dedicate a security control
failing besides all besides dealing with
all these organs organs and hectic
things I also like to spend some time on
the on maintaining and developing open
source and I maintain a vast vast set of
open source forensic life forensic
libraries some of you might have
stumbled upon before before I continue
I'm gonna have a Ministry of notice
first
I mean you've probably seen this a lot
of a lot of press
patience before is that like as a
disclaimer my opinions are not about not
the opinions of my of my employer but
while writing is I I actually kind of
realized reflecting on is that my
employers have influenced my perceptions
of information security over the years
especially in consultancy because she
must see so many different environments
is you get you get you get a lid a lot
of different different perspectives
there and and some of these will be
reflected in the talk today now I can
hear you in the room say like hey but
like like some of the things I might be
saying my might not be relevant for or
not applicable to the organization
you're currently working for and that's
perfectly fine what are asked of you
what I asked of you is take the elements
of what I'm saying think about it and
think about how how you can use what
isn't relevant to you and you use that
to improve information security posture
of your organization as preparation for
this for this this talk and and I also
kind of read a lot of articles on the
internet like one thing that recently
stood out that I found very shocking as
an internet responder on one side that
means that 2019 is going to be a busy
year if this if this trajectory
continues but also why why why is
information security especially for my
defensive point of view still such a
hard thing hard thing to do if we see
like 4.5 billion billion records being
being exposed just the first half of
2018 so this is kind of the central
question to my to my my thesis here is
this why are our defensive security
practices failing in a lot of
organizations and reflecting a bit of a
bit upon this and and ironically enough
this was one of the reasons why I left
left consultancy is I think a lot of
organizations lack a culture of
continuous improvement it is the fact
that we we see security as a one one
time salute one time solution that we
need to implement and then continue and
continue on business as usual and this
this is weird because
2019 we have more security controls than
ever before firewalls client-side threat
against user behavior analysis threat
Intel feeds you name it there's more
mandatory and requirements legal
frameworks information security
frameworks ISO Basel 3 if you're in
finance
southbend Oxley gdpr you name it like
there are a lot of controls but so why
why are securities practices still still
a thing that are slacking why did a
bitch is still occurring so what I want
to do today is I want to share with you
a couple of things that that my employer
has done done over the years to kind of
see how we've been using continuous
improvement across across across Google
to improve our information security
posture this mod might give you some
more ideas on how to how to take those
and apply this to your own organizations
so first of all what is continual
improvement it's nothing new it's a in a
nutshell it it it's actually small
incremental improvements over time it
there was a book Kaizen in 1986 that X
talked extensively about about
continuous improvement now if you're if
you're in if you're doing a software
development you might have also you
might have also heard of continuous
integration continuous delivery
continuous deployment which which are
also implementations of continuous
improvement within the developments
within a software development process
and recent developments like the FA Cups
actually try to execute it as part of
that as well
so why how are we applying continuous
improvement in more traditional security
information she could controls do our
organizations have someone that is
actually driving this continuous
integration based on maybe the outcome
of incidents so one important element of
continuous integration is testing and
it's kind of more an open question for
the room and an open question for for
your organization is that how often do
you actually test your security controls
while reading while reading up on a lot
of matters funny enough or a bit sad
ironically is that most organizations
improve the security information
security after an impactful breach which
is too late so what options do you have
to maybe prepare yourself before the
breach one thing one aspect could be is
you could use a red team you can learn a
lot from a red team especially a
successful red team put in putting the
information the state of information
security back in perfect back into
perspective but also back onto the
executive on your under the desk of your
executives but as a defender that's only
so much time time to spend so how do you
deal how do you effectively deal with
with taking the lessons learned of
average taking the lessons learned of a
red team and and actively addressing
actively addressing some of those issues
if you're if you're familiar with
project management you see here kind of
a very kind of rough way of reducing
risks in a project and it's by
four-quadrant rising in impact and
probability now high probability high
impact you probably want to you probably
want to address that directly that it's
the highest priority but then then there
are two kind of areas that are more
problematic as a defender which are the
ones that are low probability but high
impacts and the ones that are high
probability and low impacts and I'll go
a little bit more a little bit deeper
into those areas to kind of see will to
kind of show you what what is possible
there to do if you take high probability
and low impact as a defender typically
means noise means a lot of noise and the
thing is in defense see what you want to
do is you want to reduce the noise in
your environment and there's many
sources of many sources of noise now
we're low quality threat intelligence
scams fishing but also the internet the
media a lot of information out there is
unreliable if you if you if you
leak your defense if you like you'll
defendant be led by that information you
spend up chasing a lot of a lot of dead
ends now
let me let me share some a couple of
examples of how to reduce the noise with
you that we've done with it within
Google now I have to take take you back
a couple of years when when Mac when we
were using Mac OS but the platform
itself didn't have much enterprise
security controls yet and that virus it
blocked some threats didn't block other
threats block some threats partially if
so did wasn't entirely it was not
sufficient for our for our needs which
cost a lot of reinstallation xandrie
installations are costly to a business
especially especially if you have
software engineers that that that that
you kind of solver engineers that that
are four to four to eight hours
non-productive so we we looked at we
looked at the other options like what
options will be half binary whitelisting
was very effective on other platforms so
why why didn't we have a binary
whitelisting solution for Mac the TLDR
was there was none it didn't exist
now the advantage of working for a large
tech company is that you have resources
you can spend on building these things
yourself so if you're a smaller company
you might you might need to account you
might need to get a developer or team up
with other companies to get to get this
but this was one of the reasons that
Google developed Center in 2014 which is
now open source if you if you were if
you have a large matically than you want
to apply is and it basically stops
stopped the whole problem of of adware
on Mac but SSO as with so many security
controls there is a catch it was so
effective that it also stopped the
binaries from users to do the work so
kind of a problem there so one side
stopped the adware the other side stop
stop users from doing their work and
this is why why we reintroduced upvote
and for those of you not familiar with a
fault it was it was open source in 2018
but it introduced the concept
it introduced the concept of social
voting so the problem with with most
binary whitelisting solution is the
whitelist you have to maintain a
whitelist a lot of whitelist and an
organ in a foreign organization the
scale of Google it's complex managing
exceptions is a complex and costly
across the operations so how how do you
manage exceptions especially exceptions
that are small-scale in a more effective
way what a broad introduced is social
voting which allows which allows users
to vote for allowing a binary to run on
their system but this is a local policy
so let's say you have five users that
want to run the run binary on their
system and that binary is malware those
five systems might be getting infected
but it it means that the global fleet
does not is not affected by it and it
also means that there was no no
additional costs of someone that had to
make changes in the global in the global
whitelist this adds a bit more noise
back into this system at the trade-off
of preventing a lot of costs on
maintaining on having them maintain a
global a global whitelist and let alone
all the frustrations about users having
to apply for exceptions within within a
large organization in the end this despo
solution stopped us having to mass
reimage a lot of machines the number of
reimage iziz is down to a manageable to
a manageable number
another element of a very hard problem
to deal with is phishing and when I talk
with peers in order and other companies
what what two of the top three issues
that they typically deal with is one is
Microsoft Office document and malicious
ones and the second one is typically
phishing now phishing is a large it's a
larger complex problem than I'm here
presenting here but I wanted to kind of
share two to two different strategies we
have applied over the years for
particular user credential fishing
fishes are persistence even the ones
that are more opportunistic that are
less thought let's target it and what
you could do what we've done with
password alert is we warn users about
the fact that they gate just gave away
their core credentials because why why
why should the user use the corporate
dentures on anything else but court
resources now this might be good to get
a bit more challenging if you have a lot
of third-party Corp resources but still
you might want to consider not using the
same credentials for your Corp
environments as for those third-party
solutions and the advantage of password
alert is that you can you can centrally
collect these these alerts so you could
measure how effective your and our
fishing training is you could measure is
how how many users which departments are
actually the ones that are most
vulnerable to fishing and maybe focus
your attempts there instead of focusing
an organization-wide phishing awareness
program but in 2017 what we notice is
that even though even though password is
very effective in in making users aware
of being fished is that the fishes
themselves were getting getting more
getting more persistent that they're
also starting to fish second factor
token-based token-based Corp credentials
and this and this was a this was a
larger risk to the company one one way
we solve this is is we we prevent it
basically uses from entering the second
factor by hand so security we introduce
the security token that provides the
second factor directly into the system
this means that if that the Fisher no
longer is able to intercept the second
factor therefore they even they get if
they even get the username and password
they still haven't got the second factor
which which were Google limit eliminated
most of the credential based fishing for
for their work for work accounts as I
said phishing is a larger problem this
is this is just a small small part of
the problem scope
another element in in defense that is
that isn't to use in time impactful one
our false alarms and you might be
familiar with the fable the boy cried
quite move is that false alarms
typically end up in disastrous results
and I want to kind of highlight a recent
a recent recent I would say for me a
boycott quite bull situation so what was
this nist NVD has had raided a Colonel
Bach as high critical basically they
were saying this is a remote code
execution in the Linux kernel this was
copied by a lot of companies on the
internet very very quickly very blindly
with no one verified it luckily Souza
was one of the few that actually said
like wait what's going on and and
pointed correctly out that that NIST did
misclassify misclassified their their
assessment of this digging a little bit
deeper into the CV and CVS process it's
it's not that weird that this happened
apparently there's very little due
diligence or quality controls applied by
the organization that is providing in
CVS they they blindly assume the
reporter is correct for logic companies
like Microsoft which have their own like
assessments or larger open source open
source projects like Apache that have
their own kind of do their own
assessment as well this is less of a
risk because they have built they they
take care of those quality controls but
apparently for the Linux kernel in this
particular case it was not also CVS
whores are based on worst case
assumptions they NIST assumes the worst
in calculating now for your own
environment as the organization there
might be a lot more different factors
that that your impact assessments or ion
then just to see the CVS scores here and
I'll go I'll go into a couple of
a couple of considerations a little bit
further and apparently and this I think
this is for me the most the most
shocking element for for false alarms is
that there's a lot of organizations they
are out there that don't check their
information we assume an authority like
NIST is correct which for a defender is
problematic because now all hands on
deck
just because someone made them made a
wrong assumption so for me it's
informative from a defense perspective a
lot of a lot of the issues I see that
are false alarms I classify a cyber
drama these are the internet telling
things telling things they are but not
necessarily being a reflection of all
the details a lot of this has to do with
low quality vulnerability reports so if
you're if you are the vulnerability
researcher please make sure form of for
me as a defender perspective make sure
there are high quality
make sure you did do your assessments
make sure you did you clearly indicate
what what the potential impact is often
it also has to do with with
misunderstood hardware and software
behavior especially in in detection a
lot of alerts are just based side
effects of normal behavior because but
the behavior was not very clear or very
edge case these distinct service now you
can do a lot of organization controls to
solve this I mean especially for
vulnerabilities make sure you make sure
you understand your execs are aware of
this make sure because they said those
are typically the four ones to ask first
and say like hey yeah how are we put
I'll be safe how is the business
impacted by this vulnerability so the
best best way to do is to talk with them
beforehand
say like what information do you need at
what time when there's a large
announcement on the internet about about
a security control failing but there is
also a technical way to approach this
and me as a security engineer and
working for tech company
technical approaches are typically
preferred because they scale and one of
this is defense-in-depth and I'm not
sure how many people are aware of the
room of defense in depth but in essence
is pretty simple
it's you you make sure that you have
multiple layers of security controls and
if one fails you have another layer that
they take care of it takes care of it so
in case of your vulnerability the kernel
the kernel mode sorry the remote kernel
root exploit may be remote connects port
maybe not the best example but take it
take a burner ability in the library if
you have a security sandbox available
the vulnerability is suddenly less of an
issue you might have a remote code exact
in the library with the sandbox take
care of most of the exploitation
exploitation parrot if you're long if
you are able to detect that someone is
trying to exploit it you have it you
have you have a fairly fairly bit of
additional security cost of controls in
place so you can actually take care of
properly assessing the vulnerability
instead of making rush decisions and
maybe maybe bringing down your
production as well nao-san boxing is
complex I don't know how many people in
the room might have tried to sandbox
process before but if you're dealing
with with code that that uses a Python
stack a C++ may be other languages Sam
boxing is complex and this is one of the
reasons Google kind of released released
ASAP is sandbox APR to help sandbox just
individual components if you if you're
dealing with third-party proprietary
libraries it might be this might be a
solution to to sandbox those if you if
you if you don't know what the source is
or if you don't control if you don't
control what's in there I think one of
the more important points points for me
is is about the boy who cried wolf is
that a lot of these false alerts
actually fatigue or fatigue oh
responders they fatigue people good
people leave because they are either
burned out or they get bored out just by
the poor information
that they are provided with provided on
a daily basis now this this is something
closer to my heart because I said like
my background is information it's
instant response and take it off
forensics now it's probably also one of
the more harder areas to to scale and be
to do to do continuous improvements
because you're always in always in a
constant state of panic you're most of
the cases you do it they're high time
pressure the high visibility so your
execs are continuously asking for
updates there might be regulatory time
limits like a 72-hour breach
notifications and there's a small mark a
small margin of of mistake but I still
want to kind of take you through the to
the process that where we have been
partially be able to do within Google
but also partially without so I go back
to 2005 when I when I started doing
digital forensics as a consultant and
like the lessons I learned pretty
quickly is that nothing works it's hard
to automate and you really have to do a
lot of work to get to the data and and
that's what you spend most of the time
you spend most of the time recovering to
the recovering data because your
customers are not capturing that as
there's things you can do there's things
you can put in place a centralized
logging is a very simple way of of
getting some of the data but the game
changes when your organization is
certainly large like in more indicators
I was used to before I joined Google was
I went to a customer made a physical
copy of the disk maybe the copy of my
network data and investigated it in the
lab of line when you're dealing with an
organization across many spending many
locations many time zones you have to
think about this differently and this
could also benefit in smaller
organization
I start collecting your logs centrally
think about how to get information life
without having have having to take the
time for a full disk image or maybe
better yet even preserve our data
automatically before and after the time
of suspicious events and track
historical changes the thing I think
that we were able to build within within
Google and as open-source as well is
girl and girl was kind of a at the time
a game changer in the way of how we
approached how we approach live analysis
it's basically an agent that supports
live analysis of multiple platforms and
allows for quick triage
so this this reduced the time of us
needing to get access to a machine maybe
run our live script maybe get a disc
shipped wait wait two months to the
analysis you get the idea
Gerber's a gorilla's a significant time
saver now I wouldn't say that girls just
looking for everyone because I will go
into this a little bit later is that if
you build such systems you have to
maintain them as well
and your organization needs to be ready
for that as well but using a different
approach than you did before
within Incident Response helps to
quickly change the process as you can
see here we added more components over
time because live analysis was not the
only solution we've got we got a we got
a corporate cloud and suddenly we needed
to make sure we're also able to copy our
clouds
calcium's sometimes we still needed to
make forensically sound copies of disks
so we also needed a way to remotely
remotely image image discs but one of
the lessons I think I wanted to share
today is that you can speed up you can
speed up your instant response by
putting a lot of sorry
putting a putting responsive
capabilities in place beforehand before
you need them now collection is fine but
what did I do it is data I mean like an
one side I need to quickly analysis and
analyze them as well as I said before
the success of the life response agent
was that heavy we are suddenly able to
get the data much quicker but now now
processing was a challenge and if you
look at if you look at traditional
digital forensics tools they are not
necessarily the tools that are best
built with security in mind a lot of
them assume that they run in a lab
environment a lot of them assume that
they're dealing with semi trusted data
do you want to have a live agent with
root with root access or system and
administrative access on your on your
system that parses parses data random
arbitrary data with some of these
parcels probably not so this kind of if
you look at the early days of girl you
see that we're fighting we're fighting
back and forth in conceptual is like how
to best deal with this but over time
over time this this is settled in the
fact is that we offloaded the processing
to to another tool called lock to the
timeline and and this is very this tool
is very focused on on-time lining and
super time lining if you're not familiar
with that concept either because you
don't have a forensic background is it
basically a chronological overview of of
of relevant time values on a system and
this this this has been an ongoing
process for quite a quite a long time as
I said before when I was in consultancy
it's like to get out of the out of the
tool itself in this particular end case
and and and their poor time lining
capabilities we wrote a small what a
small library to use of interact with
other tools others build other builds
upon that in overtime someone someone
named Kristin Gilda Hansen wrote lot to
timeline and we started adding expanding
expanding more capabilities to death
over time but it's resulted in a vast
amount
data now the more data you collect the
more data you you process the more data
you have to analyze and this is not
always the most effective in an instant
response situation because you don't
want to wait you don't want to wait
hours or days for a full system process
you need to be selective in what you in
what you what you collect and what you
what you process one way of doing this
is if it's you could try to speed up the
speed of your processing another way of
doing is you you selectively collect
what you need but you also want to have
the full timeline if you in case you
need to really kind of go back Forli
understand what is happening and this is
why why as you can see here we started
building and experimenting with with
different tools and different techniques
like data science there are science
techniques to actually find needles in
haystacks automatically you can imagine
this that this tool chain over time is
can be pretty powerful it can help you
it can help you automate address analyze
doing things without necessarily having
to do them manually and this is kind of
the last lesson I want to get in a
giveaway is that if you think if you
think about turning a lot of your manual
work and to continue the automated
processes there's suddenly easier to
test as well there's suddenly easier to
control as well because they're
continuous you can test them you can
automate them you can extend them and
this means you can spend your time on on
improving your defenses even further now
one word of caution about open source is
that having having worked at having
maintained this is that a lot of people
assume open source does the thing you
want out of the box but it is rarely the
case you have to be ready to invest time
into it and you have to be ready to to
adopt it to your own needs
this also means you have to understand
your needs you have to be able to
communicate your needs necessary to do
the project maintainers
because your needs might not be the same
as their originally needs and if you
really rely on software in cases of
incident management well you you you
might want to have support on sighs in
case of a fire it's kind of roughly
recap I only kind of addressed the top
of the iceberg here what are ways you
could you could improve the security of
your defenses now what one way is is is
approach it proactively turn manual work
into continuous automated processes keep
the noise and manual burden low don't
fatigue your people with low quality and
poor poor quality information keep
testing keep evaluating your defenses
and what loss one lost code if you're if
you're interested in pushing the
boundaries of information security we're
always looking for for good people
any questions
[Applause]
hello okay now to imagine to a lot of
people who are working in the trenches
in InfoSec you know this is a bit like
science fiction well these are problems
with our max getting hosed let's just
create a whitelist software and assign a
bunch of people to write it it's always
good to see what's happening in the
future but I do wonder one thing that
came through right and just before I I
want to ask my own question
rich mogul was a security analyst
turned startup guy he's been in the
industry for decades and he coined a
term recently that I thought really
helped me to think differently about a
lot of this sort of stuff and a lot of
this sort of tooling and he turned that
blue collar slash white collar security
tools and it seems like the blue collar
tools the ones that actually just get
done are the most valuable I just
wondered what your take on that is
because it seems like you're really
quite a proponent of just these you know
these things that can take away a lot of
the a lot of the load that are quite
simple things so so I'm not a proponent
of it I actually actually think a lot of
like a lot of the work I started in the
early days in forensics is those kind of
tools they're like tools to get the work
done the thing is the thing is if you
keep using the tools
you cannot extend beyond those tools but
once once you're able to kind of glue
these tools together you can do even
more and that is kind of more the
message like use the blue color tools
you get those tools in preferably in
reusable components you can you can glue
together use those components to further
build build the system and for the
people here who might be working for
more traditional enterprise I mean I'd
imagine that's kind of result in you
know gluing together various commercial
tools I mean is that something that
you've looked at I imagine you would
have a fairly decent insight into some
of the commercial tooling or is it
really just the case that because you
google you build your own so so so I
mean there's definitely a tendency to
build our own because just just the
diversity of the environment it's it's a
non-traditional it's a non-traditional
IT environment so
a lot of like the commercial available
solutions don't do necessary work I know
I know it specially for forensics there
are organizations working on this but
there's also presentations of the
vendors themselves to glue those things
together because that means suddenly
they cannot long no longer lock you into
their into their product so it really
depends I mean you could use you could
you could hire a server if you're like a
more traditional environment could hire
a software developer that can help you
glue these things together you could if
you have good relationships with with a
vendor and some events are pretty open
to it
you could even work with them to get
these things together you have to kind
of think outside of the traditional box
here is that I have a tool and this is
the only capabilities I have within my
tool instead of checking through the
checklist think about everything to work
together now we do have a question here
gentleman in the blue jacket
but in
you have a little bit coming from
conference and presenting it you have
like Constitution areas deal with
[Music]
so the question was really like you know
whether or not yo Kim here's a you know
is really trying to evangelize this
position and encourage other people to
do it or if he's just speaking about
what Google does I would say it's more
it's more is more a large part I mean
that we see at least talking with kind
of tech companies or a tech companies we
see similar we see them going into
similar directions but what I said from
the beginning I mean like I don't expect
a bank or a financial institute to adopt
the same principles like I don't think I
think a lot of the continuous
improvements are very specific to the
organization I think you can I think an
organization like a bank can do it but
it's gonna be different it's gonna be
different I think if there's if there's
room to share approaches if there's room
to go like hey there's open source
solution that can do this X for you and
if you adopt it in such a way well you
have outsourced open sourced Santa and
and things like that I think one really
good example for Google is you know
beyond Corp where you've you know
externalize that and people are like
great that's science fiction but then
other companies have sort of run with it
like duo have run with their whole
beyond Corp for the rest of us so yeah
other questions we got one over here
from Brett more
[Laughter]
the Smythe's on petition the detective
work on business to debate that did not
voice the words will take on health much
[Music]
for those who haven't heard yeah it's
like asking about the risks of
oversharing like techniques for
detection and stuff we are you worried
that by sharing these people will have a
better shot at by passing your detection
so you have to always you have to always
be ticketing in mind that you see the
same as threat intelligence death that
some most of the times these information
is shared in close and close groups so
you have to be careful about what you
share but but also like a lot of the
time the attackers don't care especially
with the automated attackers they have
to hijack your resources they're there
to hijack they collect the accounts sell
them they don't care about if you're
using a very Wireless thing or not they
don't care about it just they so it
depends I mean like if you if you have a
if you have a very targeted attacker you
might not want to share that information
but a lot a lot of the attackers are are
not that targeted and those are the ones
that are actually causing for the former
defender perspective most of the
headaches so why not share those
techniques question down here
yes it really so much about using stuff
like the right way we're using Excel
information to get a better response to
the concert attack as you get to your
end to the bulk of the attackers
some of the much Peola using the tool in
if you have it replace the trying to
prevent down
jin-yi potentially the kind of technique
haven't perfect
so I mean you want to repeat the
question well I mean I I'm trying to
sort of unpack that question a bit as
well you might have tech might have
checked to me is an ontology that tries
to describe different types of attack so
if you if you want to use it in your
organization say like hey I'm giving
this attack this label because it's
important important me why not wear a
real risk of mitre attack being diluted
by every single vendor or like putting
little check marks all over their matrix
now the question we need to go back does
that answer your question or look I'm
trying to gonna understand you guys can
pick this one up after all right who's
who's next we got one right here sorry
very services
robots which are you know why for the
company that have contextual knowledge
all the company's assets they don't have
the skillset for instance
those guys seem to be the guys that I
did we
and this security maturity and marijuana
has been brought to the point where
lighting
[Music]
little I'm doing tool development these
guys have to make a decision as to
whether they engage by
it's all saved will draw down there
it's false
is there anything that you can give us
to make that decision as to whether
business more informed decision so the
question for people who didn't hear it
is like this is science fiction to a lot
of people in this room how do the rest
of us deal with the people who don't
have like for I are ninjas on staff
writing software I mean I mean could you
work together with a software company to
maybe get some of this in place
so I think I think there are but I mean
it's gonna be it's gonna be difficult so
I should just say the question because a
lot of people wouldn't have heard that
it's like at what point you know how do
you make the decision to actually engage
say an external forensics you know
consultant or something at what point do
you pull the trigger on that as an
organization that doesn't have one on
staff I mean me you probably are able to
already capture this in an
organizational security control you
already have come maybe a checklist
where you can say like hey think about
these things and make a decision of our
death if you work able to capture it in
a checklist you're able to script this
to some to some extent and that's
already the first step of your
continuous order into integration you
can reevaluate that that checklist and
say like okay is that our new cases that
we haven't thought about so start small
there and like and don't don't limit
yourself to kind of just you need
software to do this a lot of this can be
done organizational controls as well
hopefully that answers kind of because
you get any more questions one more down
the back and then I think we're going to
wrap it up
so you're talking about sharing with
inside yeah so Google being a massive
organization for those who didn't hear
you know how do you then go about
sharing you know internally generated
threat intelligence with the rest of
Google is that something you even do I
mean I mean but in yes certain
information is shared across the company
but like I already indicated a different
party organization have different needs
for different types of threat
information so it doesn't make sense to
put everything in a large reports it
makes more sense to have the teams that
need the information get that in an
efficient way from the team that deals
with generating information there are
companies that make information sharing
platforms just for that that are
hideously complicated but that some
people actually need you know I did a I
did a sponsored thing for one of the
companies that that make that stuff and
it's yeah when you're dealing at that
sort of scale like trying to figure out
where you know what goes where is just
it's quite difficult but especially
there I would say be pragmatic I mean
most of the value is in actually in a
pragmatic solution and less in by taking
the deployment of such a platform to to
correctly put put the information in
whatever ontology that is used across
the company like having information
available is probably the most in an
easy way to get it's probably the most
the most effective the most beneficial
part of what's the practical way to do
that like a wiki wiki a web service that
web servers that allows you to query the
information is relevant to your to your
part of the organization
at least I can I help you miss
you