[Applause]
okay so thank you all for coming along
firstly because I know that a mitre
attack high-level overview
yeah it doesn't sound like the most
appealing talk to give you some context
as to who I am where I'm coming from a
PJ manager of cyber intelligence working
for Symantec what does that mean they
don't let me near sales that we're
focused very much on an internal
security protecting Symantec from people
coming after it two and a half years in
cyber Intel in the Australian financial
sector and five and a half years working
for the Australian government I'm really
looking at the lens of being a cyber
noob but also looking at the looking
through the lens of the operational to
strategic landscape trying to stop the
attack bingo card from coming along
before it comes along the scope of
course I'm very very biased not aimed at
a technical audience anyone in this room
could certainly bury me if we started
talking technical and that last talk
frightens me and that guys never taught
touching my laptop thinking very much in
that adversary centric mindset I'm all
about the person behind the keyboard
trying to figure out how they think and
who they're going to come after and the
standard disclaimer last two points
there so again the background we all
know why we're starting to use
frameworks and things like that one of
the things that I really like about the
miter attack framework is the pitchers
right risk teams are starting to
understand it sometimes can be a good
thing but it's becoming a common
language that is at the right level for
inter organization and intelligence
sharing within teams as well the reason
why I'm saying that it's at the right
level is that if you go too deep when
you're starting to share intelligence
about some sort of an incident that
you've seen
you start giving away how to hack into
your network you start giving away your
company vulnerability but if you
abstract back to that moderate AK level
and a little bit deeper you start being
able to share some actually interesting
and relevant experiences and it's
starting to really solve that problem of
the poor communication leading to some
real significant failings naturally ever
in the room thank you for putting your
hands up everyone understands it it
really is that Babel Fish and again that
not too detailed it's rapidly becoming
another industry standard doesn't take
away from the work of the various in
Quebec frameworks but again I think it's
that abstraction back which is letting
us use this talk to management and talk
to people who are less technical by
nature and by trade but they're the ones
making the policy decisions that are
affecting all of our lives all of the
time particularly when it goes bad this
is certainly my opinion I think that
hunt operations detection engineering
incident response plans in play books
and especially cyber intelligence should
all use the mitre attack framework as
much as humanly possible because then
everyone's speaking the same language if
someone's talking about a particular way
of doing something or pretty much
anything we're all starting to speak
that same language
I've seen a number of failings before
both in my time in government as well as
my time out of government when one
organization is talking to another
organization using a common term the
trouble is is the definition of that
common term between the two
organizations is entirely different and
that can certainly lead to some
suboptimal outcomes and also it can help
educate management this is going to be
the ongoing theme throughout the
presentation itself and it's trying to
get the security community to get ahead
the bingo card message to get ahead of
what's happening and where the industry
in general is starting to move and
trying to stop my manager from turning
around and going I want a tick in every
box on this particular grid and again
the bias attacking itself has some bias
the size and scope of all the different
techniques naturally definitely check
out the attack on videos that are there
and around talking about the depth of
PowerShell for example is really really
relevant a lot of the conversations with
attack also comes to not everything's
relevant to my organization or my
organization needs to work outside of
the matrix that's a really good thing
being able to understand that attack is
not necessarily going to cover 100% of
everything that you see but when you can
and when you can communicate in that
common message use it because it's there
that's certainly relevant depending on
the size of some of the organization's
being represented in this room and some
of the size of the security teams as
well you will undoubtedly see things
that are sitting way outside the attack
matrix and then when it comes to
actually communicating that message to
other organizations that might help you
actually sit back and say I need to
define exactly what I'm talking about a
lot tighter and a lot and I kind of you
know define everything a lot more and so
I certainly encourage people thinking
outside the matrix some of the stuff
that we do is set up temporary
designators for things that are sitting
outside the matrix so then when might of
themselves roll out a new edition of the
attack framework or something like that
we can translate those temporary
designators back in where applicable or
continue having those temporary
designators it's a bit of an interesting
one and a tricky one to cover as well
the other shortcomings when using mitre
attack analyst shortcomings certainly
including mine automate automate in
being the goal
wouldn't it be great if we could
automate everything trouble is we can't
and of course is it still too high level
I tend to think of mitre attack as I'm
going to talk to my supervisors or my
seniors I don't think of mitre attack
necessarily as I'm gonna present a piece
of paper matrix to my hunt team and say
here's how apt 10-roll or here's how
someone operates because my hunt team
will look at that piece of paper scrunch
it up and throw it back at me and say
it's not detailed enough and they do
it's happened so looking at some
hypothetical scenarios I think it's a
really nice way to introduce some of the
tradecraft that we're using to influence
our management in the correct way
naturally you slide full of caveats
definitely have a look at your own
Incident Response data I'm going to
short-circuit the system and very much
use the data that's available from mitre
themselves and some of the things that
I'm going to do is start borrowing from
geospatial analysis people have been
reading maps forever some people succeed
some people fail that really matters but
I'm going to start borrowing and
stealing from cartographic design
principles map makers their whole job is
putting a piece of paper in front of you
as a manager or as someone who wants to
get from point A to point B and achieve
a certain goal you need to be able to
look at these really quickly understand
the message and then make a decision so
I'm gonna start stealing some tips and
tricks that I learned back in when I was
doing some geospatial analysis I'm gonna
do things like present my work on a
piece of paper to my manager and I'm
gonna stare at him the reason why I'm
staring at him is not just to freak him
out but it's to follow his eyes and look
at where he's looking on the page
and we'll start touching on some of that
stuff as well and instead of saying
defensive posture I'm gonna try and
broaden scope a bit to actually include
detection as well and I certainly live
very much within the assumed and
compromised mindset I just think that
everything is wrecked all the time some
people call it paranoia I call it assume
compromise so asking some of these
questions looking very much at my own
organization where do I work probably
important who's coming after me and
who's coming after my organization how
do those adversaries operate how does
that align to my data am i seeing the
same thing or am i seeing something
completely different and most
importantly as well how does this align
to my competitors data if I'm a bank I
really want to know what's wrecking
other banks not because I can sit there
and go you got wrecked it so I can sit
there and say well okay are we going to
start seeing some of that same behavior
on our networks because that's a really
bad scenario I'm just gonna
short-circuit everything and leave those
seeds planted and we'll have a look and
see what might I have to say again being
an expand key finance sector Who am I
worried about and what am I worried
about financial loss naturally being
number one Swift ATMs and ATM back-end
infrastructure especially when people
start referring to Swift add to ATM
backing the infrastructures which is it
took me a long time to figure out the
difference there far too long I'm also
worried about the theft of personally
identifiable information that can be I
don't want customer data stolen but that
should also expand to if I'm running a
bank that also runs in another country
am I worried about an espionage related
actor or if I'm a bank moving into
another country am I worried about
someone can
doing some sort of espionage for
competitive game I think that that's one
very very interesting point which is
starting to appear more and more is
espionage for competitive game I'm also
worried about intellectual property
theft when I'm talking about
intellectual property within the
financial sector I'm talking about that
big bucket of analytics which has run
over all this excellent customer data to
then try and sell you things being able
to understand and work through that
particularly if you're working at
somewhere like a major financial
institution so the first thing I did was
have a look ok let's have a look at a
matrix and attack matrix and I brought
this one up and yes the font is
remarkably small intentionally so
because I'm trying to keep your read
keep your eyes away from the words
themselves this is a comparison between
the Lazarus group and the cobalt group
these colors were a terrible decision
and think about why I put this in front
of a manager and I said tell me what you
see
and he said Green is good I'm detecting
everything in green orange red is bad
and like our that is terrible a really
really really bad idea because green is
not good but that's the element that
we're dealing with when it comes to
management right I look at a piece of
paper and I just think traffic lights
it's a really nice way of visualizing it
because the colors contrast quite well
but my management read it as traffic
lights so that's my failing as someone
trying to communicate to that manager so
rather than that I spun things around
and added carbon act just to mix it up a
little bit but I started presenting
things in a heat map mode darker color
lighter color a wife's tore red because
red is bad red is something I want you
to focus on and I started having a look
and explaining some of those core red
bits the actual product that I sent to
the man
doesn't I've actually removed all of the
places where there was no scoring and so
my manager only got the actual colored
squares this is part of what I mean
about fighting that detection bingo card
if you present your manager with a bunch
of white squares and then a bunch of red
squares you manager may look at both as
an equal and valid proposition and say
well what about all these white ones
can't we detect things here okay I'll
just remove them what I'm talking to my
manager because in my opinion that's not
relevant to my network that's not
relevant to my attackers that's
irrelevant information so I'm going to
make your job as a manager easier to
focus on what actually counts also we
can start bringing out things things to
note and very much as a narrative form
looking again at the energy sector I'm
more worried about things like
facilitating disruption intellectual
property theft again theft of personally
identifiable information
hacktivists and things like that as well
there's a different set of threat actors
that operate in a different way for the
energy sector when compared to the
finance sector and also when compared to
Symantec where I am now understanding
the differences there when you're
looking beyond the commodity level is
very very important and this is where it
almost slides a little bit more into
that kind of risk function or something
like that looking at an organization
that has targeted industries like mine
very very similar scenario right you're
looking at the heatmap style of thing
being able to talk to and articulate to
management the reason why we're seeing a
bit of bias in this heat map as well it
may be there's more reporting on
particular adversary sets doing
particular sets of activity also keeping
in mind
visibility bias as well just because it
just
because you can't see it doesn't mean
that it's not happening Schrodinger's
attack again
that's where little narrative starts
kicking in and the things to note
so they drive by compromise the system
owner discovery and things like that we
can start in a narrative or a sit down
session explaining some more of that
deeper level knowledge to management but
again making sure that we actually
translated in such a way there was an
interesting talk that I attended back
with the ABC we were putting on a series
of podcasts for their science show and
what they were talking about throughout
the podcast series for that evening was
the importance of science communicators
essentially letting the scientist carry
on with the experiment while the
communicator stepped up translated what
the scientist was doing to the public to
the management to the people that are
paying for the research trying to
harness the skills of the technical
piece technical people and not letting
them get bogged down in PowerPoint which
they'll probably find very frustrating
and again another scenario the
hospitality retail sector theft of PII
point-of-sale compromised credit card
compromising theft no big surprises in
the adversary space here this is Big
Time meteor it's affecting everyone but
it's interesting to see the differences
in techniques but more importantly by
reorganizing and reshuffling the way the
modern matrix looks my managers are
getting the correct articulation of the
viewpoint it's really important
considering people in Western countries
read from left to right top to down to
actually format the matrix in that way
because I want someone to actually pay
attention to the stop to the top of the
page before they get distracted by phone
call before they get distracted by an
SMS message
something like that I need them to
actually get to that point some of the
things that I really want to try now
is mapping all the vendor feeds into
these all the vendors are saying that
they're starting to do attack matrix and
attack mapping so let's give it a shot
adding a lot more of our own incident
data into these mix as well and I want
to see what visibility and collection
gaps start appearing that certainly
speaks to some of that trading is attack
just because I'm not seeing an attack
happening is that a detection problem or
is that attack genuinely actually not
happening I'm really curious as well
because I'm always thinking in that
adversary centric mindset people are
creatures of habit they do things in the
same way back when I was mulling around
with DOS prompts and hiding and unhiding
files because my parents knew how to use
a computer I would sit there I would run
the flags for particular things in
certain ways because that's how I
remembered them and that's what made
sense to me and my brain at the time I
remember talking to one of my friends
and seeing him run the exact same set of
the exact same command but all the flags
were in a completely different order and
I was like wow never even thought about
running it that way I was running it
because rash makes in English words and
so therefore that's how I remembered it
but it's things like that I really want
to start experimenting with seeing if we
can see a bit more human behavior and a
bit more fingerprinting we will achieve
peak intel shall we say if I can pick up
an incident response set of reports
gather all of that information and
actually group that campaigning together
it'd be even better if then by using
open-source we can start hypothesizing
about some attribution and also
prioritizing detection strategies as
well right
if all
the adversaries that I think are coming
after me will use certain things then I
want to be able to turn around to my
hunt and detection team and say maybe we
need to focus on detecting this before
that there's a whole range of
complications in there obviously and you
won't be able to just tick through in
order one two three four five but it's
certainly some way of prioritizing and
starting to shake out the noise that
appears and also the standardizing and
automating for analysis the dream the
place where I'd start to think about
wrapping up is mainly saying thank you
to all the people in this room thank you
to the people who run these conferences
and thank you to people who are open to
sharing their ideas because I'm not out
here by myself I'm standing right very
much on the shoulders of giants and I'm
trying to add to that collaborative body
of knowledge which is starting to spin
up and really starting to focus
certainly thanks to the guys over the
guys and girls over at mitre for doing
things like the attack con putting all
the videos on the internet and things
like that the various open-source
projects again looking at it from a
non-technical new kind of level and
being able to leverage some of the work
that already exists and just spinning it
round to try and speak to that
non-technical audience and most of all
thanks to anyone who's actually curious
about how things work and stuff like
that I did notice in tricks in the badge
before but yeah so very fast talk and I
know that I've probably thrown the
schedule again looking at Scottie as he
stares at his watch but thank you all
for attending as well
definitely I'm curious about taking
questions and I'm curious about hearing
your thoughts particularly when dealing
with some of these moderate a key
elements and if we start working and
educating and management now fingers
crossed we
avoid the bingo card that will pop up
Jim thank you very much
[Applause]
we have a question the question was is
the finance sector using this already to
share Intel starting to starting to and
it's because there was like a little
Intel sharing community that started
just kind of shrieking about it all at
the same time it's been around for a
while but the last year it's just all of
a sudden it is everywhere mmm you know
just as that common language it's been
surprising actually how quickly it's
it's caught on what do you say yeah
definitely and I think one of the
strengths for it as well is that as an
analyst if I look at a really detailed
framework
I'll get locked into analysis paralysis
I won't know if something belongs into
that of that and then my brain kind of
locks up but with the miter attack
framework it's a little bit more
straightforward all right do we have any
other questions
all right everybody please thank Kevin
Cleary
thank you
[Applause]