so our next speaker is Karin Jacobson
and I remember Karin's talk from
Bacharach econ one actually cuz he was
like he did a PowerShell talk back when
PowerShell stuff was really still like I
think we've just mentioned it on the
show recently about how like you know
then you could just people would add
script protection so that you could only
run signed PowerShell scripts and you
know hope Microsoft set this up in such
a way that if this was bothering you you
could just turn off you know script
checking it was it was it was a horror
show talk from someone who really are
Kieran was at that point a you know
Windows Windows guy right so today he's
doing something called the boring
security talk and I'm going to read from
the abstract here he says we all know
that securing our applications is a
necessity but it can be incredibly
boring with time and budget constraints
we often focus on the more exciting
security aspects and tools but in this
talk we'll be looking at some of the
aspects to our application security that
are often overlooked the software do we
depend on CIC the infrastructure sending
email and resolving DNS you know Allah
the basics now Karen Jacobsen is the
head of IT at ratify and a Microsoft
Microsoft a Microsoft MVP and we're
gonna bring him up there give me the
studies talk it's Karen Jacobson
[Music]
good afternoon everybody my name's Karen
Jacobson this is actually my fourth
cracky talk on conference fault I'm
speaking to you all and it's a pleasure
to return every year and and talk about
various epic things last year last time
as a cracker con sorry I spoke about dev
sack ops while that content was built
upon my experiences of DevOps and dev
sack ops within a team within my own
team today's content is a bit of an
extension of a lot of the stuff that
I've been working on in that sort of
respects I want to talk about things
that often get overlooked and a lot of
this stuff came about from acquisition
processes and things as well things like
protecting a CIC the infrastructure
email security practices or bad
practices DNS management and an
understanding what happens when
dependencies within your software stack
go bad so see ICD systems in a DevOps
world they're the heart of a
smooth-running organization they're a
mission critical aspect to our
infrastructure but as anyone in the room
ever considered the chaos that an
attacker could get up to if they'd owned
this infrastructure your team city your
octopus your Jenkins I see a lot of
badly set up infrastructure and so let's
take a look at some of those common
issues people love to overshare on the
internet is my usual statement it's
common to see the startups and smaller
less mature organizations operating
entirely in the cloud and exposing the
management interfaces and the API
interfaces of their C ICT infrastructure
to the Internet
we're not talking about saz offerings
like agile devops or github gitlab here
we're talking out your team city your
octopus your Jenkins there's a lot of
authentication mistakes going on the
lack of hate to dps is probably the
biggest by far but that's not going to
get you owned as such the use of shared
accounts or generic accounts is very
common this is in most cases a licensing
violation and not just a security issue
you're destroying your audit trails in
the process you're losing the ability of
knowing who's pushed what to production
when named accounts are being used stale
accounts are really common you know
systems where the developers who had
access they've long since left the
company they're off somewhere else yet
this accounts on the CI CD
infrastructure are still active there's
endless stories of disgruntled employees
coming back and trashing environments
and a CI CD system would be a great
place to do that sort of activity the
lack of MFA is another problem
it's one of the strongest defenses
against credential spraying attacks
we're not really seeing those directed
at CIC the infrastructure but only is a
matter of time I'm often contacted by
consultants working in heavily locked
down networks
the devs don't have admin rights in
production some cases and inhabitant dev
or even on their own workstations the
security teams are super happy that
they've locked everything down what they
haven't realized though is is a really
big hole in their security model the
devs have admin rights on the CI CD
infrastructure that infrastructure has
admin rights on prod so in essence the
developers do have admin access to
production now how does this happen
there's a bunch of different ways I see
with AWS cloud the the keys are given
far too much access to too many
resources and too many actions that's a
big one I'm seeing these days how do I
put this in a family-friendly way I
really don't understand why patching is
so hard anymore
you've got hours patching plans but you
might be running old versions of CI CD
tools and we saw this yesterday with the
talk about ideas of March you know
there's old versions of those tools and
get new compilers and stuff that are out
there and can hurt you for those of you
running Jenkins in your environment how
comfortable are you that all of your
instances are actually up-to-date it
sort of really rough for you with
security patches
are they all up-to-date so in February
last year
hackers exploited vulnerabilities in
Jenkins to make over three million
dollars mining Manero they were
successful for the sheer fact that
there's so many Jenkins servers that are
exposed to the Internet and from
experience these instances have quite a
lot of computing power associated with
them what shocks me with this case is
that no one really noticed that their
bills and deployments were taking longer
maybe they did they just upped the
amount of resources on the instances I
don't know think about your environment
if you're running these cloud instances
would you have noticed this happening or
would it have been the bills shock when
you get your Azure or your AWS bill and
you go why is it $60,000 for the month
would that be have you're monitoring so
how do we start to protect against these
attacks
so network security 101 tells us we
should be restricting access where
possible do you need to expose your CI
CD systems to the Internet if your
development and production environments
aren't totally within the corporate
network and it's all locked down then
maybe it doesn't need to be accessible
via the internet if it does need to be
can you restrict it down to say a set of
trusted IP addresses you know your your
secure server IP addresses your office
IP ease of you know a VPN endpoint if
you can't do that can you at least
restrict what destination ports you can
connect to if it's something like
Jenkins you might have HTTP https
management you might have SSH to manage
the server you don't really need FTP or
telnet or anything else open to the
Internet authentication and privileged
access has to occur over HTTPS it can't
occur over plaintext protocols
certificates are easy to obtain now
there's no excuse and don't be lazy and
used self-signed certificates users
should have their own accounts no shared
accounts personal preference is to use
something like SSO I don't care if it's
as your ad or open LDAP or any of those
sorts of things just use a sense
any provider the benefits of s is so
better auditing monitoring and user
account provisioning and de-provisioning
if you see I see these systems are
exposed to the Internet
Mike my personal sort of belief is that
MFA is mandatory you don't get a choice
out of that one it has to be enabled
quick side comment here if you're making
an application or you're a vendor that's
supplying applications and you don't
support SSO or MFA in 2019 or you're
gonna try and charge me extra for it I
am actively looking at replacing your
products within my environment
I don't want your insecure crap in my
environment anymore that's just the way
I'm running things now you see I see
these systems your service accounts need
to run with the less privileged as
possible avoid local system in route on
Windows and Linux if you're running
within an Active Directory environment
don't run as domain admin don't run as
enterprise admin use standard user
accounts where possible restrict your
AWS keys to only the resources and the
actions they need to perform as URIs as
your security should be assigned at a
resource or a resource group level not
at a subscription level think about
restricting access to your CI CD
infrastructure that junior dev that only
needs to view the status of builds
doesn't need admin access build a
patching plan that includes all of the
tools and you develop a chain IDs dev
tools compilers packaging software in
your CI CD components you've already got
OS patching plans you just need to
extend it to the rest of the software
stack so one little interesting story
about CI CD from 2017 they're actually
BOTS that we're going through github and
would hunt for projects that used CI for
pull request validation they would then
replace the code of the project with
Bitcoin mining code and of course create
a pull request and then of course your
that code would then be automatically
run as part of the PR validation process
we all love these automated builds the
trigger off and
decided they could but mine Bitcoin via
I will pretty quickly shut down via
github they put controls in place to
prevent this from happening but once
again
how would you detect this attack in your
environment would it be Bill shock again
that's your you know monitoring
mechanism for these styles of attack DNS
it's a critical system that never gets
the attention it deserves every
organization relies on DNS yet we really
don't think about it as much as we do
say printing or email and that's a big
downfall to most organizations as we've
seen in the last few months and so what
are some of the challenges that I see
with organizations managing their DNS
organizations really struggle
understanding what DNS entries they have
why they're there when were they created
it when were they modified was that
entry added by an attacker or a
legitimate administrator with approval
now if you're sitting here and you're
working in an environment with say
change management like ITIL you might be
feeling a little smug right now you're
probably thinking well I've got change
forms we've got requests proces we know
everything that's happening in our
environment to challenges for you when
you go back to work does your change
request process actually fully describe
what the change is and why and secondly
if I was to get your DNS zone and
randomly point at one entry could you
tell me who created it why they created
it and when they created it with that
process take five minutes
we're take an hour a day a week a month
during a security incident time will
matter in how you can answer these
questions particularly around DNS if you
think that an attacker has created that
entry and you're about to delete it how
do you know that it's not your
legitimate production service that
you're about to delete the DNS entries
for
the next challenge is around the speed
at which we now need to make DNS changes
in the past I probably happened once
maybe twice a year by a system engineer
or a network engineer as part of some
sort of application upgrade cycle
records were pretty static for years at
a time things are changing now we want
faster application release cycles we
want daily releases we want DevOps yet a
lot of organizations really haven't
changed their approach to managing DNS
we've still got ops teams going into a
console and making the changes manually
and this leads to a bunch of different
problems and the obvious thing is that
there's a bottleneck it's going to take
more time to make those changes if I had
a dollar every outage that was caused by
DNS I'd probably be driving an expensive
sports car and have my own private jet
why do these challenges occur well it's
often just a simple issue of visibility
those impacted by a DNS change are often
the last to know it's happening or they
often find out after the fact this is
another point where change management
really should have helped us with this
visibility problem but in my experience
DNS changes tend to get hidden in the
process they're low priority changes
they're low visibility changes are low
risk and so people aren't aware that
we're about to change the IP addresses
of you know are the DNS entries of the
mail servers you know that everything in
our environment needs to connect to with
the move to providers like CloudFlare or
Asia or route 53 by AWS more
organizations are actually outsourcing
the hosting of their external DNS this
is actually improved availability and
DNS services but it introduces some
other sources of problems the main
mechanism for managing these platforms
is typically some sort of web interface
there's often api's and other management
services but left to there
devices a lot of organizations will just
drift to that web experience the biggest
issue with these interfaces is
transposition errors
you've got your change request or the
email requesting to make a change you
copy and paste you miss it miss a
character instead of web mail it's web
mail or something and all of a sudden no
one can get to the service you know or
we manually type an IP address in and we
type an eight instead of a nine and all
of a sudden prod goes down all these
interfaces are different they use
different terminology and that is
another contributing factor to to
configuration issues things like do we
use user blank to refer to the root of
the DNS zone or an @ symbol or an
underscore what what terminology do we
use a big part of is that we need a
standard method for working with DNS
across multiple providers and attacks
against DNS are becoming more and more
popular especially in the last few
months in January there were reports
from of multiple US government domains
being hit by DNS hijacking things went
as far as for DHS and GCHQ to release
directives warning about these risks and
telling people what steps or what
actions they needed to take this is rare
for these sorts of organizations to
release these sorts of directives this
is the first for DHS the second for GCHQ
the only other one being one a cry for
them dangling DNS entries are another
major problem particularly when cloud
infrastructures being used situations
where DNS records particularly see names
they're created they point to some sort
of cloud service days weeks months go by
those cloud services are deleted but
those are regional cname records remain
Microsoft actually got hit by this in
2017 ResNet Microsoft comm was a cname
to ResNet - prod as your website's
dotnet couple of months later so many
deleted that as a website but those
entries remained
a security researcher discovered it
alerted them they fix the problem but
all it would have taken was one attacker
creating an azure app service plan as
your app service sorry with the name
resonant portal - prod and they would
have been able to hijack a Microsoft
subdomain think about the effectiveness
of a phishing campaign that was actually
a Microsoft subdomain that would
probably be like about a 90% success
rate
95% maybe so what tools can we start to
use to streamline DNS management and
reduce these errors so DNS control is an
open source tool written in go and
maintained by the Stack Overflow team
and it allows you to preview changes
before pushing them to your DNS provider
ratify we've been using DNS control for
about a year now
anyone at ratify can propose a DNS
change and one of our platforms team can
then go and review it approve it merge
it to master and it's a push to
production this empowers developers to
create changes they can then go and
clean up records is they decommission
infrastructure and we've removed my team
as a bottleneck so how does it help
sorry how does it help us solve some of
these challenges so it uses JavaScript
to define a simple format that can be
understood by everybody we can all
propose and review and understand
changes you don't need to be a Java
expert JavaScript expert I have no idea
about what Java Script is or does an ops
background yet I've had no problems
writing zones the screenshot here is a
piece from a public zone that I maintain
for planet PowerShell you can see how
easy it is to understand what's an a
record a text record a cname with the
human readable format you should also be
able to add comments that describe the
contents of the zone this is production
this is development this is a staging
slot
these are our mail servers so now you
can start to actually answer those
questions of what's that record actually
for get version control systems there
another core piece of this DNS
management puzzle we store our DNS
control files in git it gives us a
history of all the changes in our zone
and who made those changes git branches
they're easy to create and merge and
they allow developers and engineers to
make changes and push them into
production easily get becomes your
change tracking tool get logged get
blame you use those to work out what
changes has been made that broke pride
and who made that change platforms like
github and Azure DevOps
they extend our get experience with pull
requests these are like they like change
requests in ITIL but they're faster to
create they're easier to read and
understand and you don't need a meeting
to get them approved they shine a light
on changes in a way that ITIL promised
us and has never delivered you can
include the teams and the individuals
that might be impacted for approval if
you know that your change for the MX
records is going to impact your mail
servers then maybe you include the email
to you know support teams the security
teams and the desktop you know mobile
support teams as well they can all read
the change and then approve it
acknowledge they know what's going on
see a CD is the final piece to this
puzzle and it removes the risks of human
generated errors we can run DNS controls
preview function for all of our pull
requests and that way we can validate
the changes and report on what actions
it's going to make when we push to prod
this gives us more confidence in the
changes being made once a PR is approved
the changes emerge to production and our
CD process will use the push
functionality to push those changes into
our DNS platforms so as you can see here
we've changed our DNS management flow
from something that requires a lot of
human interaction to something that's
fully automated we've sped up DNS
changes from you know minutes to
from days two minutes so before I finish
one little example that's actually in
the wild and you can play along at that
link down the bottom here we can see a
page on Dells website and it's talking
about their hardware based encryption
the page has links to white papers and
case studies training encourages to buy
their product so let's assume that I'm
interested in the trusted computing
guide I'm gonna click the you know hover
over the little link in the bottom at
bottom left corner and see where it goes
so goes to a website called Dell for SLG
com I worked out that that used to stand
for Dell for state and local government
it was a website targeted to those
groups and quite a lot of content around
security stuff in the past what happens
if I click on that link and that's not
the Dell website that's a plumbing
supply store in Turkey it seems that
somebody noticed the domain wasn't
renewed and decided to renew the domain
or buy the domain and set up a fun
little traffic redirector so anything on
the Dell website that actually
references Dell for SLG com now goes to
the Turkish plumbing supply store your
domains are part of your organization's
brands you need to take the same steps
as you would protecting your logo or
your you know type set and your
background colors on your website that
you know to your email domains into your
DNS domains as an industry we'd love to
think that we're getting rid of email
the truth is that even if you're using
slack for all your internal
communications email is what you're
using to communicate to your customers
your vendors and your suppliers we use
email activities for things like account
creations confirmations password resets
considering how important our email is
to our business it really doesn't appear
that many organizations have taken the
steps to ensure that our recipients of
those emails can verify them as being
legitimate where do I start with what's
wrong with email least
email basted attacks like spam and
phishing and everything else are on the
increase there's more stories of
successful whaling style attacks against
executives and high profile targets
within organizations I'll come as some
sort of formal you know legal subpoena
or customer complaint and they're really
really good at hooking you know your
executives your CEOs and things like
that they're really good at preying on
those targets
I think by now we've all heard about
some of the various executive
impersonation attacks these aware say
this attack as opposed as like the CEO
they sent an email to say the admin or
finance teams or their personal
assistant saying hey I've got this
urgent request to transfer money into
this person or this country to complete
it you know our business takeover or
some sort of business transaction or hey
I need to buy iTunes gift cards to
reward customers for their you know
business to us
these attacks create a sense of urgency
and they're coming from people that we
rarely question and that's why they're
so successful my frustration with all
this is that we can actually make these
attacks harder we can't prevent them but
we can make them more difficult but most
organizations don't seem to care about
doing this they don't seem to want to
put those controls in place so here's an
email it's been sent from have I been
pwned we're probably all nervous about
about when we get these emails every
message is made up of two parts we've
got our headers
they're basically key value pairs
providing delivery and diagnostic
information and then we've got the
message body that's the bit of the email
we actually want to read so there's two
headers that cause a lot of confusion
and they're all to do with the from who
the message is from and the problem is
that when we send a message using SMTP
we actually specify who the message is
from twice in the communication when the
SMTP connection is built the sending
SMTP client specifies the sender's email
address we often call this the end
from or SMTP from later on in the mail
headers the client will also specify the
sender again and this is often called
the message header or the from field so
the message from or the header from
field it's this one that mail clients
display to the user when they open that
email these to fit these two headers
don't actually need to match platforms
like this and grid will often use
different entries to track bounce rates
and do redirects and things like that
they usually do but they don't have to
the return path header here and the
headers is created when the server
accepts that email message and that's
actually the envelope from so that's
that an initial from address that it it
saves so now some basics we can start to
take control of our email environment
and the first step is to work out who is
sending email as your brand
you've got your obvious choices your
corporate email your internal
applications but there's probably a lot
of other sources that you might want to
consider shadow IT that your IT teams
probably don't know about your marketing
and sales teams are probably using
services like MailChimp and SendGrid to
send emails to customers
another big hurdle is says products a
number of these programs platforms want
to send email as your domain and it's
typically the HR ones say an employee
creates a leave request the HR system
will then want to send an email as that
employee to their manager saying hey can
you approve this and they're the ones
that often get overlooked when we start
to sort of work out what sending email
is our brand in some organizations the
thought of determining all the sources
is too much as I said most organizations
have policies around using their brand
what colors can be used how the logo can
be used you should be protecting it like
any other asset if you don't take steps
to protect it how do I actually you know
how can I actually believe that you take
security you know strongly how do you
actually believe a bank when they say
they they take our customer privacy
seriously so once we know who is sending
email we can start looking at setting up
SPF and it's an IP list of those who can
send email is our domain it's maintained
in DNS receivers can look at that list
and then reject unauthorized messages a
common misconception
with SPF is that it validates the
message from header it's actually the
envelope from SPF has some advantages
and disadvantages we can actually tack
different records together so we don't
need to know all of the IP addresses for
office 365 or Google Apps we just
reference to those providers the
limitation here is you only get ten DNS
queries some platforms check and hit
stop at ten others don't so we need to
take a bit of care once you've got your
SPF records we can move on a D Kim D Kim
uses digital signatures it's not quite
the same level of his protection as say
PGP or s/mime these signatures are not
visible to the recipient they're added
to the headers by the sending server and
then they're validated by the receiving
server we put the public keys of the
sending servers into DNS and that's how
we do that that verification deacon
validates the message from header so
it's submit it's actually handling the
other from header that we're talking
about before it's going to take a lot
more work to set it up it's a lot more
difficult than SPF because you need to
make sure that every system that's
sending email as your organization
supports signing those messages I had to
wait six months for one size van and to
get their act into gear and it was only
on threatening that we're gonna leave
them that they actually finally deployed
it once you've got D Kim then we can
start looking at D mark a lot of
organizations are terrified that D mark
policies going to result in their emails
not being delivered to customers and
you're right you can shoot yourself in
the foot with D mark but if you take
care you can ensure successful delivery
d mark builds up
builds upon SPF and dekum provides more
validation that the message from and the
envelope from headers are aligned and
the idea is that if a message passes
both these checks and the headers are
aligned it's a valid message domains can
specify different policies these are
actions that the receivers should take
when a message fails validation senders
can also specify if receivers need to
provide delivery reports on what they've
accepted and what they've rejected your
Demark policy is stored once again in
DNS now you know why DNS is so important
to this story
start with the policy of none moved to
quarantine policy and then finally onto
a rejection policy quick note about
office 365 is it actually handles the
reject policy as it would the quarantine
policy so those emails will still be
delivered to the junk mail folder of a
recipient even if the sender main said
hey no you should reject anything that
doesn't succeed validation I don't know
why they've done this they've just done
it that way let's just talk about an
oxymoron that is Bank grade security
phishing scorecard tracks SPF D command
D mark configuration of organizations
worldwide 53% of banks and financial
service providers here in Australia have
no D mark configuration at all
38% have a policy of none and just 9%
have a policy of reject or quarantine
pretty well I'm gonna say something else
but it's pretty bad how much do they
really care about the privacy and
security of their customers they really
don't
so almost all software projects depend
on other software and this could be
JavaScript packages
docker images libraries provided by
vendors the problem is that we provide
considerable trust in these third
parties that write these dependencies we
often think that they're better people
and us a bit of impostor syndrome really
we like to believe that there
going introduced malicious code
deliberately and that they follow
similar security practices to our own
unfortunately over the last year or so
that trust has been broken quite a large
number of times February last year the
JavaScript plug-in browsealoud was
compromised and it was it's code was
altered to inject coin hives Mineiro
minor for several hours anyone visiting
the over 4,000 impacted websites
inadvertently ran the hidden mining code
on their computer australian web sites
included government departments city
councils charities disability support
provider's quite a few that actually
have access to the metadata retention
scheme also run browsealoud which scares
the hell out of me
s RI or sub resource integrity is the
best defense here it basically allows a
website to tell users tell users browser
to check the integrity of these
third-party assets if the integrity
doesn't match the stored hash it doesn't
load them in June last year it was
reported that 17 malicious containers
were removed from docker hub some of
these images were just harmless and
mining Manero others created reversed
shells or attempted to install backdoors
on the host machine they were available
for over a year before docker pulled
them estimates are that the attackers
made around $90,000 mining Manero from
the the more harmless ones as we as
we're spoken about yesterday with
Sarah's talk the best protection is a
private image repositories where you've
validated the security of those docker
images in July an attacker compromised
the es lint scope and NS lint config
eslint NPM packages they published a
malicious version that would send the
contents of the user's NPM RC to the
attacker this file typically contains
your credentials to NPM the belief is
that they were trying to get more access
to even more npn maintainer x'
these two packages see three million
downloads a week they have 31 directly
dependent packages and to 20,000
indirectly dependent packages how did it
happen
the official story is that the
maintainer reused passwords and didn't
use 2fa as I said earlier not all
maintainer x' follow the same security
practices as we do just last week
attackers added a backdoor to the
bootstraps as S SaaS rubygem the great
news about this one was that it was
picked up really quickly somebody in the
community went hey this codes doing some
interesting things and created a github
issue the developers got onto it and
pulled it pretty quickly and it only
took a few hours from initial discovery
initial posting to actually being pulled
unfortunately it was still downloaded
about 12,000 times in those few hours we
don't have a full breakdown of what
happened there's only two developers
that actually have push rights to that
repo to that that particular ruby gem
we'll find out more in the next few
weeks about how this incident happened
and last week another one last week was
a wordpress developer called pip Digg
was accused of adding a number of
suspicious
well malicious features to their
WordPress plugin
and it's a very popular WordPress
plug-in and that included a remote kill
switch that deleted all of your
WordPress tables just drop them all a
remote password change function and it
was ddossing a competitor's website as
well really nice people it appears that
they even took active measures measures
when they were detected of covering
their tracks they deleted their
open-source repos deleted most the
history and then reposted them up
without any of the malicious code as I
said it's it's a mistake to trust all of
these author
is that they're not going to be
deliberately malicious sometimes authors
do turn out to be deliberately malicious
and pretty much bastards that's it for
me I want to thank you all for listening
to me today I hope that you found
something useful in today's session it
wasn't too boring for you I'll be
posting up all the contents of this
presentation on my blog over the next
few days thank you all very much for
listening to me today well all right
good stuff I've been following that that
WordPress stuff a little and it's yeah
it's there's been some real but there's
been some other ones as well like
WordPress WordPress the world of
WordPress is like that trash fire is
burning brighter than usual yes at the
moment hey our just a quick announcement
to there's a whole bunch of prepaid
merch at the merge desk that people
haven't picked up so if you have prepaid
for your merch go get it go get it and
then merch people can relax and smile
all of that um so who's got questions
for Karen we got one down there
the question is like how big an
organization do you need to be to do all
of this stuff like because there seems
to be a bit of overhead involved
we have 250 sorry 350 employees right
now I felt it was valuable enough to do
it for that I've done most of these
steps for my home domains my project
domains a lot of it certain forget yeah
with on the email stuff yeah email stuff
is pretty much set and forget unless
you're adding a new DNS you know a new
email sort of sending service and that
helps with the shadow IT DNS is pretty
much configure and forget because you
know it just runs itself with the CI CD
one thing I want to pick up on those you
like I don't trust the authors right and
that goes for things like you know
Dockers docker containers and you know
WordPress plugins and whatever but
that's the world we're in now right
where you don't do stuff yourself
anymore you just take all of this stuff
that other people have done you glue it
together and you hope for the best so
you know I just wonder if we're in if
we're in that sort of trap right now
where the advice is to do it all
yourself
but like no one's got time to do that
so we just have to kind of cross
our feet I'd like to think of it as we
just need to every time we bring a new
piece of software a bit from one of the
big vendors or a small guy that sort of
you know go let's coding in their
bedroom for an open-source project we
need to just build that trust and go
through those steps if it's open source
and it's a small codebase take a look at
it see if there's anything that jumps
out at you no one's got time for that
yeah and there's also the problem to
where that single lone coder in their
bedroom you know might be offered like
one Bitcoin or well actually no that's a
bit high less than one Bitcoin to sell
off their project yeah to someone who
says they're gonna you know do something
commercial with it then of course they
just you know loaded up with malicious
and we've seen cases where that's
happened that if you um come to you know
chrome plug-in vendors and gone here's
$30,000 for your chrome plug-in and yeah
if somebody did that for some of my
software projects and I'd be handing it
over yeah yeah good
don't use myself projects so if you're a
Russian gangster who wants to buy some
software projects and and and you know
target all users contact here and I
think many people use my software so
you're pretty safe there I've got a
question back here
very
yeah so what do you say to what do you
say to the rest of the organization when
they're accusing you of being a
roadblock because you might want to look
at the haurache oh they're trying
to put everywhere in your organization a
lot of time these days I now just refer
to things cases or I sort of say hey
remember that time that you were
involved in that security breach or you
work with that customer and you had to
work through that security breach
because of one of the other developers
within the customer and they start to
realize that hey we need to do this work
it seems a good way to convince people
isn't it together well here's a printout
of some headlines for you clunk you know
take a bunch yeah and the other thing is
if you can reduce your roadblocks in
other places within your IT organization
that can be a lot easier and that's why
things like DNS control for us it means
that we've got more spare time to do the
security reviews and things like that
because we're not trying to manage DNS
and all the other sort of stuff that we
normally would on a day to day basis
anyone else going once going yeah are we
going there
[Music]
and see what that is
yeah
[Music]
so yeah I had to go how to do
if someone who did it themselves that's
no that's like Lionel's one of the
developers at ratify so he's actually
one of my customers so he's been on the
receiving end of a lot of his stuff
alright everybody thank hearing Jacobson
you