yes and we are welcoming me k or michael
knudsen mckay occlusion who's talking
about bluetooth okay yes so this is a
talk on Bluetooth Low Energy yeah so
this is like if just a brief overview
first I'm going to talk about bit about
classic Bluetooth just to sort of set
some reference as to what it's actually
low-energy about this and then i'll talk
about the when again hopefully i'll have
time for some demos okay so first of all
what is in this talk this is this is not
a like a hard cock on Bluetooth Low
Energy this is supposed to give you an
idea of the the principles and the like
it design decisions what are the goals
that you're trying to achieve with this
talk and sort of give you an idea of the
rough ideas of like rough idea of how
this is actually implemented how this
works so what is not as in this talk is
none of the hosts stack and applications
aspect you would say that this is
because it's sort of radio centered I'm
not going to talk about security or
competing technologies because i'm not
very not familiar with them with these
these aspects so okay so first of all
classic bluetooth so classic bluetooths
operates in like the 2.4 gigahertz
frequency spectrum just like your Wi-Fi
and that's full of stuff so it's a yeah
it's like 79 channels of one megahertz
each and the connection to apologies
like you can have a maximum of seven
connections and they they're all sort of
connected to some sort of central master
there's a bunch of different versions of
classic bluetooth I've left to have some
of the really old ones here so like the
classic blue tooth has been with one
megabit so 30 megabits or whatever
depending on which stand on standard
you're implementing so in in one ear
sorry in two point oh we got the the new
enhanced data rate which took bandwidth
to 3 megabits and in three-point oh they
implemented this scheme of being able to
use what's called an alternate Mac 5
which is basically this allows you to
use Wi-Fi to do file transfers like
offloading large data
verse 22 y5 in practice nobody really
uses this in four-point-oh which i think
came out in 2010 we got this new idea of
the bluetooth low energy like aspect of
this and there's a new spec 5 point out
coming out which is a bunch of
extensions to the le le spec which for
instance like 2 megabits long range and
some Direction finding scheme so ok the
topologies in classic bluetooth is that
yourself you can have like a single
master in a single slave or you can have
a single master which has a bunch of
slaves or you can have like complex
topologies where there's a bunch of
masters which have a number of slaves
associated with them and some of these
masters are slaves on some links and
masters on their own link there's this
scheme of the master repeating repeating
Lee pulling its slaves so just checking
do you have something for me or here's
some data for you which means there that
the slaves have to be be alive a lot of
the time to be able to respond to these
queries it's possible to do role switch
that you become the mass from the
linkage that master which means that
sometimes you can save a bit of power by
deciding when to actually do radio
communication and this the whole the
scheme for doing this device discovery
and and and setting up connection is
done through paging where the possible
clients are required to every now and
again go out and listen to listen for
what is called paging for fairly long
periods of time so this is sort of the
deep at the classic bluetooth okay so
quickly about Bluetooth Low Energy it
was originally developed at nokia under
the name of library I was taken in by
the Bluetooth special interest group and
they've tried to use a lot of different
names for it's so like Bluetooth Low
Energy low-energy Bluetooth le bluetooth
smart I think there is even more names
but it's from a branding perspective
this is a bit confusing this yeah this
this is not very success successful so
okay before we had more into bluetooth
low and just a brief detour about
sensors if we have like sensor networks
we often have diff
kinds of network topologies like we can
have whereas some something is
broadcasting it or you can have like
something is just broadcasting the
temperature is 50 degrees or you can
have like point-to-point collection
saying you set up a connection and you
sort of sync to some device and you
repeatedly listen to a sensor update
from this particular device orphans
often sensors as a battery or power
constrained because they're I mean we
want them to be small because because I
mean this makes them easy to to put in
some place without like being a it's I
mean this is it's useful if they're
small you can put them everywhere and
also I mean this makes them cheap to to
produce but this often puts a constraint
in the battery size which means they can
use a lot of power because if they use a
lot of power the battery will drain in
no time so this is a I mean so there's
some physical constraints on on this
whereas often when you look at the the
data collections out of this this is
often centralized so you have some sort
of thing that maybe connect a this is
often may be placed inside your house
like your temperature which shows raise
some display which shows but the
temperatures outside or whatever and
these are often I mean they these are
maybe have a big batteries because
there's some sort of big screen on them
or maybe they were even connected to the
electrical grid so they can these get to
use a lot of power so yeah and I mean
it's it's it's not as inconvenient
changing the batteries in the units that
are inside your house then going out to
to your garden and finding whatever
wherever you put the the thermometer
there but really I mean this is not just
for sensor so I mean and whenever I say
sends us in this this is sort of an in
the ease of abstract sense this is
something that generates some dates and
something else wants to obtain this data
okay so low power 101 how do I actually
achieve low power well first of all the
ideas you have low peak power whenever
we use the most power we make sure this
is very little we try to do fast
connections and I'll come back to this
later to say what this is if we can if
we can have a fast connection it means
yet this has some nice properties and
basically well fundamentally we've also
want to do this so we have the maximum I
sleep time the more time we can make our
devices do absolutely nothing the less
battery they will require so okay low
peak power basically this is because we
would like something to run off like I'm
fine self at I have some small tokens
here which are like okay so this is a
development board so this is not a very
that's not a design which is good for me
but anyway these are a small run off
like a cr2032 and they can run off from
a year or two and basically you can use
these for various purposes so these
devices run off a coin cell battery for
a long period of time ok so in classic
blusas there's this concept of having a
power of classes where you could say I'm
a power class where I can transmit up to
this this amount of power and business
somewhat complex scheme for devices
trying to figure out whether to increase
or decrease the signal strength like if
someone is yelling you can tell them it
like turn it down a notch also low peak
power means we state that we would like
a receive a sensitivity at a minus
seventy DBM but really we expect a
real-world devices to be able to work at
minus ninety TPM so this means that the
the devices must be able to pick up
quite faint signals finally there's
something in RF called the the
modulation index and for Ellie this is a
0.5 and for a classic Bluetooth this is
zero point 25 basically this means that
it's it's much easier to distinguish a
zero from a one inkling in Le than it is
in classic bluetooth so this gives an
increased robustness for a given power
level I mean and when you have increased
robustness this means that with that
with the smaller amount of power your
signal can be transferred on longer
distances and still be able to be picked
up correctly at the the other end of the
connection so yeah so that's low power
of fast connections so basically in two
in all
to do device discovery in in a classic
bluetooth we have to go out and listen
for paging for 20 milliseconds at a time
whereas in sorry we have to be sent out
paging packets for 20 milliseconds at a
time whereas in le what we do is call
advertising and we do this and these
take down to two milliseconds in order
to establish a connection and classic
Bluetooth you can have maybe some ham
this takes on the order of maybe 100
milliseconds because you have to complex
negotiation scheme whereas in Le there's
a connection request which is over in 1
millisecond and data transfer and Ellie
is limited to taking three milliseconds
at the time so this is what we mean by
fast connections this is not fast as in
a lot of bandwidth transferred at a time
this means that you have your radio
turned on you do your transmission
quickly so you can quickly turn off your
radio ok finally maximizing sleep time
so in it for classic Bluetooth there's
four paging a does this scheme would it
uses a 16 or 32 channels to jump around
and listen for paging whereas in their
bluetooth low energy use three
advertising channels so basically this
means that whereas in classic blues if
you have your radio turned on for 20
milliseconds in low-energy Bluetooth you
can have it turned on for maybe just 625
or twelve hundred and 50 microseconds
which is much less I mean all these
things combined together means that the
idle current of your your device is
actually dominated by how much power
does it use when it's not doing anything
just its sleep current because most of
the time it will be sleeping and this is
actually ideally suited for central
applications because often sensors have
a i'm not saying always but often
sensors have a fairly low data
transmission frequency like every hour
your thermometer updates and says now
it's two degrees celsius outside so
basically we want to make sure that the
device can use very little power for the
remainder of of that our basically this
means that the the amount of current
that you're using when actually doing
your radio transmission is it doesn't
really matter in the picture picture
because most of the time you're not
going to be transmitting anything or
receiving so this is a
this is really one of the big point of
the same sources of saving power ok so
the fundamentals of bluetooth low energy
is that we have three modes of operation
we have what is called advertising and
scanning and then you can you can have
connections these boats of operation
used to be like partially mutually
exclusive but I think in the 4.1 SPECT
this was really these constraints we've
removed but I mean these constraints are
not really relevant for sensor
applications at least on the on the
center side because typically you will
not be doing all these things at the
same time so yeah it doesn't really
matter if you get a four point no device
it should still be fine for for doing
various sensory implementations so okay
so first of all I'm going to talk about
connections connections are
point-to-point on a connection there's a
master and a slave and this there's only
I mean we only have these two entities
on the connection whereas in classic
boot that you would have a mass for an
up to 26 / 07 basically the key concepts
that define this connection is we have
something called connection events and
we have something called the connection
interval essentially you should see the
connection bluetooth low energy as some
sort of recurring rendezvous with what I
call Kwazii fixed periodicity but I
guess in some sort of I mean some sense
all connections could be expressed to be
like this so okay so what is this
connections event connection events are
basically evenly spaced points in time
and these are the only opportunities for
communications between the two devices
involved on a on a connection the
connection interval defines the the time
between connection amends so basically
the higher sorry the lower connection
interval you have the more power you
will be using because the more
frequently you will be communicating
with your peer device and the connection
interval can be a from seven and a half
milliseconds up to four seconds and
there's a granularity of one point 25
milliseconds and once you've established
the connection you can actually
renegotiate this connection as well if
you want to change this you can also do
something called slave late and see
where the mastered sells the slave
device that you don't need to show up
every time you get to show up maybe only
nine times out of ten or sorry at 1
times out of 10 or whatever so this
allows the slave to sort of
opportunistically say I'm not going to
wake up now because I'll just wake up
for the following event because that way
I can save even more power or I can see
that for the past hour my temperature
has not been changing so I mean it's not
going to change in the next four seconds
anyway and it's also possible to sort of
specify some sort of temporal
displacement of connection events this
allows you to align your your
connections with other periodic
activities suppose you're at device you
only have one radio and you have maybe
two connections so this allows you to
make sure that the connections are not
supposed to be serviced at the same
point in time because then you'll have
to skip connecting to either device but
it also means that you can align your
connection such that you turn on your
radio you do the communication when you
have woken up to some other like in in
in five minutes my my thermometer kicks
in and gives me an interrupt with some
sort of temperature reading just make
sure that when that happens I'll be
doing my communication there as well
because otherwise you'll have to sleep
and wake up only to do radio community
communication so I mean this is this
basically allows you to make the
connection happen sort of at the point
in time which is suitable to you so on
basically this shows the the connection
we have a bunch of master slave sluts so
first the master transmit it transmits
and then there and during this point in
time the slaves has this receiver turned
on and then if there's a hundred and
five a 50 micro second gap and then the
master is listening and the slave is
transmitting so in each in these two
slots the device gets to you can hear
whether the other guys there for
instance if the master is doing
something else the slave can hear that
okay the master wasn't there so he can
just go back to sleep and wait for the
next connection a connection event
similarly if the master doesn't get an
acknowledgement after he's done his
transmission the slave is supposed to
acknowledge and sent back some data if
the master doesn't hear from the slave
there he knows that okay he's not around
so he can turn off his receiver early so
this is basically basically an le
connection and there's some sort of
fixed the
X milliseconds connection interval
between each of these connections and as
I said these are the only point in time
where these guys can actually
communicate so if after like a quarter
of X milliseconds the master realizes
that he has stated that he would really
like to send to the slave device well
it's just too bad because he can't do it
until in the next connection event so
these are when we do the data exchange
and you can exchange 31 bytes in the
four-point knows maybe this which is not
a lot of data but friends for
temperature readings or precious sensors
so heartbeat monitors or whatever this
is I mean more than enough data there's
an optional extension where you can send
I think up to 255 bites and there's also
a sort of a neat thing where if you have
if you have a connection of any you can
see that i have actually I've got 32
bytes that I would like to send to the
other guy instead of having to wait
maybe four seconds until you get to send
the final bite thus this point where you
can set like what is called the more
data bit in the header which means that
you tell the other guy that I have
actually got another I've got more data
for you and that requests him to after
after you have done your transmission
you tell them that you need to come back
and listen again this there's no
obligation for the the peer device to
come up again but this I mean often the
device will have the ability to to zone
so yeah so I mean this is a even though
we can set a fairly a high connexion
interval so that we sleep for a long
time and still get to transfer a lot of
data all be somewhat slowly when we get
to the connection point so this is I
mean this is reasonably flexible okay so
advertising basically advertising is
where you configure your device to to
broadcast a packet and then optionally
wait for a response so these
advertisement packets have three
properties and I know there's four items
on the list but today they can be
directed which means that they can have
a an address of the recipient on it so
for instance I can put in I would like
this I'm transmitting this packet and
it's supposed
be my sports watch that's picking this
up it can also be connectable which
means that someone can respond to this
and say I would like to connect to you
and then finally it can be scannable
where which which is an indication where
it says you can ask me if I have some
more data than what I've just sent out
finally in the 5 coin toss back you get
the fourth property where you can say
that it's anonymous so you can do a
transmission and it doesn't have a like
it doesn't say give give out your
address so basically the other guy
doesn't know who he might be connecting
to which the moments of this is or
whatever there's a optionally you can
put in some payload data as where you
get up to 31 bytes which for instance
could say that I'm a thermometer my name
is Bob or whatever so you could put in
stuff such the other devices know
whether it might be relevant to try to
connect to you okay so the two primary
connection sorry configuration options
for the advertising is you get to set up
at the interval at which you do this you
can also set up which of the three
advertising channels you would like to
use but normally you just use all of
them yeah but the so yeah the connection
is well basically means that if you if
you think what you're advertising is
super important you do a very low
connection interval which means you'll
be waking up frequently and you'll be
using a lot of power as yeah so
basically this is whatever what
advertising looks like so we got first
and advertising on channel 37 which is
the first appetizing channel then one on
and nothing happens after that then we
have an appetizing channel on sorry
we're advertising on channel 38 and
finding one on 39 and then basically
weird one with this once we've done
these three advertising advertising we
had we turn off the radio and maybe go
back to sleep unless we have something
else to do yeah I said earlier that you
could optionally wait for a response
this is because you can ok so the kinds
of responses you can get us you can get
what is called a scan request
and you only get this you're only
supposed to get this if you have set
that you're a scannable appetizer while
you can get a connection request so if
you get the scan request this basically
means that someone says I would like to
know more and then you optionally can
send back a scan response which can be
up to 31 bites and for instance this
could be that your advertising saying
I'm a thermometer and then there's a the
ideas that maybe you don't want to tell
everybody which the moment your is you
only do this extra transmission in case
someone comes comes and tells you i
would like to know more than you can
sort of save the save a bit of power by
now they're transmitting all of it every
time but you can also get a connection
request and if you get a connection
request you don't respond to it instead
it's you have a rendezvous in a six
connection when it's basically the
connection event the connection request
tells you when to which ever i mean
where to show up in the radio spectrum
at which point in time and then you
basically just say that the connection
is started at this point in time so this
is what this is what this is a figure is
sony so first we have an advertisement
and nobody responds to this then we have
another advertisement and somebody sends
a scan request and then we respond with
a scan of response one thing I forgot to
mention is after sending one of these
advertisement of requests we we wait 150
sorry we send an advertisement we after
sending one of these advertisements we
wait 150 micro seconds and then we turn
on our receiver if we want to listen to
a response and if we don't hear anything
in 150 micro seconds we can turn it off
almost immediately because nobody is
going to show up this it there's no I
mean the concept is that you show up 150
micro seconds after the advertisement
and that's your only chance if you come
show up at 152 microseconds it's too
late so basically this allows the guy
who is advertising to determine when
other people have the chance to talk to
you so if i'm doing an advertisement to
say that I'm here you can connect to me
i get to decide when I would like to
listen for connection requests and this
is the idea is that the guy who is
trying to establish if the connection is
for instance in the thermometer scenario
that's my big base station inside the
house so he gets to he gets to have his
radio turned on and listen and wait for
my advertisements and so this cost
simple but I can be sleeping for maybe
like four seconds Everett's on them and
and before I do the radio transmission
so I can I can the advertiser side gets
to decide sort of how much power would
he like to invest in having this
connection established yeah so this is
this is quite actually this is pretty
good to sign because you can you can be
very aggressive about turning off your
radio because this you don't have to
wait for maybe 10 milliseconds or just
one millisecond for the guy to show up
he has 150 min microseconds and that's
it okay so and anyway in this case we
have we do that précisément we rate
150 micro seconds we get the scan
request then we weighed 150 micro
seconds again and then we do the scan
response and then we're done he can't
after the scan response he's not able to
come and say then I would like to
connect he would he has to wait yes and
once we've done this so we go back to
the final advertising channel and then
we do the advertising there so this is
the so this is the scenario where we
connect so we do an advertising and and
nobody hears that we do the next
advertising and then somebody hears this
and waits the hundred and 50
microseconds and since the connection
connection requests and that's it at
this point we are connected so after
receiving the connection request and or
sending it we basically inform our hosts
tax upper layers that now we were
connected to this guy because the idea
is that normally this will this will
actually succeed so there's no point in
waiting and until we've heard from the
other guy to to actually get on with the
connection so apuleius might have to do
some sort of initialization or whatever
and they can do this okay so scanning
I'm just check the time scanning is
basically the opposite of advertising so
this is listening for advertisements and
you do this in order to do to obtain the
advertisement data and you can do this
in a passive or an active way I'll get
back to this or you can do this in order
to do the connection establishment so if
we do the connection we stab
this is called initiation a sorry
initiation so active versus passive
scanning is basically whether you decide
to respond to an advertisement with the
scan request so if you do active
scanning yes you you you sense can
request saying I would like to know more
and then you wait for a response so
obviously if you don't really care about
devices in detail you just do passive
scanning and then you leave it up to
upper layers to reconfigure to act
active scanning if it looks like it
might be starting to be relevant and the
idea is that you can also configure the
the scanning in test intensity simply by
you set up scanning into it into you
have two properties basically you have
the scan interval and the scan window so
that means the the scan interval is from
two and a half mil a millisecond up to a
ten-point 24 seconds so you can set up
your scanner saying every ten point 24
seconds I would like to scan for a
window of two-and-a-half millisecond or
you can say every two and a half
milliseconds I want to scan for
two-and-a-half milliseconds so you can
you basically get to decide how much
time would you like to spend scanning
and ultimately this means how much power
would I like to use this there's a
granularity in scanning of 625
microseconds so yes the idea as I said
at the time is to offload the the the
intensive part of sorry the offloading
the the aspect of connection
establishment or finding the Pierre
device to the device that actually wants
to find you because if you're if you're
one of these devices you don't really
know if there's anybody around that
would actually like to connect to you so
why should you be listening all the time
just to in case somebody might want to
find you so instead instead the design
is such that these guys decide when they
would like others to have a chance to
connect to them so they can decide how
much power to invest in establishing a
connection but still the other side can
also say I'm reasonably interested in
scanning so i'll be doing this half the
time or i'm not very interested in
scanning so i'll do this like ten
percent of the time or whatever
so okay so once we're we're scanning and
we found somebody what do we do well
basically if this is scanning a nut
connection establishment I mean we
inform Apuleius so in the upper liz you
get maybe some some data which was in
the advertisement packet which they can
inspect so the upper layer like the
stack this could be your cell phone you
can see that okay there's a thermometer
around and I should try to connect to it
but basically they can just react to the
presence oh my the bluetooth dongle
which is in my keychain has entered the
area I should probably try to connect it
or make it beep because it's been gone
and I need to find it and then when you
connect to it you can send it at command
so it'll turn on some bass or whatever
and also when you do the scanning you
get the chip in forms of the RSSI value
RSSI means received signal what is
received signal strength indication
basically this is some sort of it tells
you how how loudly you had the peer
device and this can be used to get like
any idea of the broth distance to the
other device and also if the if you're
scanning repeatedly and you keep seeing
the other device and the RSSI value
changes from maybe minus 52 minus 80 you
know okay we're probably moving away
from each other so it gives you an idea
of the relative movement between the you
and the peer device okay so when you do
initialize initiation you respond to the
advertisement with the connection
request and then immediately inform the
upper layers of the connection the
master selects the car the connection
parameters so basically the master can
say I want to connect air with this
connection interval and so basically the
master gets to choose how frequently to
to communicate both sides can change the
parameters afterwards in case the
parameters are not to their liking okay
so basically this was this was a I guess
the the design ideas behind blue to the
flow energy and how some of the low
power of things low-power aspect is
achieved so now I'll try to do a demo
with I had these two development kits
which are very unhandy cell phones and
then I I have these tokens that I've
turned on that I will see that I mean
you can go and search for these and
it'll show how frequently devices can be
found and yeah okay so for this i'm
using a proprietary tool called apt
Clive which is not related to picture
and so it's a command line command line
interface using which you can you can
omit the like the low level control
commands to set up your Bluetooth
control I think in a lot of cases you'll
have some sort of API which corresponds
exactly to these a these are these
commands this tool is generally not
available but I've the company that did
it may have more or less intentionally
leaked it so it might be possible to
pick it up somewhere okay okay so in in
this right now I have two screens so one
for each phone so I can try to read the
blue bluetooth address on one and read
it on the other one okay first i'll try
to set up a connection just using
regular bluetooth this sometimes takes
awhile and sometimes it's reasonably
fast but this is a this is a very simple
a connection so often often there's a
lot of negotiation on top of this for
anyway it's connait establishing the
connection and now it is yeah i think it
was connect now so this took like I
don't know maybe a second or so I'll
just disconnect this whoops I'll try to
set up an le connection instead and
hopefully I mean if I what I've said is
true this is a bit faster than the other
thing which ok so I'm connecting now ok
to connect it so this was much faster I
can try to send these connection try to
send some data across and so this also
came across quite quickly it says when
the connection comes up that on this
connection this this device is at the
slave device it has a connection
interval of 148 and I must admit I don't
recall but the unit is I think it might
be
625 micro second slots but I'm not sure
anyway so this is a reasonably
aggressive connection these communicated
fairly often I can try to disconnect it
again and then I can try to make this
it's so right what I've set up now is
I've told the one device to try to
connect to the other device again the
device that was just connected to but
the other device is not advertising so
but now I'll turn on the advertising on
the other device and we should see that
reasonably quickly the connection comes
up ok it's already up so basically my
finger is still touching the return key
so this is how fast connection
establishment is so this means if you're
a thermometer you can basically do
nothing go out and scan find the other
device and connect and then disconnect
again or the other device can do this so
I mean because the connections happen
this fast I mean it you don't really
need to establish a connection in
advance but you can't do it if this is
convenient I mean this basically you get
to choose this in your in your
application if also this a as i said in
classic bluetooth there's this scheme
where you and the master can change a
can trade places so you become the
master there's nothing like this in le
but if these guys wanted to to turn off
the connection sorry to do a role switch
it's much simpler to just disconnect and
let the other guys do an advertisement
and then you connect back to him because
it's just so fast so i have complicated
rules for for doing to enroll switches
ok so now just now I'll just demonstrate
scanning which is not for for connection
establishment so let me just I'll just
do this on this device so now i'm using
this is not one command this is a
command which sets up scanning with
fairly aggressive scanning parameters
and then we should be able to see that
some devices show up ok so these are
these tokens that show up i can stop the
scanning so just so we can see what it
is so basically what we can see this is
a what is called as an advertising
report basically this says that
I have this is an event from the
controller saying I've found someone
else I've found some device this is see
you here which means that this is a
advertise that we could have connected
to as a could have responded with the
connection request and established a
connection the address type is it's this
device has made this transmission using
its public address so it's the address
which is in a in the packet is actually
the one which is widened there in the in
the rom on the chip and finally there's
some days in here which says this is a
csr a security token and finally the
received signal strength is minus 80 TPM
which is not very good given that they
are lying here but these are development
kits which don't have trimmed radio so I
mean we should really expect real well I
mean like product like performance from
these so I'll just restart the scanning
and then i'll try to set up the the
advertiser on the other side so i do
this then we can see that the other guys
advertising pretty a pretty frequently
and then i can stop it again and then
immediately it stops so so if we look at
this suddenly we start seeing these
advertising reports show up much quicker
and much more frequently than the tokens
that's because the command imbues i've
used is to is intended for setting up
connections and this is not these
devices are not power constraint so if i
do this scanning again and i start
scanning over here and then i can try to
change the data just oops i just send
out a bunch of phase and this should
show up in the data
okay me okay that's some back here I
don't know with the tool anyway we can
see that the signal strength from the
chief phone devices is like minus 38 dbm
so this is reasonably good i mean yeah i
don't i don't know why but i think there
may be the radios on these tokens are
not very good I don't know so I think
this was this was all I wanted to
demonstrate so okay moving on in case
there's any singers out there so if you
want to Hardware this it seems like
there's a plethora of devices which have
controllers from Nordic semi these are
the NRF some numbers at chips they seem
to be everywhere see I seem to have some
sort of chip which people also use for
for making these like a arduino stuff
that I've seen the apart from red pair
red pair lap a dub a dub fruit has some
devices not there's like a twenty-dollar
bought from seat and you can get
ibeacons which are basically small
devices I mean actually an ibeacon is
something like this just with some apple
apple defined protocol in the data that
is transmitted so I mean you can get a
bunch of stuff most I think most cell
phones today will have le support so you
can I mean you might be able to pick up
the signals from these tokens just using
your cell phone yeah so that's basically
any questions yep
yes so basically a pairing is handled
using okay so okay so the questions is
about pairing in classic bluetooth
pairing is done using like link level
commands but in in in le this is done
using a higher level command so you
establish a connection and you send data
packets back and forth saying I would
like to to do a parent with you and then
I think when once you've done the
pairing you use some low-level commands
to set up your link saying now it's
encrypted start using these keys pairing
this on a level on its it's higher up
than what I normally do so the details
are a bit sketchy to me so okay there's
no more questions okay one question
okay so the question is what would I
mean software-wise what is a good
starting point i think the the Nordic
ports I haven't had a chance to use them
yet but I think they're actually quite
cool because basically what I think what
you do is they give you some library and
then you you build an application which
you linked with this library and then
you program it directly to onto their
controller so their control is like a
seems like a an IOT style controller
where you put an application on to the
actual controllers who don't you don't
need to have a lot of you don't need an
extra process of whatever to to do this
but I haven't had a chance to use them
myself ok so that's last question just
thanks for listening and feel free to
come and say hi if you want to some sort
of demo or whatever yeah that's all