my name is sodden I work for CSIS I'm
going to be talking a little bit about
the banking malware first I'd like to
explain what it actually is so the
banking malware is the kind of malware
which is designed to steal money from
the bank accounts of people it's not the
malware which is designed to attack
banks and steal money directly from them
but it's supposed to use the users and
kind of trick them into basically giving
away their money so there are many
factors in it I'll be talking about
different phases of the attack
historically speaking it's I think one
of the biggest problems in last a decade
or so Zeus was the first banking malware
that was widely popular and over the
years security products have kept
improving and so did the banking network
so right now we're at the stage where
the banking lover from 7-8 years ago is
much different from today but it still
works so security products and banking
malware both are kept evolving so I'll
try and go through what it looks like
right now and won't focus too much on
the history so my talk will be divided
into five sections so I'll be going
through the infection vectors the
process of infection cnc communication
between the bots and the C&C servers and
then how the money actually gets
transferred and what we as a users can
do to prevent ourselves from being the
victim of this attack a couple of words
about the CSIs
one of the biggest security companies in
Denmark and here are some facts about
CSIS I will not go too much into detail
with these either if you'd like to know
more about Jesus you could contact me
later or you can visit us as CSI SDK we
are also working with a number of
security agencies and some other
partners so here's a list of few of them
alright so how the banking malware works
the first step is how to infect people
so the goal of this step is to infect as
many people who have the bank accounts
as possible and the most common method
that is used for this is femi mills this
is one method that works the best and
the reason for that is that almost all
companies use outlook or some similar
mail servers they have their own mail
servers and they are not properly
configured so usually you're you're more
likely to be able to pass through the
defenses on people's own mail servers
then for example on bigger mail servers
like Gmail or Yahoo and so on that's why
we see most of the attacks go through
people's business email addresses right
here is an example of a Stan email this
is from 23rd of August so it's fairly
recent it was actually from the same day
when I was making this presentation and
we can see that there's a small small
file attached to it and then there is
some text and this is quite personalized
it's a bit funny because they wrote
their d or e crime and the email address
that we have is a crime and the name
that we registered there is a crime so
there would be you know using the name
from the email and then the sender email
is a legit looking fake email address
more most of the times and the text in
it is usually very brief which kind of
doesn't say much so it can
is the user to click on the attachment
and kind of see what's in it here's a
separate example of that it's from the
same spam run but we can see that the
name of the file is different from the
previous one so it's random characters
and then the subject of the email is
different the text is a bit different
and the person who is supposed to be
sending it is also different this makes
sure that all these campaigns don't get
flagged so if they would be using the
same file name it's more likely that you
know somebody would block it or the same
sender address and so on so they use
different parameters to kind of disguise
the email second thing is that they're
using botnets to send those emails so
they're not coming from the same IP
address and hence it's not easy to block
them based on an IP address and there
are millions of spam emails being sent
every day so what actually is in the
email so the idea for them is for the
user to click on the attachment so
inside the attachment we can see that
there is a JavaScript file so it's like
a dot JS file is not supposed to run in
the browser but the user is supposed to
double click it once the user double
clicks it then the malware starts to
work and if the javascript is just an
example from that day when I was looking
there's they've been very different kind
of files that we've seen that scr files
they are pretty much similar to da txt
files you could just basically change
the extension of eggs etude odyssey r &
goo still work wsf are windows script
files they're like VB script files and
then microsoft office files we've seen
quite a lot of them they're using macros
in them so basically you open a you know
some file which looks like a word file
it is actually a legit word file it
opens in Microsoft Word and once you
open it up it says that you know you
need to enable your micros to see the
document and if you enable them then the
code executes which actually is
malicious code and we have seen also
text files but they are decreasing
because there are more and more male
clients which actually just reject any
eggsy attachment or any direct the
attachment
is contained in a zip file as well so
that's a bit declining but that did not
stop the malware producers they just
moved down to different ones there are
some other infection vectors the most
common one is fam email in this talk
I'll be focusing mostly on the most
common stuff and won't go too much into
things which are there but they're not
the biggest threats so from the
infection vector point of view the
biggest threat to any person is spam
emails we at our company receive around
50 to 100 the serious malware emails
every day and that's probably the case
for many other companies as well so
we've seen a spam email email with a
malicious zip file there could also be
another option where there's actually a
link and that link opens up a zip file
from some server and that is also one
option that is used extensively these
days as well then there's another thing
called exploit kits the idea is a bit
older and in start there used to be
these exploit kits now it's a bit more
the principle is similar but the kid
part of it is reduced a bit so basically
you heck a legitimate website where the
with the users visit and you infected
with the some malicious code and they're
basically exploiting some vulnerability
in the browser or in the some plugins
and so on and if a user visits the
website it gets infected and this is
much more critical problem because the
user doesn't really see that he gets
infected in the spam email the user
actually has to click on the email and
so on so the people who are you know
aware of this kind of thing they're less
likely to do that but exploit kits are a
serious problem and anybody could be
could get infected but the good thing is
that they're not as common as the spam
emails and they're used mostly in a
little targeted attacks but not
necessarily we have seen a lot of
ransomware being spread through them as
well so that's also threat but not su
just spam emails all right so what's the
objective of the first stage of malware
the file that we've seen in this
previous section a sip file with
JavaScript or any executable what is
supposed to do so the first thing it
does is it downloads another binary from
the some some server and usually they
have a couple of hard coded links three
four we've also seen and it tries to
download the loader from one of those so
if the loader it manages to download it
you know fair enough if it can't find it
then it will try the second URL and
third URL and so on and sometimes the
file that it downloads is not a normal
executable it is rather some howdy it
needs some kind of decoding so that's
also the responsibility of this first
aid malware and because of this very
limited functionality it is usually very
small in size we're seeing 10k B's 15k
B's mostly and because of simple
functionality they can just create a new
one real fast so if all their CNC
servers from where they were serving
these Mel word they get blocked they
will just create a few new servers and
you know start sending new spam emails
with the new links so they try and keep
it simple all right the second part is
the infection process so in this stage
the loader or the first stage malware
when it it is already in the system it
wants to infect the system and there are
a few things that it wants to do their
main objective is that it should be
pretty hard to detect that the system is
actually infected once it's infected
secondly it should be able to
communicate with its CNC servers
and thirdly it should be able to survive
the reboot because most of these this
malware runs in memory so if you shut
the computer down it stops working so
they want to make sure that when when
when you restart the computer it's still
up right so this is an infection change
a chain of a malware called pandas use
it's fairly recent this one is from last
week or so so in there we can see that a
number of steps are taken so the first
one I'm not sure if it's visible from
behind i'll speak it speak so the first
line that you can see in this chain is
it's called panna XZ it's the malware
itself and I've named it paint at panda
at exit usually they're random file
names so what it does is that it
downloads another component from the
from the internet so the panda that XD
file in this case would be called the
loader so we have the first stage then
we had the loader and then the loader
downloads the payload so there's usually
three malware executables being used
these days there there can be more or
less but that's what's being used mostly
these days and this payload once it's
downloaded it's executed so this is a
precious property they don't want to
make it you know public so much and it
only downloads once everything up till
now works so and you can basically
create signatures and so on of that so
that's why they use some kind of caution
and download payload only on the
machines that they're very confident
that they can affect so once the payload
execute it also doesn't execute as a
process which normally all programs in
windows do it tries to inject itself
into some of the legitimate processes
and we can see in this case at inject
itself into svchost.exe processes which
are already running on the windows there
is actually a bunch of those so they are
very good because you
can actually create a few more and
nobody would notice that you know it's
something weird and the last step on
this one is a cmd.exe being run and this
is usually a batch script and if job is
to delete all the executables that are
on the system up till now so this kind
of thing that people notice when they
infect themselves with malware is after
they double click the malware it's you
know goes away and they don't see
anything happening so they're like you
know maybe it was some broken program
and you know nothing happens some of the
melvar actually also used the fact this
that do kind of fool people they just
show you know message that this program
is broken try again so this but the
malware is actually executed already now
let's talk a little bit about injection
why is this used so the first benefited
has that it has is that the malware
doesn't show up in the list of processes
so if you open up the task manager on
your computer you can see all the
processes that are being run and if
there is a weird one maybe somebody
would notice so but if you inject it and
one of those it processes it is very
difficult to detect it's also difficult
for most of the antivirus is to detect
because the most of them actually don't
detect stuff in the memory some of them
do but most don't the second thing is
that it's also very difficult to kill it
so to kill it you have to kill the
actual legit process and one of the most
used processes explorer.exe and
everything in the windows all the user
interaction stuff actually goes through
the explorer EXE so if you kill that the
you know computer stops working so most
of the times it's it's very safe bet to
inject into explore that eggsy another
problem that it has is that if you try
and debug explore that eggsy you try to
pause it and see what the code is doing
you actually your computer you can't use
it you know as much as you would be able
to
use in case of some other process so it
makes it more difficult for users to
disinfect themselves it is difficult for
security researchers so that's what's
being used mostly we've also used seen
for example internet explorer EXE chrome
and so on and after the injection the
loader deletes the the first stage
malware the loader itself and also the
payload from the hard disk and they copy
the payload to temp folder usually or
some other temporary location where from
where they can restart it in case of a
computer restart now the second thing or
the next thing is the persistence
persistence is basically to be able to
run the malware once your computer
restarts so yeah the thing we see mostly
is the temp folder is where the binary
sits and run keys what points to it we
can see an example in here this is a
real example of never quest we can see
this the binary is stored in C users
username appdata local and then there
there's a random file folder name and
random filing so this also makes the
detection a bit harder as the folder
name is random file name is random it
will be random on all computer so you
can't make a signature of the file name
it because it's different on all the
machines and this will get executed upon
the computer restart we've seen more
trickier methods of persistence because
the persistence is the single-most how
to say the bottleneck place where you
can actually see if you're infected or
not because all the malware has to rerun
when the computer restarts so they try
and use some kind of persistence method
and they're not many there are not many
options so run keys are generally
generally just two there's a local
machine run key and there's a local user
run key and you can just see them in two
minutes and you'll be able to find a
malware so too
stop that we have seen for example
schedule tasks they do the same thing
you can make a scheduled task which is a
part of windows by default and that
scheduled task will restart the whatever
you wanted whatever time you can set a
time or you can set reboot and so on so
some malware are using that and then
there is malware which is which can be
run as a service so we have services in
in windows and there are background
processes that keep running all the time
and if you can register your malware as
a service this is very difficult to for
people to detect because nobody actually
looks at services most of the cases and
then there's one very interesting one
which is used by three decks it was used
in the past now they've switched to a
different mechanism what they did was
they hoped the shutdown function of the
computer so when you are infected with
grid X and you try and shut down or
restart the malware would get a trigger
for that and they would drop the malware
from the memory under the hardest and
create a run key pointing to that and
this happened just before the shutdown
so you can't really see it after it
actually happens and when the computer
shuts down boots up so there's already a
run key there is a file on the system it
would open that file using the run key
and execute the malware as soon as the
malware starts executing it deletes
again the run key and the file so while
the malware is running there is nothing
on the hard disk at all there is no
registry key pointing to the malware
there's no malware itself on the system
this was very good but this had a big
drawback that if you actually hard reset
your computer a computer gets
disinfected because it can't restart
itself so I guess they were having
problems with that so they switch to
schedule tests alright the next thing
I'm going to talk about is CNC
communication so all the malware banking
malware has to communicate with the CNC
very critical because in today's world
things are changing real fast security
companies are really really good and
they will be blocking stuff very fast so
in order to stay ahead of them they need
to be able to communicate with the
people that they've infected and use
that leverage to give the new
instructions to update their binary to
update whatever information they have in
there and this is also one of the very
important factors of the malware itself
so it requires some some talk art so in
the previous two sections we've seen how
the people get the malware in itself and
how the infection gets completed once
the malware is running as a as a thread
in some kind of legit windows process
and there's a wafer to persist it's
pretty solid so after that most of them
actually try to check in with their C&C
server and the idea here is that they
want to tell the C&C server that I have
managed to infect one of the guys and
they upload some information and that
information actually usually goes into a
database which criminals can see so they
have these beautiful charts where they
can see that they've infected this many
people in this part this part of the
world and this much of them are using
Windows XP and this much are using this
and there are also external ip's that
that are sent to them and then there's
also a thing called bought ID which is
send there's a bad idea is basically
unique identifier identifying about it
is usually generated based on certain
features of the system so for example
the name of the computer is one factor
the installation date is one factor and
so on so there they will basically just
hash it or use some kind of algorithm to
generate a unique ID on that and that is
actually used in communication quite up
and in some cases we've also seen the
list of apps
so this is a this has to actually to
actually how to say purposes the first
one is that it it helps them to find the
security researchers because if i have a
virtual machine and i'm running
melbourne it i'm gonna have some tools
that help me analyze the melvar so I for
example have our shower i'll have some
kind of a debugger i'll have fiddler or
process explorer and stuff like that so
if they see this this stuff they can
identify that this is give you
researchers that they can you know do
the opposite research to see what
security researchers are using these
days and then they can use that improve
their malware to block what they're
doing and so on the other functionality
of it is that sometimes they manage to
to get a jackpot by infecting some of
the very critical systems for example
bank's internal systems or some other
systems that are using some special apps
for example bank's internal software or
some libraries with some stuff like that
so in that case they have this option to
do further investigation on that a
manual level this is a real message
check-in message from droid x this is
the decrypted form it is actually
encrypted in several layers I'll get to
that shortly and in this we can see that
the first thing is unique which is
actually the pod ID so this is one hash
that they generated the first part is
actually the name of the computer and
then there's a hash based on
installation date and so on the second
is botnet they have several botnets so
they want to keep them separated so the
client actually tells the CNC bitch but
Madame I want to talk to so in this case
it's 220 and then there a version and
system this is some internal thing for
for the malware which they're using to
keep track of what rich version people
are using so they can update them with
the latest version and they have these
backward compatibility and stuff so the
older version of malware has lower
functionalities as they keep adding
things to keep improving so they want to
keep a track of this and then there's a
type called bot there's another
type in this case which is node I will
not go into details on that because that
will be a bit long and then there's the
IP which is usually the external IP at
the system it's not the internal IP 192
168 kind but it is the external one and
they are using certain services to get
that for example there are certain
websites that you can visit and they
will show you the your external IP so
they use one of those and then they send
external IP so these are very good to
identify serious breaches for example if
you manage to infect you know some
security agency of some country they
usually have unique IPS registered to
them so this is used for that also they
can plot nice graphs based on that to
see which part of the world they are
hitting and you know so on and then
there's this public key which is used
for communication by the C&C server to
the bot so I'll shortly explain it a bit
more but yeah this is actually one of
the keys generated by the bot and it is
sent to the C&C server so whatever CNC
server sends to the bot later will be
encrypted with this public key so only
this part can decrypt it anybody in the
middle is not able to do that because of
the way asymmetric cryptography works
all right the second thing in here is
the configuration so configuration is
basically a set of settings or a list of
stuff that the malware can do and these
configurations are the parameters to
those functionality so what banking
malware can do for example let's say it
can attack certain banks and steal money
from them so what are those banks that's
what the configuration will say so they
will they can update this configuration
with more Bank names for example how
they attack those banks there they have
this thing called HTTP injects I'll also
explain that a bit in the shortly so
they will be sending new stp injects and
the bank keeps updating their websites a
certain inject stopped working after a
while and then they will have more
injects or updated versions of them so
CNT servers there's usually a list of
them in all the the malware payloads so
the the list actually is dynamic it's
not a static one and the reason for that
is that security people are working on
this on the on these malware so they
identified these C&C servers they talked
to the people who are running them and
the companies who are hosting them so
they keep taking them down so they need
to have a steady flow of new C&C servers
in order to keep their about networking
so even if one of the C&C servers is
working it should be able to send the
new ones to the bots and the button it
keeps a life that is why it's extremely
hard to take down these banking malware
botnets because you need to take down
all CNC servers at the same time and
they are quite a lot of them usually 34
via is pretty normal and they're in
diverse geographical locations where
different police works different
countries have different laws and so on
sometimes not very easy to do that and
this is what they're exploiting and
that's why it's almost impossible to
take down a really good botnet unless
you can somehow hack it in a way that
you can attack it from inside but by
shutting down C&C servers it's extremely
difficult and there are other
configurations depending on the malware
and what is functionality is so here's a
real configuration from 3x it's a small
snippet of it it's not all of it it's
usually 400 500 lines long and pretty
big so in this case it's in the nice
format of XML and pretty easy to read in
the first section in the first line
there is a hash which uniquely
identifies this convict so the bot can
you know ask for an updated one and if
it gets an updated one how do we know
how does it know it's updated or not
based on this hash so if it has
different hash they usually can use that
all right the next is the URL so this is
actually a URL which shows which bank to
attack and this is actually a regular
expression which particularly targets
certain bank in this case it's
one bank and it has a two URLs so it is
using a regular expression to cover both
them and there's another section down
there it's called form grabber so what
this part of the malware does is
actually is able to grab the form so if
if you fill up a form for example use
your username and password in equally
click Submit this is this part of the
malware is able to get whatever you
entered in that form it could be more
than username password or and so on in
YouTube in case in this case it would
most probably be the username password
and then they have your username
password and this is quite useful for
number of purposes they are using that
in their huge ecosystem so this is one
example they are getting all sorts of
credentials that they can and then they
are using those for further infections
and other purposes and here is an HTTP
inject so how does that work this is
actually the main feature of banking
malware and the reason why it's so
successful so if you have a browser and
you visit a website what actually
happens you make a request request goes
to some server and server responds with
something and then whatever
functionality takes place in the server
stays in the server in the end but the
user gets is some kind of HTML code so
if you can change that code in the
browser the user can see whatever you
want it to see and it has it doesn't
have anything to do with the server so
for example let me give an example let's
say you visit your bank site and it says
that you have five hundred dollars in
your account and if I am in the browser
and I can change the HTML code I can
change that 500 do for example 5,000 and
you will see that you have 5,000 but it
is actually not true and this is the
main feature that banking malware has
and they are using that to steal
people's money I will get to how do they
we do that in a few minutes so in this
particular case what it does is that it
finds a pattern which is C data and then
form something and then it replaces that
pattern with the one that we see below
and it's basically a JavaScript that
injects into the page so this JavaScript
gets injected into the browser off the
victim and it is actually not on the CNC
server it doesn't affect the other
people visiting their website is just on
the browser of that particular person
and then we have some additional modules
this is actually used for various
purposes and since it's a police you
know working system they can just
download whatever they want so for
example VNC is a very common thing it's
something like teamviewer Orion see we
probably or no or remote desktop so you
can basically control people's computer
using that so once somebody is infected
you can log into their machine as a
criminal and do whatever you want in
there there's the key logging modules
which will log people's keys there's
process members scanning very good for
point of sale devices so you can
basically scan their memory and get
everybody's credit card with done some
shopping did that day and it's also used
for for identification of critical
systems for example if you manage to
infect a bank some you know some
employee of the bank you can do more
research on that today and so on there
are many more modules and depending on
the malware they're used if the
necessary encryption is a pretty
interesting and very important for
malware to work correctly because all
the stuff that we saw the check-in and
so on they can be easily identified on
the network and if you have a network
device that scans your users you can
easily see who is impacted by you know
looking for those keywords so they all
use
scription pretty much all of them and
it's usually strong encryption however
we have seen a lot of them using a
custom encryption and why they do that
it's because people have to right tools
manually to break them for the standard
encryption there are already tools
available and it's easier to break it
compared to the custom one so custom one
you have to debug the code and go
through all four I don't know a few days
or a few weeks and then you can
basically get what they're doing but it
takes time and slows to researchers down
which is very good for them because they
need time and time is money because they
have more time to transfer money
together before the security people
catch up so there are hybrid and hybrid
and layered encryption which is that you
encrypt something and then the output
you encrypt it further than the output
encrypted further and so on this is an
example of duty X encryption scheme
which is one of the most popular or
banking malware so the conflict that we
we've seen a little while ago is one of
the most critical things that they want
to hide so when a server sends a
conflict file to the to the bot it
actually encrypts it with it with some X
or encryption scheme this is fairly
trivial you have a few bites and then
you XOR all the bites with those bites
and it's quite easy to correct even if
you don't know the key and then but they
don't stop there so the output of that
they encrypt it with the rc4 which is a
symmetric key cryptography and the key
for our c4 they encrypt it with the
public key that we saw while ago in the
check-in message so that makes it
extremely solid already and then they
have a third step on top of it they
encapsulate all that in standard TLS
which is standard encryption scheme that
everybody uses so TLS is easy to break
because there are already men the middle
tools that can do that if you control
one of the endpoints you can easily
break that it's not possible if you
don't control any of the endpoints but
yeah once you do that then you have to
break all this further encryption and
you know the most difficult thing is to
know what they are actually using and
then once you know then you can go ahead
with that but it takes time for people
to figure out what exactly they're doing
and that's the time delaying tactic that
that is used without all right so now
we're gonna move on to how the banking
malware actually works in terms of
stealing money the money transfers I'll
quickly go through the three different
things so the first one is stealing
credentials part we have seen already
form grabber feature so the mail will
inject itself into the browser and then
it can see the stuff that's being sent
in the browser for example in the forums
or through the post requests which are
what is used on on the backend for
sending data from the browser to the C&C
server so they can hook that and you
know extract that which is in the
unencrypted form and there are many
banks in the world who actually don't
have the two-factor authentication so if
you actually have those credentials you
can just transfer money and that's
what's used by some banking malware it
was used by de risa a while ago then
they switch to a different method which
we'll get to shortly and the second
method which is a bit more complicated
or at least requires a bit more effort
is redirect method yeah I should mention
here is that once the credentials are
stolen they don't usually login to the
bank from their own machine because that
would flag their IP and also the banks
have this thing that they monitor their
users and have their ips logged in so if
you log in from a different IP suddenly
like for example i live in denmark and I
background here if my account suddenly
gets logged in from Cuba most likely the
bank will block it so in order to stop
these kind of problems they use the VNC
module that we talked about a little
while ago and login to the victims
machine and use the victims browser to
login to their
bank account and transfer money so this
way it pretty hard for bank who actually
know if it was a criminal or the guy
just insulted the redirect method in
this case what the banking malware does
is they create a whole replica of the
bank site and this replica is hosted on
one of their own servers the reason it
works pretty much similar to the fishing
but the difference is that the user do
not see the URL that where it is
actually hosted since they're injected
they have injected into browser they can
just change that so you see the actual
URL of the bank the the fact that
there's this green lock in the corner
it's still there so the user has no idea
that is actually on a fake website and
there you can enter credentials they
both course get the credentials because
it's their own site they can also do the
men in the middle by using those
credentials to log into the real bank
and then if the bank asks or something
like two factor auth they can just
create a new page in there and ask that
the user to give it to that so they're
kind of collaborating with the user by
tricking them into giving them all the
information they need and since they
controlled all the website they can just
do it pretty fast this method is used by
droid x it's also used by breweries in
the past and yeah it's responsible for a
lot of losses the next thing is
automated transfer system this is a one
thing which is pretty fascinating
because it's it works fully Adam
automatically and since although
criminals have these call centers and so
on they have quite a lot of step but if
you know somebody can use this it's of
course better for them because it's
fully automatic so the way it works is
that as we have seen the you know inject
things a while ago the users when the
user logs into the bank side there's
already code injected into into that and
the that code knows that the user is
actually on the for example transfer
pager or it's just past the login page
and then they can use for example since
it's a code running inside the browser
they can do stuff there so for example
what they can do is that they can
contact their C&C server from within the
browser that okay this guy's already
logged in you should send me an account
number from to which I can transfer the
money from here so once they have the
account number they could just ask the
user by for the two factor auth code by
tricking them so one thing that we've
seen in an EverQuest which is also
another Bank malware is that they say
that you have received some money so in
order to you know kind of get that money
in your account you need to enter your
two factor auth code so when the user
enters that two factor auth code that
ought goat is actually used to transfer
money out of his account rather than
giving him money and they can of course
show it that he actually received money
rather than lost because they control
the browser and by the time the user
triggered out it's already too late and
yeah this is used by never crossed for
example and been used with by other
malware as well in the past all right
since we've talked about most of the
things so far how it actually works from
start to end so what we can do actually
to protect ourselves there are a number
of tips the most important one is that
once you receive emails be very vigilant
about them do not click on links in the
emails or open attachments unless you're
expecting them this is I think the most
straightforward rule and will help quite
a lot because most of the attacks we see
comes through spam emails this is by far
the most useful way to not get infected
second thing you use is to show file
extensions because we've seen different
malware that have a different extension
for example a malware which is eggs
email work but it actually shows the ICN
of a PDF file so the user doesn't know
that if it's a PDF or not because by
default the extensions that are
extensions that are hidden so he would
think it's a PDF file and he's more
likely to click it so
have the extensions shown so you could
see what it actually is and another
thing that I mentioned is the startup is
one of the easiest way is to find
malware so check your startup from time
to time to make sure that there is no
there is no weird program in there that
you did not install and anything that
you did not install you just remove from
time to time and network traffic
monitoring is also a good thing it's a
little hard to do on your own computer
because of all the encryption and so on
for example with wireshark you get the
traffic which is already encrypted if it
is if it it is encrypted also you can
use for example fiddler but for that you
need to make these certificates install
these root certificates which is in
itself a security problem but you can
use that at a company network level so
there you can monitor the traffic and
have a contract with one of those CNC
server providers so you have the latest
C&C servers and if anybody's can be
getting them you should be able to
figure them out and you can also check
if any of the your legit vintage windows
processes are injected into and there
are some tools to to to look into that
you can just run the tool and it will
show you all the processes and the one
which are injected into they will be
flagged as red so that's also pretty
good and another very good thing that is
very helpful is to use the mobile
banking apps to check your bank account
balance regularly there most of the
banks provide one day
kind of alerts where you get a daily
alert of how much money you have and you
know since you know you how much you
spend and so on and how much more money
you're expecting you can you know using
this method figure out the problem very
fast and if you can figure it out you
can talk to the bank's most of the banks
actually ensure your money so if you
lost the money because of some malware
and so on they will reimburse it but for
them to reimburse it you need to tell
them as fast as possible and you need to
provide them some kind of documentation
so on that this was of course malicious
attack and that's all that I have in
terms of what I'm going to say so
question sign thank you need different
size
you mean the name ID yeah this is a
serious bottleneck and we've seen a lot
of problems with it in Denmark because
it's just one thing and you can use it
for all the all the things so these
athletes that they're using you can see
the URL which from where that applet is
actually loaded you can see that in the
browser by right clicking their applet
and clicking inspect so you can see
where it's actually communicating it and
there's a one legit place where there's
actually this applet is coming from and
then all the fake ones are of course
vague so this can be used but of course
for for an average user this is a
problem and there's a lot of MIT fishing
going on the other thing that is a
useful is to kind of yeah you since I
see a lot of phishing sites it's pretty
easy to identify them because of their
there's some problem with that but I
understand that it's probably not that
easy for an average user but for us I
think we can just check the URL where
the applet is being loaded from and that
should be good enough
you