so we're going to be wrapping up today
with a couple of miter talks then get to
our candy for those of you in the room
uh so our final attack update is going
to be coming to you from jared andrechek
our software development lead
jared
yeah probably need this
and some training apparently
on
the different buttons let's just test
this out for a second
and all right
um hello everyone i'm jared undercheck
as meant as adam mentioned the software
development lead for the
mitre attack uh you know software team
um i do want to point out that there is
not a typo on my twitter uh
handle there i'm on genre check on
pretty much everything from github to
the mitre attack slack
for whatever reason i dropped the e when
i created twitter and if you could
handle
one extra tweet a year you could follow
me so
all right
um
so
uh so i'm a a devops engineer and just a
little bit about me um i've been at
mitre for about 12 years now and i've
had the pleasure of um being able to
uh work on a lot of great with a lot of
great people a lot of great teams i have
some background in android forensics
where i
had
created some tools to assist with the
automated detection of potentially
unwanted applications
um and it was uh during that time that i
fell in love with automating everything
i fell in love with python i fell in
love with uh creating code that was not
just
code that could work on my computer but
my colleague's computer and then as we
transitioned that project to other
people both internal and external to
that team
specifically packaging up
tools for other people to use
anyway so i've been with the uh attack
team for
uh several uh about six months now and
uh i get to manage um both what you see
here um uh on these bullet points from
uh things from the website to attack
navigator uh the workbench we're gonna
be going over some updates on on these
things here uh in in my discussion uh
today
so let's go ahead and uh dive in now for
the website actually for a few of these
things you've already
been briefed by you know previous
members of the team so one of the
specific updates is that the ics uh the
industrial industrial control systems
attack matrix
currently sits on a media wiki instance
um out there and it is no longer going
to be a separate uh um uh tooling but
will be uh incorporated uh into
attack.miter.org uh a little hard to see
there but it's just um you know the
styling of the of the website um uh
today so really looking forward to being
able to
uh for those of you in that space to be
able to uh you know pivot around the
website and just you know be uh in one
space instead of having to bounce around
to multiple areas
um
after that um
you can also see uh once again from
lex's talk uh yesterday
we're adding the detection
specific pages to the website so that
you'd be able to
same idea as ics it's just in one space
uh be able to um
go and you know for any given object
whether it's a technique a group
whatever
be able to
see um
see more
information on the website um that way
and that's coming in april for both of
the
ics and
um
uh
the the thing i just said yes the
detections that's what it was uh all
right as opposed to campaigns here uh
which uh is is coming soon uh still just
trying to breeze to this uh as matt
malone already mentioned there's gonna
be a lot of community engagement as to
specifically how we collect the data on
our team but then also on the website we
don't have you know final you know
screenshots yet of of what it will look
like but that's in the october release
v12
of uh of attack so really looking
forward to that one um
let's see moving on to the next slide
here so this one is my absolute favorite
and i think it might be some of your
favorites as well um
search
um
so i
yeah just just wait for it like you know
i have an animation no wait maybe i do
maybe i don't you'll find out later um
so
the the the website it's uh it's it's
what we know and love to be able to
access all the information uh about
attack uh however uh while we can search
there's you know
let's go if there's issues with that and
it's a high priority this year i don't
have a date on that but we are
prioritizing it on my team so that it
will be able to um
uh
we'll just go with be more usable uh
soon this year
all right um moving on from the website
uh some other updates that are more
recent so the attack navigator um a few
people had mentioned attack navigator
and we've seen screenshots and and from
the layers
layer files there uh just uh a one quick
snapshot um uh when you when you're
working with the attack navigator
there's a bunch of tools um
one of one of which you can export has
json uh to work with or export as excel
um for those of you you're continuing to
to do
the work that you need in excel we also
have svg export and if you can see the
font sizes are just kind of wonky when
you use that and if you haven't used svg
export in the last few months because
you remember this uh in january uh
thanks to lily wong she uh
created a pull request on github uh to
at least minimally make it look a little
better right we so while we this is not
the end state we still want to work on
attack navigator this year
to be able to
export in various formats not just svg
but also with the express plan to
not require third-party browser
extensions to make good screenshots of
the attack matrix um
so that's a that's a goal of ours this
year but this svg export uh was uh
already released in january of this year
um another addition uh from uh since in
the last several months uh is the
ability to add custom links and just to
walk through what that means uh if you
were to open up the navigator and uh you
know click on a technique such as audio
capture you can click on this button
right here to add your own custom links
and just to you know zoom in a little
bit uh there it's fairly simple all
right you just you know give it what
it's just a url what do you want to call
it where does it go that's it and you
can add several of those and then when
you export those uh navigator layers to
share with your colleagues um however
you want to do that or yourself or later
of course then you can come back and see
that there is uh it's you know there's a
blue underline under audio capture if
you uh uh can't see that but if you
right-click on it then it shows up at
the bottom of the the context menu so a
little update that has been requested
multiple times and then you can just
kind of see oh this is
extra context that someone added to this
layer so you could click that's just the
url that's all it is so you can make use
of that
um
uh so that's navigator um actually
before i uh dive into the workbench
stuff i was talking to several of you um
just you know between yesterday and
today about some other anticipated uh
updates for navigator so um what i
really want to say about that is if you
have ideas for navigator and this is
going to be a theme for any of the
things that i mentioned here today if
you if you're able to go on github and
find the repository uh we have issue
trackers for all of our projects and um
if you want to go straight to poll
requests that would be awesome but if
you even just want to have discussion
right feel free to open issues as
feature requests or bugs um so that we
can uh have a conversation about how to
improve um uh or
or fix things that are fix things that
are actually incorrect or broken um
moving on to the workbench so i wanted
to uh give a shout out to uh ivan
ninachuk uh from his talk yesterday uh
as uh he's the first person i've met in
real life uh who's actually using
workbench i know some several uh people
do but he's uh that was
a a really great plug so if for those of
you not familiar with what attack attack
workbench is um
it's a web application that is open
source that's on github um and you can
uh stand up your own instance of it and
then you can import collections of um
of attack uh in sticks format so you
don't have to understand stixx format it
will do it for you um and then uh it's
actually the tool that we are using uh
starting to use internally ourselves uh
it's it's been around for about a year
publicly i think now um but it's how we
edit the the content of um
of
of attack um and
uh
there's oh i'm not really gonna go
through this whole road map here right
now it's just we have constant
improvements that we need for ourselves
and that other people will also be able
to make use of
and one of the things i mentioned
yesterday is that it has a rest api that
is just um in my opinion fairly
easier to work with than
um
manually working with stakes we'll go
with that um
and then speaking of sticks you can't
talk about sticks without talking about
taxi of course right
standardization joke no okay um
so taxi uh so we uh
some of you may know not all of you know
we uh host a publicly available uh taxi
2.0 server at cti taxi.minor.org
no need to pull that up in a browser
because it is not interesting in the
browser um however it it is already
available it's public the documentation
for it is available on github and i'm
not going to say it's buried but it is
in that file right there um and uh
so it is available
six 2.0 uh only
and uh the reason i kind of wanted to uh
bring that up is because uh
on the heel of the version 11 release in
april um and coming in may uh we plan on
standing up on a public 2.1 server
for all intents and purposes maybe that
doesn't mean anything to you
specifically however it does have
a couple of things that i feel are worth
mentioning one is the specific
integration with workbench if you have a
workbench instance set up if not that's
fine don't have to worry about that it
does have a rest api compliant a rest
api that is open api compliant with
dynamic documentation so while going to
the website today
might not get you a whole lot of
information uh in the in the future
there would be dynamic documentation
that is available for you to make use of
uh and it will be supporting sticks 2.0
and 2.1 for um
all the attack content
um uh
zooming through here so we've got
another thing that
once again some of you know some of you
don't we have a python library that you
can pip install uh kind of maybe hard to
read on that but they've installed miter
attack python and
um
just uh three top level three top level
things that it does for you is it works
with sticks once again so you don't have
to um and it's sort of a grab bag
of functionality it's just a tool that
we use ourselves that we feel might be
useful for others so it can convert
sticks to excel or collections for use
with the workbench um
and you know a few other things really
the the point i want to make on this
here though is for the future of mitre
attack python i want to work with the
community to find out what it is that
you want in there one of the things that
we feel might be useful is to add
convenience methods to connect to the
public taxi server
things of that nature there's also
another github repository we're going to
try to merge in with
but yeah that's another resource that
you have available to you
and really lastly to wrap this up
there's a lot of stuff that's open
source with the miter attack team that i
get to that i and my team get to manage
and it's in various places today and we
want to
uh
i'll ultimately go for a centralized
landing page so that would be uh
available
you know at attack.miner.org
for you to kind of get your updates
about that right there
um in conclusion i just said all these
things um and i'm jared
so
[Applause]
thank you and most importantly on behalf
of the entire community
whether it's the pit modules attacks in
excel navigator thank you and you and
your team for abstracting us from sticks
truly of course every day the rest of
our teacher you know really benefits
from that thank you absolutely thank you
[Applause]
you