hey i'm catself back with the attack on
couch
and we have ivan and andy here with us
today so we kind of are wrapping up the
day it's gonna be the last three talks
um so we're not gonna keep you too long
because i know you guys are like
literally these conversations and then
there right like it's like security
conference that's when the real work's
done right of course actually it's funny
that you say that because we were
talking i was talking with some other
speakers and we were all talking about
how we come here and we do these
presentations but the real work is like
these side conversations where we're
just connecting with each other exactly
right like oh you have this dude like i
am dealing with that same issue and like
you're an expert in this space
so um during your talk which i love the
orchestra like that was a fantastic
analogy i really want to hear even more
about that but you also mentioned a task
force so what tell us more about that
task force yes um
basically
like i said when i got to simplify last
april i saw a need to start exploring
how to really utilize attack in soar
and that's where me and andy met because
he did a webinar on attack and i was
like wait a minute someone did a webinar
i need to meet him and become his best
friend
and then i gathered a small group of
individuals and and we went to
leadership and they said yeah go for it
you know you can you can use work time
and and you know be able to do it as a
main project
and it you know they no promises on
product timelines or anything but they
did say that you know go for it you know
see see how far you can take it
and so
um i i put together a team of ses ps
engineers developers and we were able to
start you know working out what would be
some integrations with attack that would
really
use automation to a level where it
hasn't been and that's where we got the
idea of you know secondary
investigations um using the data
components
hopefully one day participating in the
attack sightings
and using more the ctid tools i'm just
blown away by how many tools there are
like workbench i just learned about the
attack flow where you're going to have
change of attacks so that definitely
plays into um you know what andy was
talking about about you know looking at
the groupings of them and so we're
really excited you know to be working
with all that and the fact that there's
all these wonderful apis for us to play
with andy did you want to say anything
about your experience
yeah i mean the only thing to add really
is um i feel like we're always uh 10
steps behind these guys because when we
started to put mitre into the into the
kind of like the front end the
experience think oh i really need
something to do oh yeah that's right
might have kind of already got that done
oh i need to build it in like the
navigator oh no hang on they've
literally built navigator okay we need a
way to predict oh no they've already
done kind of sighting so i feel like
these guys are so many steps ahead that
we you know when we're trying to deploy
and implement it in the in solution to
make it look pretty you're like yeah i
think we're always one step behind these
guys just too good
that's so kind and it does not feel like
reality at all but it's so kind because
i can tell you on this end like we'll
talk to so many subject matter experts
and it's like
oh we've got so much work to do there's
so much not done yet you know like oh
we've got to capture this and like matt
was talking about the campaigns and
we're like
we need your help like how do we even
scope these things right like how do we
do this in a very intentional way so i
so love hearing you mention other
projects that are minor and i love
hearing that you think that they're so
helpful because that's like okay
like we all work really hard yeah it's
totally useful good that makes me happy
yeah it's just speaking real real fast
on the future i i know i've been
you know these wonderful side
conversations that we talk about one
thing i've been doing is going around
with everyone i can talk to and be like
what do you see as the next thing yeah
and and where are we gonna you know
where are we gonna go with it so that's
been really exciting that we've got this
in person again because it's a lot
easier to have those conversations in
person
and i you know for anybody who's never
come to an attack con come to 4.0
because it rocks it's literally the
happiest place on earth
and so yeah come to attack con that's
all i can say
i love it you are so wonderful thank you
so much thank you
i really alright so i will say this last
conversation like last question so like
what drove this whole orc like i think
you all hit to it in your presentation
like what drove this whole orchestration
like that visual that actually came from
a teaching um tool a presentation i made
um and that presentation was called the
so what of attack
because we we got that question a lot
from different people that didn't have
you know the sec ops and cti backgrounds
you know what what is attack um i had
developers tell me oh i know how to
program everything with it i know the
json sticks but i don't know what it
does
and so i needed a simple way of telling
them how it affected my life in security
what it gives me the value
and for me it gave me a way to visualize
it and for me it's music
um you know like i said i literally my
phishing
data is the pianos the edrs the violins
and then i start hearing the drums which
is the network data
and that's it gives me
that power to understand what's going on
and and once i can do that then we can
start sorting it out we can start
figuring out what's important what's not
and that's that's a power that attack
gives us it's a language you know i
brought up the rosetta stone you know
it's a language that connects so many
different levels of data and viewpoints
and biases it's just mind-blowing what
it does and the only way i can describe
it is music
i love the fact that you bring such a
diverse background and like other
passions into it i'm a history major i
love that because like that's it takes
all of it right like not everyone
understands it in the same exact way so
and the fact that you both can
collaborate together and you have
different aspects and strengths to bring
to the tables really i always say he
makes me look good i mean
you guys make each other look good yeah
so thank you guys so much for taking the
time to be with us like all of the work
that went into the presentation so we
really really appreciate you guys being
here thank you
yes 100 very much though
so um we're wrapping up the day and now
we have just one of my favorite people
um
so
this needs no introduction can i just
say i love your presentation style well
thank you it's all based on utah
was just watching and inspired by this
broadcast all day i was like how do i
bring that cat energy
it's an homage to you we actually redid
our slides 13 minutes beforehand but you
know
i believe it
i am the coolest cat i know
all right so how is it at the end of the
day like you've been able to see all
these different presentations and in
person conference you said this is the
first one you've been back at first of
all yeah i did cyber work on earlier and
then this is it so
only the best conferences get me out of
my house
obviously so what has been your favorite
talk out of the day
i
love history and i love threat
intelligence so i do think the keynote
for me was really something i enjoyed
quite a bit because i like being able to
pull lessons from the past
and pull to the future because not a lot
has actually changed so i think celia's
you know really resonated me especially
because it really set up well for our
talk which was kind of going through the
the tactical version of the strategic
problems she brought up so i liked it as
a one-two punch of just like she brought
up a lot of aspects of synthesizing
information and getting it through where
we were providing a tool to actually do
that for analysts who are trying to do
these tasks so i like that part quite a
bit and olaf's talk um
always a great person with great
information that i learned a lot from
yeah his talk is both of those talks
have been mentioned a couple of times
today and i agree and it's been
beautiful parallels throughout like the
storytelling has been interwoven through
multiple presentations
and then everything from what you all
have been releasing and then how
different presentations have stacked
have just been really beautiful no it's
a credit to the and i know i've said
this before but there's an art of doing
a conference where there's a i can't
believe i'm using this word but synergy
all the way through and that actually
happened today which was fun
no um so we're wrapping up the day um
everyone's kind of like had well try to
give everyone an opportunity to um kind
of share something like we have these
amazing viewers that have been on
all day streaming um is there anything
that you kind of want to tell them
whether like
but yet i'll give you a targeted
question so you actually have something
to answer how about that um what are one
of the obstacles that you see a lot of
people getting into this field
and how have you seen them overcome it
with grace
silence um the biggest thing i see
people getting into is this cyber
security or attack because we can go
either way here
you're that dealership no no no no see i
threw it back
uno reverse that
cyber security
for getting into cyber security the
single biggest thing that i've seen been
accelerated for people's careers is
networking um i think a lot of people
get into cyber security because they
like the tech and tech is a huge part of
it you have to have the chops but the
reality is the way people's careers
advance is through other people and
unless you have god-like abilities in
front of the keyboard which are very few
you have to be able to have the
personalities you have to be understand
who's there get new opportunities and
the way you do that is through exposure
or well places like this uh sands where
we met actually sans uh hunting summit
other places like that are great ways to
get more exposure to different people
and talk that opens up a lot of new
opportunities and i think that's the
biggest thing i see people have a
problem with who are new to cyber or
getting into this career field is they
feel pigeon holed they don't see how
many different areas there are from
extremely technical reverse malware
engineering to
very non-technical but just as valid and
just as useful on more of a
intelligent side or writing and i think
there's a lot of possibilities on either
side that people aren't aware of until
they see that and have representation
shown to them
i think that is a really really valid
point um i've heard like the terms like
oh well it's clicks and you know like
you're people and i actually called out
um i was talking to
one of the who's now a vp of cyber
security at target and i was like what
is it about these clicks like apparently
you have to be one of someone's people
and she was like okay let me break this
down for you um
when you say your people what you're
actually saying about you people yeah
like what do you mean by you people um
she was like
really what it is is as you go
throughout your career you find people
that have just proven themselves time
and time again that whether it's work
that they want to do or they don't want
to do they'll do and they'll do it well
absolutely and like that's a discipline
that i feel like we often glance over
right on like the being the god of the
keyboard
there's an aspect of there i think we
had a wonderful conversation with my
team last night and we were discussing
the problems of cyber and threats
which is predicated by there's a
wonderful gentleman scott roberts who
wonderful threat intel man and
he has this concept kind going over it's
extremely difficult for threat
intelligence to become larger because
the skill sets are so difficult and one
of my very unpopular opinions is threat
intel is dead and i say that because i
don't believe it's possible to scale up
the skills required as the industry is
today you're gonna have very large csps
with very mature threat intel shops
you're gonna have consumers of threat
data and you're gonna have creators of
threat intelligence and i think that is
going to be where we start having this
big divide so the question was well how
do people learn these things like you
can't go to school for this you can't go
to college for this like you can get a
cs degree with a security focus and
great you know how to code secure c but
what are you doing how does that help
you with anything we just talked about
today yeah and the big thing we came
through is the reality is this was an
apprenticeship program you like that is
how we've designed this and going back
to the history lessons that selena
talked about earlier today you find
yourself someone who's teaching like
okay you've proven yourself let me show
and there's been lots of great research
like anthropologists have embedded
themselves in socks and actually study
the way socks train each other and kind
of go through this and we're still not
getting great of getting out of that um
but i think there's still this concept i
you know you could argue as a debutant
ball where i'm sponsoring you and we're
i'm gonna walk you around and say
this is cat i vouch for her and they're
like oh okay i'll spend time with this
person because you said so and we're not
going to get much further until that
expands but i also haven't found a great
way around it
that's true honestly that's actually the
way i wound up getting a lot of exposure
was like like david bianco was amazing
and like he did a co-presentation with
me and that's right
you know and like a hundred percent it's
like allies in the field that like take
that risk to be able to like
i will stand by you and like help you
along this path because i know it's hard
to see something i'm passionate about
there's allies there's advocates and
there's mentorship and i think people
think the bar for mentorship is
extremely high but advocating is as
simple as making sure the door is open
for everyone to walk through and anyone
can do that oh my god i love that yes
ah okay that is so well said that i
don't even know if anything can actually
come after that so um
and i just
dropped mike
it's not gonna work i actually won't
keep talking to you about this but we
have the last speakers um that we need
to bring on and uh this is our service
for the audience so um but seriously
thank you so much for your presentation
the work that goes into it wonderful i
loved it so thanks everyone for watching
it was very fun you should have come it
was much better in person
but we're super glad that you were
online and that you're with us because
you all the best meme means you get the
attack flag
so
um definitely like do your research on
memes there was a great one from south
park earlier that i personally loved
because it definitely described getting
wider and not taller um so definitely
take a look at that one um be sure to
heart or retweet the ones that you guys
really like uh or just comment on them
so that way we can track which ones you
like so cause that's that's just as
important um so our last speakers of the
day that we're going to be able to
interview with um
ah i love i love things changing up last
minute it's awesome um
so i'm stephan chanette from attack iq
nice to meet you guys thank you it was a
pleasure to meet you i love the fact
that you all talked about jupiter
notebooks like thank you because that is
how i we did so when i was on target's
threat hunting team that was actually
something that we moved towards because
just like you said like it was so much
easier to use a jupiter notebook to kind
of do these live presentations and we
would do these hunts and when we were
doing this hunt kind of read out we
would actually have this jupiter
notebook that had all the data that we
had like painfully cleaned at this point
right and then we could just quickly
move through that data so i really
appreciated your walk through that so
thank you so much yeah we i mean i think
jose and i have used jupiter notebooks
so much and then we've helped you know
our customers and our users use jupyter
notebooks and at first it's just to sift
through the data and you kind of look
through it interacting with kind of a
workbook
but
as there got to be more and more data
and the audience was the executive or
someone on the tactical team it's like
this is a great opportunity to use it
for presentations and jupiter notebooks
allows for markdown language and so you
can really start to visualize and paint
a great picture get that emotional
reaction drive some some kind of you
know actionability but with the jupiter
notebook is that a powerpoint or like an
excel file you know something just more
interactive
so during your presentation you made
this comment that i was like huh i don't
know like i'm curious how you guys have
faced this like um i know for a lot of
the leadership meetings
normally there was always like we need
to know how to answer questions during
meetings right like if you don't have an
answer like if there's an anomaly and i
cannot speak to it that is not a good
thing right um but you all talked about
using like live data
like how would you address that with a
jupiter notebook if you're using live
data
i mean that's a good it's a good
question right because
well you know in i think in our
experience um
you know we've probably with a certain
customer had dozens of jupiter notebooks
maybe for a certain customer not
hundreds
um we've dealt with hundreds of jupiter
notebooks but within those notebooks
that customer has gone back to them on a
daily or weekly basis so hopefully
it's not so you know
outrageously different than what they
expect
um but what what most of our our users
and our customers are using the jupiter
notebooks for is to kind of
they're trying to drive the conversation
you know yes they're being prepared to
answer a question but instead of getting
in that like reactionary response kind
of driven
like mode they want to come to the table
saying hey here's the agenda we want to
set so here's the set of jupiter
notebooks
that we want to drive a certain
emotional response so it's strategic we
want get support on these resources if
it's tactical it might be like here are
clearly detection logic rules we need in
this particular area and so they're
trying to set the agenda with
jupiter notebook driving it from a data
kind of viewpoint versus uh just telling
them presenting through a powerpoint let
me show you the data let me drive the
agenda to make some changes
so there was a lot of really positive
feedback on the scenario
um and uh and how you guys went over it
um and then one question from slack and
actually
let's see i have it written down from
who
b all right so i don't know if these are
like abbreviated names i'm assuming it
is it's like b mara sky
um
but they wanted to know if there was
like well there was a couple of things
right one was are there any github
examples that you guys have released so
that way you know it's much easier to
walk through these things when you're
like okay that's the code
yeah that's something that we talked
about we had quite a few people
kind of ask the same question and i
think we'll probably put something
together and you know from our
perspective put together some base data
set so to your point all the data we've
pulled all the data we've manipulated if
you can get in that point i think you
can get some of the output that we've
put together
with the folks that we work with we've
done quite a bit so i'll be happy and i
think that's part of the whole point too
about the notebooks is you can easily
share them right and it's not only just
plugging it in and getting the output
but for analysts see you know the
iterations that stefan did with some of
our customers see how that logic ends up
going right where do we start with the
raw data and how do we drive it to
provide that message that we want to set
the stage for uh people can learn from
that perspective too and that's the
beauty of it is that code is there you
know they're not abstracted and they can
modify it when their executive says what
about this they can just change it as
well so that's the beauty of it
no that's fantastic all right so then
another question from slack was
um for those that want to drive this
scenario
um on their own right like where
couldn't they look for that data right
like that's actually there was a lot of
questions on that on how do they find
that data
well i'll take this one so in terms of
the scenario
i mean i guess are we referring to
setting the agenda are we talking about
you know part of getting that data is
first uh understanding you know what is
the scenario that you want to drive from
a you know attack
adversary emulation perspective so
there's a lot of free tools obviously
red team atomic red team caldera there's
a lot of things that you can run and
then you know jose and i come from the
commercial side where you know for the
last almost nine years we've been
building an attack iq an adversary
emulation platform so lots of choices
out there in terms of how you want to
generate that data yeah right one of the
things that we
um and i should say jose has taken part
in is the center for threatened form
defense and the attack flows and that
new release and so attack iq has pivoted
a lot towards that as has many many
vendors in the space to look at
emulating uh threat actors not just
atomically
you know because there's various
security controls that won't catch it if
just one technique exactly it's a
combination of techniques exactly
exactly and so in the presentation we
gave today with jupiter notebooks we
focused much more on attack flows how do
you emulate that attack behavior
um through an attack flow and attack
graph and attack chain so that they are
uh
judged the adversary behaviors judged
after a sequence of number of things
have happened
and so once you have that data
important part of any emulation is that
you have what has the attacker done and
then what has the defender been able to
detect or prevent once you have that
data now jupyter notebooks come into
place how do you present it
so for the viewers and for the people
that ask the questions
essentially get your simulation set up
first yes and get the data from that
simulation and then play the jupyter
notebooks with the scenario yeah i think
and then my feedback to that that person
as well would be you already have some
data start with that right at the end of
the day you know where you have gaps you
know where you have concerns you know
where you need more support from your
management so whether it's vulnerability
scans whether it's a pen test from last
month right all that's information you
have pull that in start using that and
then at the end of the day right start
working towards using uh you know atomic
red team and collecting that information
collecting the information at the level
that we had in our presentation right
but you have something that you can
start with today and build on top of
that is going to be my suggestion too
from that perspective i love that so
what kind of like you guys did actually
mention this little bit of your
presentation but like what were some
driving factors for you all to kind of
like come up with this idea for the
jupiter notebook and then realize like
this is actually really helpful for a
lot of people we should present on this
yeah i i think for us we we started
using jupiter notebooks internally at
the company okay i put something
together and i just threw it over the
fence and said go look at what i did and
how i got there and you know slowly but
surely the developers were using this as
a way of you know quickly iterating and
putting something together because it's
not just reporting you have full python
capability so anything that you can
orchestrate or manage you can do it
through these notebooks and i think we
saw that kind of pick up like fire
internally with our customers or
internally as at our company right and
our developers then we started showing
it to our customers they really liked
that and you know i think the call to
action of our talk that we wanted is
start using what you're already using
today right in this different way that
you maybe not have thought about and um
yeah i think that that was a driver for
us just seeing that kind of uh get
picked up uh just creating this
collaboration that i didn't see
otherwise was one of the main reasons
why i you know i wanted to talk about
this today
yeah i mean
i mean very similarly um i think you
know once you start doing something
internally and it picks up speed and
then you show others outside how to do
it we thought you know mitre attack con
was the perfect place to present it this
very collaborative community right and
jupiter notebooks being
this ability to you know build out a
notebook uh share it amongst the
community going here's how we're
actually presenting the data in real
time um within one security team another
security team might pick it up but as
you said before these jupyter notebooks
aren't in a get repository somewhere so
we'd love to you know start maybe
collaborating with someone who wants to
start that effort um certainly helping
to show what we've done but i think this
is a great effort that could get started
no i love that i think that's that's
beautiful like just the whole idea of
like
that innovation that you have internally
and then like celebrating that and then
like recognizing it and then testing it
out right in these safe environments so
you can fail fast and then
seeing it work and then very
intentionally bringing it to other
collaborative environments like that's
fantastic so we really really appreciate
all of the work that went into it and
just the
i guess you could say like the pause
where you guys could like take that
moment to reflect back and then like
realize the impact of something and then
intentionally bring it forward to the
rest of us so thank you so much we
really really appreciate you being here
yeah thank you so yeah thanks so um that
wraps up our day thank you guys so much
for paying attention and just being with
us today online i know it's tough we
make jokes like you should be in here in
person
but the reality is you can't right like
like not everyone can attend the
conference
but that doesn't mean that you don't get
to be part of it like you are a part of
it here like you guys are the only ones
in the meme contest um only ones with
the flag um and you're also the only
ones on this live stream so the the
people that were in person didn't get
that so hopefully you all got to enjoy
being able to see the human side of all
of our presenters um incredible people
that definitely put a lot of time and
passion into all of these presentations
so thank you guys so much for being with
us today we look forward to kicking it
off again tomorrow and i will definitely
be reviewing these memes so bring your
game