- [Announcer] Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome back to the
stage, Adam Pennington.
(audience applauding)
- Welcome back from break.
Hopefully, if you're home or here,
you got a chance to see Cat on the couch
or even got a snack, drink,
ready to get going again.
So now into our regular program.
So first talk, coming
from our call for papers.
We're gonna have Jason Wood
and Justin Swisher from CrowdStrike.
So I'm a sucker for talks
with real threat data.
I'm always excited to hear about things
that adversaries have
really done in the wild,
but this proposal caught
our eye specifically,
combining ATT&CK analysis of
some of this real threat data
with a platform, we really don't see
that much in reporting Lenox.
So please help me welcome to
the stage, Jason and Justin.
(audience applauding)
- Thanks Adam.
You guys hear me okay?
Audio check.
Oh, awesome.
Awesome.
Cool.
So yeah, Jason, I think you're the first
bio slide.
- Yep.
So hi everybody, my name's Jason Wood.
I'm an intrusion researcher
on the OverWatch team at CrowdStrike.
OverWatch is our Threat Hunting team.
And so yeah, we look at a
lot of intrusions every week,
hands on, somebody's gone
interactive on systems.
So this is just kind of
a snapshot into that.
What we're gonna be talking about here.
I know it's just Justin
and I up here talking,
but there is a whole team
on our Outreach team that
does this analysis
and really helped build what
we're talking about here today.
So yeah, with that, Justin.
- Yeah.
So Justin Swisher,
have a little over a decade of experience.
I started as a civilian Intel
Analyst at the air force,
looking at foreign command
and control networks,
and then foreign malware
against airspace systems,
bounced around to a bunch
of different vendors
doing network security, monitoring,
threat Intel consulting.
And then the last few years I've spent
most of my time on
Endpoint Threat Hunting,
which I really enjoy and
obviously we're gonna be
talking a lot about today.
So I wanna dive right in with
why do we track intrusions?
I don't know if you've read the book,
"Start With Why" by Simon
Sinek, love that book.
And I always approach
everything with a why.
Why am I doing this?
What's the purpose behind it?
And so when we look at intrusion tracking,
we understand why do
we go about doing this?
Like we gotta put all this effort into it,
tagging everything with MITRE.
And the first thing is we
wanna understand successes,
ours and our adversaries.
What are the techniques that they're using
that they're successful with?
How are they operating and
getting past our defenses?
What are they doing that's successful
and they're repeating over and over again?
And then when we think
about our successes,
what are we doing in terms
of triggers and hunting leads
that is catching this adversary?
What are the techniques
that they're leveraging
that we're like, yes, we've
got that or eyes on that.
Where our successes?
So we wanna continue to
focus on those areas,
but then we wanna look
at the failures as well.
What did the adversary
do that didn't work?
Did they type a command wrong?
Did they bring in a tool
for the wrong architecture?
We see that oftentimes like,
what are they doing that's failing?
And also when they conduct
something like Mimikatz,
is it being prevented?
That's a failure on there
and it did not work.
But our failures as well.
We research these intrusions where,
okay, maybe we catch it here.
This is a hunting lead that fired.
What else happened where we could have
triggered a little earlier?
Maybe prevention was not enabled.
That's a failure on our end.
Like the technology could have
stopped this, but it didn't.
And then that leads into gap analysis.
What are our coverage gaps?
Where could visibility be
improved as we look at the matrix,
the techniques that we're identifying,
where are those slightly less red spots
if you're thinking about
the ATT&CK navigator.
Why aren't we catching things there?
Could we improve visibility,
better detection,
better collection, and then
improve our hunting patterns.
So we take all of that
to identify and document
and keep track of that.
And then this is hands
on keyboard activity.
Our adversaries are
developing and growing.
Over time, and Jason will talk
to this a little bit later.
We wanna understand what
techniques continue to show up,
quarter after quarter, year
over year that are successful
and then where are they improving?
Where are they growing?
Where are they developing?
And can we identify those
clusters of activity?
So, we really dig into hands
on keyboard intrusions only.
That's what we focus on at OverWatch
and in the Outreach team.
And so we are mapping
individual unique events
within an intrusion to the ATT&CK matrix
and it's really fun to be
able to kind of dig down in
and look at a single line
is an actual process roll up
or in a network connect.
And we're actually looking
at hundreds to, what,
thousands of lines, and
depending on the intrusion,
the scope of the intrusion,
and we're gonna map everything
that we can to MITRE ATT&CK.
So we have some examples here,
initial access valid accounts.
How many people continue
to see valid accounts
leveraged against them every single day.
I see heads nodding, right?
Externally accessible RDP,
just constantly happening.
So that's gonna be our
initial access valid account.
And then we'll see things
like registry modifications.
So event triggered execution,
accessibility features.
What's nice about this
line is that it actually
applies to two different techniques.
And sometimes we have to be
very careful when we're mapping.
Are we hitting both techniques?
Its, (sighs)
we catch each other's
mistakes all the time.
- Spend a lot of time.
It's not unusual when we're
bringing in new people
to the Outreach team, 'cause
we're doing this analysis,
inevitably, you have these questions.
Well, I've got this
command line doing this.
How does this map,
where does this map to the framework?
And so we're going through
that and I'm telling people
all the time, oh, don't worry,
I'll be asking the same questions.
- Yeah.
- Because
adversaries are doing different things
and you're just like, where does this fit?
- Yeah.
Yeah, we have great discussions along.
Where does this fit exactly?
What could be here, maybe it's over here,
it spurred some discussion around,
should we submit something to MITRE
for maybe a new technique.
But just some examples there
to kinda go through and
that's our job every single
day, we really enjoy it.
But last year, 2021,
we observed 960 hands
on keyboard intrusions.
- [Jason] Hopefully.
- Almost a thousand hands
on keyboard intrusions
across our customer set.
That's a lot, even for the
size team that we have,
that is a lot.
And so we have to store,
memorialize and use this data.
And that's not easy.
Not just the individual command lines,
not just the MITRE ATT&CK,
but the metadata around it.
What is the vertical?
Is it eCrime?
Is it targeted nation state?
What is our attribution
confidence of e-Crime
or targeted nation state?
And so we've looked at
a few different tools.
Obviously you have wonderful spreadsheets.
We all love spreadsheets.
The MITRE ATT&CK navigator
is great for visualizing it.
We've settled on myths
for the last couple years.
So the malware information
sharing platform, ha ha I knew I'd get it.
That's where we memorialize
a lot of our data
and it is not perfect,
but it's worked well.
We're actually right now in the process
of building our own tool
with our research and development team,
because we need some
more specific use cases.
But this is really important
because what it allows us to do is
look at trends over time, right?
What verticals are targeted?
What adversaries are
targeting those verticals?
What are the techniques that you're using
in those verticals,
by those adversaries and
where they're successful?
It allows us to ask a lot
of questions of the data
to present a picture to the
other hunters, to our customers,
what we're seeing, how we're stopping it,
how we're growing and
developing our own team.
And so just a quick example
of kind of how we do this.
So we dig...
Each intrusion event is
tracked as one MISP event
and we will tag that with the metadata.
So we have our, what we
call our intent tag, right?
eCrime or targeted when it's known.
The analyst, the customer vertical,
operating system that was used,
our attribution confidence.
We track the metric of
breakout time, right?
So if we know the initial access
and we don't use things
like valid accounts because
they could have gotten
those from other means.
But when we see that initial access
from the time that they get on
a box to the time they move,
we track that as breakout time.
So that's tagged in there as well.
We've modified the galaxies a little bit.
So we've added specific
galaxies for our use case here.
So we've got region,
sub region if we see it,
malware and tools, those are lots of tag,
Cobalt Strike, maybe Cats,
the ones that we all love
and see all the time.
The adversary as well.
So if we have a named adversary
associated to that activity,
we have that as a galaxy
and then the ATT&CK pattern.
So MISP is really great, it
allows us to tag those things.
There's some challenges
around MISP with how they
update, keep, store and track
some of that information.
We've worked around it as best we can
but what it does is it allows
us to query all of that
and build out pictures and trends.
And so that's where I'm
gonna let Jason kind of
dive into more specifics around.
- [Jason] Alrighty.
- Some of the stuff that we see.
- So this intrusion was one...
I was hunting around, I'm
like, what are some...
We see a number of Linux intrusions,
what would be interesting
to even talk about?
'Cause I'm sure you've
all looked at intrusions
where you're like, okay,
this was more the same.
We really don't care that much about this.
So I found this one I thought
was interesting enough to bring up.
Now we don't have any idea
who this threat actor is.
There's no attribution.
There was no telling whether
this was eCrime or whatnot
from the information we had,
maybe that changes over the
future but at this point
they compromised a web
application running on Linux.
And so they get going and start initiating
their actions on objective.
And so I'm watching this,
as I'm going through
command line by command line
to see what happened,
you see this command
start really very close.
There's a little bit of reconnaissance,
but then they start off
with this fine command.
They're looking for done
properties files on the system.
So, okay, well that makes sense.
I'm looking through and
tagging things back to,
mapping it back to MITRE ATT&CK.
Well, then we've got file
and directory discovery.
We're crawling through the file system,
see what we have that's interesting.
This sounds an awful lot like what I did
when I was penetration testing and I
popped a system where I wanted to see,
all right, what do I have?
I don't even know what's going on here.
So they find all the
property files on this system
and this is just one example,
looking at the Tomcats properties file.
They're looking at data
from the local system.
They actually spent about
30 minutes digging through
different property files
after property file,
after property and just
looking at this list.
And finally, I think, and
this is just me guessing
because I'm putting it kind
of my bias on this or whatever
from doing this,
they got really annoyed
with whatever they had
for access to the system.
They're like, man, we have
got to expand access to this.
So let's pull down some tools
and in this case they pull down what,
or tried to pull down what
is likely reverse proxy.
And, looks like some kind of
compromised WordPress site
where they have this stored up there,
they go to pull it down, you
see a pause on the timing,
nothing happens.
Oh yeah, don't check for the certificate.
We got an error.
It didn't work.
(laughs)
So they get it down.
Great.
Oh, we've got Ingres Tool Transfer.
So now we've got this down
onto the system and I'm,
dutifully mapping everything
out here trying to figure out,
how am I gonna talk about this
later in report or anything
that this comes up later.
And so then now let's execute this.
So far, and we're gonna execute our proxy.
It didn't work.
What happened?
Oh yeah, I gotta add execute
permissions to the file.
Oh, gun it.
Beat it when that happens.
And we've all seen probably
this in intrusions.
You see somebody hop on a windows box,
they run LS or they run
Cat and you're like,
yeah, dude, I feel your pain.
(all laugh)
Right?
But so then they,
this is basically
modifying the file system
permissions on the system.
So that they can then
try and run their tooling
and then they turn around
and try and execute it again.
We're back to executing
the proxy application.
Now they got a little
frustrated at this point
because as it turned out,
Falcon of course was running on this host.
That's how we see the data in OverWatch
as Falcon collects all this.
It prevented it.
And so they tried this a few
times and they went for a while
and then they finally went, all right,
this isn't working, now what?
Let's go back with something simple.
We'll just use bash.
We'll use dev TCP.
We'll connect out to
this host on port 99 99
and see what happens here.
We've got nonstandard port being used.
We've got the capabilities of the command
and scripting interpreter
being used as well as
the Linux file system
and capability of the OS.
Again, they got prevented and
they tried this for
probably about 20 minutes
and you're watching them
work their way through this.
Finally, I don't know
where this file came from.
And one of the interesting things
about being a threat hunter
is you don't always see all of the data.
There's one thing that
was told to me early on
made me feel a lot better
with Threat Hunting,
an intrusion's never one event.
If you miss one detection,
you didn't miss an entire intrusion.
A lot of stuff is happening.
So, okay.
We didn't have some visibility
to when this file got here,
but shell.elf.
Well, I'm gonna make some
guesses about what this is doing.
I don't know for certain it's
running on somebody's system,
it's not like I can pull it down and,
or I don't have any access
to the end environment
to pull down files,
but it looks like we're trying to execute
some kind of shell to, some
kind of custom compiled tool.
They're using this underneath,
again, the command scripting interpreter
bash the uniq shell and
then this got prevented.
Again, they tried a
number of different times
to get this to go.
And then they finally just
gave up and deleted the file.
And quasi cleaned up after themself.
The amusing thing is they
just deleted the one file,
the INI file for fast reverse
proxy, the binary there,
yeah, that stayed on the system.
The funny part is that this intrusion,
they stopped for the day.
The next day they come back
and they spent several hours again,
trying to get something to run on this.
Now the thing that I thought
was funny about this,
and I can recognize myself in this,
you get so fixated on
what you're trying to do,
that you don't stop and think, well,
why am I trying to get...
I mean, they already had
access to the system,
what are some of the things
they could have done on this?
I don't know.
They got tunnel vision though on,
I gotta get a reverse shell running
and then they finally
gave up and went away.
We're notifying the customer
throughout all of this
and getting them to respond.
So hopefully they got them
contained and cleared out.
But this is our process
there as we're going to see
command line by command line,
what the adversary's doing,
now, we're endpoint centric, right?
Selena already talked a
little bit earlier about
things that they see at Proofpoint.
We have the things that
we see in our data set
and so our graphs or the
things that we're seeing
are gonna vary a little bit.
That's fine.
But this is our process for
going through and seeing,
okay, what is this adversary doing?
And then we come back later,
the hunters, they're trying
to move at speed here.
And so they've got to notify the customer
as fast as they can whereas for us,
we can spend a little bit
more time doing the analysis.
All of this is going, being captured,
put into MISP and memorializing that there
so that we can go back and
do reports on it later.
Now this is, I don't expect
anybody to read this.
(laughs)
Really just pay attention
to some of the shading here.
This is Q1 2021.
And just kind of what was popular.
There you're seeing ballot
accounts are being used
in the command and scripting
interpreter uniq shell,
things moved around a little
bit in Q1 of 2022 instead.
So, it's kind of interesting
to just sit here and just kind of
see some of the movement.
Why did this happen?
What was going on?
What are some of the differences?
We can dive into that
a little bit further.
And in this case,
we've got Q1 2021 on the
right on the left, excuse me.
And then on the right, we have 2022,
I focused just on a few items here.
We actually initially broke
out all the differences out
and it was probably too much.
But some interesting
things to me here was,
at the top we have valid accounts is being
one of the most
predominant defense evasion
areas of the heat map.
We go to 2022 defense
that's actually swapped.
More cleanup is occurring.
The adversaries are doing
a little bit more cleanup.
Why is that?
Is that interesting?
And that's where we
start doing our analysis
when we're doing our reports,
start to look at what's happening.
Is there a trend that
occurred here along the way?
What has gone on that makes
this interesting to us.
And what do we think that it
tells us about the adversary?
One of the things I like
to say is that every
time an adversary runs a command,
they tell us something about themselves,
about what they're trying to do,
what their goals are and stuff like that.
Credential access, you
see unsecured credentials
being the primarily area where we saw
them looking for a password,
being stored somewhere,
something like bash history
or files on the system.
Swapped a little bit in 2022,
we see a little bit
more access going after
Etsy shadow and Etsy password.
Systems are being compromised with,
they maybe running with
privileges that they shouldn't,
or they're elevating their privileges.
So we can see a little
bit of movement here.
And that allows us to just kind of
use MITRE ATT&CK to see how things
are changing over the time.
If I'm trying to dig
individual command lines,
this can be very
overwhelming, very quickly.
Some trends that I noticed as I was just
kind of looking at 2022,
the most recent data.
What are we seeing adversaries do?
And this is all Linux centric.
What are we seeing here?
What I've seen is as I've
reviewed the data was,
hey, we have a little
bit more exploitation
of some kind of web application.
We're reasonably certain as
a public facing application
for the initial access.
Of course the uniq shell
is gonna be involved
for any of this stuff.
As they're executing
commands underneath it,
you see 'em trying to establish
persistence with web shells.
Now that is pretty consistent
across windows or Linux,
but that is definitely
one you'll see happen.
Defensive agent, they're going out
and they're trying to clear
their command histories,
they'll delete files that they drop.
Usually rather haphazardly,
occasionally you run
into a very conscientious
adversary that you
watch go back and delete
everything that they
dropped on the system.
But that's actually a
little bit more rare.
- And I'd say one thing
that I find interesting,
at least when I look at the data is
that clearing command
history, clearing logs
happens more on,
that I've noticed on Linux
than it does on windows.
- Yeah.
- I don't know what it is about.
Just maybe they're more
comfortable with the Linux logging
or, but I've noticed a lot
times that defensive agent,
those clearing system logs
comes much more on Linux
than it does on a window system.
- Yep.
Yeah.
And yeah, you do see
those variations between
what an actor is comfortable
with on one environment
versus another environment
and you just, I don't know,
I find it to be kind of
fascinating to see how this goes.
Again, our credential access
I've already commented,
access for Etsy shadow and Etsy password
has bumped up a little bit,
but you still see him
looking through bash history.
How many shell scripts
have you seen in your time
working that required you
to type the password into
command line as you want.
Because
we just cobbled this thing
together so there we go.
And we log all of this.
Lateral movement.
If it's on Linux,
typically you're gonna see
this happening via SSH.
If they can steal credentials,
they can do some password cracking.
Sometimes you see 'em get
a hold of private keys.
They try and use that to move laterally
to other hosts via SSH, a
lot of collection and every,
very consistently you're seeing tools
being dropped into the hosts.
Why are we doing this?
What are the benefits to all of this work?
I mean, we're putting it all into MISP,
we have some different tools
wrapped around this to try and
extract data out of it
to use, what's the point?
One thing is it allows
us to go back and see
if something interesting has happened.
Something interesting
has changed over time.
You're in the thick of it.
Just kind of doing your day to day work
and wherever that may be,
for us, it's intrusion analysis
for the threat hunters,
it's detecting whatever
is currently happening
and you don't necessarily
know what's changed over time
'cause you're just focused
right here and right now,
maybe last week or last month,
but that's about the end of it.
So using that, go back to that heat map
that allows me to see
something is changed here.
Why did it change?
Did something new pop out of this?
So you can dig into that.
One thing that I really like
with ATT&CK is it gives us
a very consistent way to
talk about what we're seeing
to different audiences.
The technology folks have
pretty well gotten into this,
though they'll always want
to see the command lines
and whatnot as much as we can,
but if I'm talking to a CSO,
they don't care that
much about that detail.
They just wanna know,
kind of the high level,
tell me what's going on.
And I say customers up here
because that's what I was thinking of as
my typical audience but for
you and your organization,
who are your stakeholders,
who are your customers
that you need to be communicating with?
And that may be
the CSO in your environment, or it may be
an auditor that's come in or whoever it is
that you're briefing on something.
And so this gives us that ability
to normalize on what
we're doing and when I say
doing something like
Ingress Tool Transfer,
the other person who is
familiar with MITRE ATT&CK
has an idea of what that means.
And I don't have to fumble
around for words and
they're trying to interpret
what I meant to say.
And for us, it facilitates
our public reporting as well.
Lot of companies are
doing public reporting.
For us and our team on Outreach,
our annual Threat Hunting Report
is our big public report that we do.
Here's the name of our
2021 Threat Hunting Report,
you can always Google that
and go take a look at that.
But that was a look back at
the previous year and see,
what have we been seeing?
What's changed over time?
What are some meanings that
we can extract from that?
We've definitely found that
it's not an exact science
by any stretch, because
as we've already said,
we'll hop on Slack and we're like,
hey, what do you think about this?
Oh, I don't know, let me dig
around and we will hunt around.
But through that consensus, it allows us
basically to better communicate
what adversaries are doing
and then hopefully inform our customers
what they need to do to respond to that.
Where do they need to
show up their defenses?
Hey, could we detect this
in our environment or not?
So these are some of the
benefits to use a MITRE ATT&CK.
That's why we go through this work
and why we find this to be useful
and hopefully our customers do as well.
I've gotten some good
feedback from them on this.
And with that, I think
that's what we have,
we'll go to some questions.
- First off.
Oh, yeah.
(audience applauding)
Give it up.
Great job.
So while we give folks in
the room a couple minutes
to maybe think about some questions,
I think we have a little bit of time here.
Really good note and feedback
I was getting from Slack was,
the appreciation for,
the way you're reporting,
not just tactics and techniques,
but really getting down
into the procedures.
What advice would you give for
Intel producers or anyone
doing IR or Threat Hunting
and their producing these
products and how to really
make the most of including
those procedures?
Like, is there any tips and tricks,
lesson learned that you
can share with the crowd?
- So probably the biggest, the
first advice comes to mind,
Selena already commented
on earlier today was,
who is your audience?
Who are you writing this to?
If I'm in an IR report and I'm,
there's something I'm gonna have
to communicate to executives
and there's something I'm
gonna have to communicate
to the technology people so
that they can learn from that.
So a lot of times when we're going through
our reporting, we're trying
to keep that in mind.
When I finish writing
something up for our report,
I really spent some time trying
to think about my conc...
What's the point?
I just talked about this cool intrusion.
What does this matter?
What can you take away from
this in your environment?
What do I want the reader to think of?
- Yeah, yeah.
Like I would, Selena said about bias.
Like my bias is I wanna
see the command line.
I wanna know exactly what they're doing,
because that's more interesting but
a lot of times that may not be relevant
to the person reading it.
And so know when that procedure...
Like if that command line says something
about the intent, says
something about the capability,
it may be valuable, whereas if it's
a command line you've
seen 10, 15, 20 times,
it may not have any utility in that report
or someone may just say,
okay, that's cool but
I can't write a detection for that
or that doesn't tell me
anything about the adversary
then you probably don't
need to include it.
So know when the detail is actionable
and know when it's just fluff
that you wanna toss in
there 'cause it looks cool.
- Any questions from the room?
Actually, we'll start right up front.
- [Attendee] Yeah, do you
have examples of (indistinct)
that I was speaking my world (indistinct).
- There is absolutely a lot of nest, yeah.
- [Attendee] There's importance
to value in capturing
kinda which techniques we used together,
kinda the sequence they
use or is it more just
technique or something in the toolbox?
- So quick recap for the online audience,
the observation was that
a lot of the intrusions
that you were analyzing
don't necessarily flow
from left to right or
sequential, it's a lot of
looping or within the matrix
or moving around a little bit.
And that's something
we've done intentionally
in terms of not prescribing
a sequence, the tactics,
but what are your observations
and what are your takes
in terms of, how do you
process and deal with that?
- So we do that...
It's kind of interesting as you look at
the different analysts and how they do it.
I am very time driven.
I will sort out all the command lines
and I'm just gonna pick
through these things in order
and make my notes accordingly on it.
One of the things we do
to try and capture that
and add some context to
that is we try and write
a summary of what happened
around this, kind of a narrative,
even for our notes.
So that if Justin enriches something
and I have to look at this later,
I can look at his summary
and get kind of a flow
for how the intrusion went and
you can see them jump around
for the techniques.
So that's one way that
we work to address that.
Is it perfect?
No, we're working on
trying to improve that
because some of these
intrusions get rather complex.
- And that's where that,
like MISP has been really good for us
for the past couple of years,
the challenge has been,
it doesn't allow us to collate
the time that that tactic was leveraged.
And so the tool that
we're working on building
is gonna bring in that time based analysis
where you can take a command
line, tag the technique to it,
with the timestamp and
then start to move through
and say, okay, yeah.
So they did some discovery,
tried to do some persistence,
went back to discovery
and see that movement.
Right now, it's just,
here's the data and then
the write up is really where
that narrative comes out.
- And then hopefully we see the...
Oh sorry.
Hopefully then, we'll see that
in the products that we're producing,
'cause that'll allow us
to speak more to that.
- And I love what you said earlier about,
the attackers aren't perfect.
They're making mistakes,
we're watching those,
but neither is defenders,
we don't have that
expectation of needing to see
every bit of data and every
single technique versus,
working with what we have
and making the most of it.
So I think we're coming up on time,
but I did have one really
interesting question
from Slack that I wanted
to run by you was,
in the course of an investigation
or any of your processes,
if you see a technique that
you can't map to ATT&CK,
what would be your reaction
or what would you do?
- That's normally where the
Slack discussion gets hot and
heavy is all right.
Where does this fit?
What do we do?
We have a process on the
team where if it doesn't fit,
we bring it to the wider team.
So obviously we're across the Globes,
we've got folks in Australia, UK, America.
And so like normally when we're working,
we're in the similar time zones,
so we'll bring to the whole team
and then that's where
that discussion comes up.
Should this be something
that we surface up?
So one of our analysts in
Australia is working on
something to submit
something we came across.
- Right.
And I can't remember what the details are
off top of our head, but it was some-
- RDP.
- Yeah, it was around
RDP and some use of it,
but it didn't fit in really
well with how things were.
So he's like, well, wouldn't
it make sense to submit this
and we're like, go forth.
(all laugh)
Do it.
- Shameless plug, we'd
love to make that slide
Adam showed earlier much bigger.
So definitely keep those
contributions coming.
But with that, thank you again.
And we will reintroduce
our MC to introduce our next speakers.
Thank you.
(audience applauding)