- We're coming towards the end of the day.
I tried to memorize this,
but I took some notes.
In closing, just kind of recapping
some of the big themes today.
I think Selena's keynote
really captured it.
It all starts with telling a story.
And absolutely, that is one
of my favorite things about ATT&CK
is I think a couple talks
actually mentioned this,
Gert-Jan I think did it best,
but ATT&CK isn't going
to be a silver bullet.
It's not going to solve your problems.
It's not going to be something
you can just throw at an issue
or kind of just adopt
it and you're solved.
It really is going to be something
that makes you better at
whatever you're doing,
whether you're hunting,
whether you're a blue team
or a red team or procurement
or just a security-minded user.
Really ATT&CK is going to be that story,
that context of why does this matter?
What could potentially
happen that connects us,
exactly as this last
presentation captured,
connects us to detections,
mitigations, ideas,
configurations automation opportunities.
All of that really is gonna
be something from you,
not necessarily something that ATT&CK
is just going to solve for you.
So it really is something
that this community,
I know we really rally around each other
and start building out,
but a second big theme of the
day was telling that story.
It only goes so far if you
don't know who's listening.
And I think that's something
that from my own perspective,
being on the ATT&CK team
for almost four and a half years now,
that was one of my biggest lessons was,
think about who's listening,
think about who's reading.
Do I need to go really far in the weeds
or do I really need to
provide high level summaries?
Biggest thing is, you
don't want to overwhelm
but you also don't want to underwhelm
and really finding that balance
in terms of, who am I talking to?
What are they going to do about it?
And how do I really connect the bridge
and connect the gap in terms
of actionability for them.
So knowing that audience is going
to be advantageous and so powerful.
Third thing I picked up
and I thought was really cool was,
when the spirit of ATT&CK, as we know,
these techniques aren't things
that we're just making up,
these aren't hypothetical ideas,
these aren't pretend threats,
these aren't potential malware.
This is all data driven.
So what that theme of, it's not
just building the framework,
but everything else we do in this space.
Let's think about, how can we prioritize?
How can we inform rather than,
the second to last talk
really touched on it,
and during the Q&A was,
let's not do random things.
Let's let our data lead
us towards victory.
And there's so many different metrics
that we can capture from that perspective,
but it only starts with,
fourth lesson was knowing yourself.
What are you capable of?
What data are you collecting?
What are your prioritizations?
What are your biggest risk
and biggest things you're worried about?
And how do you integrate that
with knowing your audience,
telling this story and
really understanding,
what do we need to measure
and how do we go about that
and at what level of granularity.
And final thing of,
I love whoever designed the
stream of talks, amazing job.
I don't think this was an accident.
But the latter half of
the day really touched on,
I think this almost circles back
to the keynote from the
very first ATT&CKcon,
was now that we have solutions
and we have these great ideas,
let's build tools around
them, let's talk about them,
let's share that with the community.
Not only to share those resources
and making sure we're really
compiling on each other
and really learning from
each other's lessons,
but also taking feedback
and saying, "This is an idea,
this is a problem I had."
You might share that exact same problem.
Exactly as the last question addressed,
there might be additional problems
that this solution can already address,
or within our arms reach.
So rather than just starting from scratch
and we all are solving all these problems
and dealing with things on our own.
Why don't we learn from each other?
We're absolutely a community
that shares many if not
all the same problems.
So there really is absolutely no reason
that we can't come together like this
and start to really be a community
with the shared problem set
and shared adversary space.
So with that, I know definitely
don't want to just sit here
and brain vomit for the next 10 minutes,
especially with alcohol on
the other side of this wall.
So just wanted to thank you again
for showing up, being
as amazing as you are,
contributing and most especially today,
it's really been a couple years
since we were able to do this.
A lot of us forgot, or we haven't,
especially how much the
ATT&CK team has grown.
We haven't had an opportunity to be here
and actually feel what it feels like
to see all you and all the online,
Slack, Twitter, all that stuff.
It's been great.
So really kind of seeing everyone here.
So definitely take a second
to give yourselves a round of applause.
And truly, thank you.
(audience claps)