- Back in the slack, I was
loving the Twitter, banter,
keep it coming.
And with that, my next
job is to introduce again,
our MC Adam Pennington to
present the State of ATT&CK.
- Thank you for the sector.
So, I'm now switching
hats, I like this hat,
so not literally,
But to talk a little bit
about the current state of the ATT&CK.
So this is a talk we've done
for each ATT&CKcon going over,
sort of what's been going
on in the framework,
what's coming, and to try to
give everybody an opportunity
to do Q and A as well.
So, I've asked all my leads
to do who am my slides.
So I figure I have to as well,
my pronouns are he, him, his,
I'm the lead of MITRE ATT&CK,
have been for about two years now,
since I took over from
its founder, Blake Strom,
I've been in MITRE quite a
long time now, over 13 years,
that seems like a long time.
My main focuses are on threat intelligence
and deception lately.
I am a past defender CTI analyst.
I've spent time in the trenches
and I've been involved with ATT&CK
since it was a spreadsheet
with no ampersand.
Was did used to be ATTACK
before it came out.
And if you see underwater photos
coming out on ATT&CKs
Twitter, stuff like that,
it's probably from me.
So, I figure with a talk
called the State of the ATT&CK,
I have to start out with saying
MITRE ATT&CK remains strong.
So my welcome,
I talked a little bit about
how it's been 2 1/2 years
since we've been here.
Since the last time Blake
delivered this same talk.
And so, we'd already come
a long way 2 1/2 years ago.
We had come from this, well
sort of ugly Excel Spreadsheet
to a bit less ugly Excel Spreadsheet.
Now, but we had expanded
a lot, we'd added tactics.
We'd gotten up to 266 techniques
at the point in time this was done.
But there's a little
secret about that slide.
This is what it really
looked like 2 1/2 years ago,
before we cropped the
bottom of that image.
In case you missed it,
this big section over here.
So, persistence and defensive agent,
especially had gotten kind of
unruly, we couldn't fit it.
A lot of techniques had
gotten sort of uneven.
And so the shape of ATT&CK has
actually changed quite a bit
since the last time we were in this room.
So this is what ATT&CK looks like today.
Yes, really.
I didn't have to crop
or chop off anything.
For those of you in the
room who have ATT&CK flags,
you might have noticed
it's now shaped a bit more
like a banner than a flag,
but it's gotten wider,
it's gotten shorter.
And so I wanted to talk
about some of what's happened
since the last time we were
in coming from this room.
So I'm gonna get into some of the changes
that have actually happened
over that time period.
Starting with ATT&CK for
Industrial Control Systems.
So we released ATT&CK for
ICS in January of 2020.
ATT&CK for ICS covers
behaviors on Industrial Control Systems.
We keep it as a separate
matrix, so it's off to the side.
If you're ever feeling
nostalgia for the MediaWiki,
that ATT&CK used to be,
you can currently go to
the ATT&CK for ICS site.
We keep it separate because
it's a unique space.
We think they're unique adversaries there
that are focused on it.
And it's kept up with parallel
updates in its own site.
And so I have some updates to that
coming in a little bit too.
Some of the big thing,
and the reason why that
shape changed so much
is sub-techniques being
added to enterprise.
(audience applauding)
That's encouraging reaction too,
but sub-techniques added
a new level to techniques.
So it allowed us to describe
things that are specific to platforms,
to specific operating systems.
It allowed us to even out the
granularity, the techniques,
and it allowed us to fit it
into a PowerPoint slide again.
We've gotten a lot of feedback
in the past two years,
actually racks in the room
act is nice to hear too,
that most people have been
happy with the change.
And one way that people
have also said that
is voting with their feet.
So we've seen most people over time
switch to newer versions of ATT&CK
in actual leverage
sub-techniques in their products.
Thank you.
So, because sub-techniques
have worked out pretty well,
something you are gonna see over time,
we have these separate matrices still,
is sub-techniques coming over
time to the rest of ATT&CK.
I'll talk a little bit about mobile
and we'll figure out when
exactly on ICS in the future.
So I know some of you
were fans of Pre-ATT&CK.
And so I'm sorry that it
is no longer here with us
as of October 27th, 2020,
but we did replace Pre-ATT&CK
with two new tactics
to take its place in the framework.
So reconnaissance and
resource development.
So this led us to talk about
in the main enterprise framework,
things that the adversary is doing
to try to get information,
to be able to do a breach
or the steps that they take
in order to actually
build up their activities.
So writing the malware,
setting up websites, et cetera.
And again, this is an area
where we're slowly seeing
more and more people
adopted into their practices
and show up in more and more reporting.
We know this is a tough
space for some people.
This isn't necessarily intelligence
that every defender has,
but we think it can be a useful place
for a lot of people to look at threats.
A platform that I think a lot
of people may not have caught
being released was our
network devices platform.
So October, 2020,
we released the network devices platform
covering network infrastructure devices.
This is things like routers and switches.
So adversary is actually hacking
into these types of devices,
replacing their firmware,
and this is added into enterprise ATT&CK.
So, I finally decided to
stop abusing Ryan Kovas,
sad cloud graphic,
'cause we are very much
in happy cloud mode now.
But so Ryan spoke at the first ATT&CK on,
he talked about our
lack of cloud coverage.
And so over time we've released cloud,
we've covered a number of platforms in it
and we've done work over this time period,
expanding the space that we're in.
So, in the space of platforms,
we added Google Workspace
alongside Office 365
and we made a shift to actually get rid
of three platforms as well.
So you may have noticed
that we got rid of AWS,
GCP and Azure as platforms in ATT&CK
and replaced them with
Infrastructures as a Service, IaaS.
The reason we did this
is that we took a look
at what was unique
between those platforms.
And so what were we adding differently
as techniques between them?
And the answer was nothing.
ATT&CK actually was showing
at the level of granularity
that ATT&CK is at.
About the same techniques
in each of the platforms.
The other thing is there are
a lot of other IaaS platforms
out there besides those three.
So condensing those let
us describe more space.
We also released ATT&CK for containers.
So, we had a lot of demand
looking at things like Kubernetes
and other container
orchestration platforms.
And so we were finally able to
build up enough intelligence
in the space and what
people were really seeing
from threat actors.
More recently over the past year,
we've been making some changes
to enterprise data sources.
So, before data sources
and ATT&CK for enterprise
were just a list of text strings.
So, these weren't that
consistent, we have to admit it.
So, we would have something
like file monitoring,
something you do, process
command line parameters,
something that you're gathering
and Windows Get Registry,
something that you're
gathering information on.
There's also no details beyond the name.
So, we were just sort of describing things
that you could gather,
but there's no information on
what we really meant by that.
We sort of hope that you'd
interpret it correctly
and no descriptions behind them.
So, we've done two releases
last year to improve this,
our first release in ATT&CK version nine
that came out in April, 2021.
We started adding a
little bit of structure
to our data sources.
And so this idea of data
sources and data components.
Data source being the thing
that you're gathering the information on
and the component being
the specific activity
that you're gathering information about.
Now, the originally when we
released this in version nine,
if you clicked on these data sources,
you actually went to a GitHub site,
you're looking at a YAML file.
That's not really ideal,
that's not how we normally
build things in ATT&CK.
We do things in STIX here.
So we fix that in October.
On October, 2021, we
released our current version
of enterprise data sources,
where data sources are now an object.
There's data sources tab at
the top of the tech website.
You can go into them,
you can see what techniques
that a particular data
source is relevant to.
And we're seeing a number
of sort of our power users
taking advantage of this and looking at,
what sorts of techniques you can gather
with specific information.
And like I said, since it's us,
it's of course in STIX 2.
Yeah, STIX 2, but it,
yeah, 'cause anything that's
actually on the ATT&CK website,
other than things like documents
and lists of conferences
is generated from our STIX repository.
It's not the other way around.
And so these objects are out there,
you can actually use 'em, do processing,
take a look at what's inside
each of these data sources.
Something that hasn't
changed in the last two years
is ATT&CK's community.
So ATTACK, and again, with an A,
that Blake's original preferred spelling,
was originally built,
primarily using adversary data
that might have gathered
doing deception ops
against APT actors.
And so if you think back to 2013,
there really wasn't
much threat intelligence
reporting available out there.
There wasn't a lot of talk
about adversary behaviors,
you had some people publishing IOCs,
but there wasn't much for us to work from
in terms of reporting, so we
had to use some of our own.
Since then, since the ATT&CK was released
to the public in 2015,
it's the community that's
kept us going ever since.
So it's the contributions
that we have coming in
from well, you, that are
letting us actually understand
what adversaries are doing,
what sorts of groups we
should be focusing in on
and what pieces of software
we should be adding to ATT&CK.
And so this is a slide
that has actually been used in
a couple of these talks now.
It's getting a touch unreadable.
So, and here's why,
we now have 308
organizations and individuals
who are named contributors to ATT&CK.
That's not everyone, so some people ask us
not to credit their contributions.
They don't wanna put their name out there.
They may have rules around what
they can brand as their own,
and it's been growing too.
So in 2019, the last
year we had ATT&CK on,
we had 82 named contributors.
2020, we had 130.
And in 2021, we had 155.
And 155 is a lot of you.
And you think of what we're processing.
We're trying to do a better job
on getting down the amount of time
that it takes to process
contributions, get back to you,
and apologize where it
does take a long time.
But we are getting a
lot of new information
and a lot of new contributors
into the framework.
One more stat as we're
continuing to other slide
and add contributors,
we're also down to 4.5 font to
make this work, sorry, Katie.
So that's the past, what about the future?
So first of all, ATT&CK for mobile.
I hinted at this earlier
that we've done stuff for
sub-techniques in enterprise,
people seem to like it,
and we've got some of the same problems,
maybe won't fit on a PowerPoint slide,
but the unevenness that's
happening in the parts of ATT&CK
we haven't gone there yet.
So we're about to release
a sub-technique beta
for ATT&CK for mobile.
So as we're coming in ATT&CK
able release version 11.
And so the ATT&CK for mobile team
has actually spent all of this past year
working on this internally.
So implementing sub-techniques,
moving their information over to it.
And we think those of you
that are interested in the iOS
and Android security space
are gonna find this useful.
So final release, similar
to how we did sub-techniques
and ATT&CK for enterprise,
we're planning on changing the
beta into the final release
sometime in the summer,
depending on what sorts of feedback we get
and how much we have to
change from the beta.
We're gonna be continuing this trend too
of taking features that we
first released in enterprise
and bringing those to
other parts of ATT&CK.
So data sources are coming up
in the same sorts of forms as you find
in ATT&CK for enterprise
and mobile as well.
So I've stolen most of my thunder
on talking about the future
and I'm gonna be having my
leads over the next two days,
give updates on a lot of their areas.
So I'm gonna give a preview,
hopefully get you back to
their individual talks,
but there's much more to
come on each of these areas.
The first is defensive ATT&CK
coming up just at 1:30 today.
Lex Crumpton from on the side,
gonna be talking about some of the work
that we're doing now,
moving from data sources
to refactoring detections.
So if you followed the changes we've made
over the past couple years,
there's been this trend
to take blobs of text
and turn them into more structured data.
So mitigations, data
sources and now detections.
And we're also gonna be tying those
to individual data sources and components.
So if you have a detection,
what is it you need to gather
to do that one detection?
In the past, you've sort of had
to guess what the mapping is
between the blob of detection we write,
the data sources we list,
and we're gonna be making
up some more explicit.
Lex also gonna be talking
about some upcoming changes to car.
So something I know a
lot of you are fan of,
but we do have some plans in store
for car in the future as well.
This afternoon, our threat
intelligence lead, Matt Malone,
is gonna be talking about campaigns.
So as threat intelligence person,
I'm actually really
excited about this update.
We're going to be doing some restructuring
to groups in ATT&CK.
So today when we have a group and ATT&CK,
we have these associated
group descriptions.
We have basically all of the reporting
that people have tied back
to this one group over time
in their reporting.
So like APT29, we've tied together
things like Nobelium, YTTRIUM
the Cozy Bear, the Dukes,
altogether into one piece.
Well, we actually did a lot of
work doing separate tracking
for the events around
solar winds last year.
So we had built up this data
and then when U.S government
came out and said,
"It's APT29," we pulled it together,
we sort of lost that distinction.
And so we'd like to get
that distinction back.
We also have a problem in ATT&CK
where we today only will do
reporting unnamed groups.
So somebody's got a great
threat report they've put out,
describes tons of adversary behavior,
gets to the end and they don't name it.
And they don't tie it to any other report.
Today we wouldn't add it to ATT&CK.
So we only add groups
that people have actually put a name to,
have called the group into ATT&CK
because we're not the ones
sort of creating the space.
With campaigns we'll be doing things
that just have identifiers
and allow us to add some of these reports.
Trying to not to hit the laser button
while I'm pointing the
pointer at everybody.
Tomorrow morning, Otis Alexander
is gonna be talking about ATT&CK
for Industrial Control Systems.
So something I'm really excited about.
And some of you may be sad
if you really love the MediaWiki,
is that ATT&CK for ICS is
moving into attack.mitre.org.
So it's gonna join the website
along with ATT&CK for enterprise,
along with ATT&CK for mobile
and sort of be full-fledged
member of the team.
So we've already been releasing it in STIX
for a couple of releases now,
but it's all gonna be coming together.
They're also doing work to expand assets
and how they talk about
different types of devices
that are specific to the
industrial control space.
And keeping up with this
theme of mobile and ICS,
moving towards parody with enterprise,
adding detections to ICS.
It's been a space that's
taken a little while,
not necessarily as much gets published
on how you defend against
specific actions in the ICS space.
But we think that we now are at a point
where we can actually talk
about it intelligently.
Mac and Linux ATT&CK.
So we released ATT&CK for Mac
and Linux way back in 2017.
And it was the work of
Cody Thomas primarily.
And he did a lot of
good work in the space,
but it really didn't get
a lot of love after that.
So we don't see a ton of
contributions in that space.
And so our eyes tend not to go places.
We have some exceptions
tend to go to that space,
unless we're seeing stuff coming in.
So we wanted to go back
and actually put some
specific attention into it.
And so Cat Self who's also
gonna be coming to you
from the ATT&CKcon couch
is focusing on updating our
Mac and Linux techniques
going through the entire framework.
We've done a lot of work with Mac already,
we're just starting in on Linux
and she'll be talking about more details
for just before lunch talk tomorrow.
Finally, Jared Ondricek,
our development lead,
is gonna be talking tomorrow afternoon.
So a lot of people are familiar with tech,
have seen the stuff we've
put out in terms of our STIX
and our actual website,
but not necessarily all of you've seen
some of the code we've put out.
So for quite a long time now
we've been releasing open source programs,
whether it's our website,
ATT&CK navigator,
whether it's for manipulating layer files
in ATT&CK navigator.
We put out there GitHub,
and so Jared's gonna get
into some of those resources
that you can put to use.
But there's one more thing.
So, we haven't yet announced
when the next release of ATT&CK is.
And so we decided to
put it on the best date.
(audience chuckles)
So the next ATT&CK release
will be April 25th.
And so, just coming next month.
It's Monday, which is a
little bit unusual for us,
but we will try to make that work.
So, we've intentionally
left decent amount of time
for questions, 'cause we thought
you might have some for me.
So with that, I'm gonna,
since this is our first talk with Q and A,
Jamie's gonna be leading our Q and A
through the rest of the conference.
So we don't have a audience mic,
if somebody is asking questions,
he'll be repeating it
to make sure that people
in the audience have.
And he is also watching
our slack for any questions
that come in from there.
- First off, thank you.
And while folks, take
your last sip of coffee
and get those questions geared up,
we did have some amazing
comments in slack.
First off, the question
from Barry Anderson,
what do you think about the
prospect of sub contributors?
- Sub contributors?
- Yeah.
- I feel like we're getting to that point.
I think you said 4.5 font,
that's a little hard to track.
- Oh, so to condense it, yeah.
I think we're probably gonna
have to retire that slide
after this or I'm just gonna
show a blurry image with lines
and not even bother to
fill in the real data, but.
- So, like Adam said,
we have about eight minutes
or so before we go to break,
but at this point, we really
do want to hear from you.
This is one of those opportunities,
we did an AMA during the pandemic.
It was a great time
for us, we had a blast,
any questions from the audience?
Don't be shy, feel free, just
throw a hand up or stand up.
Oh, question over here.
(speaker inaudible)
And for our friends on the
live stream, the question was,
is there any plans to go in more depth
regarding data sources and components,
particularly mapping
those to particular logs,
particular events,
especially as we begin
to unpack the nuances
of different types platforms?
Differences between Windows
logging and Mac OS logging.
- Actually, Jamie, I might
kick that one back to you.
- Yep, perfect, yes.
That is something we were
really excited about,
in terms of building out
the data source objects,
is we went with this mentality of,
if you build it, they will come.
And really giving folks a
chance and opportunity in space
to deliver those contributions.
So you might have noticed now,
even with ATT&CK version
10, we have data sources,
we have data components
and then those data component definitions,
we did begin to start list examples
of this is sometimes known
as this amount of event one
or a 4688.
We really do want to hear from you
in terms of how are you folks
actually detecting these
adversary behaviors?
Are there particular logs
or particular prevents
that have really helped you?
'Cause Lex is gonna
present this later today
and Adam kind of teased
it, but for version 11,
we will be merging those detections
and data components together.
So the more rich and nuance
we can really get in
depth there the better,
'cause one of the big things about ATT&CK
is we're not just documenting
the adversary perspective,
we really are trying to connect
that back to defensive countermeasures
and really make it impactful for you.
So, great question, thank you.
We're here.
(speaker inaudible)
- So for the question
for the live audience
is what is the status of navigator
and what's the future
look like for that tool?
- Yeah, so tech navigators
on your active development,
we actually, Jared will
be talking about some work
that's been done on it lately.
There are number of improvements
that we're hoping to see
in terms of its ability to
display data, work with it.
And so some people are using
it and have been using it
as an alternate way to
view ATT&CK over time.
But there are no plans to really diverge
from where we are now,
where we've got attack.mitre.org,
which has all of the information behind it
and ATT&CK navigator, which
is a way to deal with,
focus on sort of picking techniques.
So which techniques are
going for a particular group
or problem or defense
without sort of the full data behind them.
- So we had, oh, one sec.
We had a great question from online
or I think she, I think
Tim might be in the room.
So I think it's your birthday as well,
so either happy birthday or happy belated.
So a lot of folks, oh, amazing.
A lot of folks might have
actually, as you said,
just noticed the network platform.
How would you describe the scope
of what that platform
is trying to capture?
- I wrote, right now
it's pretty specifically
routers and switches.
So we have left it open
as the possibility of getting broader.
So that's not a scoping decision
that we wanted to keep it to that.
That's where we had enough
data to talk about it.
And if you look to the contributions,
it was heavily from Cisco.
We had a ton of contributions from there,
but as well as a number of other sources.
And so, we really appreciated
some of the publishing
that happened around that,
where there is a bit more
information now on threats
that have actually happened in the past,
stuff that we're able
to cite as references.
And so we felt that we'd
reached the threshold
to be able to talk about that space,
but in order to be able
to sort of broaden it,
we would need to see more
publication out there.
So the two things that we look for
to publish a technique and ATT&CK
are that there is a
publicly citable description
of the technique.
So that could be anything from...
Somebody tweeted and said,
"An adversary did this,"
or I could do this or a black
hat talk or an ATT&CKcon talk,
talking about something that
could be done or has been done.
And then we're looking for
that proof that it's been done
by somebody in the wild,
that might be somebody
whispering in her ear,
that might be a public
threat intelligence report.
And now not necessarily something we cite,
it does need to be of course unclass.
But so it's finding that
threshold in different spaces
can sometimes be challenging
and that's definitely been one of them.
- I think we have time for
maybe one or two more questions.
I think there was one.
- [Man] Yeah, so now that we have ability,
(speaker inaudible)
In its own way, I'm
wondering in the future,
would there be any interest
in possibly creating objects
for investigations that are
like follow up investigations
around the data components?
- So for the audience online,
the question very nuanced and
very awesome question was,
now that we're starting
to kind of really dive
into the detection side of ATT&CK
and we're building out these data sources
and data components,
how far are we interested in going
in terms of investigations
and other categories
beyond just the detection
engineering perspective?
And I can...
- Yeah, so it's an interesting question.
So, I don't think we've thought
too hard down that path.
I mean, we obviously have gone down
into some things like specific
implementations of detections
and things like cyber
analytics repository,
but sort of going down that path
of pulling it together
into investigations.
I don't know if we'd go there,
so there is a line where
we're trying to keep stuff
general enough to be able to work
for basically all defenders,
but it's certainly an interesting puzzle.
Jamie, I didn't know if
you wanted to add to that?
- I think it ties back to the,
if we build it, they will come,
that's something where, like Adam said,
we try to not be prescriptive
and say like, this is the best
way you're gonna do cyber,
this is the best approach for you,
rather than kind of
connect you to those ideas.
So I think it might be something
where maybe we can prototype it,
maybe we can collaborate and see like,
start with a Spreadsheet and build it
and see what it looks like,
and then if it makes sense
for a broad community,
definitely something we
maybe interested in pursuing.
So I think you said,
I think like exactly to
the heart of your question,
the detection and
defensive side is much more
than just alerts and monitoring.
So really thank you.
I think we have one time
for the final question, yes.
(speaker inaudible)
- Oh, for the live
audience, the question was,
have we thought about
characterizing supply chain
and infections and really
that kind of diving
in a really deep dive into that space?
- So we do have techniques
for each of those
in ATT&CK today.
So we do have a supply chain technique,
we do go into each of those areas a bit.
We've gotten the proposal
of doing like an entire
supply chain framework
to just expanding out that area.
Right now inside enterprise ATT&CK,
it is sort of in line
with how we cover the rest of techniques.
So doing a huge bulk up there
would be a little out of place.
But there is the possibility
to improve those techniques,
expand it in place,
possibly sub-techniques.
And so a lot of that's gonna be driven
by what we see for contributions, so--
- You know the inbox.
- Yeah, if you have suggestions
on some specifics to add, so we're...
- With that, I think we came
right in our time for break.
So thank you for indulging us
and for those on the live stream
and those in the room as well,
we will be sending over to
Cat on the ATT&CKcon couch.
So, stay tuned and see
you in about 30 minutes.