- So with that,
it's time to actually get started
on our technical program for today.
So our first speakers
are Santiago Pontiroli
and Dmitry Bestuzhev from the
wilds of Argentina and Miami.
Today's first talk was the actually
the highest rated submission
by our program committee.
We don't often hear about
Latin American threats.
It's kind of an under reported space
and we are really excited
to hear about some actors
that we either haven't
heard about much in the past
or haven't heard about at all.
So we're intrigued to hear
about the attack techniques
being leveraged by these groups
and how they might be
different from the ones
that we're used to.
So please welcome to the
stage Santiago and Dmitry.
(audience applauding)
Big green button.
- [Santiago] Which one is the?
- [Male] Big green.
- [Santiago] Okay, thank you.
- So, hello everyone.
Should I say Buenos Dias
because we're gonna speak
about Latin America?
For us, it's a big privilege
to be here with you.
Thank you for having us
and I have also privilege
to introduce to my colleague
and my friend, Santiago Pontiroli
who's senior security researcher.
Santi?
- Thank you, Dma.
Buenos Dias, good morning, everyone.
Thank you for being here.
I know last night or last
evening you had some drinks
so thank you for waking up.
So I'm presenting here
with Dmitry Bestuzhev.
He's the director of the
global research analysis team
for Latin America and
we've been working together
for nine years so we know
each other really well
and we are going to speak
about what we work everyday.
So thank you again for being here
and let's start with the presentation.
So has anyone been here before?
One, one in the room.
You need to travel here.
This is beautiful.
- Two.
- Two, two people.
Nice.
So this is forest Iguazu,
or cataratas del Iguazu,
or Iguazu waterfalls.
So Iguazu comes from the name E or Y,
that means big and Yguasu from Guarani,
that means water.
So big water.
It was a pretty simple name.
So we have these beautiful
landscapes in Latin America,
but we also have some conflicts.
If you see this picture,
you wouldn't imagine the
administration of George W. Bush
saying that this is a conflict zone,
that there are terrorist
groups operating here,
that there are very, a lot of
criminal activities going on
and this is a conflict
zone mainly because of the,
of the triple frontier.
You have Argentina.
You have Brazil,
and you have Paraguay,
sharing pretty much a single point
that crosses over this waterfall.
So what we are going to speak about
is the other side of the
coin, the virtual side,
because as we see, Latin
America is a beautiful place,
but we also have some
cyber espionage operations
that do not get the attention
that we think they should.
So knowing the culture,
knowing the context,
is important as we mentioned
yesterday in several talks,
the importance of storytelling,
the importance of,
of knowing what, who, and where
are doing these operations
and we are going to speak
about several groups.
I'm going to start with,
with one that is from
the bottom of our hearts,
and this is Machete.
- Thank you.
Yeah, so probably you've heard
a lot about Machete, right?
At least at some
conferences, but in reality,
everything you have heard,
it's not the full picture.
I found Machete by myself
before EDR existed,
Igs-DR and all those
(inaudible) we have nowadays.
It was a very interesting
story when one of the generals,
militaries from Ecuador called
and told that he had a trip to China
and he was like freaking out
thinking that his machine was infected.
I went to the, to work with his machine.
I just sat down and I
worked with his machine
and I found actually Machete.
I didn't know it was Machete.
I didn't find anything Chinese
but something very suspicious,
like a presentation on EPT,
with an embedded file which,
basically in the end, ended
up in this executable.
So Machete is also known originally,
Machete, this is the name, marketing name,
I put to this thing,
but originally it was called
as Arkantos Live Control
and we're gonna see
that later, also Ragua.
So here is one of the
example of those documents
they also used and that
exists at least since 2010,
we found also traces
leading to mobile implants.
Imagine even to, you remember Blackberry?
When people use those mobile device?
They had implants for
that Blackberry as well,
same as for Android,
and of course they rely a
lot in social engineering.
So Santi?
- So we found Machete during 2014,
but actually their operations
go as far back as 2010.
I always make fun,
we laugh about this, that we had the,
the brightest idea of
presenting Machete in Colombia
in Cartagena,
but after that presentation, of course,
Machete went underground
for a couple of years.
We didn't see any more
of their operations.
Then in 2016, 2017, we
saw some new samples.
We saw they were consolidating
their operations.
They were starting all over.
So there was a different set of malware,
a different infrastructure.
It was everything done from scratch.
Then we saw in 2019 also
using human intelligence.
So they were using documents
that they would steal
from victims,
so these were secret documents
that they would steal,
for example, from embassies
and use those documents
as a lure to catch new victims.
So for example, the documents,
if you would see the
slide before was about,
for example, about a coup in Venezuela.
So at the bottom of the
document, it says Chavez Vive,
or Chavez is alive.
So they would use this type of
documents to get new victims,
documents that no one had seen before.
This is very targeted spearfishing.
- Finally.
Yes, thank you, Santi.
Finally, during the
pandemic, we thought, okay,
Machete is gone because
literally we brought so much,
let's say attention to them,
that they had like a very
busy time, you know, even the,
one of the operators who used to be
an active military personnel,
he got transferred inside
of the military unit
to something like construction
or something like that
until in 2020, 2021,
they just got back again.
It was right inside of the pandemic.
The original name of the operation,
they put it was COVID 19.
Then they changed it to Ecorys
and what was about,
about targeting the office
of general prosecutor office
in Ecuador.
Why?
Because the ex-president, one
of the ex-presidents of the,
of Ecuador, he got in
problems, in troubles,
and he was called basically
to get to the court
and to respond, you know, to the justice.
So basically Machete,
from a military unit,
ended up in mercenaries.
Now they're still alive and kicking
and they work for money.
For this operation,
they got payment in
cryptocurrencies and what they did,
they attacked the computer
of the secretary of the
general prosecutor office
who led the case.
They stole the information.
Those screenshots are published
on a website, fake website,
built by Machete to also to,
to like set up a fake news portal,
news portal to make people
believe that there is injustice,
like, you know, unjust-full
treatment to the ex-president
and you see here is in the
script about the visitors,
when people visit the portal,
it says like, you know,
the number of visitors
like it's, I don't know,
thousands of people.
In reality, it was just fake.
So those, I mean, these
pictures, you can see here,
it's taken by Machete, not by us.
It's not from the evidences,
it's basically by, by them.
So the purpose of this presentation
is to let you know about
the contents, right?
What's going on and also
to show, how can we map it?
How can we put it, to transfer it,
into the MITRE ATT&CK
framework, TTPs, right?
Some of them, like Machete,
it's already available public,
but still we work with those
existed TTPs available on the,
in the internet and also we,
let's say, try to enrich it
with the information we have or,
or just to show you something
like very interesting
and it's, we usually put it
like in highlight in yellow,
as you can see here.
One of the very important things here,
you can see the exfiltration,
one of the exfiltration methods
used, it was not only FTP,
but also a special USB device.
Why we say special?
Because that special USB device
was linked and hard coded in
the code by the serial number.
What it means,
air gap networks were there's no internet
still were affected because spies, people,
let's say other personnel
working in the affected,
in the victims facilities,
and we should remember
between the victims,
we had embassies, military
unions, police forces,
prison systems, and so on.
So someone also like those victims had a,
let's say like intruders or, you know,
people, like spies, using
basically that USBs,
they inserted those USBs,
without doing anything,
the information was copied
automatically to the USB
and that's it.
Santi, do you have anything to add here?
- Yeah, I remember the
first campaign that we,
we saw Machete using, for example,
pornography images,
but also they were using, for
example, The Art of War ebook.
So it was kind of a, you
know, a shotgun approach,
like maybe you want to
read a very, you know,
deep book or maybe you
just want some pornography.
It's fine.
But after that in 2016, 2017,
they started using these stolen documents.
So Machete evolved, we've
seen like a clear evolution,
but also the name Ecorys
comes from the C2 server.
Actually, they would embed the
credentials in their malware.
So everything was custom.
For each operation,
they had a,
let's say a Dropbox or a,
or a drop server.
After that everything was burned
and a new operation was created.
- Yes, and that is a
screenshot of one of those
Arkantos Live Control, you remember?
They also had a feature,
a special feature,
to spy on such are called
offline conversations.
You know, like, hey, I
want, Santi, can you speak?
Yeah, sure, but face-to-face.
- Yeah.
- Okay, and we are here, let's
say, but the computer is on,
or my mobile device is on
and you can see they were,
they had those features like
audio, geolocation, video,
WebCom and so on.
So it was like a full,
actually, full operational,
like framework to spy on
whoever and right now it's,
it's still running and they
also rely a lot on open source
and for example, for video,
let's say, like conferencing,
they use Getsee, you know, Getsee thing.
So it's, there's something also,
they like it very much.
Blind Eagle.
- Blind Eagle.
This was the best picture I
could find of a blind eagle.
I am sorry for this, (chuckles)
like, I really tried to,
to have some memes or something, you know,
so Blind Eagle,
now that we're speaking
about Colombia also
is one of these APTs and I
would call it a nation state.
I mean,
some other other
companies have called this
a kind of a mercenary or
financially motivated group,
but actually I don't think
so because of the targets
and the way they operate.
So I think there are very important things
about Blind Eagle.
One of those is, thank you, Jose-lia,
for mapping it, (chuckles)
but also beyond that
is that they use a
bunch of different RATs,
Remote Access Trojans,
and between those we could find,
for example, Projector RAT,
or some RATs that are
made in Latin America
and also some phishing emails,
for example, from DIAN,
DIAN is Department del
Impuestos Aduanas Columbia,
that's the tax and customs
department from Colombia.
So they are using very
specific phishing documents,
not as specific as Machete
but they are targeting
pretty much the same kind of,
let's say, of entities,
embassies, military services,
anything that has strategic
relevance to their operations.
Again, we are adding context,
but also we thought it
would be good for you
to have also the TTPs.
So it's not only the
context you have, you know,
or mappings as well,
and you can do something
with it. (chuckles)
- Actual things.
- So, for Blind Eagle,
I was checking the mapping
that there is available on,
on the MITRE ATT&CK website
and I had a problem mapping,
just one TTP that was related
to network infrastructure.
So when Blind Eagle is
developing resources,
they would hack routers or modems,
but they won't use it
as an execution phase
or they won't use it to deploy anything.
It's just developing the
resource and use it later
for maybe proxifying the connection
or as a multi proxy or something like that
but it's actually resource irrelevant
and I couldn't find this
exact TTP in my term.
Other than that,
we added some other
TTPs and as you can see,
the discovery tactic is
marked with an asterisk
and this is pretty common
with all the threat actors
that we want to show here.
Latin American threat
actors are really noisy,
really, really noisy.
The discovery phase is amazing.
I mean,
I would need another slide
just to show everything.
- Correct.
- So Puppeteers.
This dates back to 2015, 2016,
we are going to present about Puppeteers
at a security conference in Tenerife,
one week before we saw the
report that Citizen Lab published
and we thought, okay, we
cannot talk about this anymore.
So we published a different threat actor
that we will talk about
later, but nevertheless,
Puppeteers is one of those
groups operating in Latin America
that you should be aware of
because they are mercenaries.
They target journalists,
they target opposition,
they target prosecutors.
So they target high profile
victims, not entities,
but persons, people.
I remember the first sample
that we saw was using Alien Spy,
I think, protected with
Allatori, a commercial hacker,
and when you see the email,
now Dima will talk about this,
but they would ask you like,
do not read this email on your phone,
please open it on your desktop computer
and things like that, you know. (laughs)
(audience laughs)
Of course.
- Right, so yeah, Puppeteers,
it's interesting because they also,
the person behind, his
unique name as he's known,
it's El Russo, like the Russian, but he's,
he's not the Russian. (chuckles)
So here is also one example
of those like real examples,
what happened, basically the
guys behind this campaign,
it's a group of threat actors.
One of them,
he started like psychological warfare
when he was like also in
the military, now career.
So now it's a mercenary thing
and they're also targeting people.
In this case,
in this particular case,
first they infected the
president of Ecuador's daughter.
Then from her email,
they went to the president of
the Ecuador and they got like,
you know, his communications
completely on.
Again, that is not the only one victim.
Between the victims,
we saw journalists protected by the,
the State Department of the United States.
Boom, infected.
People who were in
opposition, boom, infected.
And then in like working with the victims,
I mean, working with them as persons,
it was also very interesting
because they, they show like,
I think I'm infected.
Okay, show me your email,
like, okay, I have a Gmail.
Okay, log in, boom,
and then like you see those
emails and they say like,
I tried to, I tried to open
the file but it didn't work.
Can you send it again?
Man!
(laughs)
Like how many times did you
click on that thing, you know?
So Puppeteer used also
something very interesting.
For the ex-filtration,
for the command and control ex-filtration,
they use a multi-hop proxy.
How it works,
they wanted also to bring
a false flag operation.
Basically first, they infected
some of network devices
of a military unit of Ecuador.
It's a military unit and it's
a communication like unit,
like in charge of, you
know, communications
and they basically use it
as a first step, you know,
like fast so any like
incident responder, like with,
you know, like, not that like
high expertise would say,
look, the military of Ecuador
targeting his own president.
Like it's a shame, it's a shame.
You have to go to the jail
and here, as you see the,
the compromised webcam
and also their router
and stuff like that and,
Pisco Gone Sour, Santi.
- So, Dima got to name Machete,
and I go to name this one, Pisco.
If you know the drink, guilty as charged.
So I named this one after
being in Chile and Peru,
Pisco Gone Sour,
it's a campaign that we
saw several years ago
and it was happening at the same time
as some cyber drill exercise
done by the Southern Command.
So we saw the same TTPs
as this cyber drill.
So they were teaching some military units
about doing offensive operations.
These offensive operations
use some pretty common frameworks,
such as PowerShell Empire
and things like that.
So at the same time, or after
this cyber drill finished,
it seems the teams
wanted to put it to use.
So we saw this operation and
if you look at these documents,
it's targeting,
targeting a system developer
that has access to the
ministry of defense of Chile.
So actually they weren't
targeting directly
the ministry of defense,
but indirectly by using
one of their developers.
- Yeah, that's correct.
- So all the TTPs are new.
So the, we, we don't,
we didn't highlight anything on this one,
but we can hope we can share it.
I don't know if it's going to make it
to the MITRE ATT&CK
website, but nevertheless,
we will share the adjacent files of,
of all the attack navigators that we did.
So we --
- Exactly, because I think nobody knows
about Pisco Gone Sour
attack at all, right?
Probably you heard about the previous one,
but about this one not
so here you have also
these so fresh things.
Now there's another group,
because we have heard
like a lot of military,
military, military, but now we're,
we're gonna speak about
Initial Access groups, right,
and that is something we
have forecasted years ago
and we see today, right?
Even like groups like Conti,
we just saw them on the news,
basically also using,
relying on somebody else,
you know, to get access.
So Latin America also
has those guys, you know,
and one of them is Poseidon.
Santi, what can you tell
us about Poseidon, please?
- Well, if you remember,
I told you that we were going
to present about Puppeteer
and at Tenerife and we couldn't do it,
well, we have Poseidon
also at the same time.
And actually Poseidon is
also a mercenary group
but it's different from Puppeteer.
Why is that?
Because Poseidon presents itself
as a penetration testing company.
So it goes to the customer
and offers the services,
but once it's inside the network, once it,
it has access to the customer
files and private information,
it starts to blackmail the customer
and it offers that
information to the competition
and also they have like
another leg of their operation
that is called financial
forecasting services.
So if your company is on
the stock market, of course,
if you have private
information of the company,
I have the best forecasting system ever,
because I know everything about you.
So they would sell this service as well.
So one of the, let's say,
TTPs that we can highlight for Poseidon
is the use of digital
certificates but also again,
for the discovery phase,
I remember they have this
huge file that was called
coll-eta sequel, or
information gathering tool,
that was like 16 megabytes.
So that tool is noisy as hell.
It just tries to get information
from every possible product
that Microsoft ever did,
starting from Windows like 3.11.
So after this,
they will get all that
information and exfiltrate it
but again, it's not a
mercenary group like Puppeteer.
It's more of shady business.
- It's like, unrequested, you know,
and then Santi look what I found.
- Yeah.
- You want me to keep it in secret?
No?
You want to pay?
- Yeah.
- You better pay.
So, but Santi, what can you
tell us about Satellite Link?
- Oh, well,
we are going to talk about
different groups as well.
There's going to be a mention
about Satellite Trula,
but in the case of Poseidon,
the common control server
was actually, and, and we,
we tried to single a couple of the domains
that were using for exfiltration
and we found one that was on a ship
in the middle of the ocean
so it was a hijack satellite connection.
So you can see that it
was pretty difficult
to track these guys and I
remember when we did this, the,
the first presentation of
Poseidon, I used a phrase,
I don't know if you saw the
movie Ferris Bureau's Day Off?
So life moves pretty fast.
If you don't stop once in
a while, you could miss it.
The same is for Poseidon.
If you miss it, that's it.
You will never find it again.
- And we, we were just joking, like, okay,
you got to take down that C2.
- Yeah.
- Like, and ship, you know,
like how to take down, you know.
Another one, Saguaro,
Saguaro comes from Mexico.
It's confirmed.
They also, they targeted mostly in Mexico,
but also many other countries.
Comparing, you know,
Mexico with like 3
million victims to others,
let's say tens of thousands,
tens of thousands is like 1%,
you know, but still, that
was like a huge, huge thing.
So they targeted companies,
stealing RDP accesses,
VPN connections,
certificates, email accesses,
mobile things, all sort
of, you know, everything,
everything they could steal.
and then it's about
commercialization, of course.
So here also with Saguaro
was something interesting.
You see sometimes when
they think about their RDP
and mapping those things, we
say, okay, initial access,
I don't know, right?
But they never use those accesses.
They just, they use it to resell it.
So it's RDP in this case, it's like,
what it should be like?
Impact?
Resell of RDP?
I don't know.
- Yeah.
It's like, oh, stealing like BTC wallets.
Yeah, that is the impact.
But how can we put it in the navigator?
So it's like, you know,
it's financial actually impact, right?
- Well,
and then we have global threat actors
operating in Latin America.
So this is, this is my meme time,
I try to, to do that
with this one. (chuckles)
So yes, you have some
operations with Lazarus
and we have a particular one
that we are going to speak about.
So this was like two or
three years ago, new,
they were targeting the bank
of Chile, Banco de Chile.
- It's public, it's public.
- Yeah, this is public.
I'm not, I'm not --
- We're not bringing shame to anyone here.
- Everything has been rehearsed. (laughs)
So this operation was
pretty known by Lazarus
but they were targeting
Chile and Mexico at the time.
So this was unexpected for such a group
that has so many aliases
and has done so many operations
but with the Banco de Chile,
what was interesting was the,
the resource development phase
and the reconnaissance phase.
So they would take a lot of
time to find the right victim
to start the spearfishing attack.
It's not like Machete or Poseidon
that they use secret documents
to lure their victims,
they just find the right guy
and Dima's going to speak about that.
- Yeah and that was through
LinkedIn, of course.
So basically they contact
one guy and they said,
hey, you want your dream job?
You know, like working
for a foreign company?
Sure, yes.
So just get our special
secure application.
You get to install it and run,
it will enable your VPN
connection to our servers
and that is the screenshot
of this, you know,
thing and the code, of course,
that executed malicious code and goodbye.
- And then we have finally,
we get to pronounce Mish-tah again.
So we have TA505.
This is also a financially
motivated actor.
I think that the most interesting
thing about TA 505 is the,
the Living Off the Land binary usage
and also their campaigns
related to CLOP and CLOP Leaks.
So we highlighted this and
this was the only group
that we could map with an impact.
So I think there is something also that,
for Latin American threat
actors, we couldn't find,
I still don't know why,
but it's open for conversation.
So if you need to, to do a
purple team engagement or,
or you need to emulate TA
505, LOLBAS is your friend.
Then cognitive biases, just
to wrap up our presentation,
of course, survivorship bias that we also,
that we always see the,
the things doesn't mean
that it's going to happen
every single time,
the same as the Monte Carlo
or the gambler's fallacy.
Please hold us accountable
of what have we done here
and check.
- Last but not least,
you see we don't have enough time
to present you about everything
that is happening in Latin America.
So things like Satellite
Turla targeting Chile,
a very interesting thing is not here.
Dark Tequila Anejo is not here.
Ransomware targeting hospitals,
now everybody is thinking,
okay, the, you know, it's now,
but it's not now.
First Brazilians started with
that, had started years ago,
xPan.
We're gonna, maybe like if
we're invited next time,
if we're accepted, we'll
present all of them.
- Next year!
- And something else also, Green Deer,
also very interesting
campaign, super unknown yet.
Also it's an outsource
campaign relying on,
looks to be a Chinese threat actor,
targeting Latin America on the name,
the country of one of the
countries of Latin America
on the name of the other country,
which got very much upset
because of a political decision,
you know, like playing all those things.
- And I'm a sucker for quotes
and I love this one because this is where,
what I remind myself before
working on our report.
"Tell me what, you know, then
tell me what you don't know,"
and this for me is the
most important thing.
We know a lot about Latin
American threat actors,
but of course we don't know what you know.
We don't know the gaps in our knowledge.
So again, hold us accountable
of everything we said here,
check the adjacent files
and thank you for your time
and attention.
- Yeah, thank you very
much and one more thing,
one more thing, the last thing.
Machete also goes ransomware.
The, I don't know for what,
they also use like an open source project
based on Python, it's on GitHub,
and I don't know if, if
they're gonna use it for,
let's say like a smoke screen
or it's like diversification
of business who knows, but --
- Emerging market.
- Yes, and thank you,
thank you very much again.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
(audience applauds)
- I'll get in the middle.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you so much and we
really looked forward for that
and like I said, yesterday was amazing.
We had a couple code drops.
Today we're getting Intel drops.
So fantastic.
Thank you for really, you know, being a,
you know, great contributors
to the community.
We have time for a couple questions
and I wanted to start with
one that we got from online
that was really awesome.
Barry Anderson, thank you.
The question was, since, you
know, as you mentioned some,
you know,
governments actually have
threat actors fund themselves,
do you think that, you know,
complicates or kind of muddles the,
the separation between economic operations
and nation state activity like that nexus?
How do you kind of perceive that?
- Well, Latin America,
it's always about improvisation
and sometimes it's cows,
like what's the plan?
We'll see.
It's like that is the difference
between like soccer players,
you know, in Europe,
okay, this is the plan,
like Germany team,
like we're gonna attack
this and, and in Lat Am,
it's like, okay, let's go
and play, enjoy it guys.
Woohoo.
(chuckles)
So it's same --
- It's very difficult for us to,
to separate financial
threat actors from APTs,
that fine line for us it's,
it's so hard because sometimes
these are financially
motivated actors but
also at the same time,
if they find something interesting,
they will take it just as a
leverage for the next victim.
So I don't know, for the moment
the answer is, I don't know.
- It gets back to what you
said earlier about context too.
- Yeah.
- You really have to immerse
yourself in understanding,
you know, what's the
motivation, what's the intent?
I see how a couple really eager faces.
So I definitely want to open
it up to the audience here,
if there's anyone that
has, oh, right here.
- Okay, so on the Ecuador, when the,
the hopping into the military state,
I just want know when you were
dealing with that situation,
since you had this high level
breach with the president,
and then you have it
going to the military,
how forthcoming were
the various departments
that handle those key
security problems in Ecuador
cooperating with you,
especially once you
were able to show, hey,
the camera is showing pictures.
- Yeah.
- Again, Latin America, it's
about people, it's humans.
It's talking.
You have your connections.
You just speak to the people
who say you got hacked, you see?
And then, and they also
share with you like, oh,
now I know why, like that day,
that month, they did do
like stupidity against,
like, oh, okay, we got
the, you know, the reason.
So yeah, it's basically
always like, you know, just --
- Yeah and it also that,
that case of the camera,
that was publicly accessible.
So we had that MITRE ATT&CK router
with the full credentials
but we didn't log in.
Just by using the same
IP and a different port,
it was just, you know,
the battalion of Ecuador
having their monitoring system
wide open for the internet,
that's not cool as well.
So of course we will
inform them. (chuckles)
- Yesterday we had Aspetta,
today Pesco, thank you so much.
(group laughs)
- Thank you, too.
Thank you very much.
(audience applauding)