so I'm going to present our way bear yet
and it is a joint walk with of a high
Queen Amina Hertzberg micra superior and
high achievement and this stock is very
focused on our pikia its deployment and
security properties so let me start with
clear and brief reminder of what are
wikia is so the resource public key
infrastructure or the RPK I'm marks
networking objects and specifically I'm
going to focus on IQ cliff excels to the
organizations that on them and avocado
is really intended to do two things so
the first one is to prevent critics and
subway fix hijacks and the second one is
to lay sort of later cryptographic
foundation for protection against most
sophisticated past manipulation attacks
on inter domain routing routing and
specifically it lays the cryptographic
foundation and the keying mechanisms
behind bgp set so let me just quickly
remind what prefix and suffix isaacs are
so assume we have 11 legitimate origin
44.6 AAS service plate 20 and that a yes
announces its perfect 90 120 / tan to a
sy so now asy lambs allowed to that to
the I galaxies within that basics and
send the traffic there and also falls
that advertisement on to ASX of course
appending its own identifier to go out
so now sx learn some out to destroy fix
but the attacker is a 666 announces the
same plastics so now sx had done two
outs and it needs to choose and let's
say that s excuse using the using the
shortest path ball so now we are sewn on
traffic flows to to a 666 instead of the
legitimate owner of the prefix to
demonstrates a perfect hijacks I've
moved a spy to date to the other side of
class so the residual toner still
announces explicit and it teaches ASX
and now as 666 announces a sub matrix of
that so it's less Sixteen and most
specific physics sy centex topic there
and also realize that to sx now s
excellence out to the plastics and out
to the statistics and traffic to the
subtopics follows the longest prefix
match all so in fact the path lengths
here does not matter and topic would
flow to the attacker so how does the RPI
prevent that well a pki certifies
ownership over IP prefixes so to do that
it assigns an IV perfect to a public key
for release or certificate or an LC and
and let for now let's assume that the
South Seas can be false and they are
epigraphic designed by someone who is
authorized to do so I'm going to
slightly talk about about the chain of
classf in lbk later on and then the
owner who owns the private key that
corresponds to the public key specified
in DLC can now sign allowed oh gee mr.
is a similar code hola which is then
published and its public domain so
everyone can know about it and the light
and the five identifies the a SS who are
authorized to advertise that specifics
in btp so going back to my example
perfect 90 10 / 10 actually belongs to
georgia telecom and and they were they
took the measures in order to protect
the physics so they got certified by
life the oath of tasks for the european
domain and they also use the users I'll
see to issue a while so now those are
that everyone should know about
protecting perfect 91 dot B of the
stands
and they are also specify the maximum
length which is the most specific
specific the Deutsche Telekom allows to
announce for this place fiction in this
case it is 10 so you only that
particular Pacific she is allowed and
the only origin that allow 20 to
announce it is a s33 20 so how can how
can this help to prevent prefix and
suffix I Jack's going back to my example
and now a sexy knows about this about
this sauce so it knows that the only
origin that's allowed to announce the
split fix is 32 33 20 and so it can
identify that their status prefix is
actually is actually the attackers
announcement is actually invalid and so
it can be scouted and traffic will flow
in the quest direction to sy and then to
the 2000s tomato owner at 3320 so so in
this talk i'm going to i'm going to
divide the remainder of this talk to
flip out so the first one is going to is
going to be about the obstacles facing
the deployment of rpki and i'm going to
start about talking insecure about
insecure deployments so really like any
other security mechanism it allows the
freedom of choice and you might you
might deploy it in an insecure manner
and specifically i'm going to talk about
what we call loose soils so consider
this similar to policy now where we have
the legitimate owner a.s.a and that
owner had advertised the war for its own
puppy so it has a war for it's less
Sixteen and you can see that the oils
maximum length allows precisely that
that idea that the Occupy seeks to be to
be published by a ese so what can our
attacker do well it can it could try to
circumvent the rpi defense and doing
that by by announcing of
so as I announcer that and our second
can consider convent the app you can
type to circumvent the applique defense
by sort of announcing announcing a false
path to a say-so in this case the
attacker sort of makes up a link to a SI
and and now this advertisement looks
valid according to the RBI because air
is the actual origin the specified in
the advertisement and and that's the
whole thing that's allowed by the RTI
the maximum length is not is valid and
so a sec receives that receive that
advertisement to and which way would it
go well it's likely to go with the
shorter path so still topic is likely to
flow in the correct direction and there
have been actually extensive studies
about that and the this attack is
actually called the one hop attack in
the in the paper that I'm citing and and
then it was shown to be much less
effective than the negative prefix
isaacs so I'm going to consider that as
sort of a windfall for the upper case so
that is a good thing that applique I can
achieve but now consider the case where
the maximum length is actually pretty
permissive so they say instead of saying
instead of fighting 16 as the maximum
length actually specifies 24 so now the
law is really loose the though our
allows for advertising / fixes that are
not being actually advertised by a SI
and well our attacker can take advantage
of that so it would carry the exact same
attack except instead of the / 16 inch
would say / 24 and that means according
to the longest prefix match all the
traffic will actually flow to the
attacker 666 so let me just say that
this attack is also mentioned in our c7
115 and one of the examples and there is
mentioned as sort of film and
that's less likely to be noticed but I
actually want to emphasize that this
attack is actually more likely to
succeed especially because they attack
is supper at six so just to wake up why
does this attack walk so we have the
attacker 666 and it claims to be a
neighbor of a SI but the rpi does not
provide any mechanism that allows to
make sure that this is valid SI does not
actually originate that the public that
the attackers targets especially fall so
though I is loose and but the always
looks and allows that and finally the
longest prefix match all and shows that
that's almost a issues the attackers the
hydrogen is actually going to get a
topic and this is regardless of where it
is located in the network so how common
are these insecure deployments well it
turns out they are pretty common so
around thirty percent of the prefixes
that I'll covered by Al pki are actually
sort of unprotected because of that and
about eighty-nine percent of the
prefixes with maximum length that's
louder than a terrific strength so
predictions that are taking advantage of
this maximum length property are
actually vulnerable so almost everyone
who's taken advantage of it and finally
I want to also point out that it
actually manifest some loud for vitals
so we've seen some really important
important organizations that have used a
very permissive length in their walls
and these vulnerabilities actually
should be solved on bgp sac is deployed
but we have a long time until then so
until until then we actually better not
issue loose soils and use the minimum
maximum length that's required so the
next thing that i want to talk about is
the human error factor and and it turns
out that in the rpi there are many other
mistake
that people have made and specifically
there are bad laws which caused between
calls legitimate perfect cells to appear
as invalid if you're doing also gene
validation according to the RPI and
specifically that might cause for
someone who is doing filtering to
disconnect from legitimate destinations
and there have been extensive
measurements about that so let me just
point out that out of the about six and
a half percent of the prefixes that I'll
cover that are announcing VDP and are
covered by the rpi about just over eight
percent are invalid and another almost
thirty percent of valid but actually
unprotected because of these loose soils
that I've shown you earlier so we've
also done a short survey short anonymous
survey for network operators in this
world and we've asked them what what is
the main concern regarding doing rpki
based audio notification in your network
and as you can see the very important
thing that that was pointed out is
actually being disconnected from from
destination so this is a too concerned
about about other carriers in practice
and so when we checked who who are the
organizations behind these bad laws and
so here on the plot you can see on the
x-axis the number of for issuance and on
the y-axis the faction of l's that that
is all cause and what we found was
actually some pretty good news because
it seems that only a few organizations
are actually have actually issued their
was causing most of the of the problems
so we actually view this is very good
news because some focused assault and
maybe some convincing for these guys
might improve the integrity of the
information in the RPI quite a bit and
the last thing that I want to talk about
in this part of the talk
inter-organizational dependency
so there are two inter-organizational
dependencies that the topic I sort of
encapsulate and the first one is the
download dependency which is a
dependency in issuing or so specifically
consider the following scenario there is
a regional there is an irr and now I are
who holds the certificate for the domain
they have allocated they have signed the
certificate and I'll see for some
provider with the / 8 and then that
provider and in the in the decades that
it has this this IP prefix it's all
parts of it to some customers now as
soon as that that provider issues goes
on an issue 04 its own IP prefix it
would make customer announcements that
are not covered by oils to actually
appear in value so so and the reason is
that these customers will now be
perceived as sort of subway flicks
hijackers although they are the
legitimate owners of the architrave
fixes so we've measured so for how many
so for how many terrific season and what
portion of the IP address space they
actually exist such dependencies and
what we've seen is again some good news
so this is not applied for a whole lot
of organizations and article pictures
and as you can see here most are not
actually dependent some bad news that
come with that is a does that action
that I'll actually dependent are really
important so you can see here again a
CDF and the x-axis discussed the number
of organizations the y-axis describes
the fraction of of them of download
dependencies either for prefixes or for
the IP address space and you can see
that really most of the dependent IP
address space belongs to just a few
organizations suggesting that the IP
address space is quite large
and and then the other side of these
dependencies is the dependency in
issuing a certificate so now consider
the following similar scenario we have
the same provider but now that provider
did not bother to get enough see so the
provider does not have an hour see but
and now he its customers want and join
the rpi so they want so they need and
i'll see except the provider does not
have and also I ski to sign their
location so this might be a deployment
practice a decline in problem in parties
especially in case that this chain
between the aisle who holds well seen in
this case and the customers is quite
long the customers might try to go to
the I I up to the aisle and get
certified directly it might be there
might be some challenges in partisan
doing that so this might be an issue so
we've also checked how many
organizations are actually up for
dependent and again some good news it
looks it looks like not that much so any
the allocation player is quite shallow
and again here the x-axis describes the
depth of the dependency and you can see
that for most does actually no
dependency so that's quite good so now
I'll talk about some of the some
mechanism that a system that we've been
to improve the information accuracy but
cause it in the LP ki and so our system
is called water and it has two sides to
it so one side is the web interface
that's available at well as the tog
which allows network operators to check
whether the whether the IP prefixes are
properly protected by us and if not why
not so if they have a loose one that
would indicate that if they if the s
number is wrong that would indicate that
and would say what today s number be and
also if they have a too short of a
maximum length for what for what at my
eyes
should be being announced it would it
would say that and say what would the
maximum length be and finally if you
consider the case that I've shown you
earlier of a provider issuing you're
causing this customer to be invalid well
in that case we would also indicate who
the provider might be and watch it and
when what sort of war do it issue that
causes the customers to be invalid now
the other side for for the water system
is a sort of an online and positive
notification system that allows network
operators about bad or loose laws and so
we periodically retrieve their eyes from
the rpi publication points and compare
them against the BGP advertisements that
let's be observed and so we identify and
we identify problems so in case of so in
case of eleuthera we would alert the
operator and cases bed was we would also
allow them and sometimes the actual
offender and victim are not the same
organization so in particular that
provider and customer cases I've shown
you in these cases we would email both
sides and the email has a pretty
descriptive description of the of the L
and indeed we will get some some
promising initial results so our emails
rate 168 victims and offenders and after
within a month we've checked what what
happened and about thirty percent
forty-two percent of this I also
actually fixed and this is a significant
ties which we believe is optimistic and
just to clarify some some of the
differences followed from from other
systems it is constantly monitoring so
it's not just upon registration that you
might get a lot and also it's not an
opt-in so we constantly monitor and we
are left whenever we see something
that's bad and so we are really advocate
the taller be
be adopted and adapted by most
significant and less academic body than
us and so for the so far my talk has
focused mostly about the information
that's publicly available in the FBI and
there was and now I'm going to shift a
bit to the other sides of the other side
of the rpki which is doing go out always
in validation so so I will show some
first measurements that we have
regarding doing girl toys invitation and
then I'm going to evaluate how good is
is our PTI about the origin validation
under partial deployment so let me first
explain a bit what it means to do our
origin validation according to the rpki
and this is likely repeats previous
talks but bear with me I'm sure you'd
find interesting so so now that use the
RPK I to do outdoors in validation or lv
the network administrator needs to set
up a local general purpose machine that
runs some software which syncs with the
rpi publication points so it gets the
LCS and oils from this publication point
and then it can it can actually by date
that the signatures are correct and for
those records that are that are fine it
would ke sort of a widely stores based
on these walls and then it would push
them to the outer to the routers within
the anonymous system within the
autonomous system so really you can as
you can see the changes to the routers
are really minor and this is a big
differentiator from bgp sec so lady made
you answer a lot of windows and actually
supporting lv and today and it tells a
very negligible overhead so almost any
aes anywhere can do our way
so this is a fairly good start for a new
security protocol so now we're
interested in knowing is it actually
being enforced so I will now show part
of our measurements which we check out
the which regard who is not doing Alvey
and specifically in order to gain some
empirical insights we actually use
invite advertisements that already exist
on the internet so unfortunately there
are a lot of those using the application
that surprises for our study and we
monitor those invite advertisements to
the past and the past that are observed
in the Bible a few sensors so this is a
completely passive study and let me just
point out the dozen can't be an ongoing
follow-up study which uses more advanced
active techniques so if you're
interested in that you might want to be
on the dog for that study when it
finishes so to our measurements so
consider the following topology where we
have two origins and each of them
advertiser's traffic that is invalid
according to the RBI now in in this set
of measurements with that I the tile
present we are focusing specifically on
the AES data are not doing filtering so
we only care about those that do not
discard invalid routes and to see who
the hooded guys are we simply observe
the route the invalid dog that the
invite advertisement steak and then we
can point out that all the ESS the three
ladies advertisements actually not doing
filtering according to the ArchiCAD so
what did we find well we found that at
least 80 out of the 100 largest ice
please do not do filtering according to
the RBI
and the reason that the time presenting
it focused results on this 100 largest I
space is a dual so both because for
these particular iced teas we can
actually see a lot of paths let's go
through it goes o them so using this
passive approach it's easier to learn
about them and the second one is as i'm
going to show you in the remainder of my
talk is that these guys turn out to be
very important for the security benefits
of WT i can provide so we've also asked
that in our survey do you apply applique
I based Altoid in validation and you can
see that the numbers pretty much confirm
what we've seen so about eighty-five
percent of M sub know about ten percent
have answered yes but too deep but only
to do prefer invalid out and and only
about five percent have indicated that
they use that in order to be scouting
invite the advertisements now let me
just talk about this this ten percent
was who are doing different friends well
it was shown that the purpose actually
does not help at all against a prefix
hijacks and because in that case you
would only be informed of one perfect so
Eddie you would be persuade you don't
have anything to do prefer it with and
so you think that the s would fall
victim to the attack and also in case
you only have one provider that
connected to the Internet well you might
only receive one advertisement and four
for the perfect and therefore again and
we would take it so so as we've seen
deployment of our way seems very
powerful and so now the question is how
good is our V under partial deployment
and what are the security benefits that
we might expect to get from it under
such deployment scenarios and we we
identify two interesting collateral
X so the first one is the collateral
benefit effect well where doctors might
be able to protect AES is behind them in
the internet apology just by discarding
invited out so consider this simple
topology so we have the attacker in the
attacker at a 666 and the legitimate
specific shown as a s1 and the the owner
has a row are published so so anyone who
is doing lv knows about this one and in
particular considered a two who is doing
lv and as3 who does not so so what's
going to happen when so let us assume
that the attacker tries to do a
soporific psychic well now the day is
doing lv @ as2 we will actually discard
that advertisement and so when their
origin advertiser's it to unclip fix the
/ 16 that that advertisement will reach
is 3 and therefore if a is only offered
the good route it will not be fooled and
will actually topic will actually flow
in the right direction so that is a
pretty good effect that accusing our V
might have now let me talk about the
collateral damage damaging in fact that
we've seen so the collateral damage
means that in our context means that a
esas who are not doing lv might actually
cause damage to a SS who are doing our V
so to demonstrate that I've swapped a SS
s 2 and s 3 so now a two the does not
adopt and there's not a from our v well
s3 does and the first type of collateral
damage attack show is this connection so
so by this connection let let us
consider the case where a is to actually
prefers to take out to other
love zombie attack you at 666 the other
than out from the origin and now let's
consider the case where the origin
announces its critics the select 16 and
the attacker performs a physics hi jack
well in that case aah two will actually
announce the bed love to as3 and since
s3 is performing there will be it will
know to discover this out and since it's
not being often offered any other of it
will be disconnected from the prefix one
dot 13 16 so in honor not adopting a
stew had actually caused a esli to
disconnect okay so you might say well
this connection is better than reaching
to the meeting the wrong the wrong guess
so i prefer i prefer not to send my
traffic at all then then actually having
it reached the wrong destination but
actually using our V and the partial
deployments might cause control plane
and data plan mismatch and and that
means well consider the same the exact
same scenario except now the attacker is
performing a start with exciting well
now a stool is to advertisements and
they are so different prefixes one is
for the / 16 and the other one is for
the / 24 and therefore it will followed
both of them to a spray now every doing
outdoor invalidation would know to
discard the attackers out and therefore
it would actually choose to take the
correct path when when sending traffic
to 21 dot one dot once that's 24 for so
for the subtopics but once the traffic
reaches as2 in a is too stable it
actually says the discuss 24 prefix
action needs to be output to the
attacker so since we don't have saw
something on the internet traffic will
actually flow or against the decision of
Si and reacted
attacker so the last thing that we that
we've done in this study is to quantify
this collateral damaging and collateral
benefit and effect and in order to do
that we've used the simulation framework
which takes the internet gas as well as
the installed relations between a SS and
the simulations work as follows so every
time we take one doctor and one big dumb
and we assume that the victim has
to protect its play fix and then we pick
some a doctor set a different one for
each type of simulations that we are
trying to do and I'll show you a few
later and then we evaluate which of the
AES is on the internet we choose to out
the traffic to the attacker and which to
the victim so that would give us the
attacker success rate which is sort of a
measure of how good alvey's under this
partial deployment and we repeat that
for about a 4 million victim and attack
hotels so so first off let me start by
by saying by quantifying the security
benefits that we gain by having the top
I speed adopt so by top I space i mean
the the I speeds on the internets
ordered by the number of clients that
they have and and here you can see two
lines so the green line means that every
isp adopts with probability every top is
period of the probability 1 while the
red line means that every top i speared
of the probability one quarter the x
axis means the expected deployment so in
order to compare these two lines we
really wanted to have the same size of
deployment so if you take the 100 point
for example for the green line that
means that all the 100
tapai speeds have adopted Alby was for
the red line it means that out of the
top 400 so not 100 412 I squeeze each
one of them had adopted with probability
one quarter and so these these two
deployment sets are expected to be equal
yet as you can see the significant
difference between them so while having
a 25-percent a dachshund right by the
top I space does not substantially harm
that mitigate the attackers the attack
while the subway fixed attack is almost
completely mitigated when the top 100 I
squeeze adopt for the subtopics hijack
you can see the same the same time so
really again the red line well in this
case almost does not move this is
precisely because of that collateral
damaging effect while the what the Green
Line shows that the attack is the
meanest now in there we have an online
technical report the technical report
has has some more details about these
these simulations that also includes
some all data points so and so you can
see that it's about 75% the doc tonight
this gets very close to the green line
while the fifty percent will still
pretty close to the red line so and then
the last simulations that i want to show
you compare between between two
scenarios so one is today's status as
reflected by all measurements that's the
that's the red line and that means that
a yes is that do not adopt that we found
that are not doing our V filtering
continue not to do that and while the
green line suggest that all the top ice
please start doing our be the x axis
describes now the adoption rate of our
weakest link in the reminder of the
intern
so x axis as one means that actually
everyone everyone we don't know to not
do I will be start doing our way and and
so you can see the tremendous effect of
this collateral damage so for the subway
fix hijack even if everyone adopt it
seems that a substantial amount of the
internet would still get full and and
all the traffic to the wrong direction
because of the collateral damaging
effect caused by by these co I space who
we found to not perform filtering now
the rain the grain line on the other
hand is actually quite optimistic it
shows that if we just get this one
hundred guys to adopt what that means
that the death occurred success rate is
rather low and it continues to diminish
until 04 that attackers more and more
asos adult so really it seems like
adoption by the top 100 I Spears or by
the course the Internet can make a huge
difference and the bottom line that I
really want to emphasize for these
simulations is that it seems that
enforcement by the top I speeds is both
necessary and very importantly also
sufficient to provide some substantial
security benefit from the RPK I so I
actually view this is some very good
news because that means that if we that
focused effort and instant dividing
incentivizing these guys to adopt might
actually provide some critical benefits
so let me just conclude my talk so I
vice to issues regarding the RBI one is
information accuracy and to address that
we presented wallet which informs an
alert operators about that was loose
laws and inter organizational
dependencies and also I've talked about
ways we can use the rpi to
to prevent hijacks better and we found
that incentivizing our V adoption by the
top I space is actually very critical
and is both sufficient and necessary for
significant benefits so with that I'll
conclude my talk and thank you ludia
fort dodge telecom thanks for such
thanks for using real life examples out
of our RP ki could you please go back to
the previous slide this one done yes
that one ah okay so on the loose rollers
I wanted to make a little bit of remarks
i was around and in the room when the
max length was kind of inserted the
previous design of a protocol had a
single bit instead of it and that was
obviously much worse because that
enables accept all more specifics
specifics i guess you can agree that
that would have been a really bad idea i
certainly agree okay so kind of i think
the argument why injecting the next
length instead of asking people to
enumerate exactly what they want to
announce was based on the experience
with customers that we asked to actually
do in our psl exact enumerate exact
registration of all the routes they
wanted to announce and well okay some
operators actually are pretty rigid on
it
and we probably belong there but we know
that it's painful and kind of the idea
of giving people who really want to be a
little bit lazy on the choice of making
them more vulnerable for the form for
for having a little bit more comfort in
doing the registry this theme did seem
kind of very very much justified in the
real world and I'm quite sure and quite
sure that hole however the education to
this and explaining if you do the robot
for things you are not intending to
actually announce you are creating
vulnerability are probably has to be
emphasized more so thank you for this
comment I actually love to continue
talking maybe offline about this max
length property you we actually have
some follow-up work on that and enough
to get a opening I think for the inter
orc stuff that you mentioned i note i
note that the design of the rpki kinds
of mirrors pretty precisely the theory
of how the Internet addresses are
allocated assigned and assigned and it
seems kind of the only reasonable
approach to keep that matching however
are the parts of the rpki system that
allowed allegation that essentially
matches the delegation of the address
space is not really used a lot actually
right from the bottom it's not you right
from the from the top of the delegation
three it's not used and for the lower
layers there are only very few
example of delegation and there are
quite obviously there are quite
obviously some challenges of doing that
and then of course there is a lot of
legacy problems not many operators have
had have held a policy that for their ph
scale actually portable assignments to
customers cannot be done most people
have some legacy there and cleaning and
dealing with that is just a pain so so
let me just say that I think that there
is room for improvement in doing that so
of course as you can see our
measurements indicate that the problem
is not that big the tree is quite
shallow as you point out I do think that
there is room for for improvements in
the oil so in particular our research
paper also suggests and you think called
the wild card wall that might be able to
completely remove this download
dependencies that I've told you about
I'd be very happy to talk about that
viewing the bike okay okay so let's go
thank you map it back yahoo would
hopefully an easy question what is the
top 100 ISPs how did you define us oh ok
so we've simply we've simply looked at
the i squeezing the internet apologies
so kayla has this in fairies
installations topology and then the sort
of in spelling who is the customer of
whom on the internet so take it so given
this huge list of all the essence we've
sorted them by the number of customers
that ejs has and the top 100 of that
list are basically the team what size
the customer just the number of customer
the number of customers
that so so a customer with massive
prefix blocks that's only one customer
gets counted the same as somebody within
these tiny prefix in our account yes ah
thank you for that clarification of it
sandy Murphy Parsons could you go to the
slides which the pie chart yeah oh sorry
well yes probably if I've read that pie
chart right and then there's like
sixteen percent of the people who
responded said they employed our ppi in
some fashion they worked their names I
want their home telephone number well
okay so I believe this this result as we
also pointed out in the technical report
is quite optimistic and that is because
the the people who are likely to respond
and the people who were likely to be on
the mailing list and fall so big that
they were live they were closing they
types on keyboard well excellent
actually I cannot give you the names
because the thing is completely
anonymous but I'm very happy that you
find this optimistic tile and we also
find some evidence that there are some
people who are doing lv you can read
those paper about that ok I'll somewhat
in joke but it is interesting that their
actions were positive responses let's
see about your intro organizational
dependencies and finding out that people
find rowers that disenfranchised their
customers yes it has been a noted
problem for many times at least two
implementations right Pendragon research
labs when when
ifp is signing the raw i will say and
you know the chair is validating the
following route from the routing table
and maybe you want to rethink them so
yeah the human error does come into into
play your collateral damage slides you
were talking about the one doing origin
validation that only gets bad routes
will be disconnected but it's being
disconnected from the attacker if it
wasn't doing the origin validation it
wouldn't the traffic wouldn't be getting
were wanted to be getting any way
exactly so I I tried to say that so if
the if a is too in that example was
actually doing yeah so if it was doing
then that damage which would have been
avoided the damage is actually in a stew
not doing that yes and yes the second
thing is the second collateral damage
was because the control plane of the
data plane were not in sync and hand to
those who thought that was a surprise
it's kind of a well-known problem and ok
the final thing is there's a quote in
your paper that I've seen that at the
same title you say you expose a new
security vulnerability I would you like
to say most emphatically this is not a
security vulnerability in rpki and it's
not a secure attivo her ability in
origin validation it's a Miss
configuration by the operator well known
mentioned in the ops documents you
quoted the ops document it's something
that's been known for a long time
perhaps a bit of an overstatement to say
you expose a new security vulnerability
or four of those things are
yeah the ops document is about five
years old okay well okay thank you for
that okay so what I'm sorry google that
might kind of be following on from what
sandy says because i didn't really
coordinate with her but you sort of
mentioned this RC 7115 sort of vaguely
mentions the blue stroller things the
are 7-1 on five specifically actually
points out if you do this you're going
to be shooting yourself in the foot and
this the operator actually asked for
that don't generate the longer prefix so
yes that's information that people met
but you know to some extent if you give
people a powerful tool they will shoot
themselves in the foot until they learn
that that hook and then hopefully
they'll start well the RC actually
mentions that and says specifically that
this attack is you to open your search
to an attack that's more likely to be
sort of going out under the radar I
think it's very important to emphasize
that this is actually more likely to
succeed as well I can suspect you might
have but I think I wrote some of the
text okay i don't understood that it
says that it's more likely to be note or
what made two days maybe it wasn't clear
is that if somebody manages to hijack
the 16 that will be more likely to be
noticed mum or that that wasn't written
very well i think that's the way it is
yep freedom list ha and yes RFC 7115
indeed makes that very clear if you have
a flash point again and the / 24 and you
should essentially you only announced
those two and no other more specifics
you should be clearly states that you
should try and ish
separate rollers for them that will
provide the maximum protection from this
forged origin attack my other question
is when you do the collateral damage
studies you could do a sensitive and a
sensitivity analysis with regard to the
discard policy so you can you can have
two cases one you prefer invalid and the
other one you discarded when I didn't
look like it in the river invalid steady
video so know that this entire study
actually focuses on the owner discard
invalid so what would happen if you
would do this card invalid yes yes I was
just suggesting that there to make it
compile it might be useful to do a
sensitivity sensitivity analysis
consider both cases what happens if you
have it d prep yeah i agree we probably
should should do that I think the reason
we sort of didn't is because of this
beeper spell invalid would actually be
completely vulnerable to satwiksai Jax
and I think when we've done that we've
we've chosen because of that we've
chosen to focus but I I definitely agree
so it is interesting to to show I just
want to say just so we're going to close
the mics literally the last questions
they can get into the breakfast okay Lou
you go Fort Dodge telecom again so let
me close with a rare kind of positive
comment from me your your idea of
monitoring and reporting on what's out
there quite certainly is heading in a
direction where we need to do a little
bit more of work for me I have to say I
didn't respond to you guys sending our
operations a report at some point in
time
hell well okay I didn't see much of an
advancement beyond what the ripe NCC is
giving me daily but kind of I'm seeing
I'm seeing actually a reason for diving
a little bit deeper into what we
actually should take as a requirement
for monitoring and reporting I think I
think I think there is actually a little
bit more to be done and to make it an
important part of the overall
infrastructure well so thank thank you
for pointing and going into this
direction I think I think I think there
is a little bit more work well thank you
very much for this comment yes we we are
at the end of the day an academic team
and we definitely believe that there is
much more to be done in that system and
in that area