her next lightning talk of job Snyder
presenting on
indication thank you my name is joke
Snyder's I work for ntt communications
and I'm here today to share with you
some work we've been doing over the last
few months to make your operational
lives easier and we will specifically
focus on the aspect of communication
between ebgp neighbors all of us have
ebgp sessions and these sessions can be
considered the wire between two tin cans
and although it is beautiful that we can
pronounce announcements from our site
through your site or vice versa there
are a few tiny things that are lacking
for instance if I'm not entirely sure
who is on the other side of the wire and
that could easily happen at public
internet exchanges or because parts of
your administration were lost ten years
ago when you migrated from this database
to that database so we're left with very
few actual communication mechanisms
between ebgp neighbors one thing you
could do is you could slap the session
or use optical signals like their peer
are you there what's up Mike oh I'm joke
oh
what do you think of the game last
Sunday and then if the other guys hold
silence then either he did it like the
game or there some issue between the two
of you technical issue and this
especially becomes apparent with
maintenance we announced to our
customers dear customer two weeks from
now will reboot this device there will
be 30 minutes of downtime this is the
tracking ID this is where you can call
into the knock and etc and then two
weeks later when the session actually
goes down customers will email the knock
and and be like why is the session down
dude and then you show them the
notification you set them two weeks
prior they're like oh oh I forgot to add
that to my calendar invites first time
this happens as well we get maintenance
notifications from other peers and we
are not always as disciplined as we
should be in that regard so to enhance
this specific aspect of BHP operations I
and two of my friends we we dove into
the ITF nerd to extent the beach p
protocol in such a way that when you
shut down a beach p session you can drop
a tiny message in the pierce syslog or
whatever mechanism he uses and the way
this works is in the beach p protocol
you have a cease notification and this
is the message that is sent to the
neighbor when the session is about to go
down and it sees notification as a crude
extensibility in that you can just
append data through that message and in
some versions of the seas notification
this is used to for instance indicate
some information about y MX prefix
limitless trips or what caused the
problem and what we've done here is
we've extended the shutdown event and
the reset agent that you can have up to
128 bytes worth of communication message
in that particular beach p message and
this is really neat because it built
upon an existing BGP message type so
from a protocol design perspective it's
kind of it's a small change is we're not
we're not changing beach p in a
significant way it is backwards
compatible in the sense that existing
speakers will not act weird when they
receive this data because the session
was going down anyway so that's that's
all quite nice and what this looks like
I'm for instance openbsd will already
support this I can just type on the
command line this neighbor needs to be
disabled and I can append that short
message for instance this is the ticket
ID we're upgrading and we'll be back in
30 minutes and what that would look like
on the receiving side is you have the
syslog message that says hey the session
is now down and next to that is a
message that contains my shut down
communication which I sensitive specific
here and this I think will greatly
enhance our operations in the peering
world this is maybe what it could look
like on juniper or on cisco iOS XR when
you clear a session maybe this is what
it will look like so if we look at
implementation the ITF still has that
attitude that put your coat where your
mouth is and then you can progress
things through the ITF much easier then
if you have nothing to show for so
openbsd has this implemented go bgp TMX
the traffic analyzed engine X a BGP as
it and there are decoders for Wireshark
and tcpdump available for protocol
designers to debug this particular
extension to the beach p protocol and
i've heard positive feedback from birth
a famous route surfer application
cisco iOS XR has showed some interest
the Juniper people have showed some
interest and from Nokia as well Eifert
positive feedback so this doesn't mean
they will actually build it this means
you need to email your account managers
point them to this presentation and say
their account manager could you please
implement this feature because it looks
useful to me and the people in sight
these organizations these vendors if
they receive from multiple customers
feedback that this is actually useful it
will be prioritized and maybe later this
year will receive these features or and
if not none of you email into the
account managers then perhaps it's 2018
2019 or maybe it will never happen so it
really depends on you guys email your
account managers and of course because
it's 2017 and there's a whole world
outside North America that does not use
the clean 7-bit ascii stuff it will
support utf-8 and does Unicode that
doesn't mean that your router will
actually display these emojis but for
instance X a BGP actually shows the
emojis so that's kind of cool but you
know of course we'll only use this tool
in a very professional and serious
manner and then you know use ticket IDs
and operationally relevant information
and so the shutdown communication it is
128 bytes max this is to prevent visual
spoofing because it would be kind of
annoying it's half your syslog turned
out to be there's one shut down
communication message from a malicious
actor by keeping the message short I
believe will make it more easier to
grukk for our operations
that's it are there any questions
a couple years ago two thousand nine or
so who are you oh my Lenny Giuliano
juniper there was a draft that was
similar to this bgp administrative
information something like that where
you could just send text any text google
perhaps mean the advisory dress yes
that's it and I successor the
operational message draft yeah you know
I didn't see that but is this a similar
idea just at shut down time or whatever
happened to that there certainly are
similarities between the two efforts
however this one has more
implementations so that's useful and it
doesn't define a new VP message type and
I think that by introducing a new BGP
message type in the eye dr worker group
idea is responsible for the bgp protocol
it it's kind of hard to sell such a big
modifications to the protocol and this
beach p shut down communication it just
really finds existing positions in the
the protocol so to speak so from a
protocol design perspective this is like
a tiny change whereas the other efforts
were very big chunks of work that filter
get consensus and momentum but in a way
they are similar this extension only
works at shut down time or recess which
i figure would be the starting point
because that's where you need that
additional information most clearly
crystal field sales force I came to ask
and was exactly the same question what
which was this is obviously tied to a
shutdown is there any perceived
usefulness to having a free-form message
type that is outside of a BGP shutdown
event it is certainly worth discussing
I've been in touch with the offers of
the
a price redraft that will start at
almost ten years ago the intent is that
we first finish this work and if there
is if this doesn't address all our
operational needs then we'll attempt to
formulate a way to send a message while
the session is up and not down but we
flip the two efforts in that regard as
say risk distribution yeah this
definitely appears to be lower hanging
fruit and excellent progress thank you
alright by tying us up goodbye