our next lightning talk is job Snyder
presenting on BGP shut
munication thank you my name is Jobe
Snider's I work for NTT communications
and I'm here today to share with you
some work we've been doing over the last
few months to make your operational
lives easier
and we will specifically focus on the
aspect of communication between ebgp
neighbors all of us have ebgp sessions
and these sessions can be considered the
wire between two tin cans and although
it is beautiful that we can pronounce
route announcements from our site to
your site or vice versa there are a few
tiny things that are lacking for
instance if I'm not entirely sure who is
on the other side of the wire and that
could easily happen at public internet
exchanges or because parts of your
administration were lost 10 years ago
when you migrated from this database to
that database so we're left with very
few actual communication mechanisms
between ebgp neighbors one thing you
could do is you could flap the session
or use optical signals like there appear
are you there what's up Mike
oh I'm job Oh
what do you think of the game last
Sunday and then if the other guy falls
silenced and either he didn't like the
game or there's some issue between the
two of you technical issue and this
especially becomes apparent with
maintenance we announced to our
customers dear customer two weeks from
now we'll reboot this device there will
be 30 minutes of downtime this is the
tracking ID this is where it can call
into the NOC and and etc and then two
weeks later when the session actually
goes down customers will email the NOC
and and be like why is the session down
dude and then you show them the
notification you set them two weeks
prior they're like oh I forgot to add
that to my calendar and vice versa this
happens as well we get maintenance
notifications from other peers and we
are not always as disciplined as we
should be in that regard so to enhance
this specific aspect of BHP operations I
am two of my friends we we dove into the
ITF nerd to extend the Beach P protocol
in such a way that when you shut down a
BGP session you can drop a tiny message
in the Pierce syslog or whatever
mechanism he uses and the way this works
is in the BGP protocol you have a cease
notification and this is the message
that is sent to the neighbor when the
session is about to go down and the C's
notification has a crude extensibility
in that you can just append data to that
message and in some versions of the C's
notification this is used to for
instance indicate some information about
why MX prefix limit was tripped or or
what caused the problem and what we've
done here is we've extended the shutdown
event and the reset event that you can
have up to 128 bytes worth of
communication message
in that particular BGP message and this
is really neat because it builds upon an
existing BGP message type so from a
protocol design perspective it's kind of
it's a small change it's we're not we're
not changing BGP in a significant way it
is backwards compatible in the sense
that existing speakers will not act
weird when they receive this data
because the session was going down
anyway
so that's that's all quite nice and what
this looks like on for instance OpenBSD
who already support this I can just type
on the command line this neighbor needs
to be disabled and I can append that
short message for instance this is the
ticket ID we're upgrading and we'll be
back in 30 minutes and what that would
look like on the receiving side is you
have the syslog message that says hey
the session is now down and next to that
is a message that contains my shutdown
communication which I sent to that
specific peer and this I think will
greatly enhance our operations in in the
peering world this is maybe what it
could look like on juniper or on Cisco
IOS
XR when you clear session maybe this is
what it will look like so if we look at
implementations the ITF still has that
attitude that put your code where your
mouth is and then you can progress
things through the ITF much easier then
if you have nothing to show for so
OpenBSD has this implemented go bgp PM
act the traffic analyze engine acts a
BGP as it and there are decoders for
Wireshark and tcpdump
available for protocol designers to
debug this particular extension to the
bgp protocol and i've heard positive
feedback from birds a famous route
surfer application
Cisco IOS XR has showed some interest
the juniper people have showed some
interest and from Nokia as well I've
heard positive feedback so this doesn't
mean they will actually build it this
means you need to email your account
managers point them to this presentation
and say their account manager
could you please implement this feature
because it looks useful to me and the
people inside these organizations these
vendors if they receive from multiple
customers feedback that this is actually
useful it will be prioritized and maybe
later this year we'll receive these
features or and if not none of you email
into the account managers then perhaps
it's 2018 2019 or maybe it will never
happen so it really depends on you guys
email your account managers and of
course because it's 2017 and there's a
whole world outside North America that
does not use the clean 7-bit ascii stuff
it will support utf-8 and does Unicode
that doesn't mean that your router will
actually display these emojis but for
instance X a BGP actually shows the
emojis so that's kind of cool but you
know of course we'll only use this tool
in a very professional and serious
manner and you know use ticket IDs and
operationally relevant information so
the shutdown communication it is 128
bytes max this is to prevent visual
spoofing because it would be kind of
annoying if half your syslog turned out
to be this one
shutdown communication message from a
malicious actor by keeping the message
short I believe will make it more easier
to grukk for our operations that's it
are there any questions
a couple years ago 2009 or so who are
you oh my
Lenny Giuliano juniper there was a
draught that was similar to this BGP
administrative information something
like that
where you could just send text any text
do you perhaps mean the advisory dress
yes that's it and its successor the
operational message draft yeah you know
I didn't see that but is this a similar
idea just that at shutdown time or
whatever happened to that there
certainly are similarities between the
two efforts however this one has more
implementations so that's useful and it
doesn't define a new bgp message type
and I think that by introducing a new
BGP message type in the ID our working
group ID are is responsible for the BGP
protocol it it's kind of hard to sell
such a big modification to the protocol
and this Beach be shut down
communication it just redefines existing
positions in the the protocol so to
speak so from a protocol design
perspective this is like a tiny change
whereas the other efforts were very big
chunks of work that fill to get
consensus and momentum but in a way they
are similar this extension only works at
shutdown time or reset which I figure
would be the starting point because
that's where you need that additional
information most clearly Chris will
field Salesforce I came to ask him was
exactly the same question what which was
this is obviously tied to a shutdown is
there any perceived usefulness to having
a free-form message type that is outside
of a bgp shutdown event it is certainly
worth discussing I've been in touch with
the office of the advisory draft
that will start at almost 10 years ago
the intent is that we first finish this
work and if there's if this doesn't
address all our operational needs then
we'll attempt to formulate a way to send
a message while the session is up and
not down but we've split the two efforts
in that regard as say risk distribution
yeah this this definitely appears to be
lower hanging fruit and excellent
progress thank you all right my time is
up
good bye