yeah hey everybody good morning as Jesse
said my name is Ron windward I am
security evangelist for the Americas for
radler and before joining rad where I
was at server central and n layer for a
long time and prior to that data side of
select business so we are going to talk
today about about mirai I'm not a Mariah
researcher or I'm not actually in the
research function at all or adware but
Mariah as one of my researchers said
became the celebrity of botnets
so you know a lot of us are aware of it
obviously with what happened in the news
and so I wanted to say you know look at
the attributes that everybody says if
you can self install it and anybody can
set it up and run it and there's this
whole inspectable thing of IOT devices
that we can just gain access to and take
under control and I was interested in
that so let's look at this as maybe one
man's study of Mirai I wanted to focus
specifically on the network attacks
because as a networker that was
interesting to me what it's doing to our
networks and maybe look at how we can
prepare for for some of these so again
what this is this is looking at the
structure itself the components the
attack vectors that are included in code
with a focus on the network attributes
this is not a code review I'm not a code
guy and this is not a how-to guide you
know I'll talk a little bit about some
of the steps that I took to get things
up and running but you know it's that's
not what we're going to focus on today
so just a we have to kind of start out
with a quick recap you know the end of
September the threat actor named Nana
senpai released posted on hacked forums
net about what was happening hey
everybody here is my botnet you might
have heard about it with the Krebs
attack and
the recent news on getting out of the
business here's my code and a lot of
people were interested in that a
immediate the immediate response is why
would somebody do this and you know the
obvious answer is probably attribution
is if everybody has the code then not
one person can be you know easily tied
to the code but Brian Krebs has has a
theory too of who this is so some users
were doubting the authenticity of this
person but you know it's the the person
on hack form has has pretty good
reputation and you know has a strong
history of who they are so perhaps this
is a pretty cool animation designed by
my colleague Pascal Gaiman's in in he's
my counterpart in the AMIA region but
it's a good display of how this all
happens so a threat actor and a senpai
or perhaps somebody that looks like
Walter White Eisenberg character if you
familiar with that sets up a scan
listing server and a command and control
server and that's how this all really
starts in there there can be many
different physical servers or this can
be distributed across them but these are
the two main components on the CNC
server you can launch the actual first
bot he has a little bit of a different
behavior than the infected boss but this
is the guy who is going to start the
chain reaction right so then once the
bot is infected the bonded immediately
and I'll show examples of this starts
his own scanning port scanning on 23 and
23 23 trying to find immediate hosts
that he can an insect and if he finds
one as we can see this guy on the bottom
right he reports to the scam listen
server and he reports what IP addresses
worked
now what credentials worked and then the
scan listen server says is this is this
guy something I know about if he is
don't worry about him if he isn't I'm
going to start the loader now the loader
is going to start loading code
initiating commands onto the bot bot
gets infected process continues he
reports back to CMC and continues
port scans and and brute forces now
there's another interesting attribute to
this and that is adding access to the
botnet so somebody says a guy who owns
the botnet I will pay you for access to
your botnet or maybe it's the other way
around but there's a monetary ability to
lease these and in fact there you can
assign resources and in fact set up an
API to control it as well so that's a
high-level overview we're going to get
into the guts of it today this is you
know I talked about the brute force
login attempts that happen out of the
box were out of the straight code which
you can download on github there are 60
default username and passwords that are
available at here and this is just a
blow-up of some of these this is
completely configurable you can add your
own you can you can do whatever you'd
like with these there are nine attack
vectors that are out of the box one of
them is commented out and one of them is
broken ten maybe and we're going to go
through all of these that that that are
included most interesting to me and I
think had a lot of notoriety in the
recent attacks the DNS water torture
this is a one that I have experience
with before joining radware even I was
defending and it's it's a pretty
interesting attack I I enjoyed this
process of discovery because I learned a
whole lot more about it but I think this
was highly involved in in the DNS
attacks that we saw you know against our
friends with AD dine there are some
interesting as I was diving through the
code there are some interesting things
that are in here we'll call them Easter
eggs I was going through this and here's
something called a safe string so
obviously it's the URL I want to go in
and see what this is
rickroll so thank you added senpai
the other thing that was up here of
pretty neat if you plug this the prompt
into Google Translate and it says I love
chicken nuggets you can really have to
say anything you want but I thought it
was a little bit funny so this is my lab
architecture and you know don't pay so
much attention to the tiny little IP
addresses that are in here I can get
this to you or if this is being recorded
I believe so you could probably pause
this if you want to see some of this but
my my lab network basically what I have
here is my just an Internet router here
and I had this segmented off so this is
my test router here I set up a couple
bm's in ESX I'm one of them is kind of a
bastion host the utility host he gives
me screen access to you know to run
screen and and and access the other
hosts he's serving files locally form a
script you know that kind of thing
because so much of this is based on DNS
I wanted and I wanted to keep it
internally I set up my own bind server
as well on the network so that and I
gave it a management interface and a
test or a lab interface so that I served
us locally and give it updates and
anything that also needed real queries I
could I could do that too
but most importantly the command and
control server is is on here
he's running on a very lightweight VM
running on Debian also the scan listen
server he's running on Debian as well
and these guys are contained in a VM now
one thing I found is that when we're
running them in a VM and you're using
the initial bot that comes as part of or
that you can launch from the command and
control server you can fill your upload
capacity here so you know we we look to
things that are outside of the yet the
VM because maybe we lose access to all
these other things but another thing I
thought was that I'm going to set up
another IOT bot out here and put him on
one 92168 to slash
for this guy bought to was a raspberry
pie and he's just running raspbian I
wanted to see what would happen with him
and then here's one I - 1 6 8 3 is my
attack network so I have a actually I
put a link this up here because and I'll
talk about this in a little bit but he's
just there I haven't actually plugged in
on the land side of this for a couple
reasons
he's serving DHCP he's serving DNS -
anything that is offering DHCP I had my
cameras here so I'll talk about this
guys and then the target that I was
attacking he's just a bomb to machine
run and get Apache and he's also doing
some packet sniffing for me as well so
that's what it looks like as part of the
code as you see I was doing 1918 space
by default the code blocks a lot of
these these prefixes and here are the
ones that is edit blocks most of these
are not announced some of them are now
announced but as we can see you know in
the blue line my 1918 space is being
excluded by scans so obviously I had to
make some changes there these bottom
guys are DoD networks why are some of
these excluded I would my first guess is
that these are a lot of prefixes to scan
if they're not announced why waste the
scanning resources on the box right
there's some other interesting ideas
specifically with these ones that are
not announced you know why would you
want that and would you want to make
sure that these aren't being scanned
maybe you excluded from the code so
anyway so I changed my code so in the
code here I have basically gone and said
for all of these oh one is like first
octet so skip you know I've omitted a
lot of these for my screenshots that
skip 1 91 91 and then I have to drill
down to basically say I only want you to
scan 192 168 3/24 and the reason for
that is I don't have I didn't want to
let it just scan all these things that I
wasn't interested in right components of
the bot we have a lot of different
processes that we have to start
the initial bot as we start it we have
to enable some code we have to comment
out something in code that says I'm
going to allow you to be a bot but I
also want you to start the scanning
process so I've done that in this
example here we can see that the
scanning process started and then this
is what the scanning process looks like
so very quickly I've got all of these IP
addresses that I'm scanning from in this
case my bot one 92168 214 and as you can
see he's scanning all of these IPS with
23 and here's an example of 23 23
so immediately out of the box he's he's
begun his process so once he finds
somebody here's an example of the bot
finding an IP address 192 168 3.2 which
in this case was my was my Linksys
running tomato he tries to login right
so we can see examples based from that
list of 60 user and passwords here's my
username I try here's my password here's
my username password username password
rude no password so he tried the the
brute process this without timestamps
looks like it's a quick thing it's
actually not a quick thing and it's very
random so I would have thought
immediately that the bot once it found
something he would just target and poked
and poked and poked and poked and poked
that doesn't seem to be the case you
might try one and then it might not hit
that note again for another five minutes
and try another password so it's kind of
a random process it seems to be anyway
when I was running it I found out this
is going to take some time and then I
thought well if you have a hundred
thousand BOTS doing this you're maybe a
little bit more efficient even if it's
not you know one bot you know truly
brooding you know the target I didn't do
too much with this but this is the scan
listen process which which you have to
start you listen default on TTP 48 101
and this is the guy who's listening for
the reporting of what's working out in
the net
work as a loader process I will give
another good example of this that I'm
forcing but the loader process whose job
is just keep track of the bots loading
so you can see in here how are things
loaded and I'll give you examples of
this the two primary ways or W guests
from the bot itself and then TFTP as
well and it allows for piping in a list
of IP addresses to the to the loading
process so that's how I'd made and we
did this stuff so I talked about my
Linksys so as I'm setting this up I'm
thinking this is a botnet it infects
everything this shouldn't be too hard
right so I'm thinking back I remembered
I had a Linksys at home in the basement
and I remembered that these wrt54g s
they run some Linux and then I thought
while they're probably running busybox
to remember that Moriah and sex busybox
so sure enough I get into this guy and I
take a look and I log in and you can see
he's running tomato and he's running
busybox and I'm thinking this is going
to be great right not the case I think
the reason for this is the binaries and
the architecture code that is included
with these guys I don't think I think
that this guy has a Broadcom chip and I
don't think that that the code includes
these but I also found in other examples
that this isn't as easy as it initially
sounds so I'm thinking okay well this is
an ifc botnet camera a camera botnet so
i go to Amazon and I quickly order one
of the cameras that it looks cheap and I
think is one of the names that is
potentially included didn't work so I'm
thinking alright well what I can
probably do is go to micro Center and
get a they got cameras there so I'll go
there I got one there didn't work
another one didn't work so for what it's
worth not everything is infected but I
found one here is a 3 km AP 0 0 3 I
forgetting about my blind look I just
went to actually find one that
it was a known issue so this is the guy
that I got he is as you can see here's
an end map of the of the services that
are running on here I'm most interested
in telnet obviously so I tell net into
him and I see knowing what the user name
and password are that I can get into him
and he runs busybox I'm thinking great
I've got my guy here and in fact I did
he was he was the bot that I used for my
the IOT bot that I used for the rest of
the study so I gave an example of the
loader earlier this is where I'm doing
the infection process of the device and
this was actually very useful to be able
to cat in IP addresses and known
credentials of a to pipe in a addresses
and known credentials of the box that I
wanted to focus on what I'm showing here
is that in the loader process I start
nothing's logging in Athens logging in
okay now I've got one login and if this
was an overall loader process I could
see that I've got 20,000 logins here you
know and I could see that right now I'm
running one TFTP process I'm running no
W guests but what was interesting to me
with this was that I had to do TFTP
which I didn't think about out of the
box or I didn't think about right away
because the busybox
client that was running on the camera
didn't include a job you get a binary or
code so ultimately I had to do it with
TFTP this is when in the control of the
bot you can see like I want to show you
what is I want to see what are my boss
that are connected we have one that is
the telnet MP SL which is two bio the
code for the the platform for this box
and then the colon one is just my C&C
bot right so here's a here is the actual
capture of that bot beginning its
scanning process and we can see my IP is
192 168 3.1 40 he immediately
are scanning all of these random IPs and
he's mostly 23 but he's got 23 23 here I
had these on on a Cisco switch and for
all of these examples I'm going to show
court average port bandwidth because I
thought that that was interesting to me
so here the initial scans are doing just
a TK of scans and 147 packets per second
so one other thing that was interesting
when I when I checked the bots and we
know we've heard about in study of the
code is that telnet as you can see is no
longer enabled here so the bot process
is predatory and it tries to take over
the bot it takes over the device that
it's infecting and he shuts down telnet
so that nobody else can can control it
he is the code is running in memory so
if you flush it they would all if you
reboot the device that would be flushed
and telnet would open up again but
something else that is interesting here
is FSH is enabled now SSH was not
enabled in the initial port scan that I
didn't showed earlier and this was
interesting to me because why you know
why is this running I actually don't
know I went back again today and checked
I can't SSH into the box maybe it's just
an artifact of excuse me of how the box
is or how the camera is reacting to the
loss of telnet I really don't know I
don't think that Mariah communicates
over over SSH at all so it was just
interesting so we're going to go through
the attack vectors here this is a
screenshot of what the control looks
like so I do a question marks on the
from the botnet control and I say what
are the available attacks here and we're
going to go through each of these and
and what they do
a UDP flood just a basic UDP flood this
is interesting it's a default random
source IP and a default random
destination IP in my experience a lot of
the tools have been you know maybe a
common desta
in port or something I'm sorry I said
random destinations IP random
destination port random source port a
lot of times the tools that are maybe
from like the anonymous toolkit for 2016
there they're like look are using a
common source or destination port right
so this is interesting it makes it makes
fingerprinting more deep difficult
especially if you're doing firewall
filters on routers over ATL so a little
bit harder to handle you know if you're
if you're handling this on a router you
can see it's almost 2 Megas of traffic
that's generated here not not a ton
we've seen a pretty good UDP attack so
this is remember this is just what's
generated out of a camera so not a ton
of traffic here's what it looks like
each of these examples I'll give a a
Wireshark visual and then a TCP dump
that might be a little bit easier to see
for the folks in the back but again just
an example of random source port random
destination port oh and then a crash it
crashed my camera and this is actually
reported by somebody else that I that I
was chatting with as well it only seemed
to happen on this attack vector but
after running a UDP attack for a long
time out of this camera and apparently
some other cameras the device can't
handle it and it crashes and it reboots
and then I lose Mirage you know so
that's why that that forced loader comes
in handy as well but it was just
interesting that it crashes it here's a
syn flood it's a again random source
port random destination port a pretty
nice of one-to-one correlation between
packets that are you know fins that are
sent and the acts that are returned 78
or 787 kilobits per second we've got a
pretty good you know rate of traffic
coming back as well
now remember when these are a live
production these are going to be you
know maybe 40,000 100,000 BOTS so real
IP addresses that are that are that are
doing these and
you know the attack that targets that is
being attacked is going to be responding
to all of those random real IP addresses
here's an example of just what it looks
like in Wireshark so we're seeing we're
sending sins the host that's being
attacked is sending a reset and an ACK
ACKs flood basically same thing random
source random destination again a
one-to-one correlation
we've got a little bit more bandwidth to
add tied to this one to about five Meg
of traffic that it's a but that this one
camera is able to generate again a
one-to-one correlation for historical or
for your own viewing of what you might
want to look at when you're if you're
encountering this in your network here's
what it looks like from Wireshark this
one is good stomped flood so this is
kind of a twist on the on the
traditional axe Lud
he doesn't begin the axe load until a
session is established which is which is
interesting so a session is set up I
receive a sequence number everything's
working you know I've got an established
flow right and then suddenly I start
flooding the guy with axe actually my
camera couldn't run this attack so I had
to run him from the Raspberry Pi that's
why these are a little bit different
numbers and and in fact colors on the
slide but this guy's got about 90 Meg of
traffic on the pies I think the pie has
hundred Meg ports so not bad
but what's interesting as I say about
this is it's a it's an evasion technique
perhaps to try and evade some of the
defenses that we might have in the
network for blocking just regular axles
or students web so once the session is
established then I started with the with
the axe one here's what it looks like in
Wireshark also notice that I'm sending
pushes here so so I set up my session
and then the attacking bot immediately
starts with I'm sending a push in an ACK
and I'm trying to confuse the host the
pushes is
his intention is to say don't wait for
everything else that you might be
receiving from you just start processing
so you know just an interesting twist on
it here you can see examples of the
difference the sequence number that's
being repeated so it's just a I'd say
attempt to as I say bypass some of the
security features of some protection set
UDP flood so just a basic this has less
options oh I didn't mention that all of
these examples up here show the
parameters with which you can tune an
attack so you know I give examples of
UDP plain that P that I want to ho
attack and then the time frame the
duration that I want to do in this case
120 seconds and then I hit a question
mark and see what are just like in the
CLI of a router what are the other
parameters that I can do here so the
unique to the plain UDP flood it says
that it has randomized destination ports
I only observed destination port five
four zero zero five Wireshark decodes it
as gige vision stream protocol it's a
pretty high you can see 20 mega or so of
traffic generated by the camera so we're
working our way up in terms of traffic
that the camera can can generate this
you won't be able to see but I wanted to
include it for posterity or maybe
zooming in on upon video but here is
basically what that looks like in TCP
dump a lot of these are packet lengths
512 so that might be a parameter that
you might be able to filter on
destination port 5 4 0 0 5 I think that
this is just a you know I don't I don't
think that every time it's 64 4 or 46
this is a pretty good one so valve
technologies or valve software has a
package a software package that they
call source and source I believe is a is
a 3d modeling engine used for video
gaming right so this is an attack that
is
physically designed to to attack gaming
service right so it's a UDP flood random
source port destination port is 2701 5
which is the port that a lot of this
that this engine is running on right
it's used for half-life and
counter-strike and those kind of thing
so the payload I'll show you that
includes a query for this not a ton of
bandwidth 162 K maybe it's really a TK
if we know that the scanner is running
to but it's a targeted attack now how
are you going to find this or how would
you combat this what I don't know I
don't have access to production you know
data center data anymore but I would
suspect that any gaming network is
probably already running this traffic so
it's probably you know it's probably not
something that you can just filter out
2701 5 because I think that would
probably break the game here's an
example of the wireshark capture you can
see the query that's included in the
payload here and this is basically just
what it looks like on the actual flood
so random source ports attacking UDP
2701 5 and again I would think that if I
was running a gaming network I would
probably see a lot of this in my network
already so it might be a difficult thing
to try and fingerprint an attack or
block with you know traditional firewall
filters or a ratio
so this guy is the DNS attack which so I
said that I had some experience with
this in prior to joining server central
or prior while at server central prior
to joining
radler this is a pretty neat attack I've
got some additional and for a little
more study on it the we launched the
attack here in the code as always all of
the attacks are launched with attack
name IP address that I want to attack
and the destination and then I add
parameters to it so here I have DNS I
have the IP address and I have the
duration actually what happens on this
only this attack that IP address is
ignored it's not included and it's
because this is an attack on DNS
resolvers so here in my example I've
said DNS I put in the IP address of my
attacking server the one that I usually
attack my duration and I add a domain
that I want to to use this is just a
unrouted domain that I'm using and I'm
serving DNS for and my on that bind
server
he's 187 K or maybe 100 K of attack
traffic but he floods the target DNS
server
so he's flooding the authoritative DNS
ultimately the authoritative DNS server
for the domain here we'll dig into this
what's happening also is he's pre
pending or he's adding a 12 character
string to the front of whatever domain
you put in at that switch of domain
equals so in my case what's interesting
here is the attack is coming from my DNS
server so the the host that the camera
is using for his DNS queries which in my
case was that Linksys because he's
giving that out as part of his DHCP
request or DHCP fulfillment so the
camera is asking the the Linksys hey
given what do you know about random
string dot domain comm right so this is
how it looks on on the dns server
I'm getting these attacks from a real
legitimate DNS server and in production
this is going to be real DNS service so
how you can't block requests from
Comcast resolvers right you don't want
to do that
your Verizon's resolvers you can't do
that so this is a this is a difficult
one to try and fight its small length
high packets per second and exist in my
examples or my history of working on
this guy he can be a pretty tough one so
you might see you might be 25 gig of
traffic in terms of bits per second but
it might be you know 50 million packets
per second so you might exhaust packets
per second on your links before you're
exactly exhausting bandwidth utilization
this is a couple looks at what what
happens here so a lot of the examples
are saying you know this is going to be
added to just you know random string WMA
calm but in fact you might also see it
as just random string domain.com it
really the only parameter is do I add
what I put in the domain string here so
again this is the syntax that I'm using
target domain comm or domain comm and
the results is always a 12 character
random string that is prepended to the
to the query this one is really cool
this is the GRE IP flood he sends
traffic that is encapsulated as as GRE
the tunneled when we look into the
tunnel traffic the source IP is always
this unused or you know special special
use IP space it's always this specific
IP address this is a high bit per second
high packet per second camera attack
which you know initially when we heard
about the GRE vectors being used in a
lot of these varieties a lot of us were
thinking why is GRE being used maybe
it's being used to maybe maybe a method
to try and knock down cloud scrubbing
centers that might be using GRE
for delivery and I never really thought
that that was really it but after doing
this test it dawned on me that this is
the highest packet per second attack
that's out here and the highest volume
attack that was out here so this is
probably the most effective in terms of
volume attack that is in the tool set
here so 25 Meg in my example pretty good
here's an example from Wireshark of the
the traffic it immediately decodes it as
the tunneled traffic but you can see in
my example here might source my real
source IP my real destination IP and
there's the tunnel traffic destination
IP is random in the tunneled payload so
interesting and TP down version of it
here's here's what you're seeing
this I think was also cool I didn't
really realize what this attack was
until I looked at it but along the same
lines of a gr8 attack this is
transparent Ethernet bridging over GRE
so here I'm jamming this with with layer
2 traffic which I thought was pretty
cool
it's not as high a throughput it's about
half of a little bit less than half of
what the what the GRE IP attack is but
again here are the parameters that I can
add I could just with these with the
same normal switches I can get the
attack going but here are the here's the
layer 2 information that's Honnold
inside of it which I I thought was
pretty cool I don't really know the
reason why this would be included but
maybe some of you do and could share and
again here's what the tunneled traffic
looks like this I thought was also cool
it's the HD HTTP attack that is included
with it it is just a get flash attack so
it's a you know something that is not a
a a new idea but what's interesting
about it is for me I saw this generated
about 500,000 kilobits per second of get
requests right so what was interesting
about that is actually the reverse with
the web server was returning back to the
bots so I've got a huge difference here
in I'm only doing 500 km I'm sorry only
doing 500 k of requests but I'm getting
12 Meg's of return response here which
is you know when I'm doing this with a
ton of bots and you can see how this
could easily exhaust resources the
content that I was serving here to get
this 12 Meg was just a basic it works
page in Apache right so it's a pretty
big thing it could be a pretty big
attack for the host that it's attacking
and just some of the things you'll see
are incrementing source ports which
makes sense because I'm doing continue
again this is what it looks like decoded
in
Wireshark again you probably won't be
able to see it maybe for future
reference but it's just basically get
flash and I get HD 200 okay that I get
back to the server
and I'm serving content mariah has out
of the box five different user agents
HTTP user agents included here are the
examples of them you'll be able to just
find this in the code but I thought that
was pretty cool to have five different
ones included so each of these attack
vectors had a time parameter if you
remember in most examples it was 120
seconds that I've added in my examples
but they can be as little as you know
several seconds and that makes a new
challenge for us as Network people you
know our traditional ways of finding
some of these things let's say you're
BitFenix here who this annex these guys
if you remember they had a they had a
breach on their exchange they're a
Bitcoin or yeah there's a third largest
Bitcoin exchange in the world and they
had about seventy two million dollars
stolen from them so here there's you
know from the Mariah attacks Twitter
feed there's obviously still under
attack for things but 60 second floods
30 second floods that's a lot of what
you'll see in the Mariah attacks Twitter
feed which I would I would recommend
looking at and why is that interesting
is if I'm dealing with a 20 gig attack
that lists for 30 seconds 60 seconds
that's what we call burst attacks it's
like kind of like graphic grew a
guerrilla warfare on our networks right
we're they're hard to find they're not
always going to show up on SNMP graphs
they're going to really manifest
themselves as either output drops on
switch boards or router ports or angry
users saying my app is slow hey network
guys fix the network and then network
guys are going to say no my grass was
fine it's the ass well it could be one
of these so just keep your eye out for
that make sure you have some tools that
are able to catch some of this sample
rate maybe adjusting your SNMP polling
intervals that kind of thing
but it's very easily controlled here and
I would just definitely check out that
that's what
feed variations to the code so I
mentioned that this is highly
customizable and it's available for
anybody to go ahead and do this is not a
rat where research this is the link from
where this was this was security week
article I think but this article by
since December 9th um fifty-three unique
versions of it we saw in my examples and
my out-of-the-box code that we were at
you know TCP 23 so telnet and 23 23 but
our friends at which telecom found that
you know they were they were the
recipient of a modified version of this
that was that was targeting TR oh six
I'm so obviously trying to try and
attack different ports here the domain
generation algorithm I thought was a
pretty neat addition we see this in in
other other versions of malware or
attacks but it's what was interesting
here is that it has the ability so so
much of the control the command and
control is obviously based on DNS and if
we can knock down DNS we can potentially
knock down the command and control
function but when you add a domain
generation algorithm the what the bot
does is if it can't meet reach its
primary C&C connection it will go into
this process of trying a new randomly
generated domain algorithm or randomly
generated domain so and in this case it
switches every day
so it's interesting Conficker was a I
think as high as 50,000 per day so it's
you know one per day is a it's progress
you might say but there are better
examples but it still is interesting and
you know one method of how if we knock
down the domain it can adapt alright
this is an example of the guys at 360
this is their I believe that they're the
ones who discovered this but
this is their example of how the domain
algorithm in Mirai works so you know
just a just a statement to how this
thing can be easily modified and changed
and you know really with the code being
available to all of us we can we could
do anything that we need it to do right
so how can I catch this in my network
out of the box this is these are the
parameters right so unmodified
command-and-control runs on telnet that
might be interesting to us because we're
probably not seeing a lot of telnet we
shouldn't see a lot of telnet in our
networks I would think so that's one way
but as we see it's modifiable so I would
suspect that it's not all variants of it
or probably not all running this this
way replication scanning also is through
Telenet and 23:23 so keep a look out for
that in your net flow scan listen it's
default port runs on 48 101 so watch out
for that you might see that in that flow
honey pots are a pretty neat way we're
going to talk about one example of a
honeypot that I had had played with a
little bit and there are there are
scanner services out there on the
network or on the internet that we'll
look at you know you can put in your
prefixes and they will check kay what's
what's vulnerable in your network
they'll basically try to scan your
network for you
so Symetra is they have a honeypot that
I enjoyed playing with I think that it
has a little bit it's still under
development more to do if you I would
say try it and if you like what it's
doing maybe consider contributing to it
here's how I installed it on a bun -
this is basically all it is this is the
exact syntax I'm getting it out of
github I'm adding these these guys I'm
installing my requirements and this is
my launch command to run it and this is
what it looks like so you run it and you
know you can see this didn't take long I
mean I think that this was 2 or 3
minutes and I'm already having a
a guy trying to brute and execute
commands that are identified as as Mirai
attacks Mariah is not the only IOT
botnet I mentioned in the beginning that
one of my colleagues calls this the
celebrity botnet obviously because of
what it did but there were other ones
here here's information to all of these
so pay attention to them as I say
Mariah's not the only guy out not the
only game in town but if you need these
links I can get them to you as well and
then in closing so people are arguing
about the longevity of Mariah you know
if you go into some of these websites
and F for help or look around and trying
to get help people are saying forget
about it rise over maybe they're just
tired of people coming up and asking
questions but but people are saying and
whatever is infected is infected and all
you're going to get is a low-hanging
fruit I don't really agree with that
because as we can see and as we saw with
the with the DT attack of trying to take
over almost a million routers code as it
is now is flushed from the devices when
the powers is reset so that means
anything that is infected and then
rebooted unless it has been modified is
ultimately a target again so I don't
think that word I don't think that this
is over yet and I don't think that new
it's I don't think we're I think we are
going to see more variants and more
things being taken advantage of
[Music]
it's the game changer just the ability
for everybody to have access to this
code and have clear written instructions
this is really the first time I can
think of that there are everybody has
access freely to the code and there are
how-to guides on the internet about how
to set this up basically everything you
need to do to set this up modify it and
have your way with with the botnet so
those operators we need to be mindful of
what's happening in our equipment in our
network we have to be mindful of the
equipment that we're deploying we have
to be mindful of our customers yesterday
in the security talk I talked about the
growth and the the take rate of IOT
compared to users on the network and it
was a huge jump between now and
estimated for 2020 about what was I
think it was going to be about twenty
billion devices attached IOT devices it
attached to the network by 2020 and the
majority of that growth is in the
consumer base so our users who are not
the technical people right and they're
not going to be the ones who are caring
about the security of these things as
operators I think that we have a pretty
important role in in policing this stuff
and I don't necessarily mean shutting
people off but maybe if you're seeing
this in your network and you're seeing
something from an access link coming in
from a subscriber notify them send them
an email maybe do some you know if
they're as if they're an access
subscriber maybe do some steering to
direct them to like a web page is to say
we've tried to contact you your services
a you're part of a botnet we're about to
shut you off that kind of thing but I
think it's important and we have to give
thought to how we handle these attacks
in our own network I gave examples of of
how customizable these attack vectors
are how easily you know a lot of them
are different than what we've seen in
the traditional whole you can look and a
lot of the traditional tools that are
used for attacks against our network a
lot of them as I say random source port
random destination port a lot of them
are legitimate traffic like the DNS
queries from legitimate DNS servers a
lot of them are legitimate like you
don't want to block all of the the valve
source engine traffic if you're a game
network that might use this so how are
you going to pull out you have to give
thought to how you're going to
differentiate between the good traffic
and the bad traffic and it's going to be
a challenge
and with that I'd like to open it up to
questions or feedback or comments or
suggestions of anybody else who might
have some experience in this
so Phil Rosenthal from Beluga City
Ananias from the wonderful presentation
thank you so much my question is why is
there such a large difference in the
amount of traffic that it can generate
between these different aggregates is it
inefficiency in the different vectors
are they limiting it
that's a good question thanks so I from
what I see I would guess that it's
probably the the task that is required
on these low powered devices to generate
the traffic right so it could be that my
camera which is a couple years old is
requiring more CPUs to generate the
output of whatever the attack vector is
on one attack vector versus the other so
I don't know that they're limited I did
see somebody in response to if you
remember my UDP flood rebooted the
camera somebody said well what you want
to do is limit the you know the attack
vector that's coming out of that and
other people say well you can't really
you don't know what every capability
that every single device are going to be
so that might not be a good option I
think it's really just a function of
generating the traffic and just as you
might have the same response on a small
Pentium versus a you know in a poor ass
modern processor another I guess related
question so if you own one of these
cameras would you start noticing that's
like there's something wrong with with
your camera did what was infected it's a
good question and I don't know because I
didn't really set it up to look at like
am I losing my data feed
I might not I think I would probably you
know if it's tied to CPU resources I
would think that I would probably maybe
have some issues with my video stream
well I I didn't look at it personally
but I would bet you would thank you
thank you
okay well thank you I will be around
only for the rest of today unfortunately
I have to go to another event tomorrow
but we'll be at the beer and gear
tonight as well so look forward to
talking with you thank you