thanks a lot so where this came out of
was broken into speed internet land
speed record and this erupted kind of a
furor on the nanog mailing list with
remarks like what am I missing here this
OC 48 Lucy 192 production curse
commercial networks and blow away these
speeds on a regular basis then somebody
else said I'm going to launch at that
tape across the parking parking lot with
a spud gun and see if see if I can
achieve 920 megabits a second so if I
thought it might be interested maybe go
into a little bit more detail and so
this is as I say not think them to use
with a rocket-powered sled that travel
at 6,400 miles per hour I think to test
the an ordinance of some kind so what I
want to go through is who did it what
was done how was it done what's special
about this who needs it anyway and then
what comes next and a little bit on
where do I find out more I'm not going
to go into the heavy technical details
so it's mainly just an overview of what
we did so the collaborators were people
from Caltech slack that Stanford Linear
Accelerator Center Los Alamos fern and
then we had other people helping from
our garment to start oh Linda wink
listen start starlight and then they
were various isp data tag starlight Tara
grid surf net and Cisco and level 3 and
Intel and then there's some funding from
the do II European Commission and the
National Science Foundation you can see
all the pretty logos that everybody has
so what was done well we set a new tcp
land speed record and the the way the
Internet to measures the record is it's
the speed of the data transfer times the
distance so it's typically measured in
terabit meters per second so this one
the record was ten thousand six hundred
and nineteen terabit meters per second
because it's fairly easy to transmit
data over short distances similarly
comes when you have a large congestion
window with TCP so the first in November
at we succeed in doing 8.6 gigabits a
second across the u.s. that was from
Baltimore to Sunnyvale but that was with
ten parallel streams there are ten
separate CPUs sending 210 CPUs at the
other end and the internet land speed
record specifies that can only be one
cpu at either end so in that sense that
was not a internet to land speed record
at the same time that we sent from
Amsterdam to sunnyvale night at 923
megabits a second and that that was
using jumbo frames 9000 bike frames then
in sunnyvale in February we got at this
time we got Intel 10 gige Nick cards and
so we had another crack at it and this
time we got 2.38 gigabits a second from
sunnyvale to Geneva again with jumbo
frames and this is actually about 99% of
the available bandwidth you could put
over since it was a packet over silently
and you gotta lie for headers etc the
little grasp that you can see shows you
the gigabits per second along the
left-hand axis and along the bottom
which is time and you can see just to
the right they pegs out at roughly 2.2
36 gigabits a second for over an hour
so that was actually transferring over a
terabyte in one hour from in that case
sunnyvale to Geneva so how was it done
well at sunnyvale in the level three
gateway we had a GSR router which is
kind of loaned to us by Cisco we had a
large number of CPUs one you and for you
I service some of them were disservice
some of the CPU service and one of these
servers in February had the Intel there
Nick card in it caltech provided the
CPUs and then at starlight there was a
t6 40 juniper router and then internal
to that a 7609 which then had more cpus
and then across the data tags link
across the Atlantic two-and-a-half
gigabits a section which was actually
the bottleneck it's kind of interesting
to think of a bottleneck has been
two-and-a-half cubits a second for an
end-to-end transfer but that's what it
was and then to CERN where they were
which is in Geneva Switzerland where
there were more more service so here are
some of typical components you can see
down at the bottom right there's the GSR
as a 12,000 over the six CPU earth 666
useful slots in it the one new high
servers with an earthquake strap around
exhibits in California the disk servers
and the intel nic card which is just and
you can see the site the size of the
card because the ascent piece sitting on
the heatsink kind of interesting to see
how big the heatsink it occupies almost
half of the card we were using we use
that for the last test the original test
we're using disconnect Nick cards so
let's see i think i'm gonna skip
next one so what were the trip what were
the challenges in this well it's a pci
bus limitation 66 megahertz 64-bit CPU a
pci bus can do 4.2 gigabits at best so
we actually in the latter tests we made
sure we had hundred and thirty-three
megahertz the cpu pci bus at
two-and-a-half gigabits per second and
180 millisecond round-trip time that was
discern we needed 120 megabyte windows
so these pcs had to have plenty of
memory in them so that they could
accommodate that window fairly easily we
ran into some of the tools which we are
using for the testing BBC p which is a
file copy program wouldn't allow window
bigger than 2 megabytes so we did match
so we didn't wind up using that slow
start it's a one gigabit second takes
about five to six seconds on 180
millisecond link so if one wants to
measure ninety percent of the
measurement in the stable that's non
slow smart state then we need to measure
for over 60 seconds and all through we
would need to ship 700 megabytes as a
gigabyte gigabit per second in order to
be able to run for that amount of time
so you need a fair manner disk at both
ends and then of course the problem with
the standard TT piece back is with its
additive increase in mas progressive
decrease that as soon as you hit a loss
it can take a long time to get back up
since you're only adding one packet for
act coming back and you can see that
down on the right there the bottom scale
is 0-2 thousand seconds and you can see
it only goes from about about 450 to
about 600 20 megabits in a thousand
seconds so it takes a long time so
you're very sensitive to any loss this
is a test circuit so there wasn't much
loss but in his last certainly would
back us down quite a lot
so in terms of what was special it
wasn't just measuring the speed on the
backbone with a lot of aggregated links
it was actually an end-to-end
application one cpu at one in one cpu at
the other end we actually did try with
multiple streams and single streams but
we were able to actually get good
performance just using a single stream
it also illustrates quite nicely that
even though TCP was designed for 56
kilobits per second network it actually
is not run out of steam yet it's
actually scales up to the multi gigabits
per second region and TCP is nice in the
sense there are other protocols which
you can use for transmitting data some
which are based on UDP the nice thing
about TCP is it's well understood its
mature it's got a lot of nice features
reliability and it's friendly to other
users of the network we also looked at
some new tcp stacks is at least three
out there at the moment ronstan Sally
Floyd called high speed tcp another one
from the Cambridge University in England
called scalable tcp and a third ones and
Stephen Newark Caltech called fast TTP
these all get around the problem that
the additive increase and enable you to
actually recover much quicker after
losses they worked very nicely in the
nice thing about all these tcp stacks is
they only need to be deployed at the the
sender they don't have to be deployed at
both ends
and all these and in that case we were
able to get good performance and not
need the jumbo frames if we use the
standard tcp we had to use jumbo frames
so we use commercial off-the-shelf
hardware and software there was no
special equipment here I think in terms
of importance to others I mean raises
the bar on expectations for applications
and users not come to some examples of
applications that need these speeds some
applications can actually use them and
so they actually provide planning
information for people who want to think
about whether or not they should be
shipping truckloads of data around the
world or 747s worth of data around the
world or whether or not they can
actually use the internet to do it and
the network is now with these kinds of
speeds we're now exceeding the network
is being to exceed the speed of which
you can accept that amount of data into
a PC and the PC increases in performance
and not happening as fast as the network
speeds have been happening the past so
it's looking much less likely the
network is the bottleneck but rather
it's the it becomes a catalyst enabler
and the bottleneck has moved somewhere
else to the PCs itself in terms of
shipping data around the world we
certainly in hind you physics at my own
field use the ship's data fire by a 747
s from slack two places in Europe and
the best you could do you know assuming
that the plane didn't have any delays
anything like that would be about 10
hours and if you had a fully load in 747
and it took 10 hours to get from say Sam
sis go to Geneva then that's roughly two
to four terabytes second and actually
that's not fair because you then have to
unload the tape shipping it off the
plane you have gone through
customs and everything else like that so
actually the turnaround is closer to two
weeks so who needs it well as I
mentioned after you left I know physics
need it because we're transmitting we're
receiving from our equipment roughly 50
megabytes a second and we need to
transfer multi terabyte files per day
across the Atlantic and we're doing that
and as you already have databases which
are about well over three quarters of a
petabyte and in the that's doubling it
roughly each year so that in a decade we
expect to be getting close to an exabyte
the other sciences that need this so in
particular data intensive sciences such
an astrophysics global weather
bioinformatics the human genome fusion
and seismology and then industries such
as aerospace in medicine medicine
particularly the radiation oncology
people people when a patient visits a
ghost a visit to a hospital typically
they will create a pic pictures like
mammograms for this is two breasts taken
two views that typically comes out to be
100 to 500 megabytes per visit and
there's thousands of visitors especially
around the world so they already in the
UK alone they already have 400 terabytes
of data which they which once you can
start sharing that date you can start
mining it and looking for new ways to
treat patients new new commonalities
between what's going on and everything
so I think that there could be big
improvements in patient care and things
like this is one begins to get these
speeds obviously in the future media
distribution becomes very interesting as
a gigabit per second that's roughly two
full-length DVD movies two full-length
matrix reloaded in one minute when you
can do that you kind of have to wonder
what blockbusters business model becomes
at 2.36 gigabits that's roughly 200
full-length DVD movies in an hour and
you kind of have to wonder whether
sharing movies will be
like to sharing music is today which is
kind of be interesting to see what
happens maybe the internet will then
become full of somebody I think put it
on the list of cease and desist notice
is many many pages long from the lawyers
saying don't do this when will it have
an impact well this is kind of I'm
trying to get a handle on this the top
left graph shows you the amount of
traffic am i doing oh all right so the
amount of traffic you're getting on es
net is roughly doubling per year the
next graph dancers the capacity of slack
which has been done increasing by ninety
percent each year if you if you take
what's available in industries today and
you double them at these kind of rates
then industry firm which has 620
megabits today will have 10 gigabits and
three and a half to five years and we
can expect similar increases too many
other places the question of the home is
interesting in the lets you see there is
an initiative in California to try and
get one gigabit to the home and to
industry within within the next ten
years whether or not that will happen I
don't know but that that could mean
these these speeds will be very
important ok I'll skip that ok what's
next we want to beat the two and a half
year its second length you want to do
dis to dip this is memory the memory so
it's not really useful to most
applications you want to evaluate new
snacks you understand how to make the 10
DD nicks work well that's 1500 bite
empty use that we made lots of tests we
did not succeed in all the tests you
wanna just do I think the big thing is
to move these from here Odette hero
demonstrations to the commonplace in our
case we had 24 people working around the
clock who have pretty much wizards in
their own
areas i mean not each person didn't work
24 hours but you know because of people
in geneva things like that and still we
did not manage within the week that we
had the 10 new year cards to do all the
tests we wanted to do so it's fairly
complex today so that is a little bit
more in case in case you want a bit more
information this from urls their
question
shut up to them okay there's a clearly
established methodology for testing
world land speed record 1950s and does
require the average of a bidirectional
test you have to run the car in both
directions cross Delta my hat are you
planning on doing this anytime soon I in
that magnet but it would be Spanish to
do specifically the test is the average
of two runs in each direction in an hour
okay do they have to bathe a run for an
hour well these cars off the cars only
run for a few seconds no that would be
pretty easy for us to do we didn't do
that no I let's face if there's a lot of
water between serve and slug the land
speed record at all
hi avi Friedman just I haven't followed
the whole threat but one of the things
that some of the people in the
commercial internet space internet
measurement space did I thought was
interesting with they started measuring
not milliseconds but milliseconds per
mile and I think one of the interesting
ways to calibrate some of this is point
out it's much more challenging to get
higher speed you know the more distance
you can they could be interesting to
start looking at reporting measurements
for in terms of beautiful seconds come
out of a throughput per unit distance I
think that would also be interesting
when someone says well you know they got
it I got the dad drives shot across the
parking lot vs we just lost five minutes
of lunch boys and girls 30 seconds of
Lincoln
so what do you want from ISPs other than
faster links faster interfaces the ISPs
do anything differently to enable this
of course is all n system good and I
think what we wants my ass piece it's
because I think we just want this to
become commonplace we wanted to be
available not available and you know at
a price before available terms of faster
legs but nothing else we see that we
have you moved earn parents thank you oh
yeah Yello fame