well Sue's hooking up her laptop I know
she's most nervous about me introducing
her because i know many stories and i
thought of when to tell but I won't
because well I just won't but Sue and I
go way back to one of my very first
networking job actually Susan as well
for a while there was at University of
Michigan there was Susan r Harris who's
in p p harris and susan hairs and for
the longest time i thought they were all
her so in a meeting i exclaimed how
could you do all these things how can
you write the campus and lose letter and
all these things as it turns out it was
three people so i was a little relieved
but anyway sue is the reason that i got
my first engineering job she probably
doesn't remember but I've always been
appreciative of the lies she told to get
it for me and she's here to give a talk
it's true it's so true but it was it was
all in the spirit of getting me to help
her help her fix routing problems so
that she could go on to you know the
routing registry stuff and making the
NSFNET safe so anyway with are you
hooked up oh cool well here's to
so first of all I started all of this
and kudos to our previous speaker and to
Randy in his panel because maybe this
talk is now not as well needed which is
why we tried to cut some of the time
period but so I'm going to try to pull
out a few points because the way I got
started in this talk is why should we
talk about bgp attacks you know though
there's a couple things when i was
looking at bgp and as the co-chair
people have asked me you know how
serious do we have to take into account
the BGP security in the ITF the security
80s have wanted us to really be rigorous
in our look and I wanted to find the
real world problems because if you don't
have real little problems you're you're
building code that's for pie in the sky
or something
it so one thing that I've been pressed
on is when you how will our the security
concerns from the government and one
thing is Steve alluded to the fact that
they have started to really take a look
at it and I actually found a couple
interesting quotes after the attack on
the root servers in October there was a
quote from one of the people schmidt
from the US government that says we're
looking for institutionalizing the
standard program protocols for
communicating back and forth between the
root super community protocol and the US
government AKA watch out they're coming
for that and then there's another one
that talks about in February they have a
strategy to secure cyberspace whose goal
is to engage in power Americans to
secure portions of inner cyberspace that
they own operator control of which they
interact that isn't the routing
infrastructure I don't know what it is
and it does actually specify bgp
protocols and DNS protocols it's a one
to five year plan so in case you didn't
think the government actually had
comments on this and I'm sure Russell
Krauss will go on to two more fun
comments but I actually found those on
public websites and there are people
looking at it so as I went forward I
started this to try to have a panel of
people standing up and saying like Rob I
got a real problem here I'll tell you
what it is and I fixed it in my network
that's not what I got I got a lot of
quiet so I'm here with the ITF saying
gee you got a really secure it and I
want to say only if you do
infrastructure
well we've talked about this in an
analog steering committee and I think
Curtis when we talked about the review
the previous slide and tried to give you
some real comments about what the
vulnerabilities were what could happen
where should you look what you should do
came up with one of the best quotes it's
the disservice to the community to talk
about the existent exposures without
being specific about what those
exposures are there's always totally
only only the good guys factor but that
only goes so far in reality you have to
tell the good guys first I think in the
context of looking at vulnerabilities
it's hard for us to talk about them
unless we actually have fixes because as
Steve last time Steve gave us talk
attacks followed and so I understand
people not talking about it and I
understand that there might be a reality
where it's not your most pressing attack
as our previous speaker said you know
attacking with TCP sins and various
things might not be as easy as just
getting a compromised router password so
that's why Eric and Bill say there
aren't really in attacks and Vijay said
well we have some things that the vcp
could fix you know there's this high
amount of prefixes and again I'm
pleading one of the normal reasons as
you miss configure the routers so how
and you don't have your maximum prefix
filters or prefix filter set there are
syn floods to port 179
and is it attack well our last speaker
went into that please take a look at it
internal multi-hop be GPS which are
hijacked and inject bad routes which is
a variant uncompromising bad routers
it's another thing may be caused by
those clear text passwords i know in
Alaska presentation we showed you how
many clear text passwords we can find in
this room ana nog wireless perhaps we
ought to think about that and you know
there are things that can be done ulti
hot bgp over IP second Dave Ward did
some really good work in how to talk
about ipsec and you'll find that in the
thing now Susan I apologize for this not
being in the notes but a couple of these
notes I got just on the comment that
they wouldn't go in the notes so this is
a case that Rob Thomas went over this
morning I think when he talked to but I
want to re-emphasize that you know
they're purchasing compromised bgp
routers you've heard a whole bunch today
about fixing your router security
putting prefixes filters on prefix so we
don't mean to be unhelpful in the nanog
but to say come on get back on the
things that we know how to do do the
BCPS the next thing is miscreants using
vgp speaker routers to know their
enemies especially other miscreants
they'll make both dis announcements
sort of spoof you so what's going to
happen okay now not all BGP is in ISPs
but there's a lot of BGP in enterprises
and I talked to Mike and works with
enterprises and I've actually talked to
enterprises and you start to talk about
them in different places and say BGP
attacks and attacks and they say huh
what does it matter you know but I think
if we begin to socialize the routing
registry we may get people passed hot
that's probably what we're trying to do
here so remember that attacks scope when
I talk to people and I'd really really
like to hear more specifics in my ITF
chair Pat Lam sure Randy and I'm sure
Steve would like to hear pieces about
real attacks because then we can wait
solutions you know attacks go after the
infrastructure deployed boxes bgp
vulnerabilities deployment issues and
i'm not getting your RPF checks but one
thing that Dave Meyer says continually
is ninety percent of the problems that
he sees are still miss configuration or
reconfigurations of routers the
questions that eventually when we get
past the ups I screwed up or this
happened because it's in consist
are some of these due to attacks i think
at that point i'll pick you up on that
yours
yeah well a lot of words going to say
about misconfigurations to birdie Bowers
of superfluous resort was already been
said I won't go too much worth maxit to
wonder some of the hackers are being
paid with Nigerian vacuums we all know
about Miss configuration we all know
about AAS 7007 I mentioned one other
incident about four years 34 years ago
AT&T worldnet was off the air long
enough that it made the wall street
journal i had the front of conversations
with very high executives in the company
explaining that it was a BGP problem
originating some other isp is announcing
gate its last 24 that we're uh Turley
relying on for our infrastructure and it
caused problems here this is a threat
model that CEOs and CTOs understand
appearing in the Wall Street Journal
many many less noticed attacks some I
had the thrill of explaining to other
high executives quite recently about it
egb
spammer as well you know with FTC found
the two-thirds of spans used to be
illegal Committee one felony is the
second one three it's not just minor
ISPs major horse that has madam is
happening today
the threat that is always worried me the
most I just told zone view these days I
first got into roaring right internet
security by thinking about routing
secured back in 86 I start worrying
about the strike 21
a very small internet within Bell Labs
the height you hijacked two routers for
some fashion one year either end of a
connection one of them you announced a
better route to the destination you set
up a tunnel to a monitoring station or
connection hijacking station set up a
GRE tunnel to the other hijack router
that's closer to the destination so
you're rejecting the traffic correctly
unless someone's monitoring the route
very carefully they're not going to
notice that was going on your customers
rep monitor path changes not just a s
PAP an actual about changes and filter
out from the noise to you this is not
hypothetical this is happening today I
have a very reliably informed that this
has been observed in the wild by some
customers who care about such things
this is I so I must be kind of it
it's always been one of the more serious
cases yeah they can do end-to-end
encryption too high the actual content
to the traffic it's a lot stuff
the spammers are a nuisance attacker in
some sense but of course that's a trap i
will understand it's a lot of traffic
that we don't really want to be carried
if no other reason our customers don't
like getting it more serious enemies can
do more serious damage the major
hijackings the AS 707 is in the ATP
world that incident are easy to notice
incorrect because lots of people are
screaming and got lots of grip myson
alarm suicide you're not the small scale
were inspecting a few prefixes are much
more deadly and can be parts party
responders no one is looking for this
today's defenses can't cope today's
attacks
what's coming tomorrow your first
approximation everyone's voting so what
do we do about it
so one of the things I wanted to note
from everybody ji light we have a large
amount of Miss configuration I think one
of the things we've got to look at I'd
like to hear and this is what this is is
a plea to try to get comments about bgp
problems okay I've given up trying to
get people to talk publicly BJ was brave
enough to give that at ITF talk to
myself talk to Steve's talk to someone
so we can find out because I think we've
got to minimize these costs of having
bgp infrastructure our outages so I'll
be in the back or Randy Apollinaire
comments now
bed ready Randy course will make the
lil explicit what
we're very right there is well secured
with ssh we need the funny things about
large is pieces to the fact we have a
lot of people had a lot of access to
routers and use tax or radius so
therefore you get the password to one of
them and get the past with all of them
we've got a relationship with an
external party or router vendors in this
case you had access to our outer sphere
specific testing preferences and
describe employ
and their firewall the machine that had
legitimate access to our network routers
will expose miscreant was stupid enough
to change one silly thing the
configuration at the hourly rancid
router sweet caught and if you don't
choose rancid silly
we figured out shut it off
just to be clear I am standing here
saying first person these things happen
so I guess
his whisper corn of us talked to us
about it with try to give general
tutorials as randy has mentioned as the
program only as mentioned should give
you the tools to fight this but it's a
problem today
please give us information so we can
disseminate best practices should I
think that's it