Pete wickenburg I hope I hope you're
here are you here thank you so much you
did a wonderful job not only working
with merit but coordinating the vast
crowd of support of volunteers from both
you en and the University of Utah this
is a partial list some of these folks I
met some I didn't but they have been
around many many hours over the past few
days getting ready for us and as I said
this was one of the smoothest we can't
thank you enough I think Rodney are you
still here he's at the airport
schlepping his Segway back to Phoenix
I'm sure but Rodney did do a lot as far
as negotiating the hotel contract for us
this time we are grateful for that
boundary fed us yesterday morning thank
you so much for supplying the food and
this time you noticed we try something
new with one vendor showing equipment
during each break yesterday afternoon
that was endace thanks again for the
support and these are the folks who set
up tables at the beer and gear last
night
and these are all my pals from Merritt
um they're their faces are familiar to
you I know I'm probably by now after all
these meetings you're starting out their
various responsibilities Don is that you
at the door peeking in is Carol here by
any chance yeah Carol never shows up but
you all know her and she is a dream to
work with she does a wonderful job
coordinating things at home as she does
with you Betty Betty Burke is our
infrastructure manager at nerd and
handles the technical aspects of a
meeting working very closely with our
network gurus Bob Stovall and David
Gilbertson from Mission net sue joiner
Rav and general network expert Jason
handles our real media I got it right
this time Jason and Don sort of helps
Carol with everything Joel yay glee and
Lucy are packing up because joel is off
to the wilds of East Asia and they're
both heading out but thank you where are
you going ah
a jolt does the music for us to add
these these the people from the
University of Oregon have become such an
integral part of the meeting and we
appreciate all your help hello cg Wayne
just is hardly like not even blinking at
this highly embarrassing but cool photo
I've put up doing thank you so much for
all your help all these meetings if you
borrowed a wireless card do remember to
turn it in to the probable yes to that
corner of the room where we have more
people from you en and Utah helping out
I will ask you to leave the room quickly
because of time zone changes we will be
tearing down today so we won't be
leaving the network up sorry about that
you've seen the announcements on the web
and on the list that next fall we're
going to hold another wonderful joint
meeting with Erin it was a huge success
last fall in Eugene thank you so much
for those of you who stayed and went to
the air in meeting I hope you do that
again will be in Chicago as you can see
here and will follow the same format as
before with nanog being Sunday through
Tuesday and Aaron Wednesday through
Friday I stole a copy of the errand or
chart from the web to me this is very
striking that at the top there's not a
CEO or president there is the membership
the rank-and-file people just like you
and me because the policy that affects
all of us so much the assignment of IP
addresses for all the Americas that
policy comes from us and as you see if
cleverly put a little arrow in here in a
box pointing to you I do hope you'll
stay around next ball attend the air in
meeting you will be amazed at how much
input the community hands
hello we really need is PS to come to
the air in meetings so please please
stay a lot of the feedback on the
policies comes from people that assign
address spaces but aren't necessarily
the people who do routing and it really
behooves you to be there so I just
wanted to stress what sue was saying
thanks you've been wonderful thank you
so much for coming and we'll see in a
few months