so welcome my name is Joseph or celli I
work for Juniper Networks I'm the
education services department so being a
trainer I'm used to roaming the floor
around my classroom so now that I'm
stuck behind a podium it'll be a little
bit different today but you know we'll
make it work
this is a tutorial for MPLS it is an
introduction so we are going to start at
the basic level we're not going to
really talk about maybe the history of
why we're using it or why we got there
although I am a big history guy we're
not gonna really delve into that will
cover basics and a little bit
intermediate stuff this is such a broad
topic I've kind of focused in on a
section on plucking about part
manipulable and things of that sort
but I got a section RSVP I got section
on LDP so got kind of three pieces of to
play with here the first thing to get
out of the way is everything in here is
out of my brain for better for worse
hopefully it's better and not worse but
it is out of my head and please ask
questions okay being a being a trainer
if you don't know something just flag it
down hey you
whatever I'll be happy to stop and clear
up any misunderstandings so with that
out of the way pardon me
what does MPLS multi-protocol label
switching kind of at its core that the
paradigm is you're forwarding data
traffic be IP or other protocols based
on a fixed size header okay in our case
the 32 byte sorry 32 44 bytes 32 bits
MPLS header okay could be one could be
multiples but attains a label value yeah
you guys can hear me when I stand back
like this can you you can't okay well
you can't cuz you're standing I guess
I'll stay close
continue label value and we're having
switching tables okay so very analogous
to kawan ATM is right you're switching
tables you have label values hey a theme
has this place I'm not a big proponent
but you know has its place so it draws a
lot of parallels because of this label
switching paradigm and
you know there are pieces of MPLS which
very closely parallel the ATM world
alright and we were building overlay
networks right layer 3 over layer 2 we
have this huge ATM switch network
we're bolded VCS right radda radda
these point-to-point links from the
perspective of a router IP address
riding protocols etc but underneath that
the actual physical transport running
overly the switch network you had
traffic engineering capabilities at the
vc level ok so if a certain link in your
ATM network was over congested you can
move certain pcs to other places so that
was kind of you know a good way to do
traffic engineering except from the
routers perspective it's still
point-to-point link ok and for
granularity perspective everything as
the next hop of the router on the other
side of point-to-point link went across
that vc okay so could be one subnet
could be thousands of subnets okay
everything was going along that same
channel the other useful thing about
doing the overlay was that we had
statistics we could pull out the VCS ok
now granted again you don't know for
granularity perspective what exactly
prefixes less you were sniffing you're
doing some other monitoring but you had
stats to pause the BC so these were good
things that we liked that we wanted to
keep moving forward to MPLS so in that
perspective a lot of times you can call
a connection MPLS connection and LSB as
a virtual circuit ok it is basically the
same thing except now we have more
granularity we can actually map an
individual IP prefix to a single MPLS
connection ok so instead of having all
the prefix between me and my
point-to-point buddy now on a per prefix
basis I had the ability to send traffic
into this virtual connection ok I can go
to or router next door to me go to a
write on the other side of the network
so we had good things there and as you
would expect we could pull statistics as
LS B's okay so we get that same good
stuff now in MPLS the one big difference
is in ATM you have this bi-directional
thing by default okay well MPLS the
connections are unidirectional goes from
me to my partner
if you want the same route back you need
a second ed pls connection okay from
that partner back to you they take the
same settle inch can take different to
the links doesn't really matter but if
you want that symmetry you got to build
two connections okay so that is kind of
a big difference um and in fact what
we're doing is building this tunnel okay
whatever prefix is you map to this IP
part me IP prefixes into this LSP into
this MPLS connection you're gonna be
basically turning through the network
okay so those are got some good things
traffic engineering it's another aspect
of MPLS that we can do and we're talking
about here is the ability to send your
traffic along different paths and the
network then what your I GP would come
up with okay or Beach P for that matter
right any of your regular routing
protocols so to get from one edge of my
network to the other edge of my network
instead of going straight through the
middle maybe if that's the best metric
path I can take some windy path some
links aren't normally used and hopefully
avoid some congestion if that's your
goal now the last two bullets here I'm
not really gonna get into a lot of
details per se as to how to make this
happen okay but at some point one of the
routers in the network typically the
start of the tunnel the start of the LSP
he's gonna have to make a decision as to
what prefix it belong down that LSP okay
so you have this mapping of IQ prefixes
an the juniper box is by default it's
bgp transit traffic okay your beats me
next top matches the other end of your
connection that's the we're gonna go
other vendors do it differently and
we're gonna talk we get to LVP about
this forwarding equivalence e-class or
effect and it's just like big fancy
sounding term and in reality what we're
talking about here is the transmission
of packets through your network that all
meet the same set of criteria they're
all belong to the same LSP maybe you're
doing some sort of class of service
things like that but you're gonna treat
all the packets the same inside this
connection that's basically what a thick
is right and we'll see we get to the
other
section it's a prefix okay it's a prefix
and here's a label to get to that prefix
so label header okay we got four bytes
so 32 bits in this fixed length
like any good virtual circuit type
technology it's locally significant okay
so from myself to my next-door physical
router the label value exchange and use
on that connection is gonna be between
the two of us and that's it now the same
label value could be used on the next
link down right that's perfectly fine so
this is nothing really new from doing
ATM vp IVC is or del C's for frame relay
usually they're gonna change but again
they don't have to okay now they're a
sign-up stream now we'll see in a couple
minutes here I've got some slides that
show directionality okay because it is a
unidirectional thing you're going from
one spot in the network from yourself to
the far end of your connection so
there's some directionality there and
traffic's flow through this LSP they
flow in a downstream direction so what's
gonna happen here is we get to the
protocols especially for RSVP you're
gonna sign things upstream so in other
words what you're gonna tell your
neighboring buddy is here's a label to
use when you want to say me traffic on
this connection use this label value
okay so because you've assigned it out
of your personal label space you
understand what to do with that label
when it comes in the door and your
neighbor upstream from using they're the
same thing upstream from him and so on
and so on till you reach the top of the
connection now we do have four fields
here you get the label value itself okay
so we have 20 bits worth the label we do
have 3 bits which are technically
experimental but they're being used for
class of service okay so there is sort
of a mapping there between the default 3
bits for IQ precedents into these
experimental bits we have a stacking bit
and we have a stacking bit which implies
that you can have more than one emulous
label
header I cut to use those terms
interchangeably on a packet okay and the
truth is you can so I have the values
here if there's a value of 1 that needs
you the bottom of the stack which means
beyond you is the layer three protocol
information could be active v4 could be
whatever if the value is zero then
what's beyond you further into the
packet is another MPLS header and we
have some time to live okay so time tool
is important because just like an IP
right we don't want stuff flit around
the network all day long it's eight bits
just like we have for IP and there is a
mapping for IP TTL into the MPLS TTL and
by default it's gonna decrement one
along the way and it's gonna go hop by
how does it translate back yes it does
yeah you can traceroute fluid MPLS LSP
and by default you'll see all the hops
along the way no using standard a strap
standing right cmp if you wait to the
end yeah I actually have some routers I
can connect to and I'll prove it to you
so where do we stick this thing it's a
shim header ok the appeal of header is
gonna go between whatever layer to stuff
you got
okay so then applies Ethernet ATM frame
whatever you got it layer two doesn't
matter we're gonna stick the header in
between that in the layer 3 data and you
can have stacking right talked about a
second ago so here's just a little
graphical representation of having two
labels or three labels attached to an
individual packet now as far as routers
are concerned and we'll see this in a
second here when I have the trance I
don't really have one of these good
diagrams by default when the riders
gonna do it looking I look up on the
header information we're gonna be
looking at this top label okay so even
though I had them listed left to right
here in reality you have the concept of
the top label which is the thing closest
to the layer to header and on the bottom
you have thing close to the layer three
data okay so if you're reading some of
the specs and things says bottom of
stack well you're on the bottom you're
close to the layer three piece most
times when you have multiple labels
you're talking about say a VPN
environment there's a good example we
have multiple labels I do have some
slides in at the
presentation of doing an LD P connection
over RSVP game that makes sense when I
get to the end and again that's a double
label type environment so label space we
got 20 bits all right so we got lots of
space to play with there are from 0 to
15 are defined by the ITF and
technically 4 to 15 are reserved and
aren't used right now so we only really
have four well-known label values ok
label value of 0 is specifically for
ipv4
it's called explicit null and what it
means is when I receive a label value of
my function is to remove the MPLS header
and do an IP lookup I mean within the
little space you got 20 bits worth the
space that'll be a value of 0 well yeah
because you got 20 bits it's got to be a
0 so one would be you know zeros on a 1
at the end so your value of 0 in that
space
and it's defined for explicit no ok the
zeros does show up in the label value
and we'll do uh apartments sliding in a
second here about how to use that value
bonus router alert which pretty much
says if you get this Center to the
control plane okay or the routing engine
or the brain of the routers got to do
something with this and that's not
really widely used today
no no um no that's ok
the explicit Knoll says that if I'm the
end of the tunnel ok I'm going to signal
upstream use the label value of 0 yeah
yeah ok and I got some slides and I'll
talk about that a second some label by
u2 v6 it's supposed to know does the
same function as before except this for
a c6 ok label value 3 is implicit null
also signaled by the egress router now
label value of 3 tells the next upstream
router the penultimate router in this
case again I got some slides come and so
on
using terms I'm not going to define yet
to do the removal of the MPLS header
okay and send me whatever is left so
instead of doing the removal at the
egress the end of the tunnel you're
actually pushing it up stream by one
router by the speck you will never see a
label value of three show up in an MPLS
header okay you signal it you tell the
router to use label three but that's
really an indication to do this removal
function okay so you'll ever see a label
I you three words opposed to leave a
value of zero you will see a header show
up for the label value of zero now it's
got to be the bottom of the stack
because by the by definition when you
remove the header you have to do an ipv4
lookup okay
so you can't have a zero value somewhere
higher in the stack so we got a bunch of
these rules to play with and we'll see
the difference between a 0 and a 3 in a
second now other than that
from 16 always the top of the space can
be used dynamically to start handing out
labels okay and every vendor does it
differently for juniper we started a
hundred thousand four dynamic allocation
you can't go up from there we do this
remaining set aside for doing static
LSPs we have some ranges set aside that
we don't use for reserved stuff now it
doesn't mean if somebody tells us to use
a label value in our quote unquote
reserved spaces we're not going to use
it sure we will it just means that we
won't allocate from our own space
upstream one of these label values are
there any interpreter standards for
labels no you don't really need them as
long as everybody can use from 16 on up
oh you're talking between a s's no
that's kind of a cap hearing
relationship me if you want to do that
then you establish with your pair okay
so we have these nice fancy terms we
worried about and in reality you could
probably bill the rest of your life
without remembering in this stuff and
you'll be ok but for sake of
completeness all right let me go through
them real quick we have the concept of
how do you hand out labels
okay so label distribution we have two
methods to do that we have downstream on
demand we have this thing called
unsolicited downstream or downstream
unsolicited depending on which specular
they actually use both terms so
downstream on demand is pretty simple
you will only allocate a label when your
upstream router ask for one okay so I'm
going to ask for a label and I'm gonna
expect to get one back
that's downstream on demand unsolicited
downstream is the opposite of that which
is you don't have to be asked you can at
random well there's some rules we do for
LVP and how we do this but theoretically
speaking you can just allocate a label
so here's a pretty fixtures a label have
at it use it if you want to
that's unsolicited downstream worse
downstream on demand there's an explicit
request and the sending of a label value
so we'll see we get to RSVP how
downstream on demand works will seem to
get the LVP how unsolicited downstream
works okay so they use different values
their label retention if you're told
about a label value what do you do with
it okay so you have this liberal mode
which is I'm going to keep everything
ever heard of ice conservative mode
which is only going to keep the stuff
I'm actually using so here we have this
an old age-old trade-off right between
memory and failover speed if I'm doing
conservative mode I conserve memory all
right so I'm only keeping a subset of
stuff in memory but if one of those
links goes away or my neighbor goes away
that I have to relearn and the label
value still use something else guess
that takes time whereas liberal mode I'm
using that memory hanging on these
labels but in a failure mode I can
quickly switch over to something else
label control so retention is how I am
stuff label control is for me when you
actually send labels okay so even though
I said in downstream on solicited or
unsolicited outs
that you know you can just randomly send
a label that's a sort of okay in reality
you're gonna have to abide by one of
these things at the bottom here either
order independent okay and an ordered
very simply says you can only send a
label value in two cases one you're the
egress you're the end of the tunnel
which means you can start advertising
labels upstream or two you receive the
label already for a specific IP prefix
you can allocate one from yourself and
send it out okay which basically ensures
that if you get a label in inside the
header you're gonna know what to do with
it because you've allocated a label for
it independent is sort of like a very ad
hoc system just at random totally random
I can just start allocating label for
prefixes even if I'm in the middle of
the cloud I'm nowhere near that you
dress so theoretically speaking somebody
could send me packets with MPLS pardon
me headers attached and I may not be
able to afford it on to the actual
egress router okay so we don't really
like independent we do ordered because
whatever things are good but it's there
okay so yes and label reflects the end
point from the egress of perspective
sure but in the middle not necessarily
okay label value you simply just I was
told a label I'm gonna allocate label
upstream guess I'm doing some swapping
stuff
okay so point to points yeah it's point
to point so in the downstream on-demand
case you and I have a connection and I'm
going to ask you for labor you're gonna
give me one okay so you're gonna hear
the issue of mapping the prefix to the
label is the job of the ingress rider
the top end router okay
so exactly right so if it has multiple
paths to multiple different
LSPs tunnels through the network and it
hears about prefixes for multiple places
its job is to make its own choice that's
which way to go
no there's not really multi-point
capability now it's all points myself
sir independent yes you got me yeah
seriously
I don't see any valuable purpose in
independent I'm sure there's a reason
why it's in the spec somebody probably
insisted on it being there but from an
operational real-world useable
perspective I have yet to find a really
good need for it okay okay because we're
sticking this MPLS header between layer
2 and layer 3 when something shows up at
my door I gotta know it's MPLS ok I got
to be able to know that got to look in
the switching table to figure out what
to do with this thing and don't do a
routing lookup ok so this is here for
your edification there are predefined
hex codes that we use at the base PPP
level all right we got Oh to 81 there is
actually an MPLS control plane piece ok
so that's using a to 81 everybody else
uses 88 47 not gonna spend too much time
talking about that so this is my
connection in LSP a label switch path ok
this is my tunnel it is unidirectional
goes from Azusa router to the far side
and that happened to be using the bottom
path
this is the effect this is the end
result okay so this is the the traffic
flow if you will okay from the left side
of the screen to the right side and
whether you're doing RSVP or LDP what
we're going to end up with is LSP is in
the long run okay so terminology
everybody's favorite topic the start of
the tunnel starlit connection is the
ingress router this is where packets get
mapped so it's the job of the ingress
router to do this mapping between IP
prefix or prefix is to the LSP okay so
if I have LSP a b and c and i decide to
send traffic for ten 10/16 down LSP a
that's my decision okay and when the
writing look up comes in and I attach a
label it belongs to the label I heard
for my next downstream router on LSP a
it is the hidden router that's a term
that people use a lot okay it's the goes
into router because traffic goes into
the tunnel alright so let's get the COS
into thing going okay upstream upstream
downstream we do have directionality
here okay so from the perspective of the
routers further along the LSP if you
will okay the ingress is the most
upstream you can get okay so yeah this
upstream downstream that's going to be
important we start talking about RSVP
okay because messages flow either
upstream or downstream depending on what
their function is now we had this
functionality called the label push this
is the fancy way of saying let me add a
label
okay so whether I have a native IP
packet and I'm adding a new MPLS header
or I have an existing packet with an
MPLS header on it and I'm adding a
second or maybe a third MPLS header it's
a push operation okay so you push it
onto the top of the stack
in the middle we have transit routers if
you want them okay you don't have to
have transit routers technically you can
go directly from ingress to egress and
they're directly connected
that's perfectly allowable and I
actually know some people that are doing
that mainly for statistics reasons
because everything else is Ellis bees
but if you have them you can only have a
match of 253 any idea why we have this
constraint TTL is a pretty good answer I
only got eight bits to play with the TTL
255 - ingress and egress leaves me the
rest in the middle
MPLS only switching oh you can still do
that
Oh in other words can you go and buy a
box it only does that and doesn't
understand IP don't know don't know we
certainly don't so the job of transit
rider is to do what we call label swap
operation okay now if you can think
about label allocation okay let's look
at this first transit router here when
we establish this LSP and we'll talk
about that in a second it allocated a
label upstream to the ingress okay
pretty much said here's a label to use
if you want to send me traffic for this
connection okay so when the ingress ads
label push this header ships it on down
to the first transit router it's gonna
do a switching table lookup got into
label value got it on interface X
reference out in the table and being a
transfer router is going to have on the
outbound side and outgoing interface and
a label value to use okay the label
value to use outbound is what the next
downstream neighbor told me to use for
that connection
labels have local significance okay and
typically we're doing things in a per
box basis yeah that's supposed to per
interface basis okay so we're gonna swap
operation label and ylabel oh okay
and traps are gonna flow downstream next
physical hot now the router who's first
upstream from the egress router has a
special function special name the panel
tonight router okay so a nice latin
thing if the last one is the ultimate
router next one upstream is the
penultimate router okay that's all it
means ultimate the pedal taut router can
either do a swapping operation as a
regular quote-unquote transit router or
it can do a pop operation which is the
removal of the MPLS header okay and the
function it's going to perform is going
to be based on what the egress router
tell us to do and we'll see in a bit
there's two ways to do that you either
tell the penultimate router send me an
MPLS header which case he's doing a swap
or you tell the penultimate router to
not send me sort of an MPLS header kind
of painting with a big broad brush here
so which case I'm gonna do a removal
operation okay now the thing to remember
about this removal operation and we call
it penultimate hop hopping there's
there's a nice acronyms for you right
now can I'm happy the function the
pulper outer is take off the top label
and send whatever is left downstream
okay so whatever is left could be an IP
packet could be a packet with another
MPLS headers on it okay not the job of
the penultimate to make that decision
tear off with top label and some
whatever's left so the egress router yes
sir what's the advantage of penultimate
hop hopping PHP give me two seconds I'm
getting there I got a slide so the
egress router is the mirror of ingress
okay this were packets leave the LSP
this is the tail and this is a good goes
out of router
yeah it's downstream of everybody else
and we have the label pop thing okay
potentially
okay so the removal of lables lable pop
so we're all we're good we got labels
ingress transit penultimate egress
okay so ultimate pop popping versus
penultimate hop popping ultimate hop
popping means the egress router itself
is going to be doing the pop operation
this would be the one tearing off the
MPLS header okay so what's going to
happen here is the egress router is
going to signal a label value of zero
upstream for this LSP connection and
when traffic gets to the penultimate
router it's gonna do a label swap
whatever label came in is going to be
swapped for a label value of zero okay
so the packet that actually is
transmitted from peltzman to the egress
router has an MPLS header on it by
default just one actually by spec just
one it isn't the bottom of the stack of
all zeros and the label value eg our
adder receives us in label value of zero
says do a pop followed by an IP lookup
clustal service is way outside the scope
of today's talk that's why you probably
keep it yes that's really good reason so
we're gonna wrap you look up on the
egress router in our ipv4 routing table
forward based on whatever that says yes
yes
it is it is well there's two ways to
play play there by default our boxes
it's maintained if you run with our
defaults it's maintained because it's
also two zeros but you can't go box by
box and make it do something else okay
so why do pelts with hop hopping well
what if this egress router had thousands
and thousands and thousands of LSPs
terminating on it it's doing lots and
lots and lots of popping operations okay
so let's pass the buck let's move let me
slide forward two slides here let's move
the functionality of this pop-up stream
so specifically it's really helpful for
stuff that's not a sick base right
because we do a CPA look CPU lookups on
the egress router doing lots and lots
and lots of pops gets kind of bad so we
just we're gonna pass the buck okay move
it upstream so going back a slide the
egress router is going to signal a label
value of 3 what that tells the
penultimate router is your function for
this connection is to do a label pop and
for whatever is left to the egress okay
so whatever is left is ipv4 the egress
router simply does a v4 lookup Merry
Christmas find the next hop and off we
go
if whatever's left happens to be an MPLS
header then the egress router does a and
peel us what you look up finds a label
value and off we go so that's all we're
saying here we're passing the buck now a
label value of 3 is never going to show
up in an MPLS header it can't by
definition
okay spec says no can't do that bad bad
driver
so the signaling thing and all the show
outputs you'll see label value of 3 but
don't actually use that to transmit
packets ok means PHP do the pop and
throw so if didn't answer the question
okay
hardware routers it's not as much of a
big deal yeah right but most folks are
doing this by default ok yes sir
okay when I'm ah so I have a single hot
bellows piece what we call it right
ingress to egress okay if the egress
router signals label value of three what
that means is I'm supposed to do a pop
operation but if I'm getting an ipv4 I
don't really add a label so what it
turns out to be is regular before bond
both sides of the link okay but
technically from the ingress writers
perspective I forwarded across an LSP
so all the traffic stats for that get
allocated for that LSP so if you're
using it for traffic stats stuff that's
pretty helpful okay good question
okay so let's look at how we send IP
packets well the total here I've
established in LSP from left to right
the pardon me the values but the
interfaces are the label values that
were allocated okay so the egress sent
advertised label value of three
penultimate router advertised next value
and so on so on okay so that's what
those values are so IP packets shows off
on the ingress doesn't writing-table
look up and finds this subnet one into
168 1/24 destination of the IP packet is
wanted to a sixty eight one one so cool
founder out my next hop is the LSP
so my functions do a label push add on a
label and on a header and I still gotta
hit earth got a label value of 101 456
and I forward it to the next downstream
router both the transit routers in this
case part of me do label swap operations
they understand the labels that came in
because they're the ones that allocated
them so we swap 101 56 for the next one
in line again
pardon me swap 108 101 for the next one
in line now we come to the penultimate
router
got a label value in over 100 thousand
and one it's switching table says do a
pop okay so it tears off the top label
throws whatever is left downstream in
this case happens to be an IP packet
okay so we need to buy P shows up the
egress router will do a regular v4 route
lookup we find a next top off we go
okay for our transition - how do we set
these things up any questions on
terminology label values I'm on the
ingress and I want to figure out what
the path is through the network doesn't
spit out LSP mappings not exactly
if using RSVP you can see what hops are
taking but you have no idea in the
middle on those transit routers what
label batteries are being used unless
you go to the transit rider good
question okay so signaling protocols are
CP okay resource reservation protocol
pretty well-known originally designed
for end hosts in a network to be able to
allocate resources all right set up a
connection between themselves for the
transmission of packets we had this
notion of policing and bandwidth
allocations your resources are allocated
which works really well to enterprise
environment but you know in the intranet
or an SP environment you may not want to
let your customers dictate how the
resources on your riders are allocated
most people kind of have issues with
that so RSVP in its native form is not
really used for this what we did was we
extended the protocol okay we added
extensions to it specifically traffic
engineering extensions and now instead
of two pcs being the end hosts of this
connection now we have two routers
specifically the ingress in the egress
router being the endpoints of our
session now of our RSVP connection and
between them they'll hate resources and
that's cool because you own all the
boxes in between okay so we don't have a
problem there because it's supporting
traffic engineering we have the ability
to exactly map out what links in the
network to use for forwarding we do have
this notion of bandwidth reservations
which I'll talk about in a couple slides
from now and we're gonna allocate labels
along the path of the LSP okay and it's
downstream and on-demand functionality
is their dynamic bandwidth response sort
of let me get to that I get to the
bandwidth slide
another popular protocols LDP label
distribution protocol as far as a
protocol state compared to RSVP it's
more lightweight but the downside is you
don't have traffic engineering built
into LDP okay so you're forwarding
things using labels but they're
following the IGP shortest path or
whatever your routing normal v4 routing
best path would be for the destination
how can we determine that good question
can you wait till I get to the end okay
if you want to do te stuff with LD P
there is a version called constraint
routing LDPC l DP okay the only real
problem here is it got limited support
from vendors like specifically on our
t-series routers we don't support that
on our eseries routers with you and
what's not mistaken there was a decision
in the working group to say okay it's
defined it's built but we're not going
to develop it any further so it's just
sort of kind of laying there and maybe
it'll die a slow death somewhere I don't
know yes the use for acquisition was are
you serious boxes so let's talk about
RSVP first because there's a lot more to
talk about with that there's a lot more
that goes into it yeah
popularity that's uh that's kind of a
sticky wicket both our customers do both
and some networks using combine most
will pick one or the other some of the
issues involved interoperability okay
MVP is more widely available for Interop
so maybe that's a decision they go that
direction if they need to do traffic
engineering or one or traffic
engineering then they'll use RSVP of
course and there are versions of code
values and things that will interact
with that too okay so of course there's
no clear answer they're far away
use your IG PDS traffic engineering sure
sure yeah if you're happy with the
actual links that are being used for
forwarding in your network then yeah you
can use LTP you don't have the ability
to explicit pass stuff yeah no you have
an LSP it's a connection from you to
someplace else well that's an
implementation dependent thing for us
we're gonna do a random choices like we
do in our regular routing table okay so
if I have three possible ways to get
there
for an individual prefix I'm gonna pick
one
okay so the connection from ingress to
egress an RSVP session okay it's this
concept of a session this logical
connection from ingress to egress and
it's defined by a couple things we have
the destination address so the egress
router ID typically is what we're
talking about there's a tunnel idea
signed by the ingress router okay then
we had this concept of protocol okay
most of times you're going to see a zero
there but technically these three things
define a session okay that's the logical
connectivity from ingress egress and all
the routers along the LSPs path know
about this session and our maintaining
protocol state for this session now
technically speaking you can have
multiple senders assigned to this
session which some people think whoa
wait am i got these multiple physical
boxes all sending stuff down the same
LSP not exactly we're talking about here
is from the single physical ingress box
multiple paths for this LSP so traffic
engineering things I have can have a
primary path and a secondary path say
those are different senders from the
perspective of our STP and we allocate
them differently by this LSP ID value
okay so the ingress router the ingress
router picks these different LSP ID
values based on which path it's using
within the confines of a session so I
have secondary path there fast reroute
detours or another way to do that okay
so there's some advanced things that you
can do with different senders
technically now once you establish your
session that's the point at which two
neighbouring RCP routers become
neighbors okay so you don't do any LSPs
in your network and you run a command it
says show me on my RCP neighbor he's not
gonna have any that's not to say they're
not there they only show up after the
LSP is established so let's get a little
bit kind of different construct than
we'll see in LDP so a couple of message
types path and reservation messages this
is how we're gonna establish our session
okay so we're going to stablish the LSP
path messages flow downstream they're
dressed to the egress router in the IP
header they have the router alert
option turned on that's what allows
every router along the path to look at
this
RSVP path message and begin to establish
this protocol state to establish the
resources for this session
this is IP it's our FTP it's using IP
information okay it's using IP routing
to get from point to point well you have
to have some kind of ITP knowledge to
make this work yeah yeah I mean you
can't just the transit may not have to
carry the full BGP table right exactly
or any IP routing knowledge outside your
domain MPLS can't work without IP I
usually hate to say in like absolutes
but 99% of time yeah you need some IP
knowledge to set up your LSP in the
first place okay yeah yeah to set up the
LSP you need IP stuff what to set up
then you're not really using IP so what
I hate to always say always it always
get me in trouble
so after path messages go hop-by-hop
down straight to the egress router the
router knows it's the destination
because that's the destination IP in the
path message it generates a res be
message a reservation message and surf
before that back along the path of the
LSP technically these are addressed
hop-by-hop okay we'll see how that works
in a second and the reservation basic
part of me the resume message is
basically locks in the session if you
will okay so the path message is sort of
like hey I'd like to establish a session
okay cool we like to do some
establishment when the res B's come back
upstream you're actually locking in the
session information okay so here's where
we're doing our label allocations
because we're doing that upstream okay
here's where we're reserving our
bandwidth if you're going to do that
the path is determined by your IGP or by
some constraint that you put on the path
in this automated path yeah I could just
say starting ingress go to egress make
it happen yes yes so once you do this
you have an LSP a single operational LSP
if you want one to go from the rider on
the right side of the screen to the left
side the screen you set up an additional
LSP over on the right side and you'll
send path messages this way downstream
and Reza's DS back upstream to the right
and now they have to LSPs each of which
has a separate session information each
of which is allocating protocol state
etc etc when you're setting this up okay
you're gonna say I want to get to this
egress IP address okay you need to have
some kind of IP knowledge to get there
oh that's also like be based actually
subsequent messages are actually
exchanged post a hope neighbor to
neighbor I can see it coming yes
no you send them hop-by-hop there are
the path messages destination address to
the egress so everybody along the path
knows where I get there
but they are sent hot by hot it's a
single path message yes no it's a single
path message all the routers in the
middle it can inspect the contents
because of the router alert option sort
of look when I get some RSVP objects
like explicit rod record route we're
going to modify some of those things
okay
yes the router ID the egress address is
an IP destination I agree what do mean
by setup for before you establish the
LSB now everything as far as RSVP is
concerned it's its IP you can doom to
ITP load routes so but for the purpose
of transmitting RSVP it's still an IP
thing so there is a way to set up this
LSP to the e to the egress and have this
ingress router when you do a ping say to
the egress address go through the LSP
sure but there are a few protocol
packets don't do that okay so I know
it's kind of a weird thing but trying to
abstract protocol establishment
maintenance from user packet forwarding
questions are good because this is not
like you know super easy stuff okay so
here we have our LSP setup okay from
left to right and we get some back Oh
interrupts okay
backhoe interrupts right we lose we lose
the link or a neighbor technically
somewhere along the path okay so this
basically will tear down the LSP this
breaks the session this breaks the
connection and we're gonna have these
tear messages and we have a path tear
which follows the original direction of
the path message and removes the
protocol State okay so if a path message
as protocol state path tear takes it
away
and the same thing for a res me tear a
resume established protocol State res B
tear takes it away okay so from the
point of failure propagating to ingress
and egress we have these ter messages
which basically removes all knowledge of
this RSVP session okay so no longer
viable we don't have a link to transmit
across anymore now we also have error
messages error messages just alert the
ingress or the egress to an error
condition okay they don't do anything as
far as adding new or removing protocol
State typically and this isn't always
the case but typically you're gonna see
error messages during the establishment
phase of an LSP so if for instance I've
told my LSP I told the ingress router to
get to the egress following path one two
three and it gets to the second router
in line and it looks at this information
I gave it saying oh I need to get to
router three next but I'm not directly
connected around a three hour I don't
know how to get there I don't have a
route whatever you can't for it on the
packet that's an error condition so
you'll stop processing and you'll send a
path error message back upstream to the
ingress router other error times you
might see the error messages if you're
doing say a fast reroute type detour
it's kind of an advanced topic but
another way to get error messages when
you're not doing a session establishment
okay but typically you have problems
sitting at the session that's all Aran
messages do just just alert you
um you can do message bundling okay to
add multiple individual messages between
you your neighbor so you're not
constantly sending stuff there are
timers involved here with how often you
send that reservation message and stuff
yeah so there's some sanity there okay
now I didn't want to get too gory into
details here but I do think it's
important to talk about the contents of
these RSVP messages okay technically
speaking we have this kind of TLB type
construct we call an object there are
some that are required some that are
optional okay so for path message right
path message from ingress to egress we
need a session object which is going to
contain stuff about the session right
destination IP that tunnel ID value we
talked about okay so the session thing
has got to be there it's kind of
important that's how you identify the
resources for the LSP
we do have an arts to P hop which is how
you're recording who your next
downstream or next upstream neighbor is
technically this has changed hop-by-hop
okay so this is how you get packets back
upstream go from router a to router B
with a path message it has router aides
interface address in it router B
establishes a protocol state and it's
part of that says oh my next upstream
guy is router a and here's his IP
address there's an interface address and
router be sent that same path message
from router C it's gonna change the
value in this object and put its own
interface address there that's how a
Darcy knows who's that upstream guy is
okay so when you get to the egress you
start sending the residues back that's
how we know the exact path to follow
back to the ingress router okay with
this hop object sender template it's in
there to define who the sender is hey
it's there Ella spits we can put the LSP
ID with this T spec object if you're
doing bandwidth reservations that's
we're going to put the value of
bandwidth that you're trying to reserved
and we have this thing called a session
attribute where we have some priority
things where you can define this LSP is
more important than this other LSP and
you can kick somebody off the network
that's where that information the store
now technically speaking these were all
defined originally for the spec we did
extend them for traffic engineering so
to understand things like tunnel ID
values and things like that in addition
we have some things that we want to care
about for an LSP first of all we have a
request for a label that's pretty
important because we're doing downstream
on demand okay so as the path message
flows to the egress router each router
knows ooh when the residue comes back I
need to allocate a label here RSVP runs
right on top of IP so it's neither it's
a dumb protocol don't know yeah I don't
know if there's been das attacks against
our CP stuff good are you making sense
yes you're gonna be sending these
messages using IP routing so if you have
a route we're going to send it whether
it's a private address or not if
somebody gets in and does malicious
things to your network for IP routing
purposes they could interfere with RSVP
you can do md5 sure between neighbors
yep explicit route this is the power of
RSVP first doing traffic engineering
this is the way that you tell the LSP to
not use the ITP shortest path go here
first go here second go here third etc
etc so you get to egress okay so this
explicit route objects euro this is the
way we do traffic engineering you can
manually create this or you can let the
router do it for you
and we'll talk about ways and how that
works okay so you have either manual or
dynamic creation take your pick lastly
record route this is the way the ingress
router knows whose along the path for
one for two we're gonna use it for loop
detection okay so much like in BGP we
have a s path right you get in a message
you look in the a s path if my onus is
there this is a loop flowed away same
kind of concept here if you receive in a
path message or res B we'll see in a
second
and you look in the record route object
and you find your own IP address there
this means you've already seen this
piece of information specifically within
the session okay so we're talking within
the session not overall RSVP this is a
loop throw it away this will generate an
error message okay not not establish the
LSP so we don't do looping by default
can't ever make it happen okay on the
return path the res b-side we're gonna
have again the session because that's
our unique identifier are gonna have the
hop information again this is
information up so you know who your next
downstream routers IP addresses we have
this thing called a style okay and this
is how we're gonna allocate and pardon
me some bandwidth things you either have
the default which we call fixed filter
which is for every unique sender to the
egress that's a separate bandwidth
reservation okay so we have a primary
path bandwidth of ten maiya gets ten may
used up you have a secondary path for
those same ingress egress sessions and
you ask for another 10 Meg that's now 20
mega used up okay you add a third path
ten more mega it's 30-minute that's
fixed filter every unique sender to
egress it gets its own reservation stuff
the absolute that is shared explicit
which is for the multiples of senders to
the egress okay again within the session
here okay but you can have multiple
senders primary secondary secondary
third fourth paths we're gonna share
that bandwidth reservation okay so
you're not going to do this double
counting function so those are your two
options it's carrying the resident
flowspec this we're gonna have our
bandwidth information that mirrors the
stuff in the sender spec the LSP IDs
carry the single the filter spec so we
have different names pretty much the
same information the label hey that's
kind of important okay in the path
message we asked for the label is a
label request and the residues were
actually doing the allocation and it
gets contained within a label object so
whatever the value is you're gonna stick
in that twenty bit value that's what you
stick there and we have a different
record route okay so we recording split
path backup this is in case you have to
get paths down on the way back something
changes routing changed you lost a link
before you can establish the LSP okay
you start writing things differently
just a next extra added protection yes
sir what I'm doing what specifically
okay so during so during the
establishment session or once it's
already established okay so what's up I
got a break okay yep okay it's going to
depend on the ingress routers
configuration
okay so more than likely you're gonna
try and set up a new LSP to the egress
along some other set of physical paths
okay yeah you're gonna tear down the
whole SP you gonna build a whole new one
along some other set of links
generally speaking okay okay bandwidth
or is like talk about bandwidth when it
comes to RSVP yes sir and a new link
will I move LSPs to that that are
already operational you have that option
by default no but a fault one struck
they're gonna stay where they're belong
you have the option of moving them over
if you want to no you told her out you
tell the ingress router you got new
stuff reevaluate the network links and
it'll pick a new path
yeah LSP is up okay okay what do you
mean by note by the paths no longer
valid like a router in the middle dies
that's the same thing as a link failing
yeah yeah the whole L speeds got to go
away the those terror messages the path
tear on the reservation tear yeah see
how you detect the failure is kind of
going to depend right
if the link failure and it's a sonnet
you're gonna find out right away if
you're going into a switch there's some
timers there when you have to hear from
your neighbor if you lose the hold-down
you lose the neighbor relationship then
you'll start CERN sending terror
messages upstream downstream our ship
he's got pillows and keeper lives right
now free for you and your neighbor okay
so you can have multiple sessions Volker
lsps between your neighbor you only
really need to know if he'd the
neighbors alive okay okay bandwidth this
is always a fun topic to talk about
because what's your affecting here by
these bandwidth reservations is whether
the LSP gets set up or not that's it end
of story
nothing else happens okay I didn't want
to put it red or make it any bolder than
that but we're not doing policing ok
routers along the LSP don't do policing
now can you police before you get into
the LSP chirp that's no problem there
can you know by some means network
monitoring that traffic that you want to
put on this LSP normally average is
about 10 Meg sure you might want to set
up a 10 Meg
LSP okay so some of the people that I've
talked to that are actually doing
bandwidth reservations that's kind of
what they're doing they know that for
the types of traffic they're going to
put on this LSP the average data rates
are X and so they establish LSP is based
on those rates and so that they know
that they're not going to over subscribe
any links but again we're talking
averages nothing says that you can't be
transmitting full
or from two different ingress routers
hit the same link and over subscribe it
that can certainly happen okay you're
playing the numbers game
can you change without taking down the
LSP yeah okay you can if you have stats
from down and doing some monitoring
things on the ingress router you can
monitor how much actual traffic you're
sending you can automatically adjust
those bandwidth values
okay if you've turned on the statistics
and things like that
that's the ingress router the ingress
router you can tell the ingress router
to monitor the stats on this LSP you've
allocated ten Meg right now and if over
a period of some time it ever just say
20 Meg then recycle the LSP and ask for
more bandwidth yes you can
well is there a way to limit stuff you
pretty much talk about timers okay like
you don't want to do it every second you
don't do it every minute typically if
you want to do it maybe even once a day
yeah if you're doing it too fast enough
in the mode of who this stuff is unused
you flow your traffic here and then
suddenly that's unused and you throw
your traffic back here and then then now
this is unused in right he said they're
shooting in the network and trashing is
bad okay so you want to be kind of
predictive light and by the way you have
to turn that you have to really ask
nicely for that that's not the default
default is your land bandwidth and it's
there for the life of the session if you
wanted this minor thing you have to ask
nicely the bandwidth the setup by you on
the ingress a customer can ask you out
of band but it's not running to an RCP
there yeah sir
yep yep it's establishing definitely
yeah I mean you'll refresh to make sure
your neighbor still alive we keep the
protocol state alive but as long as
everybody in network runs and there's no
failures it'll just stay up forever so
you have to go to the ingress and tell
the ingress please turn this down okay
er oh who that pick up the pace zero
this is how we do traffic engineering
okay this is very much like loose and
strict source routing for IP stuff okay
you can define loose hops within the
confines of your network which says at
some point from ingress to egress touch
this node or touch these two nodes or
touch these three nodes okay you process
it in order okay with this loose concept
we also have the functionality of doing
a strict hop which says you must be
directly connected to this next address
I just gave you okay so you can define
go loosely to this first route or go
strictly to the next one and then
loosely someplace else that's fine you
can define if you want to strict from
ingress to first transit strict to the
next strict all the way along the way
and that's how you get this non IGP
shortest path thing if you're doing
loose you're using your routing table to
find the next hop and to get to the next
hop okay so if I said get from A to B
and some point touch router C then
between a and C we're doing IP routing
lookups to figure out how to get to C
and then once we get to see we're doing
writing lookups on how to get from C to
the egress so along the way there for
loose hops we're doing IP running
lookups if if you said I want to touch
router C at some point and writer C is
not there you're hosed yeah you won't
ever set up the LSP
yes
you're specifying IP addresses okay so
typically for a loose hop you're putting
out of the loopback ID get there somehow
for strict talk you have to specify the
interface addresses every next-door
neighbor okay
so here's an example I want to get from
writer in router C and my ero currently
says use router D loosely okay so I
firmly my path message the destination
address is still the egress router C but
because I had this ero I have to do a
radical look up and say how do I get to
router D no I turned out to be directly
connected to him so I've put on the
router Dean rider DB receives this it's
got the writer alert takes a look at it
says oh look
has his ero and the only thing listed is
myself okay cool I can now ignore the
rest of the ero because there's nothing
there now I need to get from myself to
the egress router I do a routing woke up
okay now assuming that we have Ollie who
equal cost links here I could either go
through router be router e right that's
a choice based on what the routing
tables decided on router D happens to
picky and we set up the path along the
bottom
okay so strict is what you would expect
I got to be directly connected okay so
from the ingress router I said go to D
strictly then go to B then go to even go
to C so I'm good this nice little
serpentine path to my network and every
router along the path when it inspects
this path message is going to examine
the ero okay so first right on line D is
going to get it and say oh the first
address is D strict is that me if it's
not this is a bad yarrow I can't do
anything with this I have to stop
processing and send error messages back
to ingress but it is D in this case so
process of the path process the path
message and now go to for about to the
next hop be technically speaking we take
these information out of the ero
okay so here we're modifying an object
again we've poured it on try it or B
does the same thing a my next and so on
and so on only to get to the egress
now you can mix and match if you like go
to D strictly and then from there get to
be using IP routing and once we get to
be use IP ready to get to the egress
okay
so totally cool mix and match no problem
there now if you're gonna manually do er
OS
you got to really know what your network
looks like okay you got to have
knowledge of how things are set up
because you can end up in problems for
example go to be loosely then de loosely
okay so the path message end up on
router e it's the last thing in the ER
oh its job is to go around and look up
to get to the egress rather see in this
case which says go back to B he's gonna
forward the path message back to B these
gonna look in the record route object
and find its own address for that
session and go you know what this is a
loop we shouldn't do this stop
processing and send error messages
okay LSP will not be established in this
case so make sure you know which it's
apology looks like yes well the old
speeds not established at that point so
their error message is just telling the
ingress router hey I couldn't establish
this okay and it'll try well in the case
of you defining the ero it's going to
keep trying that path forever okay but
if you do some automatic stuff depending
on the situation you may be able to take
it from path
yes topologies changing a lot of times
manual arrows can become a hassle that's
where these come in really handy
okay automatic gyro basically we're
talking about here is the ability of the
ingress router to automatically figure
out how to get to the egress okay
specifically for RSVP we build this
thing called the traffic engineering
database and we populated with
information that's transmitted inside
the eye GPS themselves okay so for OSPF
we have typed an opaque LSA area scope
we're going to flood this stuff within
our OSPF area and that information to
specifically put into this Ted if you're
running an Isis Network you have two
different TLDs okay one for Isis
information one for IP information 20 to
135 and again this information gonna be
populated into this Ted okay so you have
your you still be regularly state
database now you have this special ten
it's gonna contain things like current
bandwidth available current priority
values things of that nature sir I
believe so at least we in Cisco do
what's it so who I'd wreck the connector
to because you have to make sure you
have a path okay so you have interface
addresses there you have router IDs you
have bandwidth information priority
values we also have this thing's called
administrative grouping okay you may
know it as affinity classes you may know
it as colors may notice administrative
groups lots of different names all means
the same stuff okay all this information
is stored in the tip and when you tell
the ingress router to go from yourself
to the egress it's going to consult this
database and it's going to use a
modified version of SPF called
constraining shortest path first OC SPF
to figure out how to get from the
ingress to the egress and the result of
this see SPF run is an ero a strict hoc
arrow detailing every exact node along
the way okay
now by default if you just say get from
ingress egress go it's probably going to
follow the same path that your IDP
shortest path because the same values
the same topology exists okay but you
can supply constraints
you can apply some of these
administrative group things you can
apply
pardon me bandwidth reservations those
are constraints that you provide to see
SPF which alters the output okay we'll
see how that works in a second
so the algorithm in sort of a very nice
high level you have this tracking
database if you've asked for a bandwidth
reservation on your LSP the first thing
I'm going to do is go to this Ted and
we're going to tear out of it all of the
links which don't meet the capability of
your bandwidth request okay so if you've
asked for 20 Meg's say on your LSP and
there's a link in the network that only
has available 10 Meg left we're going to
take that out of this the Ted okay
technically we have this little subset
of right this separate data structure
we're going to tear the information out
you can't use that link does I'm not
bandwidth request enough bandwidth
available so if you have bandwidth
you're gonna do that tear all those
links out then the next two have to do
with those administrative groups as
colors okay if you've told the LSP to
only use links which contain this group
value say gold links then every link
which doesn't have that value doesn't
meet the constraint it has to be removed
from the tip okay sort of a reverse
logic there but if you asked me to do
this link color if you don't got it you
got to be taken out you don't meet the
constraints then if you've told me to
avoid links with a certain color say
management links then I got to remove
those links that do have management on
them okay where that root value assigned
to them so what I do is I prune out
based on my constraints all these values
and now in love with the subset of data
and now I figure out how to get from
ingress to egress on the remaining set
of links stole could might be the IGP
shortest path might be some other
serpentine path of the network now in
addition to this
well if you still reach ability sure
you'll establish it well you're not
really excluding the path you're
excluding certain links in the network
from from LSP being able to use them oh
if you've got a stub and you exclude the
link to the stub then you can't you
never each ability to stub me more you
won't set up the LSP now number four
here talks about manual arrows you still
have that ability okay I can still say
get from router A to B and touch see at
some point we're going to go through and
do our pruning functions and they're
going to run CSP F from the ingress to
the first hop in my manual you are oh
then we're gonna do a second CSP F run
from the gyro the first time I arrow to
the egress okay if I've defined multiple
year loose hoppy arrows manually we're
gonna do mostly CSPs all along the way
when we're done we're gonna combine it
all back into one big ero so we're
taking all these little subsets of runs
we did we made it from ingress to egress
following some paths that all meet the
constraints we have a explicit round
object that it statically pardon me
strictly Maps out all the hops along the
way
see SPF is bounded by your IGP so either
your OSPF area or your Isis level you're
bounded by the scope of the Ted okay yes
sir not to my knowledge I think so yes
but it's very interactive
how about that the extensions are
defined so what you put into the Ted is
defined how you actually use that
information as vendor-independent okay
so how about that the algorithm yeah
okay the LSA is and the Isis teal these
are to find yes sure sure
now if the end result is multiple paths
in my network I got to make decisions
now okay because the end result has got
to be a single way to get from ingress
to egress so I go through all my
constraints I go through my manually
arrow and I still have multiple ways to
get there first I'm going to do is check
and see already these multiple paths
through the network does the egress
address I'm trying to reach match the
last top address okay now if you're
doing loopback egress routing none of
them will but you can't set up an egress
as an interface address okay in which
case if path one two three are available
to get to this Ingrid egress node and
you've told the egress address to be the
IP address of this interface we're gonna
pick Path number one okay so that's
really what that one said that first of
all it says but if we're doing loopback
egress addressing that doesn't help us
so now we're going to pick the fewest
number of hops physical hops if we still
have multiple paths at that point then
we're going to come to this nice little
load balancing thing it has to do with
your bandwidth reservations in there's
lots of gory stuff that goes into number
seven here but at a high level random is
the default which means you'll just
randomly pick a path statistically over
time you've load balanced stuff across
your network okay very consistent with
what our BGP transit traffic load
balancing thing does or you can
configure this thing called Moscow which
means move the LSP to the link which has
the most reservations currently on it in
other words fill up my pipe first then
go and start filling up the second path
then go and start filling up the third
path the opposite of that is least fill
which is put the LSP where there's the
least amount of current traffic well
current bandwidth reservations okay so
number seven is very bandwidth dependent
but if all this random works pretty well
if you really get into the gory guts of
least we will still a lot of Peaks after
I finish explaining it like in a
training class people go hmm
I'll stick with random so okay no
problem so anyway you have an arrow when
you're done now admin groups hmm what's
your transmitting inside OSPF and Isis
is this 32-bit vector okay with a zero
one turned on at every bit position so
from position 0 31 that's what you're
really transmitting ok now local to your
router you're going to give up these
nice fancy names gold silver best effort
management don't go here Jo Bob call
whatever you want to and you're gonna
sign that name to a value and then
assign that to your interface but in
reality what you're transmitting in the
Ted is this big vector so you can define
this link as a gold link could be a gold
and a best-effort link you can put
multiple values on that same physical
interface that's fine so when you look
at the Ted you're going to run through
this include exclude stuff you're gonna
figure out hmm
this router has gold on this interface
it's connected to this router does this
router also have that same bit value
turned on if the answer is yes then they
agree on what that value is and you can
use that link if you've asked for that
color or that affinity class whatever
you're calling it so if you have
multiple values either as use gold and
so use gold or silver sorry Falacci lore
on these crude side same thing exclude
management or exclude best-effort okay
so you can define multiple things to
include erected watch alors you take the
included exclude and them together so
you have two both and if you look at the
algorithm steps you'll see that right
you have to satisfy both the includes
and the excludes but within the
individual include actually we have
these logical whores
so examples that always helps here's my
nice little sample network and watch the
colors define
notice one link down here has both
silver and best-effort on it I'm trying
to get from C to E and all the weak
metrics are one so we'll just even
things out here also notice from C to D
there is no color to find at all
that's perfectly allowable now I decided
to include it sorry I want to include
gold or silver
okay so gold or silver so the first
thing I have to do is remove from the
Ted links which do not have gold in
links which do not have silver okay so
that's what the next slide is going to
be the removal of those links from the
network okay so I'm left with a subset
of information now I go shortest path
from A to C so it goes sorry from C to e
so I get the a and D D technically has
multiple ways to get there using ITP
metrics it's sort of to go to G and E so
because I said include I tore out links
which did not have either my colors on
the exclude side last four excludes I
have to remove links which do have that
value so if I want to exclude
best-effort I have to take out the links
which have best-effort on it which is a
whole one link so that goes away we
should write across the middle now if
you noticed in the include my CD link
had to go away because it did not
include the color but for excludes no
harm no foul if they have colors listed
and of course I can combine both okay so
I should include gold or silver which is
what we saw a second ago and exclude
best-effort so all mine on gold the
silver links go away my one link with
best effort which was my d 2g link is
now also gone away
and now I only got one way to get from C
to e now if one of these links that I'm
using right now say had best-effort
assigned to it you can't sit at the LSB
I don't have a way to get from point A
to point B using the constraints you
gave me yeah you asked for too
restrictive of information
include actually correct okay um config
stuff let me actually start talking
about LDP real quick but basically you
need to tell the router to support the
protocols
okay so family MPLS on our interfaces
the Junos boxes turn on our CPA MPLS on
the operational interfaces for iOS stuff
at the global level and the interface
level you got to turn on MPLS traffic
engineering
okay so you define the path to the
network you give it a name can you
define what the hops are you loose
restrict and the IP addresses that go
along with them okay and this one here
is the reference of that user-defined
arrow to the LSP creation okay so here I
have this thing called user-defined
arrow and I apply it to my LSP
so get from this ingress router to the
egress router whose address is 192 168
32 one using this set of loose hops
can't go to 29th one first then a 24 1
then this to 36 10 to 40 okay
that is true the short answer is Isis is
on by default for OSPF to turn on the
traffic engineering command at the
global host PF level okay so LDP kind of
a whole different construct here okay a
whole different construct from our CP
here we're going to have the concept of
two neighboring routers either
physically connected or Canberra remote
becoming LBP neighbors okay so you're
gonna start sending out multicast you
24:02 to the UDP port 646 packets saying
I'd like to do LDP I'd like to do LDP
I'd like to do LD P until somebody
responds okay usually when I'm training
I just do this into other students pipes
up but I don't have time for that now
okay so when somebody finally responds
does a cool would like to do LVP as well
you then have this neighbor relationship
okay now a couple things happen here one
we have this at the very bottom bullet
this console with an LD PID value okay
that's how you're defining your label
space am i doing per box or per
interface allocations okay we'll see how
that works in a second the second thing
is we have this concept of how are we
going to form this follow-on LDP session
so we're gonna have a session to worry
about we're going to be the source
addresses and destination addresses for
this session you either use the IP
source IP of this hello message or you
can include this thing called a
transport address which pretty much says
if you want to form a session with me
use this address
so I'm flinging hellos I hear from a
buddy we now become neighbors now if I
happen to know I want to become
neighbors with somebody on the far side
of my network I can do this thing called
a targeted hello which is a unicast from
you to that guy same kind of information
transport address label or LSP LVP ID
okay that router does a a targeted hello
back to you now your neighbors okay
so you either multicast or directly
connected or unicast for remote stuff
now once you form a neighbor
relationship you're gonna have a session
which I'll talk about a second sorry I
forgot about the slide ldpi devalue okay
kind of critical six bikes by default
it's four bytes of your router ID
followed by two additional bytes so we
have IP address : and a value value of
zero and those last two bytes means I'm
doing per box label allocation okay
that's our default so we're gonna get a
zero there pardon me so this becomes
important when you start setting up your
sessions so two guys will become
neighbors they know each other transport
addresses they've also learned what the
LDP ID is for each of these neighbors
the routers are the neighbor with the
higher radder IDs and we come with a
call the active node it's gonna set up
the TCP session okay so we don't have
this closing connection thing going on
the active node sends TCP same port 646
to the neighbor setting up this LDP
session okay now if you have one I have
two routers with multiple physical links
between them they'll form multiple
neighbor relationships which will end up
with one LDP session okay so as long as
there's at least one neighbor
relationship the session stays up so if
you lose one leg who cares you lose -
who cares three new peers if you lose
the last one then the session goes away
so once we decide who the active node is
we're gonna start sending these
initialization messages okay this
basically finalizes the session setup so
this is kindly BGP right TCP then bgp
open messages so same thing you do TCP
then you start flinging these LTP
initialization messages and inside that
you're gonna include a couple of things
you're gonna say here's my local LD PID
and I'm trying to connect to this
neighbor who advertised earlier this
other LD PID what version or on version
one of course we have this help this
whole time I'm going to negotiate so we
know the sessions up but this is the
thing I include in my initialization
messages and I flee it to my favor so my
neighbor the passive node in this case
gets it in and uses these LD PID values
to know which exact neighbor is trying
to establish the session okay so that's
why those LD P values are important way
back in the hellos
so assuming that I like me being the
passive node all the information that
was advertised I said to keep live back
saying check like what to sent me the
passive mode is going to generate its
own initialization message with the same
information send that pardon me to the
active node if the afternoon likes it
sends keep alive once we've done those
things
initialization to keep eyes back session
is up okay session is up and operational
at that point and only at that point
does label things start to become
important okay you can't former paper
relationship you can't form a session
nothing's gonna happen beyond there so
building up the block here so now that
we have this session the first thing I
do is I got to tell my neighbor what my
interface addresses are we're gonna
start using this for some of this how do
I pick the IGP path okay so here's me
here's my IP addresses on all my
interfaces pardon me I'm gonna send that
to you in this address message and
you're gonna send it to me in an address
message so now I know I start to build
some kind of topology information and
have a reference for when you send me a
label in the future what physical next
step should I use to reach you cuz you
said to me what physical address should
I use in this address message so once
we've done that then the important stuff
happens as far as MPLS is concerned we
start advertising labels now we're gonna
send both a prefix and a label value the
prefixes contained in this nice thing we
call effect
remember effect from way back when
earlier runned about 90 minutes ago
that's a prefix it could be your
loopback address could be some other IP
address it's up to you to define what it
is by default we do loopback addresses
so what you're basically saying is
here's an IP address here's a prefix and
here's a label to use if you want to
reach that prefix and you send it to
your neighbor so even though the
neighbor didn't asked for it not down
stream on demand it is an ordered thing
because we have this established session
I didn't fling them of a label randomly
we had a session we've agreed to
exchange labels
okay that's the key that's the key to
making this all work so I send a fecking
a label neighbor sends me fecking a
label we're happy now if I have other
peers who I'm have sessions established
with they've sent me their fax i'll riad
ver ties those facts to my new neighbor
by default there's a full mesh of
connections and you'll end up with a
full mesh of LSPs okay so we don't
really do the split horizon thing I'm
going to send you my stuff you're gonna
allocate labels for everything I say she
would send it right back to me okay
we're gonna advertise we're gonna put
all this stuff into an LTP database okay
so for every session I have I'm gonna
have here the labels and FEX I sent out
I'm gonna have here the labels and fix I
got in for that session and for a second
session when I have the same information
and for a third session etc okay for
some of these sessions I got none of all
these entries in my LDP database saying
here's the stuff I sent here's stuff I
got okay so that's what this is so by
default let's say we've got ten riders
in a network
everybody's running LDP we all four
neighbor relationships we all form
sessions you should be able to go to any
individual router in that network and
have effect and a label for every other
by default loopback prefix in that 10
router network which means you will be
the ingress router for nine LSPs one to
every other router in the network
whether you're physically connected
side-by-side or whether they're four or
five hops away now because we have this
conglomeration of information we do have
this possibility of doing routing loop
issues
okay so here's we're going to combine
those addresses we sent earlier with our
current routing table okay that's how
we're going to avoid writing loops okay
we'll see that a second here's a nice
snapshot of the database so I have two
routers one two sixty eight sixteen one
and twenty not one have a session
between themselves the first chunk here
is the input side okay so 20.1 has sent
these addresses and these label values
notice it sent label value of three for
itself right we are doing cage B here
and on the outbound side 16 has
advertised these prefixes and labels
okay so 20.1 sent a label value of 3 to
16 he allocated a label value in this
case 100,000 won 12 right here and
advertise right back to 29 1 okay now
he's not 20 not wasn't we're gonna use
that because that's me
I don't you tell us beat it myself but
we aren't advertising that information
okay so we're gonna consult the
writing-table and figure out alright I
was advertised this effective say wanted
to is 68 1 1 kind of label value for it
cool do I know about 180 168 1 1 in my
writing table if the answer is yes then
whenever my next hop is in the writing
table that's the label that I'm actually
going to use in my old EP database ok so
has a construct let's say I got in 3 5 3
sessions I'm getting 3 different labels
right labeled 10 20 and 30 from my from
my peers and I got three interfaces
interface right 10 20 30 volts make them
on that job and to get the one into a 68
1.1 I'm actually to use interface 20 the
guy in the middle that's my writing
people says so even though I've heard
labels on all three sessions I'm going
to install in my switching table but
when I heard for the interface that I
use for my IP stuff now I still keep
these other ones remember that's our
liberal thing I still keep knowledge of
those other labels in case interface 20
goes away IP writing is going to be
converge on a new interface and that new
label is going to be assigned as my way
to get along the LSP so just a quick
example here this goes back to the how
do I pick one I got interface fast easy
0 0 and 0 0 1 for LDP isis says use fast
e 0 0 0 that's the way I'm going
um doesn't extract things helps kind of
sorta it's more like a consultation
thing it speaking of course the high
level here and without going into gory
details okay yes sir
well sort of
I mean you're gonna set up a session
with your neighbor most times he's
directly connected to you okay so just
like an RSVP you have the concept I'm
directly connected to somebody how it
comes to using the advertised prefixes
however that's where the big difference
comes in okay so for RSVP you're not
going to necessarily use say the
loopback of a transit router when you're
mapping on the ingress how to use the
LSP where an LD P you are because he is
also an egress as well as a transit okay
yes sir okay well the LDPE
I got a full mesh yep well so what I've
got now okay if you want to talk
specifically for for the Junos boxes
we're gonna end up with this is my net
three Ronnie table a loopback of
everybody else in my network okay and so
whatever protocol by default BGP is
gonna reference that that's you're gonna
map stuff okay yes ma'am
yes and I got I got two more to go
super go okay so real quick if you want
to do te for for LDP and you don't want
to do CR LDP okay you have the option of
tunneling LVP through an RSVP LSP oh I
know brain twister okay so basically
what you got is this BL DP Network and
somewhere in the middle you set up RSVP
LSPs now you have to have bi-directional
here so you need two of them at least
okay and within the RCP that's me too
your traffic engineering the ingress and
egress routers become LVP neighbors and
set up a session a targeted hello
session between themselves okay so what
it looks like graphically is pretty
simple I'm running native LVP from A to
B they become neighbors and have a
session I'm running LDP natively from E
to F they become neighbors and had a
session I'm running LVP between B and E
using these targeted hellos they set up
a session okay so from the perspective
of the LDP database I got three links
right a to be B to e e to F so for LDP
to forward traffic from A to F I'm going
to send 100,000 583 then 100,000 and 1
then rather easy to do a pop because he
sent label 3 right so from LDP's
perspective three hops 3 set of labels
but in reality to get from B to E I'm
actually tunneling within an RSVP LSP
which has its own set of labels that we
allocate a great path reservation label
request label objects ok so what you're
gonna see here is a concept of a stack
ok rider B is going to receive a label
of 100,000 583 it does a lookup in at
switching table and it says the first
thing I have to do is do a swap for my
LDP partner so it's going to swap
100,000 583 for 100,000 and 1 because my
LDP neighbor told me that label then
it's going to add its gonna do a push
and it's gonna push on the RCP label
100,000 6o 39 ok so it's a swap
pushing on the same router perfectly
cool for DeRuyter see does a swap for to
write or D now he was told from RSVP
label of three so he's gonna pop off the
RCP label and throw whatever is left to
his neighbor which in this case is a
labeled packet and funny enough writer
he gets this and gets in this label in
one hundred thousand and one which it
knows about because it Ella cated VL DP
doesn't look up does a pop because
Randolph told in the pop any four words
I Peter address less protocol state on
the edges of your network okay cuz if
you only have say if you have a bunch of
pops and from the pop routers in your
core you hope you full mesh the RSVP
stuff in the pops themselves as run l DP
and letter let it go and you end up with
a full mesh for everybody by default
okay so we've barely touched the surface
here there's a whole lot more for MPLS
which is way outside the scope
intentionally okay
please feel free to send me emails I'm
happy to answer any questions for
anything we talked about plus anything
it's on the screen ok if I don't know
the answer somebody else would I know
does know the answer ok so that's all I
got
thanks for staying late appreciate the
time