so just introduce myself my name is Mike
McBride I work in a multicast
development group and I'm on the
deployment team within that group I
spend the majority of my time working
with providers in the inner domain space
as they have deployed multicast so today
that's what will be discussed is
deploying multicast across the internet
between domains and I was both here we
go the agenda that will we'll go through
is will first talk about the protocols
that are used today to make multicast
work and that is multi-protocol BGP and
M SDP those are the two primary
protocols that are what is being used
today and what is going to be used in
the foreseeable future
I'll share a variety examples of
deployment scenarios of how this works
including how we're getting multicast to
work here at Nanog out to the out to the
world and then towards the latter part
of the presentation we'll be presenting
the the newer concepts of
source-specific multicast multicast VPNs
and even more recently multicast in the
ipv6 world so we have a lot to cover in
an hour and a half I'm going to be due
diligence and getting through it all I
may have to click through a few slides
rapidly to reach that goal but I think
we can do it if there's any questions
feel free to tal them out we won't be
able to spend a whole lot of time
getting into them but we can discuss
them as each section ends or feel free
to send me an email it's McBride at
Cisco comm or I'll be hanging around
afterwards feel free to to discuss
anything you may have question about
alright says since this is not an intro
to multicast presentation I just wanted
to give a brief overview of the piece
that we will be discussing today we're
not going to get into exactly how PIM
sparse mode works I'm assuming that
hopefully you already understand that
concept which isn't critical in
understanding what I'll be presenting
today but it does help so
the Campus side the enterprise side
there are protocols of course there's
hosts that desire to receive certain
multicast streams
I know popular one it with the guys that
I work with is you know the fashion TV
streaming you get to see all the models
cruising around on the on the catwalk so
your host needs to find out which group
this is so they're going to send an i
jean-pierre report once they know which
group it is that they want to join and
the IGP report will be intercepted by a
router and that router will subsequently
be able to afford that request out
throughout the internet drop the network
of course they're typically switches and
switches have been optimized with a
variety of protocols to make it so they
want to simply flood the multicast
packets like they would with broadcast
packets so there are protocols out there
that we won't be discussing today but
you can use to make it more optimized to
have them sent out the multicast packets
sent out to certain ports and then
there's multicast routing protocols the
protocols that actually do the
forwarding of the multicast traffic
there's sparse mode there's
source-specific mode there's
bi-directional Pam and the what we will
be discussing today is multicast VPNs
and then we get into where we'll be
spending the majority of our time today
and that is on the inner main side the
protocols such as multi-protocol bgp
which makes it possible that we can
control a multicast traffic between
domains and what the kiss source
discovery protocol which allows us to
discover which sources exist so that we
can join them and source-specific
multicast which I'll go into these some
more detail as well throughout this
presentation I've been asked to try to
keep this as vendor-neutral as as
possible so I've taken out a lot of the
configuration examples that were
specific to one vendor and so everything
that I am
so I've I think I've done a pretty good
job of making it everything that I'll be
presenting today is is true across
across vendors there are some slides
where I I wasn't able to remove certain
configurations specific just because it
I needed to have that to explain some
details so multi-protocol BGP sometimes
people refer to this as multicast BGP
and since that's the what we're going to
be discussing today that's really what
really what it applies to you for our
discussions multi-protocol BGP makes it
possible for us now to have a variety of
prefixes advertised we can include it in
an update now we can have V for unicast
s-- we can have V for multicast we can
also now have v4 v6 unicast a v6
multicast updates as well as you can tag
information you can have a variety of
updates within multi-protocol BGP
however you still need to have PIM to do
the actual forwarding of the multicast
packets and the neat thing about
multi-protocol bgp which we'll be going
into a fair amount of detail is that you
can use the same rules for BGP as you
can with multi-protocol BGP can have the
same policies and sing of my preferences
so with multi-protocol bgp now we can
have separate tables we can have a BGP
table use for our unicode unicast
prefixes to use for the regular unicast
forwarding and we can have a multicast
BGP table because we're receiving
multicast prefixes now within these
updates and so we can maintain a
separate table multicast BGP table that
can be used for our controlling our
multicast traffic do you have to have an
BGP to make multicast work across the
internet the answer is no you don't you
can simply use the unicast the regular
BGP protocol to do your RPF checking
throughout the Internet
but for those of us that want to control
our multicast traffic to either have it
go a certain path or to sign certain
policies to a multicast traffic you do
need to have multicast bgp just a very
quick reminder of how multicast reverse
path forwarding check works because it
is key to understand this is that if
let's say that I'm a router and my arms
and my head are interface it's tough I
get a multicast packet in on my left arm
before I forward it out my other
interfaces I'm going to do a reverse
path forwarding check and I'm gonna look
in my even my multicast BGP table if I
have it or I'll look in my unicast table
and I'll look at the source of that
multicast packet I'll and I'll decide if
that left arm that that multicast packet
came in on if it's the same interface
that I would use to get to that source
then I'll go and accept that packet and
send it out the other interfaces but if
the multicast packet comes in through my
head but the unicast routing table is
saying to go out my left arm to get to
that packet then though the packet will
RPF check fell that's a good thing it
prevents loops so all this that we'll be
discussing with multicast bgp cable this
makes it so you can control your traffic
in ways that you want it to be
controlled the way this works of the
multi-protocol BGP is that we have
address families now we have address
family one AFI one for ipv4 and address
family two for ipv6 and within each of
these address families we have sub
address families so if I receive an
update and if it's an AFI one with a sub
a of five one that's an ipv4 packet and
it's only used for unicast so it's going
to go into my unicast table for unicast
forwarding if I receive a packet with
say bail Phi two I'll put that in my
multicast BGP table so I can use that
for RPF checking and sub a if I three is
used for both will go into both tables
now all vendors have their way to be
able to prefer the packets as they come
in for reverse path forwarding with
multicast we have static routes static
em rail it's just like with with unit
so that we can force the youth RPF check
to go out a particular way and that
would have a default distance of 1 but
with this multicast BGP table we can now
have that as a preference and the way
that that works is if I have a if I
receive a multicast BGP update as well
as a unicast BGP update if they both
have the same distance the MB gpupdate
will be preferred and that will be used
for our RPF checks so that's again the
way that we can control our traffic by
default we'll do a distance comparison
between the tables with our
implementation you have to configure
another keyword longest match to make it
if you wanted to have a more unicast
like for a longest match prefix you can
configure it to do to do that there are
some scenarios or you may want to have
always use the longest match to be your
RPF check if you're sure that that's
going to be something that will be able
to handle multicast so there's a
capability negotiation that occurs
between between routers just as you know
there there should be so if both routers
are trying to establish a connection
with one another with BGP if they're
both specifying that yes I can
understand both unicast and multicast
updates
I'm multi-protocol BGP aware then the
capability negotiation occurs between
these routers and the sessions brought
up it's established
looking at this a little bit more
closely if I receive an update from a
BGP peer if it comes in with an address
family of one which is for v4 with a sub
a fi of one which is for unicast and go
ahead and put that into my unicast BGP
table now if I receive another update
with a sub B fi of two I'll go and put
that in my multicast BGP table for my
again my RPF checking and if I receive
one with a sub a v 3 then we'll go into
and do both
so we wonder why would you even bother
having you know running multicast BGP in
a environment where there's a concurrent
topology like your your unicast and
multicast traffic is going along the
same wing well one reason would be that
you may want to assign different
policies to your multicast traffic and
you would subsequently want to advertise
those updates to the rest of the world
with those with those policies so that
would be one reason apply the more
obvious reason that you would want to
run in multicast bgp is when you would
want to have your unicast traffic on one
link and your multicast traffic on
another link and so on one link you can
just specify this will be just unicast
only and on your other link you can
specify that it'll just be multicast
only sub AFI two so multi-protocol bgp
multicast bgp now it solves part of the
inner domain problem you can now control
your traffic sign policies to it just
like you can with BGP but we still need
to have PIM to do the actual forwarding
and b2b again just allows us to control
that traffic so that leads us to the
next piece of the puzzle that is M SDP
which is required so that we can
discover sources out there M HDPE is an
amazing beast it was meant to be a
temporary solution until something else
came out that would take takeover
originally it was thought that BGM P
would be the protocol that would would
take over to be used as a long-term
solution I'm not sure where BGM P is
today I don't maybe some of you you know
it seems like it's kind of died in the
ITF but what's happened subsequently is
the Emmis the different vendors have
optimized MSBP to make it more scalable
and to make it better or I'll talk about
the amazing spec but spec 20 was
published this week for M SDP I don't
know if that's a record or not but it's
been just hideous with trying to
have agreement and all different rules
and you know what it's just an amazing
process but MSTP isn't going to be going
away definitely not for a v4 we'll get
into what will happen with v6 toward the
end of this presentation but it's being
used today it's being used well if
you're if you regulate nit f you'll find
a lot of MSD P bashing but it's being
used in production and most people like
it it's just hard to understand and
that's why we're gonna go into some
detail so let's say that we have which
is the case we have a variety of
different domains and they're all doing
their own multicast they're all enjoying
receiving it they all have their own
rendezvous points but the problem is
they don't know sources that exist or
throughout the internet like you know
just different you know Microsoft and HP
they got their own sources and other
people want to be able to view those if
you're not within their internet how you
gonna give you that well that's where
MSTP comes into play let's say that in
domain II you have a receiver that's
wanting to join a particular group it
wants to receive fashion te so it's tend
to join to that domain ease rata good
point in domain a is where the actual
sources for this stream it starts
sending out the packets and it registers
to the right of a point in domain a as
soon as a register is received by that
rendezvous point in domain a it if it's
configured for MSTP peering with all
these other audio points it will send an
MSD PSA update a source active update
just letting everybody know in a small
packet that this is the source and this
is the group if you ever have a receiver
that's interested in this you know how
to get to me and I'll will will start
forwarding it throughout the internet
that router in domain a is the region or
originating RP that's important concept
to understand because that's what we do
our PF check against with regular
multicast packets as they come in we do
the RPF check based upon the source with
MSD P it's a separate RPF check it's
called an MSD P P R RPF check and we do
it on the originating R P so that's what
domain a is our P is so the essays are
flooded throughout the internet there's
a variety of rules that
have been hard for people to grasp to
make it so that these packets don't just
get flooded endlessly since these
packets do have a infinite TTL limit so
they would endlessly loop if there
wasn't this complex rule so the essays
do eventually get to domain II it does
have a receiver it's interested in
getting that traffic so it sends a join
if it's running multi-protocol beach
appeals from the joints throughout the
internet that way and the way that
sparse mode works is you cut over to the
shortest path tree of the main e and the
receiver is able to happily see the
fashion TV models walking along the
catwalk so that is s a forwarding for M
SDP again it does contain your not only
the source and the group but it also
contains the originating RP address it
will also carry the first multicast
packet which is a hack primarily for SDR
I won't go into the details of that but
it just makes it possible so that SDR
can it's it's bursty so that's that's
required so here we go for the next ten
fifteen minutes or so I'm going to talk
about some rules with MSD P and this has
been difficult it's it's I think I've
all presented in a way they'll be fairly
clear I hope it's cause for a lot of
confusion with for people in trying to
implement a misty P wondering why the
packets are getting dropped but there's
really just a few rules here that I
think I'll make pretty clear with the
variety of illustrations to help you
understand how M SDP works within your
domain whether it's just within your own
enterprise or as a service provider the
certain thing you need to do to make M
SDP successful so there are primarily
three rules it's really two rules and
I'll explain why that is but sometimes
you have an MST P P R within your own
domain sometimes you have an MS DP P R
outside of your domain and sometimes you
have an MST P period without being a BGP
pair at all what was decided originally
with M SDP is that we were going to have
our RPF checking based upon
bgp it's already out there in the
internet and so we'll use BGP as the
next hops and the advertisers of the
next tops as our underlying RPF
mechanism so it's very reliant upon BGP
there are a few exceptions however and
we'll go into detail on these but when
you're appearing directly with the
originating RP there's not a chance for
a loop so you'll just skip the RPF check
altogether there if your MSD PP r is a
mesh group here we'll also skip the RPF
check and if your MSD PP r is your only
MSD PP r there's no chance for a loop so
you'll also skip the RPF check so let's
get into rule 1 on how this works your
MSD PP r is within your domain it's a
internal BGP peer the rule with this is
and this is the most strict case within
your domain and there's ways again to
skip around this but within your own
domain you ask the router check to see
if your MSD PP or address equals the BGP
PR address if yes the RPF check succeed
if not it will fail let's look at this
in detail and I think I'll that make
this clear
so router G in a s5 is the originating R
P it has a source it's registered to it
it's a router G's address 172 16 6.1 is
the reasoning RP and it's going to go
ahead and for it out at the MSD psas
to the other RP is that it's appearing
with in this case a s7 it gets flooded
down into a s 100 and that's where our
focus is now is a s 100 router a
specifically so router a receives an MST
MST PDSA update coming from router II so
it has the choice now am I going to
accept this or am I not and we're going
to fill on this to prevent a loop
so what router a does is okay okay my
bgp peer dress is 170 216 3.1 I received
the MSD PPR dress
I received a mess DPS a update from a
peer address of 170 216 3.1 they match
they're the same
so I will RPF check succeed it's pretty
basic it's kind of anal but it's pre its
that it works which we made sure that it
was it has to be the exact address with
when it's within your domain now robbery
down in s 100 wool as it should forward
off that sa also to router diem out our
D before gone to router a router a will
get this si from two different MSTP
peers so the same decision algorithm
occurs in this case the MSTP peer
address 1 33 16 4.1 which is router D is
different than the actual BGP pure
address that I would use to get back to
the originating RP c router a in its BGP
table it says ok what's the best path to
get back to the originating RP
originating RP is router G up there in a
s 5 so the best path is saying to do
that would be to go to 172 16 3.1 which
is router AE so they don't match our PF
check fails and the packet is dropped as
it should be that's a good thing
continuing on with rule 1 a common
mistake and we've a question back
that's exactly right so the question was
is is the RPF check done based upon the
the next top it's actually and i'm going
to get into some newer rules towards the
end but it's actually the advertiser of
the next top in bgp back towards the
originating RP so it's all based upon we
don't care about the actual source in
the nest API RPF check it's the
originating RPE exactly right that's a
very good address that's a very good
question and we're gonna address that
right now because you are mystique
peering it could be on the loopback it
could be on the directly connected and
you know which one you're gonna use same
with bgp well that's a common mistake
and that was a great segue thank you is
that when a update in this case we have
our BGP pure dresses 172 16 3.1 let's
say it's a loopback address it's not the
next hop okay that's that's fine Miami's
TPP our address is 152 1621 maybe that's
another or loopback or some other
interface on the same router they're not
the same address so we're gonna RPF
check well it's extremely rigid on the
in your in the inner domain side even
though their addresses are on the same
box they're not using the same address
so that will RPF check fill so a common
problem is if you're using a route
reflector route reflectors become the
advertiser of the next hop they don't
become the next hop but they become the
advertiser the next stop so what happens
here well same problem is what I
mentioned before we've you know this is
a common problem when you're deploying
multicast in your domain is when you're
using route reflectors in this case the
BGP pure dress is the route reflective
172 16 1.1 your MST pure addresses
router over there they don't match so
we're gonna rqf check fail so what do
you do about that
there's a couple things and we're gonna
get you to med scripts but you can put
it into a mesh group let's as I
mentioned earlier we'll make it so that
you'll skip the RPF check you can peer
to the route reflector some people balk
at that they don't have to be appearing
always with the rail reflector but
that's one way to get around it but it's
just important that within your domain
that you use the same members DP pure
address as you would for your BGP peer
address and it's a common mistake and
it's you know it's just time to be aware
of so now we're getting to another all
this is really the only other rule you
really need to remember within your
domain you've got up here with the same
BGP address the second rule is when your
MSD peep here is an external address
it's outside of your domain how do we do
this RPF check back towards originated
RP what we do is we look instead of the
next instead of the advertiser of the
next top back towards an AARP now we're
looking at the next AAS in the best path
back towards originating RP so it's not
quite as rigid you don't have to be so
concerned about using the same ip
address it just has to be the next day s
and the best path back towards resuming
RP let's look at some examples to
illustrate this to make it clearer okay
so same scenario router G is the
originating RP either PEC the SA is
flooded throughout the internet it gets
down to router a and a s 100 that's what
we're gonna be concerning ourselves with
I need to make a decision as the SA
comes in from router e the decision is
okay I received the SA from 172 16 3.1 I
know that address is in a s 3 so for me
to be able to accept this packet my as3
better be the same the next day yes and
the best path back towards original RP
if it is all accepted in this case they
are the same and RPF check succeed let's
see what happens when it comes away the
other way around
yes three will flood that sa over day s
1 and s 1 will flood that packet down to
a s 100 decision process needs to take
place first day s and the best path back
towards visioning RP is still a s 3
that's the preferred route whether you
have it in em bgp or bgp whatever
whatever you're using but the a s of the
MSTP peers and asks one they don't match
so the RPF check will fail so this is
our way to make it so that our PMS DP
essays will not endlessly loop those are
really the two rules need to to
understand just kind of a slide to kind
of see what happens yes in back that's
right
that's that's correct so the question is
is you know this is based upon a s path
you know what the best a s path is back
towards visioning RP and that typically
if not always we need to be in software
and that would be true so looking at
this a little bit further is when you're
using your border routers for your
honesty peering you very quickly within
your own domain a s100 have to very
quickly get back to these very rigid
internal MSD be peering rules of having
to use the same IP address because
router a in this case becomes the
announcer of the next table so
everybody's got a peer towards that
address but if he peered further into
your network like if router e here
instead of pairing with router a was
instead peering with router B then you
would be able to skip all that having to
appear with all the exact IP addresses
and I'll illustrate that a little bit
more further cuz that's not commonly
done okay even though this next rule is
listed as rule three it really it's
basically just an off take of rule two
and that is when your MSTP pair does not
equal your BGP peer it's the same exact
scenario where you have to just find the
next day s and the best path back
towards originating RP and just hang on
what hang on with me for like another
five minutes we're almost out of this
tedious RPF check e but it's just kind
of important to understand if you
understand this you're probably the only
30 or so people on the planet to
understand it and you make yourselves
extremely valuable to people you work
with and this time of day that's kind of
important unfortunately so let's look at
that rule router a gets a si from route
or e it's not n bgp appearing with
router e it's appearing with router B so
it's a very reliant upon BGP so you know
how's this going to work what's the same
way router aides table will just show
that router E is the in as3 which is the
best path back towards originating RP
and the S of the MST PP r is an s3 so
we're going to
RPF check succeed
and when it comes around the other way
we will RPF check fail for the same
reason as in the rule to just happens
that we don't have a direct MPG peering
with them so the nice thing about this
and this is what's commonly used in
service providers today is they have a
group of rendezvous points within the
core of the network they're running any
cast of RP and all you discussed that in
detail and a few slides and those
routers are the routers that are
appearing with all the customers instead
of using all the border routers to MSTP
peer with all their customers that just
uses subset of routers you know 10 or so
or 10 or under are peas that are MSTP
peering and the nice thing about that is
since those are external MSTP pairings
we're just using the the next day s and
the best path back towards originating
our P rule we don't have to be so
concerned about the actual IP address as
with internal MSD be peering and router
he and router F would be in a mess group
so it would be skipping the RPF check
all together and you'll understand that
if you don't already get more detail but
that's this is a typical deployment
scenario and as our PF check works the
same as a previously previously
discussed
alright so mesh groups mesh groups were
created to cut down on SA flooding and
this is the intra-domain solutions a lot
of providers use this as well as
enterprises if you have a lot of MST
preparing going on they are flooding the
essays to one another eventually it will
stop but they are going to be flooding
as they should to all their M SDP peers
to cut down on that you can put them all
in a mess group and what happens within
a mesh group is if you receive an essay
from a mess you appear you will not
forward it out to any other message to
appear you'll forward it out to other
peers you may have outside the mesh
group but not to any others within it so
it cuts down the flooding and the reason
that you don't have to send it out to
other mesh appears is because you know
that they've already received it because
within a message group you have to be
fully meshed so looking at it in this
scenario if router 4 in this case is
outside of the mesh group it sends an
sa-2 router to router 2 has mesh group
peers router 1
router three that could be 20 or so
these peers but in this case there's
just three to illustrate it simply
rather to afford those essays - its MSD
P mesh group ears but router 1 and rally
3 will not afford them to one another
because they know that they've already
received them that cuts down on the
disait flooding but router 3 will send
it off to another MSD PPR outside of the
mesh group and there's there's some
examples configuration examples that you
can easily apply to other vendors but
just kind of illustrates how that works
so as I mentioned before we're at draft
spec 20 and it's just been an amazing
process of trying to get agreement and
just to get the darn thing closed and it
looks like as of this week it will be an
experimental RFC don't have a number yet
but it looks like we are finally done
what we did is we just basically took
out a ton of stuff and just try to find
a common denominator that we can all
agree upon and you know made a lot of
maze instead of musts and so y'all take
a look at that spec it's a it's pretty
efficient I've subsequently submitted a
multicast an MSD PBC P that's common
practice which discusses a lot of the
things which we are discussing today to
help understand how you would deploy it
came up on the mailing list that it's
just really difficult to deploy MSD P
that's the one of the reasons we hate it
so we need to have some sort of a best
common practice and so that's been
submitted David Meyer and John miler are
on that as well they gave it their
blessings so that's good so you can look
those up to take a look at
that's on ya
right so the question is in this back on
slide 38 router 1 and router 3 being
though they're in the mesh group peer
peering they aren't going to send the
essays to each other and the whole
motivation it's pretty simple is just
what you just said is just to cut down
an essay let's say you had 50 M SDP
peers they had if they received if
router 2 received that essay and had it
sent it off to it would have the Senate
it would set it off to all that semester
group if M SDP peers they would
subsequently send it to all the other
all their other peers and they would
send it to all their peers so if you
send it it be its scaling is what it is
exactly so it's if you have a lot of M
SDP peers it works good if you don't
then it's not that critical however it
is used than many can start Peas and
we'll discuss that also good question
all right so I'm this is the first time
that I presented this portion of the
presentation all these RPF rules that
I've discussed that presented to you in
the latest draft there's been some
additions to Tam SDP to try to make
things a little bit better and I would
assume most implementations now have
implemented these new these new options
these new rules and so in latest code
not what's up primarily not without
their today but without their today is
what I've just discussed but with newer
code that has the latest draft it's
compliant latest draft there's some new
things that need to be aware of one of
them is that we've taken out the
requirement of always having to use BGP
to do the RPF check now if there is no
BGP you can fall to an IG PDO SPF is is
whatever to the RPF check and that's
kind of cool we can now accept essays
from a BGP next-hop not just the
advertiser of the next top but the next
top itself and it will straight each of
these and there's also the ability now
of latest draft to accept essays from
the closest peer along the path not just
the next a s and the best path back
originally RP but any a s that's the
closest one in the next-best bat next
path back towards visioning RP so I'll
talk about each of them briefly and then
we'll move on out of the nightmare of
RPF checking so let's say again you
don't have BGP but you are winning OSPF
and you want to be able to use that for
your RPF check now and now you can you
can you can get to that so in this
environment we're not running BGP router
a gets an update si from router B
they'll just look in its unicast routing
table it does have a route back towards
originating RP which is 2.1 1.1 the MSTP
peer is also 2 2 3 . 1 2 1 2 1 and so
the Nats and the RPF check is successful
will forward that on to other MSTP beer
we can also use as part of the IGP check
the advertiser of the next top like OSPF
and is is where you have a router ID you
have that rip doesn't have that just has
the next top but with protocols like
OSPF you do have a router IP so you can
use that if you wish if that you're not
required just to use the next hop so
let's say 4.1.1 2 1 is a loop back on
router B we can peer with that the next
hop towards with it the originating RP
is 3.1 dot 1.1 so what normally we'd
fail but we do have the advertiser
originating RP which is for that one
don't want at once that we're all happy
RPF check succeeds so let's be aware of
that that's something that's if it's a
requirement of yours that you just you
want to be able to use an IDP then just
be aware that there's code out there now
that in the FT form that you can use we
can also now accept essays from the next
hop not just the advertiser next hop and
in fact next top is actually preferred
so in this case in this route reflect
your scenario router e is the next hop
towards the next hop back toward region
ERP the MST be pure dress is 172 16 3.1
but the bgp next hop is 172 6
3.1 so the reflector is the advertisers
are next top so normally it would fail
as I stated before but the next top is
if you're using like next top self is
the next top and we'll use that now for
RPF check just again just put that in
your bag of tricks and just be aware of
that and then yes yes it's
implementations lagging behind the spec
so implementations are now becoming spec
compliant as we've quickly tried to
bring the spec home into tow RFC status
which looks like we've done now and so
this option is now available to use if
you need to but if you were going to
implement with existing code today
probably on all vendors I'm guessing not
only ours the rules that I've mentioned
at the beginning is what you would need
to be aware of so it's going to be some
time before the the new code you know
how radical is that you know obviously
and you're usually in the in your
service provider space usually use brand
new code out there so well maybe maybe
live on the edge I don't know so the
last thing is to be aware of is that in
this case s1 receives an essay from a s3
in the existing rules if the first day s
in the next best bath back towards
original RPE is not your MST be peer
which would be router 2 then it would
fail because round 2 is the neck a s2 is
the next day yes and the best path back
we're judging our piece you'd have to
MSTP peer with a s - now we've relaxed
that a bit so just a no look at the ass
path just look at the closest a s and
just if that's good and behind just
let's just let's just use that one and
be on our way
so there we are that's MSTP we do know
what we're doing pretty good for time so
we've discussed the two protocols now
that are being used to make multicast
work across the internet if you have
your own
company and you want to start forwarding
multicast traffic out to the world you
need to talk to your provider and say
okay we need to start setting up some
carrying and I'm get an MSD Peep hearing
setup with you it will go over some
right now some examples different
deployment scenarios of how you'd get
this to work let's first go into any
cash star piece most of you probably
from so much familiar with any cast RP
any cast RP is a solution that was
created to be able to have redundancy
and load sharing what you with most
multicast you can have one rendezvous
point for a particular group it should
be nice to be able to have a variety of
you know rendezvous points the bill do
you use for for backup load sharing and
redundancy and that's what any cats RPE
function does is it allows you to assign
usually it's a loopback interface on
several lot rendezvous points let's say
to two or three or whatever and they had
the same exact IP address slash
thirty-two and your sources and
receivers will be directed just using
unicast routing towards the nearest
rendezvous point and if that one fails
they'll just be directed to the next
nearest one it's it's kind of cool and
all we'll look at an example of how
exactly that works it's very fast
convergence just depends upon unicast
routing that you're using so let's let's
take a look at example we have East
Coast and West Coast rendezvous points
and they have an MSTP peering with one
another they both have the same in a
cast RP address 10.1.1.1 so the
receivers on the west coast send their
joints from particular group and those
joins are directed towards the nearest
RP which is on the west coast same thing
happens for the receivers on the East
Coast a source fires up on the west
coast and the receivers on the west
coast receive that that traffic cuz
they're interested in receiving it but
the routers the receivers on the East
Coast have no clue on that source
existence because they're not using the
same actual rendezvous point
so that's why MSTP is needed the West
Coast run of a point will sent an SI
over to the East Coast letting that
router know that it has an active source
and if he has a receivers interested go
ahead and join towards the source which
it does and receivers get the packets
and if there's a source on the East
Coast the same process occurs so let's
say that router a dies
heaven forbid so what happens while the
receivers continue to get the traffic
because typically with sparse mode
you're gonna cut over to the shortest
path tree and the Ronnie of a point can
die you don't care you're just you're
getting the traffic natively for any
news sources they're going to be
directed over to the other Ottoman point
just as quickly as unicast direct Rodney
connected over to the other rendezvous
point so it's very quick fell over it's
very seamless and it works it works
awesome this is where I had to just put
in configuration commands that I was
familiar with just to kind of make it
clear all your router is within yes
question
yeah very good very good question I will
discuss it right now they'll answer your
question how it's good this the question
is that since we're using the same ip
address where they accept the essay from
one another if they receive the essay
from the same IP addresses itself no it
wouldn't so that's why it's important to
use a different address no illustrate
that right here so all the routers in
the internet within a domain and this is
commonly done is in a service provider
space typically we would recommend using
static configuration for your RPS
so they're all configured to statically
point to the one in the cast RP address
in this case 10 dot 0 dot 0 dot
your loopback interface on both
rendezvous point 1 and 2 loop X 0 on
both routers however are used for their
MSTP peering those are separate loopback
interfaces and they need to be used to
use your MST be period you use those
addresses because as was mentioned if
you were using your anycast RP address
as your MSTP peering address you would
fail because if you receive an essay
from peer that's the same as you that
would be a loop so you're gonna you're
going to drop it so your anycast RP
address is just use for anycast RPS
that's where all your routers in your
net point to separately you have a
loopback interface which you use for all
your M SDP peering alright let's move to
a multicast exchange environment we have
multicast exchanges throughout the world
there's the games multicast exchange
NASA its own familiar with mostly as
well as the Palo Alto exchange what they
do is all these here one providers are
appearing with one another or using n
BGP and MSTP so that they can have the
sources known to them as well
and
typically you'll have just a regular you
know switch everybody connected up to a
switch what is getting more common
nowadays like at star star cap in
Chicago I believe it is where they use
point-to-point VLANs instead for a more
deterministic approach to yard PF
checking the best way that it works
today is is just as it is with unicast
is you have your multicast exchanges
sharing essays and mpg peering one with
one with another for security with MSTP
we do have a recommended filter list and
there's a draft out now this one from
build nicholas has actually timed out
and I paint him and he's going to
resurrect that one and it's gonna be a
note too I guess but there's there's
certain groups out there that
particularly an application side they've
chosen for their application global
multicast addresses and so that's kind
of a bummer for the multicast and the
inter domain space because when they're
setting these the local RP will reg will
go ahead and send out essays about these
applications that are meant to be just
domain local so the whole internet is
hearing about these these applications
which they don't need any be hearing
about so as we find them and as well as
as well as other well-known groups we
add those to the list of recommended
filtering so that we prevent at the edge
unnecessary essays to be flooded
throughout the internet while we're on
the topic of MSD P and security there's
also recommend and recommendation to use
a sa limit all vendors that have
implemented s MSD P will have an SI
limit right now the essay counts is
typically hovering around 2500 essays so
people usually either choose 3,000 for
an MSD ps8 limit or maybe 5,000 just to
give kind of a room but it's possible
and it's happened in the past and the
things about a lot better nowadays but
it's possible that there could just be a
huge flood you know you get
you know 30,000 essays and that sa limit
we'll make it for that won't cause a
problem alright we're going to now
quickly go through a variety of
scenarios of deployment scenarios with
with multicast across domains this first
say that you have a customer who is
interested in
well you're the customer interested in
sourcing multicast or just receiving
multicast from the internet you don't
have your own RP you don't want to
maintain you on RP just want to use the
service providers rendezvous point and
there's fighter set fines go ahead use
ours so what do you do well you point to
their rendezvous point and so any
sources on your domain or any receivers
that send a join that will all be
forwarded off to their audit good point
those transit provider over here in a s
109 it has its dual rendezvous points
and you're pointing as a customer to to
one of those and so that the provider
will also be pointing to its own
inaudible points and both the customer
and the provider will be doing some
filtering they'll do the the filtering
for BSR border and the important thing
on that is as I had a nightmare one time
working with a provider where a customer
is using BSR which is an auto discovery
auto RP discovery program and that was
getting flooded into the providers
network and so it's wreaking havoc on
its own art piece and we don't know what
the heck was going on and the BSR border
command wasn't being implemented which
will stop it at its tracks it won't go
in or out when that border command is is
configured so that's an important one to
use a boundary of command is also
recommended to use you create an access
list and you filter out any multicast
group ranges that you want with with our
static assignments it's important to
have the override and this is another
thing that we were missing with this
provider is we were missing the override
command we have a static RP assignment
you receive adenine a mcli learned RP
whether it's through auto RPE or BSR and
that will be preferred unless you have
override on your static command if you
have override your static command that
static command will always be the one
chosen for your ERP that's the critical
to to use if you look at your RP mapping
you'll show the RP address of the
providers RP there's no MSD P running
here you're not running your own RP at
the customer site so there's no need to
have it so there's no RPF check the
multicast RPF check once the packets do
come into this customers site it will
just use its if it's running BGP it will
use that if it's using a default route
it will use that as it's just it's
regular multicast RPF check and the
transit provider will have a static
route for your subnet and advertise that
out to the rest of the world both via
unicast and multicast because the rest
of the world may assign policies to your
your updates so that's why they will
want to have yours be known to the rest
of world via MIBG B all right so let's
say the provider tells the customer you
know what can you maintain your own RP
already or just it's simpler just use
own RP or maybe the customer wants to
mean they're on to RP they want to have
more control over that so they do so
they create their own RP and they're
using multicast just fine within their
own domain and they want to be able to
advertise their sources out to the rest
of the world or receive information out
from the rest of the world so the same
filtering would apply but now we're
running MSD P because that's the only
way that we're going to learn sources
that exists out there in the world since
we have our own RP now we're on our own
Island we need to know what the other
islands are doing so we'll MSD beep here
with one another will have a filter list
to make sure that we don't get hammered
by unnecessary traffic will have our
miss TP RPF check if it's just a tell
site customer with one ms DP appearing
then the RPF check will just be skipped
because there's no need for a there's no
looping problem it's just one MSTP peer
the transit provider will be pairing
with you typically there would be beep
hearing what the customers originating
our
so there's no need to do an RPF check on
that either because it's there's no
chance for looping and then the
multicast RPF check will just be done as
before when the multicast do start the
packets do start flowing in though this
use your unicast routing table to do the
RPF check so this is the scenario of how
we're doing multicast here this few next
few days here at nanog the University of
Utah has has made it as provided the
network scenario we have an N bgp
pairing with Sprint they actually have
their multi homes they're preparing with
internet they got a link the Internet to
you as well but just to make it as
simple as possible we have a MPT
preparing with a border router within
Sprint we have an MST pairing with one
of the several RPS within the Sprint's
backbone we have the filters set up the
run of appoints the the Sprint's
backbone is running the thinny cast RP
as a mesh group going on these are peas
within the Sprint backbone are have MS
deep appearances with all the other
customers in addition to nanog and the
MSTP RPF check is done just as as we've
discussed the nanog router will just you
know use it it would have multiple MSTP
pairings because it has other other
providers out there so we'll just use
whatever the BGP route would take it to
get there it will use the Sprint's AAS
and the next best backdoor path back
towards originating RP if that does
happen to be the next day as the best
path back towards the ERP and then
Sprint's MSD be pairing with nan out and
the nanog AAS here would be the next day
s and the best path back towards
originating RP since then I gar P is the
original RP and the multicast RPF check
is is yes question the back
which we're all supposed to talk about
but yeah go ahead I'm just you know I'm
just joking all right it's
vendor-specific so just go who cares the
connect source address makes it so that
you can control which address is used in
the MSD P update so in this case in at
Nanog it sparingly 3.33 3 which is a
sprint router and it needs to know about
that address via BGP or M BGP that's
significant
that's just specifying an IP address you
could just as well specify an IP address
that's exactly right that's right that's
oh I see that ok yeah so there was no
confusion on the pause that's just no
that's like with the unicast you just
can specify instead of actually
specifying IP address you specified in
your face yeah I don't try to make that
clear next time so then the multicast
RPF check dis uses you know be TPM bgp
if it's there hopefully it is and where
you go another scenario is where you are
dual home one provider may be multicast
only another provider may be unicast
only you want to break it out that way
so you'll obviously just be MSTP peering
with the multicast only provider and not
the unicast only so you'll just be
setting up filters with that transit
provider
the MSTP RPF check again you just have
one MSTP pairing so there's a no-brainer
there's no there's no check necessary if
there was you just use em BGP and decide
which which path you should accept and
the multicast RPF check is done
similarly with with BGP and then lastly
which is most ideal is you have multiple
providers both providing multicast and
unicast transit
your peering with both ms DP as well as
m bgp setting up filters with with both
their advertising your networks because
they're learning about your network for
you at NB GP and you'll just choose the
whatever the a s is that's next best
path back towards written erp that's
what will be used to do the RPF the
winning of the RPF check for ms DP and
same is true for the multicast packets
which is again a different RPF check
once they cut start coming in will just
whatever is the best path that will be
the one that will be you chosen for the
RPF check so there's a variety examples
that kind of flew through those but
hopefully that gives you an idea of kind
of the deployment options and we'll
continue to talk about some more here
i've got a fly a little bit but we're
doing not do it too bad with time glop
you may ask with you know with unicast
you have addresses assigned by iana with
multicast that's not the case it's kind
of a free-for-all you've got this
multicast group address range and what
do you do so you know you could pick
some people could be picking the same
group address for the multicast sources
and there could be a conflict and that's
true that could be the case a a concept
of glop was created which has gone from
the concept stage to the implementation
stage
I don't think glop stands for anything
that's just an acronym I believe that
David Meyer came up with and it's a
temporary allocation of 2:30 3/8 and
again I say temporary MSD P was
temporary and it's going forever so
maybe this will last longer than we we
plan but it's just a way to allocate if
you have an a s
you can inject that a s into 2:30 3/8
and come up with your own slash 24 used
for your multicast groups the way you
figure it out is just you know take it
write it out in binary if you want or
hex and map the high-order octet at the
second octet of the to 30 3/8 address
and the lower lower order octet to the
third octet and you get your address all
these slides are should be posted by the
way on the site so you are you viewing
them where yeah okay cool alright so you
guys have them so you can review this
later if it's confusing at all but the
easiest way to do it is just to go to a
website from our friends at university
of oregon plop in your AAS and it will
tell you what your last 24 is for use
and again that's the recommendation here
there's been a lot of different
proposals in v4 for more dynamic
allocation of bad dresses
nothing has stuck yet and so we'll wait
and see if anything changes with that
any questions before I move on to the
last three sections here I've got about
a half hour all right on a router it's
probably vendor specific ours is six
minutes you'll stay in the cache and
then timeout if it's not updated once a
minute we send out the contents of our
si cache
it was specified in the spec that you
must cache yes a so
well you're not concerned about the
receivers you're just concerned about
the source so yeah okay sources so so
yeah and you register your receipt from
a source you're gonna go ahead and send
out a new essay it will be the new it'll
be an essay for that for that new source
because otherwise you'd be flooding all
the time so once a minute you play the
entire contents your essay cache if a
new essay comes in within that you're
gonna flood that so there all right
yeah you're still sending at least for
us it's the one that dealing and that's
been a Pacific I I don't know how other
vendors do that younger so
source-specific multicast it's a great
idea it's something that would have been
awesome if we come up with this years
ago we would have been able to avoid all
the rendezvous point mechanisms
altogether with the advent of IGP
version three host can now specify the
actual source that they want to receive
with AGP version one host sent a report
to the local router saying okay this in
the group that I want to receive you can
send me any source for that group it's a
stark emoji just any sources for this
group in IP version two it was the same
thing but the enhancement is that when a
host left a group it would actually send
a leave message to let the writer know
that I'm gone so you can send out you
can quickly prune me off or in version
one it would take several minutes for it
actually to stop forwarding onto that
land with version three the hosts again
can now specify the source and the group
I don't want to just receive any source
there could be a hundred sources for
this group and I have to receive them
all I just want this particular source
very cool source-specific multicast on
the routers make it possible that one
would received such an IP version three
join we already know the source we don't
have to go through this whole process of
trying to find out sending the packet to
the rendezvous point the receivers join
they're sent to the rendezvous point we
cut over to the source path tree we
already know what the sources we gonna
immediately cut over to the source path
reach towards the to the sources it's
very cool the last top router sends the
joins towards the source it definitely
simplifies address allocation if you
think about it if the two different
companies choose the same group two to
four de 1.1.1 who cares because they're
both sourcing it from their own unique
source and since this the host is now
specifying both the source in the group
it definitely solves that
it definitely simplifies that problem
and there's a variety of RFC's out there
that describe you two different versions
of ijp which we've discussed version
three is more and more prevalent now in
the stacks of various hosts we're just
now trying to push to get more and more
applications that are SSM or ijp version
3 aware so that we can start getting
this thing to take off in the inner
domain space because if there's not
rendezvous points needed then it
eliminates the need to even have MS DP
you don't need to have the SA feel that
we've all been talking about if if SSM
is used as the same is being used today
it's just not widely used as maybe
hopefully as more and more applications
get developed it will be used more
privately so the way that this works is
a sources firing off its multicast
content a receiver learns of this source
and group through some out-of-band
mechanism network administrators are
cheering because we don't have to deal
with having to have that around a bit
points there anything have the network
take care of it it's we're just letting
the receivers take care of figuring out
how they're gonna get the source and the
group advertised either via email or web
server or whatever so the receiver
learns what that sourcing group is it
sends an IP version 3 s comma G join to
its local router that local router is
running SSM so it recognizes that and it
immediately sends a join towards the
source because it knows what the source
IP address is traffic begins to flow and
those of us in the multicast development
group are out of a job because it's
extremely simple this is awesome and we
hope it goes nuts these are just
different drafts and whatnot that
specify where s SS SS m is and IgE v3 is
and it's supported in a variety of
router vendor os's we do maintain a list
of stacks
I did pv3
that's right in the pro-peace witches it
is getting there yeah the question was
is v3 now widely deployed widely
supported in vendor switches and the
answer is yes and no it is it is getting
there there are certain you know like
with us for instance it's you know it
makes sense to concentrate on certain
switches and make them v3 aware and
depending upon customer feedback others
may not be included in that so the
answer is yes I don't know if you're
running code right now that supports
that but but you could okay so this is
just a summary it is also just another
thought for security it also will help
prevent certain types of denial of
service attacks if I'm receiving a
stream I even if it in my own domain
let's say that I met a you know I'm at
my desk and I'm receiving a corporate
broadcast from the company CEO and it's
being broadcast out on TG 4.1.1 Taiwan
if I'm not running SS am and using v3
then some malicious co-worker could be
in his cube you know thinking a video of
his own head doing you know who knows
what and sitting for that same group and
jamming that content so I could be
receiving both and it could be all
messed up because I haven't specified
what source I want it just any source of
that group so that's one of the neat
things about SSM is that you've
requested a certain source and groups
would be much more difficult to specify
spoof both
yeah that's the question is can you run
the SSM with him well that's a good
point because that's the same is Pam
there's Pam sparse know there's Pam
dense mode which we don't talk about
anymore really it's kind of old school
and there's bi-directional Pam there's
source-specific multicast Pam there
different types of modes that yes can be
used in different parts of your network
so if you're currently using rendezvous
points which you typically would be and
you wanted to start introducing SSM then
you just mainly at first just need to
upgrade your border routers they're not
the border routers your last top routers
the router is closest to the receivers
because they need to be able to
understand the v3 joins and since SSM is
the 232 / 8 range you can just specify
this is my range that I'll be using only
for SSM and then in the long term you
can if you wished you can just open up
that range to not only include 230 but
for all your groups if you wish so that
would be a that is something that's
commonly done
of course we can have local SSS
so the question is is there been any
studies done or testing that has to do
if what makes sense when you know
depending upon whether you want to use
that's a sam or sparse node or any other
mode for that matter I think that
there's actually been some with us some
scalability numbers done but I don't
know what I don't know if that is but
SSM is designed for one too many you
know because it's you know one yeah at
what point is the one to many of the few
too many and the many to many
you know what point it's you know that's
I don't that's that's AG accident
question I don't think we have really
good answer for that it's just kind of
depending upon your preference you know
a lot of people that have many demand
either that's where they're gonna be
going to by directional pan and so it's
there's the logical solutions for
different environments inner domain
multicast is primarily a one-to-many
situations so SSM is ideal but the pipe
is not a bad idea to try to come up with
some sort of a study on what makes sense
number wise good question all right so
we've got about twenty minutes to
discuss these last two I think well I
think I'll make it so more and more now
there are providers using multicast MPLS
VPNs and up until now only unicast has
been supported in such a MPLS
environment and service providers were
coming to vendor router vendors saying
hey I've got these customers who we have
started implementing MPLS VPNs and they
want to now start running their
multicast traffic over this environment
and there's no switching of multicast
packets within the MPLS VPN environment
it's only unicast package there's no
there's no fixing the label to a
multicast packet so what we're going to
do about that we need to we need to come
up with some sort of a solution
well the workaround up until recently
has been just to create a bunch of
point-to-point GRE tunnels between
all the CII's which is if you have a lot
of CDs can be an administrative
nightmare and it's just not scalable but
that's you know that's what that's what
you would do and the supervisors and the
customers have come to us and said okay
so whatever your solution you come up
with to make this better instead of all
these point-to-point tunnels it needs to
be a solution where the provider can use
whatever pinmode he wants SSM
bi-directional Pam or sparse mode
whatever and the customers should be
able to have their own mode as well it
need to be independent not dependent
upon one another so okay we take that
and we'll make the implementation
support any PIM operating mode and
customer and provider networks so our
implementation as well as other
implementations are based upon multicast
domains specified in the ROS and draft
and it does just this and that is that
you've got your provider network and you
get your customer network and what we do
is when a multicast packet comes in from
a customer VPN well take that multicast
packet and encapsulate it in another
multicast packet for it across our
network D capsulated on the far inside
and send it off on its merry way and its
original multicast source mode so it's
what the solution is it's a dynamic
mechanism for creating tunnels between
the different TPEs per customer and I'm
going to illustrate it as we go along
here I think it'll make sense on how
this how this works it's being used
today in a variety of provider networks
so from a customer's high point of view
what they have is they have their own
independent VPN for both unicast and
multicast they have their own color and
it's it's being being forwarded from the
providers perspective of what they've
done is they said okay for a blue
customer I'm going to use a particular
group address 2:39 dot one dot one dot
one for the blue
murders for instance so again when
multicast packets come in from the blue
VPN and I want to transit my MPLS VPN
core i will encapsulate it in 239 dot
1.1.1 which will be that only that
address will only be used for the blue
customer and that will be sent to the
other pease that lead to that customer's
remote locations and then for other
customers will use a different group
address range for all those multicast
packets so let's take a look at little
more detail and exactly what's going on
with multicast VPNs so receiver joins a
particular group and it's the pin packet
the pin joint is sent from the CEO off
to the PE that PE router gets that join
and it sends that packet to a
destination address of 239 1.1.1 it
encapsulates the customers packet
multicast packet and creates a new
multicast destination address which goes
to the other PE s within the VPN the PE
that leads to the source will the TCAPS
like that join send it off towards the
router that leads to the source the
multicast data would begin to flow the
PE router that is connected to that
source will encapsulate that multicast
packet he the PE router will become the
source IP address again we have a new
destination multicast group address to
39.1 1.1 they'll be sent to all the PE s
the PE that leads to receivers will D
capsulate it and send it on its way and
the receiver gets the packet and it's
able to view fashion TV receivers all
happy so if there's any news sources
that come up they will also be
encapsulated in that same group address
so one benefit of this is that it
definitely reduces state and for the P
routers PT routers just have to they're
just going to know one group address
range one group address for that fill
out the forward
so that's one of the advantages
disadvantages can redo it can result in
wasted bandwidth there are PE s that
don't lead to receivers but they're
getting the packet for getting the data
anyway that's one of the the problems in
the solution and this is something that
is where the interoperability stops we
could between vendors use the default
NPT and everything would work just fine
but beyond that it's not specified
exactly what to do and one of the
solutions that you could do that we've
done is to use a separate data MDT for
high rate sources so what that would
mean is that when this the multicast
traffic is forwarding across this
default multicast distribution tree MDT
it would exceed a certain configurable
threshold on the PD router that's
connected to the high rate source the PE
router would send a control packet to
all the other peo outers signaling those
routers that if you're if you have
receivers that interested in particular
source please send a join towards me to
me and we're going to use a new group to
39.2 to one so the PE routers that have
receivers will send a join to this new
group now and the data MDT is built
using this new group and the traffic
begins flowing along this new this new
tree you still have the existing default
MDT for any news sources that come up
and all the control packets they still
occur on the depot in DT but you can now
cut over and again that's about as
specific as I want to get because that's
a solution that that that we do and you
may just want to ask your vendor what
solution if any that they may have for
that they may decide that it's maybe
just not it may not be necessary they
just want to stick on the default NDT
so that's kind of just that this is just
kind of the picture of how it all halite
up how it all ends up with your
different VPNs and setting up your
default NDT and and works pretty good
any questions on that before we move on
to v6 yes in the back that's right so
one of the potential drawbacks of
cutting over to a data MDT is that now
the PT routers have to maintain more
State for new groups and that's true so
you would just need to decide whether
and that with us is configurable whether
you'd want to you've ever even cut over
to the data MTT I would think that for
efficiency's sake in many cases would be
preferred to covert to it data MDT but
good point maybe not always
all right v6 right lastly and this is
kind of the fun part this is all new
stuff we have a new multicast address
range and you know it's F F F F F /a
excuse me and that's why I neat things
about v6 addresses you've got four
scoped bits that you can specify whether
this address is link local or global or
regional or whatever so that you can on
your routers set up your filtering so
that ok no address that's global will
will pass my my interface so it's ooh
but so it's much it's just it's it's
easier to do your boundaries with v4
today we have to set up a boundary
command and specify the the group
address range that we want to to bound
just a little brief history I'll try to
make a brief on were multicast v6 stands
with unicast v6 it's been around for
several years now
a tunnel topology in the six bone and at
the last IETF it was decided to
decommission the the six bone and to go
native and that I there was a specific
date that was chosen some of you may
have been there and at that working
group and we're following suit we really
want to aggressively make it so that
we've learned from previous experience
with the old M bone which in some ways
we're still kind of fighting with what
the tunnel topology is to kind of go
native as quickly as possible
so what renee der out in europe did is
they created a m6 multicast six bone so
it is a tunnel topology for a lot of
testing and a lot of people are involved
in that a fair amount of applications
have been created to it to work on on v6
and it's it's there today and again we
knew that we wanted to aggressively get
out of that mode however and go to a
more native approach a lot of people
have created native networks as we
vendors have come up with with
implementations and so there's a lot of
different environments now like for
instance nasa their production network
is v6 capable for multicast and so
there's a lot of these little different
islands people of companies that have
now gone to a native native mode and
there is a new network that was created
a new environment that was to be able to
support these native implementations and
that is six net rene der who maintained
this m6 bone is an active participant in
em in the six net and this is a network
of a native solution where we're able to
test and people are able to natively get
a solution for for multicast and unicast
for that matter and so we're in this
mode now we're just really trying to
it's really trying to push people to go
natively with these sixes as quickly as
possible there's a variety of stacks
come a I believe was the one of the
first ones if not the first one there's
a variety of applications now that
support v6 from multicast there are some
obvious differences between v6 and B for
multicast one of the differences to be
aware of if you're not familiar with the
terms is with v4 I've talked about IGMP
internet group management protocol where
the hosts and reports in v6 that's
referred to as MLD multicast listener
discovery and there isn't even a version
of MLD that's equivalent to ijen p
version one
well ml d version one is equivalent to i
GN pv version 2 and ml d version two is
equivalent to a champion version 3 so
just I put that slide in there because
you may have to go back and look at that
one again I mentioned the scope identify
those the four scope bits which make it
a little bit easier to filter on the
edges and the interesting thing and this
is kind of what we're going to get into
is the whole idea of how we are gonna
have an inter domain solution with v6
and that's still in debate people in ITF
are aggressively trying to make it so M
SDP isn't even allowed to be implemented
within v6 they don't want to have to
deal with all these different rules that
I've mentioned and the SI flooding and
14 throughout the internet some of us
think that it may be unavoidable at
least at the beginning so we can get
things to work quickly we shall we shall
see you know one of the solutions is to
you know have global our P's everybody's
dependent upon a certain RP a solution
that was brought up for B 4 and M SDP
replaced that because people service
providers didn't have to rely on the RP
of somebody else and you know it makes
it so you're reliant upon other domains
I'm gonna in a few slides here
discussing different options that we
have available to us and we'll end on
that
so RPF with v6 multicast is the same as
with the v4 or multicast you just use
your you know it's protocol independent
and you just use your unicast routing
cable m bgp supports v6 address families
and we can use those for RPF there are
some definitions to be aware of a pim
domain is a topology served by a common
RP so if we have one big fat happy kim
domain within the internet we have a
bunch of different routing domains of
course that's based upon the AAS but one
big PIM domain is that what we want well
time will tell and I've mentioned scopes
and boundaries so I'll pass on that one
so this is our last two slides here so I
think we've done pretty good so here's
our here's our inner domain solutions I
can see three solutions that are
available to us to make this work with
v6 and we need your feedback on what
you'd prefer because the ITF sometimes
is kind of a you know it's our own
academic sometimes world and we we need
real customer feedback so we have SSM
there's no need for rendezvous points
it's extremely simple have the receivers
learner the sources and groups and just
fire off the joins towards the source
and it's extremely simple some people
really support this saying you know what
let's just have SSM only it startup
right from the very beginning let's SMS
SSM only in v6 yeah I hear yep yep back
there okay so that's something that a
lot of people want to see happen another
solution would be okay well we some
people feel that leaders really can't
get away from any source multicast
it's just you know it's gonna be a long
time between all of our host acts are up
created to build support v3 and all the
routers etc so we just we want to be
able to use v6 multicast today we need
have a solution well if that's the case
then today we need to have M SDP like
solution or just use M SDP to make it so
that we can learn of sources and other
PIM domains and as we've discussed we
have all our different RPF rules etc but
the receiver will be able to receive the
packets from the source so that's
another option that's available that
still being debated
and then lastly is the concept of again
having one rendezvous point out there
using ASM and everybody is able to just
rely upon that one RP for certain groups
and that's what our solution will be at
first that would probably work because
it's kind of a small still kind of in
the testing phase and that's in fact
what's being used today but going
forward would that work well there is a
proposal out there that some of us have
actually implemented that has to do with
embedding the RP address in a multicast
address so with v6 again there's the
there's certain bits that you can set
that will flag that the RP is embedded
within this multicast v6 address so the
RP address is known so there's no need
to use MSD P to find out their sources
everybody as long as they're using
routers that understand this embedded RP
will they'll to know what there are P
addresses based upon the multicast group
and then be able to send the packets off
to the rendezvous point some people that
think that's very attractive it in the
spec specifies that this is a temporary
solution it may or may not be or maybe
it won't take off at all we need to know
if everybody is ok with depending upon
some other RP out there for our sources
and groups to get the our sources and
receivers to get together we need to
have anybody to hear from you guys you
still a need MSD P for any cast RP
solution or an MSD P like solution at
least it's pretty simple to implement
for PIM sparse mode you intermediate you
know your outer is again need to be
upgraded to be able to handle
understanding these end up embedded our
piece and perhaps there could be some
scalability concerns because you have
this big virtual flat domain instead of
a bunch of little domain islands so this
is this is where we're at
all three of these are being used right
now in the m6 bone and six net all three
of these meaning we have embedded RP
solution we have static our peas that
are being used as well as BS are those
are the three ways right now that we
know of a rendezvous point within the v6
world if anybody's interested in
actively participating in v6
let us know feel free to send me an
email if you wish and I can steer you in
the right direction again it's McBride
at Cisco comm and that is it any
questions before we close not bad I had
like three minutes to spare thank you
that's it