together we're going to be going through
this afternoon one of the tools that we
hope if you're not already deployed it
that you look at the point in your
network this is a sinkhole tool it's a
technique that isps various ISPs of
deploying and using for all sorts of
different security purposes on the net
this is part of a series that we've been
doing kinda like annual series where we
take a real world isp security
techniques and tools that you can you
know basically deploy with any you know
vendors equipment we keep it as as
neutral as possible as more of
techniques so the first one where Chris
Brian and I did with the unit
backscatter trace back technique and all
the techniques along with that
and then our last year kevin powell and
i did with the cpe protection because of
all the cpe break-ins were seen with
different routers and so now we're going
to do sinkholes for this morning so the
objective with all these tutorials is to
communicate you know real-world
practices so these are things coming
from you than in Danny and I connect our
position working with different
providers in isb security space we can
gain from our peers kind of like well
here's what we're doing dis providers
we're doing that provider and they
permit us to kind of generalize it and
express it here so so others can copy
what they're doing without knowing
exactly what they're doing or exactly
who did this so we don't give away into
specific details so so here we're trying
to get everybody in sync with the with
the sinkhole technique so what are
sinkholes sinkholes are kind you can
consider equivalent as a network
is basically a sectioning network that
sucks down bad packets and then when you
take those you take those bad packets
and you do things
you can analyze it you can
look at what sort of vac scatters coming
from it you can look at attacks in
progress you can take an attack that's
hitting one of your customers that may
be stressing out an aggregation router
and redirect it to the sinkhole and do
your classification
mitigation technique off office and call
so it's kind of like a multi-purpose
tool which is where we get this Swiss
Army knife expression for it because
we're finding our peers are coming up
and saying hey you know we found this
new idea that we can do
we found this other idea we can do the
sinkhole so once people deployed it
they're finding more more different
types of uses for their situational
sometimes to do to their network or
sometimes comply Jeremy and the ones who
are plenty of everyone we try to apply
here in this presentation so give a kid
like a general journal scenarios what
an aggregation router
when customs
see one customer
going to happen
here you got to go on that ride
I really something I never now
other customers on there but them
your logins around
so what to do at the sinkhole as you
take the / 32
sinkhole now you got the traffic going
off to the side to a part of your
network
or get from
things like that
now the customer that
he's being hit here
fold at 45 negative it's off to the side
guess what it is
rest of his address space
/ there was being
she was
for the Restless last 24
das is still in action but
you got more tools available to you
traffic away
other things that people use indoors
watch your network scan
placement
about the place many people start
primarily we go at once
in a place in your network that's not
many different techniques
and the multiple single
so you can deploy the sinkholes widely
across your network
so why go through this
we'll say I just draw
this attack a black hole
JCP donk
scuse me back
and more useless being found
what we mind as equals
worms as we saw us
something that no
oh I got an incredible
we got a worm that propagates around
we're buying the sinkholes are very
powerful
um
so just to give some clarification of
why we call this a sinkhole
the black hole routers right
so sinkhole goes beyond them to see cold
Tar Pits are places in Vice
connections
will you put a sink hole
our shots
we can wonder sing long you're not going
the same thing of money
much water turn you have all these
things inside
Swiss Army knife spoon
so um now
and over to Danny
and by the way you
anyone you want to ask a question
I'm going to run my
right so basic see
right so expand
is you know how much traffic decent in
SC colon you should be really here
for a single so
to understand how much traffic you've
actually got in prefixes you want to
monitor is something you should be aware
of
one of the things as well is that you
don't want routers generating tons of
unreachable messages that sort of thing
if the house goes down so you can put a
static arp on it you know kind of like a
shiny just put a static arp entry on a
router to get rid of to get rid of you
know the unreachable stuff that kind of
thing if your box goes down you can
still for the traffic on the Lana it
doesn't impact anything or send a lot of
garbage back out of the network so
alright what's monitoring a sinkhole
dark eye peas the dark ipd is kind of
yes a pretty pretty broad term and the
common definition for that I guess if
there is one is you know is bogan space
RFC 1918 kind of stuff unallocated
address base from your own network that
either hasn't been allocated aura it
wasn't used or or you know the RFC 1918
those sorts of things off and you know
what you can do by you know by watching
this address space that you should be
really careful because you again the
amount of amount of data that comes to
this address spaces
is more than most people expect so so
you should be aware of you know of how
much you want to modern start small
either with you know an allocated
backbone or infrastructure links that
sort of thing or an allocated customer
prefixes or you know we're just don't
you know one of the RC 1980 prefixes
that sort of thing so you can monitor
again you can monitor backscatter
backscatter from attacks I want to talk
about Beckwith backscatter is in just a
moment if you're not aware dark IP stuff
you know who's scanning so just by
putting one IP address there i mean i
have one IP address on one of my home
subnets that I monitor and it's amazing
actually how many how many scans you see
the day just you know random scans and
the other probably compromised hosts
that are scanning looking for some
ex-boyfriend so you can you can get a
handle on those
alright so monitor scan rates is you
know there are lots of tools to do this
I work for are over and meet our company
has it totally does some of this but
there's a ton of stuff out there that's
free that does this as well and you know
to you know to get something in place
and free and start with your small
sinkhole actually understand what's
going on on your network and you can
idea about what's happening is kind of
the the goal here I guess that's what
we're trying to get across is to even be
prepared to understand what's happening
and work so
okay so this is this is actually a
screenshot from some of our stuff when a
worm actually shows a list of infected
hose down at the bottom and you can
actually see a huge bike there and this
was from a sinkhole and if your mind as
you can say whoa look at that you know
the the average rate above what I
expected for this interface or this
device or this prefix went up and and
you know here's a list of all the hosts
that we're scanning this prefix so
they're probably all compromised or
you've been affected by this worm or
whatever it was that happened you can
you can actually figure it out first
just assuming that there's a bunch of
noise on your network that day and you
know and discarding it because it will
grow so
alright monitoring backscatter
me actually he really let me talk about
backscattering real quick vs so what you
see here is this is ok I don't know
where the term backscatter actually came
from i'm guessing that indicator used it
first i don't know if it came from
elsewhere but it's what you see in this
example actually is a couple of packets
with sous a spoof source addresses here
and so they're hitting some victim in
this case this is the big demand and
then the victims replying back to you
know VT and see in this case and that's
what's units that someone referred to as
backscatter it can also come from you
know router and reachable messages or
you know a number of things and it's
that's the backscatter that we're
talking about so if you can get a handle
on on you know where that data is going
back to and watch that you can get a
good idea about you know what's
happening so
the song get you at home okay 11
you put backscatter inside your network
is and you only monitor say like you
know say say if you take your router
your sink holes that you put your all
your AG you use it as your black hole
generators for your home for your route
advertisement so you take all your your
site or aggregate blocks and just stick
them on your sink holes and then you can
watch the backscatter and one it one of
the providers this is how they kind of
get an early indication of which of the
customers being attacked because they
see only the backscatter from their
network you know from all the networks
that provide to them and that will give
them an indication k which my customers
are getting hit which customers get
ready to call me and and and this one
guy said that you know it's really fun
sometimes to have the customer call the
escalator chances oh yes hey how you
doing I understand you're under attack
right now I can see it on my monitor
right now listen let's go ahead and plug
this up you know it helps you getting
more proactive mode with the customers
that way
so backscatter is pretty pretty nice
tool which only if you set it up then
yeah we actually have a couple of
examples on how you do that with your
aggregates in a moment
anyway that was the kata stuff you know
you can go there and look at some of the
analysis and the other thing they did on
backscatter it's actually pretty
interesting and the the backscatter you
know the traceback stuff to Chris and
Rob and yes Brian Greene Jim pony and a
few other folks from real calm and
elsewhere did and they presented I think
the trauma and all gets still still
online so if you want to go back and
have a look at that if you know if it
makes more sense now that's something
you ought to do it
on my side
my name's been framed okay so this is
just a sample of an account accounting
be a packet filter is looking at some
address ranges right so this is yeah
this is this is Jeff Jeff one out one
time there's this was actually cut paste
with a net on discussion whether it was
in our discussion about how many spoofed
addresses in bogan space are there
really out there
you know and have disliked packets so he
had some router somewhere in the network
and you just did a classification kcl
which was all permits and all denies in
this one this is denied case and he just
you know this is all source addresses
out of the Dogon space and he's just
said okay how many how many is out there
they were out there in silicon counters
and he was like surprised over his
network but there were that many spoofed
bogan addresses health care on his
network it didn't think there was any by
the way Barry did most of these slides
and gave them to me about an hour and a
half ago so it seems like you know some
of them better than I do and that's
probably what I said all right so uh
okay so now I'm to sinkholes and
internet-facing and what this actually
looks like what you see here is okay so
common I guess that you know the current
practice of service fighters is to
announce your network aggregates only
the you know the moat the most are the
longest or the shortest prefix I'm sorry
to announce the shortest prefix for your
network dagger it's and only one and an
advertised that from you know what
single announcement out of your network
and and what that does is that any of
the unallocated address space within
that block ends up getting dumped on
your router and your router's got to
handle that and so that's that's what
you're seeing here is you see large
large cider block is being a as being
announced and all the garbage packets
you know to either scans or you know
we're back scatter or whatever is is
being sent to your router just tossed
and you can actually analyze that data
since you're carrying it on your network
anyway so that's what this is getting
there's actually
alright so so it wasn't a big deal you
know that bit of noise that you saw the
backscatter and the random scans and
that sort of thing when now when there
were ten host somewhere that someone
manually compromised but you know with
with botnets or using these zombie
networks that have 150,000 nodes and all
of them have you can make dsl access or
something this work becomes a lot more
significant so you know to just throw
that stuff in a router and fill up a
single link in your network or a couple
of links in your network and you know it
and you're out or you know if they can
do unreachable zorro macro replies
whatever the whatever the the attack you
know characteristics are if they can
respond to those or handle those in
hardware well you know when the volume
goes way up the you know the overhead on
your router in your network and you know
and your service availability are
impacted so so one of the things you can
do actually is is spread out take some
of those unallocated blocks and actually
throw them on you know into your scene
kohli or some or all of them you know
depend on the volume of traffic and what
you want to handle and so that's that's
what you're seeing here and basically I
guess hang on I'm all series
so so basically pull in you know certain
certain allocated prefixes certain
blocks from the from from your aggregate
from the network aggregate or a set of
the Android so we're just your
infrastructure address space and get an
idea about what's going on instead of
just letting your router dump the
traffic or the router become the become
the victim right so so one of the things
you got to be aware of right is if
you're going to announce more specifics
for your larger Network aggregates one
is you definitely don't want to leave
those aggregates out of your network so
put in put explicit policies in place to
handle that and and make sure other
things if if you were to announce those
prefixes rider you decide to change your
announcement policies things like mes
could be affected which I have an issue
with mu DS that's in a separate issue so
I won't get into but uh m.ed s could be
affected based on your announcement
policies that sort the sort of things
that you know that come from central
network aggregation and you know I'm
great gathering stuff so anyway ok so
the default route on a customer CP
device planets it's the ultimate I guess
the ultimate vacuum for Union for
garbage right so what you're seeing is a
evah default route and you get a lot of
garbage and they don't have anywhere
else to send it they're going to send it
to you so if you analyze that
alright so I've actually talked about
some of this and a lot of it's just you
know there's a lot of volume there in
the you know the amount of traffic or
you know what should otherwise consider
noise and so fan lies that and you know
the overhead of it how you handle that
traffic is going to become more more
significant especially the sinkholes and
you know and and these botnets grow and
the bandwidth and the capabilities and
characteristics groups so to try and get
a handle on that would be a good things
alright dark IP space advertising dark
IP space and sending it back in your
sink hole that's what you see here is a
advertise you know unallocated
infrastructure addresses unallocated
customer blocks both on space RC 1918
well whatever it is it's not a big deal
to allocate address based out of era I
mean to 10 ounce more specifics of
unallocated to trespass or photons
within your network and just keep them
inside your networks to make sense is
everyone with me here no questions so
far
we have lost someone everyone follow me
or just reading you know
anyway let's just hurry up nessa so what
you see here is any casting calls what
you could do is because this is a lot of
volume a lot of data you see so you put
sinkholes in different places in your
network and announced that you know
either the same addresses or different
address ranges out of those sinkholes
and you can handle the volume better you
know then handle things that would
otherwise be pummeling a router you know
with no visibility kind of transparently
and you just see router CPU go of it and
not know what's actually happening in
your network so if you know if you get
to the point where you want to monitor
things on network wide basis and
skeleton but multiple sinkholes in your
network for different prefixes or to any
cast the same prefixes this is one of
the options you want what it takes and
this is kind of actually how we've seen
some of the service writers we worked
with Barry and I both grow their
sinkholes they started with the unix box
and they went to distribute it you know
multiple sinkholes in different place in
their network for different prefixes and
then to any casting them so that there's
low distribution because you know the
characteristics of different attacks
typically you know target one or two
sources versus and rhenium sources or if
you know one or two prefixes should we
say so if you could spread that out of
your network it's a it's a little more
robust and gives you a better handle on
its going son
and that's it so any questions so far
for Barry comes back up and
so any any cast of I mean any casting is
a technique that how many people always
ask this question how many people are
actively using any cast in their
networks today this is this is one of
the things i was wondering because any
case have been out for quite a while and
one of the things i realized was there's
a lot of different providers out there
that don't realize this technique is out
there don't know how they could use
those or services in the end what's
interesting is a couple of big providers
I asked her back on crews are you guys
Annie Cassidy nests and was like silence
it was something that was done like five
years ago and it's still there but they
didn't know what it was go running or
not yeah how is this works so any case
is one of those techniques that really
works it came up with and we use it with
DNS services probably the most common
purpose of it we also use it for
advertising are distributed sinkholes
and and also for black hole ground
advertisement like for instance when you
take inside your core and you take your
aggregate blocks you take the entire
advocate space you might advertise it
out as the pretenses and you do it
inside your core you never do it on just
one of your background for routers you
do it maybe on three or four that's
actually any casted those you know big
blocks of / 19 / 18 / 20s you're not to
any cast MP because you put on many
robbers the any castle that's
and then some some guys use any cast for
Ralph convergence is about companies and
tricks with it now this thing call came
up with sinkholes because there's one
big provider he started and he did a
sinkhole and he just did some dark IP
address to face his address space to
belong to handle more specific it was
pretty cool hey let me let me go throw
and wheat Chris Chris and Brian's
document on doing backscatter trace back
you know Beck's got a trace back a
sinkhole is one of the pieces of the
three piece of the puzzle with Doc's got
his back and in there they said you know
Chris and Brian said oh yeah we use 96 /
3 so so he took 2 96 / 3 sticks them on
a sinkhole and he goes I home he said he
says I dost myself because there was so
much backs gutter on the network when I
put out 96 / 3 all this traffic just
whacked I didn't he was his overwhelmed
my circuits going into my lab you know
he didn't expect that much traffic
coming into it so so he called me shut
it off and he called me is what can we
do is well why don't we spread it all
over your network we just put sink holes
all over the place and then you know
because that's actually what's going on
right now because you dropping packets
all over your network with backscatter
to drop on a router silently and it just
packets get dropped and if we only want
to use it with that scatter than we
anycast it and then they'll get pulled
in to a different part c network instead
of just one party so you don't get you
don't end up tossing your song so that's
where they using any casa backscatter
came from so in a dns model because
that's a good reference model and it's
kind of a similar reference model you we
got DNS servers sitting out there in
different parts you networking we any
any casting an idea in basic anycast
week we basically got you know it's the
Microsoft DNS client you have to to dns
IP addresses and you take those same to
gina's IP addresses you stick them on
every single one of these servers in the
advertisement network so anybody anytime
when somebody tries to resolve one of
the addresses you know that's in your
little you know my case a Microsoft
client you know and it tries to resolve
on other DNS addresses it goes to the
closest one to you right and you can do
this the border gateway protocol is a
border gateway protocol technique for
doing it there's an interior gateway
protocol techniques we're doing any cast
in this right on some people even to
protect with DNS servers to take one of
the two DNS addresses put it in I GP so
it's only reachable inside the network
and the other one on their order a
gateway protocol it gets advertised out
for the world so protector the most cash
flow easily so this is kind of known we
know how to do this so when you can do
the same sort of thing with sinkholes in
this case you know here's a guy little
DNS forward in his daughter you know it
needs to be changed it basically take
the customer he's sending out you know
he's infected he's got slam or something
affected and when you take in try to go
through and send him to a sinkhole he'll
go to the closest sinkhole instead of to
one central sinkhole go to the closest
one and then as you stretch out across
your network that allows you you know
for the edge that way and also it
distributes distributes no effect so
this the idea of the antique a sinkhole
a configuration example for this is kike
figuration example taken from a typical
you know DNS sort of configuration where
I have servers and insight on my inside
of my work and these can be you know
sniffers or other things inside that I
want to send traffic over to I got two
addresses on I got one address i use for
management i go to that configure and
log on and do things with it and the
other address is the address i'll use
for for my sinkhole that all advertised
everywhere the same address every where
and when I a ver inside my network I
just my little sink called using
derogatory protocol and then outside
I've got 40 gateway protocol
advertisement network in this example so
so when I go through on trigger and say
ok say like the top once a server
instance a when server instance a is my
sniffer and i want to send stuff over to
my sniffer that I send out and use that
one /w to this case it's 10 that 00
/ them to use that one 27
so so with the sinkhole sinkhole you
know designed to pull an attack and any
cast placement allows me to go through
and place multiple sinkholes across my
network without going through and do a
major we architect on my network and we
kind of know we got several providers
who have done this now that's how they
deployed their sinkholes we started with
one and they've moved down to a knee
cast model because it's very easy for
them to find an extra port somewhere in
a pop or next report and appear in
connection and stick a little switch off
of it and some some extra low you know
extra routers off the side of it in
there in the lac space to build a
sinkhole in that particular Colo
location may spread them all over the
place and then control it centrally from
their security desk when they do the
security mitigation
so and you know this is this example is
spreading across about regional data
center sort of a Pocho you can push them
all over the edge or no there's all
sorts of flexibility that you can do
with any castle of civility otherwise if
you have one central one then your talk
about you know upgrading circuits
control and bandwidth going into this
thing calling having you know the
concern of happens too much of the
attack traffic going into your sinkhole
and saturate that likes going into the
single there's a lot of traffic
so so I can kind of Souter this in the
early stages because you know I got you
know only a few providers who are doing
this but we as more people looking at
this will probably see more traction
hopefully more people kind of look at
this as a lot of security tool deployed
the ones who have these deployed during
slammer we're in a good advantage
because they were able to use the
sinkholes to say okay I got six
different sinkholes and hey you know the
west side of my backbone in the United
States has more Slammers than my east
side of the United States they are
actually able to look at the different
sinkholes and say in this case using the
tractor turbo worms able to say like oh
wow did we able to get regionalized
attitude to find out okay where should
we put most of our helpdesk support to
help our customers to plug up the
slammer and they're able
the sickles going on out there so that's
that's another plus for another this is
another one of those tech techniques
these tricks that somebody came up to me
and said like hey you know here's
another technique we found is in
protecting we point-to-point links
inside your backbone so here in this
case you have a point-to-point link on a
backbone and you got to think about what
what sort of traffic goes cross on a
point-to-point link right this is like
you know inside your backbone so when
you think about it you break it down you
know more degree protocol ntp things
like that inside your network you're
using loop backs alright and so you
loopback addresses right are not your
point the point lines that separate your
ones who use a point-to-point links are
things like you carry gay tree protocols
you know things like your your link
protocols right now those when they when
they look at the look at it they all he
needs to see the connected route because
it's directly connected so don't
actually need a routing protocol will
come up and run it because they're
sitting adjacent to each other right so
when it comes to like you know being
able to send traffic to these
point-to-point links right you don't
really need outside world to be able to
get to these point-to-point links I mean
do they really need that somebody really
need to ping your backbone link somebody
really need to ping you know some
customer outside planet lead to pay me
or c180 OC 48 points you know not not
really you know when you think about but
people can trace route because they can
trace about these are the Aster
addresses to show up because they trace
route these addresses show up people
could say ah here's intelligence for me
to have a target I want to go after on
his attack a router I do a trace a
couple of tracer on Stewart provider I
get enough addresses on the
point-to-point links i can go out there
and rock black the routers so to protect
them in the past people use different
things to protect these these
infrastructure point-to-point
people use a CLS in the past some people
tried using RFC 1918 you know as as a as
a public example but you have problems
with reflection attacks with it which
I'll talk about what a reflection attack
is so so one idea that one of the one of
the guys came out with says hey you know
they had this what happened was a
scenario where one of the customers was
attacked so they went they jumped in to
help their customer out and then the cut
the attacker shift at the attack off of
the customer and attack the routers that
supported the customer so the attack
targets shifted from the customer to the
service providers routers to hit the
service providers routers you know and
so here they're going okay what are we
going to do now these backbone links to
protect it and what they did is they
threw on a sinkhole he basically took
clear all the infrastructure blocks all
the point-to-point link addresses
society network and they advertised off
the sinkhole and what that did is the
attack that was going after a a one of
their routers point-to-point links all
went down into the sinkhole
alright so it shud shoved it down down
to sinkholes it was a way for them
protector the point-to-point links that
way alright so so in this case give give
an example here you know it's not at all
important here is not a perfect sort of
solution because there are links that
for instance when I go and say like in
this case the top attack flow I'm going
after 198 0 to 2 which is that first
link that first router in so that first
router in there this technique wouldn't
protect that one because router a which
is my border router the parent router
has a connected prefex going to that
right but if the second one the one on
the bottom which is 198 0225 that's
inside that's that's more than two hops
into my network inside my backbone
anything I try to send beyond their
would go down to the same so like a lot
of security solutions it's it's not a
perfect solution but it is a tool it's a
technique that you can turn on so it's
one of those things that if you plan for
you can go through and just set up a
little rule and have you know all your
infrastructure addresses you know handy
that you can go through and inject them
if you want to so with this one provider
does is they have a their st. call ready
to turn on they don't have a turn out
all the time but I ever ready to turn on
and you know exactly all their addresses
and so this situation happens again they
can easily go on a box activate the
little rule they have prepared and be
able to use this technique to protect us
up some of the infrastructure addresses
alright so so this is kind of like you
know traffic getting sucked down into
the sinkhole instead of being sent off
into one of the point-to-point addresses
now another thing is you know some
people say well RFC 1918 addresses i use
RFC 1918 addresses but you know that
some people would come and say yeah but
I RFC 1918 addresses has point-to-point
infrastructure addresses which RFC's you
know says you shouldn't use public
internet space but people say all give
me more security because people can't
attack me then but then nobody ever
mentions to them while you can do a
reflection attack and reflection attack
is where I send in addresses which are
basically RFC 1918 addresses it's pooped
in my source addresses and then I hit
customers who have access to my network
and then what happens is my customers
then reply to my infrastructure
addresses which are parsing 1980
addresses so you get all this back
scatter junk and just reply this
reflection that's a couple reflection
that's targeted at a particular
interface so in this case my reflection
target is is on router be and I used
that as a reflection target and so again
here this is one of those things where
if you have a black hole the
infrastructure block partly
infrastructure addresses is a technique
that you can use the mitigating win if
this sort of thing happens with these
sort of reflection sort of attacks and
this is especially coming true as people
starting to also look at you know
putting ACLs on the edge when you put a
CLS on the edge protecting
infrastructure blocks you got got to not
only do stop the destination address we
also got to do the anti spoof the source
address so you got to have an ACL that's
constructed just like an enterprise ACL
where you don't allow any source address
two equals my own block my
infrastructure blocks
and no destination address going into my
infrastructure blocks plus it's
explicitly permitted like an ebgp pier
in connection so you got to do both some
some some providers i was talking to
we're just doing one they're just doing
a destination is it but you got to do
both otherwise you're going to booking
these sort of reflection attacks out
there now while all this is building up
to and pour it for for this tutorial
we're probably going to get over the
Scimitar quick lusty the people have a
lot of questions on it is is preparing
for the next turbo one usually we do
these in the fall and all but we were
asked to maybe kind of do this this time
as kind of like preparing for the next
rubble one now we all know we got hit
with this guy was slammer and as we
talked about the last nanog when we did
a post-mortem on it you know thank you
thank goodness we had started working on
ways to talking to each other ISP to ISP
because as I as Pisa Salih singh vs
because we had an SP sec and a couple
other tools out there to talk to each
other we were able to quickly figure out
how to contain it and do the containment
filter zone so just to stop it otherwise
this thing would have just been a really
real nightmare you know it was pretty
bad that it is really once you contain a
warrant right you know kind of like
there's three stages of war mitigation
stage one is identifying what's going on
stage two is containing it it's kind of
like you know sorrows out an Asian you
kind of contain you got to isolate and
you get a you know section and off in
this part of network and then the third
thing you got to actually go out there
and cure it you got to fix it well what
happened with slammer is luckily we had
people out there that can identify a
quick and we figure out a containment
quick but then what happened is it took
quite a while to start clearing up the
problem and the ones who were able to
clear out fast with people up there with
sinkholes because one of the things that
a sinkhole would do as the sinkhole will
give you a statistic from the
backscatter off the worm of the scans
off the worm you get to sort of things
got from there you get
the the worm actually hitting you
because these worms go out there and
start scanning you know the entire
internet space and so if you have some
bull gone space and some dark IP space
on your sink hole guess what your sink
hole is going to pick that up that's
because they hate you know I got all
these scans going on here you know
what's what's going on some of these
scanning me here let's identify this
plus fire at my sniffer and kind of take
a packet capture and say oh this is a
worm and the other thing you're going to
get out of it is the backscatter from
all the other failed attempts across
your network so you're going to towards
the source of data and they're going to
the sinkhole with me and what you get
all this audio sinkhole is who's
infected because you know you got a
computer in effect in the computer not
trying to hide the fact that hey
uninfected I'm trying to affect use the
code red and uh you know slammer all you
can easily use the sink holes that go
back and say these are my infected hosts
and this is the third stage of container
which is he actually got a clean it up
right and the providers I had these in
their networks were able to go through
and and we contained it and then they
were out there to go out there and get
their customers fixed because they had
these sinkholes in place all the guys
had to go out there and build the
sinkholes you know while slammer was
going on said he can start identifying
he's who's infected and cleaning my back
after loose in this case this is
actually emulating you know what's what
happens in Cisco Cisco we got sink holes
that are we know our providers all all
of our upstream providers that Cisco
uses have sinkholes deployed so we know
that the providers can use it and then
inside our DMZ area we got one and
that's the most active one that's the
one that we use all the time because
it's in the DMZ air in between you know
firewall letters right and then inside
Cisco's corporate network we got
sinkholes deployed all over across the
entire global torrent I to network those
mainly sit around oh so teen idol and
every now and then especially will get
lab servers pop up with my code red and
infection so they get about two or three
Code Red named infections a month that
pop up and they're able to spot them
right away the sinkholes is picking
right up into hot okay and they're able
to go down and they go over to the lab
and disconnect the left you know and
then they called the lab admin and say
okay one of your machines is affected
out at the analyst let's plug it up with
fix it let's get a patch sort of thing
as you're able to spot these inside the
corporate network quite effectively so
the sinkhole concept is not just
something that you can do in a highest
be back home scenario but inside
in a service providers own service
infrastructure corporate infrastructure
your customers and enterprise scenario
it's a cool off more that's good for the
morn mitigation so so in summary the
nature of the threat in slammers case
you know the 30 minutes is thrown out it
was more it was more like you know 10 15
minutes when you look at some of the
studies about the spread of the
infection vector when you have turbo
ones that go out and spread that fast
you can't wait until the warrant happens
to go and build these tools and since
these tools are not rocket science right
none of the things here is hard right
and they're not expensive because you
know as I said we got guys who just took
a spare workstation loaded up zebra and
and TCP dump on it and they had their
sink hole right so they're not expensive
to do and with any cast deployment you
don't have to we are rebuild your
network to deploy on all right so it's
not like something you could say well
all these differences why you don't the
point but you can't wait until the next
turbo warm happens to the point is
something that you got to do now to
prepare for the next over one now we
know the next turbo one's going to
happen we don't know when we don't know
what the attack vector is going to be
and the infection vector is going to be
for the next to the one who know it's
going to happen we also know because you
know where was y'all is not my head on
the table when we had last night ugh and
we had people up here on stage saying
here is all the errors they made in the
slammer confront you know scan rate you
know and say like you know slammer was
fast but you know they made all these
computational errors and they could have
been faster you know and here's a map of
how they could have been faster you know
and you see you see you know people do
that sort of analysis which is very
useful analysis but then somebody who's
probably planning these next
look at that you know get it from 10
minute global spread to like a
five-minute global spread so so the key
thing here is be prepared that's what
this talk is called up for that so and
on here we'd like to you know thank some
of the contributors on here and some
people contributed this over time you
know tenth Alistair small to offer
roland albums / who runs our cisco
deanzie and many many other guys help
help Kenny I put this together and now
we're open for questions comments
comments
more stories anybody who's had a single
interest in uses port they we have not
expressed
syndicate
okay well if there's nothing out there
Danny will be up Danny and I will be up
here for anybody who wants to come up to
the stage because a lot of times in
security nobody wants to get up and talk
security when it's being taped
we played on the internet so we will
close up and we'll be here and then
we'll see hopefully see everybody
tonight at the security ball and those
of you who don't know about the security
ball that's our kind of like regular
meeting where we're take trying to take
one piece at a time and do more and more
security on the internet and working
with each other and so we'll be talking
some more what's going on with nsp sec
you don't know what nsp sec is come to
security buff and find out okay thank
you