okay everyone please take a seat I want
to take this time an opportunity to tell
you a bit about our capture the flag
event which was concluded this last
Friday
okay so unlike many other city of events
our CTF are besides Tel Aviv CTF is a
bit different
we aim to host the CTF that is a full
community wide in scale but we would
like to give an opportunity to everybody
to take part and participate in the game
so when we plan the game when we planed
the CTF we try to have a variety of
challenges that are be fitting many
different skill levels we know that we
expect that only the best of the best
would reach the end the final stages of
the CTF however our greatest metric to
understand the success success of our
CTF is how many people actually
succeeded in solving the easier parts of
our CTF so we designed about not about
this specifically 29 different
challenges and some of these chances
were pretty different and unique this
year and I'll mention them in a bit
first I would like to say thank you and
a big round of applause for our CTF team
please join me here on stage
CTF team yes you guys City and team so
our city of team really put a long hours
long night into developing the most
vicious the most hateful the most
unbearably unimaginable challenges to
make the life of everybody as bitter as
they can and from the experience of
people who shared it as you can go into
the center of the screen so everybody
can take a picture of you and you'll be
as embarrassed as possible pleased
embarrassment this way okay a big round
of applause
so these are the guys and girls actually
made everything happen they invested
their time their effort their energy
their tears the blood into making those
challenges that great changes that you
had the chance to play so thank you
again and now continue so we had an
amazing CTF this year and I well I'm a
bit biased but I still think it was an
amazing city of this year we had over
300 different teams participating in the
game and we did something a bit
differently this year which I would like
to explain yeah we didn't limit the
number of players on each team but we
wanted to encourage people to play as a
team in order to share knowledge share
information and create a more cohesive
group of players among themselves so we
had teams as large as 12 or 14 different
people on the same team but we also had
team of one person so all of them are
considered teams and all of them played
and they played very very well we had 29
challenges and we structured it in a way
that the city have lasted 10 days and in
those 10 days 19 challenges were
released and they were all open to play
at the same time so the logic behind
that was that you get nine days not ten
nine days to play all of the different
there 19 challenges so when you get to
the final day the top three teams the
top three teams scored the most will get
access to a very special challenge that
we designed called Magic Kingdom and
Magic Kingdom was a bit different in the
world of CTFs usually in the city f you
get a challenge which is kind of like a
riddle there is a specific thing to
answer a specific rhythm to answer to
and the solution to that riddle will get
you the points so in Magic Kingdom we
did something a bit different we hosted
three different live as your
environments including Active Directory
and many other servers with a jump box
for with credentials for specific three
teams so that could go inside that live
environment and
Kawai at that light with Marmon using
whatever tools whatever they deem
necessary narrator in order to make that
happen and this is a bit different
because we didn't give them any
preconditions or any ideas where the
flags are going to be hidden they had to
explore the network to find the servers
to find the boys necessities on those
servers kind of like in a Red Team
exercise and then exploit them as best
they can in order to reach those flags
so 19's were ordinary well kind of like
ordinary CTF events but the Magic
Kingdom had ten different flags in a
hugely weird environment that most
serious players are not used to we
really took them out of their comfort
zone we had a couple of unique
challenges and when I say unique I mean
that in most city F that you will
participate in or read about you will
not find this kind of managed challenges
so before we and I'll give you some more
information about that our ratio we had
a lot of discussions into how many
points to give into what kind of
challenges how to differentiate between
the challenges how to make sure that the
easy ones are easy and the hard ones are
hard and in the end we came up with this
ratio if we hear that they cried and
they cried a lot that means it deserves
a lot of points and if it was easy and
no tears were involved well it's only a
hundred points nobody cares so most of
our challenges and a high score pal a
high score point because of this because
it caused a lot of Tears a lot of
sleepless nights and we're not sorry
the first unique challenge that I want
to mention here is blockchain so we had
the challenge that is focused on hacking
blockchain hacking etherium in order to
find a race condition just like the
hacks that were in the news relatively
recently so that was quite a unique
change you don't see that very common
thank you very much Nimrod for this
awesome challenge
we also had an amazing challenge made by
Rory here that in order to get the flag
you had to capture a file you had to
dismantle it decode it into whatever it
was encoded with and in the end you get
a file and then he had to 3d print the
file in order to get the object and on
the object you would find the flag so it
was absolutely awesome and crazy also
special thanks to guy who could not be
here with us today not me
guy be and a different guy be and here
we actually had a challenge that was
based on a zero-day that he found which
was always awesome to give people change
on something nobody ever heard of or
nobody ever found
so this Lua challenge in Lua bass
challenge was about issues in the Lua
parser that you had to exploit and I
believe that a lot of people let's call
it had a lot of fun with a Bowser set of
challenges so a round of applause for
guy he will see it on the recording
later ok so here's a brief review of our
challenges I'm not going to go over them
one by one but we had a very large
variety we had a specific challenge
around the hacking dose 3.1 was a tonal
three-point-three environment which you
don't really see quite often today we
had a translation it was called a secret
service a necessary issue in a
translation service
where's Daniel Daniel over there an
awesome challenge that really got a lot
of groups hung up for a while until they
understood what the point was and and
this is a specific challenge as was
challenged I want to say something a bit
about that so the some stuff is
important challenge was conceived to be
relatively easy challenge and in the
initial discussions we wanted to give it
a hundred points however when people
actually attempted to solve the
challenge we found that no one was able
to solve it and then only one or two
will are able to solve it and that we'd
like five solve six source of
so the idea behind this challenge was
that you need to enumerate all of the
different cipher suites in the SSL
server that was part of the challenge
however if you use the wrong tool or if
you actually didn't enumerate all of the
possibilities
you only get part of the flags which
cause a lot of frustration to many many
teams so Thank You Ezra for an awesome
challenge and we had a very nice
challenge by the mode called Buchman I'm
going to refer to it later please keep
that in mind I want to say something
about my challenge
Faiza there at the top that was an
interesting challenge it came up for an
idea from a different conference called
blue hat that was earlier this year and
one of the talks there the tanta battle
how would you go and break something
we'll all you have in the API is the way
to read hash pieces of memory you can't
really read access the mirror itself so
the vulnerability that they discuss was
that there you could read memory with an
arbitrary length so once you understood
that you can build a lookup table and
solve the entire challenge so I really
loved the idea I really loved the
concept I love the work that they've
done so I built a challenge around that
and that was a lot of fun and everybody
that didn't attend blue hadn't ever
heard of this found this challenge to be
a bit formidable so my apologies ok the
challenge of themselves this very nice
screen was one of the captures that some
of the team sent us where they found a
vulnerability in our server that's
always nice to know when you're running
a live competition that your servers are
vulnerable but also we had a lot of
communication with different teams where
they had issues with connecting issues
with understanding issues with actually
conceiving who should they contact and
where they should do this but also where
they only solved part of the challenge
and they weren't sure if they solved
everything or just part of it but also
we had some repeated messages with
different groups which I will not name
we're six I think different members of
the CTF team got the same kind of
messages asking something might be wrong
please check again what you're doing are
you sure something is wrong and isn't
wrong please check again what you're
doing
so in the end it was still solvable the
way it is but there and we did find an
issue with that challenge and we issued
the fix with dust attack we issued the
fix for to clarify some issue around
which emulator we use I'll skip ahead
because I'm running a bit out of time
though there are a lot of funny things
happening in the background so here you
can see one of the teams that use the
emulation software in order to
understand the 3d printed flag so the
resolution that they got was not high
enough in order to read the flag so they
asked for a recommendation on an
emulation software to solve the
challenge so that was actually pretty
funny this is a different story
which was pretty funny around the
challenge called Buckman so in pac-man
we actually had a game called Buckman
live on the server and we got a message
from one of the teams that he was
playing for over in an hour and he can't
reach the level up challenge he can't
reach that level on the game can and I
will freely translate for you I'm inside
the game it's been over an hour I've
been trying to reach level up I don't
understand what I'm missing can I get
like the e the smallest hint possible so
as you can see we're pretty laughing
hard and said no you're not supposed to
play the game solve the challenge that
was funny ok and now for the winners
first of all before we begin again this
year an honorable mention adam donenfeld
and here i would like to move over for a
small message that he prepared for us
everyone sorry for not turning up this
year currently in Korea I'm kind of
disappointed about myself for not being
a little bit more prepared for the Magic
Kingdom series it wasn't really easy to
do that everyone sorry for not turning
up this year currently in Korea I'm kind
of disappointed about myself for being a
little bit more prepared for the Magic
Kingdom series it wasn't really easy to
do and now for the winners third place
earnest and young please send a
representative to stage so we can mock
him all together
ey
[Applause]
so you I had a very large team and they
ruled the game up to I think the eighth
day and then other teams passing by on
the other hand they did awesome
challenges and it's almost everything on
the first day so hurry to them thank you
second place JCPS
[Music]
[Applause]
so JC TF is one of the most awesome
teams also many intel representatives
there are also hiring thank you to the
JCPS team also a very very strong group
thank you okay first place done okay
done here won first place which means
that he gets a very special portion of
embarrassment for him first of all thank
you very much done for single-handedly
beating everybody else so first of all
first place you win a switch but the
most important thing you win the besides
Cup
thank you you were above awesome thank
you and with that I'm wrapping up
everybody thank you for playing
come join us next year either as
challenge writer or challenge players
thank you