we have I don't know if you guys
remember that we have a tradition at
besides we have a shot sometimes they do
it after we do it before because it
helps people deal with the stress but
it's not compulsory if you don't like
alcohol then we can give you other
things as special pink juice yes good
morning everyone
once get this party started thank you so
much for coming out my name is Eva
galperin I'm the director of cyber
security for the Electronic Frontier
Foundation and also the head of EF Epps
threat lab which concentrates on
producing research that protects
especially vulnerable populations all
over the world so I am here to talk to
you about one such project that was
non-consensual E foisted upon me by the
universe about fighting spell swear and
stalker wear so in order to to properly
understand the background of this
horrible situation we must go back in
time it's very timely why me to what I
call the beforetime or 2017 so way back
in the beforetime in 2017 I had spent
several years doing security research
specifically research on a PT's
targeting journalists and activists back
in like 2010-2011 it was still news that
that there were a PT's that were not
five eyes Russia China or Israel people
were very excited to learn this they it
was also news that these apt
you were targeting journalists and
activists and so there was there was a
lot of work to do
unfortunately I at the end of 2017 I
discovered that one of my research
partners with whom I had done many years
of this research and published many
papers was a serial rapist so oops and I
was mad a little bit and I I did what
most people do when they get mad I
tweeted and okay really just me so what
happened was I'm sitting there and I'm
reading a an interview with one of his
victims and the interviewer the
journalist asks his victim what took you
so long to come forward it was you know
it's been many years this is a really
horrific story it sounds like a really
bad guy why didn't you say anything
earlier and she said I didn't speak up
because he was a hacker and I was scared
he threatened to compromise my devices I
didn't know what was safe I didn't know
what he would be able to do to me if if
I spoke up and when I read this I was
furious and so I went to the Twitter's
and I tweeted if you're a woman who has
been sexually abused by a hacker who
threatened to compromise your devices
contact me and I will make sure they are
properly examined so I thought that this
was just sort of a you know random angry
tweet and maybe I would hear from one or
two people it was really no big deal I
was just gonna like event my spleen no
no so approximately ten thousand
retweets a God knows how many emails
later I had a project on my hands and
that was no fun so I was getting
somewhere between 0 and 12 contacts a
day
mostly made up of people telling me
about the worst thing that had ever
happened to them the victims were mostly
women the abusers were mostly men but
there were also cases of women abusing
men of abusive same-sex couples
I had one case in which a man came to me
because his ex-boyfriend had outed him
as gay to his extremely conservative
Korean family so there were there were
all kinds of things that I saw over the
over the course of my let's go with
involuntary research and it turns out as
as with most research projects that my
original assumptions about what it was
that people needed were wrong most
people that came to me were not
suffering from device compromise most
people didn't need forensics sometimes
it was a scam I don't know how many of
you are familiar with the emailed scam
going around in which a stranger sends
an email saying I have installed a rat
on your machine and I have seen you
masturbating and I have recorded this
and I'm going to send it out to all of
your contacts to your eternal shame this
is
it is a scam please don't send that
person Bitcoin and so I was contacted by
a lot of people who had these things and
just like couldn't they couldn't tell
whether or not this was legitimate most
often what I saw was account compromised
basically if I had a login it was
compromised email Google Drive Facebook
Twitter snapchat Instagram whatsapp
Apple IDs tik toks I had to figure out
what a tick tock was I am an old person
we don't have these things that's like
vying only slightly longer so I spent
some time thinking that the problem was
device compromised the problem was not
device compromised it was almost always
account compromised and the good news is
that we have advice
for account compromised account
compromise is reasonably well understood
and so if someone comes to you and and
says that they're concerned about
account compromised you tell them change
all your passwords use a password
manager turn on the highest level of
two-factor authentication that you're
comfortable using now I know that I'm
about to get a whole bunch of well
actually's from the audience about how
you should never use SMS 2fa and
everybody should be carrying you the
keys around at all times
listen I agree with you I do but I also
believe very strongly in harm reduction
if I am talking to a group of people who
are not comfortable using you the keys
or who can't spend 40 or 50 bucks on on
a you the key or who can only you know
sort of wrap their mind around 2fa SMS
it is better than nothing
and so following the harm reduction
approach you meet people where they are
not where you think that they should be
and certainly if they're not where you
think they should be you don't tell them
well you just don't deserve security
clearly your partner should be able to
spy on you wherever you go and whatever
you're doing so the bad news is that
sometimes it really is around a very
small fraction of the cases that I
looked at involved actual rats but they
were also the most disturbing
they were usually the ones that were
linked to a long-term harassment to
physical threats to physical violence to
kidnapping and all kinds of really
disturbing abuse including weirdly
financial abuse and it turns out also
the rats were usually not on devices
that hackers had threatened to
compromise because it turns out the
hackers are lazy
and hackers are also usually kind of
cowardly and so often what they would do
is they would threaten to compromise the
device in order to maintain a certain
amount of control without actually
having to install a rat but in the cases
where a rat was installed usually you
didn't see that kind of threat because
the hacker didn't want to tip his victim
off and wants to maintain access so you
don't see that particular type of
control there and one thing to note is
that abusers lie about their
capabilities all the time it helps keep
the victims feeling confused and
powerless when they don't know the shape
and the limits of the abusers
surveillance so here I am looking like
brie Larson hair flowing in the wind and
I had so many emails and so many
messages every day from people telling
me the worst thing that had ever
happened to them and I just plotted
through it like I was the universe's
helpdesk and started to help one person
at a time
now this is not efficient this is the
hero model I get to feel very good about
myself because every day there's
somebody who tells me something terrible
I tell them how to fix it they tell me
you know oh you're you're a superhero
you're a saint
you're brie Larson wired writes up an
article about me Fast Company writes up
an article about me I look out into the
distance like a thought leader very
dramatically lit but the hero model is
being a hero is very satisfying
but it doesn't scale I and so I spent
some time thinking about what I could do
that would help more than the people
that knew to contact me directly and
more than one at a time because helping
one person at a time
is extremely satisfying but a really
good way to end up burnt out I and not
do I don't know the rest of my job so I
engaged in some thought leadership so I
have advice for people who compromised
accounts but the worst abuses that I'm
seeing oh the result of compromised
devices mostly Android phones running
spouse we're in stalker where they were
giving away people's locations the
contents of their emails their text
messages their whatsapp messages photos
snapchats
insta their web browsing searches the
contents of a phone are really revealing
searching somebody's phone is the next
best thing to having access to the
contents of their mind this is one of
the reasons why why a PT's find
compromising phones so great for Intel
and this is also the reason why abusers
think that compromising the the phones
of their of their former partners or if
their victims will get them so much so
this leads us to the next question which
is so how do I know it's spouse where
the good news is that it's much easier
to find spouse where then it is to find
a state actors malware you can just go
to google and search for it I am as I've
pointed out before extremely lazy and so
I was excited to discover that I could
just search for this stuff and pull down
sample after sample after sample so this
is the results of a search for how do I
spy on my girlfriend's phone it's pretty
straightforward you just click on all
the links download a bunch of packages
so again how do I know it's spouse we're
like they will tell you this is from
cocoa spies advertising copy access to
Coco spy gives you the lead on how to
spy on your wife with ease you don't
have to worry about where she goes who
talks to or the websites that she visits
or have an actual conversation with her
about your relationship and just in case
you didn't think that was creepy enough
oh don't worry
the creepiness goes up to 11 so this is
a screenshot from mobile spy mobile
spies spy app for personal catch
cheating spouses this is a lengthy
paragraph about how common cheating is
in in relationships and why cheating is
very bad and this is a photo of a man
who is beating his female partner and
there is blood on her face now let's be
clear in this photo cocoa Spy is on the
side of the abuser they want you to be
that guy doing that to this woman and
they're selling you a product in order
to help make that happen so that brings
us to this guy Jean Pierre Lister there
it's actually not a big difference
between sort of free easily available
rats and stalker where or spouse where
so Jung careless sewer was a hacker who
went by the name of like that dark comic
coder I
and he made dark comic rat which you may
or may not be familiar with it was cheap
it was easy it was ubiquitous and I
spent many years tracking the use of
dark comet by a group of pro-assad
Syrian hackers who are using it to
target opponents of the of the Assad
government now when John Kerr the sewer
read these reports and his his work
became synonymous with tracking Syrian
activist
you've shut the project down and one of
the things that that he said was
essentially listen when I built this
thing I thought guys were just going to
use it to spy on their girlfriends it
didn't occur to me that it was going to
be used by you know murderous hackers in
order to send you know innocent
dissidents to torture camps and so what
I'm going to be doing is I'm going to be
shutting this project down what is
implied here is the guys spying on their
girlfriends using this route is
perfectly fine and that is really the
the notion that we need to change that
is really the most important thing
interestingly enough the wired coverage
of Jean peerless sewers decision to shut
down dark comet was hilariously
sympathetic the title of the column the
story that Wired wrote about it was how
the boy next door accidentally built a
Syrian spy tool sure he accidentally
built a Syrian spy tool but he
deliberately built spouse we're in
stalker where he's not the boy next door
he's not a good guy if you see this guy
tell him I'm looking for him so again
how do you know it spouse we're how do
you know the the software that you're
looking at is not just some sort of
innocent like keep track of your kids
keep track of like everybody in your
family so that you know whether or not
your partner is going to be late for
dinner
kind of situations and the key here is
deception spouse we're and stalker wear
is designed to run invisibly on the
victims device and so if the program
runs invisibly you can't give consent
even if in order to install the
the program you need to have the
username and password and up until
recently most of the companies that I
talked to including most most AV and and
security companies would tell me that if
you have the if you have the login
credentials you have legitimate access
to the device and my reply to them was I
have some news for you about how abuse
works
it was extremely common to see abusers
convince their victims to hand over
their login credentials in fact this
sort of behavior was routine and that's
why we really need to rethink our our
definition of this stuff so I did a
little research I went and downloaded
all of the most common spouse wear and
stalker wear again very easy because all
you have to do is search for it on the
Internet
then I ran the packages through through
virustotal almost immediately I think
just same-day checking and I discovered
that the pickup was very low these are
my results from I think back in April
right here I think this is a result for
the truth spy showing a showing that
only seven out of sixty a V products
were accurately recognizing this product
is malicious here is another one we were
seeing 10 out of 61 again not very good
and what this means is that even if you
had a even if you had the truth spy on
your phone maliciously installed by a by
an abusive partner and you had AV e on
your phone it still wouldn't pick it up
so that's useless
so back in April I managed to
Vince Kaspersky just start taking stock
aware and spouse we're more seriously
and what they did was they added this
sort of capability to their to their
product if you download the Kaspersky
you know mobile mobile AV now if they
run into any of the stalker where a
spouse where you will get this message
right here a privacy alert letting you
know that that this stuff is malicious
and bad and offering to remove it now it
does not remove it automatically one of
the reasons for this is the way that
abuse works it turns out that there are
situations in which alerting your abuser
to knowing that you are being watched
or taking steps to thwart them can
sometimes lead them to escalate to
greater violence and I really want to
leave it up to the to the target to the
victim the the survivor to decide what
their appetite for risk is instead of
making decisions for them because if
there's one thing that I have learned
over the course of this project it is
that every assumption I made about who
was the victim about what they needed
about what needed to be done and about
what was helpful turned out to be wrong
so the more power that you give them to
make their own decisions the better
additionally look out put out a a blog
post saying essentially oh we have
always done this we have always taken
spouse born stalker we're very seriously
and you can you can download look out
and it will find all of this stuff for
you yay so two down
sixty something to go so there's still
some work to do but it is my
understanding that the AV industry has
really started to pay attention and the
they are looking at adding this sort of
capability to their products which is
really cool because now I will be able
to tell people just download antivirus
and you will know whether or not their
spouse where stalker where on your on
your device so again what can antivirus
do I antivirus can start detecting
spouse wear and stalker wear label it is
malicious and stay on top of it there
also a few things that Google can do
Google could do a better job of policing
the Google Playstore right now spouse
weren't stalker where in the manner that
I describe it stuff which is designed to
run invisibly to the user on your device
I is not allowed under the Google Play
stores
policies but sometimes this stuff sneaks
in anyway so Google should really stay
on top of it you may also ask yourself
what can developers do one of the things
that developers can do no matter what
product they're building is make it
easier to rule out a rat and pin down
actual account compromised and you could
do this by having one page or tab where
the user can see all of the accounts
that have access to the data and which
data they have access to you can have
one page or tab that allows users to see
devices and IP addresses that have
recently brought logged into their
account and of course support 2fa again
preferably something stronger than SMS I
would really really like to see the
normalization of not just to IFA but the
strongest level of 2fa that you can
really convince users to accept which
leads us to the next question what can
government's do so I'm a little
skeptical of authority governments I
know that this is going to come as a
terrible surprise to everybody in this
room
and so when faced with a problem
frequently people say there ought to be
a law and when I hear there ought to be
a law become very suspicious so let's
start by looking at the laws that
already exist the following is a US
legal analysis because I have a floor of
angry us barred attack lawyers in my
office and I do not have a floor of
angry Israeli barred lawyers this is a
sort of project for anybody who is who
is listening to this talk if you are an
attorney a analysis of the laws that
these that these programs are breaking
in your country would be extremely
welcome recently citizen lab put out a
put out their own legal analysis of the
laws which are being broken in Canada by
these companies so there's room for
everybody let a thousand angry lawyers
bloom and write analyses so US law and
we will go through this fairly quickly
because I imagine US law is not terribly
interesting to you there are some
federal laws that are being broken
including the federal wiretap Act the
stored Communications Act and the
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act
I am extremely hesitant to use the
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act because
frequently the Computer Fraud and Abuse
Act is the law under which most hackers
are prosecuted and it's extremely broad
but there are definitely cases in the
use of spyware and stalker where where
it's not a broad reading of the law to
go after them so the federal wiretap Act
prohibits the manufacture distribution
possession and advertising of certain
intercepting devices it's not limited to
the developers of spyware the FWA s
prohibitions are quite broad generally
covering the devices that are primarily
useful for the purpose of syrup
just interception uh not just illegal
surreptitious interception and as a
result even the surreptitious monitoring
of children which may be legal
advertising it may may still be illegal
and as you can see we've had the
government go after a company called
stealth of Jeannie for this very reason
and they were violating the FWA the
federal wiretapping Act you can also
call in the FTC the Federal Trade
Commission in 2012 the FTC charged
designer where LLC a company that
provided spyware to rent-to-own computer
owners and entered into a consent decree
with the company agreeing not to collect
data from computers without giving clear
and prominent notice and obtaining
affirmative consent we also have state
laws so one of the most annoying things
about US law is that we have laws for we
have federal laws and then we have state
laws and we have 50 states with 50
different laws for greater confusion I
and almost every state I believe has its
own wiretapping statute some of the
states have what we call two-party
consent wiretapping laws which is to say
that in states such as California and
Maryland you cannot record a
conversation which is happening between
two people without the consent of both
people which makes spyware and stalker
where that records your conversations de
facto illegal because the person who who
has the stuff installed on their on
their phone was not able to consent they
don't know it's on there but also the
person that they're talking to is not
able to consent because they're not able
to ask them for consent there's also the
consumer protection against consumer
spyware act a awkwardly named California
law
that is specifically designed for for
the purpose of going after spyware so
again the tools exist this is not a
situation where we need new laws what we
need is for the Department of Justice
and for state attorneys general to start
enforcing the laws that already exist
and we need to see greater analysis all
over the world of the laws that are
being broken in other countries because
the Internet is global and spouse where
and stalker where and abuse are global
and it's not just limited to to the
United States so the more lawyers that I
can throw at this problem the better and
finally I just want to remind everybody
that I didn't invent the terms stalker
wear or spouse wear I don't do this work
in a vacuum I it is only possible for me
to do this work because so many people
did research before me that includes the
journalists at motherboard who have a
series called when when spies come home
who did a lot of the research that that
my work is based on Thomas Brewster at
Forbes did a lot of this work Chris Cox
has done an enormous amount of work
Harlow Holmes who works for the freedom
of press foundation has been doing a lot
of the sort of one-on-one hero work that
I was talking about earlier helping
women individually and without them I
would have essentially had to reinvent
the wheel I'd also like to give a shout
out to citizen lab for their for their
Canadian analysis of the laws that are
already being broken I think that that
stuff is extremely important and I would
like to give a shout out to Dave Moss
and Cooper Quinton who are my co-workers
at ya FF the right lab who supported me
all through my research and last of all
I want to give a shout out to you guys
because
somebody has to build on this research
somebody's gonna have to do with legal
analysis somebody's gonna have to go and
make the cases at the AV companies
somebody's gonna have to show up when
somebody makes a new product and say
well let's talk about the domestic abuse
case and what I'm hoping is that it's
going to be you thank you very much
[Applause]