the magic of technology
um if i could tell the seven-year-old
myself that i would have
something in my pocket that was way more
powerful than the most powerful computer
i had at the time and i'd be presenting
yeah just amazing hi everybody my name
is jed
last year i left my job as a in-house
security manager to
work as a security consultant at a
managed service provider
i provide guidance and support i do a
lot of pre-sales and post-sales work
i play with lots of interesting cool new
technologies and
occasionally have to help people manage
incidents
over the last year i've learned a lot
i've seen a lot of environments
i've got domain admin and global admin
in more places that i care to think
about
thankfully i have a good password
manager and i use random passwords
everywhere
and there's a couple things i want to
talk about today because i know there's
a fair few defenders in the room
and because i love analogies and i'm a
little bit of a narcissist
i'm going to talk about those by talking
about my toyota corolla
that's my corolla the best car in the
world
i bought my corolla back in 2012 because
my wife and i were expecting our first
child
um prior to that i owned a starlet and
as anyone who has ever owned a starlet
knows
one cannot simply fit a car seat in the
back of a starlet
um and so after trudging around auckland
for a day going from car yard to car
yard finding a whole bunch of different
things
i bought a corolla which is like a
bigger version of a starlet
it can do north 100 in some number of
seconds
i've never seen it on any of the top 10
prettiest cars list anywhere
it doesn't have car play or sat nav or
push button stop start
there the spare wheel is one of those
useless space savers
but i could fit a car seat in without
becoming a contortionist
it's one of the most reliable cars ever
made which is important for me because
we don't have two
it's got a big enough boot to pack a
family size camping trip and it even has
a class one tow bar so i can take the
bikes
aren't using them correctly anyway
they're certainly not using all the
features
which leads to something that we often
talk about but we need to remind
ourselves about more
security is not just about the
technology people and processes play
equally
if not in more important roles because
technology by itself
never solved anything accidents happen
there's only so much you can do to
mitigate the impact but the impact of an
18 wheeler is still going to hurt
regardless of if you're in a corolla or
a hilux
instead of focusing purely on the safety
technology
are there things that you could be doing
to improve your your driving to minimize
the risk of that impact
do people in your organization know who
you are are they scared to bug you
because you're busy if something went
wrong
are they too afraid of being told that
it was a pebcak issue or an id10t
error because ha ha but building a
resilient organization means building
trust between people
so they can make mistakes and that's
okay because we can fix it together
how do you go about fixing it what about
your processes
how do you know you're taking full
advantage of the technology you have
how do you know you're maintaining it
properly are you doing things that are
risky
just because that's the way it's always
been done that server 2003 box you have
over in the corner didn't fall over
yesterday
but that doesn't mean that it's okay
that it's on the backlog
waiting for a spare moment to fix it at
some point in the foreseeable future
so instead of trying to map your product
set to mitre attack and worrying about
all hypothetical coverage points
to the minute detail spend your time
talking to your people improving your
processes
auditing your vulnerabilities test your
processes especially
backup restore and account compromise
what would you do if someone came to you
and says
i've got a problem i don't know what it
is i need you to help me fix it
show people how and why you use a
password manager
i'm assuming of course that everyone in
the room has a password manager if you
don't
or you don't know why come and talk to
someone me
for example i'm resisting the urge to
say make people in process great again
because i think there's been enough of
that but
sorry remember i said that most of you
probably have the right technology for
your needs but keep in mind that needs
change
and it's important to track your needs
against what you can deliver
covid was a great example of this
suddenly expectations for what security
meant
and how we needed to defend our systems
changed vpns are no longer the best way
to do things
you can't always rely on people even
using managed devices anymore
but that's okay because there's never
been a better time to be a defender
the mitre apt evaluations prove that
while there's no such thing as a perfect
security tool
all of them do a good enough job sure
there are differences in their
approaches and some
are stronger in some areas than others
but they all provide a good enough level
of protection for you to build on with
your good piece
with your good processes and your good
people
but if after improving your processes
and
as best you can you still aren't getting
what you need you're in luck
because i've been lying to you that
is not my corolla it was but it's now
jenny's corolla
see last year my wife and i were
expecting our third child and as anyone
who's ever owned a corolla nose
one cannot simply fit a car seat in the
back sorry three car seats in the back
of a corolla
so i sold it and this was the trade me
picture
and that's my rav4 it's like a bigger
corolla which is like a bigger starlet
and so my final point recognize when
your needs have changed and you need to
make a change to accommodate it
but know what problem is that you're
trying to solve
so that you can claim explain it to
people clearly evaluate solutions
properly
implement it well and measure how
successful you've been
i've seen many a late night email come
at us looking for a solution to an
ill-described problem
it usually ends in tears if not at least
the budget blow out in a partially
undelivered project
also don't get distracted into thinking
that everything about your environment
needs to change
just to accommodate one change every
car i've owned has been dark blue
because i like dark blue cars
i don't need to change to burnt orange
just because that's now an available
option
if you feel you don't fully understand
what or how things need to change
that's okay too hopefully you have a
managed service provider who can
help and that you trust to give
impartial and good advice
you but you have friends if you look
around you everyone here
today is here because we we are
interested and passionate about security
and some of us are even old enough to
have scars of experience
talk to others explain what you're
thinking and ask for their advice
thank you if you think i'm wrong or
would like to talk further hit me up on
twitter
or email because i'm under time i've got
one bonus thing for you because it's
always a good idea to drop open source
tools at a security conference
if you're like me you probably had to
type a horrible long complicated
password or url into a sandbox where you
can't just copy and paste it
i had to do this enough that i actually
got motivated to write a very simple
small tool
it's up on github if you go to github
it's actually i
even went to the effort of putting it
into the windows store so that you don't
have to go through
the rigmarole of asking for a security
software exemption from your security
manager you know because asking yourself
for things is always hard
be safe look after each other and please
be proud of your toyota corolla thank
[Applause]
you