so
where are my beautiful assistants there
all right so um
you don't yet even know what you're
doing but you'll figure it out um
so i'm not sure if anyone is familiar
with this
we're going to play a game i know that
not all of you went to university in
hamilton so hopefully you'll um
be familiar with never have i ever if
you're not it's
usually a drinking game where someone
says a thing that they've never done and
the people who
have done that thing will take a drink
but i didn't feel like passing a tequila
bottle around was very covert friendly
uh so instead
um with a spooky season after all we've
got some
halloween candy there which you can grab
some handfuls for
my lovely assistants will distribute it
around the room for you to grab some
handfuls of
um this technically there's no eating in
this building
um please be a tidy kiwi and
hide all your rapists and we'll pretend
we were never here
all right so this is a drinking game
about
security awareness everyone's favorite
topic for a friday afternoon
and i'm
uncannily asked to speak about security
awareness because i've been doing
security awareness training since before
security awareness was a thing
um i was a digital literacy librarian
decades ago for a long time
i used to teach teens how to
change all their privacy settings and
facebook and then i need to teach their
moms how to use facebook so that the
teams would have a reason to use
their knowledge about privacy settings
so i used that to leverage my way into
security which means that
i've done a lot of work in security
awareness
writing presenting i've been
involved in four different e-learning
products
i was even a voice-over artist for a red
panda once
so trust me when i say security
awareness
doesn't work which is not to say we
shouldn't do it i think it's more
important than ever
but the way we currently do it does not
protect us
from growing threats
security statistics are all nonsense and
made up by marketing departments but
generally speaking they all come out
around the same figure that somewhere
around 80 or 90
of security successful security
incidents are a result of
humans being exploited because people
are people they are vulnerable in very
special and interesting
ways and they will continue to be so and
people will continue to make it their
day job
to exploit that but the way we teach
security awareness is not keeping up
with this
growing uh growing threat
because we still do something that i
like to call no touchy fishy
i just need to live on that leave that
wrong enough for the best gift in the
world
what do i mean by no touchy fishy you'll
know it when you see it
especially if you've ever worked for a
university
yeah hot mess
you've probably seen some variant of
this in your life of the like just here
are some bad things if you spot any of
these bad things that's a bad sign
don't touch that email
the problem is that all of these things
that we're telling people are signs of
nefarious activity
are also quite often more often signs of
something
perfectly innocent and when you go
around telling people that things that
could be perfectly normal and safe are
actually signs of
some great conspiracy against them you
sound like
a conspiracy nut
so here is the drinking game has
everybody got some candy
did anyone grab a handful there all
right so
who here is prepared to say that never
have i ever
sent someone an email with a link in it
all right
now never have i ever
sent someone an email demanding that
they do something urgently
like i'm a consultant it's literally my
job to send people emails and say
can you do that thing please you said
you would do that thing can you please
do that thing
has anyone ever just sent out an email
never
have i ever sent an email with the typo
with some bad
grammar that got someone's name wrong
yeah these are things that we do all the
time and just telling people oh just
look out for those things if you spot
those things that sign of a baby
is useless because people see those all
the time and they get
used to those things being things that
people will do all the time
no touchy fishy doesn't work here's an
example
you know from a real security awareness
program of a real fake
email a real email out there telling
people
hi i'm from the dropbox i'm going to
shut your account if you don't click
this link it's very urgent
the problem is i've seen this email
before in my own inbox
from the real dropbox and if you didn't
have a side-by-side comparison if you
didn't know what to look like
look for would you really be able to
tell
the difference and it's got a link there
you know it's got this urgent click now
or lose everything it's terrible
in fact with this big scary bold text
they're telling you 15 yes
i think this one actually kind of is a
bit more of a scammy vibe than the fake
one
and you know i know what to look for
i've seen the security awareness
training and i know
that you know
real people out there don't know the
difference between a cdn
link and a bad link yeah they don't know
the difference between oh it's not
coming from the right sender and
oh we just couldn't get mailchimp to
work properly so we just kind of use
this other thing from our other domain
they don't know
the difference and they so they slowly
learn over time that i don't worry about
that that's probably fine
because real companies i see are doing
that all the time
so the way that we're teaching people
security awareness doesn't
work because they can't
tell what to do with the information
we're giving them
and blaming them for not getting it
saying that ah the user is stupid it's a
peb cake error
it doesn't help them to improve their
behavior
the good news is that we can change
we can make security actionable
we just need to change the way that we
do it and we need to start by well
actually
we need to stop doing security awareness
because awareness
is a very small part of learning and
it's only the first part
knowing is the start you need to build
on that knowledge
and get to the point that people are
able to action it
change their behavior
and i'm not going to dwell on this
because it's meant to be a lightning
talk and this is meant to be fun
and but there's a lot of different
things you can do to create an
environment where people
can build on their learning and put it
into
action change their behavior in ways
that will ultimately make your
organization more secure which is
actually the goal of security awareness
training
and i want to rush through a few of them
i don't want to dwell on them but
just a look a couple of the things that
we can do in security awareness programs
to make them better to make them
actionable
we can make it safe to make mistakes and
i'm not just talking about psychological
safety
although that's very important please
make sure that you're not too hungover
so that you can come see sarah's talk
tomorrow morning
about creating cultures where it is safe
it's going to be awesome uh i'm also
talking about creating environment with
the technical tools that you have
um so that the people aren't the last
line of defense they're the first line
of defense but you've got other things
in there they're gonna
tell if they did open that email or
click on that link or put in their
details and try to
minimize the impact of that
and when you've got those tools in place
people should know about
the tool catching a thing we should
actually be giving them that feedback in
real time
they say oh oh okay that watch that one
there that i saw then
was a scam and i did get caught out by
it
cool now i know what to look like
instead of look for instead of one
that's the abstract example
in that training that i do once a year
this needs to be something that people
are practicing
in little incremental bits all the time
so that they get the hang of it we need
to treat people
as more than just users i don't really
like that word we use it a lot
i find myself using it even though i try
very hard not to
um and part of this is the corollary of
people need lots of practice to get good
at things is people
also need rest they can't be constantly
bombarded and they can't be constantly
demanded
you need to be hyper vigilant threats
all the time
and if you're not it's going to be
terrible and everything is going to go
wrong and it's your fault
that's not a conducive environment for
learning so
use the tools that are available to you
to reduce
the number of those it's so obvious even
a computer can spot it
scammy emails that people receive that
websites they might be exposed to
but also if there's one thing we can all
do that doesn't require any fancy
tooling
as part of our security awareness
training
it is this okay here is some advice
i don't know if anyone recognizes this
does anyone remember around middle of
this very long year when new zealand
police announced that they'd had
a breach with a third party provider
that they'd used for some
market data and they put up this advice
and it's good advice
like i don't think there's anything
necessarily wrong with this advice the
reason that this particular
press release got lightly mocked is that
it came out literally two days after
this article in which it had been railed
that new zealand police had
sent an email to everyone on the
firearms license database saying hi
police here random firearms holder can
you please send us an email that says
what guns you have where are the guns
how are they secured
you know um love
the police p.s this is definitely us um
and to their credit a lot of
farmers got this email and alerted new
zealand police to it by ringing up 105
and saying
hey i think you've been hacked
and i mean i'm not i don't want to pick
on new zealand please with this example
because this is a really common thing
organizations that are definitely doing
security awareness training
like microsoft i'm sure that
the staff at microsoft maybe sarah can
tell me
get some security awareness training
once a year that will have some things
in it like
legitimate companies will never send you
an email with some generic greeting
i'm sure that ird are giving all their
staff annual training that's telling
them
don't trust a message that comes from a
random address in fact they have tips on
their website they're like you know spot
a scam
print fifty id and it says it's gonna
come from some random address you don't
recognize
like some short code
sms number cool um also again with the
no name hi iid here your mates
this is from a government sorry from a
university department's
it help pages and i know that if it's an
i.t department at a university they're
putting out the annual security
awareness training
and they're saying oh hey don't worry if
you want to download software and it
gives you this warning like just
click yes it's fine i trust it from
wherever it's from i know they're
getting security awareness that's
telling them never downloaded anything
you don't know where it's been
and i mean banks definitely i'm getting
security awareness training because the
pci council is saying hey
we've got a box we want you to check it
give everyone training once a year and
tell them to look out for suspicious
things and
you know the staff there are giving
people advice like don't use password
managers it's bad because it means
you're writing passwords down
yep i don't want to mock any of these
people
who sent these messages because they
were trying their best
because whoever is in charge of that
security awareness program did not turn
around and say okay
you're not just users we need to train
you as the people who are
creating the content sending the
messages to not do the things that we
are telling people that legitimate
companies would never do
if we want to help people to spot
the real scams in a way that's not going
to
overwhelm and consume them and turn them
into lunatic conspiracy that's like
us we need to
start teaching them to not send these
messages that's one thing we can do as
part of the security awareness programs
that
maybe we're providing them or
contributing to the content of them or
recommending that other people do
as consultants this is one thing we can
all do differently
right now to make the world a more
secure place
to help people to reduce the false
positives that make people
a little bit complacent and make it a
little bit harder people spot the scams
amid
the real emails in their inbox so that's
my only takeaway
that i want to leave with today apart
from
please be a tidy poo echo
thank you all
you