part of the day we can keep going all
night and really we got stopped because
of prizes surprise oh oh those are
delicious ok we're going to last talk of
the day everybody can hear ok i think
the mics working we can hear the
feedback of myself so come on everybody
last talk of the day hello Austin there
we go come on really pretzels are taking
you down that much from deep breath it's
almost over another hour we hope to
entertain you all right yeah all right
so let's uh so we're going to keep this
hopefully interesting for you here but
I'm going to kind of calm Michael down
here a little bit yeah kind of gets a
little bit out of control some calm down
a little bit I want to introduce us so
Michael golf myself Ian Robertson we
both go out and find bad juju and stuff
and we basically kind of call ourselves
of course as a result the milf hunters
so you know what were you seriously what
were you thinking get the mind out of
the gutter all right all right now we're
in life form and so we go after the
trigger finger their thing all right we
go after the bad actors of course that's
what we're going after and so some of
our background here which we think
brings a unique perspective to what
we're doing is we're both we both do
forensics analysis we go pretty deep on
stuff no pun intended malware hunters
wear blue team errs defenders of the
good it's really easy to find
vulnerabilities and stuff it's much more
difficult to find ways to prevent and
defend your networks and that's where we
like to share this kind of information
we're both developers and we're also
consultants so we're wrapping this all
up and hopefully we can impart some
information that'll help you all and be
able to take back some actionable
information
and of course we have unique huh and aha
moments so let's start off with a
typical malware investigation from an IT
perspective we've we've done several
talks we've surveyed audiences and this
is typically what we find if a piece of
malware is found on the system usually
the IT person will be alerted to it by
their antivirus program sometimes it's
drive-by downloads sometimes it to USB
stick something like that and typically
they'll just perform another antivirus
scan and if it comes up clean awesome
we're good if it has another problem
then they will initiate a scan
questioning and how many people in the
room actually see this in practice and
IT again lot more hands come on they're
recording raise the hands of its be
percentage we've all done this before
this is you know depending upon the
tools that we have at hand I love this
example here just from the perspective
of the wonderful guidance that kaspersky
gives you hear of what's their
recommendation ignore do nothing Hey
okay you know what's that problem solved
absolutely I've taken action and you
know what maybe I want to apply this
great logic across everything else so
let me check the apply to all objects
button to just simplify my life great so
antivirus sucks we know that okay it
hasn't been able to keep up with all the
all the samples that are coming out you
know a lot of repeat stuff but just
small has changes is all it requires to
bypass it in a lot of cases and you know
with the things that Michael and I have
analyzed we've got a detection rate of
about three percent of things that are
actually malware we've analyzed we're
getting hit rate of three percent when
we throw it up against things like a
virus total so pretty low and that's
really common the reason for that I
think even being a size three percent is
because they fish us as well and they
know what AV you're using so they're
okay to give you a piece of fish or
something
not really stealthy in an email fish and
your AV will not catch it but when we
upload it to VT we get some hits it's
probably the only reason it's a three
percent yep the other interesting thing
too is when you're looking at what does
get detected in antivirus with when
you're looking at say buyers total right
it's pretty common where you'll either
get maybe one or two hits on something
or you'll get like almost everything
hitting on something because they share
the information they have in the back
end so think about that the next time
that you're looking at changing up your
AV product or considering whether or not
it's all that useful to you so I t has
it has a few options when they're
dealing this with us right you can
either ignore the basic problem maintain
your status quo okay I know we've got a
problem I know we can't find this stuff
easily but we don't know what else to do
so we're just going to keep going we're
gonna ignore it we're just going to not
deal with it I'm just you know that's
what that's all we're doing or you can
do a better job watching for odd
activity and go into deeper
investigations looking at things like
you know doing a much better job looking
at things with splunk or using big fix
and unique ways or doing anything else
any kind of an additional analysis and
drilling in and doing deeper
investigations or you can wait until
you're told that you have a breach and
then you can spend a lot of money on it
and most of those breaches you'll get
notified of come from external third
parties where the stats here ninety-four
percent of her since been reported
lately that's amazing that basically
means we're not able to admit ourselves
or we don't know yes David oh why are
one and three different yeah yeah it's a
matter of time that's right yeah it's a
matter of time this is a fallacy right
210 day average right here third-party
Brighton because this is what a lot of
this is what a lot of folks think right
a lot of a lot of IT shops think that
I'll just be there it's okay but the
reality is you will get breached you
will have something happen and you will
have to spend once somebody once the
right person finds out you'll have to
spend a lot of money on it it really
depends on who that third-party is
how they bring that information to you
if it goes to the press is generally the
you know organs goes to the press or it
goes to some other source where you have
to now legally take action and follow
state breach notification law that's
when the money goes in right that's when
it starts flowing paste bin I got a
reported payment so typical of forensics
investigation examine registry keys
right so we're basically looking at
windows system it's ninety percent whats
in all of our environments and we also
look for nearly drop files obviously
this is kind of what you know what you
do in a daily basis or the tools will do
in a daily basis you know tripwire for
example we look for new services running
in processes we can do that via look eat
the logs and doing it Splunk you can do
it manually whatever tools you use so
you might use it in sporadic Tornetta
queue or what your sat in front you're
gonna get picked on come on right and
then you once you look at all that stuff
the process is running you're going to
then start looking at what's suspicious
to you the short list of stuff and then
we're going to generally exclude sign
files and we're going to talk about that
in a second and of course there's other
friends at goodness but this is kind of
the not deep forensics this is the first
pass the triage kind of forensics we
call it sniper forensics so with all of
your tools and tricks that you use at
some point you're looking at a system
that you think is probably infected and
you're looking at a file and you're
asking yourself the question is this
file ballot is this a good file is it a
bad file and so we put up a few examples
here for you so this is an nvidia user
experience driver it's got a lot of
information on it and you can look at
this and you can tell that you can tell
what this is supposed to be you don't
know if it's good or if it's bad we've
got some information on you know what it
is this one here you don't have a file
description it says the type of file
application extension okay for file
version 10 20 probably not true product
name is assembly imported from type
library blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah language is invariant language
unusual and now you have a file name
down here
original file name that's embedded into
the PE so okay I don't really know what
that is I'm have to do some more digging
and find out what that is and then
you've got something like this file
description to do all right how many
developers know what that is there
placeholder right all right file version
101 product name to do product name all
right awesome let's see we've got a
copyright of 2011 the date modify 2012
it says it's French it is not French
it's probably developed in France and
then we've got the original file name so
you're looking at this one going what
the hell is this this looks funky this
looks really weird right let me check
that out how many people have gone down
this route how many people do we all
have to do this if we're we're ops
people looking at the stuff we have to
determine whether this is good or not
all right so how about this one I
apologize for it being a little dark
here but here's another example this
file here not a lot of information on it
if you run this file it comes up with
program name is signed exe title very
descriptive verify publishers it's got a
certificate on it of Dell that's
actually a part of a Adele what is it
Dells local backup utility so this one
this utility actually does some
privilege escalations on box in terms of
analyzing this from a mallard
perspective this thing's what looks
really weird so you know they did a
really bad job of naming this thing
clearly nobody freaking ran this in a QA
mode to see how this thing looks to the
consumer or folks like us that are
trying to analyze a machine anybody here
from Dell take this back please tell
them to fix it we're going to pick on
another rid of yours
yeah yep tell you how many people here
would click on this and trust everybody
in the room is going to click on this
because we pretty much all do hide it I
actually clicked in it multiple times
just to make sure it export so how do
you know if it's good so what's some
kind of common things beyond just the
run another antivirus scan that that we
do and yeah this isn't very deep
forensics right but this is kind of your
starting off all right so you run it
against virustotal you run it against
you do some google searches on it you
look at file advisors sandboxes you
compared to other files on your other
systems and if needed you can download
and compare it download the same utility
if you can find it and compare that
version and see if it's the same so
let's step through those okay buyers
totals this is really interesting one
because I've been in a bin but today
specifically today a friend asked for us
to help him describe this problem a
couple slides from now that make sense
and I went back and forth his first
response to this was oh just triggered a
couple odd keylogger scenarios that
triggered with mcafee it's a false
positive because this file is actually
signed it's in it's in bit 9s database
it's actually signed okay it looks good
there's other you guys have clicked on
these things go to the data but this is
a well-known winnt I well known to us
not willing to all you but a well-known
piece of winnin TIA it is a launcher
okay and so I had to actually go back
and described to him how this thing
worked because his first thought just
like all of us normally do just like we
used to do look at this and say well
this one's now bad because of us but
look at this information hey it's VT
says it's okay and--but nines in the
repository we're going to move on but
the reality is this is a bad juju really
bad juju it's piece of it and we'll talk
more about what that means here in a
second but most of the time you analyze
it looks like this yeah and of course
sooner here's load
TI payload but the interesting thing
here is this is a real windows file
that's been modified we're going to talk
about that too yeah the key takeaway
from this one is when you're doing an
analysis when it says detection ratio 0
okay the only thing you should be using
virustotal for is to confirm that
something is malware if you get a bunch
of hits it's malware if you get like 20
40 hits anything basically beyond
generally around three to five hits you
say about five hits are good but if you
get zero hits don't trust it it can
still be malware a lot of time that's
why we're saying 90 right ninety-seven
percent of the stuff that we've looked
at that we know is malware doesn't get
hit in here zero hits now the cool thing
about this particular one is the fact
that this is a real windows five okay
now a lot of people say if i upload my
malware and virus total comes back and
says never seen it then you've just told
the malware writers that you have the
malware because now they can check
virustotal for the hash and see that
someone checked it we've been discovered
right so is this a decision you have to
make when you're researching this stuff
to determine whether or not you're going
to upload the virus total when we do
this we've already determined that this
stuff is bad we're putting it up here so
we can laugh and say yep they didn't
know anything about this right so we're
validating what we already know and yeah
we're letting them know what's a cat and
mouse game with apt we're letting him
know they know we know where they know
we know
and all that it was back forth back
forth but the reality is we triggered it
we let them know we know you know you
know Google so okay I find out of the
file as part of this payload and I
google it three hits okay what in Google
can you google and only get three hits
one hit two hits four hits nothing right
if you don't if you can't get something
that Google out of it that's bad and so
here's an example if you look at all
these they actually have nothing to do
with what we put in the Google search
another indicator that something's amiss
here and then Ian did a good ones you
just wanted to trigger one because we
see this a lot when we do these yeah
it's very common that if you put in if
you're searching for a file one of the
first hits that will come up is a his
sites that say oh yeah we can help you
identify and fix your problem and help
you replace any bad dll's that you have
on your system just install this utility
it's awesome and so I just put in some
BS dll name i called it your dll and
local comes up dll-files how to install
your dll MPP tools free download I mean
so you can't rely on google for going
and trying to tell you whether or not
the stuff's good or bad it's all
information you have to take into
account so file advisor here's the same
file if you noticed earlier it was
formed dot exe but if you notice here
it's ink formed X exe this is probably
I'd love to get a copy the real one but
this is probably it's real name so the
Marian's have actually changed the name
in the use of it it is probably a valid
executable probably or has the Microsoft
certificate that I was signed with and
stolen we all know that happen with
Stuxnet so it's one of those cases or
micronauts off not know that it's bad
yet and have it has not revoked a
certificate the funny thing here is if
you look down here and we're not picking
on the vendor like this is really good
in certain environments right so but
we're just trying to point out that our
industry is looking at things wrong we
need to change I mentioned that Wendy's
talky of the day you know you got to
make bold statements we gotta think we
got to think outside the box we got to
change our behavior three seemed been
seen three times anybody noticed the
got see end at the bottom of this one
one and one makes up for a hundred
percent of what it's found in Midnight's
repository they're telling me they're
telling me they're telling you that this
is a good file okay anybody here if you
see two out of three hits from China are
you to believe this is a good file from
that screen right there Victor on it
alone yeah that's anti clear no one can
see it right so PC phone this is
actually a part of activesync okay what
version can't tell you that don't know
haven't looked that far I just know that
this is the launcher for some really bad
juju but the fact that this trust is
here that we rely on these tools that
these vendors sell these tools with this
trust you know is a bad scenario you
have to take all the pieces of
information and say hey wait a minute
what I just saw earlier is counter to
this what's going on here now we have
the other files now the other thing with
this one we don't have the screenshot on
this one but behind the scenes here
there's another screen that shows you
the trust rating level so it's out of 10
and in this book for with bit9 this
particular product you can move a little
slider bar to say how much trust you're
willing to to provide for the software
and so you base it takes that into
account so you say okay anything that's
like 7 or higher you know for example I
little go ahead and automatically trust
those things this one here anybody have
a guess on what that rating was how many
people think it was 5 or higher all
right Christian doesn't count cuz he
already knows all right how about 8 or
higher all right two hands three hands
no put your hand down Victoria no Victor
I was like no other city it was so 10 it
was 10 ok you couldn't even if you're
using this particular solution
configured this particular way now the
debate is this matt is this malware
maybe originally it was you cannot see
2009 May twenty-third 2009 it's 2013 it
has a thrust of 10 out of 10 it's been
seen three times twice in China
how many people here trust the spot and
I'm telling you it is part of activesync
might be here trust this file should
have been revoked should be removed
that's my opinion that's his opinion
couple of people depending on sure we
told them this a year and a half ago
it's still in the repository this is
pulled up from this week they don't like
is talking about this but it again it's
it's we're have to educate you that's
what we're here for sand boxes so we
also utilize sandboxes problem with sand
boxes is if I have a static dll if I
have that executable that X cube will do
something but I bet static dll and I
throw in sandbox it doesn't do anything
that comes back with this nice little
screen cannot load equals yes you need
to have an installer something to
deliver the dll into memory for sandbox
to work we've also received malware the
minute I put on the vm to analyze it
five minutes later it's gone so they're
doing vm detection right so you have to
look at this stuff and safe hmm how am I
going to see how many a sandbox is
payload I don't have the delivery
mechanism to already Anna box I've
looked at it I don't have the X cube all
so again here's the load birth showing
that it's you know again no valid two
different sandboxes no valid win32
binary because it's just the vol but yet
here I'm actually loading a fished
scenario and there is a report that we
see that's the weapon that's the wop
ending on so so if you were to you were
to be looking at the screen here you'd
probably look at this and say well this
doesn't look like malware right it looks
ok so for the to get a little bit deeper
into the the dll aspect of why these
sandboxes can't find these things
there's there's two ways well there's
more than two ways but there's two basic
ways that you can basically execute code
from within a dll and one is you've got
an entry point where as soon as the dll
is loaded up it'll go ahead and execute
that code within that section the other
is you're basically tapping into one of
the methods that's within the dll one of
the imports and when you're doing it in
that method it doesn't know the sandbox
doesn't know how to call that DLL it
doesn't know which method to use or
which parameters to use you've got
really good stuff where you can have a
method that
normally takes let's say windows dll and
there's a method that normally takes a
parameter that is a always a positive
value and you've baked this malware so
that you're going to pass it you're
going to passing in a negative value
when it sees that negative value it's
going to take a different action well
how's the sandbox going to have any idea
of that logic that it needs to pass it
this particular thing to get to execute
that way it's too easy to get past these
sand boxes and by the way this is
another valid PE injected modifying
windows dealer so two of them in here
and that's the wonderful results that
you get some of the sandbox with some
sand boxes are better than others
clearly this one wasn't very good in its
results doesn't tell you a whole lot and
you can go to the different screens and
information but this is you know kind of
what we have is the tools we use so how
do you know any enough that's good
comparing to other systems how do you
know the other systems are good if
you're comparing it you know is your
infection just on one machine is it on
two machines is on three machines we've
seen compromises across hundreds of
machines quite often I our vendors so we
had a conversation with wanted a con he
recently said yes I was brought in to
look at one box we know that service
compromise want to look at and they
found it and said okay have you checked
all these others now we're pretty sure
doesn't have it but you mind if we check
it and won't take very long to load our
agent level up okay over 100 infections
st. Maur right yeah so if you didn't
build a protected repository in advance
if you don't have a good set of very
simple from a very simple perspective
good set of hashes to compare and some
good things then once you're in this
mode of incident response you can't just
suddenly go okay let me make something
you know I'm not time and so if you
don't have that you're probably
replacing some reliance on certificates
that is you're going to probably weed
out those files that are digitally
signed that have authentic code
certificates on them since you can focus
on the ones that don't
CLP only did that so i work for HP i
love to heat them now that I don't work
for them pick on dell earlier now i'm
gonna pick on HP want to hijack this
light so these are typical HP files if
you've ever had to go through whenever I
do a come up with my short list to focus
in on these damn things are always in
there he's not that you can yeah they're
always that in their goddamn et bunch of
fixit's I know people and I told them in
there like it okay so if you look at one
of the pieces of information as Ian just
described certificate wise verified
unsigned now I'm sorry but these are HP
management dll's what in the hell they
doing not signing their management dll's
that's one the other is the name of the
file hpc something something something
the internal names are pml driver double
yellow why is the filename different
than the internal name warning or
Arvidsson again to us it's one of those
things we look at so it's like ah
there's not one there's not two there's
not three there's four a lot of these
and the bottom one clearly SNMP why in
the hell would you do that for SNMP
drivers I mean just it's really stupid
right this is the behavior we have all
of you take back to your shops and say
you guys have to quit doing this start
looking at this this is a five minute
job that you can determine if your guys
are writing stuff that they can fix this
so we can ignore it easier to move on
and all you can ignore it and move on
and of course you know the the idea that
weeding out the ones that have
certificates because they're probably
good is pretty bad we found just in you
know the stuff that we've worked on
Intel Microsoft lenovo all these
different certificates there's tons of
different certificates this is just a
short list but you know big name
companies things files that they are
stealing their certificates and then
they are making injected dll's or they
are making their own crafting their own
executables and appearing as those
products so if you see something like
that very difficult to determine just
right away by looking at the certificate
whether or not it's good
and another problem is Microsoft's
caching of certificates the the crls is
awful it's really freaking back
Microsoft can cache certificates for
months months and I have had on more
than one occasion where we've had
something that we have caught it had a
looked like it had a valid certificate
on it checked it against the built-in
Microsoft API calls and we go and we
pull the CR l's manually and we look at
it and it's been revoked and been
revoked for months it's there is no way
and this is actually built in windows
thing the windows API will refuse to do
a crl check on demand if it does if it
has never checked their certificate it
will go do one but if it has checked a
certificate and its stores if you look
at the certificate details if you drill
down far enough on a certificate it'll
tell you how long it's cached for
there's no way within the operating
system this is documented for you to
force it to do a crl check so once it's
cached if that changes any time soon
screwed so if you're doing in your code
any kind of certificate checking please
do not use the built-in windows api and
keep that in mind when you're doing your
certificate checks yeah no no I
literally there's there's actually
there's an msdn document I can point you
to that spells it out in no uncertain
terms that this is a built-in operating
system function and it cannot be over it
there's no way and I've drop there's no
way you actually have to write your own
crl and OCS CP parser or you can wait
ones and months and months yeah
well basically it will it's got some
internal it's got some different steps
of it goes through to make that
determination one of the things it does
is it'll go and it'll check when it
checks the website the website can
present it with here's how long you can
cash it for ya so it depends Mel tends
to be that but it doesn't have to be
yeah based on info these are Chinese
these are Americans would you trust
these for those or none well what you
now know see the challenge here
certificates so more on certificates so
again we'll talk more about the details
of sick check you haven't used it before
but this is part of the Tencent malware
we got the certificate of his leash use
reuse stolen sign again it shows that
it's sign shows that since inside its
got all the data cut it off so you don't
go you know run down and then again
here's the product ID QQ question
question question probably have some
Unicode in there you know first thought
is yeah this is probably okay we know
that's bad but to you it's probably okay
so that's the challenge here that we
have with the stuff that they steal the
certificate did they reuse the
certificate did they do a PE
modification that that kept the
certificate intact these are all
questions that you know we have to
evaluate when we're doing yeah you can
take a certificate out of one file just
the digital certificates just sitting
within the PE file you can take that and
you can move it into another PE file
okay which is fine now unless your
function that's doing the certificate
check checks the sort of the the hash as
a signature that gets built based upon
portions of that PE file and there's a
digital signature that's made based upon
that that signature alright that
validates unless your code is checking
that then you won't know that yes this
you basically what windows does is it'll
check the certificate you'll pull this
certificate out and verify the
certificate but it won't verify that the
certificate is signed for that
particular file so watch out it's
awesomeness yeah by the way
the last one the form died txt that you
saw up there a fish this is also a fish
example is he a pattern here the fishes
have valid certificate to get
by-products maybe to try and make you
think it's okay so here's another one
again formed exe so now you can see what
it actually it is now fortunately since
we've had this a while now we get this
required certificate is not within its
validity period when verifying against
the revocation list but a lot but same
thing microsoft corporation inc formed
exe but yet it's been delivered is
formed exe right there i can tell you
what a fishing should be changing names
ninety percent which it looks like look
at the names don't change but here you
go it's signed it just can't be updated
because we know why you can explain it
so again certificates the good in the
bay so on the Left we have a real
windows system32 load load verb dll
here's the ballot signed again can't
validate it it's been there awhile but
here's all the signs stuff and here's
the name of the file its load control or
dll from the movie and then here is the
same file that in the course of
infecting the machine they copy off they
PE infect and look what happen to it a
the hashes change the f1 FC won the name
and everything else all the metadata is
the same but you now have an unsigned
file but for the most part these are
exactly the same clouds so the good the
bad and the ugly if you look at side the
actual PE header here are the four
sections but the p infected now have six
this is the modified version of that
file VOD so what they're doing in this
example is they're just once you're
getting on box they're not actually
dropping a particular updated dll
they're getting on box or sing what dll
you have they know which one they want
to target and they're just injecting
code they're taking that making a copy
injecting code into that dll they're
rewriting the PE section headers they're
pointing in two different locations
they'll put some stuff at the end of the
file that will call that as either part
of the entry point or whatever whatever
want to do in their code so everything
about the file otherwise looks very much
the same now if they stole a certificate
and then they resign this file boom bit
product like bit nine maybe even you and
reviewing it would see a valid did it
get in move on totally bad so download
and compare you can download appear
files right I can go up and then that i
can grab this thing i did this with a
lenovo cam driver took a while give her
the favor trek getting plenty bo drivers
holy moly and finding the exact same
file that i had in the malware that took
a while and then finally download it and
I realized yes it's modified but it's
sign so here's an example of a signed
file that was modified or did the vendor
themselves at it oh got it from do this
and distribute it anybody heard about
the leno cam driver possibly having a
backdoor this is what i'm talking about
this is probably an example of that yes
yeah signed by the winnabow it may not
been revoked yet because again i had not
checked it from that perspective but
first pass it was a sign valid file and
it kind of looks okay and again you can
you download on versions anybody tried
to go and get like previous versions of
adobe or winzip or 7-zip or pick a tool
QQ browser kick you chad and pick a tool
right can you go find all these versions
so that you can actually do a compare
because they're using older stuff it's
really hard right it's not necessarily
an option maybe in the software there's
a license and hardware restriction
dongles what have you and do you really
have time to do this to an investigation
no sniper forensics you know we want it
we want to find it you want to contain
it you on a wrap kit it move
we want to do long-term deep long
expensive time-consuming forensics take
the drive out do it later we're looking
to find eradicate I don't have time I
don't have time for them I gotta move on
so how can you help what are the
actionable thing so if from a
development perspective we could get
software that looks less like malware
like good software that looks less like
malware that would help us out a lot so
that means marking up your metadata in a
consistent fashion so those things where
we showed you the to do right the the
version numbers that probably are you
know like 10 20 20 the defaults all of
that stuff the having the internal file
name be the same as the external file
name all of those things to keep it
clean and to make sure that that's
repeated over and over and so you kind
of build that pattern and make it more
difficult for somebody who's writing
malware who's maybe going to misspell
something or maybe going to have
something a little bit different they're
going to stand out a little bit more if
this good stuff is consistently tagged
from a metadata standpoint was there a
question no okay code sign all of the
pease so all your executables all of
your dll's OC x files you can sign your
activex controls all of those things
should be signed and you should use make
sure you use your relying upon authentic
code built-in certificates in the file
itself don't use the windows catroot
windows security catalog because we've
seen some compromises of that make sure
you timestamp it against the CAS so
there's that's a for many of the
products that are out there that's an
optional it's an optional thing most of
the time the products don't do it so
make sure that you are time stamping
against your CA so it puts into the code
and signs into the code the time that
that certificate was written use a
different signing key use a different
signing certificate for each product and
change it out every year at least or
maybe every major product release
you should look at this from the
perspective of your hopefully not but
your certificate make it compromised
your signing certificate make it
compromise your private key if that
happens you're going to need to revoke
your certificate you want to have the
least impact across your product line as
you can you don't want to have your
customers seeing all of your
certificates on all of your products or
revoke do you want to limit that down so
these keys these these private keys
aren't all that expensive not from a
large company perspective so get one of
those each for for each of your products
and tell the internet what is good ish
by publishing your hashes publishing the
files that are contained within your all
of your product set right when we did
the Google right we're googling for
something but there's no source of truth
there's no source of true saying this is
something that's good now if we had the
metadata and we could say this is what
this file is we know where to go look
this is from Dell or this is from Intel
or this is from your company when we go
we could go to maybe your website we can
maybe do a google search and we could
very quickly match these things up to
say ah yes it says it's this product it
says it's this hash we have a match we
have a total match on this stuff so
therefore we know it's good okay but
without putting that information out
there all we're going to get is what
some other third-party decided to
publish out there like download this
free tool to infect your computer and
analyze your stuff to see if it looks
like malware go through these same same
steps like we do this these very quick
steps to go through it and see how does
it come up does it look like network if
it looks like our try to design it so
that it doesn't so it doesn't hit those
flags so that you're not triggering so
that you're not getting tagged by
virustotal is saying one out of 40 or
two out of 40 or three out of 40 with
these you know semantic suspicious
incite type of triggers
so we can go into some detail on that
one on the next slide here I'll take
this one so again you know by search
from trusted third parties we had one
you're in Turkey right yeah you don't
want to buy stuff the turkey because
it's cheaper don't be a turkey you know
turkey and again you know don't use
foreign search us company and say we
love you for that by the way yep but hey
there's an advantage right we're an
american company if you have to sign
something with a foreign cert in that
for a foreign nation we understand
Russia is going to be monitoring the
Olympics they've already told everybody
and I can try to hide it and so maybe
that stuff would have to be written
inside of the Russian certificate we
understand but from an IR perspective
your own people's I rrr anybody's ir
that's a good thing it's easier for us
to deal with we can look at their
certificate we can see if it's our boat
etc do not use Packers and other leet
hackers tools for your own stuff yeah
but it's cheaper and free and all that
no no because people except in will pick
a smiling side now that for this people
like zip ting will pick up on that and
say something fishy about this file so
you don't want to do that you want to
use reputable stuff and again funky
naming conventions stop it HP Dell and
pick a few other companies but I mean
it's it's really it's kind of a bummer
to have that many files that are clean
and that you know we have to build a
list of bad looking stuff that's
actually good so please name the
internal and the external the same avoid
unnecessary privilege escalations and
you know again don't do things like
install the app data and program data to
try to skirt UAC UAC should come up
there's a reason for it when we find
stuff that's written to there we
definitely look at it more closely and
then we're going to make a call to you
we're going to ask you for this
information and you're going to say
don't keep that info we actually and we
know somebody Adobe so I reached out and
asked them hey can we get a list of your
hashes for CS products because you know
by a company policy we do not provide
hashes to anyone so let me get this
straight you've got like Brad loads of
files and you won't tell us what's good
hmm methinks they have had a problem
with that and who has compromised
certificates yeah gee I don't know I
don't know you're the skirting just
saying so again you know has access to
all of your favorite code base right so
protect your building arm too often we
see built environments that are on the
same network as everybody else who's
administrators and such if they bought
one of your boxes hello mid 90 or say
hello Adobe they're going to get into
the repositories bad design shouldn't do
this this is the keys your cast of your
code your good stuff probably has all
your stupid private keys there too so
they get in there boom done a bit nines
case at least the vm was powered down
for what six months before it powered up
and then you know all the data went out
but again if you lose your code nobody
will ever know because you're not
managing this in the right method you're
not doing what we're saying here because
we did you could very quickly revoke
that ink form cert patch and update and
now this stuff would flag and bit9 and
AV something fierce and again if you
lose your search will know because it'll
become more common to report them and
again if you didn't take this action
revoke will soon you didn't know you
were compromised and of course things
get worse just ask these three vendors
yep so from those who are concerned
about security from a I don't want the
public to know and pay a lot of money
for breach you you know I see not a lot
of effort being put on securing a build
environment because you say well ok it's
a code and the codes everywhere right
the codes on developer machines you
codes all over the place so you know it
might as easily get popped over here as
it does on this build machine but which
is maybe true if you don't protect that
environment well but if they steal your
certificate right then that's going to
be known somebody steals your code they
may not go and put it out and paste bin
or some you know some site 24 and share
it with everybody they may be interested
in it for themselves right they're going
to do for themselves and
share that out so it may not become
public knowledge that your code has been
stolen but if they take your certificate
what are they taking it forward they're
taking it to use it they will be sending
it out to somebody it will show up at
some point on someone's vote folks like
us are going to see that at some point
go ah you were compromised and we'll
start asking questions all right as soon
as that is known then that's going to
trigger you know that third-party
reporting you've been compromised what's
going on and then the breach engine the
response engine kicks in and the dollars
start you know having an impact right on
trillian sensation right mandiant will
love you both so even if you don't care
about your code at least protect your
build environment because you build
environment hazard is going to have your
private key on it so what can you do to
protect it keep those private keys
offline if you can limit your code
access limit anything that you can do to
help protect that production environment
maybe you have a separate production
versus test internal test build system
right maybe you say okay well we can't
you know we can't have all this stuff
off line we got to have this you know
online all the time right we're doing
compiles are doing continuous
integration okay awesome but how often
are you pushing code out to customers
how often do you actually say this is
the final code we're going to go ahead
and go live with this one bring up that
secure environment do what you need
there's your private key generate your
certs check everything make sure
everything's good and then you go yeah
nobody would ever ship infected code or
something with bad juju on it knowingly
right nobody would ever do that because
they don't have a good code repository
HP we both work somewhere that did that
you know HP's done at the printer
drivers it happens because they're not
protecting that that compiled pelo
they're not taking that copy offline
yeah keep it you know test live blah
blah blah why not not find Travie place
I worked you couldn't get into that
environment you try you literally
there it burned a CD he walked it over
he analyzed the heck out of it made sure
it was exactly what it was and then he
build the software from that in an
environment which got boxed and shipped
or downloaded very controlled not a lot
of people do that so with that thank you
questions comments with brainstorm not
too hard huh so something you could
actually do question about the four then
five children or hitting on yeah I would
just go straight with sha-1 and then if
you want you can do the chocolate 56
shop whatever but I think right now what
I'm seeing across the board is it still
pretty much shot one and I think it's
going to remain shot one for a while but
you can there's no reason to not just go
ahead and pin and include the islands
md5 using that much anymore help laws
that have posted oh absolutely yeah yeah
it's got to be for every individual I
would do ever I would every file in the
package just everything and listed all
out you know like little directory tree
type format or whatever but just you
know put them all right on there if it's
just you know we'll see folks that just
publish they the Installer but that
doesn't help at all you know this all
gets installed and it's probably deleted
off the system where it's sitting in
some you know uninstall the rectory and
keep it in some calls you know
your shop you gave us what we now
control good question comment come on
date of the day always yes I'm good
that's it you just want to be the price
all your greens hang out waiting for
prizes yes the matter you guys made of
the wall of shame because I say like
people well that's you don't green light
red light that they revoke it no no I
mean what we're trying to do is just
trying to give demonstration so you know
this is these are the things that we
encounter that we have to work through
and then you have to you know take
there's there's a there's going to be
problems in every product right there's
going to be problems with every solution
that's just that's just the way it is
but knowing what they are being able to
answer on them and understand here's
where it's good your boards badly like
the virus total example you know if it's
above five I know it's about five it's
bad definitely bad don't assume that
zero is good Sheriff or anybody those
vendors know that you've discovered what
appeared to be seized an hour yes we
work directly with all of those vendors
guess I won't even actually get ahold of
letter isn't in foreign country let me
know we really don't want talking yep
we're both in this new English I'm yeah
one more since there was a bit of
human hands how strict rule is that how
scriptable is this yeah I mean that's
the thing we're building thousands and
thousands thousands of meta installers
and so forth unless it's scriptable all
right we just next screen 15 sponsored
by your glasses a chapter and i'll be
doing a hands-on training all day it
will kind of be theoretically split into
two pieces the entry-level kind of
thinking that will do be providing let's
talk about some stuff and you'll see
some of the tools that excuse and i'm
shocked and talk to us of those and so
that you potentially could do this for
example in the example we had a racer
trace of napkin I could go to their
offer don't want to do shopping d I saw
out of LA and get whole disturbed
entirety if it was everything safe or we
had 150 miles there that's a hey you got
something tall practice with these
tryouts on the board and we look it up
for me and has all the information so
we'll teach solo strips in this session
in the number 15 so these are you in
here somewhere there you go as a visit
Camilla crater that ice is a supporting
this source fire and critical start will
be traveling to kellys I providing lunch
and sign up it's a threat station people
for no show and you're funded me know