thank you for coming I know it's early
and let me appreciate you guys coming
out and watching the presentation thank
you for the introduction so today we're
going to talk about malware automation
but before we begin I'll just discuss
the most important part of the
presentation Who am I so as mentioned
that the principal malware sang tasted
ours a and also the author of Mallory
kitson botnets it's a trilogy so this is
the first part I'm working on the other
two so if you have a budget for a book
this year please get a copy of the book
all proceeds go to my two kids 529
college fund and as we all know college
is very expensive so please get a copy
it's on sale in amazon by the way and as
mentioned i was with damballa for three
years f-secure for three years and trend
micro for eight years Trend Micro's
where I started my career they hired me
fresh out of college and then they
trained me how to reverse member so I'm
forever grateful for Trend Micro and you
can follow me twitter send me a message
ask me questions i'm always happy to
help out if it's an easy question I
answer immediately if it's a little bit
harder sometimes it takes me time to
answer it takes me months or years but I
will answer your questions and if you
want to read my blog in RSA that's the
link Whitney tops blog and about our
team recall the RSA first watch red
thread research team you can follow us
at RSA first watch and all our blogs are
in blogs that are si.com alright so
about the top so today I'm going to give
you an over-the-shoulder view of how
attackers create malware in a ver in an
automated fashion so for us to
understand that we would be discussing
first the current state of malware the
attackers arsenal and then the creation
process of an army of armored malware
and we will also discuss the
advantages of automation and then i will
show you guys a demo so i learned a hard
lesson actually give live demos i have a
live demo here but just in case i have a
video backup alright so the current
state of malware so as you can see here
in this chart this ashley represents the
total number of unique malware that has
been discovered year-on-year so this
chart was updated last october fifth and
the sequence see compared to a 2012 it's
already like 60 million more unique
malware that were discovered but then
again there's a flaw in this chart the
way it represents a uniqueness in
malware because here it represents
uniqueness in malware based on hash so
that means if you get a malware file at
one bite at the end of that file rehash
it then they would say it's a totally
unique malware but then again it's just
the same malware so that's one thing
that's wrong with this chart but every
year we get charts like this from our
security providers designed to scare us
I think but then again all of these
statistics here they're real and this
only represents those that were
discovered it doesn't represent malware
that hasn't been discovered yet so a
friend of mine mr. Solomon Sonja when he
presented in a hacker halted one of the
figures he cited Center multiply this by
four and that's the number of mallar
that hasn't been discovered yet so
before when it comes to campaigns or
malware outbreak there's only one
malware involved if you get the copy of
that malware create a solution for that
malware deployed the solution you
basically stop the malware outbreak so
that's the end of the story so SQL
slammer Melissa I love you warm my doom
all of those attacks were named after
the malware because it was only one
malware that was responsible for these
attacks but today most of the
attack campaigns that we see they are
using an army of armored malware so it's
not just one malware or one family of
malware these multiple families to
conduct their attack the main concern of
the attackers is the functionality of
the malgor if the malware has the
functionality they need they will use it
in their campaign and if you stop one
malware you just stop that malware the
other malware that are in part of that
campaign they keep on doing their own
directive and if they're stealing
information they keep on sending
information to the attackers so how are
they doing it they have tools so they
have the DIY kids they use armory tools
and they also use AV scanners as part of
their own QA which I will explain later
in this presentation so when I was
starting my career this was the first
DIY kit that i stumbled upon this was
created by a 15 year old kid he was 15
years old during this time from chicago
and this was really cool when the first
time i saw this kid because you don't
need to have assembly language skills
that we create your own malware unlike
before if you want to create malware you
need to know assembly language skills
but here you just need to know the
command line you can create your malware
and other groups one which calls
themselves PS MPC also created their own
so the same concept you just need to
know the command line and then you can
create your own malware or during that
time virus that's why pcl viruses
creation labs fast forward 10 15 years
we get spy I and we get soos so the
things that you need to take away from
this presentation are the main
differences between these two sets of
kids so the kids before they're more
about the pissing contest like my kid is
better than your kid while the kids
today they're more geared for online
crime like are stealing information
making money for the graders who or
whoever who bought the two
that they use in their campaign it's
more about the cybercrime and another
thing that we need to remember also when
comparing the kids of all to the kids of
the day is that vcl and PS MPC they can
only create finite number of malware
samples so if they can only create 20
samples 50 samples it's very easy to
create solutions for those you don't
even need to reverse engineer the kid
you just need to generate all those
samples and then you can solve them
that's why they were cool but they were
not that hard to stop we could create
signatures for all of those in one day
but with spy on Zeus virtually they can
create infinite number of unique malware
samples that's because they use time as
a seed so as long as time exists they
would create unique unique infinite
malware samples so the only the only
time they won't create a unique matter
example is that if the universe rip and
we're all back into being Stardust's so
arming tools so most of the DIY kits
they already offer some sort of armoring
or protection for the malware but of
course the attackers want to rely solely
on the protective mechanisms being
offered by the DIY tips so the use of
arming tools as well so uh one of the
most popular arming tutor packers so we
have different papers we have upx you
have belied the meteor and all that and
some of them like for this one these are
just based on three modules that you can
google and most attackers they will just
create a fancy GUI out of those are
publicly available modules and then they
would sell this uh in different hyper
forums and some script kiddies would
actually buy this for like ten dollars
fifteen dollars a pop so if they have
1000 customers for ten dollars that's
ten thousand dollars for them
already and it only takes like a couple
of hours for them to grade this so like
for this one this is also another
example of an encrypted Packer but this
one offer additional options so as you
can see on the right it says there can
compress resources it has anti debugger
crack you can compress icons most of
these features aptly work but some of
them they don't work but some of the
buyers of these tools they really don't
check so for me the way I analyze all of
this is that I have a bond file so I
would subject that pawn file to each of
these options but then sometimes when
you look at it it's just garbage of code
they just add garbage of code sometimes
it's all of them only like not
operations X or a register and then
that's it but still some people would
buy this but of course that doesn't mean
that some of the options here don't work
some of the more important ones they
really work and they give researchers
and security products a hard time
especially when it's a when it's a when
it comes to analyzing and reversing
malware so another army tool like for
this one indetectable net some
people if they don't have access to
those tools that i mentioned you could
go online like that and then get
services like this so indetectable
studnet when i was doing my research and
this this was free but now you need to
have a certain code and you need to know
the secret the URL so that you can
access this website so what it does it
asks you to upload your files and then
it would give you an encrypted version
of it but of course if I were if I were
a customer of this one I would think
Dwight twice about uploading my files
because then there's not nobody or
nothing stopping them from keeping those
files that are uploading to their
website first number one I don't know
who owns the websites but still people
with Ashley
get the surfaces of this website and in
underground you could athle sell malware
samples for one cent or even to a dollar
depending on how sophisticated that
matter sample is so if they're able to
gather 1 million Mallory samples then
they just encrypted set it to sell it in
the underground for once and that's a
lot of money for these people who are
running the website plus having services
like this you're aptly victimized in a
in three ways so number one you just
gave them your file and number two you
just gave them your credit card number
so that you could get the key codes and
the secret URL to license their website
plus they charge you 10 15 euros for
that access so you're actually being
victimized three times so another arming
tool is called the file joiner and an ex
a bundler so these two tools I always
call them the information routine
converted into a tool so before most
infections routine are built into the
viruses or into the malware because
their main concern is to infect all the
files in the system so if they happen to
infect a very popular program somebody
would copy that transporter discs it and
then that this gate would be like to a
friend and then that friend would put in
the PC execute that program then the pc
will get infected but of course nowadays
malware writers don't concern themselves
with an infection routines but if
they're going to spread their program
all over the world and make it enticing
they use these kinds of tools to bundle
their program with a very popular
applications so other I don't have a
screenshot here but there are tools also
like this that are for android apps so
you bundle you just write your own or
malicious or Java code and then bundle
it with an Android app and then you can
post it in a third party google play on
vacations so the main idea here is that
you get a very popular app you get your
program your money
this program bundled it together and
then spread it around you could post it
in a file sharing websites you could use
a peer-to-peer program or whatever ways
you want to share your program as long
as it's very enticing now software when
this tool first came out software
publishers what they did is that they
started posting the hash of their
software that the users download but
then of course if their website is not
secure enough nobody is preventing the
hackers or i should say hackers are good
people the attackers from compromised
from compromising their website and
changing the hash to reflect the hash of
their creation bundled with a legitimate
software so AV scanners AV scanners
they're used for quality assurance
purposes now if it's a highly funded
attacker group they could have different
of virtualization of virtual machines
that have different our security
products installed so that they could
submit all their creations there and see
whether it's detected or not and some of
them even have security appliances that
they have in their lab depending on how
much money the sponsor has but for this
one if you don't have all of that the
resources some of them just use a multi
AV scanner so this one athlete downloads
all of the engines from popular vendors
and then subject their malware creation
here to check whether it's detected or
not it's like an on-premise virustotal
but then again the disadvantage of using
this tool is that when they remove some
of the features that cause all of these
AV engines to actually have conflict
when they're installed in the system
they also remove the dynamic scanning
features so what's the what's left there
is that only the static scanning using
signatures or whatever the security
product is using it virtually killed the
heuristics and dynamic capability of the
security products although they
understand the trace most attacker
groups still use this kind of tools now
if they're small time attacker and they
don't have money or don't have dental
to buy the tool they could always go to
sites like this like virustotal novar
tanks and veer scan but the most popular
one that I've only seen used is no virus
thanks it's because of the option there
that says do not distribute the sample
but then of course even if you take that
there's no way of saying that they're
really not distributing it to AV
companies publishers are usually there
somewhere that says even if you take
this if you find this to be detected by
five or more a few vendors we will
automatically submit this to two
security companies but then of course
some have some attackers they would
athle risk it because the fact of the
matter is is that most security
companies they receive hundreds of
thousands of samples a day and like our
keynote this morning prioritization is
important if you cannot do it if you
could not do everything so nobody can
process hundreds of thousands of samples
a day so what security companies do is
that they prioritize all of these
samples samples coming from high high
paying customers are handled first and
those that come from these sources like
this usually it's sits there for months
even if they have automated systems that
automatically analyze malware great
signature for those malware's some of
these samples they sit there for months
even years that's why it's always fun
even when a malware when a big company
gets infected most AV companies would
say hey we have that sample in our
collection the past three months just so
happens that we didn't have the manpower
to look at it all right so the process
if you have the DIY kit you would be
able to produce your DIY kit malware and
then that malware you can subject it to
different standalone arming tools you
can mix and match together this the
different learning tools the more you
have the more you randomize the order of
the tools
you mess up the researchers that would
try to analyze and reverse the malware
and also confuse the security products
that you're up against so always
remember that the attackers creation the
malware it's up against two folds the
researcher and the security products and
most of these tools athlete take care of
making sure those two foals have their
lives miserable when they're handling
this kinds of malware and once you have
aptly submitted all of those two
different stand stand alone arming tools
then the Quality Assurance process
begins now they can use a on-premise AV
in the cloud AV different security
appliances network appliances I guess
and all that depends on how much they're
funded and then if it passes their
quality assurance then you have an army
of armored malware and also if you don't
have money to buy a DIY kit like a car
before it was leaked out it was
reportedly being sold underground for 40
grand a pop but then after that need out
they do just google it for zero dollars
and then you can get a copy of it Kim
calm apni hosts the copy of that in his
own megaupload side so if you don't have
money for that you can always use old
malware and subject them to different
standard on arming tools do quality
assurance and then you have an army of
armored malware actually because of this
it gave me I had to talk like this a
thing like a couple of years ago I
called it the green malware made from
one hundred percent recycled malware
because you just get malware and that it
it's made new again by all of these
tools now the inspiration for that talk
was that in my previous adventure one
client oddly approached me and he said
or they said we got infected by a very
sophisticated malware now most fortune
companies when they get in fact that
they always say it's a very complicated
malware but then after beating away all
of the
ducted mechanisms after weeks and months
of work I found out that that matter is
like five between five to ten years old
it's a very old malware that at least
strengthens my belief that attackers
really don't care whether the malware is
new or old as long as it has the
behavior that they need or the
capability that they need and once it
has actually their main concern is the
capability and then protecting their
creation so once they find something
that has the capability they need the
only thing they need to do is to make
sure it's protected enough so that it
could bypass different their security
products and it can make life hard for
researchers if ever there samples get
captured and subjected to different of
malware analysis and methods so speaking
of QA quality assurance so the Quality
Assurance oddly depends on the attack
type so we know to attack types one is a
targeted attack so in a targeted attack
if the malware can escape through
different security products employed by
the company or the enterprise they're
trying to attack they wouldn't mind
releasing that malware even if it's
affected by ninety-five percent of all
security products or ninety-five percent
of other security appliances if it's not
detected by the five percent and it just
so happens that five percent is the one
being used by the company they wouldn't
mind deploying it so when it comes to QA
it depends on Utley on how they would
attack it depends on the type of attack
now also when it comes to targeted
attacks mostly those that are targeted
are people that have access to sensitive
information within their company
sometimes it's based on roles probably
they would they would target the c-level
executives or a network management any
person within the company that has
access to sensitive information within
the company now if the company doesn't
have any segmented network meaning if a
receptionist computer can have access to
sensitive data then they wouldn't mind
target
the receptionist and it for them it's
much more easier because most of the
time when there's a security education
going on in the company usually the
receptionist is left out most of the
employees are attending the security
awareness and most of the people are
left out like the receptionist's so and
also for this one like a based on my
experience every time we would talk to a
company in my previous adventure we
would also talked to the family members
of these people like other immediate
family members or members living in the
same house we made them aware also of
security and also leaking out
information within their social media
circles like for one example let's say
he's a c-level executive in a fortune
100 company and he's attending last con
and he has a daughter the daughter would
say hey guys party at my place my dad is
in this weird conference I had no idea
what it is it's called last con it's
there until Monday so party at my place
now if attackers are actually monitoring
all of his family's social network that
would give them enough information that
we try to a fish ship now they could
send him email thank you for attending
last con we really appreciate your
attendance please click this link to
print out a certificate or if there's an
attachment there please click the
attachment it's a it's a sign of our
thank you and all that now if he's
tech-savvy you say oh and I know this is
this is a this is a hoax but then again
not all people are tech savvy enough to
actually not do what the email is saying
now most attackers if it's if it's
really a high-profile target and they
really want to get into the company some
of them won't send him email instead
they would send him a snail mail
probably that snail mail would have
picked out of a URL what could have a
USB stick or whatever or anything there
that would actually make him do
something to that Mallory deployment
technology and hack malware installed in
his system and of course another attack
type
opportunistic attack so every time I
take off opportunistic it reminds me of
Oprah Winfrey you know how in her show
she always says too bad they're not
Oprah or else I'll tell you guys you get
the car you get a car you get the car
and all of you will be this happy so so
she likes to give away stuff to
everybody so opportunistic attack is
like that the attackers spread the
malware and they really don't care who
gets infected at the end of the day they
just check their control panel and see
how many they get infected and if it's
an opportunistic attack when it comes to
quality assurance now they're more
concerned about their creation not being
detected by most security products and
security appliances and once they become
successful of course they're all happy
they reap the rewards of stealing all of
those information from the compromised
machines so why are they doing this
exponential effect the more you have the
more chances of you winning and also if
you don't want to use it in a campaign
you can always sell it in the
underground imagine if you have if you
can produce hundreds of thousands of
samples a day and you have buyers for
one cent about that's a lot of money and
easy malware update also to not AV out
not only AV but most security vendors
even security appliances it depends on
the on the budget that tackle group has
and the amount of security appliances
and security products they have access
to so exponential effect as I said you
can produce infinite amount of number of
malware samples and then you can mix and
match them so even if you just have one
malware from the from the malware DIY
kit or even from an old malware you can
do this but the good thing about Mallory
DIY kits especially if it's the one that
can produce infinite number of malware
samples if you just create as many as
you want just get one subjected into an
arming tool now most are bring tools
also use time
see so based on one sample could also
create infinite amount of malware
samples and then and so on and so forth
so this athlete makes things hard for
researchers and automated systems now if
you're not really familiar with the
different DIY kids and the different
tools most researchers even automated
systems would say you've just got
infected by this malware family name
this or you've got infected again oh
that's a different family it's not we
call this this and that so the naming
becomes screwed up but then if you
really take the time to peel away all of
those armoring that has been put in that
malware you'll find out that once you
reach the germ the germ is the pure
malware code unadulterated without any
protective mechanism you'll find out
that they're all the same like in one
day the samples you see like the 50,000
samples they all boil down to just one
German so in the future hopefully
instead of using the chart like that to
identify uniqueness we would definitely
get reports of malware instead of
millions and millions say this year we
saw a 15-member families doing the
rounds and then about the next year and
say we only saw ten but these ten
Mallard families are much more powerful
than the 15 that we saw last year and
actually that's what I'm are doing in
RSA first watch is a trying to come up
with a yearly report that really
represents malware uniqueness based on
family and not based on Ash all right
easy malware update so unique samples
per malware deployment technology so
what's a malleable deployment technology
so it's a technology that attackers used
to have their creation reach the target
not really executing the target but just
reaching the target so what are the most
popular manual deployment technology we
have the drive-by download we have
emails and we also have USB sticks
especially those that are given away in
Francis the one you have in your bag
soho make sure before you do anything
with it you plug it in to a ton air gap
system so let's take for example email
so let's say I have a botnet and that
and then my botnet has the capability to
spam millions and millions of samples
but then I just want to target one
company and that company has 50
employees so I would tell my botnet
create 50 spams targeting this company
now then the question is how do how do I
get their email how they get their
information and all that I have to have
a blog written about that in a in our
say-so so let's say already have their
email addresses so my botnet would
happily spam 50 email samples I mean our
50 emails that those 50 employees within
the company so let's say one IT guy who
is a security expert get that spam and
you say oh this is very obvious this is
a spam mail and then you would send it a
security provider then the security
provider and say you know what you're a
high paying customer so we'll give you a
solution in two hours but again you have
to remember that the way most security
companies defined solution it's not
really a solution it's just detection
when you say solution you have to
completely eradicate the threat from the
system but then again given that the
sophistication of malware today they're
like the aliens in falling skies once
they embed themselves into the human
host taking them out kills the human
host it's the same thing with the with
computers sometimes when you try to
clean them up here you actually mess up
the whole operating system so let's say
yeah I'll give you a solution in two
hours so he gets the solution he deploys
it to the company and then he happily
reports to the CTO hey don't worry about
that spam we got a couple of hours ago I
already have the solution have already
deployed it were protected but then the
next day the network ad said hey I
thought were protected but according to
my logs
I still see some information being
exfiltrated out of our company so that
happened that or that happens because
the 50 email samples that were produced
or that was spanked by the eat by the
botnet it aptly contains 50 unique
malware samples so the one that was
caught by the security expert or the IT
security expert that sample you won't
see it ever again you would only see it
one time and the solution that he
deployed only sold that one sample it
didn't solve the other 49 samples that
were sent out with the other employees
that's why in the industry I really
don't believe we're in people would say
hey we've analyzed this malware these
are the hashes because chances are you
wouldn't see those hashes ever again you
would only see it once so one thing that
could happen that's why they became
compromised probably one non technical
savvy user got that email was gullible
enough to follow whatever that email
said exok click the link execute the
file or whatever and that computer got
infected and from that computer the
infection spreads so that's what usually
happens so when you're when we're
actually dealing with attacks today as I
mentioned earlier we're not dealing with
a single malware alone we will now deal
with different families of unique
malware and also when it comes to
malware serving domains it can rotate
malware in minutes so what's a malware
serving the main so when it comes to a
botnet a botnet apple uses three major
network infrastructure one is the cnc
the one we always hear the one that
aptly influences how the matter behaves
in the system one is the domain drop
zone if it's an information stealing
malware all of the information it steals
it sends its out to that domain if it's
a primitive one probably just it uses an
SMTP to send that stolen information now
another
another network resource that it use is
a malware serving domain so usually the
malware serving domain contains the
configuration files malware updates
component updates whatever that the
Malheur needs to function in the system
now malware before when it attacks your
system usually it's only one file
everything is packaged into that one
file but malware today they're made out
of different components you have to do
you have the rootkit component the one
that's responsible for hiding the
malware you have the attack component
that attack component functions
depending on the directive of the
attacker if it's a if it's a DDoS attack
that attack component has the capability
to do details if it's an information
stealing attack that component is
probably a memory scraper a keylogger or
whatever and most importantly this is my
favorite I call it the Horcrux component
so if you're fans of Harry Potter so a
Horcrux component is that it checks the
infected system from time to time to see
whether there are components missing
probably an incident responder came in
he remove one component thinking
everything's good but then the Horcrux
component we say hey something's broken
so the Horcrux component would happily
rebuild it and sometimes the files that
it needs are in the malware serving
domains so that's one one purpose of the
Mallory serving domain now let's say
Adam Albert the botnet or the malware
that infected the system uses a Mallory
serving domain that have access to
millions or even just thousands of
malware samples so a company would say
hey I think we're infected basemen are
very sophisticated and expensive
security product computer a is where the
infection is so an incident responder
would come there do forensics on
computer a and the end he finds out oh
yeah I was able to get the sample so
I'll get back to you tomorrow I'll send
you the solution that you can deploy so
they deployed the solution it removed
the malware or detect
it and then they do the remediation
probably from backup or whatever but
then again the next day the same network
security ad would say hey there's still
data being excavated in our network now
that happens a lot because even if the
incident responder was able to get the
malware from that system in two hours or
in just minutes it has already been
updated by the attacker so whatever the
incident responder was able to extract
from that system that's already old news
so even if he spends days solving that
sample that sample is not in the
infected machine anymore or or it's not
going the rounds in the network anymore
now ecially mallory serving domain so it
will it will not be detected as much as
an anomaly they would probably update it
once every day once every two hours
using disguising themselves as normal
traffic so if you have access to
thousands and thousands of malware
samples it's very easy to update the
sample in a compromised machine making
the attack very persistent and also to
knock abl so Mallory creation time
versus solution cycle time so mag
recreation time as you would seem my
demo it just takes seconds that we
create one unique mallory sample but
then the solution cycle time you're
counting ours like when I was in trend
micro we were promising two hours of
detection or else we would pay you back
your money so seconds hours it's it's a
loosening and for security vendors and
AV evasion is effectively utilized
before when a sponsor if it's a state
sponsor or just a criminal underground
they want to have that technology or in
their malware when they're doing their
attack they would need to contact
directly the person who's an expert in
that technology but nowadays since we
don't have they don't have
they now use tools so sorry it messed me
up so so nowadays since the people get
arrested some of them get arrested they
would be invited to the US and then they
will get arrested the mother writers
aptly what they did is they try to have
a buffer within the attacker group and
themselves so there was now they're
saying instead of you hiring me and
knowing where to contact me how I look
like and all that how about you just buy
this tool located in this hyper form and
then send me a Western money union here
in this state and then I'll have my
money mules worry to me somewhere in in
Russia and then I'll give you a key so
that whatever functionality you need you
could have it you could unlock it in the
tool and since all of the tools are
freely available and most attack
attacker groups have money if you have
money you just get all of those tools
and then all of the aviation technology
that are available today you could use
it in your own attack campaign so that's
how easy it is nowadays and one is 21 a
signature ratio so if the researcher is
not smart enough or is not aware enough
about the tools to different tools
attackers use and the automated systems
they're using are not really smart
enough what happens is that they would
end up creating one signature for one
malgor sample so if it's like 10,000
unique mother samples they would create
10,000 unique signatures when in fact
it's only one germ and this happens all
the time actually if you would have a
blacklist database that that's more than
five Meg I would ask questions to my
security provider because I usually if
you have all of this it's in the gigs
and gigs but there was this
industry-wide project before which is
called pattern slimming so what happens
there is that are all of the in the
world malware are only in the ones that
that's being deployed to the customers
what the gigs and gigs of data base are
the one that's being given to the
testers so you you would
magazine's 100 percent certified by this
magazine one hundred percent passed this
test but then again they're using a
different set of signatures which is
gigs and gigs but in fact they're using
as a small portion because if you would
really get those gigs and gigs of data
base you would actually kill the
bandwidth of your network when you
deploy all of those solutions and
understanding the malware requires
reversing and not just analysis now if
you didn't want to understand the
malware you really need to reverse it
now analysis would reveal some
information but then I always believed
that the school house is on fire and the
bank is getting robbed so sometimes
Mallory would exhibit the most obvious
the most obvious of the most obvious
behavior but then again you really need
to reverse it that's why most of the
reports that come out they would come
out like six months eight months after
the fact because that's the amount of
time that it took them directly under
standard member like for me if I have a
reversing project if it's a very
sophisticated sophisticated malware it
takes me weeks even months toughly
reverse that manner so reversing is
easier said than done all right so we
only have two minutes so this is how you
create malware this is in real time and
this is just a slowing using a very slow
system so here we would use Zeus so
everything is pre-configured you just
need to turn it on your automated
scripts and all that and then it could
create samples for you the one on the
right you would see dis created one
sample now if you have if you have kids
you can watch your kids baseball game
basketball game come back and see
thousands and thousands of malware if if
you work for the government you have
this running in your government office
the government shuts down you got
furloughed come back after 16 days this
would still be running and you would
have thousands and thousands of malware
so that's how easy it is to create
matter samples well I was explaining
that it already created eight unique
mallory samples now when I say unique
this is not unique in hash it's unique
this is just juice so behavior
is the same across the board but then
how it looks on disk and in memory is
totally different from one generation to
another now so if you're not familiar
with the kids you would say it's a
different family all together and then
you add armoring it messes things up
like this armoring it does is it doesn't
use time and data succeed it uses random
keys but then again the number of
combinations is in billions and
trillions so it's still like having
infinite amount of malware sample this
one also has added features it has anti
sandbox technology and all that cool
stuff like I would explain how they got
the idea for the randomization but if
you guys are interested you can always
approach me because it's a 30 minute
explanation but if you guys are really
interested please feel free to send me a
message so this one it already from one
sample from that DIY kit it already
created three samples all right so let's
put it together an automated system
attackers use just get a bare metal
system you get the virtualized machine
with the Caped breathalyze machine with
the armory tools you have shared folders
all the kit although samples produced by
the Katie dropping that folder from that
folder drop it from to the armory tools
vm and from there it drops all of the
finished samples and armored samples
folder now all of these can be automated
in the bare metal machine just by using
agents that actually monitor the
different folders and then once you have
all your armored samples to sit back
enjoy the fruits of your labor labor
sell it use it to conduct an attack and
whatever you want to do with it but I'm
not saying you guys do it this is all
for educational purposes and all the
samples are destroyed after all of my
experiments just to make sure that the
camera gets that information
and T takeaways the real story behind it
usually is just a handful of kids
responsible for a for the millions and
millions and samples we see every year
and the way they do it they are able to
produce those number of samples using
automation and if you have security
providers ask the right questions so not
don't just take their word for it ask
the right questions now if they're going
to conduct demonstrations within your
company don't let them conduct demo
using their own samples you have to have
samples of your own probably samples
that you were able to collect in your
own network or samples you were able to
collect from industry contacts and then
have them try that because those samples
those samples you have there usually
represent real world scenario and a new
solution is needed so signature less
detection so I'm actually working on one
solution right now utilizing machine
learning it's a year-long project
hopefully it works so I won't get fired
and instead of analyzing the Malheur
samples themselves we need to go after
the tools and not the creation analyzed
reverse engineer the tools reverse
engineer the kids but then again it's
easier said than done attackers realize
this that's why they're tools and their
kids also have protective mechanisms it
takes a long when I say long sometimes
years to happily understand one kid now
if it's leaked out their source code
then your lab because you just need to
read in English so which is good so if
you're so inclined please feel free to
give me a standing ovation this was
taken in my previous talk they were real
audience from my previous top so again
if you have budget please buy the book
it's for my kids college fund follow me
on twitter facebook linkedin and thank
you very much for attending
you