all right there are a bunch of
intelligent talks by really smart people
on completely industry-changing ideas
and methodologies and things like that
that is not one of these talks that's
absolutely not this talk is really just
going to be a bunch of super practical
oftentimes hilariously simple and stupid
techniques that work in web app sex so
I'm just going to burn a bunch of our
defensive techniques because yeah yellow
as the kids say cool all right well I
said I run security engineering at etsy
which is a few different teams there I
spend most my background in offense and
I want to give a shout out to the full
team because they're like I may be the
one up here talking but it's the vast
majority stock of this talk was Lizzie's
guys so excited obviously they're
oftentimes amusingly simple techniques
that actually work in the real world so
everything we talked about here finds
real bugs and real homes and
specifically we're going to focus on how
do you detect when vulnerabilities get
discovered so knowing when Oh Simon all
right so how do you know when someone's
looking at your app and just found a
vole and we're going to run through that
for some different bone classes and then
we're going to talk at the very end
about how do you increase attacker costs
in a few different ways how do we make
it more expensive for somebody to go
find bones and you're out so like I said
how do I know when someone just found a
bone the joking name that we get to use
for that is unintentionally responsible
disclosure so thinking about it and
here's probably the only one of the few
parts of this talk that's kind of
methodology side and kind of bigger
picture sizes thinking from your
different vulnerability classes what
signals get created when a vulnerability
is discovered and then one of ulnar
abilities actually exploited and taking
a look at it from that side of thinking
every Volm cost is actually going to
trigger some sort of signal in your
application that's being discovered
that's being exploited and let's run
through some of those signals and come
up with some practical things for that
and your instrument it's not just a
server side that's what's kind of
interesting is you don't just instrument
the server in places where you can you
instrument the client to even when the
attack even when the client is hostile
it shockingly works a lot of times to
instrument a hostile client to maybe
give you a heads up that they just don't
you so
going to run through examples for XSS
sequel I and remote code execution and
then I'm going to jump into the at the
end of the talk about about increasing
costs and I hope that I time this talk
right so that there's probably probably
fairly quick and we'll have example or
we'll have questions and things like
that because i'm sure that statements
like these are going to cause questions
in fact you know what it's probably
going to run quick enough that shout out
questions shout out when you
think it's go okay let's take
the most common we're jumping into XS s
first let's take the most caught this is
the most common testing pattern from
from looking our data so this is the
most common nexus s testing pattern that
we see in our application it's the very
trivial one right you inject this HTML
there's no image name XO it triggers an
alert it triggers an error that triggers
an alert you pop that up and you're like
okay great I just got I just got
execution from each male side so what's
the first thing let's break this down
into how this actually works you're
inserting if this if this tag actually
execute if you win is an attacker here
it's because this image tag just
executed in your browser what happens
there well the first part that happens
is you try to load an image named x what
does that look like on the server side
there's a get 2x what does it almost
certainly look like a 404 in your
application because that X doesn't
actually exist in your application so we
went back and we pulled 30 days of
attack data out of our app and we took a
look at they were in the 30 days there
were 75 almost 7600 attempts to inject
an image tag there were only 72
different source targets for that almost
what fifty percent of them when you walk
out are three things do you think in a
major web application XYZ X or one
exists as an endpoint they don't we ran
an experiment on this and the things
that we learned out of this were that
this hilariously found people finding
XSS because what happens is when you
inject that image tag and it works your
browser does it get to / x there is no
/x in your application if you alert off
of 404 is 2 /x you just notice that
somebody found it found a texas
the majority of false positives when you
turn this on all come from one class
they all come from search engine for
always you can in the first 24 hours
white list all of your search engine
crawlers on this and then the only
things that comes in that come in are
actually real bugs it's hilarious
alerting off of a request to slash X in
your application actually works alright
let's go back and let's look at this
again what happens next after you do the
get 4 /x what happens chat apps not a
trick question straightforward there's
an error right it doesn't load so you
fire the on error event handler you do
an alert one right cool so what I just
said a minute ago of don't just
instrument the server side it's rent the
client side to what happens here and
alert one fires how often do you think
an alert one fires in a real web
application oh well actually I'll get
too bad a minute funny funny story um
but write your first approach then is ok
this never happens let's override alert
and let's tell if it phone home anytime
and ever execute to my application
because alert one should never ever
happen I want to give props words do
here facebook we had some discussions
with him turns out they they came up
with this in 2007 we came up with this
independently in 2012 one of the awesome
dudes at Facebook mine frame on twitter
if you don't follow me should did a talk
a trucks con last year that was awesome
and this was one of the slides and then
right oh well they just burned it
so we'll talk about it now too and we
went back and forth on Twitter a little
bit and then we rolled it out and so
that's what I want to talk about is is
the results these are the actual results
of overriding alert and having it phone
home whenever whenever it executes it's
a highly technical diagram as you can
see here so let's go back this failed
spectacularly because of false positives
we turned it on and it just just started
flooding instantly and the reason why is
when I said a minute ago how many times
you think your application really calls
alert one well we should have checked
that actually before we turn that on to
their an application called alert one a
decent amount of times which is
embarrassing so let's go back and this
is going to be one of them
major themes that to walk out here with
which is that the whole kind of let me
get buzz-worthy for a second but it's a
shortest way to say this data-driven
security taking a look at your data and
not just the assumptions of how you
think a tax work because often we're
totally wrong or we have we think that
they're going to work with this way
they're going to work a different way or
they do work that way but there's also
times of false positives there so
looking at your data collecting that
data then looking at that data and see
how attacks are actually happening and
what are the unique signals out of that
attack data so overriding common methods
cool but we're only interested in really
what are the what are the payloads to
those that's where it starts get to
unique so we pulled 30 days of attack
data again and we looked at there were
8500 XSS attempts in that with alert
prompter confirm those are the those are
the big three that's 99.999% of your
exes s attempts are going to use one of
those three they were these numbers are
a little bit misleading quite honestly
because the huge spike in prompt on that
is not what you actually see in a real
web app the majority is still alert it's
followed by prompt and confirm it
happened to be during that those 30 days
there was this one just astronomically
large scan that happen to use prompt so
it's Q the data there and then sometimes
you actually see them with both or with
multiple ones you'll see like a long
string that that in one area attempts to
do in alberton the other attempts to do
a prompt I have no idea why but you see
it so let's look at the data from there
what are the payloads were interested in
again you watch this just you watch the
top ones happen and then you watch it
fall off a cliff of just long tails and
ones that you could never hope to
instrument far and away xss
document.cookie and then integers this
is integers or because of scanners so
when you do a scanner and you're you
know it's a headless thing that's
crawling all over a web app you need to
if you trigger execution for XSS you
need a way to map that back to what form
field that was or what input that was so
you do a unique identifier for each one
and then you keep it you keep in a you
know a dictionary of that and then you
see the results come back and you say
okay 1153 just fired that was this input
let me throw that into my results and
you would just watching criminal
go by and you're like okay cool it's a
scanner one wouldn't like weird lesson
we learned out a document cookie is you
can't just look for that string any of
the any of the document objects in
JavaScript by the time you can go and do
like a string match on this it won't be
document.cookie you'll be the contents
of and so what you actually have to
match on for document.cookie and
document domain and things like that are
the contents of so any if you want to
match on document.cookie find one of the
unique cookies in your environment and
match on that string because that's the
only thing that you actually can match
on same with domain match on your
domains not not on the literal string we
couldn't figure out why that wasn't
firing for the first day or so when we
were testing and then we the magic and
printf debugging you learn so we ran an
experiment off of off of these three
hilariously finds real bugs we thought
that this would find a real bug once and
then there would immediately be a blog
post on us doing this there hasn't been
which is awesome no one take that as a
challenge or a thing to tweet just being
open it needs adjustments in the first
few days you'll have areas of your app
that or maybe like you think or debug
code or something like that but turns
out it gets hit by one percent of your
user base and that at scale that becomes
a ton of data you're whitelisted real
fast though like this in our case it was
spend about the first 24 hours on it
whitelist a few things and you're good
so what else does a good job of
detecting access and we're gonna stay on
the client side for a bit I want to give
them a shout out google chrome's XSS
auditor thing sounded like a laughable
idea when when first heard it it's
totally awesome like props to them it's
good stuff it is so chrome XSS auditor I
could probably spend too long on this
and I'm probably gonna get this wrong
anyway the TLDR is that there's some
code built into google chrome that
essentially it it's scoped for a very
narrow set of attacks but it does a
pretty good job of them which are
reflected XSS attacks that happen in
HTML so either inside HTML or the
creation of new HTML elements they don't
try to solve javascript because
actually very hard and so they focus it
for this and they did really good job of
it so you you essentially and this is
the part I may have wrong but
conceptually it's close enough you
record the parameters that are sent in a
request that compass ostensibly come
from the user and then you compare about
what shows up in the DOM and if there's
something that comes from the user
request that then creates like an HTML
element like that ah you strip them out
and so this is this is like your classic
you know search engine thing of like Q
equals script alert one when that comes
back into the DOM and triggers as HTML
and execute they strip it out that's why
when you're when you're doing like pen
testing with chrome you go in and you
disable this feature as the browser's
are doing more and more of this and I
think Firefox is starting to do this too
I know no script does something similar
like that it's awesome they really
deserve a shout out on that the problem
here is that ultimately you're running a
losing game well you're winning the game
that you're trying to that you're trying
to play but ultimately they can't chrome
can't fix xss in your application and
the user can like you can you can defend
the user against a lot of like basic
things and that's awesome and we should
be doing that but how can we as
application owners and defenders use
this same principle and get some like
cool value out of it so you can use the
same you can use the same thing how can
we do it on the server side what you do
is you scan you scan input you know gets
in your posts and things like that for
HTML escapes and for tag creation if it
exists you set a flag and you say okay
this input was potentially hostile here
trying to escape it's trying to create
cool set that flag to true and then
build up an array of what all of those
look like so there was a double quote
closed bracket script alert open bracket
script alert one there was a quote on
error equals alert one whatever it was
build that up into an array at output
time right is your as your outputs
flying out the door check that flag if
it was true then iterate through the
page that's going out and see if any of
the hostile input that was in that array
is actually as valid HTML in the page if
it's live inside of a tag if it's it's
own tag whatever
and if it is you fail open here actually
there may come a point where too early
and are testing on this to say for
certain what what comes of this there
may come a point where you start to do
the Google approach and just strip it
out and get like get very proactive
there I'd be shocked if we end up doing
that just because the cost of failure is
kind of high they're kind of breaking
your app but you can sure alert like you
go from here and if that's valid HTML
it's going out the door thats in one of
those requests you just found reflected
XSS in your app and then the important
part here is maybe you go maybe you do
the risk trade-off of maybe I'll break
my app but I'll stop some reflected XSS
if your time to patch is very high but
if you're doing with an app that's got
it on a six-month release cycle or
something in the same way that you then
use laughs and those sort of things
there if your time to release is very
quick right if pushing the production
takes 20 minutes then cool detection
works works great they're right by the
time you discover this XSS and by the
time you actually attack your target
it's almost certainly going to be more
than 20 minutes you got to go build up
the payload that you really want like
you just found XSS with with script
alert one you need to go build up the
table that you want you need to get your
target to click on that if that's like a
targeted attack or you need to build up
some sort of worm if you're trying to
just go for mass propagation and yeah if
you can patch quick enough then you just
patch you kill it all right let's talk
about bottom tables so favorite friends
let's go to sequel injection so let's
talk about anomalies along the actual
attack chain of sequel injection there's
kind of this I don't think it's a
misunderstanding I think it's that we
just kind of gloss over the fact of from
when you discover sequel injection
vulnerabilities to when you actually the
time from tick or one equals one to
paste bin is actually a timeline right
it's not instant it's not i just found
is a verbose equal error message and now
i've got the full table there's an
attack chain there and we can instrument
that attack chain there so it starts out
with this this isn't the attack this is
the discovery this is sequel syntax
error showing up I've talked about a few
of the things in the section in some
previous talks but I think they're both
a really important and be
really effective and so I'm going to go
back over a few of these because this is
one of the best things you can do that
you can almost certainly turn on today
alerting on sequel syntax errors showing
up in your application it's almost
certainly already in your area log it's
incredibly high value even if it isn't a
right this is near that that's that's
some generic bug that well knowing
knowing what I know about our stack this
isn't exploitable but it's still above
right and you'll start to see that in
your stack very quickly okay here's a
here's a bug that's not exploitable
let's fix it here's one that oh wow yeah
okay that one is exploitable let's go
fix out immediately and the important
point is there they're all bugs some of
them have serious security implications
some don't they're all bugs moving down
the attack chain this is looking from
the attack side is you need to figure
out what that database is what hair are
the tables that contain the information
that you want what are you actually
going after you need to map out all the
table names and things like that from
the defense side what does that signal
look like almost certainly your
application doesn't request sensitive
table names as part of a get parameter
when your user sessions table shows up
as a get parameter to your search query
uh you probably want to know about that
one probably a little unique and the
important point there is actually the
fact that that's unique and not even
necessarily an attack and that's what's
cool about thinking about this from
anomalous signals and looking for
anomalies is that if they are anomalies
false positive cost is extremely low the
cost of looking at an email that says
sensitive table names just showed up and
you're in a request here is almost
nothing if it happens once a week
because you look at me like oh yeah
that's false positive obviously or
what's that I need to go check that out
when the cost is so low it's it's crazy
to not do it finally kind of near the
end of the attack chain and I'm kind of
kind of jumping over a few things here
but at the end of it a response
containing your database is orders of
magnitude larger than a normal response
right a search for kittens and select
star from user table uh wildly different
response sizes when anomalously large
responses start going out the door
that's another incredibly interesting
alert in
modern applications where that starts to
the little devil in the details and the
trick on this one is that lots of our
applications do have endpoints that are
that result in huge response sizes you
either whitelist those out because
you've code reviewed them enough that
you're like alright that's cool it's job
is to return this one file or this one
thing it's going to be a large spots
responses but I'm cool with it I think
it's good and so that's how you actually
that's what you deal with in the first
week or so of this as that functionality
gets found whitelist those you go from
there the point of all this is not to
just alert in one spot all these are
interesting by themselves but they're
incredibly valuable in a chain the more
that you do the more context you have
when you start to look at it and we're
clarity you have because like I said
false positives happen and they happen
all the time in production
infrastructure so like let's look at
this from the alerts I was talking about
here you have you have a sequel syntax
errors alert in place that's
deliberately great it doesn't go off you
have a database table names alert in
place it suddenly goes off I know large
response size has ever go out the door
obviously I'm over simplifying here a
bit but this is false positive right but
the fact that you have these three
alerts or n alerts means that when you
get when you feel that you've
instrumented the attack chain fairly
well and one in the middle goes off then
you know like okay well this odds are
this is a false positive I'm so
obviously going to treat this as real
and go analyze it go take a look at it
but the fact that sequel syntax are like
thinking from the other side if sequel
syntax errors goes off and then data
database table names start appearing
like a couple hours later and then a few
minutes later large response sizes start
appearing and then around the
organization this face starts appearing
you know that something is actually
going on right and every alert that you
have along this chain increases your
confidence that you know that
something's going on all right no code
execution like said shout out with
questions I'm flying through so does
anyone remember this reddit post from
like a month or so ago it was like
everyone just started rolling with it
was amazing if somebody asking like hey
it's just good to create users for my
web application it would just pipe input
directly into the shell and so the
reddit com
we're just it's just an entire thread of
this it was spectacular I like I like
the one about the permission to is like
something like it's going to create a
user account first so I just like to
ID'd everything or yeah Souter is yeah
it's awesome yeah yeah it's called Yolo
dot PHP okay let me let me go from
making fun of someone else to making fun
of myself which is learn from our pain
on this one so if i can give you one
statement here it's even the code that
you want to be permanent in production
is nowhere near as permanent as your
temporary debug code that you forgot
about one of the worst volens we ever
had was some temporary debug code that
was in production and we went and we
looked at it and it essentially allowed
this is again where it gets embarrassing
it essentially just took just like the
previous one it took a youth elite took
like a URL parameter and just piped it
to system like it just straight-up
executed and it was behind a bunch of
things that you had to you had to have
some special access to get there and
stuff like that but it was it had like a
specific ticket number in the code like
oh this is to do with this deployment
because this is the only way we can test
this one thing that it's out on this
certain web server and like it's totally
with the best of intentions it wasn't
just like somebody pushed something like
that to production not thinking about it
they knew it was dangerous it referenced
like a whole ticket around that it was
like remove this in a week the date
stamp on that was a year and a half two
years so ago it's one of those what's
great about this is it had the easiest
patch you ever get to do which is just
get RM right and it's just gone but it
got us thinking about this like holy
crap that's scary right this is one of
the worst phones we've ever had and it
was one of the simplest and it was just
absurd how do we how we go about
automating this to try to find this like
this should have what are the alerts
that should have woken us up in the
middle of the night if something like
this ever existed again and it turns out
you I'd say everyone in this room
already has the tools to find exactly
that sort of vulnerability pattern and
it's your access log um I'm jumping
ahead a few slides but looking at where
your traffic goes and alerting where it
doesn't so what you do is you map so you
you take your your htdocs or your your
production reading right you
level with the files in that and then
you take a look at your access log and
you map requests to end points and end
points that don't get requests or
anomalous if you have a if you have a
production website that has an end point
that has had less then I'll make up a
number a thousand requests in a month
that's dead code like that is completely
dead code go look at the access log
that's going to be entirely search
crawlers and things like that hopefully
not search crawlers because then
somebody can find you but probably
search crawlers dead code kill it don't
kill it automatically alert off it but
the the awesome thing about this and
alerting off of it um yeah like sit
still reachable and everything the
awesome thing here is you pay a one-time
ah you pay a one-time hit to go review
all this so your fur you build this you
build an alerting mechanism that says
anything in the last month less than a
thousand hits alert that first month you
get a whole array of like files to go
check out that's your that's your code
reviews from the next couple days it's
really nice because you can look at Indy
like no dead code gone clearly debug
file gone it's like very quick code
reviews but then the incremental change
off of that is almost nothing right your
one-time heat is bad you spend a couple
days for your app sec team and then next
month you have one file or two files
like it just drops off a cliff alright
let's make it rain for attackers alright
cheapest way to find web app phones one
word what Sandra hmm Google yeah that's
right ok there's apparently a lot of one
words that are good answer right I was
stalling because I needed to take a
drink automation so yeah kind of Google
if we want to think about this from a
way of economic costs for attackers the
more they can automate the cheaper that
it is just like for the rest of us think
about it from the economic side so how
do you kill the spot in their tooling
like in their tool chains so that
automation goes away in as many places
as you can kill it how do we force
attackers to be manual now some of the
dirty secret of what I'm going to say
here is that well your best attackers
are actually doing things manually
anyway that's fine what you're trying to
do is raise the cost of attacking your
application because a lot of your
attackers are going to be financially
motive
and the more costs if I have to go
develop custom tooling to attack that
person and I can do everything off the
shelf and attack that person and I'm
financially motivated I'm going after
that guy require manual effort so let's
talk about breaking off the shelf
scanners for for a large-scale web
application is going to sound tribute at
first it gets there's a little bit
clever bit near the end which is that so
every off-the-shelf scanner all of them
give off incredibly strong detection
skills there isn't I don't think a
single one on the planet whose job is to
evade detection because they have to get
that breath in that coverage and it you
know it's things as basic as user agents
like we're all familiar with although
what's hilarious is the number of people
who don't change user agents on their
scanners and you're just like oh hi
sequel map it's been second since I've
seen you how's it going to attack
patterns I forget which tool this is I
meant to look this up someone in this
room probably knows there's one of the
security scanners it tries its brute
force protection or its brute force
detection by logging into Smith account
just watch these things all day every
day it's like somebody really loves the
Smith account totally thought about
steady finding that tool seeing what the
first password it rises and just setting
that password for a generic Smith
account that means nothing just a troll
it but yeah cameras on right yeah and
then things which just flat out don't
exist right you're a Java shop or you're
a PHP shop request the ASP those aren't
legit period end of story request for
any sort of technology stack which you
don't use they're not legit so these are
some of the incredibly strong signals
there are weaker signals and there are
different signals too but thinking in
terms of categories these are these are
kind of where it's at that's that's the
trivial bit right detecting scan it
detecting a user agent not hard and your
first intention there is like okay well
cool I detected I block that breaks
things that breaks things really quickly
it's one of those it seems easy on the
surface shared corporate firewalls
mobile gateways eat like you're going to
legitimately break way more stuff than
you
if you just go do that so what we what
we stepped back and realized is we don't
want to block IPS IPS are not a strong
correlation to identity anymore they
might not have ever been what we want to
break our scanners and only that how do
we focus on that so what we did is we
went back and we said okay for every
request entering the stack which sounds
like a performance nightmare and
actually shockingly is not classify a
request when it comes in is at the
scanner not bouillon yes now if it is a
sign of weight to that based on
confidence so some of these things I
don't I don't map this back incredibly
well but a request with sequel map as a
user agent that's a scanner period end
of story um your ones that are like reg
exes for cross-site scripting patterns
and things like that you assign less
confidence for it but what you do is you
then request when the press comes in you
say scanner yes or no if yes feed that
into a rate limiter you never thought a
talk on rate limiting could be
interesting until you went and read mr.
Nick jeez talk on rate limiting it's
actually awesome and it's something that
you should be using so extensively in
your application like everywhere it's
one of them it's like graphene right it
may not be somebody somebody may not be
watching that graph but you want that
graph there for when you need it rate
limit needs the same way it costs once
you develop like a good rate limiting
library in your framework it costs
almost nothing to deploy it everywhere
in application it's awesome absolutely
do it nick has a good talk on it so feed
a request this this request is a bad
frequent bad request right a scan a
request feed it into a rate wonder if
the rate limiter is above a certain
threshold so we've done we've seen a
number of bad request number of scanner
requests from this IP cool drop it it's
done right above the search request you
just lost that IP for your scanner and
this is how you start to this is this is
a bit that didn't go into in the slides
but this is this is how you increase
costs on it is you start to make them if
you feel that you have a pretty good
handle on mass registration and things
like that you're in your systems you
want a expensive resource for attackers
is IPS not necessarily at like one or
two ip's but if you suddenly
can get I'm throwing arbitrary numbers
here but if you can suddenly do 20
requests out of Nick doe or some
off-the-shelf scanner and then you have
to cycle an IP and that tool is going to
generate like by default you know a
million requests good luck you're done
right you're not going to generate
enough you're not going to go through
enough eye peas and develop the custom
tooling to have to do that to just scan
a site like forget it i'm not going to
scan it i'll go like just poke around
and type script alert one not that so if
it's about that threshold drop oh my god
i forgot to put in the most awesome part
so when we drop them we actually uh so
from etsy etsy saul handmade and vintage
and everything like that right when you
trigger the threshold we now return HTTP
439 request not handmade for scanners
it's awesome that was there there were
high fives around the office when
somebody thought of that one so it's
cool you don't walk the entire IP you
block scanners ah via that now the
design goal of all of this was this
don't worry about the text on there it's
not important the the design goal was
that if you are scanning in your
terminal window and browsing etsy in a
browser your browser should not be
impacted in any way you should still be
able to use the Site legitimately and
just illegitimate use drops off and the
funny thing is what we've seen from some
of these scanners is that they don't
even really realize that they suddenly
just hit a wall of you know HP whatever
response code so they just keep scanning
what's fine because you've completely
killed that data set lessons learned
from it set your initial threshold tie
the cost of you don't care if or if a
scanner gets 50 requests or 20 or 100 or
something like that what you're killing
is the aggregate you're killing the two
million requests your automated scanners
are going to go nuts on this anyway like
they're going to trigger enough to
trigger your thresholds start high work
your way down if you feel comfortable on
that definitely wait based on confidence
some things are high confidence some
things are not just by the nature of
them that's fine just build that into
your system and be ready i'm going to go
into it an interesting failure we had
right now because this be ready for the
weirdness that is the internet let me
just give you an example so how else
could we increase costs hey if someone's
doing something
add why are they even there in the first
place how can we just auto ban accounts
that are that are doing scanning and so
we did that as a hypothesis we thought
okay some attackers are going to do an
authenticated scanning some are going to
do authenticate it because in any
application you can get way more way
more exercise of the application by
authenticated scans so we went back and
we looked at the numbers and that the
thought was here that if we can force
attackers to constantly create new
accounts in addition to having to
Cyclopes that's a real cost and
especially if on the defensive side you
feel like you've gotten pretty good
tooling around detecting mass
registration and things like that so hey
if we're going to be able to work force
them to have to create thousands of new
accounts and we feel that we're all
right at detecting that and we can close
them pretty quickly cool that's another
source of cost so actually was
house-sitting in annex keynote this
morning I pulled our last seven days of
data which you may extrapolate from that
that I was finishing these slides few
hours ago but don't focus on that from
our last seven days of data as of this
morning 437 scanners how many of them
were authenticated anybody want to take
a guess good okay were you seeing next
me where was I it's ten awesome you yeah
exam ate a minute suspiciously Anna why
did they all say it home okay um I want
to guess what are false positive rate on
this was or are we would not have wanted
to ban them right yeah hmm yeah how many
james wicket one through ten accounts
did we know it was fifty percent it's
crazy um these were legitimate users
this blew our minds like we expected
this number right you expect it to be
low even lower than you think of like
people are going to create an account
type into session cookies and fly
through their scanner and things like
that cuz sessions timeout it's a pain
like white hot guys know that you have
to deal with that commercially it sucked
it's a pain this we were not prepared to
deal with this is AA like browser
plug-ins is honestly our best guess best
guess we're pretty sure on that but you
can go back and fifty percent of those
you
sirs were clearly legitimate they were
users who had been there for years who
have made purchases like they were as
legitimate as users could be they
weren't doing anything bad on the site
in any other place it was clear that
their browser was owned and so if you're
going to auto ban accounts it turns out
nope that face bomb right that would
totally fail you would start banning
legitimate users all over the place and
the point of all of this and my closing
thought this is as close to a conclusion
as it gets is that attacks don't always
happen like like you expect going back
and looking at the data and hopefully
looking at the data before you make
those decisions if we have just decided
to start auto banding because it on the
surface it seems legit we would have
started just breaking users left and
right and the more instrumentation that
you have gives you the context and the
confidence to actually make those
decisions and you're awesome go for no
idea yeah it was nuts it's like they do
they do requests that would trigger this
mean fall backwards I'll even show you
some examples they do request that that
definitely trigger this that look that
are clearly not initiated by the user
almost certainly coming from their
browser we can't actually tell that
because it may just be coming from
network like living on the host hitting
us directly that doesn't really make any
sense like it should be in the browser
they weren't but I don't have numbers
for you this is actually something we
were packing on the last few days so the
pattern we saw a lot of different
patterns so I don't think that it was
all the same thing because you see some
that are like clearly one thing one this
one thing like requests xml r / xmlrpc
all the time clearly widget users
clearly legit browsers does thousands of
requests to slash xmlrpc yeah no idea
what that is yeah Magna dem two
questions
for the last part it wouldn't is it so
enough positive to do that maybe you a
temporary bandage maybe we're hours
using like that and I'll work the user
that you will they might be compromised
wouldn't this will be a kind of ends on
your site yeah ah you're a discussion
forum maybe are you an e-commerce site
and my second one is where are you doing
the instrumentation on the rate limiting
the detection of scanners and the the
check looking at the input for for bed
bed scanner bad news yeah yeah um the
question was like where are we where are
we doing this we're doing it in our
framework it's one of the first things
that when a request comes into our staff
that a run-through so it's right a pop
it's really before you even hit a
general application cover though we did
you check the inputs and comparative
what comes out okay where do you do that
ah the check at the end goes out in your
templating so it's watching there and
the check and be getting is in the
framework more presents yet as kenny's
thing on content security yeah also this
when you talk quite a bit about XSS
probably too much now what what are you
guys seeing as exploitation I mean
you're talking about detection but
clearly somebody's trying to get exploit
running on you guys so what do you see
yeah so we have one of the nice way to
generate all this data is run a bug
memory program uh-huh and the internet
shows up it's great if you really hate
sleeping i recommend it highly so that
definitely generates a lot of things
that we see the bug bounty program we've
seen knock on wood we've seen almost
entirely white hat behavior but you
don't know that and the ones that like
the ones that are some of the most
vexing things that i'd love to figure
out but never will our we've watched
people find bones on the site and then
never right like we know that they found
him and then they never right into down
he or anything like that um that I don't
know like we fix them quick and like we
burned their they're vulnerable to that
even later on it's like you definitely
found
xss there you didn't write in what's
going on there um that's that's an
interesting one so I know they're not
what if these folks that are working on
like bots that they can run through
exercise balls and I'm just wondering if
you're seeing that behavior ah like
automated detection or like thoughts
dead Russ I running BOTS to do anything
so they're just using your cross site
scripting problem as a way to either
feed a bot rana bah oh ok yeah ok yeah
distribute malware sure sure sure sure
um yeah that's good thought could
Bennett it's weird because you'll never
know on that one right like someone
found a bone they never told you about
it yoga more that we had there that were
nice with in the beginning that's one
dude Damon he's awesome found this this
accessible I'm like a Friday he wrote it
up on credit netsec like a year year and
a half ago it was really cool because
Nick day after day and I were hanging
out and watch this guy fine to find an
XSS and it was cool you and then he like
they spend time building up like a
really good payload to show like a
really good proof of concept this was
before we had the bounty program um
build up a really cool proof-of-concept
show like oh here's me you click this
link it'll flip your privacy settings so
everything becomes public and extract
like an email address and like is good
he spent a lot of time on and everything
like that we watched and fine and we
push to fix before you had a chance to
report it to us which was fun in like a
really exciting point in my early upset
career and then he wrote in on like the
Monday any more days like this my proof
of concept stopped working over the
weekend that seems a little bit
suspicious timing I want to let you guys
know I was not black adding here like
just so we're gonna cool about this
that's my home IP like everything's
legit and here's the details of the bug
report that had ready to go for you guys
on Monday morning it was cool we have
like a really good dynamic with them and
actually
things I'm most proud of in our security
program was that when we launched our
bounty program we went back and
retroactively Li Dao need him in a few
of the other guys you into it found cool
stuff before we have the program cool
more oh just drop or do you
throwing the random sleep one in there
that's okay I could experimental eat oh
yeah this is not an offer to anyone
we're going to find that yeah that's the
part I may be intentionally or
unintentionally not included is cool
this is this is all about increasing
costs right the next one of the mex
illogical steps you can come to
increasing costs is injecting false
results in two data sets and with that I
will shut the hell up oh when we're
testing for XSS yeah um so the way that
we approach this neither previous talk
on that it talks about how you go about
trying to do that at the framework level
and a lot of people doing really
interesting work there like far as I'm
from us um but an hour in our platform
bit mostly XSS is mostly killed by
default in the framework level and then
you can grep for exceptions to that
which is what's fantastic right so if
everything's escaped by default you grep
for what's on escape or what what has
made that output beyond escape and
that's how you that's how we look for
excess yes Abby is prepping the coq back
so you're using the oh it for that one
that we're doing for the reflected
exodus yeah we're using users we're
using the user traffic because you look
at the hospital input come in and you
look and see if it went out on escape
and then you know that something
happened there we miss
the code it came out an escape and
actually fired its HP now okay cool
keeping up more yeah I think I got a
couple minutes on Kiawah to make energy
decline one you have that doesn't or
maybe that's afterwards like that I mean
that alert is completely automated like
all of that all that happens on every
request and then if it then logs result
if it like oh just fat like reflected
exercise and that triggers an alert and
that bubbles up okay yeah you guys run
your own automated scanners for all
these types of attacks and so are you
white listing them or you say we need in
the tanner we have all of someplace yeah
yeah the Internet is a really good
automated scanner turns out it's
sometimes you just don't get the
vulnerability reports we don't we've
experimented with them in the past we've
done in the past honestly that to set up
the infrastructure forward to be able to
really have it be fully automated and
not something that somebody has to tend
to manually at all they do we didn't
spend the time on it it was a we felt
like it was a bit of a time sink and we
focused on some other efforts there not
to say that we won't go back to do it
and explicitly not say that it doesn't
have value in other environments because
I've seen a value in ours it wasn't the
right place it wasn't very time and we
feel that we're getting good coverage
and value in other spots or yeah have
you guys thought of your tried using a
web to kind of find some of the same
stuff that you're finding sure the
question was to have you thought of
using a web we've taken the concepts of
a whack that we like and built them into
our application that's part um and where
I where I actually see I used to I mean
I used to be an often so when you like
that probably would have set me off
before right oh why anyone all offense
just has a generally a different opinion
about laughs the one thing that I think
that they can conceptually do well is in
environments where you can't patch
quickly and it's a very kind of clean
bug in that light this is a zip code
field
has sequel injection well it's pretty
easy to then apply the regex it says you
get five digits or you get nine digits
and that's it you only get digits I
think laughs have value they're like hey
I can't patch like this app has a six
month release cycle so even though the
patch is clean it's going to go out in
December and that's where a fkin can do
well um the the other sides of it we
solve that capability by being able to
deploy quick so be if you don't know
like the SHPO we deploy to production
about 30 times a day and so we can
respond pretty quickly on on those where
we want to and then for detection and
instrumentation things like that we've
really kind of we focused on building
that in yeah this field was accepting
cross they have you found any
large-scale designer architecture stuff
and so maybe we need to put this behind
login screen it's as if led to any sort
of learner assessment yeah certainly
areas that trigger bones that you don't
expect your stack to have trigger much
larger security assessments on that's
one of the that's one of the big
takeaways of a bug bounty program is
that before you launch or not to view
this too too hard but before you want to
bug bounty program come up with a list
come up with a list of vulnerability
classes that you expect to have and kind
of a weighting of that I expect a
million dawn XSS I expect to sequel
injection and then match reality to that
a month out holy crap I'd 50 sequel
injection I have that systemically I
need to go do something more about that
we've absolutely had it both on a
vulnerability class level and on an area
of the code base level of like i would
give you like a brutal example that is
like a voman report will come in it will
look very real and you look at it and go
not that like oh that bug is worthless
or something like that but what is that
endpoint like what is that function
everyone looks around the table is like
I've never even heard of that and that
goes in trigger is very very quick
internal pen test
things like that like what is that area
of the code base is that in like a
completely different repo but publicly
accessible definitely it like you should
absolutely be using your vulnerability
information not just at like tactically
a spot fixes but driving both what do I
have systemically and what do I don't
what do I not so that I can address that
a framework level and where what are the
dangerous areas in my code base in
general like in aggregate like that area
over there's dangerous has a lot of
wounds this area's new clean code that
doesn't what should I be doing over
there all right I'm probably totally out
of time I'll stand i'll stand outside
the room guys have questions thank you