all right great the title is talk is
view this abstract in your browser but
before we get into that will do a quick
warm-up so who likes cross-eyed trip
down this guy does that Samy Kamkar and
so who's seen this website this website
is used you can sign up create an
account and you can actually see the
entire last con schedule on there and
you can create your own custom schedule
by clicking and choosing the talks that
you want to see so it did a kind of a
little trick last year when I spoke here
I found cross-site scripting in the
pages that you're able to create your
profile and your talk description so i
actually put a little cross that
scripting code in it so that if you came
across my talk or my profile it would
automatically add my talk to your
schedule so i have a little bit of fun
there and i wanted to see if I could do
that again and so last year I used this
the injection with a little pipe acid
there was a strange thing where if you
had a slash in before the event handler
that it would not pay attention to the
rest of the word you would be able to
bypass it and you also see that there's
equal space because I didn't put the
words right after the equal sign
whatever rules they were using it was
bypassing them so when I tested it this
year they actually fixed the slash
bypass and block the onmouseover
keywords and a bunch of others but
fortunately there's a lot of event
handlers that you're able to use what
you're going to cross-site scripting
right I mean there's enormous amounts
and they're adding new ones the
specifications all the time so this year
I just put all of them in a little test
and boom still path across that
scripting on the same site this time you
can use the on mouse out function so
yeah cross-site scripting right on that
side black let's do not work so try them
when you're securing a website alright
so those one so the title this talk is
view this abstract in your browser my
name is Phil Provence
a little bit about myself howdy I just
moved to Houston I'm originally from
California lived in my whole life so
it's great being here and I've spoken
out several other events I've spoken at
black hat to work on DEFCON 5 and I
spoke last year like I said earlier at
last con ab psych USA my title was
application security researcher and
consultant a knapsack consulting inc and
i consider myself a book bounty hunter
and i also spent almost a year during
bug bounty with you for one of the large
bug bounty programs that's out there a
little bit about my company since they
did approve my time to be here obstet
consulting we do PCI compliance and
validation penetration testing web and
mobile apps that's where I spend my time
source code analysis Network pen tests
and we do secure web application
development courses so check out the
website upset consulting com alright so
the themes this talk we're going to be
talking about authorization
vulnerabilities PII that's personally
identifiable information such as your
name address email credit card and
telephone numbers you know things like
things that you consider yours and you
don't want anybody to have them unless
you explicitly gave it to them and we're
going to be talking about Google doors
club if you know what if you're a dork
is a couple of you google the works
right now that is not a Google to work
although you might consider it to be
Google dorking okay this is really what
that is is it's using highly specific
Google search queries to find
vulnerabilities it's used by black hats
to quickly find websites to hack rather
than searching the entire internet doing
a network scan for port 80 and seeing
what websites are out there and then
seeing if they're running the older
version of the patchy or something like
that they'll simply use a Google query
and search for keywords
that web server might have on that
website it's also a popular way to
automate botnet exploitation so a little
bit of a side right there if you don't
know this already a lot of botnets what
they'll end up doing is having the bots
do use google dorks to search for
vulnerable websites they might be
looking for like a wordpress site or
something like that and when they find
them they'll actually attempt exploits
against those servers so that's one of
the ways that but Annette's ex fine
servers to exploit and then grow so a
little bit more about google Dorking and
your if you don't know what that is
you'll get it as we go go along it's
you're using very specific filters in
your Google search query rather than
just looking for the contents of a
couple of words on the page you can use
all sorts of other filters for example
you can search by file type let's say
you only want to bring back dot PHP
files or dot s PX files because you're
you're looking for a server to exploit
something that's for those frameworks
there's also the filter in title so you
might do a in title search for admin
portal and the title is going to be what
you see at the top of your window when
you're browsing the web site evil cams
another interesting one if you use that
you can actually find a lot of web cams
that are publicly available on the
internet that have been unsecured by
using an entitled search for evo camp in
url so if you do a search for that it's
instead of actually checking this text
of the website it's going to be testing
the URL of the website and looking for
that information so the examples PHP my
admin or download under Scott underscore
hub PHP and and you're basically looking
for those words in the euro and site
this allows you to filter specific
domains so let's say we're looking for a
news article but wanted to limit it to
the new york time so you could do site
in New York Times calm and then you'd
only be searching that website you could
do the same thing but let's say you're
only looking for vulnerabilities
on bank calm you know for example and
cash that's not really a Google dork but
very useful what cash is if you put that
into the beginning of your string and
then a URL after that instead of that's
useful for when the page is actually
gone down so web servers taking the page
offline but Google caches every page
that it sees or merely have a page that
it sees so that will actually return the
google cache of that page so you'll
still be able to see the content even if
the owner of the website has taken that
information down and then it's good to
know that you can do negatives so you
can do- file type if you want to exclude
PDF files and we want to filter your
search just a little bit more so how
could this be used here's a really cool
googled orchids just just a simple one
user underscore password and then in URL
PHP my admin so PHP might admit that's a
PHP build application for managing my
sequel databases and it's a pretty
powerful framework because if you're if
you're able to control my sequel
database you're actually able to
compromise the entire machine based on
the privileges that my sequel has in
most cases so you can see here that this
simple or a returned 21,000 results and
if you're wondering what happens when
you click on one of those pages it
actually takes you right into a PHP my
admin console from there you can run
sequel queries against the database draw
tables to whatever malicious things you
want and you can find thousands of these
sites just by searching Google and if I
were to guess I'd say most of the ones
that you're able to find on that search
query have already been compromised
they've all had been hacked a dozen
times maybe and but they're still
sitting on the net because nobody's
realized it and taking it down
alright so back to the back to the topic
at hand email because that's what that's
what we're going to get into so using
emails actually receive and just a
little bit of imagination I'll show you
how to discover personally identifiable
information without even breaking a
sweat we're going to be combining emails
that have actually received and I'll
show you those emails combining them
with google dorks to find information
that companies reputable companies have
left online for anybody in the world to
find all right so i'll go right into
horrible examples here all right so
hotel website calm confirmation numbers
and receipts so think about what kind of
information you give away when you sign
up for a hotel when you go to a website
and you reserve a room they may ask you
you know what are the names the people
staying with you you need to give them
what nights are going to be there your
credit card information it might ask for
your mailing address so they can send
you information in the future they
obviously will have your email well i
signed up for a hotel a while back and i
received this email this isn't natural
you know blocked a few things out and
we'll see you'll see right there that at
the top of the page it says click here
to view this email online and that's
you'll see a little bit more of that
that's kind of where that the title of
the presentation came from you also see
a link view and print receipt and it's
like where did these things go and now
surprise that when i click these things
I wasn't prompted to type in my username
and password instead it immediately took
you to a page with all my information it
said okay well here's your receipt you
can print it out if you want and so
they're gonna be thinking like why is
there all this information available
without me having to type in I using
password and what if I was able to find
this out for other people so i looked at
the urls of the links on this email and
you can see on the first one and the
last one they're actually pretty similar
and I abbreviated the there's a random
token that's put in there and that
specifies my user account but we see
HTTP colon slash slash click male doc
hotels.com / ? us equals so I tried
putting this into google site hotels com
in URL q s in the word confirmation and
we got a fair number of results so given
this these are not this is not going to
be my information here this is going to
be information that's publicly available
online that's being hosted by these
companies first link i clicked on i get
this this isn't in chrome it says dear
valued customer your reservation is now
confirmed and it's been paid in full the
confirmation number is this thank you
for looking at our website I scroll down
the page a little bit now surprised of
what I saw here's the entire rest of
that person's receipt at the top we see
the name of the person who's going to be
the guest it says two adults preference
king-size bed number of night seven
nights two adults goes on to list how
much it is each night it goes on at the
bottom to say the billing name which is
surprising what not surprisingly but
different from the guests name and the
card type card number and billing
address and below that there's actually
the phone number what do you guys think
about that
and the thing about this is there's no
one company that's that has this problem
and you'll see that as I go on but
obviously that's a big problem there's a
lot of information here what could you
do with this well the first thing that
came to my mind is well if you have this
much information on somebody you have a
lot of background maybe you could try
like a social engineering attack or
something like that you know where they
were on a certain night maybe you could
call them up and say you are the hotel
and you have some credibility because
you could say oh yeah your your
reservation number was this the last
four digits of your credit card number
is this there was a problem with your
hotel stay and you need to send me a
check at this address or something like
that but there's all sorts of other
problems one of the things that you see
here the billing name and the guest they
have they have different last names so
maybe the people who reserved this hotel
don't want anybody else to know that
they were in a room together at this
hotel so maybe there's another tactic
that the attacker could take in
blackmail or something like that at this
point you don't really know but somebody
that was malicious could definitely look
into it and use this as as a starting
point to definitely go further alright
so I'll give you guys another example
this one's in google calendar and so I
call it private events and calendar
tampering if you're not familiar with
Google Calendar it's very similar to
Outlook where you can create an event on
your calendar you can share that event
with your friends and when they accept
your invite it'll show on your calendar
that they accepted that they're going to
be going so I sent myself in a bike and
you can see the links there it says are
you going yes maybe no and I just put
the links there so you can kind of see
what what I saw when I right click on it
and click view URL and then I converted
that into a quarry to see what kind of
results i would find
and we got a good number of results here
and these are going to be other people's
calendars so the quarry ought to end up
using was site wwwdcom that's going to
limit the scope to just google com in
url calendar in url event in url action
and in url response updated alright so
one of the first links there meet with
brig and penny at sacramento and you can
see at the top that it actually thinks
that I am Greg at HB Gary calm so so
those who don't know Greg would be the
CEO the now-defunct security company HB
here you and I bet you would not be
happy about his private event calendars
being posted online for any what you can
see but uh now everybody knows who he
was meeting with and at what time and
where what he was doing here's another
one I mean you it's kind of fun just to
go through these lengths you open a
whole bunch of them and you just see
what kind of information it takes you so
this one was a pretty funny one and now
I don't even know where it came from but
it says 11am $13 fusion of yoga Pilates
exercise come join us in a semi clothed
awakening of your next shot key energy
and the sacred chuckers of your body and
the funny thing about this is you'll see
it says there's a link there change your
response so i was able to click change
my response and so yes I'm going with
more than 50 guests
it's going to be a big party at this
exercise but yeah there's it you can run
into the same problem if let's say you
invite a friend to an event on google
calendar and their friend says hey I
didn't get the invite can you send it to
me so you forward it to them now they
actually can click that link and pretend
to be you they can change the comments
on that event say you're not going no I
don't want to go to that party it's
going to suck anyway it'll show up on
your calendar as the first person that
you sent it to so there's a spoofing
issue there and I brought it up to
Google and they said you know they're
aware of it and the latest policy is
really strict on a vulnerability
disclosure I think it's like seven days
or something like that and I asked them
about that and they said well that's
only for actively being exploited
vulnerabilities and the thing about this
is how would anybody else know who's
exploiting a google search besides
google so that's kind of that's kind of
a tricky if you ask me all right well
here's another example cell phone
carrier shipping confirmations this
one's pretty fun all right so here's an
email I got just the other day and
blocked out the important information
here so this is just the email and it's
is it's okay if they in my email that
they say you know here's your subtotal
here's your receipt information
confirmation all this stuff but it's
another thing when you find that
information online you see at the top
get ready for the fastest 4G network in
America view online all right so if you
online that's that's it we'll just
basically show you the same information
that you got in your email draw on a
website and you can see there the URL
died stripped from that link i turn that
into a google quarry and we get site
verizonwireless com in URL download asp
in URL gu
i D the GUI d is going to be a unique
token each user is going to have a
different one and that's why we're using
google to find these pages rather than
trying to guess the GUI d if we just
want to find somebody else is it's not
like you can just increment it by one
they usually don't have that problem
although they have in the past in this
example they don't but we click on the
first link there and wow we get a lot of
information it says hi kid Montes we
have their order number we have their
shipping address their payment address
their payment type which is a visa we
also know that they're getting a new
iphone 4 with free two-day shipping a
give by shared data and then this email
was sent to so now we have their email
address too and then of course they say
that they respect your privacy so so so
you know that it's legit yeah when I saw
this I was just completely shocked that
you know I'm looking at somebody else's
information and the damage that you can
do it maybe it doesn't come come to you
right away but if you know that
somebody's going to be getting a new
iphone and you know when about when
they're going to get it maybe you're
going to hang around their house and see
when the delivery guy comes by you know
here's another one we have the order
number we have the name of the
individual and has this address and his
phone number it also has it looks like
this guy's a multi-line plan so we have
several mobile numbers we have their sim
ID we have two iphone 4gs and a tracking
number so we can actually watch as
that's being delivered we have all that
information available online and there's
just pages and pages and pages of this
it's not just this one example that I'm
showing you right now
you can change the query a little bit
and you get you'll get different results
so and also when you first do it it'll
actually say that you have one result
click here for more because it it thinks
that they're too similar but so the
numbers that it comes back with it was a
little bit weird but yeah the mechanism
for caching from google I'll get into
that any other comments on this page
right here everybody else huh verizon
all right there are a couple examples
that I didn't get into here just because
it's a little bit sketchy but there have
been pages with full credit card numbers
and cvv details on the website that I
found and interesting thing about that
is is very illegal for companies to
store cvv numbers credit card limits
reward categories and points those ones
are all over the place and personal
identifiable information in the URL over
HTTP that's that's another one that was
seen pretty frequently so so the
interesting thing about this is it it's
not direct at any one industry it covers
pretty much all industries and you know
there doesn't seem to be a writer reason
between you know which sites has its
warner ability or which sites do not it
just depends on who set up their email
system and and I think that's basically
it okay so why is this happening all
right so a lot of it comes down to these
personalized emails they want to send
you a personalized email they wanted to
have receipt information or an invoice
or a link so you can unsubscribe and all
the times the unsubscribe links if you
find that URL
tell you the person's email address
which would be pretty useful if you are
in marketing or sales or something like
that you if you'd be able to find out
what emails one of your competitors is
subscribed to or something like that
you'd be able to send find out who they
were and send them your own stuff more
black hat stuff but one of the
interesting things about is they use
unique URLs for tracking the user
interaction and that's why there's URLs
all over these emails they also wanted
to be pretty so that people view these
email so they load it up with pictures
and HTML but it has to support all email
clients and that's one of the things
that breaks down to and follow the
unsupported clients that's why they have
that link view this email in your
browser because if you're running some
weird email client they still want to be
able to sell to you or give whatever
information they want to give to you
that way and that's why they have these
links and you're able to view it on the
website another reason they do it is
just for convenience and recently there
was a issue with okcupid com where I
guess that's a dating site and the
there's a blog post about how the emails
that they sent out automatically logged
you in when you clicked on them so if
you forwarded that information to
somebody else or somebody else got
access to your email account they could
just click the link and they don't see
all your messages and your inbox and
things like that and a similar dating
website and how about we when when asked
about it said yeah we built this feature
because people requested it it allows
for more easeful and immediate user
experience and I guess both of these
sites decided to the exact same thing
and regardless of the security costs and
that's that's always the thing right you
have to balance convenience with
security and where does that where do
you want to balance out all right so a
little bit about solutions to this
problem and if the website has this
problem it's not all over there are a
few things that they can do but first if
possible make sure you're doing it right
don't provide any kind of information at
sensitive without requiring the user to
log in
any kind of information and if you don't
want to have them login at least have
them provide like a pin number or some
kind of information that you can't just
randomly find on the internet but if
it's already too late you already have
one of these websites on that you're
responsible for make sure that you
you're doing proper housing so always
use HTTPS on these sites all right
expire these pages quickly less than 30
days that way if Google finds these
links they're not there for very long
you're limiting the exposure you're
limiting the risk there and then you
want to add the headers cache-control no
cash no store and pragma no cache and
hopefully the most of the search engines
and everything else will honor these and
especially if you're using HTTPS they
won't actually keep the links with these
sites though drop them because they'll
understand that's supposed to be secure
and it's not supposed to be cached or
stored alternatively if you're admins
don't have control in order to change
the HTTP headers alternatively you can
just add meta tags within the page they
do effectively the same exact thing
another thing that should be done is
implement robots.txt allow these sites
they didn't have robots a txt properly
implemented and what that does is that
provides restrictions on what website
search engines are allowed to go through
on your website there's no law or
anything like that that says they have
to follow it but most of the reputable
companies they'll follow it like if
Google sees that you're disallowing all
the pages on your website it's just
going to see that and then stop
everything else exactly exactly but a
lot of these things and i use google as
an example but you can use bing or
DuckDuckGo or any other search engine
and you can find a lot of the same thing
but google way is the biggest search
engine and it is going to give you the
most results so you want to make sure
that you're limiting that as much as you
can so like I said establish search
engines will honor this file but they're
not required to less reputable scanners
may just ignore it so there's no game
but you definitely want to have that in
there where if you have this problem and
people are saying hey what's my
information doing on your website
everybody to see you want to make sure
move these pages from google so the
people responsible for your website they
can use google webmaster tools and they
can submit a request to have a paid
rivet and i want to do this for all the
ones that have been leaked onto google
somehow you can also remove the google
cache and they say that if the page
still exists use the robots.txt to
prevent google from crawling it but even
if the URL is disallowed they may still
index the page and listen in the search
results because somebody else linked to
it okay so however if you submit a
removal request that will honor that
over it and then we'll keep the page out
of search results and then there are
some laws and consequences the one
that's probably the most damning is in
California there's a law that says that
organizations are must notify
individuals when PII is known or
believed to be acquired by an
unauthorized person right now all you
guys are unauthorized persons so in
summary emails may contain links that
assume you are authenticated these links
can get indexed by Google and other
search engines and Google dorks can lead
you to very sensitive information and
it's very easy to do so what I want you
guys do is to try it yourself I mean
it's really that easy search your own
email inbox for phrases like view this
email in your browser if you are having
trouble viewing this message you'll say
click here click here to view this email
online or even unsubscribe unsubscribe a
lot of times you go to that unsubscribe
page and I'll say your email address is
you know blog whatever com are you sure
you want to unsubscribe you can find
other emails by using those links
anyways well thank you very much las
gone
you