thank you so much for coming everyone
we've got slides up excellent my name is
David Cunningham I'm a security
consultant from Canberra and my
background is really in federal
government so hence my interest in
everything in the essential aid and the
information security manual I'm the
co-founder of the application
whitelisting company airlock digital
that company was really made because I
was going around to many federal
government agencies deploying
application whitelisting using a variety
of technologies and typically I would
come back with in sort of one or two
weeks after deployment answering
questions babying the solution and I was
building a lot of tool sets to solve the
problem wrapping around other vendors
products and basically already built
half a product so we decided to take it
the full way to make application
whitelisting
a lot easier I'm the author of the sans
top for mitigation strategies course
which is now very much out of date and
needs an update to the essential aid but
basically that course was teaching
security practitioners the practical
information that they needed in an
environment to implement these
strategies because there was the advice
from a SD saying you need to do these
things and there was a vast from pen
testers saying I can break well I
wouldn't call it advice I can break
anything that you do so what's the point
so there was none of that mid-level
information that you know real-world
people that are doing this stuff need
and my focus and interest is really on
endpoint security I really really enjoy
it so what's this talk today about
really it's about some tips and tricks
and things that I've learnt deploying
the essential aid over the last sort of
10 years down in Canberra and one of the
main things that I always talk about is
the essentially isn't easy but it is
really worth doing you do get the
biscuit at the end of the day if you
jump in and get these controls right and
the reason that they're not like any
other strategy strategies is because
they require ongoing maintenance this
isn't something that you deploy
antivirus you install in your
environment you sit and forget and
that's why they're called strategies
right they require maintenance a bit of
upkeep but definitely don't let that put
you off also no single product can
perform these strategies you can't just
install something and we'll take care of
it for you their manual processes
however a product or a framework can
significantly improve your success and
lower the manageability
or improve the manageability of these
controls and organizations that
implement the essential aid gained a
significant security benefit how much of
a benefit I'm sure you've all seen these
this slide basically ASD when this was
their advice from the top for saying if
you implement the top four strategies it
mitigates at least 85% of targeted cyber
intrusions that they see and speaking of
people from ASD eighty five percent is a
really conservative estimate there's
some standards from homeland security
called the national cyber security and
communications integration Center and
they say that basically ninety-eight
percent of the incidents that they
responded to in 2014 and 2015 would have
been mitigated by implementing a similar
seven strategies as the hate that ASD
are talking about what are they the
proactive security strategy is informed
by a SDS operational experience in the
field they're designed to proactively
detect intrusions reduce the risk of an
intrusion reduce the damage even an
intrusion does occur on your network so
reduce the time to detection and one
that people don't often talk about which
is increasing the cost of intrusion for
the bad guys right so your adversaries
run a business - if you make it cost
prohibitive for them to attack you then
they're going to go elsewhere
effectively and just to complicate
things a little bit there's also a
maturity scale applied to each one of
these eight strategies zero from you
haven't done it at all or you're not
aligned with the intent of the control
to four which is full high-risk
environment you've implemented it to the
letter of the standard so application
whitelisting is the number one strategy
and it's one that I'm probably most
familiar and enjoy the most and the
intent of application whitelisting is to
remove code execution on your system or
untrusted code execution on your systems
and the reason you want to do this is to
prevent the bad guys from using the
tools that they need to carry out their
attacks so for example if there's an
actor inside your environment they might
want to download an FTP tool to
exfiltrate data from your environment if
you prevent them from being able to do
that it significantly limits their
capability of the things that they can
do and it makes attackers do what's
called live off the land so they need to
use functionality that inherently exists
inside your environment in
order to carry out their objectives many
security the security community's been
talking about this a lot lately and they
call it Lowell bins or living off the
land binary so these are functions
inside Windows that you can use in order
to do sort of nefarious or or
interesting things the challenges of
whitelisting are really it's a technical
control right it typically requires very
sort of focused security people to go in
implement whitelisting understand it and
build a process for the business that
they can manage however many
organizations fail with why this team
because it is largely really technical
and in the real world security people
aren't the ones that are managing the
whitelist typically organizations want
to pass that offers and operational
control to the server team or some other
business area that's the challenge that
we've really tried to solve with air
lock it's taking that technical
complexity out of whitelisting and also
the challenges our business processes
really need to be thought about before
you try and tackle whitelisting so for
example if someone brings in a USB key
with a new piece of software into your
environment and that user wants to run
it what's the process about how they get
that approved and what's the process in
which an organization reviews the
software decides whether it's trusted
and updates or whitelist and who's
responsible for doing that in various
areas and that's also a big challenge to
actually map out and assign those
responsibilities in terms of auditing
application whitelisting how do you know
whether it's done well in my consulting
work I built a number of tools to sort
of demonstrate this because it is such a
technical control but what we've done at
airlock is we've built an application
whitelisting
auditor that's free and I'll have links
at the end of the talk that you can go
and download that but basically you run
it on your systems it will spray binary
is all over your system it will tell you
where they've been successfully able to
execute so it will show you where
there's gaps in your policy or security
risks in terms of maturity audit mode is
zero for white listing so if you're not
actively blocking untrusted files from
running ISDN say you get a zero no
biscuit and some maturity level is four
which is if you're only allowing fast to
run based on their cryptographic hash
value which is a very challenging thing
to do to demonstrate this challenge a
lot of people this are taken from the
sans course there are
basically a lot of people say hey how
about you just wipe this turd Dobie Rio
which is represented by the top box out
there that doesn't sound very hard right
well if you're doing application
whitelisting well of executables and
dll's and scripts you need to actually
whitelist each individual application
component and that's represented by the
bottom square down there and I actually
I think this was for Adobe Reader 11 I
went through encounter to every single
executable file that was part of that
that application and you have to add
sort of that many rules represented by
each box to make the application run
it's not quite as as simple as it may
seem from the outset now this video was
taken from a federal government agency
that I was doing some work for fairly
recently basically it's the majority of
attacks that we're still seeing out
there right it's this is an oli object
embedded inside a word document and
basically it was a phishing email that
came in you double-click on it and what
it does is it just drops in executable
to the system and runs it and this is
how a lot of people are still getting
compromised in today's day and age right
so it's really raising the bar from from
these type of attacks that are still
working here's what we need to do
deployment tips for application
whitelisting
step one decide on the maturity level of
whitelisting that you want to achieve so
I said before that zero was audit mode
for was full hash base we need to decide
as an organization before deploying ok
do I want to wipe this two executables
do I want to wipe this scripts how much
maintenance and am I prepared to suffer
as part of the whitelist
and where do we want to be as an
organization and based on that maturity
that will allow you to evaluate the
application whitelisting technologies a
lot better so you can ask more specific
questions about ok if I want to wipe
this to this level of maturity you know
does your product support that and how
does that look in a real-world scenario
once you've evaluated the technology and
you've understood any limitations that
may be present it's about developing
those business processes so map out
those scenarios say ok when a user
brings in a new piece of software that
was you know unknown to me I didn't know
that we're bringing in how am I going to
deal with that scenario allow the user
to get on with what they need to do and
verify that that's legitimate and up
my application whitelist and then step
four is actually going about deploying
that solution I was having a discussion
on on Twitter I showed this deployment
tips to a guy called Casey Smith which
is doing a lot of work on what we call
low bins and basically he's very
passionate about this as you can tell by
the old caps but he's basically venting
frustration that a lot of organizations
just allow executables and dll's to just
run on their networks so number two
patching applications and I know there's
a question that you're all asking right
now which is what our applications but I
put that up there because it's a really
important question that nobody asks
until they're having a debate later on
about do we need to patch this is it
really an application underneath the ASD
guidelines but basically an application
it's important to define it's anything
that sort of runs on top of the systems
so typically we've got office
executables any applications
traditionally middleware is web servers
any developed code that's on top of your
system as well it may have security
vulnerabilities in it that you do need
to update and fix things like web
browsers and once we've defined that it
becomes a lot easier to have the
discussion about what we need to patch
an update so the intent of patching
applications is quite obvious right it's
removing known security vulnerabilities
from your system however there are a
number of challenges here threatened
intelligence is one so it's
understanding when the latest zero-day
is floating around on the internet for
an application that affects you how are
we going to understand when new
significant security vulnerabilities
come out for the applications that we
have installed the challenges is also
just understanding what applications you
have in your environment so building an
inventory of those applications is
challenging performing risk assessments
and I'll talk about that in a couple of
slides time performing application
packaging and deployment and rapidly
deploying applications is challenging in
terms of auditing it's kind of difficult
you really need enterprise tools out
there they used to be this great tool
from flex era called the personal
software inspector which has now been
discontinued but flex era is generally
pretty good company to do software
auditing and there's a number of other
and
price tools out there but as an auditor
you really want to go in and just do
sample auditing of various end points
within the organization to say show me a
list of what applications you have
installed and then go and check whether
you know they're up to date things like
that ASD say on a maturity scale that if
you patch greater than a monthly basis
you get their score of zero which is
quite harsh but some if you apply patch
within 48 hours you actually get a
maturity level of 3 in terms of a
real-world example this was taken from a
federal government agency many years ago
now and basically it was an adobe reader
exploit that was very very new at the
time and really this email in these
examples like it are why many of you
that may be familiar with the top thirty
seven strategies wide user education
went from back in the day from like
number ten down to I think it was like
number twenty seven which was very
contentious at the time but basically
social engineering and fishing is so
good nowadays you can't really teach
users not to click on things and I know
that's probably some of you would
disagree with me in there
but in this case we had just patched
Adobe Reader from a recent vulnerability
that was using we were able to not be
susceptible to that that particular
attack deployment tips step one you need
to generate or create a vulnerability
risk determination policy and I know
that sounds really really dry and it
kind of is but this is about making sure
that you have a standard process to
assess ok we there's a zero-day that's
out in the wild that has remote code
execution and we are vulnerable to it
how do we assess that risk and know it's
really risky for us and then what has a
business agreed is the timeframe to
patch that vulnerability right so if
Microsoft releases are critical it's
applied to us you might have a policy
that says we need to patch that within
two days or we might say that based on
our assessment you know we have a month
to patch this vulnerability and what
what it does having that in policy
before you actually go about this is
basically avoiding those arguments in
change control if you have it in the
larger organizations about why is this
so important you know you're not really
articulating this to the business so
it's making sure that you have a clear
defined
way of communicating risk and also the
responsibility of time frames to
patching step 2 inventory your
applications understand what
applications you have out there in the
environment step 3 patch intelligence
advisory so it's sort of trying to get
information about when vulnerabilities
exist for those applications that you
have and if you're not buying a service
to do this a really effective way
actually is to just subscribe to
basically Security Response feeds things
like you know the Microsoft Security
Response Center on Twitter and the Adobe
security research team and try and find
work with your major vendors to
understand how do you let me know when
vulnerabilities come out and have a
process for getting that in and step
forward deploying your patches number
three is configuring Microsoft to offer
some macro settings and macros over the
last five years really increased in
prevalence and basically the idea is to
prevent the download and dropping of
malware macros are pretty much used as a
malware delivery mechanism into your
environment and the challenges there are
is just user acceptance so it's
terrifying as a security person if you
just turn off all the macros across the
organization without really
understanding how the organizations are
using macros in the first place
because they're quite well used in the
typical business and so many business
areas do weird and wonderful things with
them as an auditor basically you need to
look at the office trust Center settings
inside the Microsoft Office applications
to determine what the macro settings are
set to and also I've written an office
hardening auditing script that's
available on my github the link will be
at the end of this presentation the
basically you can run it and we'll tell
you what the macro settings and postures
are of all the different office
applications inside your environment
maturity is zero if you have user
configurable settings so if you don't
actually enforce macro settings in the
registry or via group policy a SD
consider that to be a zero and the
reason being is even though by default
the office application will say that
macros are disabled with a notification
users can just go in and change that so
they consider it to provide you know no
security benefit
at all and maturity level 3 is macros in
trusted locations can execute and I'll
talk about trust of locations basically
trusted locations in office folder paths
or network shares where any document
that's inside those locations can
execute without any security
restrictions and what the majority of
organizations do is they'll go into
office and they'll put in every single
file share inside their organization as
a trusted location to say that all of
the documents when they're run from here
can run you know regardless of what all
my other security settings are and in
curry it sort of works on this scenario
where basically if you receive a
malicious email that contains a macro
you double click on it or the user
double clicks on it it's not running
from one of those trusted locations so
the macro will be disabled however if
the user needs it then they can save
that copy that into their you know their
home drive and then run it not perfect
but it's the unfortunately the best
thing we've got in terms of office
security configuration settings so I
definitely work with trusted locations
because it can get allow you to disable
macros in some scenarios even if you're
a macro heavy organization you can do
auditing with our office telemetry so
there's an ability in office to spin up
a telemetry server and get an idea about
what documents you use as a handling and
what features of officer using including
the amount of macro use so that can
provide you a little bit of insight into
how many macros are actually out there
in the organisation before you just go
and turn it off and also remember to
disable it per product macro settings
aren't something that you just go hey in
office I'm gonna turn this off Microsoft
Access for some reason has macro
settings I don't know why or what you
could do with it but you it's important
to go through the whole suite even Visio
and everything and make sure that you've
got all those settings turned off across
the board but that um that auditing
script will really help you with that
number four user application hardening
this is basically to configure different
products that are inside your
organization to reduce the attack
surface of applications that load
untrusted content so it's any
applications that open files from the
internet browse content from the
internet or any sort of
external source so web browsers office
productivity applications things like
that the challenges of user application
hardening is it typically reduces user
functionality they might use some
features that you are turning off and
the challenges are also attaining
hardening information from vendors
unless you're talking about the really
big vendors like Microsoft Google they
typically don't provide a lot of
information about how to harden their
products or run it in the most secure
configuration possible and I definitely
encourage you all to speak to your
vendors and basically ask them ok how do
i harden your application and if I want
to run it in the secure configuration
what does that look like and see what
type of response that you get from them
and also one of the challenges but also
under the I guess it's kind of easy in
some organizations as well is blocking
advertisements a SD say that one good
thing to harden web browsers is to block
all advertising had your proxy and I'll
explain why that is in a second
auditing it's really about checking
Group Policy and registry settings as I
said the hardening script which I've
made helps with a number of those
products and also look at the asd
hardening guides that they provide they
provide a lot of guides for office
internet explorer and a lot of different
products the maturity is if you allow
flash and web adverts to run and Java's
in your browser you get a maturity level
of zero and the reason why they say if
you allow web adverts you get a maturity
level of 0 is because advertising
networks of especially in the last two
years really being used to deliver
malicious content to end computers and
users there was I think it was about
four months ago there was an issue where
an advertiser managed to get
cryptocurrency JavaScript miners running
on YouTube so people would go to watch
youtube videos and then their computer
would be doing mining through them
delivered through an advertising network
and it's becoming an increasingly big
attack vector maturity level 4 is you've
harden your web browsers you
disconnected flash from the browser
you've got no Java and also you're
blocking adverts
so what I would say for deploying is
step one is use proxy if you have one to
block advertising content if you don't
have a proxy then maybe try and use some
you know
extensions on your browser to actually
block advertising from loading step 2
blocking flash and unlinking Java from
the web browser I know it's easier said
than done but flash is becoming less
prevalent all the time so next time
you're doing your operating system
refresh maybe in Windows 10 you can try
get that in as a new sort of requirement
step 3
implement the office hardening guide if
you use Microsoft Office from ASD and
step 4 harden the web browsers based on
a lot of the vendor guidance chrome
internet explorer firefox say there's
some good guides out there about how to
actually improve the security of those
platforms number 5 restrict
administrative privileges and the intent
of this is to prevent adversaries of the
bad guys from gaining administrative
access on your systems in the first
place and can anyone tell me what is an
administrator anyway have a guess yeah
anyone with privileged access which is
essentially sort of the same question
again it's it's like what is privileged
access and this is something that it's
really hard to define and what I usually
define it as with with customers is to
say that I think an administrator is any
account that has the ability to change
the configuration of software or systems
on your endpoints so if they can modify
your system in some way then it's an
administrative access and if you think
at minute of administrative access in
that way it really changes the scope of
what is restricts administrative
privileges but it's easy to have a base
point like that definition to work from
challenges are identifying what access
is required from users and also the
business processes for obtaining access
so it's important to have some sort of
defined process in your organization to
say hey if this administrator is
starting and they need access what
access do they need how do I provide it
and also how do I review that every so
often and also there's a requirement on
the Australian Government that says you
need to use separate administrative
workstations inside your organization
which I haven't personally seen done
before but basically the idea is that
you have two terminals on your desks and
you have a standard user account and an
administrative user account and you only
use the administrative user account on
the workstation that doesn't have
internet or email on it the reason being
is because if you have one computer
where the standard user account your
remote desktop to somewhere else you
type in your administrative credentials
if there's a key logger on that machine
they're going to capture all that
information and get your administrative
account anyway so it makes sense it's
just implementing that from a practical
point of view can be quite tricky and
there's a number of approaches that you
can do which are probably a little bit
simpler than having to physical pcs
auditing bloodhound is the best thing
that has happened in the last two years
and I'll talk a little bit about that in
a second if you're an auditor you want
to look at the business processes so you
want to go into an organization and you
want to say tell me how people get
administrative access so if I was to
request domain administrator what do I
need to do to get that access and also
what checks do you have in place how
often do you review that access can you
show me your last access review that
you've done inside the organization you
can have a look at their privileged
access management solution and that
management solution may not be a
full-blown product it may be Active
Directory so have a look at whatever the
organization uses to delegate and
provide access and also have a look at
their proxy make sure that
administrators are blocked from gaining
access to the Internet the maturity is
privileged accounts are browsing the
internet or email you get a zero and you
get a maturity level 3 if you have some
sort of privileged access management
solution in place you only grant that
access when you're required and you
perform regular audits of administrative
access so bloodhound this is something
that a number of extremely talented
researchers released at DEFCON about two
years ago and it's designed to scan your
Active Directory environment and
basically map out your permission models
inside Active Directory and identify
attack pass it's designed for red teams
and basically what it's designed to do
it's completely open source and free is
you go into the organization you scan
their Active Directory and that's you
only generally need a standard user
count to actually do this you take all
their information about from their
Active Directory and you go away for two
weeks and you study all the attack pass
and which users you need to attack to
get to your particular objectives it's
very visual and it's free
as I said in built for red team so if
you're not using it the bad guys are I
highly encourage you to at least scan
your environment and have a look what's
in there you don't only takes about ten
minutes to run it is a fantastic tool
and that's sort of what the attack paths
look like inside bloodhounds so you can
see okay if I need to get to domain
administrator I need to attack it this
particular user over in finance who has
access to this group or this machine
then I can jump onto that machine and in
a domain administrative account might be
logged on to that machine to steal their
session and you can build up these
amazing charts about how you're
privileged access model is performed so
you can't recommend it enough so
deployment tips step one audit with
bloodhound
is set to become initiative accounts
from accessing the internet and email so
don't associate email addresses with
your administrative accounts and block
them from going through the proxy if you
have one step three validate and remove
privileged accounts on a regular basis
and that's trying to do them sort of at
least once every six months and this
might be as simple as having a whole
stack of paper that this person has
signed that they've got an
administrative account and then you go
to the top of the stack and then you
check it yes they're still here yes they
still need the access and they move it
to the bottom of the pile you know
there's better ways to do it but um it's
just having some sort of process in
place and step four obviously when
you're getting to a really mature state
it's providing only the access that's
required for administrators as they need
it a one bonus I put down there is
removing enterprise and schema
administrators from your environment and
only providing people schemer and
enterprise admin when they need it
typically these rights are only needed
when you're doing a big Active Directory
schema and had been changes so and also
those groups are set up so if you are a
domain administrator you always have
rights over those groups those groups
don't have you know some sort of God
right over your your Active Directory
instance well they allow you to do
certain things but don't be afraid that
you can't put users back in
once you've moved them out because
domain administrators have that
privilege number six patching operating
systems the idea here as expected is
prevent adversaries from using
vulnerabilities to get more privileges
on your system so typically operating
system vulnerabilities these days
because operating systems are getting
increasingly hard and against attacks is
adversaries use it to get administrator
access when they only have standard user
access and remove classes of exploits
through features and this can be seen in
Windows 10 with all the new feature
updates microsoft's doing a lot of
fantastic work to bring new security
features into the actual operating
system but just like applications we've
got another question which is what is an
operating system and according to asd
operating systems are basically anything
that runs on sort of a network device as
well as what you would think of an
operating system like Windows and Linux
on a computer as well and it's
challenging to update and maintain your
network devices auditing really there's
a whole bunch of scanning tools out
there typically in an enterprise usually
what I say is you know go use necess if
you don't have it already it's
reasonable and you know it does a good
job of actually inventory your your
environment maturity is if you've got
unsupported operating systems in your
environment like Windows XP and Server
2003 you get a maturity level of zero
and also maturity level of three if
you're only using vendor supported
operating systems and you're doing rapid
patch cycles so pretty straightforward
that one multi-factor authentication the
intent here is to limit adversary access
through credential stealing right so if
your credentials get stolen from your
environment then it's pretty much game
over there was a situation that I was
aware of a number of years ago where
what an organization got compromised by
state actor all of their usernames and
passwords were completely stolen and
what the organization had to do was
basically disconnect the internet
connection bring down their whole
environment and reset every single
password over the weekend and then bring
their environment back up again what
because the attacker knew all the
usernames of past
they went hmm he's the password for this
particular account that was password one
I wonder if that's now password to when
they've reset it and they were
unfortunately right so they logged just
logged straight back into the
environment after the reset by
incrementing you know choose your
credential and then they had to reset
and do the whole environment all over
again
so multi-factor authentication
particularly on your remote access any
any ability to get remotely into your
systems it's a must these days to have
remote access or multi-factor on there
and the challenges are just user
acceptance and the technology
integration in their auditing is viewing
the logon methods so if you're an
auditor you can go into an organization
and say show me how you access this
environment from home if you can and
making sure they jump through a
multi-factor access point and also ask
okay if you as an administrator need to
do something on your servers how do you
do that and watch them jump through that
process and make sure they hit a
multi-factor point maturity you don't
use multi-factor 0 3 is multi-factor for
remote access privileged accounts and
accessing sensitive data and ISDN call
out no SMS and this is something that
Security's community is talking about a
lot lately where we're recognizing that
SMS is not a secure out-of-band
multi-factor token method for delivery
anymore so we can't use that deployment
tips step one enable it for your remote
access solutions multi factors typically
very easily natively integrated into
these platforms and then what I would do
is have a look at technologies that you
can use out there from vendors to
actually do your internal systems step 3
network design and what I mean by that
is you aren't going to install a
multi-factor clients on every single
server inside your environment it's just
not going to be practical so what I
would suggest instead is designing your
network so they're sort of jump hosts or
choke points inside your network so in
order to get to the server zone you need
to go to this particular server or
endpoint first before jumping into your
actual server environment and that makes
them multi-factor implementation a
significant amount easier because they
have a user has to go through that check
at least once then in step 4 implement
that solution number 8 pretty
straightforward is
daily backup your data if the intent is
recovery in the event of security
incident and this is really driven by
ransomware and the uptick in you know
data loss so your organization is not
held to ransom the challenges are really
cost and also their access that typical
backup solutions need inside your
environment so many times I've seen
organizations deployed backup solutions
where they've just given the backup
account domain admin access and it's
logging on to every single server
basically you know doing doing those
backups and that's a real problem
because if you run bloodhound in your
environment you'll see that you can
pretty much steal domain administrative
access from any single server that your
backup account is backing up so you know
getting that privilege reduction tends
to be really tricky so if you're talking
to a vendor that does your backups
definitely ask them what privileges do
you need in order to do you know and
backup data auditing observe their
backups make sure that they've got a
process to actually do the backup of
that data and make sure that they've
previously tried to recover their data
there's a lot of people that don't some
basically test their recovery processes
the maturity a SD say that if you back
up less than monthly and you've never
tested a recovery that you get a
maturity level of zero but maturity
level of three is you're performing
offline backups you performing backups
daily and you're testing a full recovery
and I know that that is quite a
challenge in many scenarios and if you
do all that you can become like OPSEC
Harold and identify malware on your
network and Harold as as many of you
would know lives in a very interesting
space where he's not happy or sad just
like many security researchers when you
identify something good but it's also
bad at the same time resources
bloodhound definitely check that out
that is must-have tool the airlock
application whitelisting auditor that I
talked about before to audit your
application white this can be found on
our website
airlock digital comm also check out the
ASD hardening guides they're invaluable
and fantastic for hardening your your
solutions they're free and also the
scripts to do auditing against those
hardening guides so if you go to my
github there I've got a script that
checks your Windows 10 deployment and
tells you which controls in the
hardening guide your compliant with and
which ones you're not and also the
office 2016
hardening as well it will tell you where
the macros are enabled and what features
you have certain which ones you don't
and I'm working on those all the time so
definitely check back regularly and
there's lots of improvements there so I
guess we're at that point any questions
yeah so I have a mic here so does anyone
have any questions we've got a few
minutes for questions just a quick one
the evaluated products list lists rel
7.1 yep with FS PP protection profile
yes 1 how does this fit though I'm not
seeing much LS PP protection profile at
the AOL for Plus out there in the
marketplace are you seeing any at all
because everything we've said here ya
know 15 years ago with with the with Mac
yes major access control b2 through to
OS l SPP yes which is a defined
protection profile yes for the server
environment yeah I'm not seeing much out
there you see not really I guess it's a
whether it's practical for organizations
to run those systems and get the
functionality that they need right so
but there is definitely a disconnect
there I mean it's sort of outside my
scope to sort of talk in depth too much
about it but there is definitely a
disconnect there between the
certification process and also how you
need to update your operating systems to
the latest version as soon as possible
so the certification tends to be a
little bit behind but no I'm not really
seeing those sort of hardened platforms
out there too much 1u not seeing much
rel 7.1 out there not acute as a server
yes thanks for the question any other
questions
yep yeah Oh off on mobiles fine because
there's push notifications to the actual
device and that's done sort of by a
secure channel so you would need to
compromise the device in order to get
that OAuth whereas I think that SMS
out-of-band is really about the
vulnerabilities with telcos so it's the
ability to do SIM swaps
and you know try and get the SMS not
from your device but through some other
method of porting numbers and and that
that process is still a bit too sketchy
to be a valid method so anything that
sort of delivers the code out-of-band
through another mechanism to the end
device and has some validation that
that's the user on the other end it's it
is okay yep yep one more question um you
had patching oasis what about stuff
lower level than that so things like
your device drivers here your firmware
your TPM all of that kind of stuff which
we've seen quite a bit of action on in
the past year or so yes yeah I think
there's no particularly guidance about
updating that stuff and and I guess as
an auditor most auditors when they would
go into agencies wouldn't be looking for
that low-level so I guess it's as a due
diligence piece you know I guess the
whole standard inferring that hey we
need to update everything that's at this
lower level in terms of whether it'll be
checked or not I guess it's about risk
right so if there is a significant
vulnerability in the TPM module that
could be exploited remotely and does
affect you then that's when you would
say ok we're going to adhere to this
standard and that's where the risk
management sort of ulnar ability
determination policy that I talked about
is really important because then you can
just bundle that under that risk and say
hey this is critical to us we need to
fix this regardless of what the
nitty-gritty definitions are ok thanks
very much let's give David a hand for
the great presentation oh thanks