[Applause]
thank you thank you everyone
well welcome to sa Benson response
real-life examples on how to attack and
defend before we start let me tell you
something this is not like a fairy tale
story this is not a kind of story with
the good guy always win in the end what
you're going to see here the real
examples of my experience doing SMB
forensic analysis this is how the market
in terms of ASAP security it is reiner
so this is a brief disclaimer no one
reads it anyway but it's very important
to put it out there
Who am I my name is Jordan central
cheering my background originally was
general penetration tester like when I
lead assessment all the it's explained
writing and slowly starting from 2008 I
started working on this type of big
systems called earpiece making a lot of
focus in s IP and also in Oregon as well
since then I had the pleasure to work
with almost like a thousand S&P
implementations worldwide you name it
like big companies so their United
States Europe military institutions and
also with a lot of OMGs in the planet I
work at Bitzer I'm actually one of the
founders of mixer where we specialize in
sa be an Oracle we have a lot of
customers fortune 500 and we do a lot of
stuff we do penetration testing analysis
when all its and what this chart bring
us forensic investigations by the way
we're now expanding to asia-pacific we
have a big core in all the Americas but
now we are expanding to Asia Pacific as
well so this is the agenda that I have
prepared for you guys first it will be
like a brief introduction very very
brief introduction in just for the sake
of time to s IP so we can all be at the
same level and something funny take the
eSAB word out of it I can prepare for
you three different misconceptions that
I always hear about maybe you hear about
those misconceptions to again take the
words AP out first misconception that I
have for you
we can never have an sob security
incident before another misconception we
thought that ACP sir attacks were not
real and the final one the probability
of an ACP sir attack is low okay so
let's just start with a brief
introduction to us ap the first question
that you might be having is okay so what
is a CP CP is actually an acronym and it
stands for assistance applications and
products in data processing so no wonder
why choose people call it a CP it's
actually a German company was founded in
1972 but X IBM employees another if you
know the history but those guys were
working together creating an inner P for
actually IBM don't I don't know why that
project gets canceled and they decide to
leave IBM to create their own ERP and
let me tell you that that was one of the
most successful business decisions in
the war
why because s AP is huge is everywhere
look at these numbers that I prepared
for you they have more than 88,000
customers worldwide they are present in
more than 80 countries so there and they
totally dominate the market 87% of the
biggest companies out there the Fortune
Global 2000 are using s AP I know that
in the SI p war is kind of confusing
some people even call it like
Stephanie's but it's really confusing
when you start hearing all those names
like ear PPI CRM it's kinda hard to keep
up with those names well for you to
understand better I can repair like a
brief division of both from one side you
will have the enterprise solutions those
systems are the ones that your workers
like the HR people financial guys will
be learning every day to do their work
and from the other side you have the
supporting solutions those solutions
will support the enterprise ones the
difference here on the supporting
solutions is that you won't have a lot
of end customers most of the
we'll be logging in there are technical
so coming back to this enterprise
solutions we are going to start hearing
a lot one small word called netweaver
we're going to see later what NAND
Weaver means but just having in your
mind all the enterprise solutions that I
have prepared here for you are net
Weaver base that is the opposite for the
supporting solutions except for this I
Beecher see those are not netweaver base
basically says IP that you want to buy
different pieces of technologies and
start integrating those technologies
between the ecosystem of SA P so what is
this netweaver time I'm talking about
where netweaver is the framework where s
ap is built in let me tell you that is
the most important piece of technology
on the SI p world the most important one
and it regulates how s ap will interact
with all the different components a very
important set of things about Ned Weaver
is that first is service oriented
meaning that each SI p system will have
all the different services running on
all specific SFP ports unlimitedly right
now that most of those services that I
mention about they have private
protocols their proprietary protocols
meaning that are not documented out
there and finally we can find two
frameworks or two divisions of netweaver
we have the a bub stack commonly used
for back-end systems if your company's
processing credit cards what is there
and you have the Java stack commonly
used for front-end but don't get me
wrong both of those stats you can find
on the Internet so let's follow this
diagram here this is how a netweaver
system looks like again this is like a
very brief introduction what I have here
the ESP application level is actually
the netweaver framework then L we
refrain will regulate how this abcs
thing connects to the operating system
and the net we were framework on
will regulate how the SP system connects
to the database so 75% of all the
netweaver systems are exactly the same
then the business logic will make the
difference between an ERP system or a bi
system or a CRM system but 70% is
exactly the same and as an attacker if
you put yourself in the role of an
attacker that is really good but we are
defending and if we are defending that
is really mad why because it means that
is some phone boon ability for the year
people they have 75% of probabilities of
that one ability also working on a bi or
a CRM system we give with some of the
basic concepts that we are going to need
some transactions well let me tell you
that in the SI p word even though they
are improving it is not point-and-click
meaning that you will have to remember
some codes some transactions that will
act as a trigger to call a specific ASAP
programs you can have the fall
transactions or custom ones
why because you can also have the
default prevalence and Kisan SAV
programs for the sake of this talk for
now we're going to only understand is a
B programs as a bad provenance just for
the sake of this talk so what is the
neighbor program well first let me tell
you a Bop is a proprietary language
created by ASAP I'm going to show you
later but it's very very similar to
QBasic also we have a variation of those
programs that we can call sav function
calls again they're colored in a bap but
they can be seen as api those api's can
be called locally from the ESP system to
itself or remotely from one ASAP system
to another or for an a python script
Rubeus crib over java application to an
NCP system most of these function calls
are authenticated but there are some
that they are not meaning that you can
call it without any username password
so before we start with these
misconceptions and again I told you
before that we're going to see like real
attacking scenarios
some of them even covering the media I
also want to tell you that I'm not going
to give names I'm not going to give the
names of the companies that they
suffered these attacks just out of
respect and consideration for the big
things so let's start with
misconceptions we never had any CP
security incident before ok this is the
scenario that we had to work with
someone had this massive company in the
United States those guys were the
filming is industry apparently a domain
controller was also compromised the god
domain admin privileges everything that
you can think of it was compromised the
domain controller say before switches
servers workstations database and of
course also the databases that were used
by ASAP the this is the first entire
solaced this company decides to pretty
much duplicate every single piece of
technology that was there it was crazy
they created the concept of a wide room
and only the technology that was
reinstall on that white room was allowed
to stay if I wanted to go there to work
I had to leave my phone I had to leave
my computer my SmartWatch everything
that was the inertia related you had to
leave it outside I was craziest the
first and only time that I saw this kind
of behavior so what was the main concern
here what the victim was specifically
concern about credit cards most
important ones and personal identifying
information bank accounts etc they
wanted to know if that information was
actually retrieved they already knew
that the word totally compromised
someone was already the main enemy but
they want to see if the information was
actually extract they give us the air
people action system why because all the
credit cards were processed there they
say ok guys this is therapy system work
on this the only caveat here is that we
didn't do the forensics of the database
they contracted another one known
company choose for the database so every
time that you hear we never had a nice
ap security in cm before you need to
start asking a few questions right can
you really be sure in Java the Java
stack that I show you before most of the
security audit trails common able by
default great but the name of the most
important one the one that was acting as
a back-end and what the credit cards are
let me tell you that most of the
security logs do not come enable by
default so you need to start asking the
questions the first question that you
need to ask to your customers hey do you
have what is called the security audit
log enable and instead secretary log
enable in all your ASAP systems across
all your users with all the filters let
me tell you that 90% of the time the
answer is no but let's be kind let's be
kind let's assume that the answer is yes
you need to continue and you need to ask
these that the other logs enable do you
remember that I told you before the
netweaver bus service oriented well let
me tell you that each one of those
services has its own set of locks and
for most of them they do not come enable
by default let's be kind again let's
suppose that the customer does have
those locks enable even though most of
them do not have them we need to ask
another question and the most important
one is actually grabbing someone
actually grabbing those locks and doing
something with those locks is someone
doing a correlation and look at looking
at those logs 95 percent of the cases
the answer is no most customers right
now do not have the basic information to
start a forensic investigation on an SMP
system and this is not an isolated case
here in Australia or the United States
pretty much every single company out
there most of the companies out there do
not have everything that they need for a
forensic investigation
so what we had to do we asked for the
virtual machines of the ESCP system and
here's another thing that you need to
take into consideration in this ap you
have what is called the central instance
and then you have application servers
you have application servers to support
a different number of end-users the more
users you have working on a specific
system the more application servers
you're going to have well there is a
caveat there if you want to do a good
job you need to ask for the logs of
every single application server and
central instance why because the
attacker can hit just one a specific
application server and from there
directly jump to the database so maybe
three application servers are completely
clean but if you forget that one the
word the intrusion happened you will
never see anything about the hack once
we go that we mounted the DS and we
started reviewing the logs for your
convenience I have created this table so
you can go back to your job and see if
you have the logs enabled that's the
complete path this kind of like the
Linux example of where the logs should
be at least by default so let's review
together what this customer had first
the e Bob security of the log it was
partially activated it was not fully
activated by the least they got
something perfect it's a pig away log
it's one of the logs that does not come
by default the customer did not have it
domitius server LD log very important
piece of technology in s IP if it is
badly configured someone can do
man-in-the-middle attacks and intercept
the entire traffic that goes to the ASAP
system again as it doesn't come by
default the customer Dino Hallett and
finally we didn't even have the
balloting system locks so as you can see
we were really really far from an ideal
scenario so what is this security lock
today Kim mentioning this is a quote for
an essay B it's a tool designed for a
littles and security professionals when
they want to see details about the
events that are happening inside the
ASAP system let
tell you right now that the security log
is definitely definitely not one of the
best pieces of technologies that ACP
have created out there but don't get me
wrong it's still extremely important to
have this enable why just for the simple
concept that something is better than
nothing there are a million ways to
bypass the security of the log and we're
going to see a one very soon so how you
work with the security of the log there
are three transactions involved with
this m-19 you are going to activate the
security log you're going to say to what
users the security logs should be
enabled it could be for a couple users
all the users or just one front rack
session is in 20 and I set this between
quotes you are going to review the
events we're going to see later why with
the we didn't even use the some 20 I'm
furnishing 18 we're going to be deleting
logs and you might be thinking wait
Joran but something is caching why you
would like to choose the lid locks well
let me tell you that in the SI p warned
the locks do not how to recycle
themselves ACP will keep logging on to
by default it reaches a hundred
megabytes if you don't recycle the logs
manually or with an script the SMP
system will hit the hundred megabytes
and will stop logging until you recycle
those logs the profit parameter that you
see there is how you can regulate how
much information the AP will store until
it stops logging by default again is a
hundred megabytes and also I have
include a little chart down there that
it shows you some of the LD filters that
you can activate with the security of
the log finally log on a time if the
user gets lock unlock successful log on
etc so there was the main problem that
we hit here is that we have G hides and
G hides and gigawatts of lock and this
was just for a not fully configured
security log this and 20 was not good
enough we couldn't see what we were
needed to see so what we had to do
is to create a parser let me tell you
and this is another painful thing that
in SI p the locks are not symmetric
meaning that each one of the services we
have a different syntax for the logs
some logs as is the case of the security
log and not even plain text or binary so
we created this parser for each one of
the lines that we had we created this
table so if we were at the beginning
with 10 gigawatts of information after
doing the parser we ended up with a
kinnor gigawatts we had the seed the
name of the system when the event
happened the hostname the IP of the ASAP
system the username that was used to
produce that event
the message from the SOP system per cell
and the timestamp so once we were able
to parse of those slots we need
something to correlate the logs we use
this plank you can use any sim that you
have in your company but we use this
plan by the way is plant even has are
like a free trial version if you want to
try and once we put it all the events in
this plan we started notice something
very very common and once we know that
and we knew it the x time yes just there
we could go inside the SMP system with
the same xx and corroborate the or
hypothesis what you see and the first
chart is something very common is
basically a brute force over the data
dictionary using NSIP that user in SA P
is ACP underscore all that for you to
have an idea is live in root on a UNIX
box is the almighty user you can do
whatever you want if you get access to
that user so what we're seeing here
we're seeing a couple of failure logon
attempts until we see a successful logon
and a password change of that user the
first thing that we did is a ASAP basis
this was you
they say no so we continue investigating
we continue reviewing what this attacker
was doing inside the ASAP system and we
notice that they call another
transaction ACAD
in SA P in order to code inside s AP is
not that you will have a separate either
at least most of the times you had to
log in inside the s AP system that is
the AC ad they erupted developing world
range and there was a problem there when
we saw that they were calling this
report that report changed the entire
forensic investigation
why because before that we thought we
were dealing with the script kiddies
someone that was like looking at Google
with the default password for that
default user but this program on to that
time I thought I was the only one that
had that psyllid a technique to bypass
the security of the lock this program
can be used to bypass the security only
log so we were not dealing just with a
script kiddie anymore we're dealing with
someone that had real and deep knowledge
on s IP this was a serious attack let me
show you you don't have to believe me
let me show you how it works what you're
seeing here is my Linux berta machine
I'm going to open an SMB client and I'm
going to do exactly the same that
attacker did we're going to replicate
exactly the same we're going to see what
the security elite trainers IP was able
to catch so fail at logon attempt fail
at Logan attempt and we're going to
login perfect we're inside the s AP
system we're going to do exactly the
same let's go to a CI D and as we are
here let me show you what a Bob looks
like so again something kind of similar
to Q basic and we're going to execute
this program this particular program
will let us execute what is called the
remote function calls remember we
mentioned at the beginning
there are hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of function calls in Si P you
could use function calls to create users
to read tables to delete security of the
log attaches for this demonstration I'm
going to use one that is called Earth
see read table and of course this
function call reads a table
you just need to pull the table that you
want to read here you execute it and
automatically you will get the content
of the table let's see now what they say
B knows even where the security Ollie
log is fully activated let me even close
the entire session and we're going even
to use a completely different user oops
let's see we have we're going to go to
transaction SM 20 and we're going to
even ask this ap to reread the LD lock
so we can get most out of it we are here
first failure logon attempt second
trailer logon attempt we call
transaction AC ad and we use the RS and
scored this frame underscore call as you
can see what happens since there it's
completely invisible from SAV we don't
know what function call was called we
know the input that was provide for that
function call and we don't know the
output so what do you think that means
from the forensic investigation point of
view well we have to tell the customer
you know what you need to assume that
you were fully compromised there is no
way to discern what type of information
was obtained about the attackers because
the security of the log is not getting
any of that information
ok so moving forward the other
misconception that I have for you with
photos a pizzeria tags were not real
this is not is a really good one the
Treasury Department of an important
country on the north
medigun region gets visited by the
law-enforcement agency we don't care who
or by what law enforcement agency
apparently their entire platform was
compromised and they were using that
platform to distribute malware but there
is one particular D here the law
enforcement tells this Treasury
Department that the tip of the spear the
original compromised over their platform
was through an NCP system a dual stack
ap system a Bob and Java that was
directly exposed to the Internet by the
time that we actually arrived the system
was still exposed to the Internet the
law enforcement also makes a very
particular claim they say that this
might be part of a sponsor state attack
but they don't provide any kind of
evidence to support that claim the main
concern of this customer was at all
costs identified personal identifying
information was actually stolen why
because if it was by law they had to
make it public the second objective was
to understand okay what happening how
they get in and if it was lateral
movement or not with it exactly the same
procedure as before a give us the
virtual machines and let's start parsing
those weird machines or parsing the logs
inside the border machines the only
difference here is that we already have
an idea of what was the original tip of
the spear what they were using to hack
into the ASAP system but of course we
need the evidence to actually prove it
so one more time the log table for you
to follow if you have at home let's see
what we have on T scenario the evap
security all the log that again we know
that it's not activated by default
what's in there now completely empty
this is a peek at way log a very common
component very common to see that is
under attack doesn't come by default the
logs so it was not here
Misha's server nothing we were lucky as
I mentioned before that the Java logs do
come by default so we do the witty
shadows and this
case the operating system was Windows
and we also had the logs from the
editing system we do exactly the same we
start creating the parsers to create the
logs and as you can see from this plant
capture that we have at the right side
it was very evident that the system was
compromised we starts indirectly their
operating system commands we start
seeing the attackers trying to shut down
the windows firewalls Donna the shady
binaries and executing those binaries we
even go to see some heaters and east as
the image that you will see at the left
side of the intrusion and that keine
supported or theory that we have before
at that point we knew what the Tucker's
utilized to compromise the system what
they use is something that is called in
pokers servlet the invoker servlet in SA
P it's a class loader in meaning that it
will let you call Java applications by
its name or by the server class for
example if you go to Jordan dot-com
slash myservlet it was exactly the same
that if you go to Jordan dot-com slash
my package dot example dot my servlet
but there is a problem each time of that
you create a java application you also
had to create a file that is called web
dot xml and inside that file you are
going to say ok every time that someone
wants to access jordan comm slash
myservlet you need to ask for username
password but there is a problem there i
told you before that you can call it in
two different ways so what do you think
happened well when the the attacker goes
to jordan come slash myservlet ACP will
ask for username and password when the
attacker goes to jordan comm slash my
package dot example dot my servlet is a
complete authentication bypass you
actually get to invoke every single
method or every single functionality
exposed on that vulnerable web
application one of the web applications
that is vulnerable it will lead you to
execute operating system comments and
also create remote you
sirs inside the sav system but again
don't believe me let me show you first
I'm going to show you that this is
nothing
esoteric this is the entire exploit that
by the way is available on the internet
and it's in Metasploit for example we
are consuming one particular URL and
that's it by invoking a Python script
you can type for example Who am I place
the user that is actually running the
ASAP system you can shut down the ASAP
system you can corrupt the kernel by
deleting binaries you can jump to the
database you can do whatever you want
you can even do something like this any
comment you want you are the owner of
the ASAP system so what that mean well
first of all it means that our theory
was right we suspected that these guys
were compromised by this exploit that by
the way that exploit is five years old
what was the first thing that we need to
do is stop everything that we were doing
and go directly to the customer and say
hey you need to patch this as soon as
possible why because as I mentioned
before the system was still exposed
directly to the Internet it was still
vulnerable they had to apply what is
called is a pin notes the notes that I
give you right there patching as it is a
very controversial topic by the way and
the caveat here is that they need to
restore the isapi system for the changes
to actually take effect perfect so we're
in the right position to understand what
happened and we know now what was the
point of intrusion we need to know ok so
what else happened
well we concluded that yes 100% the
point of intrusion on this file exploit
by analyzing the heuristics of the
attacks we were able to see that at
least over three different human beings
attacking the platform at different
periods of time we were not
able to prove that personal identifying
information was actually retrieve or
stolen and that's exactly why you never
hear about this case they were not
required by law to make it public so
they did not and also we didn't see any
evidence of lateral movement that
occurred chose attack a today's AP
system and then try to start hitting
things on the DMZ or jump to the
Internet so finally the last
misconception that I have for you is the
probability of an SCP cyberattack is low
okay this is another slightly different
to the others the IT security department
were concerned because they have a
security in the past a couple months
before we arrived and they suspected
that the AP systems were actually we're
also compromised in part of this hack
that they had but the supreme straighter
said the opposite they say no you know
what our receipe systems are clean
they're fully patched nothing bad
happening in our systems the ECP
security guys didn't have enough tools
nor the knowledge to actually prove them
wrong or corroborate the theory so they
call us and they say okay Jordan we want
you to do two things here first of all I
want you to depend test because we want
to see how it is to breaking into the
systems and second we want you to do a
forensic analysis this is the time frame
of where we had issues in the past we
want you to try to find evidence that
the SOP systems were actually
compromised as well perfect every time
that I hear that the probability of an
appeaser attack is low I say yes and no
I mean definitely yes if you compare it
with the probabilities of someone
attacking your cell phone or your
workstation but s AP has a particularity
here take a look at the image that I
have prepared for you that is a
vulnerability of 2002 of that all the s
AP systems running Oracle has a database
that by the way is the most common
flavor
worldwide are having except if you are
like the super uber greater kernel of sa
picker and the super uber mega version
of Oracle
you are vulnerable this let me tell you
that 85% of the cases that you sit there
and you try what I'm going to show you
soon
you get compromising the ESP system
database without providing any kind of
username passwords so what is the
problem here
well in s AP there is something that is
called the OBS dollar-sign mode that
basically Oracle trusted someone
somewhere already authenticated the user
it doesn't care who by default when you
start the ASAP system it creates an
operating system user and that operating
system user is mark at this OBS dollar
Simon mechanism that user without
providing any telephone 10th occation
connects to the Oracle database and only
has access to one particular s AP table
is the table is AP user that has a
database user as well and an encrypted
password I know this is kind of
confusing so I prepared this for you the
application server says a I'm the
operating system user without providing
anything to you authenticate me and give
me the content of the ASAP user table
thank you ASAP gets that content
decrypted connects again with the
database user and the password that user
the second user does have full
privileges over the Oracle schema and
again let me do this real quick instead
of believing me I can show you we're
going to attract one database that is
called tl-one so for that in my machine
I created the user till 1 atm
that's it I'm just creating a random
user on my machine and we're going to
use the SQL plus this is the regular
database query utility that you used for
Oracle is actually official for Oracle
and you're going to tie this super super
complicated command that you see there
you do sqlplus / add target one is
sfe system that I have running on my
machine 15:27
is the default port in Oracle in the s
IP war until one is the database that I
want to connect there are many ways to
brute-force this database enter that's
it I'm connected
I never provide username password but I
am connected but I only have access to
this table
sorry I only have access to this table
what we did was reverse engineer the
algorithm that Oracle was using and we
were able to get the password for that
user as well what is called the master
password and once you get the master
password use the SQL plus again and now
you get full access over the s IP
database schema you can steal credit
cards you can do whatever you want for
us as a forensic investigators this is
really bad and we're going to see what
or why
so before that there is a particularity
this authentication mechanism on you can
actually switch it off actually
Oracle recommends it to turn it off and
it's now deprecated but this EP in order
to make it ASAP to work you need to put
it in true if you switch it off it's
even worse because the only way that you
have it to make the SF assistant work is
to have an S ApS are three user with a
hard-coded password ASAP so what you
need to do here is to restrict who can
actually connect to what is called the
listener once we were able to prove that
was really easy to break in we start
analyzing for backdoors on the ASAP
program tables long story short and I
had to trim the demo here in order to
make it on time we start to seen a lot
of backdoors planted inside the
customers NCP system and because of that
we needed to ask a full forensic
investigation or all the ASAP systems
that were in scope we were not able to
tell because of the missing logs if that
bug doors were prior or after the
intrusion that this guys had the only
thing that we know is that the bugger
was injected in them it was transported
to QA and it was transported again to
production can unlike in a legal way
so as I'm running out of time and we're
wrapping up here
what you can expect from a forensic
investigation as a key first of all let
me tell you does as I mentioned it's a
highly complex and difficult discipline
more often than not the odds are not in
your favor more often than not as well
the customer will not have all the
available logs to you that is the main
complication here expect many data
sources and entry points if you are
lucky enough that the customer will have
the logs available for you and because
of that easily basically you might end
up with terabytes of information to
process how that seemed at hand and
hopefully you have a very good hard
drive and the most important in here
under no circumstances when you do a
forensic investigation s AP you can
guarantee
that the system was not compromised you
can do the other way around you can tell
yes oh I can see here because of this
that your system has compromised but
never the other way around
otherwise you will be lying I'm finally
prevent prevent prevent the form these
considerations are the root of all evil
I think we are doing good with time but
thank you and if you have questions
please feel free to us also we'll be in
the conference in case you want to ask
more thank you thank you John we
actually have time for one question
which has been asked is si si P pen test
different from a regular pen test for
example with web applications yes
absolutely
um and normally people ask ok why we
don't see too many hackers actually a
trying attack in sa persistence
rather than workstations or phones well
before you learn how to actually attack
an SI p system you also need to
understand the business side ok why is
ap was created how does it work and once
you had the knowledge then you can start
doing a pen test yes I would say that is
different especially because if you
break something you are breaking a
couple millions as well well thank you
but any more questions ok thank you very
much give Jordan my friend close once
again thank you
[Applause]