thank you very much good morning and
welcome everybody my name is Dean
Kerrigan I'm a partner at Clayton Co
that we're a global law firm I'll be
moderating this morning at the end of
the table we have Patrick Beckett he is
a Queensland manager of Willis Towers
Watson WPW are a global risk consultancy
organization David Gallagher is
representing Liberty international
underwriters they are insurers and David
has been very very heavily engaged and
involved in rolling out cyber policies
solutions to help organizations manage
mitigate their risk and indeed respond
to cyber breaches and incidents when
they arise next to me is my partner
Matthew perk area we've got two lawyers
on the panel this morning so we've got a
lawyer an insurer and a risk consultant
we promise not to be too doom-laden but
there will be some positive things
coming away from this discussion Matthew
in particular has been doing a lot of
work and has a great deal of experience
in privacy and cyber related matters as
Valdemar said please feel free raise
questions on the way through if you have
them we'll try and save a bit of time at
the end if people have questions at the
end but really just to set the scene the
cyber market in Australia has really
taken off over the course of the last 12
to 18 months principally because of the
change in legislation at the beginning
of this year February are the change to
mandatory data breach notification
requirements in our privacy legislation
that's been coming for a long time but
that has very much been I think a focus
a catalyst for debate discussion and
also I guess a prompt for organizations
to focus more closely than was the case
previously in relation to the need to
be prepared for to be able to respond to
data breach incidents without going into
the detail of the legislation too much
it is it is novel legislation it does
require organizations where there has
been a significant data breach to notify
both the subjects of the the data breach
that is the individuals whose
information has been lost has been
stolen or has otherwise been misused as
well as to notify our Australian privacy
Commission Commissioner of the office of
the Australian Information Commissioner
so the net result of that is obviously
to shine a real spotlight on data
breaches give rise to exposure in terms
of legal liability regulated regulatory
investigations and of course
reputational liability to those
organisations which prior to February
this year could really have sailed under
the radar in relation to breaches that
have occurred so that's been a real
catalyst and of course against the
backdrop of the change in the regulatory
regime there is an increasing prevalence
of data at data breaches arising from
attacks cyber attacks simple human error
data being lost and we're not just
talking about digital data here we're
talking about information in any form
whether hard copy written or or indeed
any other form if that is lost stolen or
misused then that could depending on the
circumstances give rise to a data breach
could be notifiable I think another
catalyst driving all of this is the the
regulatory focus from our peak
regulators here in Australia assic our
general corporate and consumer regulator
and opera in the context of the
financial services sector have been very
very clear in
public communications that they expect
the board's the senior management of
organizations at whatever level whatever
size within Australia to be aware of to
take responsibility and be very
proactive in driving change within
organizations to equip those
organizations to be cyber resilient so I
guess the fear at senior management and
executive level within organizations to
do the right thing and be seen to do the
right thing there's also really driven
behavior and we're seeing a real optic
in relation to insurance solutions and
insurance coverage for data breach
exposure we'll talk about that in a bit
more detail but I think just on the
theme of resilience it's clear to me as
a lawyer that although insurance isn't
necessarily going to prevent data
breaches it is very very much a useful
in some cases critical solution in
relation to fixing problems in enabling
organizations to have solutions and
responses to coordinate a response to a
data breach when that happens and we'll
talk about the solutions the
functionality of the products and how
these insurance products can actually
assist organisations when they do face
data breaches and have to respond to
those so just to turn to some of the
issues I've touched on it already but
Patrick and David if you could just
briefly cover off some of the the main
types of cover that are provided in
cyber insurance policies yeah brilliant
we might just flick to the to the next
slide and just to probably cover off
again the point that Dean made given the
the theme of the conference of
resilience I think it's a strong
contention that we'll make today that
that's right insurance is something that
kicks in once those front end kind of
mitigations failed that's the part
insurance plays and it can play a very
significant role for any sized or any
type of entity in building
organizational resilience so we'll go
through a bit now about what a cyber
policy does cover and the benefits it
would confer on an insurer be those
insured persons or an insured
organization and insurers and the
insurance industry breaks it down
generally into kind of two areas what we
call first party costs and third party
costs simply what that means first party
costs are those which would be borne
directly by the organization in trying
to fix or remedy a situation whether
that be a data breach or system internal
systems down or systems down of a
potentially a service provider the
second part is third-party third-party
costs or you can think of those more as
liabilities I guess and that might be
those costs which another third party
funnily enough seeks to seeks to
recompense from you for losses they may
have suffered so you know should you
lose someone's data potentially you may
have claims from those third parties who
may have claims from customers and other
people who are who are Alliant on your
services or those you've given some kind
of express either contractual guarantee
or implied guarantee that you would keep
safe their confidential information or
or material so that's generally how its
classified under for by insurers and
under an insurance policy if you've got
the clicker there those first party
costs is really the the area which they
drive
kind of increase the sale of insurance
policies because this is the real
benefit that insureds feel that they're
getting from a policy so what this
allows generally if you have a breach
that becomes too significant for you to
deal with internally so we're talking
about there are relatively severe events
you get or may have the benefit of of an
extensive list of vendors from a number
of different fields and this has been
kind of a again talked about it many
stages through through the conference to
be able to to move from your what would
be your internal capabilities and bring
in some of these experts I think plays
exactly into that that resilience
element in that having the benefit of
these firms whether they're legal
forensic whatever it may be will most
likely help your firm bounce back to
where it was to a business-as-usual
position much swifter than it could have
on its own merits thanks Patrick could
we just go back to the previous slide
just wanted to point out in that
right-hand column there we've listed a
range of third-party losses there so
cyber insurance policies will typically
have quite extensive cover in this area
and the two big things on that list that
stand out to me are really the privacy
and security liability cover and also
the claims arising from network security
failures there's some other things on
that list there and you sort of think
what have they got to do with cyber
insurance or security related issues
like deformation for example or
infringement of copyright really I think
those things were really added in to
cyber insurance policies to kind of beef
up the cover a little bit and provide a
little bit of extra and that typically
has kind of spread across a number of
competitors in the industry so you're
looking at a privacy and security
liability Patrick's already touched on
that that really I think most
organizations pretty much everyone now
will store some type of
personally i dint identifiable
information or PII at minimum the PII of
employees of the company but that could
extend our a lot further than that we're
tech companies for example often have
extensive databases with PII sometimes
their customers or third-party P I will
be stored on mass and these databases
that's a huge risk if that data gets out
there in the public domain or into the
hands of third parties who shouldn't be
able to access that data and we've had
many examples of that almost daily
around the globe and including in
Australia and you know the Red Cross
Blood Service was one example as being
mentioned here at the conference this
year and the previous year there's no
shortage of examples of that occurring
but also in addition to PIR there's
confidential information so that could
be confidential corporate information
could be trade secrets other
intellectual property can you ensure the
value of intellectual property is a
question we'll get to I think later in
the discussion but really that's that's
the crux that's third party liability
cover but also the the failure of say
you're a third party provided to your
customer you might be providing some IT
services of some sort if your network
were to fail that could have a serious
impact on your customers not all cyber
insurance policies cover that failure to
supply type exposure so need to really
get down into the words insurers refer
to those triggers sometimes there's
wrongful acts so you need to read the
specific words within the insurance
policies to see whether that's covered
if it's not you might want to negotiate
that cover in of course you use a broker
in that process that's a brief overview
thanks Jen so we've seen that there are
definite benefits in terms of having
cover tailored and fashioned for
particular exposures and risks that
arise in the cyber context if you use a
cyber policy as compared to a standard
liability policy or a standard property
policy
if you flip that over though what are
some of the common items that are not
covered by an average and I say average
because there is no such thing as a
standard cyber policy in Australia or
indeed elsewhere but what are the sort
of things David did that aren't
generally covered okay since I've just
meant mentioned intellectual property if
the company had their intellectual
property stolen you know that's the form
of data those losses wouldn't be
recoverable generally under cyber
insurance policies you'd really have to
negotiate some cover there and I've
looked at instances where that's
happened it's a little bit of a
complicated process to put a value on IP
would typically look for that IP to be
valued by a third party say one of the
big accounting firms for example and
make an assessment about around that so
in a complicated area to underwrite and
assess but it's possible cyber insurance
policies don't work always cover
personal injury or property damage
losses so that's an area that's kind of
developing currently and there are
covers being negotiated in sometimes sub
limits if you look at broader insurance
programs there might be covered
elsewhere in the program so as an
underwriter I would take that into
account and factor in what cover already
exists the broker might be able to might
be aiming to fill in that gap within the
in cyber insurance policy as opposed to
building up a say a property program or
adding the cover in there where it
doesn't exist but the certain other
things that really stand out you think
failure of telcos or utility providers
such as you know the electricity
providers satellite failure those type
of things generally their exclusions and
cyber policies for those we refer them
as systemic exposures from an insurance
company's point of view it's it would be
an absolute disaster if we gave cover
and say Telstra went out and if
to 75% of our cyber insurance portfolio
it would potentially blow up our
insurance company so we need to control
that exposure what we do cover though is
things generally inside our insurance
control so you think there's a failure
the electricity supply doesn't trigger
the policy but if the failure occurs
within the Insurance Power Board and
within their their hardware or their
systems then yes potentially that that
could trigger the policy there's a few
other things if you go through
exclusions you can see some fairly
standard things and they're war and
terrorism is another big one to point
out policies these days do provide right
backs for cyber terrorism so you know
actions of hacktivists sometimes
state-sponsored threats and that type of
thing but again you've got to get down
to the words and the policy and get some
advice around that because it's a great
deal of variation and the wedding's out
there yeah we probably shouldn't let the
under audit talk about the exclusions on
the policy they're the only ones to get
me excited about that they could be here
all day but I think two things to point
out quite quickly is that I think
there's almost a bit of a misnomer
especially at the moment that's rather
there are no standard insurance policies
in the market at the moment but at the
at the top end for the majority of
quality insurers who are providing a
cyber insurance product they do provide
largely the same thing you know largely
the same covers they are written in
different ways in certain parts and you
should take advice about that but I have
confidence in most of the products in
the market that they did there and I
written appropriately I think there's
more difference and what you should be
asking in many cases is okay well what
is this insure done previously what's
their experience in this field and you
know what have they been like in paying
claims previously I think you know
there's a lot of people pushing into
this market putting their hand up and a
lot of wordings are cut and pasted mrs.
Howard
it's Market Market works they are tend
to borrow good ideas and bad ideas from
from each other quite frequently so that
the coverage is is largely there I think
there's a few other questions if you're
assessing and insurer that could be
asked the other thing that generally a
number of clients sometimes get a bit
confused about isn't covered by cyber
policy is direct financial loss so
that's money that you lose we've heard a
few examples throughout the conference
about kind of payment instruction fraud
in that type of thing if you're sent a
dodgy invoice and you pay out to someone
you weren't meant to you know a million
bucks ten million bucks whatever it is
that loss of money would not be covered
under a cyber policy you would need a
specific crime policy so a lot of
clients think well you know I lost money
due to some kind of nefarious computer
act that must be covered under the cyber
policy but no that's a kind of common
pitfall to make sure that your crime
policy is is up-to-date as well
okay thanks gents we've seen from the
work that we've done that it's it's
almost impossible to ensure that an
organization whatever its size is never
going to experience a data breach even
the best run best governed most
resilient organizations with very very
strong organizational capability and
systems and processes are subject to
these exposures in that situation when
things do go wrong and somebody an
organization finds themself having under
the new legislation to notify the data
breach Matthew what are the main legal
issues that organizations and businesses
need to be considering at that's but
that point in time I think the role of a
lawyer in responding to a
in in to a cyber breach is a bit more
nuanced than it often is and then in
legal experience lawyers are often
brought in initially as a breach
response coordinator effectively which
is a little outside of the normal legal
process where we assist in insured in in
the vendors they need to solve the
problems whether they're forensic
whether they're in credit monitoring or
whether it's in PR in a number of areas
the other aspect of what we do in that
is more purely legal and it really
focuses probably more on the sort of
third-party claims in the regulatory
environment one of the first things we
would need to do is assess you know the
nature of the insured and the
organization involved and where it fits
within a fairly complex regulatory
structure some of you I recognize from a
workshop around earlier in the
conference where we looked quite
specifically at the legislation that
applied at a state level and federal
level and also globally the can impact
an organization when they suffer a data
breach and potential loss of other of
their clients data that's one of the
first things we would look at whether
what obligations arise in the course of
responding to those regulatory
obligations the very fact of a data
breach and the need to notify could
result in the regulator launching an
investigation into the organization and
having a look at its compliance with
privacy principles and of course
organizations can be exposed to party
claims even potentially a class action
if for example or medical data or other
data was lost in the class could be
formed in that particular environment
obviously the engagement of employer at
an early stage helps to provide the sort
of privilege you know should it later
become a litigate
issue so it's really in that broad range
of areas would be involved thanks
Matthew and the experience is that
getting that right that response to the
that the breach and the loss of data
getting right early is absolutely
critical in terms of making sure that a
bad situation doesn't run away with an
organization and and become a whole lot
worse and that's where really some of
the functionality and the provisions of
the insurance policies the ability to
deploy teams to assist the insurance
organizations managed through those
difficult situations is a is a key and
very important part of the the cyber
policy cover that's available let's look
a little bit forward now in terms of how
things are developing it is still a
developing market in Australia for cyber
cover there are no standard wordings
there's no standard terms and conditions
maybe I'll oppose this one to you David
what what sort of expansion in the cover
the benefits to insured's
starting to emerge in the local
Australian cyber insurance market okay
that's a great question because this
whole area of innovation in cyber
insurance policies is really driven by I
mean it's competition the lot of
insurers out there there they will try
to differentiate themselves and come up
with different extensions and add-ons to
the cover by endorsement and so on one
of the big areas on point too is
reputation or harm cover and what people
usually think about reputational harm
it's spending you know there's PR costs
and those type of things once a breach
has occurred or some type of cyber
incident but true reputational harm
Congress a lot more meaty than there
it's actually measuring the lost
business an organization has suffered as
a result of a cyber event and how do you
do that well there's a bit of forensics
involved and measuring
the loss of income and in particular the
net income or profit as a result of a
certain cyber event occurring so you can
do that by looking at financials for the
previous 12 months the projections and
organization had and then working out
where the dip occurred after the network
outage or privacy breach or other cyber
event occurred so you need to get down
into the nitty-gritty and look at the
financial results sometimes it it can be
quite tricky if you're dealing with
organization that has thousands of
customers you may need to measure that
dip over time and that you might have
you know three or four percent
impairment to that net profit where
you're dealing with organizations that
have certain key clients maybe three
maybe one of those leaves throughout the
year as a result of the cyber event they
lose trust they lose faith in the
organization and decide they're going to
go elsewhere and it may be very obvious
in those cases what the reason was for
them leaving so that's one area there's
there's a lot of activity and failure to
suppliers another one I can think of
say now tricity Grid they may have
certain key customers that you know bhp
and others for example that rely on them
for their industrial processes so if the
electricity grid were responsible for an
outage there may be contractual terms
where they may need to be some type of
reimbursement so do cyber policies
provide this cover as standard
absolutely not that's an area that is
developing i think patrick already
mentioned and touched on crime and
social engineering so crime is really
the traditional crime policies cover
stolen funds or misdirected funds
sometimes and money so cyber policies
have really focused on data
and the cost of reconstituting data
that's been damaged or deleted they
haven't really provided that cover for
theft of money and funds but we're
starting to see low sub limits creep in
for some of those types of cover and I
think Patrick might have more to add on
this point as well being a broken yeah
thanks a couple of things there I think
pure reputational harm cover is
something the insurance market has been
kind of working on for a number of years
because essentially if you ask a company
what's your top three assets their
reputation is generally up there
however I would suggest to any of our
clients you know again back to this
resilience piece the insurance policy
itself is the best thing you can put in
place to protect your reputation because
that's the thing that's going to allow
you to bounce back to that business as
usual state as quick as possible and
really that's how you protect your your
reputation if you have an issue if you
have a a if you have whether it's a
breach or a systems down that occurs and
you're able to remedy it rectify it and
be back to where you were in a short
period of time well that's going to do
wonders for your reputation you know
should it be something that's handled
poorly and fluffed and it drags out
forever and a day well that's going to
do your reputation no end of harm so I
think the policy itself is fantastic
reputational protection and with that
kind of future gazing on what may come
into policies I think there's some
really good parts of the policy that are
underappreciated by a lot of clients and
insureds at the moment and the one I
pick out first and foremost is business
interruption insurance interruption
cover so what Dad will come in for and
it you can get it in a in a manner
that's extremely broad as well so the
insurance policy will pay out for your
loss of profits or increased cost of
working should you know a service
provider of yours go down meaning that
your system is going to go down and your
business can't operate which i think is
you know somewhat crazy but insurers
that are more than happy to to provide
this cover so you know on a worse case
if
Amazon Web Services went down for a week
and a half and you know all the
associated businesses who rely on that
service went down because of that as
well
essentially the insurance policies are
paying out for you for your loss of
profits and increased cost of working
during that week and a half now think
that potentially in the future will
cause some issue for insurers but at the
moment they're offering their coverage
so I'd suggest to my clients quite
strongly that you are that you take it
up thanks Patrick I mean it sounds like
the insurance market as a whole is
listening to responding to and expanding
cover having regard to their
ever-changing threats of the the data in
the cyber landscape from your
perspective as an adviser to buyers of
insurance is there anything you know
high on your wish list
are there any gaps in the cover of
ailable that the insurance market is
providing that you think need to be
plugged to be honest no I think I think
the market is quite buoyant and advise
my clients quite confidently that you
know the coverage is that is that there
at the moment is extremely broad and
it's written in a way that should cover
any you know most scenarios that that
face companies that buy the protection I
think we talk a lot about you know data
breaches and whatever else which don't
apply to many of the companies we deal
with that business interruption piece is
something which is applicable to
essentially every company so I think
the coverage due to the competitiveness
of the market is in a very good place
you know I hope that covering my wish
would be I hope that coverage does stay
in place I think once we see a few
claims especially a few large ones is
really the likely thing is some of that
coverage might start to be curtailed but
we're not there yet so hopefully not
anytime soon sure thank you that's
helpful the entry into an insurance
policy whether it's a cyber policy or
any other policy is is a contract like
any other contract and what that
requires is a willing buyer and a
willing seller I pose this question to
both of you David first I mean what
should organizations be doing when they
are looking to take out cyber cover and
to satisfy you and convince insurers
that they are a good risk for the
insurers to be issuing policies to to
get the best deal really is companies
that impressed with this cyber maturity
are the ones that we prefer to partner
with we have a whole range of insureds
out there are various stages of
progression in terms of the maturity
terms kind of a tailored sometimes a bit
more restrictive or perhaps higher
excesses lower limits for those that
aren't quite there yet but those that
have taken steps to go down the track
perhaps engage third party consultants
to help them with that will yeah
definitely from an adjoining perspective
we would favor those that can prove that
they're at a certain standard it's it's
a difficult thing to have the right
cyber insurances really the challenge
has always been to get the right
information and I think when we launched
six years ago now it was very difficult
to get any information sometimes we were
quoting risk based off external
information sometimes a professional
indemnity proposal form
that didn't really allow us to look
under the bonnet and see some of the
systems and procedures that were in
place within a company that we're about
measuring the amount of data that a
company holds what type of data that is
and then the security and privacy
protections around that data but also
there's the network resilience side and
assessing what the impact could be
doesn't network outage for various time
periods what is the business impact what
controls does an organization have a
place to mitigate those type of network
issues so there's many aspects to
underwriting and it's a very fluid thing
and it depends on the size of the
company the industry the company is in
so as I dried as there's no set template
we do have a proposal form that
certainly assists us begin that process
but ideally the risk I look at like to
meet our clients and have discussions
with key people in those organizations
and a lot of that information comes out
it's not just taking a box into a
proposal form we can see the people are
on top of issues that sometimes from
penetration tests we can see not
necessarily the results of those
penetration tests because those can be
highly confidential but to know that our
proposes have a risk-based approach
approach to addressing those issues that
come out of penetration tests you know
that that impresses us too so this
really is hard to encompass like in a
30-second kind of sound bite as to what
we're looking for but there is a really
involved process especially for those at
the larger end of the scale more SME
risks it's a little bit more
straightforward and we can kind of look
at basic proposal forms there sure
thanks David so I think that the key
point is it's communication transparency
and disclosure before I flick to Patrick
I think we've got a very topical
question from the floor at which we
might interject with well of actually
have two or three questions which start
to roll into that and actually ask
further info so related to that is there
any framework or policy within the
providers to do discounting based on
either organizational professional
memberships chips to organizations like
ah cert or holding things like he
compliance or actual other third party
audit compliance assessment and
validation results like a data center
doing what does it say 16 or some of the
other certification proposals that's
kind of one of the major parts no
problem so as it's been touched I won't
go over too much David talked about the
top out of town and Dean is certainly
right it's about communication at the
smaller end of town if you're an
organization with less than you know say
50 mil in revenue I can get you a very
good insurance policy based on you know
literally no information at all
essentially your revenue your employee
numbers and your business name and
that's because insurers of that end of
the market can't kind of write each
individual small account they assume
everyone's that are pretty low standard
in terms of the security and everything
else and and try and bigger build a big
enough pool to deal with the issues that
that arise but that's right it's about
telling a story so you know many
companies that are investing really
heavily in security and infrastructure
and if you're a site so you're involved
in security within an organization if
you haven't already been tapped on the
shoulder
I suggest you you might be dragged into
the process of not just filling in a
proposal form but meeting with insurers
and telling that story about the work
you're doing internally because the
proposal forms generally to be quite
frank that never rubbish I mean we get
pretty poor feedback from a lot of
security put persons who are filling
them out because you know you're doing
quite diligent and detailed work and
you're getting asked yes/no questions or
you know on how to kind of uh how to
articulate that so that's a problem and
you know we need to kind of elevate and
we do for our clients elevate them above
that proposal form if you're a medium or
larger entity and have you know those
discussions with key personnel and the
owner eyes and just kind of responding
the question about standards absolutely
that does have an impact on the way we
assess and price risk whether it's nest
or ISO 27001 PCI compliance absolutely
we look for those things some companies
that have gone through ISO 27001 we know
that you know
annually it's a arduous process
sometimes if the scope is across a
business so that definitely impress us
and I will put those types organizations
in their top quartile not everyone's
there in Australia at the moment even
with PCI compliance that it's amazing
some of the big retailers they're partly
hampered by legacy systems and they
won't get the full compliance they might
be 85 percent of the way there but they
still maybe a number of years away from
achieving that and that definitely
impacts us and that PCI fines and
penalties could be imposed at any point
in time if they're not compliant so yeah
that does impact the cover we provide as
well so obviously related to all of this
given you actually want your clients to
be secure and you want to lower your
risk of having to pay out as part of the
premiums you're actually considering
bundling services to actually help them
that will provide them guidance and
support to actually help them improve
their current posture and ability to
lower their own premiums mitigate your
risk of their risk and obviously provide
a better service for everybody
I don't think we're seeing that enough
so that's done on a number of other
policies but in other realms of
insurance you know just say you pay a
premium of $100,000 a year you know
often an insurer will allow you to take
10% of that premium and spend it on
whatever risk mitigation techniques that
you may want to employ whether it's pen
testing or or other external services
that you can then demonstrate to the
insurer that we're in this together
we're improving our risk and then ensure
happy to put some of that premium
towards it so you're working in
partnership together unfortunately we're
probably not there with a lot of
insurers yet but that's something we
hope increases increases over time
we do have a risk assessment process
that we we can you know access and it's
a third-party provider but that third
party they're actually based in London
they have an enormous amount of data
across industries so the value in using
them the results can really be assessed
to the peers for an organization in
particular industry so we have run these
surveys and it's it gives a great
insight we run them across twelve
different security domains these
controls are reviewed with respect to
NIST and a whole range of other
standards as well so it's something
we've tailored to the risk that we're
underwriting rather than being a
holistic risk assessment the insured by
use but there's certainly great
recommendations that come out of that
process and our insureds have where
these have been run build those
improvements into their risk management
process so it's something we do and
something I'm working on locally as well
he felt that capability here thanks
David
we're nearly out of time there was just
one question I wanted to pose to Matthew
in closing slightly changing tack and
that is we've spoken all all about the
pure mandatory breach notification
issues challenges and I guess
opportunities that come out of that but
if we think about the flow-on
consequences of that Matthew
particularly for for vendors what do you
think are some of the issues and the the
implications of the new breach
notification regime for liability IT
liability for vendors I think IT
liabilities been a fairly benign market
in Australia I mean many professionals
regularly get sued
okay.what ducking while they're doing
that I don't know maybe I don't know
anyway I'll press on and the bottom line
I think we'll find is that um IT
suppliers are going to be more in focus
in the future
it's they've been one of those
professional groups that have escaped a
lot of attention except in some rather
large cases I think what we will see
with mandatory notification is more
litigation brought against organizations
that have been breached but also a
greater focus within those organizations
of their cybersecurity and their
reliance upon external vendors and I
think they're going to become more keen
on recovering against those vendors for
their losses they've suffered I think we
can expect and David can probably speak
to this more accurately than I can but I
would anticipate that insurers who have
paid out under cyber policies
particularly those first party losses
that can be really quite significant in
notification of notifications to to
people whose data has been lost
the price associated with that can be
far more significant that you might
expect I would anticipate they'll be
looking to recover those losses against
the third parties who were potentially
responsible for either inadequate
protection inadequate patching you know
you can there's a whole range of
potential litigation exposures that
could arise thanks Matthew
we'll wrap up there if anyone does have
any burning questions then we'll be
outside so please come and collar us but
if you join me in thanking the panel
thank you gents
[Applause]