hello everyone thanks for coming along
to my talk
yeah they accidentally let it dive into
an info SEC conference so you're about
to get a talk from a dev on info SEC so
Who am I developer background head of
security at the Bureau of Meteorology
so what is that role mean well it's a
bit of I'm gonna call it a somewhat
experimental role it's focused on fairly
obviously making sure that the
development process has more secure
outcomes that's not a necessarily a role
that every organisation has it might be
something that just a general senior
manager a team manager has or is managed
through feedback from a security group
so it's a little bit of its own own
experiment in whether or not we can make
improvements to the way we we build our
internal software we've certainly got a
lot fairly large in-house build at the
bureau so unlike some places which might
be more focused on say procurement based
activities to obtain their software
we've got a fairly large in-house build
which also means that the feedback loop
between finding an issue and correcting
it can be fairly tight we don't
necessarily need to negotiate with a
vendor around obtaining in your release
of a piece of software it's something we
can do or could do through a continuous
integration / continuous deployment
model if we have all of the right
feedback loops in place it's also as our
agency so I've said we've got a
significant dev capability we also have
a lot of science so we have we have many
scientists in our organization basically
what a scientist does all day long is
sit in front of a computer type and
computer code comes out but they're very
clear that they're scientists not
developers yet nonetheless something we
still have to give some due care and
attention to the security of that
activity and then we're also an
operational agency so when we're talking
about our company's risks they're
definitely not just IT risks the risk
profile of the bureau we've got some
fairly significant public facing
services so when when we're lining up
our cyber security risk as an
organization they're lined up against
services which can in some cases go all
the way through to loss of life and
fairly substantial economic impact
so our risk management frameworks have
to encompass both the business risks in
a fairly significant way as well as
cybersecurity risks I'm trying not to
make assumptions about the pre-existing
knowledge of the audience it was really
hard for me to work out how to give a
tightly focused presentation that made
sense and yet was going to appeal to a
tolerably fairly general audience as
well so I might just do a quick round
the room just so that the audience
itself can get an understanding of who
else is here not not going to take too
long just really quick so who's been a
software developer before hands up bro
okay all right it's my team that showed
up that's cool who has not been a
software developer and has been in an
ops environment okay maybe a third and
who's actively involved in inside pen
testing or red teaming or something like
that smaller amount okay
so that'll help me work out how to pitch
my slide so this is what I thought about
who the audience was going to be so
everyone security interested I'm
security interested motivated enough to
get to a conference so I can assume a
certain amount of pre-existing knowledge
broad variety of roles I think there
might be a few fewer managers than I'd
imagined probably slightly higher up on
the hands-on security professionals and
and frankly more devs than I'd expected
as well because when I was looking at
what a cert was everything's backwards
to my way of thinking everything is
incident backwards and everything I do
is build forwards so we've got to work
out how to stitch up incident backwards
with build forwards and that's a lot of
what I'm trying to talk about today so
who do I want to reach anyone who just
need to starter on securing their build
pipeline I don't really mean the
infrastructure hardening of your build
pipeline that's also important but I
feel like that's very much just that's
that's the job of a traditional
infrastructure team I'm talking about
the output code that a development
process produces and the hardening and
security of that code that is produced
as well as the systems if we happen to
have any product vendors in the in the
room looking for bright new ideas I've
got a few things that I'd love if you'd
build for me people who want to be part
of a secure dev can
there's really good dev communities
there's really good infoset communities
secure dev is still a little format
formative I think and anyone who wants
to directly contribute to improved
scanning tools some of the ideas might
be a bit old hat I was quite worried
that talking about secure CI SEC DevOps
some of the concepts how we could take
it further might be a bit old hat for
this audience so I went searching for
something to appease my concerns
I found this five hours ago coming out
of one of the latest reports from black
duck yeah so apparently it can take six
years to steer a disclosure of an open
source vulnerability in a commercial
product through the pipeline so okay
maybe it's not so maybe it's still a
problem
and how much open source is actually in
our products again coming from the same
report like fair bit you know 30 to 70
percent a fair chunk of our commercial
products or open source code so okay I
feel like I'm a little more comfortable
and a little more in-home now I'm also
really just talking I'm well aware this
is only one piece of a puzzle one thing
that something I really don't want to do
is say somehow we've thought of the
answer to all the problems
it's just what securing your dev
lifecycles really just one piece of the
puzzle okay
a few things we're not talking about
decommissioning organizational decisions
architecture deliberately insecure
configurations things like that not
really focusing on that not really
focusing on language choice and language
support I've got opinions about them but
this talk doesn't pertain to those or
operating system-level patch management
that's that's also a thing but I'm
really here talking about product level
or application level vulnerability
management okay
so pieces of the build puzzle so if you
imagine you turn up in a new company
you've got a new job say everything's
new certain certain things you're going
to find you're just kind of inherent you
show up there's a culture that's in
place there's a level of maturity and
knowledge there's a let that there's
existing products with existing
libraries and dependencies an existing
attitude towards quality during
development and the code base that
happens to be
and if you show up as a new manager or
move into a new role you're going to
inherit a lot of things so we're gonna
have to deal with that certain things
will just kind of happen business is
usual part of the day job with any luck
continuous integration as part of the
day job code reviews should be part of
the day job linters checkers static
analysis unit testing security oriented
unit testing some security automated
analysis those things aren't but should
be pretty much expected but you'll still
find a pretty wide variety of whether or
not this is in place within existing
teams if I look at some of my previous
experiences in various teams definitely
some of them have been a lot more
security aware than others and in I
really discovered a lot of the security
objectives when I moved to a more
security aware team and it was quite an
eye-opener for me I've never got paid
particularly to do it I'm not saying
people don't care about security but as
a a team that has focused on
functionality there are a lot of
concepts that just might not be a
priority for your group and when we're
thinking about supply chains your
organization might be selling a security
oriented product you might be in a
security oriented area you might be
selling to security aware customers but
it's not going to be true for all of
your up streams if you go back to that
ratio of code coming in from open source
again no criticism on open source but
not every single one of those people is
going to be working in a security aware
team so even though describing best
practice and defining it might be a
little old hat achieving it isn't
quality nearly never goes out of style
then we have what I call discrete
activities so these are things like
fuzzing dynamic analysis pen testing
dealing with code rot and patching if
it's not already part of the day job
though they'll come up they'll be
organized at the end of a project or as
part of a gate or because something
happened so they'll be more of a
discrete activity and in in our in many
cases I'd say penetration testing falls
into that discrete activity category it
might be organized by an ops team or
security team around a piece of
infrastructure rather than an app and it
may or may not be that every app or
every library or every piece of your
supply chain is necessary
you gonna get hit by that if it's not
part of your standard build pipeline so
what does all of that mean for for
InfoSec so I mean broadly we're all
talking about cost and risk I'm not
gonna spend very long on cost and risk
because I'm realized it's fairly dull
but it's nonetheless true so when
someone brings in a penetration testing
team they want to bring in the attacker
mindset and the attacker behaviour so
that they can validate that what they've
done is okay some people will think it
is the actual assurance so if you've
brought I've heard it described if you
if you get five painters and you say
paint me a blue dog you get five blue
dogs they'll all be completely different
the same thing is true of a pen testing
exercise there are certain commonalities
but it's a creative process and because
it's a creative process people may well
find different paths to achieve to
finding vulnerabilities and achieving
their objectives as a result I've always
seen penetration testing far more as a
validation exercise then as the actual
assurance exercise it can provide you if
you have an infinite number of
penetration testers you know a team of a
hundred of them just sitting there
penetration testing after every commit
fine then it's your assurance if you
have it doing shall we say a random
sampling of your work it's validation
it's not actual assurance so what are we
talking about so cost cost of
penetration testing in that kind of
comprehensive way I've just described as
unrealistic cost of development is
generally you can have more developers
than pen testers so you have an uneven
an uneven distribution of you've got new
code versus validated code the best you
can achieve is a sampling of the code
that you've produced as a rule or your
infrastructure yes it'll tell you how
vulnerable you are to the most depending
on how much you pay for your pen tester
somewhere between the most obvious and
the medium obvious and the very
significant issues that you're still
vulnerable to but how effective is that
cost and how does it relate to the the
costs and benefits that a genuine
attacker is going to be facing so back
in a past life I did a whole bunch of
economics which I enjoyed because it
provided me a lot of conceptual models
so what we're really balancing is the
value of our system operation
up against the value of a campaign to an
attacker and the cost of our development
versus the cost of their exploit
development they're the kind of
analogous components and what we're
trying to do is increase how much we're
able to produce but in terms of the
security outcomes lower our security
costs so that it's cheaper for us to
find fix and secure our systems than it
is for someone else to develop and
exploit against them whether that's at
the at the product level or the
infrastructure level one of the other
things when a highlight is something
called opportunity cost so that's this
thing down in the bottom right there
called loss if discovered so that means
you know you've lost your zero day
someone's found a bug they've got in you
find it and you fix it quickly you
radically reduce the value to the
attacker of that exploit so if you can
tighten up your product lifecycle you
can reduce the value to an attacker of
that exploit that that make may be cold
comfort if you've already been exploited
but if you can establish your reputation
as a group team or product that is on
the money when it comes to finding and
fixing these things both in terms of
your CVE response but also in terms of
benchmarking your software quality
people are going to go to the next guy
okay they're going to look to they're
going to look to the next person so very
quick review of supply and demand this
is another way of thinking about the
same thing so in this particular diagram
it's a very basic supply demand diagram
don't get too focused on this is a
conceptual model don't get too focused
on the precise meanings here but what
I've got here is so demand here is the
demand for exploited systems now that
you might think of that as from an
attacker perspective how valuable are
they how much effort are people putting
into it and how many of them are you
producing is a software organization
everyone it is to some degree vulnerable
I think that it is entirely reasonable
to talk as a group of adults about the
fact that well when you read the papers
and you look out there it is a matter of
risk not of certainty so the more
systems we produce you know with a
particular vulnerability rate you know
sort of level well we're increasing the
potential supply of vulnerable systems
people are as far as I can tell
putting more effort and paying more
money into X
avoiding these systems people are also
putting more money and more effort into
securing these systems and the
interesting thing about InfoSec is you
win on both parts of that demand and
supply curve in terms of whether your
skills at a month are in demand
so it's a very comfy place to be from a
career perspective so our objective
really is to reduce the supply of from a
developer perspective reduced that
supply of vulnerable systems and to me
that means we've really got to reduce
the cost because this is a cost and risk
unnatural bedfellows okay so that's my
basic pitch how do we do it shift left
okay I'm gonna try to get through I
promised a few things in my abstract if
you know if you like me I'm not really
sure you sitting there remembering my
full abstract I promised a few things I
promised some new thinking I haven't
really given you any yet I've given you
a kind of exposition of what I consider
best practice I promised you some
machine learning that will come right at
the end and just a little quick sort of
you know smoke and mirrors show right at
the end and I promised you a new way of
looking at these so as the as an
operational agency that produces its own
own code I'm less focused on our
products than I am is on our holistic
code base I'm more focused on what is
our fleet of application developers
doing and how's our central or or
multiple how's our overall portfolio of
code base going I'm less worried about
whether you know just Microsoft Word is
a good product if I'm selling Microsoft
Word or just you know you know just a
particular product is a good I'm not
trying to secure products I'm trying to
secure an organization and I'm trying to
improve the outcomes of it so if you're
in an organization with a dev function
can you answer for yourself does anybody
know what the indicators of quality are
for your organization as a whole well
and and if you if you can't the answer
is why we have a head of security role
so I'm focused on looking at where all
those scripts that are that are lying
about the place checked into some github
repo some get repo locally somewhere
where are all of your 20 teams you know
how are they all doing
you know forget about that product that
we've done that all the penetration
testing and the hardening and put all
the best devs on and put all the leads
on and put all the effort on and what
about those you know 200 lines of PHP
someone wrote five years ago that's
still hanging around somewhere inside
the network onion so you know a few a
few basic assumptions here the later
something is done typically the more
expensive it is to fix I realized that
taken to the extreme that makes for one
heck of a first day on a new project
something always has to come later right
but with security particularly with
security automation it's possible to
roll in all of the positive feedback
loops on day one of development and
essentially not a significant cost if
you try to run that either if you've
never run those tools as part of a
development process like super waterfall
no standardization on tools you know for
example and and it all comes out in the
pen testing report at the end you're
gonna have a devil of a job cleaning all
of that stuff up there is a large
category of problems that you can just
totally avoid by turning this stuff on
right at the beginning in terms of
security I so if anyone's not doing it
it can be hard to achieve with teams and
there's cultural change and you've got
to pick products and you got to work out
if you know there's difficulty to it but
it's the right answer as far as I'm
concerned the more something can be
picked up automatically fewer mistakes
will pass through software development
is a refinery process tools matter tools
drive culture as well as learning and
efficiency so yes it's easy to look at
these tools and we will a bit later and
go oh my goodness look at all of those
things they didn't pick up but the
feedback loop they provide is invaluable
so if you can provide even there's both
the technical coverage but then there's
the cultural value of having every
developer have this feedback loop
sitting in front of them as part of
their dev lifecycle so CI tools drive
culture humans and computers have
different failure modes computers are
really good at not getting bored they
will comfortably check all of your
Comeau code every commit no problem not
not an issue for a computer humans will
get bored okay they're more creative
they can change strategy they
they can formulate a more complex you
can work out how issues would relate to
each other to form a more complex
exploit but they get bored okay
computers don't get bored licensing
again I don't know if any vendors are in
the room but freemium is really the
preferred licensing model if we think
about not just this take everything I
just said about organizations and just
go well let's just talk about the like
the whole community like you know me the
people I bought software from the people
I'm giving them to someone building some
products off my services you know that
doesnõt open-source things that might be
in this thing you go all of them if we
can get the basic tools consistent and
freely available even if the more
advanced capabilities that come from a
commercial vendor are pay to add if we
can uplift the entirety that's probably
secured us more than any you know more
than just securing ourselves you know we
don't want to build well it's great to
live in a fortress if you can afford a
fortress we don't want to live in a
world of fortresses with bandits roaming
the highways we want to try to do our
best to provide ease of adoption to
security uplift to our development to
our development supply chain okay so
let's talk a little bit now so yes so
the new thinking in that is the
organizational holistic approach in
terms of managing all code as opposed to
a product oriented view let's talk a
little bit about the technical side now
so the actual weaknesses that lead to
the lead to these CVS so when I started
CVS were kind of a mystery to me there
were these amazing things that were the
gold stars of being a pen tester okay
and you know I'm like wow these people
can just like you know they can
decompile a thing and they can read
assembly and find it and you know get in
there and they've really gee that's
that's an amazing work and then I
realized well what they were doing was
just finding bugs well I can find bugs
okay I found my common ground my main
issue is more that I've found million
bugs you know if you go well penetration
testers are amazing in the completed
product if you can imagine how many just
like kind of like you know knucklehead
can't believe I didn't think of it bugs
you fix during a development
lifecycle like you know you really need
to understand there is a tremendous
category of bugs that get fixed before
it becomes a product so so bugs are our
home turf for me in fact so this is top
25 software is you know now little dry
little academic okay so you know bad
sequel injection you know really still
okay fine it's still a thing
okay let's go through a few of these
other ones uncontrolled format strings
buffer overflows apparently still a
thing you know dangerous download of
code without integrity check these
things are not rocket science you know
none of these things are breathtakingly
complicated but they are complicated
enough for teams of time for humans who
aren't focused on security to let slip
through and a lot of them are fairly
straightforward you know they're
straightforward to talk about they're
straightforward to find but they're not
straightforward to find all of every
time and give feedback to developers who
might not be aware of them and their
managers and their organizations so the
challenge I think is is how do we
actually genuinely uplift something like
an organization rather than just an
individual how do we make sure that your
next round of pentesting reports don't
well we fixed the five you know the five
horrible terrifying ones they found and
we gave it to the team and then they put
it on a shelf because they got moved on
to the next feature and then eventually
the manager moved on and now the new
manager has a document somewhere on
their shelf okay how do how do we fix
how do we fix that problem and the
answer is is you have to bake it in you
have to bake this stuff in so I don't
want a pen testing report I want
automated tools from my pen testers I
want rules coming back from my
penetration testing that I can bake
straight into my software engineering
processes so that I know that we do that
thing every single time now that's not
going to be possible for everything
obviously typically you know
particularly system configurations and
so forth but there's more that we can
get from the relationship between
software engineering and penetrate
testing than we're getting now and
there's more that we can get out of our
build systems than we're getting now
okay
so old hat so this would be a fairly
well agreed uncontroversial
uncontroversial developers view of what
you can actually detect with static
analysis tools so this is pitching to
the people in the audience who may not
be at the point of having sort of picked
all this stuff up yet I assure you it's
worth doing it'll take a little while to
get your devs on board many of you will
will genuinely find this a bit old hat
but let's talk about some things that
can be can be picked up hard-coded
passwords redundant code so let's
imagine you've got a CV you're managing
a product which just put my product
manager hat on there's a CV e in it you
fix that ten lines of code or hundred
lines of code how do you know that those
same lines of code aren't somewhere else
in your 500 thousand lines of code okay
how do you know that someone hasn't copy
pasted that you know forget library
dependencies and beautiful well-managed
things how do you know that someone
didn't just copy paste that into
something and send put adjust up on you
know put adjust up on the web somewhere
and go hey download this it does it one
of your other devs put it in some other
product how do you go find that stuff
you know you actually need to get back
to the source code level you can't just
deal with it at a CVA level linters and
syntax checkers people think that that
is not amazingly relevant to security
but what it does is it simplifies the
journey so like basic things like
regular expressive expression searching
works well if the code has a consistent
naming strategy it works poorly
otherwise so if you need to global find
where a particular CV set of source code
is that's going to be an easier job if
everything's nice and consistent and
easy to read and easy to look at so as
you try to connect back the fix to
something that's genuinely going to
provide you hardening beyond the neck
CVE this stuff starts to become more
relevant as you give it to a new dev
it's easy to get someone behind an
automated tool if the automated tool has
a simpler job to deal with because every
nice and well organized so that can be
picked up unused code dead code branches
you can't reach etc etc that's all worth
turning off whenever I read the the you
know the I don't know top essential for
top 894 things whatever it is one of
them is you know turn off on required
functionality and every time I hear that
I hear I've got to find all the dead
code I've got to find all those code
branches which weren't designed to be
hit so I never tested them but if
someone can call that function that's
actually still there how do I find all
that stuff so well you can find it it's
actually not that hard you get decent
testing you run it through the rig
you'll get a nice report semi-automated
security testing and then there's can
pick up you know enumeration of cert so
between semi automated and manual we're
moving now into the world of today's
penetration testing as I understand it I
think I've been really clear I'm a dev
and I don't understand penetration
testing I'm not one of one of they've
all said over here so that one of you
guys I don't know how they must all be
in the same Club or something I'm not
sure but I'm not trying to speak from
that perspective I'm trying to speak
from the developer perspective as I
understand it that you know that that
moves very much into the world of
traditional security testing or
penetration testing okay great so we've
got all of that if you've got all of
that you're in a really good state to be
ready to take advantage of the next
round of technical innovation which i
think will be coming soon let's just
talk a little bit about existing tools
commercial and open source like some of
their shortcomings so this is this is
moving into what's next what is the next
generation the next innovation so
problems
okay center of the universe tools so I
understand you've got a nice product
probably it's got a legacy of its own
and it got built in a time when people
didn't have Travis CI and Jenkins and
get lab CI and X unit reporting and all
of these beautiful things so you had to
build some kind of information center of
your own but and this is true of some
open source tools as well it's not a
universal criticism the output formats
are all different and nothing written
you know that not necessarily a nice
conceit coherent one to five severity
scale on the
things which is consistent by tools but
anything that thinks it's the center of
the universe is going to be expensive to
adopt people aren't going to want to
pick it up because of their existing
investments in other technologies or
they're going to see it as this big
decision they're going to need to do
some big evaluation of all these
alternatives and someone's gonna have to
really argue for the right one and then
the perfect becomes the enemy of the
good you don't pick it up because the
one that duck fixes all the problems
that some people want costs too much and
the one that's easy to integrate doesn't
do all the things so you're going to be
in a debate about that and the 20 little
funny open-source checkers that all find
two problems each but do that one thing
really well
they're just no we're in this solution
so tools that think they're the center
of the universe are a problem
context-free keyword matching and
regular expressions so a lot of the rule
engines in both the commercial and the
open-source tools are they're not
amazing okay they're like I I haven't
fully explored all of the commercial
tools so I'm not going to sort of speak
ill of any vendors and I and certainly
also not of the open-source tools which
also have limited capabilities but like
the tools will pick up useful things but
they're noisy they're often wrong and
they will miss stuff and they don't need
to and it's because they were based on
basic rules so we need more semantic
understanding we need all this stuff to
be powered by machine learning okay and
what can we the key to that is like what
can we actually achieve with the machine
learning like you do we just feed our
codebase into the Google brain and a
nice pentesting report will come out no
probably not but we can do things like
categorize code sentiment analysis is a
machine learning technology which is
basically you know you do that on some
input text did we like it did we not did
it get a positive rating on TripAdvisor
did it not customers also bought things
like this basic categorization security
issue not a security issue front end
code back end code administrative script
application logic these kinds of
categorization can be applied to the
code that we write and I'll show you
where some of those shortcomings are in
some of the open source tools in a
minute
okay so that's entirely possible
commercial versus open-source so I don't
want to get into you know sort of like
you know religion and politics on this
particular topic
it's more that if you want people to be
able to easily like you paying for
extended capabilities that makes a whole
bucket of sense we absolutely want the
ability as organizations and as
customers to pay for extended
capabilities but the basics can we can
we integrate this thing can we turn it
on is it going to work with our stuff
all of that none of that is your is core
business to issue detection all of that
is just overhead it's just the cost of
adoption so if we can just go a decent
freemium model with some basic common
standards between the open-source and
the commercial tools we will all make
more money and everything will be
cheaper because what we're not what
we're doing is reducing the cost of the
overhead not the value of the tool so
it's possible to have if not the best
better of both worlds and language
frameworks need to be able to better I'd
this one's totally out of left field it
doesn't relate to anything else I've
said but it's just this thing I wanted
to include which is that our language
frameworks should be able to be marked
up and said well this thing is some user
input you know let's let's start to see
languages saying Security's a
first-class concern let's get let's
allow our language features and our
frameworks to have better tagging around
what kind of things are coming up so
that our scanning tools go oh this is
user input I'm gonna turn the paranoia
up to ten when I'm weren't wondering
whether this string could be manipulated
I know this is an admin script I'm not
gonna worry about the fact that it could
be misused because an administrator is
doing this
okay new possibilities I sell promised
I'd do something new so let's talk about
where we're going so tools there in IDs
okay lots of people have really nice IDs
lots of people don't the supply that the
extended supply chain this will not be
everywhere so we'll so absolutely we can
we can continue to uplift as an industry
static analysis tools typically aren't
really clear about what's going on from
a security perspective with with the
issues they they find there's often a
distinction between security static
analysis and written regular static
analysis so with any luck they'll just
sort of slowly eat security tools and
it'll just become the tools all over
again automated testing often there's
separate frameworks and plugins that for
doing things like fuzzing and the kinds
of activities a pen tester might do so
you need someone to go I'm gonna go
evaluate all of these security libraries
and turn them on but a lot of them are
real no-brainers okay there's a lot of
things which just should be on and
dynamic analysis is still difficult we
can do it it's the commercial tools as
far as I can tell seem to be doing
dynamic analysis and by that I really
mean things like tracing call execution
flow through an application so you can
understand better where your user input
is is reaching and which databases it's
hitting because you might not expect you
might not realize particularly as I said
if it's you know imagine it's your first
job and you don't actually know this
thing backwards
you might not realize that you know a
piece of user input a can in some
circumstances actually reach this
database over there so there's a lot
there a lot there okay so can we really
do better so I'm leaning I'm in the home
straight I've got eight minutes to go
I'm going to leave some time for
questions so we're going to just race
through a few basic examples of
deliberately horrible code that I would
never write just to show you what the
tools can do okay
so just to be super clear on that okay
has vim come up over there yes vim has
come
over there okay so what I've got here is
a hard-coded password and some dodgy
sequel okay so if we if we look at our
dodgy sequel so we've got insert into
the administrative tables user and
password field anything the user
supplies okay so so we'd like we'd
probably like our tools to be able to
detect these kind of things select star
from secrets where any query the user
supplies and then you know it's still
horrible sequel but it's like much
neater you know so this is the kind of
code probably that I'd be close to that
like not but wouldn't work like this but
the structure of it building up the
string etc that is probably more like
what you'd actually see in some code if
someone was going to build up a query
string
okay so bandit is an open source tool
for detecting Python Python issues so
let's run bandit over our dodgy sequel
so it's found a couple of issues so
let's see what it's found it's found
okay it agrees that inserting into the
administrative table anything the user
has supplied is a bad idea but what it
said is our possible sequel injection
really possible like that's more than
possible and and ditto with it with this
select but it's missed the extended
string construction sure I have no doubt
that this would be a day's work for
someone to go in there and actually
improve the rules that are doing the
recognition without going all the way
through to machine learning but if we
can start to get some more general
abilities to detect and learn from learn
negative patterns in code we're going to
be doing a lot better and like I said
them there's no question about machine
learning whether it works or not it
obviously works the question is whether
or not we can frame our secure our code
static analysis problems as machine
learning problems it's a data issue not
not not anything else okay so I've got
one more example which is some dodgy
passwords so if we pull up passwords in
code using the the well-known md5
library because I wrote this 20 years
ago let's go through a few examples okay
so if we okay so we've got a super super
secure password management API that
we're calling and what I'm just doing is
comparing what it is that band
it's gonna ping off versus not ping off
when we look at these tools okay so it
finds password equals the hard-coded
string password yay this will actually
happen and you should actually find it
and turn it off because people when
they're writing the first version of
their code just on their laptop will
write test code like this
and if you're not careful and if you
don't have the tools it just might wake
make its way into pride if no one you
know you don't have to beat your senior
dev you've got to beat your intern
you've got to beat you beat your
first-year student you know you've got
to shift the mindset around can these
tools do better than a smart person
because the smart person just doesn't
scale I can't photocopy them and have
them running you know 25 times a day on
a hundred projects I just can't do it
okay so admin password so it this one is
also fine so it's also a hard-coded
password but I used the extremely tricky
obfuscation of not using the variable
name of password and it just flies on
past okay so these things are not
complex to extent and as penetration
testers and as people investigating the
code you could be providing better rules
back to these detecting detection
capabilities you could you could do a
pen testing report say I found found
this in your code and also here's some
code to add into the your bandit
framework so that you're just never
going to catch it again we can be
getting more value out of this and then
your pen testing reports aren't just
gonna sit on a shelf they're gonna sit
there adding value every day you know
that that's where I think we need to hit
this thing here you know uncomment use
password 343 if you want admin on the
real server that's the kind of thing a
junior sis admin might just stick in the
script that they've got for themselves
you know that's the kind of thing that
if you're just not particularly focused
on whether someone you didn't expect was
going to access and read this script
you might just store away there's the
there's the prod version there's the dev
version just chuck it in there it seems
incredibly obvious and really as soon as
you've been to two security conferences
or read two books and actually had your
manager tell you it's important and get
caught out by a seen senior dev well
sure you're probably not going to do it
again you know
probably but it's really worth having
these tools in place I so that that's
the end of my live demo I would have
loved to get into actually doing some of
the machine learning techniques but what
I really want to show you is that these
took these these rules are basic useful
and can be extended and there's a lot
more we can do yeah so in conclusion
there really is a world of extra
possibility still in static analysis if
you're a pen tester you can come and use
all our static analysis tools and
penetration testing is not not the only
or even the most important means of
shifting that equilibrium on the
economics it's important but it's not
the only thing all right
thanks I may have used all the question
time already I'm not sure no no we have
about seven minutes seven minutes I
didn't see any questions flowing through
through the app so I don't know if it
was working or not maybe it was a poor
coating by Bill something like that but
if you do have any questions and you
just didn't use the app yeah definitely
oh I'll come around thanks for that
if you're starting out of this journey
to kind of implement kind of what you're
talking about in terms of secure coding
and yeah your organization does have CIN
and a number of other dev tools in place
and there's a fairly decent development
team you know a mixture of skills etc
what is your top three things or top two
or top one thing in the next step in the
journey that you should try and do is
that it's a tooling user training
is it management support I mean what is
the number one thing to sort of move you
along that journey yeah it if you've got
the buy-in from one team that can start
this on their own that's probably that
that's it you can certainly uplift a
team at a time so if you've got the
buy-in from one team you can get some
runs on the board from one team if you
have a mechanism where that's going to
be recognized then that'll be enough I
if your team just starts producing
better outcomes and the pentesting
reports get better and everyone goes
what a great outcome you're solid if
your management is in all your
organization's in the situation where
they can't tell the difference between a
well-functioning team and a less
well-functioning team's that those in
terms of those outcomes then you've got
a whole different set of questions and
you're going to need to educate your
management in terms of educating the
developers I think the first thing is
the basic tools
just just go static just basic syntax
style guide checking just do that and
they'll start to get used to it get get
it into their IDs you know so for anyone
who hasn't seen it it's like the
Microsoft Word grammar checker it just
comes up and tells you stuff about the
quality of your code as you're going and
then just have conversations with people
about the quality of their code and what
these indicators mean and just build the
grassroots support if you want to do it
as an entire organization work out
whether you're going to run it as a
project or whether you're going to do it
through BAU and work and get the support
of your ops team as well so that they
will generally get on on board with you
because they're generally generally very
supportive of anyone who's going to take
a security conscious approach to the
work show them the tools show them the
reports etcetera etcetera and get them
get them excited about what you're doing
that's usually pretty easy to achieve
as a rule dev devs are not don't
necessarily you know have those
conversations much
you mentioned scientists I'm wondering
how you at the bomb capture them under
your code quality system they're often a
force of their own they're often not
part of the dev team formally they often
have been trained in any of this stuff
yeah that any luck applying these
systems to your roads
yeah well mixed I mean you know we're
talking about people here it's always
gonna be mixed they're generally really
smart so if you can get them excited
about the challenge of what you're
trying to solve then I think you've got
a lot of the way out scientists tend to
be very much based on their own skills
and capabilities perhaps a bit like a
penetration tester is focused on you
know that it come there's a reputation
there as a scientist that they're
managing and if you which means that
going I will here's the new policy isn't
really a great way to reach them it's
going to be much better hey I ran this
tool I found a bunch of things can we go
through them and then do the same thing
a fortnight later don't make them run it
you run it and go hey I'd like to have a
chat and and and turn the tools down to
their lowest setting and just have a
chat to them about about you know 20
lines of code that you found and don't
tell them why you're doing it I don't
mean to try to foist it on them but just
treat it as a conversation about what
they've built in the quality of what
they've built and how you can help them
and that grassroots approach will be
fairly successful thick generally going
to want their own autonomy in the
scenario but they will a lot of them
will we'll see the benefits some people
really get on the journey around things
like validation and sometimes you can
introduce you can use the continuous
integration to do automated testing of
their scientific accuracy as well and
then you can get them kind of on board
with the whole methodology of the
feedback loop but it like it's certainly
not just easy yeah right it all got time
for maybe one more question if anyone
has it if not I got some so that's good
but do you find that the
current tolling being an open-source or
commercial actually let's let's stick
with open source because it's because
it's mostly free do you find that teams
nowadays like a new team has enough out
there in terms of tooling to just get
started with these things look largely
yes I have to say unless like for almost
all languages there's you know there's
at least 20% coverage from these tools
that's useful so you can turn them all
on the main issue will be noise if
you've got an existing code base then
turning them on for the first time is a
challenge if you're writing from scratch
it's super easy a lot of the issues will
be their output formats are not coherent
and consistent across different things
so if we can there is a tool out there
called koala spelt with a c which is
just awesome and but it produces a sort
of effectively a common JSON format
across being able to integrate it so you
can just treat it as like another part
of the unit testing if you have a dev
team that knows about unit testing if
you don't have a dev team about unit
testing you need to find a human who
knows about unit testing and get them to
embed for like two months to get it all
off the ground and then it'll be alright
alright as with any other questions at
all great like thank you very much for
the presentation can we have a warm
round of applause place
[Applause]