good afternoon everyone the after lunch
session is often really hard I used to
live in Hong Kong and people would
actively snore
after a dumpling festival essentially
which was lunchtime so um thanks very
much for having me I'd especially like
to thank Zack and calcium for for the
opportunity to come and speak with them
and look at the way that we add value
together to help organizations with
their Incident Response and what I'm
gonna be talking about just briefly 15
to 20 minutes I'm gonna be talking about
a little bit of what we've learned so I
just want to briefly introduce myself I
don't come from an insurance background
though Aon is probably the world's
largest insurance broker amongst other
things and risk management company
I come from 25 years in IT security so I
used to like many of you used to run
around and connect companies up to the
internet for the first time and install
their first firewalls I think I
installed one of the first if not the
first Cisco pix firewall which was
agonizing it didn't work I got it
working in the end but I was on my knees
in a cold data center for about eight
hours so it was it was a bit of a pain
in the neck so I'm sort of one of one of
you one of the Oscar community more so
than I'm an insurance broker and I'm
definitely not here to pitch insurance
what I am here to talk about because I'm
here to talk about the risk management
I'm here to talk about what we're saying
we have current incidents underway that
are literally crippling to business and
you know insurance is coming in on that
so I'll talk through all of that okay so
just to start off and this is a point I
always make the only way to reduce the
brand and reputational damage of a cyber
risk is to handle it well it's the only
way to reduce the damage to abandon
reputation in terms of that it's all
about really being prepared being ready
to handle an incident and handling it
well and we've seen examples of this
we've seen I don't know how many of you
are familiar with the Red Cross Blood
Service they had an incident they had
insurance they had an incident response
plan everyone's forgotten about it
if I ask for a show of hands probably
not that many of you would put your hand
up on that one
but how many of you have heard about the
Australian census and what happened
there now that's how you that's how you
don't
an incident you know and I think we can
see others like Equifax more recently
basically what happened with Equifax is
that within 48 hours of the Equifax
announcement they had something like 64
class actions happening against them and
the fact that that business is going to
be allowed to stay in business I find
very confusing to me so I just want to
talk quickly about what are the key
motivations that we're seeing so I aunts
customer is the head of risk and this is
a new world for me coming from IT where
yep you're lucky if you can get up to
the CIO very lucky if you can get up in
front of the board but the opéra head of
operational risk or the head of
insurance or whoever is very key player
with the company and that's because
insurance is a massive spend and I'm not
just talking about cyber I'm talking
about property insurance industrial
special risks general liability
professional indemnity directors and
officers insurance I could go on and on
and you'd all fall asleep and i promised
socko wouldn't let anyone fall asleep so
i so in that respect
huge spend board level visibility as
opposed to a component spend of an IT
budget which is where IT security often
comes in house up who's a seesaw or who
wants to be a CSI I thought everyone
would put their hands up to that one
anyway so the role of the seaso as its
evolved is the seaso as it should be
actually has a dotted line if not a
direct line to the audit and Risk
Committee potentially to the board after
and that's the board of directors so
what they're saying is they're saying
well our risk could be mighty one of our
biggest risks is IT so we need to have a
look at mitigation areas around there so
in terms of impacts to directors and
officers we're all familiar with the
Yahoo breach 300 million account details
all this kind of stuff and it's an
interesting little offshoot that maybe
you might not have seen because it's
like yes yet another class action
against Yahoo was what they did is they
put together and it's never been
successful before they put together a
class action against the officers and
directors personally for negligence
because they had the deep in the share
price as a result of the loss of value
in the sale to Verizon who I used to
work for so that was successful and that
was settled that's that came in at
seventy million dollars u.s. dollars
now splitter makes 12 people if that's
how many people are on the board
that's pretty crippling you're not
sending your kids your grandkids to
private school anymore are you mr.
director so they're starting to get this
and they starting to get very concerned
so if we want to start talking about
mitigation mitigation strategies
mitigation technologies these kind of
things we can have these conversations
at board level they care they believe
that they're not was not sufficiently
knowledgeable in terms of governance on
that oops so cyber insurance very very
very quickly this in a nutshell when I
first started I thought maybe you get
some money back you have a cyber
incident you get some money back like
car insurance well that's not it so yes
you can do that but the main thing about
it is the Incident Response or first
party capability of the insurance so if
you've got an insurance policy and we've
seen a couple of these recently big ones
you've got a fridge magnet with a 1-800
number that you can call and that 1-800
number will put you straight through to
an a team of professionals that will
come in and help you one of them is John
Moran who's sitting on a panel just over
for me who works for Clyde encode he's a
partner he's a specialist in cyber risk
he would say Shh don't tell anyone until
we figured out what's going on here you
know then we'll make the correct
statement so you've got legal advice now
as you know lawyers cost a lot of money
you get IT forensic companies like KPMG
forensics Symantec Mandir they tend to
sit on the insurer panels so they're
going to come in help you contain and
potentially commence the investigation
you've also got the things that people
don't really think about certainly IT
people don't think about notification
notification costs and PR very very
important what am I talking about here
reducing the brand and reputational
damage from an incident because if it's
handled well you can get away with it
back to the Red Cross and that's pretty
much it you can also have business
interruption costs covered you can also
have where you will typically have third
party claims so again going back to the
class action I'm sorry if I go to like a
broken record but if you get sued by a
hundred thousand people you're gonna
want some insurance on that one because
we've got to pay them HR 10,000 my
mental calculator goes e which it does
quite a lot by the way
mandatory breach notification you will
have had this shove down I haven't been
here for many sessions but you will have
had this shoved down your throat
gdpr this is also driving organizations
to become more operationally mature they
don't want to have to mess with this
so they're building bigger stronger
castles they don't want to get in this
kind of trouble and end up with a four
percent fine and just on this something
that I find quite amusing are just
something I've been thinking about
imagine you're Procter and Gamble or
Ford and you have a big problem with a
you citizens data and the hague turns
around and says ford you owe us four
percent of your global revenue do you
think Donald Trump's going to let him
pay that what do you think we might have
World War three just something I've been
thinking about okay large retail example
so everyone talks about target I'll talk
about target we were targets insurance
broker at the time they had a major
incident this is 2014 pretty much being
the benchmark for how expensive these
things can be what happened we target
they came in via a third-party service
provider we're all aware of third-party
service to rider risks and our
responsibilities and making sure that
third-party service providers to do
their thing and what they did you know
that we know it was organized crime back
because of the way they act acted so
they got in realized that they they got
into third-party service provider
realize that they had access to targets
Network performed reconnaissance found
the point-of-sale system and waited
until Black Friday which is a big retail
festival and then took all the credit
card details and sold them under the
dark market now the cost of target are
to that of that breach are anticipated
to be now more than two billion dollars
to the company and they're still in
business that says something about how
much money Target makes but they had
insurance they had cyber insurance they
had 125 million in insurance which is
which doesn't even come close in terms
of that and quantification of insurance
is something that we do and this is an
important point to make a lot of
companies out there have bought cyber
insurance and they've bought a five mil
10 mil limit why five mil seems like a
lot of money 10 mil seems like a lot of
money without really quantifying where
that comes in and what's covered under
other insurance so one of the things
that a undoes amongst other services
that we offer is we we will come in and
we'll quantify this risk and so when I
started I thought this was a darker
how can someone possibly come up with a
cost estimate for a cyber incident but
we do it we run the quant we do gap
analysis against other things and we
provide a company with a report that
says if we have this worst case scenario
because everything else will come under
the worst-case scenario so say your say
your retail loss of all your customer
data say your mining company inability
to mine coal or whatever you know supply
chain interruption we cost that out we
come up with the biggest cost and then
we we put up with a report we put up a
report that can go out to the board and
they can sit there they can look at it
and say we have this major incidents
going to cost us 30 million dollars we
need 30 million dollars in insurance or
we reckon we can wear it off our balance
sheet and 30% of companies to do this
exercise do so I just wanted to follow
up just finish up by talking about
something that's very important so when
the when the balloon goes up and you
have it you have a cyber incident one of
the ways that you can reduce the cost of
investigation and thereby make the
insurers happy is by having all the
information at hand so when I talk to
customers when I start off I look at
their operational maturity so how much
you are you as an organization in terms
of what are you logging what do you how
can you investigate do you look at
Network behaviors how you keeping all of
that information and that and that is
critical to reducing the time and effort
required in terms of performing an
investigation so again back to my
initial statement the only way to reduce
the ban and reputational damage from a
cyber incident is to handle it well and
have the right tools etc thank you
[Applause]
leaving will have questions at the end
but sure yes and no so the yes is yes
100 25 million was all paid out but in
terms of were they well enough defended
against their party wrists I would say
no and I would say 95 percent of the
companies that I talk to have
inadequately done due diligence on the
third parties in terms of and and I
would advise everyone to go through
those contracts don't click yes like you
do on your iPhone when you get an update
its you need to know limitations of
liability and that stuff really
important hello everyone thanks very
much and thanks folks
so yes I'm Zack Siddiqui and pleasure to
have the opportunity to come and talk to
you today so let's ask ourselves the
question what's the first thing that
focuses forensic incident response team
is going to need when they are arrived
right is the the a team essentially
they're going to need immediate access
to everything that goes on in the
organization they'll start collecting
all of the information but by that time
the attackers are gone so realistically
there's not much that they're going to
find rather they're going to want to
leverage your capabilities to collect
all of that information and if you don't
have enough to track and capture the
threat there's going to be absolute
chaos a challenge is that the threat
signatures often come after the fact so
how is the forensic response team going
to identify a threat if a signature for
it has not yet been developed how do you
go back in time and understand the
impact if you didn't collect the source
of truth in the first place what about
your net flows who's talking to which IP
addresses what about your DNS requests
that identify or they'll help you
identify command and control services
the current issue
is that many organizations are capturing
only a fraction of the traffic because
there's a limited capability to capture
retain and search all your network
traffic so this leads to not knowing
what's going on in your environment by
capturing all these security logs you're
giving the you're giving your
organization the chance to respond to an
incident with facts you give yourself
the chance to piece together enough
information to identify threats
individuals in the organization machines
in the network that have been part of
the attack vector if you look at it from
a cyber risk insurance point of view you
should have a capability in place for
the forensic Incident Response Team to
consume when they begin yeah folks is 18
there are three important points to take
note of here first the more mature your
seam environment the more effective your
insurance solution will be second the
more mature your seam environment the
more effective your insurance solution
will be and third the more mature your
seam environment the more effective and
we're sounding like a broken record if
you've got heuristics and intelligence
and anomaly detection and you're
aggregating you're normalizing you've
got a well-tuned log management or seam
solution then you should see the
exfiltration of data as long as you're
capturing essential things such as your
bytes in bytes out from all of your
network flows okay you're not going to
see a large data exfiltration unless
you're capturing packet volumes this
will tell you what information is moving
from where to where only then can you
trace down to a particular time frame
when an incident actually happened and
that's when the value of a seam with
real time correlation capabilities comes
in
in this age of turnkey cloud services
were seeing such overseeing things such
as commanding control servers that use
the same DNS right but alias to ever
rotating IP addresses it would only ever
look malicious if you're able to add up
the total packet bytes of all of these
servers combined so there's an
opportunity to classify a set of command
and control servers are you know
different IP addresses as a single
cement command and control servers right
but how do you do that one effective
strategy is to take that single fqdn
from your DNS logs and correlate it with
network flows and URL logs to identify a
range of external IPS that are part of
the same command and control service
that way individual flows that would
normally go unnoticed can be aggregated
to something that's noticeable now and
this is before threat intelligence feeds
are updated with the latest threats but
this is only possible if your seam has a
correlation engine that can do it fast
enough if not you must invest in a
correlation engine which can be
expensive if you don't do your homework
so I'm just gonna do a quick survey I
promise you it won't hurt put your hand
up if you are logging your network flows
oh that's really good
so keep them up and and keep your hand
up if you're also logging your DNS
requests okay keep your hand up if
you're also logging URLs from your proxy
okay so hands up if you're doing all
three okay so maybe about 20 percent
I'll leave you with a few key points
about why you need to be logging as much
as possible and why logging that
trifecta that you know that three things
that I just mentioned is really
important amongst other things
log everything because you'll be
thankful that you did when you have a
critical security incident log
everything because you need to
demonstrate you're taking appropriate
action to the Privacy Commissioner in
accordance with the mandatory data
breach notification legislation log
everything so that you've covered
yourself and you can demonstrate a chain
of events that shows that you could not
have reasonably foreseen and protected
against certain threats log everything
because next-gen firewalls despite what
people say and not to be all in the
end-all of security log everything
because your security operations staff
need to be keeping an eye on what's
happening in your environment on day to
day to day basis log everything because
if your company makes large amounts of
money you could be vulnerable to
financial flows related to organized
crime log everything because you could
be requested by law enforcement bodies
to assist with investigations of
violence murder and suicide yeah and
traffic of illicit materials such as
child pornography and log everything to
assist law enforcement bodies in such a
way you prevent damage to your corporate
brand because the information that you
are a custodian of makes you a valuable
contributor to your company's crisis
management plan and these are not things
that I've made up these are things that
have actually happened that we've
assisted customers with information is
the security practitioners lifeblood
there are only two types of security
professionals when it comes to logging
those who know that they need to log
everything and those who regret
at some point in the future that they
didn't thank you very much okay we
definitely have time for some questions
so I've got the mic here so raise your
hand high if you have a question because
the lights quite bright here any
questions yep okay thanks hi I'm Matthew
from Monash University my question is
around providing insurance to some of
the industries that are known to really
struggle with providing adequate
cybersecurity so that the health
industry is one that comes up a lot
where you know they haven't really
caught up in the cybersecurity space so
how do you manage to provide insurance
to them it's a $64,000 question so you
know it's we as a broker you know it's
it's our role to to pull the insurers
into line to say to the insurers look
this is a risk and we we want the
customer you know I will frankly say to
some organisations that I don't think
that it's time for them to get insurance
I walk into some customers and I do my
basket-case assessment that's what I
call it I don't tell the customer that
but the basket-case assessment sort of
goes along the line do you have an
incident response plan have you tested
it do you run security awareness
training etc if they can't answer any of
those questions adequately I might go
off and you know I can help you with
companies it can help you to do that go
off and do some testing and we probably
have a very we have a very large
proportion of the healthcare companies
as our customers all the way from you
know your high level high level ones
that have multiple different things
pathology and ambulance and hospitals
and all that kind of stuff all the way
down to aged care and you know you get
you get you know so a smaller aged care
you know it's like a single nursing home
that kind of stuff how do you how what
do you think their controls are but I
guess what we have to do when we're
talking to the insurers if the customer
looks like they're not going to be able
to fill in the proposal for me know it's
a stupid word but the insurance industry
uses proposal form to mean application
form so I'm a client for insurance then
we'll talk them through the steps then
what the insurers might
and I had this for the hospital small
Hospital what they what happened there
is that um one of the insurance company
they wanted a ten million dollar limit
and one of the insurance companies said
you can only have a five million dollar
limit because you don't encrypt the
records at rest another insurer said you
can only have a five million dollar
limit because you don't use two-factor
authentication for administrative tasks
so what I'm kind of getting at is
there's no forum there's no firm level
but as you get further down to smaller
companies the insurers start to
aggregate the risk so all they want to
know is how many staff you've got how
many records you've got what's your
annual turnover and they'll box-ticking
they'll give you a policy so that's a
smaller company when they get larger it
becomes a lot more complicated and again
that's where I think that's what my job
is to try and help people work out help
the insurers and help the customers work
it out absolutely I'm so speaking to
Mike Burgess I think he's here at the
moment but um when he was back at
Telstra and we talked about the parallel
spend of insurance and IT you know at
some point it crosses over it makes
sense just to keep spending on controls
never stop spending on controls but at
some stage transfer the risk over to
insurance so that you've got that
another motivator that I've seen and we
had this with another health care
company in in Brisbane Queensland and um
which were we are and in the end the
chief security officer
they couldn't squeeze more money into
their insurance budget to buy cyber
insurance but they wanted the incident
response in their chief security officer
turnaround said have some of my tools
budget so I'll pay for the first years
premium because I want the incident
response capabilities right now because
I can't go out and and get a retainer
with mandiant and with a law firm and
with this and that and ooh is that
response testing so I think the two
things might have at each other thanks
for the question any other questions
please we've got plenty of time so
hopefully we've got a couple more all
right stand here for another ten seconds
okay well look thank thanks so let's
think
Zach and Fergus please for the good
presentation