excellencies ladies and gentlemen dear
friends from all around the world
good morning
good afternoon good evening wherever you
are at this point of time here from
munich in the house of the bavarian
economy to the eighth edition of the
munich cyber security conference again
as a digital edition
i'm very proud and glad that i can open
this conference here today
and in my short introduction word let me
briefly spend some context of the
content and and what we want to deliver
in our conference here
and the motto of this conference is
drifting clouds and we want to provide
some leadership perspective on the
ever-growing threat of the cyber attacks
and drifting clouds actually stands for
a lot of what happens in the world right
now
if we take two levels up and see weather
as part of our climate i think we all
know as human beings that we influence
our climate
and we also know that only through
cohesion and collective action of all
nations around the world we can
influence that climate will not
influence our planet too badly
if we take a level down and take weather
conditions to the current political
situation around the world but also the
security situation then we can see
really dark clouds
and eventually some storm coming up
and also the same thing it is only so
strong diplomatic initiative
and collective action that we can manage
these security threats and also
political um threats
and overcome them
and at the third part clouds in the
context of i.t and cyber security of
course have a different meaning
cloud infrastructures are a very major
part of today's it infrastructure of our
data management of iit management and in
that context we sometimes don't know
whether clouds are part of the problem
solving or part of the problem itself
and in this context we have tried to
build an agenda
for you which actually addresses a
couple of points and we have four themes
which we want to address the first theme
is how governments see
cyber security and what they want to do
about that that's the first part the
second part is how we want to mitigate
the challenges we have on the
ever-growing attacks
in the cyber world
and how to better anticipate that for
the future that's two themes and we want
to put a very special focus on the
security of supply chains
what we have experienced during the kobe
time is that the supply chain came very
much under scrutiny and we see from the
crunch of the chip crisis and for many
other materials that the supply chains
are very vulnerable so the security in
supply chains
are very
important in order to safeguard a
worldwide stability in many of the
economies around the world
and around those we have put a lot of
competent panelists together to give us
an input for the dialogue we need in
order to solve the ever-growing cyber
threats
and
with these short words i would like also
to hand over to the very first speaker
of today and i'm very pleased to welcome
mr margaritis skinas your commissioner
and vice president and responsible for
the security in the union he is here for
the second time we are together here in
the studio so we have to make a proper
handover like in corona times right so
when i leave the microphone mr skinners
will join and your the floor is yours
thank you very much