ladies and gentlemen it's time for
hacking trackback
me
week
thanks to you thank you very much
Chinese panel discussion writing Agnes
scientific study to find the real story
and
first what they're doing ET star punch
me
question why ensuring
stutter is better K
great I thought to start off by
answering a question
to our way were research team of four
people from Malaysia over she school
polish in southern Chile in Canaday and
a
generational your world climbers located
with a two hundred miles north
out there healing she itself as a
publicly funded university offers and
many
Fort Lee a four year degree programs
English mash the full range
and she was singing about 6,000 full and
part-time students
and as you can see the in the picture
something character shipping and
chilling in seeing
blodgett pushing logic lakes the caption
cell speech
across but some 150 acres catches and
not really expecting something region
and other aspect I wish
had should bring is a course a
the option extreme in the wintertime his
plot is no
and recalls and it can it just yet me
in his dealings with his cash talking to
him on the phone email when you
and when you do now is introduced the
for membership other cheney que no
particular order
churning wish doctor
John Dodge that's my personal
everybody sheesh he lies inside game
and change I like seeing rest of us see
things from a very different
perspectives in Albany
and just a little bit aback when johnnie
an jeannie who is an indication
an Jones business is business strategy
in ecology and pushing
and he's being a he falls management
consulting teachers on board directors
yesterday jury's business and non-profit
organizations
and he's also on the h-1 a warning
business strategy environmental journal
previous to that he had a life misses
you
someone real job we thank Anne
as the vice president a home for large
mining
involving company and he's also is CEO
venture capital firm
mentioning
and
this is yours truly aside from leaning
against reason swatting mosquitoes
from demolition graduate the MBA program
in Ranchi
got 12 years experience in the field by
T
and in particular it information
technology
yeah customer relationship management
also
recognized contributor to the
Information Technology Infrastructure
Library
victory by the sensual Computer Inc
telecommunications agency in the United
Kingdom thing is a slow
is channel yanomami
is and just playing is a be conquered
reelection
and he plays a eventually getting a
degree in IT management and
Masters level his interests include
Peking gourmet meals
and hamster keeping importantly he's a
lot cheese and suffers from
Donald Morris makes me have
any dockery at Shell
also known as bernie yes this is our
virginity
and bernie is an internationally
recognized expert in human resource
management
and a has been recently appointed rector
in school commerce
in 1890 she's an accomplished offering
well respected me feel childish
pornography community standards
franchise legislation
and stress management anxiously game we
should be in this year old he
research experts work for you engine
powerful enough to pay
who we are seeing you stand let's take a
look at
study why is it that we engage
in studying all the usual ago and
for us going together in nursing is that
there was a longish
strangely fourteen years hackers
wonderful things that happens again
and me han should begin to wonder
why it is pushing stuff in the news
or what's being reported by shorties
because from
from the organization behavioral
perspective in business perspective
most started his reading media
interesting secrets from sorties do not
make any sense whatsoever
and so consequently we came to your
belief that happen again
is misunderstood and grossly
misrepresented public
sure objective became to be traded spill
something amiss
and providing public in organizations
with a balanced view
arch had Packers in society in the
contributions
only 1e
is answer the question why are we here
at HK
well checking you need to learn more
about you
over the last year was talkin English
language around the world
and response financially to you the pic
chain by
media is that you guys are very helpful
and you've done your
most to me play this week sure she's
contact Jay
may contact names supplies with as much
information as you can
and wall what we're trying to do Henry
dispel some
mess wuz use a scientific to all and
since
from research there seem to be real
science
been done to try to properly represent
tankers for who they are any
contributions
to postpone a week bonuses should a in
something you have
action see to engage in issued a and
we've kept E
try to you ensure his complete anonymity
something portion given your experiences
dealing with law enforcement
game other shorties page you've been
jury apprehensive
picnicking no connecting he's and we
quite well understand and respect it
so we thought we can Tunisia K and
meet you in person ang see things we can
encourage you
to engage in this day only a
for the last few we've been working with
at Cummings also known as bring us
anti-jewish head right now just so that
he can talk to you about the studying
and his involvement any perceptions
Disney
promise you like to make about us
forward to working as we've been doing
and thanks Ken up INS
an email from a this bernie S doctor
bring shell I'll early last year
but she apparently been trying to track
down for
couple months I'll unsuccessfully hammy
telephone boxes you go through
first but I was quite surprised to hear
somebody had gone to such effort to try
try again
from whatever reason and
she got to talking with you about this
study they were they were trying to
conduct and I was very interested in it
because I
I call you in seeing all these
misrepresentations in the press
an aide myself in to jack it is a
misrepresentation to the press and by
law enforcement past
and I thought anything that can be done
to
help dispel some these
misrepresentations
and are present an objective viewpoint
%uh
I what hackers are about in
in the grand scheme of things would be a
good idea
they certainly been very lopsided view
in the public mind thanks to various
government law enforcement agencies and
the media who just doesn't take the time
to thoroughly research and investigate
stories
rate keep it nine at ten stories and
in Press newspapers web sites television
radio
you'll find just as Kevin mention just
explanations that make no sense
logically or or
for any reason are so up
hopefully this study will on me give
them an updated
put together some real statistics is too
%uh
the makeup hackers with their with your
goals motivations are
who they are %ah demographics as for
everything they don't wanna know your
needs
%uh any money music that touches me
by my late November can easily
weekend %uh I have actually work for
these people on the same for
by email for the past six months your
cell and found them to be here
tree above board I was a little
apprehensive initially thinking well
what's there what's your motivation here
sis another round
slanted study and back I think you're
being rejected
and we'll have something to gain
here by helping them do this study so I
would
strongly encourage anybody are here to
stop by the table using
your hallway here pick up another
surveys on
ATV seeded being interviewed by 10 for
what is it and 50 minutes it's a short
talk
they don't have to know your name no
particular interest in people who have
been charged with
I coat hacking related crimes but
basically anybody who
which represents houses hacker me to a
friend or
trusted colleague something up so
all I can do is a is tell you after you
meet people from my answer
they're really look bored arms nothing
underhanded about what you're doing
and they're really striving for utmost
in objectivity
study so arm a hand is off to
bernie or John okay ball and before we
continue in the presentation
home he wanted to present something to
add me
leading working way with at now for a
major issue that's that's my a t-shirt
is happy with a tissue Anne
you over the over the course the winter
we were talking to it on the following
quite often we talk to me one time
anyway you're trying assemble a space
heater
his Florence plane was quite call it was
calling my ass and they told me was
thank thirty-some below zero anywheres
am
soul every you to say to get you just
small talking
stacey dash eliminate
at
his neck
would really like to embarrass you
hitting
house thanks as communication as for
your tasty
okay and Sox Sox keep your feet warm
okay thanks very much take touched
thanks Ed him to get a Disney key
okay so don't want to take a look at &
Media Gallery
fact or fiction and what we wanted to do
was have this is an interactive session
we and getting put in just a few samples
of
some quotations within the last few
months from various different media
sources
on juries different topics but about
hackers
Anne would like to get you in Porter
reaction
to use as we go elsewhere say nearly go
through in recent quotes headlines
any anybody like to come up in give your
comments on speak really appreciate it
first one me from London Free Press
nothing petty
body claim
any hackers deserve to be treated as the
criminals
they are the story continues
hackers hurricane to fire senators
people who get their jollies by setting
buildings alight and watching
gleefully from a distance as flames
licked the sky
consider using matches hackers use
computer viruses and programs designed
to
on março computer
people may have a sneaking admiration
for young hackers use technical seeking
for all corporate giants
but thats misplaced admiration NASA also
want to admire the demolition skills an
arsonist
Western Express would anybody
like to me shishu reaction hearing
laughter show
how many people agree with that member
station
CTS
this is actually a column
I but aside from the you whoever scribe
debt
what do you think to content
bank
yes she's like a Stephen King novel
right
the you the
yeah I had
pic justice me K
okay
okay its former columnist
week
okay right you not trying to get to
actually knowing differentiate who's who
I am just going to move on because we
have a number of
give approach explain interjected
now everyone 10-year NC concede that for
what it is
but for the average member the public
who may not have any exposure to are
needy computers at all origin people who
are treated in their use
%uh I would think that is a good
percentage in public
might swallow this carnage and there's
just
very little in the way it balanced
information be
County media and Ashley I think he's
such a kind
trying to do is to actually getting
accurate data put together
scientific study are present their
findings
and up we have that covered in
made available to it will be mailed made
available at one sitting here and in
fact she
you should get an early captivity you
conducted
on India any questions
but a wink wink okay next one is a
statement about
Essex there's a vacuum in cyberspace in
it you need to be new ways of teaching
right from wrong
and usually wake and related recent
computer crimes
and he's gonna focus on G bottom quote
and standards of conduct a guide online
as you promise on the notion that we're
going to have to face to face
relations meet people but in the virtual
world
that we enforce me dissipates maybe I
can see
comment what you think statement d
kick
okay so you think it is ethics disappear
because
your online
all
me
K anymore
yeah I'm I have a question before we
continue can you hear in the back
on somebody's making the comments of fun
it probably I think if people might come
up to the mikes on
or Mike here we let one go 6 sketch
researches actually being funny
wire shelves its independent
incorporation sees
donating any money we wanted to keep
backing stuff head
we I can speak like in a sense on the
principal research along with Bernie
shell
a.m. we're funding our normal activity
were employed by the University as
professors this is part of our academic
research level
were personally funding the travel for
this out of our own professional loans
university this year
we could have sought in fact 'em
up support for this and we didn't wanna
tarnishes and so we actually got a
little branch much small business
development unit in the University and a
few other things but it's there's no
external financing at all for this
project and its
we're trying to keep as clean as its
them hard but it's is we're a bit about
shoestring is a common
well I can I think I could start to
comment and then turned over to
Burnett a.m. we picked the question was
where do we plan to publish this
information
and and in what form um we plan to
I guess that look at the history bernie
has published a couple recent books by
in and we would probably we may in the
publishing a book or some other material
but that's down the road we planned to
publish some %uh the
I'll work on 2600 a
we've if you fill out the form and
itself
will give you back an individual
assessment of
whole of this we're using standard
techniques in the in the
in this reform we plan to use credible
sources tell us not to say that was sold
at one end up in the public media as
well
a but I may be burning today red yes
we really trying to keep this
as objective as possible reporting
so as we would typically do on any map
return our call me
minutes late the mean response the
standard deviations in group responses
primarily
and that group levels that no individual
could feel the history danny is in any
way
being lease I we've already been
contacted by
number media people I guess desperate
to have her findings I the one member in
there
we have trusted so far in this came
after
bernie asses are reviewing situation
I is Andreas his team from
came Broadcasting Corporation Toronto
Andreas
dance show called undercurrents and I
guess
many ways he's considered to be in
trouble and the media feeling because he
likes searching for the truth
and not popular answer so
Bernie s has spoken to Andreas
for number hours understand it and
that is the only media group that we had
committed to enhance my understanding
that
they are coming to interview bernie &
ass
your colleagues actually coming into
coming I personally could make it this
weekend
the conference for cost reasons there
they're coming and Tuesday
to on interviews with people involved
the artillery shell
and down actual departed the study is
geared towards
activism as well he wanted to cover that
NC
indication they're very churchy and she
told me
in a study on is really no real
scientific data it's been available to
the public option is being
and anecdotal information on there may
be some government studies done by
long fortune agencies that certainly you
can't necessarily expect to be
unbiased on norm is publicly available
so on is really in
gonna be an open book had Indonesian
responds
not the issue did not anyone know your
name is necessary she want copied or
something
in any case a your answers you can be
compiled with but all the others in
and used his sickly it's not not
anything you need to be concerned about
your individual
responses be index to you
I'm
no i i its
I think what I'd like to address that
directly what I was trying to say
really and I'm trying to skip over
things quickly as we're trying to make
the data accessible
and that's why we say 2600 we're using
we're going to use standard test this is
a very Scion the
these are well-established questions
that were using for you can use good
statistical tests on it to be
have to be peer review you know we have
to yet and we have in fact before we
could even delivered here
we had to get this approved by the
universe the ethics committee
before we could be sliver here so this
we have to go through hoops player not
before we can even
administer this early in a satisfactory
as being ethically done
and the date is gonna be properly done
don't was once we get back home
and that if we say it's confidential we
have our own ethics
with you people to say what you doing I
mean it's it's just his party this
academic community in Canada anyway they
take it very seriously
I don't know him answer your question
but I'm trying
are
I
I i think that the way to address it the
best way to get back
accurate information as get as many
people as possible to fill out a survey
for
if we do have but at 10 quacks fill out
the form then we go back data if we get
a couple hundred people here that we
have are still at the 10 quacks it ought
not to ask you to get daily
it's a concern of ours so we really need
your help if you want to have a
legitimate
a profile of what you that you
was one one person said earlier they
felt
I we interpret it to the this is not a
homogeneous community this as some
some black cats and has some white hats
and some put people in some bad people
and there's a different ride you people
and I think we have a special group here
and we have to make sure we get a good
cross-section
not just a few people and eventually
will turn out nicely II
I don't mean uptake too much but I okay
I think we should do wish
shoal of fish he had question me comment
period later
me if anybody wants to stay after they
reached between six and seven years
know whether a panel discussion during
that time you want to talk to us to be
great
just want to move on we have a couple
other interesting ones just look at
richard Young
am me put football team looking
and at shirt from corporate SB Nation
I winkler makes a statement almost all
hackers are little more than
nuisances change he knows that there's
only about 200
a 200 hackers in existence in the world
any
only the user's computer geniuses any
comments on that
can can you come up to the microphone
show really
yeah week what we'd like to do actually
is good
she'd actually also scripps
in we do know dead here are and meaning
which identified
hackers term crackers is used script
kiddies
wherein students and there are
different behavior said state people can
identify it
people here whereas dudes have specific
activities in a case like to focus on
and would like to understand why the
focus on school what makes
when mixing te quite like to do that
which the patient today
provide for society hey function me
he
week
okay we do have some questions in here
to train
differentiate people based on the type
of activity litigation
and then what we can do will be doing
some statistical analysis based on some
things responses to see
word is we have a group joining up have
been
consultation with Shay Eric Raymond to
get
his feedback in others action unity
as to differentiation techniques for
Packers pushes every entry and
money she elements take people seem to
misunderstand
shorties and media seem to misunderstand
is the notion
tent you think a lot of lawyers
been involved in these cases which
really focus on content
isn't any is which you the
differentiates whether or not you
intentional community claim
more actually community claim even if a
crime was no action itself
yes we do have some questions and
they're banging
spell to you exactly what they are
because we don't ship lies in Italy
stay results okay
a
kisch which any I quickly agree in your
comments
actually you having gone through his
book H did not find any references to
support any statement that he had made
and but I saw doesn't introduce it to
see
what people's perspectives was on the
subject since it is he was actually a
este guest speaker back in
94 at hope me and a friend and I we had
a min at 97
attend beyond hope okay energy
it's really sinking me okay
this is a great a really great
interesting article
it's a guy saying why are there so few
female hacker's shan't ask anybody who
purports you know
from national expert and catch to you
MIT several researchers churchill coltie
Michael so well
also important jeering Packers at
unanimous had gmail
especially male as exchange
he continues to say it's a testosterone
problem
women into hacking from the same general
reason that women are not interested in
vandalizing stop signs cars their knees
drawn to the hostile elements
cyberspace séminaire and
best one he's in a bit competence women
have the brains and skills to hack
but they're more interested in building
communities im 13 and Exchange
like web design a creative any comments
about the subject
winning and creativity I
he said idyllic
okay over here he hitch
he can
and in the back here
here's a quick traditional flavoring
this
in this colony cash if you read the
whole thing I do have a copy
edition your body was to have a good him
using read
come fish me nothing in here it is
actually correct factual
but is publishing hey escaped rhetoric
you just move on election
your question was whether or not we have
shorty
checking any statistic song males
shemale populous
yes we are we do have questions should
reach think Erica told Mediaset
doing guesstimate stack 15 percent
winning
stick issues a great day great article
Anne image new software SAT
and thing I'd like to focus on is the
statement a is software can
shank like a hacker was a hacker sank
like
yeah K
in the back
K
right here
okay
heaney okay he
usually
area he here we go
tiny can't roll hacker kevin Mitnick
advises CIO's to hackers hysterical
am she's I real-world experience in
circumventing security measures
scans being coming July interesting
experience in education
kevin also argues plenty recall that
some computer planned community
intellectual curiosity rather than those
are for personal gain
adding just because someone's been
arrested for hacking doesn't mean and
criminal
so for which you may recall
shanks really positive shit was tracking
process
belch the today
gershwin kleenex me
as contamination owner and CEO network
security technology States
if you're never going to be king if you
need to hire a hacker you never gonna
catch ahead
before bringing hackers into the Hall of
jewish NCAA
CIO magazine reports are for items CIO
should seriously weighing
fledgling comments
background check says to
never shown the back on workers ever
been done if a hacker candidate has held
other corporate positions in addition
and beware the security company robert
hasn't had outsider speak with your
customers
tuition focus baby
a statement about hackers ish and you
two cases houston won their shoes to see
if you were hacked again you can't never
ever being look at by corporations yes
can easily make
is officially cation me most anguishing
actually illegal purposes would not take
the time to become certified
shore if a hacker can any
is certified as an information security
professional
or systems network administrators
it's a good sign hacker does not have
the legal
intentions came she
reaction had army I'll chocolate just
too more here a topical ethics
background checks in resumes not offer
any insight into
individuals moral makeup face to face
meeting
perspective penetration tester provided
fuel for the morals
and attention since kennedy and lastly
leveraging existing staff inspiring
a hacker is still an option their
classes often taught by the FBI
shi'a NNSA they can teach employees the
ins and outs
hacking any comments
for yes everywhere K
greenback
me
here
he
me
use
here
he
okay community manager
and one last time me
he
adjusting actually can close to unity
Anne decision regime hurtling lone male
Hey Baby want to come up to my hardware
and it
he begins with Federation San Francisco
sex party
I found myself needing kneeling real
rapturously at the fetus reach arming
naked man
his level of arousal seen in carrying on
a conversation
suddenly shifted from pornographic
fantasies to the implementation
the web server program a patchy on
offshore computers I
only day one wide open and read anything
more comic
is a variety haitian providing a profile
good cross-section ish media articles
make in this pic
in this case I don't know how is a got
it from topic to topic be
active in it I guess we'll have to know
day K
eligible voting last one here question
US crackdown on cyber terrorism is going
to be
very much and she furnish most people in
the room here
playing pledges to protect privacy
private citizens commerical continues
yet no point has announced plan to spend
billions of dollars to protect america's
computer systems
from hackers and viruses and finally
there's never been a time like this in
which we have the power to create
knowledge
and the power to create heck and both
those powers resting same hands
it easy sensual that we do not undermine
liberty
in the name of liberty anybody want to
comment
answer here can you please pick up
microphone great protect the privacy
practices in the camp take the price you
can con
K anybody else and
in the back here
K your hand up your vacuum like cummick
again having her tension with a light in
my eyes no
pressure back
K
in each day and have posted some
interesting
alone since the payphones shame when you
get to see the edge
own the privacy she any worse any
sry copies are signs in your presence it
a lot built on calls are monitored
put them into the patrons remind people
that your fingers in
phone calls may well be mighty any kind
mentioned a
day the final statement on the slide
am i body in a machinery
know this bill clinton
not surprising
over him
here
his
okay
Asian call you up now to concludes the
presentation
here
okay so Lake I said earlier you need
your help
meanie biggest says we can
and you know without your help to sing
in English Canada
ang so far he had a great response
talked a lot of people up networking
what an interesting conversations and
everything has been great
actually restraint that our series
too long in people are gonna finish so
far with you
started as finished in your a peaceful
day and
their fans that the t-shirts
or we will be getting an reaction with
these teachers where we
he's gone he both looked at as I here's
your smile there
sneer some but he had a reaction
nonetheless
which is good and
T-shirts porcelain for a
20 bucks I ish if you do a survey
will give the tissue trade you for half
price 10 bucks
and and %eh
we're also doing interviews an issue
book interview its first come first
serve
mogadishu to Sri
but we'll miss you shimon slots for a
new survey also
local in the senate
chanti but frankly it basically
paintings and their own pocket so it's
not a
telling a corporate giveaway company can
dislike TV teacher is the big deal is it
spend a lot of money but he sure CNN
themselves in pockets
I'll
opening for questions no finishing any
comments or questions you
you can get answered me social
presentation thanks
okay
Kenny anybody have any questions
comments
like to share key his milk
okay
you can come in CS a rare display ish
placed a
main entrance yes you just relinquish
any elevators
test just have a general comment on the
use the word hacker
quite liberally in this presentation
it's not an invention in the nineties
read in the eighties
term hacker goes all the way back to the
regional model train enthusiasts back at
MIT
who I guess you could say are
responsible for the creation of the
Internet
for the maintenance of the Internet for
the personal computer
in just about every other modern
computing device we have in the world
today
to vilify such a wide variety people
in a broad stroke as other people
pointed out is a grave injustice
and of course are criminals in all
aspects of society
even within the hacker community butter
cheese hacker in literature
sense is think a misunderstanding about
the word really means
I just wanna say the sounds like
something really knew that hasn't really
been done before
I think it's real good idea and it
sounds like you guys have an opportunity
to
to go forward and said how people don't
get the stuff
future and thanks and keep kick
anybody else
you have any questions please feel free
come CSC will be around a
toll Sunday morning from you but
something new to me
gene consists any
any questions you wanna ask his feel
free website and what shade is postage
and back in church as well as
on our displaying we have some
information she said she can take with
you she like
to people to connect this the survey are
actually at Petes status survey online
pitch black okay mom show that URL is
available on hand out but the year
game extract okay thank you very much