little Tom we have our local sheriff
office
and the just
two months ago where or local sheriff
was fired first
speed a we had no sheriff
and the deputy Ross the
on sick leave well
started the question me too I was other
worry
but the flu i willz
classic but they start to question me to
have a question idk
also into it a lot officers who
questioned me at the
brought his notebook with him and the
what provoked
working integration with booked but I
had to helping right
it we couldn't couldn't use for and
later on when they're a
has two sign the interrogation document
he had to use my printer to get it
printed alt
so I made a co pill the document I
wasn't supposed to have a lock on it so
I medico P I'm a male
to my lawyer lawyer and during the
interrogation I went to the bathroom
and the take a phone call to her biggest
ovations newspaper tips
kept them all and the
half hour later there was a photographer
outside our windows
a office shit I'll already here
at they didn't like it and didn't like
depressed because
the this economic and
Computer Crime Unit a spin attack
the whole time from the region press
because all their fault
really stinks okay
a couple days later when the
all you guys a hurdle the story I think
so you started the
bombarding mph slower in Norway with the
bus because they're so I crashed
and
and the
the opposite
to the case here in United States we'll
have almost 100 percent support option
or
the whole region Press a lot of
television station had been
support us and
said the whole cases but shit air
and most people in Norway also support
Joan
for example the the beginning of January
a we got a message
let a.m. joan was awarded
a national college student price
for his writing of SS I got
a by a
and he got about 2009 and all of us
aboard and they also grabbed bank at
in that all slow and at all me all the
television celebrities
today
thing
okay the that you know it had been a lot
over
I'm press attention that they also tend
to safety in a rich
26 all the main Norwegian
a news better papers had the story on
the front page the whole front page
and they all supported John the
there was also also into that
when the Norwegian Minister of Justice
I'll
back to college Secretary of Justice
here had mentioned the case
in a meeting with the police and
she had the mention the case as a crime
while it was pending and
be I is also no under and investigation
solar two weeks ago
we got a letter or excuse for an from
the Norwegian Ministry of Justice
the
the case also had a great TV
coverage poland's main oration
the TV station and has been no or
after all Swedish television on French
television
and also ABC News by I didn't
did I don't know if they will all to
send anything because
as a no way on by this lay the
the whole the
it Computer Inc lookin chain Norway
also support us 100 percent I can go on
an example we use on the ISP and more
their Poulter per litre worry posted
links for all called
and I want a the Manisha in Norway
physicist the United States American
company
witcha affair affiliate in Denmark
commitment to service our
and I agent in Norway you got a
telephone
from the manager and he told me had he
had the
got a telephone from me this criminal
unit in a way
and they asked him to send them copious
allora that's out there and then he told
them
letter in in Denmark is in Denmark
if you get a court order from Denmark
only
give you what you want and the nearly
fused together
anything before that a court order and
the
let me said to me I have made the copies
if if in case if they are you get a
court order
but if he said anything you want me to
delete
hick
the the case in no way is
the pending and they was supposed to
reach a decision and dole may
but nothing happened that put a lid on
the case
the we have heard that they have sent
the case to some
law professors to get to see what AM
make up the case but the for some folks
have told us a
there he can't do anything 11
I think I will close the case without
doing anything
and
have to tell you that or case is
not that important but the whole case of
free speech
and the free programs is very important
but because he's cuddly does to
the the a complete control from this
the major companies I could give example
I already heard that they planning to
make DVDs which will self destruct often
better than ten times but perhaps there
the next step will be in like in men in
black
if you buy a film look at the other end
a an issue memory
so you can buy it once again by ahead
national soul
thank you any questions questions s
up
but there was set an OB GYN an early
next nice n
they started a petition and after
receiving
I'll 10,000 signatures pay and that
and there's also been there was a
discussion on TV
with them his name
Islam education on me he said started
the first ISP no way
is what I really need to do is no way
and he basically called the
them cooking
the economic crime in the column gestapo
song we see the love's park
and other questions
as you well the most most important part
was done by our
German member eBay used about
and for 5-6 hours to the ocean
engineering
that exceed the plane my Park
to about 3-4 hours to fuck you till
don't we can fix the bugs
at
yep
one him
it's just us three
me the gym member on the couch London
named
both died in San dunno also to me s
well miss all also
questions like Kim when did you meet
the other members have more where did
you meet them and
who didn't want and did I have a link on
the main page that hosted on that page
and when they put that link and also us
those kinds of questions and
they were impolite country let mean that
art
yes
up
all warrant
boy role
all
world yes
my its my phone got me started when I
was small six-years-old
I started using his computer and I'll
seven yet to get
my own computer so we can use his own I
so is going up to start s
yes I'll actually I work with the
we show postal service but also have a
part-time
company and selling computers s
me
yeh mostly I see an email yes
the not really it was a lot of
propaganda in the beginning
know as well and most no
most the day newspapers wrote yeah
articles
which refer to descend scoping until
this and small and
Musa magazines the just basically be
wrote articles
met add much same content but the
recently they start referring to this SN
as a pay-back can device that's that
wrong as well not that good
test
on Monday said
s
well and the trial among them nothing
more than the
2006 on a trial I've been added
dissident
named defendant the California trade
secret try
lawsuit but a.m. unless I go to
California can't really do men think
the cat the cat they can to make me but
that
they won't get mixed extradited
at s
good
and their focus is a British
programmer who worked there he did the
first the and CSS actually divided into
two parts you got all three say she
and decryption fell through station call
was posted in assembly
announcement anonymously on the Internet
at the Rec focus is the person who
revolted in C
at on jury member to case
a sweet asian girl segal and
actually did rebuff the GPL Heather but
the
later sold out but don't focus but the
Dec focus got in legal trouble in the
Britain
to be at 2 give away all those rights to
call
on the maintenance s
yeah I I thought the German member about
3-4 days before I left earlier when US
and opted to each member im bout month
s
up
I've been shot been what a what lawyers
like to refer to as the hacker paragraph
K with you said basically says new break
into a computer system
and the second part charges scope right
infringement
our contribution to copyright
it is me whole app
although we're at the time 3
all your I will be sent in this November
and the diction and bright
known only sage I guess is somewhere in
20's
that in German members about 26 I think
s
could
want
yes at
yeah and uses at only call
that common problems so still wasn't yet
but the source code the both the source
gus
that most certainly some internet the
boss some
but it wasn't the same as the binary
Russian
was one of two one of two early russians
sweet should have worked but if he
didn't
I'm not surprised but the binary version
should work fine
yes the only unit
Hill yet
no all
make I'll Mike
could get convicted but won't mean much
on the single count
point
it's not just an election
but actually I didn't really key come
forward was wired
publish my name and song on the live man
miss
s
he will knows the German member he
reverse engineering
the acting any player he sent his the
results to me and I created the actual
DCS application
CD Universe changing
announcement s
think up
up
but you can't really stop piracy there
is no such thing as copy protection
some national way to stop it have to
just
make people buy legal copious by making
reasonable prices
good products skink
good yes that's all
and yes no more questions up
and no way knowing the maximum
and peace two years for the hacker para
of
and that three years for a cop and
change
infringement in California I'm not
really sure
civil town bills
I'm not facing civil Panthers in no way
script it's a criminal charge
s
back
well the region colonies action a
separate issue as the region code is
stored and
a file called me deal underscore PS dot
IFO on the DVD disc store at pics of the
and if you buy a region
to DVD in your opinion what pay and US
left:2d crypt the DVD then edited the
Utes
I file and then you can play it and
that's the only have a region actually
playing
tested
up
yes absolutely that was that's what
we're trying to do trying to redefine
piracy
and take welfare fair use rights good
yeah I think so s
yet yes section yet section ole law
so the they don't really have a law that
it they can
get me get me on slick trying to apply
that all long this case which
probably won't work get a creaking and
DVD disc as a computer system
like broken into my own DVD good
s
good
if Emanuel's lawyers months into
gongs witness I will s
index are we talking to access and that
the sucky circuits issued a
slow
well-lit cutie three value talk about
bolting
or the pipes issue or you got the VZ SS
ellen is great
no a it might end up like mp3
but I don't really find a quality that
good
yes
actually actually sold out I got a job
now I
so I'll be I'll going to take a rest in
high school
as you going nowhere a pillowcase
study study enrollment a sense
and fun couple yes I'll probably be
studying in France
%um and work still up
s
a QP 3p2 resolution you mention up
no resolution what you eat and some but
its Palo NTC
good
both the PAL pala solution is sis
and 2720
times for 80 I can hear it a key step up
to my phone
thanks okay people here know yeah hurry
okay a other the resolution a
impact to video is 124
by 768 a standard that all the hollywood
movies are released
and the player converses to to by the
local TV standard
however if you are hack into the player
and a couple minor
with the proper attack video card you
can have poll
a resolution you can't DVD on
units in Stony you hell and he wishes
and he sent twenty times for 80 NTSC is
yes Balika and
at best but I my understanding is that
the
that's not true recipe that's what they
want you
yes really on the DVD is a is a focal
the picture
by pack player think
yes yes he was your HDTV set but I I was
in there
sentence mater you get full resolution
that is if you take it right of the
additional
asshole quite I'll
Ikea actually not good
hated by hey hey yes we do yourself yes
sorry out its not sell
yeah at another thing I want to comment
on is that in Australia
it's illegal to sell a DVD machine that
has not been hacked
actually open new Dr recess that
perhaps that is illegal to sell II DVD
player that has its own
cold help
I'll as also very likely the whole
European Communities going to is going
to say health ins and goes to
yet cuz I summation you know about look
again okay
problem we'll see so i i think only
america is going to be a step
I living here yeah but you have to you
have a good the lease or anything
really long yes but I've never trust
same color
nice to I i get those day
DVD's I more decent stations such as a
monitor or
you tell which is well not graceful I
would like to see a
sharp their movies online watch like
actually read the little details
credits and other things can never see
on an enticing color
that's all it and your questions
cutie should be questionnaire
bank and the pending trial you can know
and have decided that
take it to court not K hand US only face
charged in California so it's a meet me
in new york
test
else to bring the technology dole phones
that long
if our code is still open to young the
it was on there about a month ago I
don't know if they change it
should be there and that's that there's
no
talk to them again included up s
way
a well good
well im head
yet experience you situation
you actually read the DMCA actually
quite evil day
say really a bad law and hopefully it
will be me down constitutional
excuse me
a keep
I doubt it of and more questions
hood
the well known in no way but you
European Union see passing photon
love unit lane legislations and some
Miami impact knowing
but then nothing that bad as the teams
unit
lead ek
welllll not really because Sunday at
we might find out and we Europeans and
the same position s
death good
our yes
yes that's correct
I
well ed anything sulfur base is not
secure
can mention that
these Norwegian internet guru
he called the same group Shin a
ok and what's this thinking of Mikey
most exception
you fell
that then how good encryption is doesn't
really matter
because it's Eagle it's implemented in
DVD player
suit yourself to reverse engineer it and
dump national
the creation code and the keys and we
have it
yet see as
said and this is something
and I don't really know which one to use
but in he I guess he used the
ida or meet W 32
this as yet
telling us that said
K in
me sleep thank