dude
is Randy Cohen in the house alright
Jello Biafra a supposed to be here at
some point
but here's a link to his own keynote so
okay this is the Napster panel
our moderators when I miss brown 11 take
it over
back I don't go around I'm
it snapped urs out pretty timely issue
right now I'm
at least legally is at a crossroads at
Big Data
senate judiciary hearings on Tuesday and
kinda orrin Hatch
Metallica showed up in roderick went up
the birds showed up
along with that and after executives and
people from the a
recording industry TIAA I'm
I'm here i guess im not really a tech
person
I'll are just graduated from law school
and I'm
I did some research for placed on the
Berkman Center for Internet and Society
I'm at Harvard Law School we put on a
conference on mp3 is very
Anna prince in any kinda like open
source
and how it relates to law basic
technology marches
around check out there their sites I
heard outlawed at Harvard idea
you're interested anyway savers can talk
about I'm
not just the legal stuff I guess for big
picture on
but in general you know what can the law
do in the situation if anything he
should help should be more pro-consumer
should be
know or pro listener pro-army artist and
a
kinda back on question is is music
different and this I'm
in this context is it different from
other kinds of are
based on when answered a.m.
that projects which have the
palestinians I'll start here with that
seeing all my life hi i buy I'm see my
body and often
IIT Jimmy Department of Culture and
communication at New York University
I and I'm I'm basically a call for a
store and i
which means I've dealt with that whole
lotta pieces of paper and
not that many compressed electronic
files
until recently arm and I i have been
working on a history
copyright for a number of years I only
to find that the very end of my book
something exploded into the public
consciousness a at just the wrong time
because I'm not yet done with the book
I but that's the way things go I solve
some I find myself
I having to talk about mp3 and Napster
in terms of its effect on the copyright
system
in terms of its affect on creativity
commerce and democracy arm and some sort
thrilled with the opportunity the
attention
but officer overwhelmed by the whole
thing on and so if at any point I
seem like I a deer caught in headlights
because he's a really bright headlights
I'm often not that are adept attack
person
arm I I know the culture more than a
technology to sell
that hopefully what I will at going here
knows the law
and we'll see what also got going on you
know
was a unless low IQ working radio for
I guess about eighty years and
I currently hosts a syndicated radio
feature tech
news updates on about 300 stations
nationwide
I'm I'm will tack blur
and the news report since news reports
are about 10 seconds long these days um
I really don't think this is a tech
issue anymore in terms of
I mean these guys are saying you know
I'm not really tech person I I don't
think
it's about being
technically astute or whatever because
if your bike he know you can download
Napster
and I your I want you work for
university they won't let you
and Ray and so and since it is so easy
um I think it's kinda
grown into into a bigger issue than oh
this is just
tech geeks um we also have some music
artists
here and which I'm excited about because
a lot of the pro issues people say well
this
you know that this is going to really
help the small guys out but is jello is
saying today
is that really happening so turn it over
to these guys
a I'm James Hanna I'm in a band called
airwaves they a whereas yet unsigned so
basically it's a 75 percent of our
distribution
is through the web using our our web
page and I
mp3truck.com I really don't
I really don't know much about the
specific legal issues but a
it's that we had a direct and act on a
our lives in how much you have been the
most though and I
same and they waged a I'll we went
together for
probably six years around the area and I
that we are setting up the website and I
allowing people who download music for
free a has definitely a
given us many fans from all over the
place
a whether or not a arm allowed us to
sell our own records more
no story but pass to people
here in a music and having access to it
is is gonna
for now you're playing there tonight
right
we should be playing I believe you know
nine o'clock and I remove their
the alright the so I just want to start
with some some questions for the past
sorta kinda big picture and maybe later
we're getting a little more than kinda
not involved in the real stuff but are
basking Zeron
rethink do you think that is a good
thing generally and is the only good for
consumers is also good for us and who is
it
that poor you I think Napster is a
company is our would be almost
irrelevant
it orphans court case I'm in the sense
that we don't need anymore
i mean there are no other file-sharing
programs that work better
arm that will continue to evolve and get
better arm
and the are decentralized and not
subject to
legal action arm but yeah I think this
is amazing
transformative moment up for for world
culture and world music
arm it gives people an opportunity to
hear stuff they could never hear
anywhere else
arm with and he's never before imagined
arm and thats that only gonna be good
for
for the virtual are sharing which you
know from elementary school we should
have learned is very important thing
arm and a very valuable now hear
something keep in mind
arm a lot of his attention about Napster
as a company
and whether or not this whole thing is
going to be good for artists about
products are good for labels are bad for
labels
on ignores the fact that
this is a global phenomenon and arm
a CD bought in a legitimate store
in Bombay India costs about two hundred
rupees
on a cab driver in India makes about a
hundred rupees
a week arm there is no way that a cab
driver in India
can justify buying action leading a CD
collection
on there's no way that that cab driver
can ever hear Metallica
on but effect cab driver happens that
access to a computer
happen to have access to mp3 players um
and
electronic technology a lot more
affordable and India than the actual
items on then this cab driver has an
opportunity here music that he would
never hear anywhere else
on and so it's too early to tell
arm the extent a positive externalities
this
but they're going to be some serious
ones I guess we'll never know we hear
it's good for listeners but I'm
what about artists left already think is
a good for all artists why is it that we
have
be a ours against privacy bring up home
page at
I mean our sins against Arizona yeah
the I'm not going against president but
I'm I'm
plant full page ads in major newspapers
while we have people like Jackie
basically abdicating mp3 away it's
really weird several weeks I've been
working on putting this panel together
for for weeks and I contacted the RIAA
which
I've learned a lot about this company or
organization rather that
they are basically the sister and her
brother the MPAA
to same concept um and
as these guys can tell UN people that I
talk to at Yale and Harvard in
in terms of public discussion the RIAA
jumps out panels at the last moment
they would return my calls I started
down
getting really kinda vicious about it
and just calling every hour on the hour
I and lightly i since I work in radio
I've got friends
I'm they gave me the most direct phone
numbers at the High AA so
that mean I'm really happy I but
you know even up until Thursday they
just
really don't want to talk about this
because pardon me wonder they think
they're wrong if they know that they're
wrong
um in terms of the artists that
you'll notice that the artists that are
anti mp3
in a lot of ways are the ones they're
big enough to negotiate the contract
I have had major big bands come by the
radio station to do an on-air paying
you know they've got an album the
selling well not be talking to a woman
saying the other
get really great you know you guys kinda
came outta nowhere how's it going and
the guy looked one is good let me
straighten the face and set the time on
food stamps
any was serious any
actually had a copy this contract on him
and and and and showed it to me
and from just talking to these guys
you know even if they have a huge album
that sells
well most cases are not seein
hardly any of that money I'm i've seen.
let a record contract and having
10 percent huge
that is a huge huge deal most the time
comes down to four percent by percent
I'm so that's why you see the madonna is
a metallic is out there because they
have enough
pole with their and they've negotiated
new contracts for they get 25 percent
after they get forty percent
so of course there are more upset about
it from
but then you have guys that are unsigned
I
that are like whatever get the stuff out
there get me sign
great time and Jane to keep them
like hear from ya how earns a for is mp3
helping us they offer
food stamps and how it's a well a
as far as you don't really we haven't
actually made any money
any money that we get from it just goes
into like %uh flyering producing more
CDs I mean
we're not selling like 1000 records or
anything like that but
it is allowing us to generate fans I
mean people writer Mike
Singapore in Italy and South America
and something we can never do for
everyone on a label basically
the I'm okay we just words we're just
now joined by
Joe the operatives sat in here I'm liked
it
by saying anything go ahead but I guess
but it sorta I'm not sure why
quite where we are and I would be like a
baby on the way we caught a nap through
panel will start shortly and I got here
started very shortly I'm sorry that I'm
I'm
I guess we can just a ask you where you
stand on that really think it's a good
thing for us
in general they fed earlier today I have
not made up my mind
at all what I wanna get away from is
this black and white
vision that Napster is the big bad major
labels who rip off everyone make a and
from the artist Claire down to the Panda
summer their own employees
than from cases verses the little guy
who just want to check out the music for
free
there's a lot in between their two
arm I'm not against mp3 anymore me i
mean the
the majors are seem to be terrified
because they don't understand it but
didn't fit into their plans to introduce
yet another CD format the buyer
collection yet again
and this time it would go through thick
speakers instead of to remember quite
stereo a any
Jorge her to me it seems like mp3 would
be no more damaging to music
big and small than video rantoul was to
the film industry
and if you recall the MPAA who is suing
the organizer this convention in the
trial starts Monday
originally tried to stop the rental
videos
and thought it would be the end of the
film industry and instead it seems to
double their incomes so up
mp3 I don't feel too threatened by to me
it's a weird
that people wouldn't be interested in
hard goods that maybe I'm just stuck in
that mind
that because I'm a record collector and
have been since I was about 13 or 14
and tho but then when you get the
Napster it blurs
because it not just Metallica and doctor
dre /a
verses kids in dorm rooms
not a that not everybody who makes music
make that much money as Metallica or
doctor dre /a
the problem is there's many many other
people who'd like to be able to even
raise enough money to record another
album or another song let alone quit
their job that they hate as much as most
of us ate our jobs
and care because they can't make any
money on their music
and they're the ones including myself by
my dad
who may I'm not sure but may stand to
get hurt the worst
by this one friend of mine who are might
know
about seventh grade he was with such a
gifted guitarist he could play Hendrick
that aged
well and eventually involved in the
progra
rockin new AG stuff but now world fusion
music we've got interesting again but
anyway he's always done is
own paying strictly to his own vision
does not have any jackass at a major
telling him what to do
the price he pays is he scared shitless
he may be kicked out of the rent control
apartment he's had for almost 20 years
because he can't afford to pay the bills
anymore
so he's put out a website for his band
ancient future dot com
and says for every 900 here
that website get one person actually buy
with the D from him and he is quite
scared of Napster whereby you he might
even lose that extra one hit out nine
hundred I don't know I don't think it's
that
drastic but
may be part of the problem is that the
major labels are so damn greedy
that tho ni originally announced okay
okay we'll make some stuff available for
downloading
50 thongs that are vast catalog most of
which stinks
will be available to download an mp3 for
a generous
three dollars and forty ninth at the
fall
you multiply that by about 10 thong
Thunder thedi here fifteen what that
the virtually equivalent other thirty
five dollars to fifty dollars
CD when you could go by much cheaper at
the store they don't get
in other words and the debt everything
I've ever done is downloadable through
mp3 thumb up it's free the rest i think
is like a dollar 14
trackers something which is less than
the price of a 7-inch singles
like may be driving the price down will
help have also been told by Napster
enthusiasts the thumb
don't mind paying if they know they're
supporting them but you need the money
and the price is the little bit more
reasonable than three dollars and forty
ninth at the thought
but a lot of them don't tho
I double what the solution to that is
except to ask people to think about the
artists
and for the art is who are rolling and
Metallica money who just trying to
scrape by in my case I got in the park
so early I never finished college only
work for two months
and if I lose my livelihood I'm
unemployable
well I think it's yet to be seen whether
people do or don't want hard goods arm
and there's a lot out potential for
this whole technology being really good
for the sale of hard goods
on perhaps and different distribution
methods
perhaps are that point for different
price structure arm
if you if you look at the report that
%uh professor feder from
arm from Universal Pennsylvania Business
School submitted along with
the the a filings that Napster a
filed I guess with two weeks ago on he
very clearly argues that are a good
number
Napster users arm are using this
technology the best possible way for the
music industry
everybody knows the CD sales are up this
year versus last year
are the most frequent number we hear
about 8 percent when you compare the
first quarter fish
up this year where the first quarter
last year on so no one knows
where this illusionary losses coming
from
from and the the survey that freighter
dead showed that
arm most the people he talked to you use
Napster to decide
whether to buy a CD in which CDs to buy
some becoming
more educated consumer better consumers
so if you believe better
this can only be good for the sale of
hard goods and might even be really good
for major labels
arm it if they would stop panicking
about it now if you was in a chatty
truck he says this is going to be the
death made major labels and he's very
happy about that
on and he actually is trying to
represent the interests love
above emerging artists artis you can't
get on radio
artist who can't get on on Warner
Brothers
records on and if you follow his
business model
it might be good but chances are um if
Napster survives as a company
arm the results can be somewhere in
between these two things
some artist are gonna be able to figure
out a business model owada
to make a living with out actually
producing a piece of plastic
and then other artists are going to have
I a lot of success
putting out arm a document which people
so appreciated
still know that sergeant Pepper's a
document that sounds that document
arm and sticky fingers a document even
though the zipper doesn't go up and down
on the cover my CD anymore
arm but you know that's important thing
people appreciate it
are people value in they don't pay $18
bucks for it
arm n if if the price the city's would
come down to a reasonable point
a whole lotta what we call piracy would
probably
go away I'm but the mp3 movement is a
rational revolt a passionate fans
but it is entirely rational arm min
people aren't
reading up a a record store the broken
window
under actually becoming better consumers
I'm so
we'll see how it all breaks out in terms
of dollars on but music still gonna be
music
and people are still gonna be poured
some way the rich might not be as rich
as they are now
but hopefully the low end up the income
stream I get a little bit
better now banks have you got an article
coming out in
nation right that Rd and it's coming out
and Monday and online
online at a nation that I'm
anyway and that you write that LED
copyright system works best do you think
is copyright law relevant here is there
a role for and how the hell about the
artists and
its own what the what it it really I'm
it actually has a lot to do with the the
DCSS case
and a DVD case because on one of the
reasons
that the major labels are freaked about
the proliferation mp3 is a format
is that they can't put it under wraps
they can't
control access to this stop anymore and
controlling access is one things I've
been dreaming of for a long time
they hate the fact you can get you CD
they hate the fact you can borrow your
friend see
they hate the fact that you can check
out CDs from wipers
they hit the back and check out books
from libraries alright because these are
all losses to them
their dream is to have a metered system
up delivery a any cultural material that
would be great for them and
what when they panicked in around 1995
to 1997
screen to the clinton administration
scream to congress that
I digital digitisation up cultural
products
was gonna lead to massive piracy what
they're really saying is
this is an opportunity for us to encode
all this stuff
in in not in the electronic locks
arm and be able to deliver it in streams
and me to rate
are and if everything you paid for me
dirty everything was
part about jukebox that comes into your
home on then they not only control
every time you look at it and charge for
every time you look at something I read
something
on but they can also get rid of this
whole idea
lending or arm even
arm parity I mean they could actually
shut you down if you started causing
trouble
out to any other product at the
potential for cultural control
is overwhelming they don't see it that
way because you know they're not
thinking far had enough to think about
cultural control
up what they want is economic control
and has a very strong arguments for that
on so the beautiful thing about Napster
and a beautiful thing about the CSS
is it poking holes in their plan it
pokes holes in the planet up trouble
wrapping
every piece of culture in copyright law
and electronic locks
and contract law like quick rack wrapped
were you agree to a contract that you
haven't even read every time
quick access a particular site arm so
copyright law is I not neces-
the foundational copyright laws not
under attack by this technology
arm thoughts on the plan
a big media companies to be able to meet
her off and cultural expression is
definitely under attack
and I can ask her a question for jello I
when you found out that people were
were consuming your art without paying
for it
did upset you I am it's been going on
for so long in various forms I mean it
often can be a bigger problem trying to
police
that been letting it go I mean I was
actually a muse and I found out that
Kennedy's that was being
bootleg behind the iron I la make
curtain
in Indonesia and the way it was
identified as rock music was they put a
british
flag on the cover the cat that I know if
I was cool to crack the Islamic curtain
I thought it was funny
they also knew in the day the communist
regimes that were specially repressive
in czechoslovakia
former Soviet Union east germany there
was no other way to get my stuff but
tooth lot but on tapes under the secret
police is no
and my thing was are you serious he said
something to the effect
I'll there is no is that on this pager
not have my little notes I don't see it
here
or do I arm but the
such a good quote i really wanna hunt
for a second I
there and that is that I'll try to
paraphrase that I'm spacing here
the fine mondo 2000 tradition I guess um
and that that is the it is impossible
the control
the flow of non-physical good form they
can be so easily and
infinitely copy Napster even a bad
crack down on something else is going to
take its place
thong bored teenagers somewhere is gonna
find a way
to get around all the lot from the toll
booth
and though again I don't have an answer
for that
the thaw it like it but I get that the
pair when they were with my stuff is
weathered
I mean if it than organized mafia
bootleg I get pissed off especially when
chain stores stock it won't stop the
real
stuff that was a big problem in the
mid-eighties Raleigh
pirate pressing the Dead Kennedys come
helms coming through the mob oversee
and the stores and under selling our own
and we were when we were broken but I'm
like time at bat up that Mia like about
going to the wrong people as far as
people parading live tape and everything
else I didn't care I traded him to
in order to get all the home I have a
confession when I was in high school
I had all night that carry on front
apron France
thank you money a free music is always
been part economy I mean that and that's
and it's true that the good and why and
in the back hallway heart
I'll the way that a lot of emerging
artists and emerging generous
have built them their fan base on both
long before anybody who's signed a punk
band to a major label
on punk bands got their stuff out there
through tapes through friends
through communities and that's exactly
what happening on Napster
communities listeners are getting
together so you gotta hear this is
really cool
which is exactly what my friends did
with me with that Kennedy stuff
I really should but the office later but
abided by all those other
time well we want her exactly 100 but
right now I'm
that figures in debt because the other
former band members
dude me an attempt to steal the
copyright that my thong
which so far they succeeded at trial and
I have to appeal
because I would let him put holiday in
Cambodia levi's commercial
I mean unless opens the weird scary
question
what up some really noxious corporation
like cores or the gap
takes 10 my thongs put that on a
commercial
says well we downloaded it from Napster
so not only do we does not need your
permission we don't have to pay you
a for your thoughts and your voice is
being used to sell a product by
corporation that
folks with you so there example then
when copyright law can help out the
little guy and I kinda situation
everything yeah yeah okay and
see value you've made an outing to to
trading takes a friend like meeting once
a week and swapping mixtape think that
kinda thing
that's pretty much been out at the
National Defense free
relies on at least one part in it do you
really think it's the same kind of thing
because it seems to me that
I I think that's true to a certain
degree but and
is in control Parliament also yes some
punk band start out in like hip hop
stuff starts out with
people getting their tapes at giving
away for free but they're doing that by
choice right
is there a difference there natcher bomb
well
issue control works on two different
levels one is copyright law
does grant creators some limited control
under limited circumstances for limited
time arm
over the duplication up there of that
works and that's considered a good thing
it really is because it does provide an
incentive
to create and to publish and distribute
widely
on and so the middle how this whole
thing breaks down with mp3 the Napster
and Gnutella
there has to be some sort of system that
retains thats
arm that incentive to create I
and it's hard to say how that system
going to work
I'll but a lot up this argument over
control is based on a really
from inappropriate Romanus romantic
attachment
to to the to the the active creativity
in a sense that
a up saying on I you know
a third they're playing with my soul
or they're playing with the product of
my soul and there should be a law to
restrict that
and I we actually don't want to
restricted by copyright system
arm that prevents people from I'll
using and sharing and and rewriting and
commenting on calling from
previously produce material I'm cuz that
actually is where cultural creativity
comes from
think that your money them in jello and
James and Keith maybe I can answer this
on
do you feel that way that it's use a
course XY or something
uses Internet is didn't feel like I have
a moral
I'm transgression against you visit
I think all rape would be a better word
would you date picker and I for term yet
quiet now
buying this lawsuit from people I
thought were my friends
a were you saying before that you think
it's a good thing that
artists don't have complete control over
their distribution because im
will might motivate them to create more
well
is that we said cutlery loss was to be a
balance arm
and you have to take into account the
yet to give artist just enough
incentive to produce a while to
distribute that works but you don't want
to completely close system
because every artist builds on the work
a previous artist now that doesn't
include course
if callers were to take jello songs I
and and even tweet them a little bit
that would be a purely commercial act
arm and I the way the copyright law
works is jealous that some claim to that
arm depending on the contract he signed
with back in the day and all that kind
of stuff
are but so it's not the answers not
simple either side
are but we have to have a balanced
coverage system that has holes in it
that lets are a kid in his garage are
sample
some classic material and put it out in
a new way
on and also lets people make fun of
previous material
arm and lets people use cultural
material is copyrighted in a classroom
of a research or in news media to be
able to comment on it
I'm and all those things are under
threat right now but I don't understand
how that's more you mean it's motivation
the young black male like people on a
that very well very
I'm glad you made it when she signed to
a major label they can by
use what rights they have to your music
against you to create more
ona I i'm not think that without some
church usher
I i mean the the basis for the very
existence the cover system is to
is to give offer some sort of financial
award to creators right but
arm but that's not a complete level
control
over ever use that the music in all
cases there there these very specific
holes poked in the system
up by Congress by users by courts a over
the
the last two centuries that sorta allow
for certain level the freedom
and that's what we call we talk about
their use that we're talking about on
but
core using a commercially produce on in
a commercial is not fair use it actually
I an overtly commercial act and
therefore requires permission
I would also add to that that some
corporation
after being denied permission by the
artist put a bette Midler song on a
commercial with somebody who had a dead
ringer for her voice
and Bette Midler suit them and one
lesley Anne schism good from the ethics
standpoint have Napster and downloading
stuff
um I read an article in a audio
production magazine
about there's all these companies that
develop add-on
software for Pro Tools basically what
most radio stations
stations use for production and there's
all the small companies that write these
add-ons and
people use them every day but what
happens is two or three people and the
audio production community radio
stations and
production houses by it and then they
swap it
online and there's been several cases
where
these companies end up going out of
business because
their stop this you know basically
pirated
and people the use those add ons love
them they use that saw for every day
but they're not supporting the stuff
that they love and it's
and in it kinda sucks because there's
really cool creative people out there
creating stop
any I kinda feel like if you enjoyed
something whether it's gels music
or written add-on Pisa software or
whatever you should put your money where
your mouth is
and support that person financially says
unethical
assertion right what you think what you
think the law can do to to enforce that
if anything
well I mean I don't at your the longer
do you know
and after I'm just a hippie I'm
I think you try to enforce it then
you're gonna get into some pretty
draconian
stuff a and every time you
every time you come up with okay what
they would think we shut down after
tomorrow
at to relevant there there are
masters under different names on the way
or already out there
with the new hello from portraying
what I i think is also like some kinda
strange better spread and
Europe a minute
coming up so shamelessly play to the
crowd if
if everybody used open source software
free software and
almost all cases are we wouldn't have
this problem but that's not gonna happen
I i mean we needed
there will be always commercially
produce offering some it can be great
are summer's gone especially in
specialized industries
be
while 00 I we were talking about supper
Paris in this case
right I'm using parities what this is
all things about thats
that's different arm but not nonetheless
arm
and that's why it was just that I'm
gonna start like router
for the second loss I don't get enough
to my business questions to applaud me
arm but a I
a
however I'm a there there're
to you proposal I mean really two
solutions to the idea of software piracy
one is I encrypt it into such a degree
that its
difficult to get around arm the
the electronic locks but everyone is
wrote room knows that won't last very
long it just
it just rate you know it's like an arms
race and nobody gets
get paid at the and arm and then the
other is
arm is really be at the mall answer and
that is some have
a community ethic about software and
about piracy
and probably about music as well a man
have a healthy
I attitude toward the toward this as a
commercial system
now here's the the thank me every time
um a company like Microsoft or company
like time warner
arm ratchets up the arms race tries to
take
control over big chunk of the culture or
tries to take
control over their product to the degree
that their
you're forcing you to use a particular
system for a particular use you have no
choice
you have to play a Sony DVD on a sony
dvd player
on that makes people angry and they feel
like it okay
to arm trump the system ruin the system
fight the system
matter who gets hurt I'm and thats a
shame
arm but so the only way that people are
gonna stop trying to
a throw the whole system at a black on
is it
all these companies were able to lower
their prices to the point where we all
appreciate what we were getting
for the dollar arm that's not an easy
answer I mean it is something that's
going to have to sort a
I grow up by through communities and
that that's how ethics works on
it people talk to each other about
what's right and what's wrong on
but it's always important to remember
that if you introduce law
to enforce affects your often asking for
more problems than your solving
be to be a little under I have an hour
left at like to open up for
questions from the audience I'm couple
good
be are are on now I a comment and then a
question
um one think that's really great about
the internet is that you can have
the dysentery mediate the the whole
process the retail chain meaning that
you take out the middleman I suddenly
instead of having
the artist and the the listener having a
few couple
you know maybe distributor and
publishing company in the Middle he
suddenly get where the middle to and you
can go directly from one to the other
my question is um
if you couldn't control
the copying process is mainly for for
jello and James here
if you couldn't control people copying
your music I
this cap to affect making money and
music in one is the CD sales are the
music sales and the other is the
performance
fails could you do you think you could
survive just on the
on the the performances I mean talking
about in the Middle Ages we had
wondering minstrel going around
we take and they were here poor remember
the first right people to be executed
when the game got boring
a there's a lot of wandering minstrels
out there who would like to be able to
like get their teeth fixed at the
dentist
or have a place to live that isn't like
a toll
fucking hole and stuff and don't wanna
and the rest of us don't especially
who who are right on the press the first
the falling into that
don't wanna fall into that because
people rich enough to be able to burn
their own CDs in their dorm room
thumb their nose at the idea of paying
the for the music paying the musicians
who make them happy
them know what wandering minstrels are
not the answer but an idea just came to
me
is there is already movements to by you
know abuse the workers in third world
sweatshops for both clothing and other
goods
people like global exchange have stores
that fell
only Fairtrade merchandise
and so maybe one playing to do
would be for the artist per per Miami
really underground one
to form some kind of reunion or
distributor
whereby if you get this from us that a
reasonable price
you know the artist is getting paid and
you know that
you know succubi major labels and
management and law offices are not
getting any p for the pie
because the the free distribution and
copying is unstoppable
that's never gonna stop at this point I
don't know how
though the only thing the artist can do
just say hey you like iced up please
give us a little human respect at the
same time
all thought that a site 10 July get
nobody mentioned yet
speaking of the major label greed Sony
and crew just lost an anti-trust action
by the Federal Trade Commission
who ruled that their CDs were priced
five dollars higher than they ought to
be
in other words if they priced them at
the same price that I sell mine for it
never would have happened to them
that okay what i won to say if all to
make sure the tree in a statement and a
question
I think a.m. over the the last two years
I am Leonia talk about the thing a
Hall I could get my money
yeah but isn't it more than only
thinking about the
how I got my money in the old way I
think we have a
to molest think about the idea how to
get
good generally so the question as
Hall did to the distributed
a all about him um
what's the question of money in the
future that the way we should
a stop to talk about in my hand and my
makes no sense for me to thing
on all we talk about musicians know we
talk about some up with no we talk about
some software engineers
no question s we all Inouye work
not only on the web on the net we look
more than that
and death some some people ok on told
them that
why can be all stand up and say hey come
on w3c of some terrible writer
I work for you up on thumb box II
a program some script I have to get
money from you
and then we can talk about but I do with
10 percent of his money
I can give it then to that net that can
give it back to
1 percent for the militia and so on so
there's more than only a question of
how to get real money or credit card
money
it's a question of how
I think this abuse in all who in the
future
and that's not only questions out of the
side of musicians all
artist generates a the thing everyone
had to
think about because the net as
its it's like it relaxed feel like a
machine
and we were up for this machine it seems
to be very is stranger crazy to think
about this
but in a way at is we are the employer
open that so I am
50/50 should be well for kind of Big
Brother thing
control but did you muck systems which a
you walk around on the window and there
yet a time you on your t-shirt
and the window popped up and said all
come on you had a Walkman in your hand
and you listen to a track
but you weren't hadn't reckoned record
for this all all the next day a GPS
system good controlling me
all my my I get and I scanner because I
look too much on a picture our offer
terribly up I a t-shirt or whatever have
you have to think more
yet to use your pension deal with what
what what what could happen
if you say okay no interest I'll never
know down there down upon a bit so
you're
your basic question was why are we cut
is the kind of false distinction between
music
and other kinds O intellectual works is
that kinda what you're getting at
yet that about the future money that
they talk about the future
yeah thing I think up the ECA economic
redistribution generating
so in the meantime against
okay I'm you pick your people yet it
felt very socialistic but my own filler
another P professor told me a
capitalistic
in a spiral I think way that the thing
is I think way
the perfect speculate on real quick to
than online expression by the capital
and I think that that
the comparison between like coaters and
musicians is tough because
I think that minutes there's a lot of
parallels but
on cutters can give back to the net help
build the net and you know make it a
better machine but
I don't musicians and music is a much
more purely aesthetic code
is is that it also is functional and so
I think it's that tough analogy to make
but anyway next question
a swell try to make this is our quick as
I can but
arm a like it has a line behind me but
anyways are I'm not allowed to say too
much but sent I talk to my house and
tall a company check a day it gave me
permission it's more information out but
I'm currently beta testing you know a
new sort of music distribution like
Napster
the code names called artfully but they
plan it Cain shit official name sometime
down the road but
anyway so this is like it unlike a
Napster client is still allows you know
person the person the communication up
mp3 files
I'm they're still you got all mp3 or not
so St Elmira like call sodomy protected
right time and anyways I'll
the system well basically every time a
files changed
will display a couple a banner ads we
don't know what's coming 15 yr
whatever the official it but it just
kinda I'm getting rough layout but
ill display banner ads the advertiser
pays for those abs
percent goes to partly company and then
the rest let me know goes to the artist
um unsigned artists as well he'll sign
record companies condemns
met registry into the database
but anyway some other terminals with
this so system that's been brought up
and why it's probably going to be too
late for a while coming out
and I guess I can direct that question
to
too many artists on the panel how would
you feel jello and indicate about
having you know that meant getting paid
and you know you're going to get paid
every music on the net
to happen at embedded in in our mp3
the app's not embedded in the file it's
only up display you have highlighted
transfer
well yeah he's on the air at and the
officially weirded out download anything
a mine mp3 is WWW more damn
emo Rd a.m. records dot com which is
advertising
free the last thing I would want would
be 10
like why my spoken word piece die for
oil
soccer being downloaded wall in at to
join the marine
playing across the mp3 player in
that cool why I haven't time community
for example well if there is a in the
currently on a pure
I copy back for a playback
program that are
a AZ I i can claim such more
I apparently I after some mad about
balance from
per day the artist is I cut a certain
amount of money
based on the %uh place so but still his
laptop based on some sort of a
sponsorship program where somebody's
like sponsoring like
are you know its banner ads on the
website min
why
gathered specific question when is move
on to the line
okay on it style online I have
questioned of
okay well let me get her one quick
question
yeah well the thing with this music
software is it's also going to have on
my question yeah
it's gonna be a have this John Rhys
system in their work gets down the more
detail but
a thing as as what another thing to
worry about us
what do you think the idea that pretty
soon there's not going to be any like
major top bands name or any other pretty
so you know everybody's gonna other
customize music collection and you know
it's like okay
one band has like 200 advanced gather
around the world where you getting this
idea from
where we watchin TV advert when you put
your channel felt like that but there's
back in the big bands that by everybody
listens to and then Mike
a small group of people that has more
the first case there's always going to
be pop culture and and you're never
going to get rid of the Britney Spears
and the hell I I we know we know that
for a fact but but you're saying that
like being out big time you're always at
LA
millions of albums if we get back to
wandering minstrels for a minute I think
you're not gonna see left the
that you may theme or because the
the the culture corporations figure well
we can't make any money on albums
anymore
so we're only gonna push makeup pop
stars
and in order then what people are
conditioned to desperately wanna see
these make a pop stars in order to make
back the money we would normally make up
the days after all major labels now own
concert venues
to universal concert is part of the same
universal they don't then CA editors go
well because of that we decided to raise
ticket prices to a hundred bucks
and only the hundred people they all the
bad people willing to fuck up at only
about 100 bucks
the theory are the only ones anybody's
going to be able to see
that is the the nariño I would not want
a theory on top of that they might
also cut the lead we've got for youth
good to give a shit about their music or
we've got somebody pretty
all we can do 100 dollar cut third and
market dolphin action figures
which cannot be downloaded through
Napster let's go with that
doll come on Britney here we go get all
the money that either
next question the next Hicks idly I make
your questions in the form of a question
alright yeah up to a clever at
streaming across her I
continuing I continuing with the banner
ads I issue
I go ahead please better at will call
you know more pretty soon after dawn
Marty my partner in crime and I get
through
I he actually has a a proxy at the DP
.org
I a way to block all double click ads
and
on krajina write a book like 101 ways to
find the owner
and a question for a question is some I
think that people still buy it like what
does the hard goods
and Mike with a red hat box that's free
software and bookable by
do you think that people's will
'em drop-off in growth mp3 become the
definitive
a I'll you non making me
magnetic media format not visible why I
can't speak for everybody but
I don't think on a bus stop by and
cities for a long time I really like 'em
on and I've already invested several
hundred dollars and
the machines the plane I only have one
machine plays mp3
arm and it weighs eight-and-a-half
pounds I can take you to the Gen
I hope you like dropping a few hundred
bucks for another machine the place them
on and i also do think that that liner
notes a valuable
I think cover art valuable arm and I
think
an album actually works together if
it started as an album now I never
listen to
on insane Kalmar the way through but we
wanna bet it's not actually an album I
do wanna bet its
two or three a singles and a bunch of
filler
arm on the other hand you know
Springsteen's Nebraska is an album
and if it came out today arm it would
only be valuable as an album
we reach new york is now much
effortlessly from beginning to end
on and you can't really pick a single
out a bit every some cops to itself so
I mean to live in in some sort of all
our I made up for that just cleared
music fan speaking
every other kid in America may have a
completely different view of albums
but albums became the that choice for
distributing
music be out singles in not the way to
succeed early seventies
because people really like the idea such
a paper Quadrophenia
I mean that really move people arm so I
mean I don't think it's gonna go away
for a while
although thank you when not today 20
twelve-year-old become tomorrow's
20-year-old comfy nor even
ever to buy a CD player let alone a
turntable that
could change I'm yeah this is in
response to what Joe
same for about strand doesn't have a job
and he just
works on his music is a really talented
musician
and we haven't address the independent
scene so much but I'll
I've been in and out a pop-rock band and
just all kinds music for years
and you should know that if your gonna
do that not have a job you can be living
off food stamps no matter what
but as in terms of Napster spreading I'm
the music throughout the US are you
gonna make your money
you gonna have to go on for just putting
up a website and just trying to sell you
see
CD again so many hats or whatever I
you're gonna have to life-giving well
this is just the response I don't have
that almost finished up for
but up yet you're going to have to go
out on tour
a supposedly naps are probably get your
CD hyped up if you have one out
and there's no way I'm just gonna make
it just by not having a job
you can be really out in that really sad
but
you just not gonna make it just our you
should know because you know
you have your own label about pancho pop
rock band rose know and everybody on
that label would dearly like to quit
their fuckin shit chop
and play do what they really love whole
time
sure what up some those bands don't
really tore how many of them
ours do how many CDs that up buzz kill
cell
um not as much as I wish IIIi
thanks very much here's why i'm I guess
at some that are
yeah when the biggest thrills as a
musician is performing
performing live so i cant you really
just can't %ah
sit at home and not try to sell your
music over the Internet or
through your mailbox and really be
satisfied as a musician
I think there's another issue 2 is it
are you creating art with music or
whatever
to make bank are are you trying to
express yourself
and maybe introduce a new concept other
people
and make people think about things I
think punk rock and a lot of activist
music
um it may not just be about the docket
it's about
social change sky
the next question um I really like I'm
what does heard about
I'm absurd have a union or a
million online independent label that
every musician that was interested could
be a part of that
I'm unit so that the the consumer are
the listener
would R&B buying it for for a reason
and I was also I was thinking about time
we talked a lot about what might happen
are a little bit about what might happen
two major labels but what would happen
to independent
labels a if the Napster type thing it
was really big
and if we didn't have some kinda union
or
other kind of cooperative met so I just
I was instead of just
have people talk about that again we
might not be able to afford to pay our
bill
in the halfcourt do you need labels for
well I don't want to have to do every
got damn phone call to every radio
station every press person in every
letter that comes then myself
I don't have time I K create anything
anymore by do so I MUST hire somebody
else to help me with that
and at this point the label has nothing
at all to repair decal has five people
working there doing various things
and the reason other people come to
wanting us to put out their stuff
is that tho those five people can help
get their stuff out there
too far more than that then people who
would find it random browsing on the web
so the 182 or somebody might have heard
above and actually show up to ring that
do a damn bit a good if nobody goes to
see you play
I think they've also bull the it'll be
harder to have an independent label if
announced that thing is
never it'll be different it'll be like
some independent labels are gonna be
able to
grass the stuff really well and run with
it Tom
I know a well my that supply I don't
know I don't run away but I think what
money the Broncos any different cuz
label on is probably going to do really
well
because it has such a strong are fan
base
I people who are deeply loyal to her and
and the bands that are with her on and
they don't have a website yet
and have there something like twelve or
fourteen span based web sites for
and they all point she they'll give the
address up where to get the season where
to get the t-shirts
arm and you can get her stuff on mp3 all
over the place
but people are still buying her CDs
whether it's in the back up concert hall
or it's out there they're sending her a
check are and
if you can work that out i mean overhead
might be lower might be higher you don't
know
been the web changes all those questions
on on the other hand there's there's a
II truck is repetition that com is an
independent label
arm and itself at space and that I would
generate revenue
on it also are likes to I think the
church dollar song I am and what I want
I'm pretty sure HR two dollars on
for download and and thats truck do you
think it really shows you what labels
worth
arm away ball is a gatekeeper it's
making an editorial decision
for you and saves you time if you wanna
hear on artist
that that chuck dee dee eggs arm and you
don't want to have to wade through
300 mp3 downloads for $299 again be crap
I'm interested in a calm and his people
have a
sorry given it a stamp of approval and
you like everything else you've heard
their
the gatekeeper function works and that
can save everyone a lot of time and
money
and maybe distribute a little money
within that economy as well so that
these
folks who can't get on major labels and
certainly can't get on radio
can make a little cash I in addition
want to get touring
get another question arm I well maybe a
little more about the
possibility that happen Union I'm I
wanted to just hear what other people
are thinking about back kinda pasady
I know that s maybe that's 12 to think
about afterwards I guess out of the top
of my head
that came to your Yahoo 11 all
though make me run it I already got to
my you ok
what to do anything about us to move on
to the next time question please
I'm I have a at two questions one based
on
the response to that last question the
first question is
that everybody I says all these
wonderful things in the beginning about
how Napster is going to be used to get
you know people in India access to
Metallica or people in this country
access to independent songs that they
don't say
but all the software from what I see is
you search for so long
and in my experience that only only use
Napster once
and I did a search for Devo internet one
copy with it
I did a search for bin will they might
be Giants and turned up nothing
and found a million copies love whatever
Britney Spears in Inglewood
why I tell you what and I'm just sayin
that
people are searching for what they want
so is added
really gonna be that you just had the
most popular music on there
in a way but for stopping what they
might be giant city music dot com
II I black inferno me that has set and
they
they might be dances totally down with
any sort of new business model the deals
electro music distribution
because they they hated that they got
the short end the stuff for years from a
joyful
however are now but that's really the
question and the solution to that the
one the only way that
that emerging bands marginal bands are
going to actually win this game
is if communities of listeners operate
the way they should know where they
always have I think they well
on one of the great things about Napster
is I you can talk to other people
who share your musical tastes are and
you can do to Gnutella to order that
their massive traffic can you tell is
really sort of that poor right now
arm is in a gene Hart army I thought
that she was supposed to be hard
and maybe this happen pressures newshour
it's like new resin
PG&E roomies II thats
yes it's like me it's like they're
writing about water so anyway
by animal fragmentary but the arm
hit communities that listeners are
allowed to
I give each other taps I tell people
what's hot what's good
which is how much music as always work
arm then
then yes you can find stuff not gonna be
able to find evidence you like bill
fight back catalog stuff that well
I'm actually surprised that you know
someone else hasn't decided some major
develop and as a but every device on on
there maybe they are there somewhere but
you just get lucky
I think this is also a reaction to to
what happened the radio
um radio has changed dramatically
two or three companies own every fucking
radio station and that's no lie
there's companies that own 8 100 radio
stations
their I is one guy to decide all the
music for k-rock New York k-rock LA
and live 105 in San Francisco out with
the computer
and its and I'll and in a lot of cases
some
it a it is a the software
is called selector I and
and it's getting to the point now where
actually have a colleague that works in
Denver
and they have a a little farmer DJ's
there the DJ's
read the computer they say there's a
Metallica song in a van Halen sign they
go it alone without a doubt Van Halen
and that voice file shipped to radio
stations nationwide and placed in
between those songs and those songs are
displayed of a server
at radio stations in those markets
that's what happened a radio and I think
that's that's why Napster and the
Internet music community is a reaction
to that because
the radio really really sucks had
in
don't get another crack yeah
maybe last photograph playing music
during the techno file
as well they should you know I'm jealous
said a before about the labels that it
was
the artist finding something to work for
them but because they couldn't do all
the work
and is not part the problem that the is
in the current system now that the
artists are working
the labels on working for the artist the
artist working for the labels in most
cases
major label yes independent label
hopefully not all that does not count
the independent labels who are wanna be
major labels
they were shall remain nameless below
a I was wondering if you think a stuff
like the Napster is gonna cause more
horizontal and vertical consolidation
integration in the industry for
perfect I'll stop where you're talking
about like a company owning not only
a Becker companies but also doing like
the concert and stuff like that
is you know sup like the Napster going
to change that
or its gonna make it worse at go ahead
I'm
Gophers I have no idea I like anybody
that's what's going to happen to that
with that but another thought that
occurred to me up here as
imagine if Metallica and Napster go to
trial
and the ruling is that not only Napster
can do what they're doing but anyone
else can
to so immediately Microsoft moves then
Sony moves then Oracle moves there and
and
weep Napster clear out the door the site
finally will be just like the fifties we
don't have to pay
anybody anymore that I would hate to see
competition question also because that's
a real wealth
doing and one other wanna claims in a
countersuit by up to get lawyerly per
second but it's good news
I'm and want to claim the countersuit by
natural lawyers against the RIAA is that
can obscure claim call abusive copyright
know basically saying that the
RIAA in the labels that belong to it I'm
are
base for making this suit in bad faith
in order to keep out
this format that they see the threat so
that can address that
that question hello I was her
overall wondering can you stop it I mean
can anyone they try the government right
they went right to stop technology
but I think the problem is that they
don't realize that you can stop
something
because its never it's always changing
I mean you have Napster and Gnutella you
have cue that Mac you have all the
things I mean you have mp3 she has asst
up movies
I mean shut down mp3 it is going to be
something else
I mean and you see Lisa better people I
mean
metallic like doctor dre /a Eminem to
the really have a right to be better
and then go apostle these are the
poorest people in the world
or were considering a that now i mean
dali you can even do that well
and there you really Carphone dali
really well
than any girl however is exactly what
I'd hate to see aspiring musicians wind
up like
her the crowd at
same question is about at I mean like I
my I suppose my question is that
I mean what's really the point I mean
the about in taking the RIAA against mp3
that common after
I mean is can anything really be
accomplished well
that sinister question i mean the for
small there's nothing
thats arm the RIAA can do
about all the mp3's on everyone's hard
right right now they're not gonna sweep
through an attack
I users although Metallica likes to
attack users
are the RIAA does not because it's bad
business to alienate your
your potential customers and deep in our
hearts they know that the people who are
collecting mp3's
are the biggest music fans in the world
so going after
boss me included would be really bad
business are
that's number one so they're not going
to what you just said you re not gonna
go after users
is are as previous operate cases have
shown
are when the motion picture industry
tried to go after people
for time-shifting for recording a shows
at eight and watching a bit
at midnight on congress and the courts
always stand up have always stood up for
what for a
a for what mister and missus America do
in the privacy of their living room
unless their inlet harried conceptual
potential effect between
people of the same I'm have the same
gender that's that's a totally different
issue than
however arm a so
so no they're not going to bottle up
that the reason for going after after
Napster
a is out of frustration and arm
ultimately it's not its yeah purity I
know but it's all
it's a strange thing cuz I mean they
gotta know that if they get an
injunction against Napster on July 27
on July 29 all the staff to use and
Romney tower
and there's nobody can sue at that point
arm and
I mean it's just going to be in amazing
shape everyone knows what's up
arm and and there's really nothing they
can do except
except that deny all these venture
capitalists are I
all the money that they've invested in a
company that basically have a good I'm
convey
don't charge for anything anyway and I
guess one last question is that
what is I haven't heard one response
when the
reasonable reasonably acceptable
response to
the claim in the pac-10 record still too
record sales are up
are up a per set and I listen to the
Senate Judiciary
work hearing on natural isn't like
everything on the news and record sales
were up till
what it what the big deal and a problem
is control they would love
to get secure digital music it would
love to be able to wrap everything and a
well would love to be the way that they
deliver this music
and they want it delivered through your
cable box are into a player that they
supply for you
and their dreams are being dashed
because a couple other a
a couple a very creative programmers
decided
to to make a few simple leaves and the
system are
and thank goodness for creative
programmers because they're the only
ones protecting
I us from a completely sealed system
kaelin like I am
take one more question what am I talked
about right now is we're little bit over
time
as it I like to comment first the every
type
seen more control IC market
not grow him shrank I so the real issue
i think is
how a relief I think is isn't the whole
distribution channel
for music movies 6 Adara controlled by a
small number people
and what they're really fearful love is
looting back troll
and are we really talking about changing
the whole business model
in such a way that who knows how it will
actually change the long run
but I think I disagree that people are
gonna stop buying
CDs at all I think that the whole market
is just think it
huge just gonna grow more but it's gonna
be a different market
it's no longer going to be controlled by
a small number people
is gonna be controlled by a larger group
of people and more independent for
example will be able to get into the
market
more be and will be able to get the and
and if the result will be more music
bought not less
metallica is pissed because a song that
you can't are you couldn't even buy at
the time
was really some years ago unfinished
rarity or something
is an hour that well I think a lot of
people use an app for that
finding some like obscure parking German
b-sides or something like that
not just from the album versions and
that was that I can make a difference
man if you want your
if you like the band you want the album
you want now it's not going to change my
butt is that bad I mean look at all I
think Madhubala metallica which it
believes is sponsored by some large
record company
the Metallica fans are out there looking
for more metallic music they should not
be glad I like it how it should be
flattered that some want to hear
something that might impact unfinished
and now you're gonna find pick up your
gonna disagree
power but only have one more thing that
some rather have been
way the most socially significant song
up this here maybe this entry
you wanna to this entry start already up
was American skin by Bruce Springsteen
which you can only hear an mp3 arm he's
he's not recorded it he probably won't
record it the guys been a business
twenty five years
he's released two live albums if you
don't wait for a live burden
Americans can you be waiting another
15-20 years to get run to another one
but American skin is about important
public issues
arm and a and there's been so much
public discussion about because the
police reaction
because I'll are various journalistic
interpretation there's a lot of good
commentary going on in various
publications
about what that song actually means and
two but without mp3 there would be none
of that public discussion
or more question isn't a Napster just
the directory service
I mean if it get shut down because it's
providing a directory services all the
other directories should be shut down
also
right and that's that many other women
who had will grow in its place
the next day that's that's why the
argument that NASCAR's gonna make in
their loss or they have made in their
brief is that it's simply a director in
them person and in writing
to list the stuff against it the other
side that is with the IAEA's planning is
that
that its they're contributing copyright
infringement it's not just the
Directorate said
it's a place it to step up to the mike
get some say
I'm it's a place where you know people
come to share files and so that's
the other argument anywhere last
question lol couple other things
gotta get that the I yet I is not number
one
on the eight percent rise in thedi fail
the third
only news to me I hadn't heard that I
have to question
what percentage a bad 8 percent actually
came from
independent and what percentage of it
came from the skyrocketing fix
bath and think and and others failed
with
well that one thing that might be
skewing that
figure and another thing that skewing
the bar that independent for
automatically growing and will
automatically grow
that is not necessarily true and I mean
fail the money
at least independent rock label: have
been going
deadly down over the past few years
and party but maybe because more and
more people are listening to hip-hop and
electronic music is another generation
comes up
but another reason is that especially
after the Nirvana explosion and then the
Green Day explosion
way more people wanted to be in band and
do it themselves or
and portly trust fund babies also began
starting labels for the wrong reasons
but the point being more and more cool
bath
more and more cool label but the
audience
did not grow anywhere nearby the same
level
for the flight to the the pie for those
artists
get smaller and smaller and smaller and
smaller and smaller
that if not death there early growth
up an individual independent artist
there maybe more artists that the fight
the Pirates deadly get lots more
okay one more quick question okay it
seems to be a way you're saying is that
what pisses you off isn't the little guy
just
downloading music to sample and stuff
but when
people take your music and then make
money off it
while you're not making so what's your
question
and while masking you think you'll be
helpful ever copyright
a audit is Semoran
to been new I'm
license where it can be distributed
and people still live CDs they are but
company cannot take your music and make
money while that I can then
night taking music and clearer
commercial make money often
well tech technically they can't do that
now I mean I
yeppers course couldn't take someone
signed play on their end without getting
soon lose and
I mean like we're staying up for yellow
that I've already
but I'm more like coming
healing but like a licensing scheme
kinda thing right the way the way open
source work yeah exactly right with me.
there already is a kind of
compulsory license for if you want to
version of someone else's song
I say like wet Van Helden cover
you really got me however the picture to
recover winter long by
annually on you have to let the other
band cover it
but that's a different thing from
copying the song but anyway I guess on
would wrap it up through every time it's
like to ass gotta thank me and I'm
ok helped me thank the palace rather and
in
in good
also thanks to Glenn who came all the
way from Washington DC
to have this panel in
doing