the cells can you not everybody
what most fearsome Marcel back on
schedule have a cap attack
guys its
I think there's actually one of us here
who is scheduled to be here
you I'm returning from the CDC
a.m. this is oxblood um
motions did you supposed to be here he's
on a plane
that's why we're here I think added
together we mention mental
pounds all approaching
home also I think wrong bus routes post
I'm not quite sure why he's not by
god damnit were gonna carry on made over
here
arm on shapeshifter mama social justice
activism
organizer for the RNC protests the
max um
so as a I'm afraid the sounds really
disorganized
think we're really gonna shine on the
cumene and
you that you told me last night that he
couldn't make it so
here we are um so
I I think the interesting thing about
activism is
week we have yet to arrive at a formal
definition on
the no one's really quite sure what it
is although it's
something that gets you in the newspaper
when you pull it off
and usually involves doing something
illegal
play on beyond that no one's really sure
um either its and defacing web sites
or opening up firewalls for a
citizens and foreign governments to be
able peruse the Internet
and see whatever size they want I am
or its a massive distributed denial of
service attack
against part to the Internet house
information
you don't like om for our part I don't
think we've actually
proposed any definitions
a like pete was saying before there are
depending on what side up to social
justice or
hacking community divide you sit on
different people even spell it different
ways if you go to
all to this store Google or something
useful activism with activism with an H
in front of it
he'll get a ton of stuff I if you get
the CDC proposed spelling which is
packing with to visit Mon benefit you
get one entry
so I'm not really sure what that means
but it
it's interesting that different people
take a different ways I think
this being a certain amount of activity
in the last six months I believe
with the electoral hippies in the UK and
a few other groups who are essentially
social activists and the at
technology onto traditional forms
organization and social protest then
you've got
number of people in hacking community
who are interested in this
area I food need
very few people to help them participate
in anything one person could
probably do something in college
activism so
it it would suggests that on one hand
requires large numbers on the other hand
possibly very issue or many depending on
you want to involve it it is very
interesting that it means
a number of things to different groups
I'm one of the things that
I personally been trying to work on over
the last year cell
is forging links between hacking
community
and the social justice community other
two very distinct groups
often don't talk or occasionally talk
past one another
on they have very different ways
operating and receiving a problem sir
issues and then executing against those
is a project that the
the CDC is undertaking I am
will be starting are we in fact we have
started
I'll a hacktivist application
development group we have in that group
I
six people I to affirm I know I can name
now the others I just haven't been able
to nail down and find out if they want
their names
publicly associated with this bit wanna
see a technical members as braun pastor
who was supposed to be here today
I and another name some as you might
know the mixer
German hacker through Road an explosive
that distributed denial-of-service
application which
we do not endorsed by the way I'm but
he's very
a gifted technical expert and will be
helping so
under our direction we also have
a couple luv international human rights
lawyers
I am Not sure that I can mention the
names but a lot of people would know
they are
I and one or two members at the social
justice communities so
we will try to develop applications
have them spread through attacker world
on this on the other hand
I on the other side of the street we're
going to try to get a lot of each
social justice groups involved I sherry
interest in
many of the same issues so is going to
be an interesting project
trying to unite or two forge some kind
coalition working towards something
positive
she could I um and talk a little bit
about
direct action and I think hacktivism
fits into a direct action is
arm direct action is when you take
action against saddam
let's say a corporate entity like the
MPAA or Microsoft
or um maybe a pharmaceutical company who
is denying access to essential
medications for people who
linder all nations who can afford them
arm
basically with direct action is you take
action against them
and it can be L Ranger things you can be
on civil disobedience in the street
personally on the street activist
arm I do up for just this reason I'm
organizing for the
RNC which the Republican National
Convention amber up organizing protests
against them
and other corporate sponsors and how
they don't represent
people but the rear percent corporations
so long basically
activism is like sort of you know it's
its in that spectrum
what direct action is arm activism sort
taking a different approach
arm most people think about activism the
think I you know
people in the streets changes something
like shine K
it says you know IMF World Bank on the
side it
or a you know or if you are dropping a
banner of %uh
a building that has the message on are
like a greedy section where they take
over a ship
thats does whaling something like that
so
activism is for the new approach and
again
be ok the effective tool think then in a
getting your message across as part of
the bomb but
all the civil disobedience of business
you know mom we get attention to bring
to our issues that we're bringing up
arm so there's like direct action
against the RNC you know
be there's people on the streets you're
protesting at there could also be very
well be people on the web for protesting
it as well
home so
as
Jimmy close this seems to be little bit
more workshop the lecture and I think
that's okay
and so in the beginning
and when defining activism it might be a
good idea
to say at least but hectic isn't is not
is that thing the heck a community has
to be very carefully
we live in the year two thousand if
someone drops out the banks he doesn't
take a machine gun he takes a computer
and it for political group having lotsa
bullshit in brain
protesting against anything there might
be forms where we can say this
hacktivism
but if its comes to deny non-citizens
into structures
we had that story without Legion up on
the ground
I remember maybe maybe you can say some
words to that
so I don't want to be involved in
terrorism and i think is very important
for hackers to say we're driven by
curiosity
and not by a denial of service which is
vandalism
or by you now love financial interest in
robbing banks whatever
cell I think at it might be a good idea
to make a list
what is hacked it is in at least from
the motivation and what's it not
said to get also in the media a little
bit more
shop and feature on this sure um
although I don't know if you're here for
the last panel
and the prospects educating the mediocre
to poor I guess
a yes I wasn't and that's the reason I'm
standing up because
I think it's a said patriot if this
attack UK trees and then we talk about
that is hacking someone says although it
might be these might
this sameee read the heck he tickets
written down heck is
wants information to be free said it has
to do with living but doing it has to be
by
to real city and it hurts not to do
maybe not even to do with computers for
me
okay I mean computer is just a tool
and tools might change but the
motivation
should not change because other ways it
might be like
getting a hammer in your hand and then
the whole world it's like nails and
thats
dangerous situation brain um
is a good comments and questions um I'm
a little afraid just
and step forward and say what is
hacktivism one and what it is not
because and I think
intelligent people can have serious
disagreements over this
arm myself and I think fluoresce the CC
we
we agree that we should not be denying
access to the Internet
or to particular web sites just because
you
disagree with the content on any on
whether that's a corporate site
or you know political site the IP
dispute greatly
mmm I think we believe that more
speeches better speech
than the enough you're serious about
the marketplace by ideas that the
internet supposed to be that
you not gonna go try to damage
infrastructure Gahanna
country-level on a website level on a
you know whatever back to me and
I think one of the issues that will be
evolving over time
have to sure how to deal with said is
parted the whole
activist perspective is issued civil
disobedience
something we saw through the civil
rights movement it's probably the
easiest example in the United States
where
group certain groups broke the law of
the land because
interview was immoral so this is always
being sorted this idea of
occasionally breaking the law further
social justice
now it in certain instances it's
extremely clear
you know party
issues civil rights issues the United
States and other things
and over time these things been
addressed and but a lot of people were
arrested
and they sought to be arrested in this
is one of the things I'm almost
worried about with wit activism that
people made
make excuses to
do something rather extreme
and and and who's going to decide well
is this a good idea or is it not
this is more learn of me at the end of
the day the public is can decide
agree with something on on but this is
going to be something that's definitely
going to be coming up in
I don't know like ish if you like the
occasion read
Wired News you find out that somebody's
defaced certain website and they're
saying that activism
I'm I'm often very confused i cant
tell often the difference between
somebody to chasing web page in somebody
saying they're doing it for political
reasons I think it's the kids become
somewhat convenient
saying no one is doing this practice
reasons and
its its third quite a few gray areas is
there are
all throughout packing in general
should once more common
you question and no breach a Swedish I
think
actually laid out a pretty good ground
rules for whether not act is not as
did you did you pick your cause before
you picked the site
i think is funny as free logic
that's why 1 a.m.
first policy mister BF remember getting
wounded shows
15 sixteen years ago I homo younger than
mister Joe
on-site at the half I lot okay
thing and senator about arm but my
question is this:
I ahead expands our interests are on but
recently called
distraction and industry action and I
believe this is Britain
before the deputy wtoo demonstrations
there are some very interesting things
they talked about in terms people
organizing
and in very interesting ways and doing
things
to perot change using all school
technology
useful technology using identity
changing things using
economic systems that were not part of
the mainstream economic system
I read that again very interested and
hacktivism I suppose
because it was a science fiction book
and
I went through a bunch a voiceless
bookstores and a
activist posters in New York and I found
nothing
except a lot of a leftist rhetoric that
was mostly anti technological
and my question is think it's important
for the activist community and I
whether it's leftist or some other term
applies to it
don't care I think it's important for no
people that are
pro technology and see their uses
deposit uses a technology to communicate
with
she wrists who I think are very used to
seeing technologies in a good thing
and a I'm wondering is there a way how
can we get together
and communicate with clinic with the
other side
arm I've been in parts and both have
been activist I'm also
here kind of project Knology for certain
reasons
and what can be done to you nineties to
keep I think if leftists
or activists can see to use technology
in a certain light there will be a lot
less rhetoric against
and there will be a lot more movement in
certain directions that maybe hacktivist
oriented
home but I have no idea how these table
for
negotiations we take place
I can us to answer that um I think
technology
arm its bad in some aspects and it's
good in others it's bad
when Armani oil company has the
technology and they're drawing on
somebody's native land I think that's a
bad application of technology
or on one issues for us things like
nuclear weapons and the
with the thought that doesn't make any
sense at all even a blog half the world
say can chill out how they are
like how big your out guns are I'll be
the leader technology is a hella
tough you are on I think some
applications of technology earnest
completely useless and bad but then
there's other things the leak
and demonstrations and mustard the TT 0
demonstrations and the 16 demonstrations
in
and 90°c be used we had a whole
communications network setup
where arm we could tell what was going
on
across the entire city like what the
police for doing what the delegates were
doing
we were able to coordinate using that
technology so I think communications
technology can be good when it's in the
hands of
activists and social justice activists
and also on
as the issue of the independent media
arm the independent media
was baby by using um
like they had a high-speed connection to
the Internet and
that helped the the social justice
activists in that we got a story
on unedited to masses amount to people
tourism we had arm satellite up things
and people on cable access
TV stations around the country were able
to download that
so I think at the hands of Weezer to
democratize these a technology that we
can
like it's its toll useful bottom as far
as %uh
as Microsoft and Tino you name it what
corporation
arm I don't think they should have day
control technology
its I'm not to disagree on
irish lotto points at I totally agree
with her on
I'm really sends a strong a and
I think ish if you're my kinda activist
and you're pretty your particular
political opinions don't really enter
into it
I don't particularly care if you happen
to be very liberal
mostly clear scissor conservative Julie
not my thing but
on the thing I'm most interested in is
what do you think about global Internet
liberties
you know what do you think about on in a
citizens of the world being able to
access the internet being able to
browse the web and send mail to whatever
they want
without interference from the government
or tracking you know they need to be
able to have
free speech privacy access
and encryption and is your for those
stains
think you are defied all activist
or your back to the same place
on the only thing that some one thing he
said that
like basic question is what most people
don't have access to the Internet
rent a majority of people on this planet
it's a big gap and right now the way it
is some
most people don't have enough resources
to get a computer
mom and thats marking the economic
system we're currently in is
I'm capitalism's pictures that some
people get a whole lotta money
and then most the rest the world Esther
support those few people on their habits
I agree entirely although some
I don't know if you've noticed it was a
very small blurb in the San Jose Mercury
News
last month but figures 3 paragraph
stating that
the United Nations has released a report
I am
and predicting that by the end of 2004
every single human being on the planet
will be within half a day's
lock up and internet terminal
I'm whether or not whether or not
they will have the money to pay this
different story
and will whether or not their government
allow them to
access to news sites they want to
actually read or
publish information for that matter
that's a different story but the rock
hardware will be there and a very short
order
I think sigh I think it's interesting
that
discern two sides of this issue
two different perspectives you from the
direct action signs from hacking
community
he's very valuable that as many people
as possible get a hold of computers and
do have access
I think that's one particular challenge
in its
very noble work to really initiating get
that going
might my particular take on this is
I want to make sure that when those
people do get onto the internet that
it's still
essentially free and disease and i'm
looking at
really have to do specifically with
internet freedoms
by and have all kinds of the
respect and compassion for what's going
down on the Earth's Best
what I can actually do is happening a
little closer to technology
I think that a.m. that in itself
mean that kind of work has been going on
for a long time people trying to
keep the internet free and
scientifically pure and open to as many
people as possible and
as uncontrolled as possible and it's
close to its original intent as possible
oil arm starring
my name is Ricardo Dominguez some from
the electronic disturbance theater
he also a former member of the critical
Art Ensemble
um about two books that might be useful
the electronic disturbance
and electronics civil disobedience
another unpopular ideas
published by atong media also
the electronic disturbance theater
initiated a series so
week denial of service systems or
powerful symbolic presence or virtual
sit-ins
on presidency deals website all to 1998
in response to the optical massacre
against the sup these two communities
but
I had to look brief dialogue with the
both CDC
and some other communities not directly
but indirectly
and dumb to the the critique go from
direct action versus free speech i think
is very important
up both of them i think is the set of
are valid issues
up but again as Tweedy i think is
pointed out
if one has been grounded in long-term
activism
light is so I was working with us up at
the store since the beginning
I was already thinking about electronic
civil disobedience since
the eighties in terms of its
relationship to apt up in aids activism
and what we could do in terms of force
multiplying
the boys to the community um and I agree
that if we were to do
radical denial of service agence any
part of the Internet
in a long-term way it would be something
that would go against
um I think a technologically optimistic
community
about would should look to network is
much of the world as possible
but I also believe that there are times
and spaces
where a direct action is necessary
and how that direct action is played out
i think is up to you specific cells
and I think those cells should be aware
with um
aware of the dynamics that will take
place
up when the electronic disturbance
theater did its gestures
I'll father sup it is the flooding at um
we knew
that %uh element up and with would be
taken up
about it wasn't the most technologically
a
Dept use up the technology but we did
see it as a way to promote
arm in the mass media the issue of
Suffolk these morn what was going on and
she of us and that was our main focus
and the way we measured the
the strange up in action was if in the
media
in the first paragraph they mentioned us
up at the stars
then that was a victory for us
and I would say about 75 percent of the
time
it was indeed a mentioned in the first
paragraph
when we lost something was when they
mention cyber terrorism or cybercrime
which is what they try to put
electronics civil disobedience into you
but one up the agendas that we have been
trying to put forth his nonviolent
direct action
how does not happen online and how can
it also
whole people on the streets um
and one way that it can help in
implementing more nonviolent direct
action
is to make sure that the infor- mation
war ecologies
I'll be there right or left such as when
short of or authority dennings
a is that they try to understand the
difference between
electronic civil disobedience cyber
terrorism and cyber crime
and I think to a certain extent we the
hacktivist communities has been
a rather victorious just recently on May
23rd
dorothy denning presented to the US
arms appropriation community Committee
on cyber terrorism
her a dialogue on cyber terrorism and
she specifically mentions the electronic
hippies
the electronic disturbance theater I
believe I'll call to the date column a
few others
and she specifically states that this is
not cyberterrorism
it is not cybercrime a and I i think it
to a certain extent that
does allow and give us a certain amount
of leverage
especially when we're dealing with the
media which is ultimately the
the kind process whether we want it or
not the way it spreads itself I'll
anyway it was more of a statement than a
question but you also want to thank all
love you
for the fine fine work that you have
done and continue to do
thank you thank you Co
Keith
ahead a.m. a question that I haven't
seen addressed
specifically yet the debt did
really makes a difference between
hacktivism and
cyber action as opposed to traditional
forms of direct action
in traditional forms a direct action
others this
this is not always true but in what you
usually see is mainstream civil
disobedience like that %uh BTO protest
or the civil rights protests or what not
there be part of the whole thing is that
you go into it knowing that you may be
arrested try taken lever and thats
that's very much an accepted part of it
and that's in fact with things like the
civil rights movement
in sometimes sometimes you step aside in
fact is a goal
to gain coverage you had people arrested
and you say look these people didn't
break the law and they got arrested
what's wrong here
but in hacktivism an insider action that
seems the
the river seems to be true it seems to
be very
wants a very easy but it seems to be off
in a goal that you can pick you can do
direct action but not get your hands
dirty
you know you can't deny service are you
can pack web page or you can even just
put up your own web page it's like I
think this is bad
but then you can say this was done by
cool hacks urs at the apocalypse or
whatever rather than this time I just
met his match dress when you want to
arrest me tera
and I think that's good in the sense
that it makes it
you have to be that much less courageous
to do something it makes it much easier
get a lot more people
active on something but I think it's bad
the sense that
in some ways you only want people that
are really willing to get arrested to
actually raise their voices because if
you're not willing to you
pay the pricey may not really understand
what's going on doesn't make any sense
and I just was curious what
what thoughts you all would have about
that the fact that it's now an anonymous
form
of destiny streets it's not essentially
anonymous I know that
I have some issues with the Electra
hippies although I respect him because
at least a consistent
and they believe in what you're doing
but they have deliberately
made a point of letting people know who
they are and if there are any issues
any legal issues related to that or any
recourse than
there they set themselves up to the
target itself
respect him for that a lot of other
groups and I just don't know who they
are
haxor types I am and and you never know
what they're actually trying to achieve
at a time other than placing a web page
doesn't seem to be any strategies
up doesn't seem to be any communication
with the media or
targeted or you you're always left
guessing scratching head what's going on
in some ways could you not use that to
next not always true again but to some
extent
one of the defining things about cyber
terrorism versus either action would be
that if you're willing to say
here is my name if you wanna contact me
or here is a place you can find more
information or what not or
Here I am ready to me made a martyr of
up
that would usually to find you someone
who believes strongly enough to cause
wrong right
that you were doing activism whereas if
you are only willing to anonymously
damage something did you probably don't
really believe in anything beyond
do this would be fine if we took the
site down I'll I think those certainly
clarify things for people who wouldn't
necessarily be already
in the No on those kinds actions
arm you know when something happens on
the Internet in terms of
you know security compromises
a lot of people in this room the know
about it pretty quickly
in whose quick removal
home but the the people at large the
general public they have no idea what's
going on
and and as long as its completely
anonymous and mister
the case isn't stated very well in the
HTML source code people don't really
have any way of knowing
why this site went down
particularly if it's a anonymous
distributed denial of service attack you
there can be myriad love conclusions
drawn
on so yeah it's important that people
least explain what they're doing
even if they don't necessarily identify
themselves
yeah arm I think turn on mister um
action activism comedian and I think
there's lotsa tools and then the
activist toolbox arm
activism technology can be one of them
direct action the streets civil
disobedience is another one
and there's plenty of other our own
actions that people can take that aren't
both public and non-public and its you
know
we can use all the money there's view as
it has anybody heard about Adbusters and
other
there's a hole on property enhancement
thing that they do as far as billboards
they all turned on to
say different messages and stuff like
that so long
I think you know that's that gets that
which is a different kind
people than you know are not mystery and
you're sorta at the whim
love corporate media Hughes videotape EU
and you made your lucky that you have a
few I'm see people there but
arm know I'll have no problem with
people who do announce actions is on
this you know
user you know the other target you have
an issue you explain it
on as long as you do that on the you can
do non sections all you want
think they're just as they're both very
valid on that note arm
and I Section places like China and
Russia is very important because
in places like China even putting a web
page your free speech is totally
impressed
you risk execution I'm just for your
words
cell anonymous anonymous action is very
important
places like Russia also the police
angels rating the ISP's
I'm with black boxes they can track you
know
what you do cell make martyrs of in the
is an important thing ordered set
yourself up for that takers must leave
Iraq is important but not
menacing in some countries other on one
thing you should point out as it's not
just the
currently totalitarian informally
totalitarian regimes that are installing
black boxes switches it's happening all
over
and you know sting like a national
honest
if you know even if you think your
country is spying on you
you know the US is
I just want to say one thing about
martyrdom bomb I do
direction on the streets and I in no way
wanna be a martyr hit
I am totally against that I can
you know you know what happens happens
but I don't tell I get my crack
in my head cracked in Indy all happy
about it you know I don't accomplish
anything
so another knock at my head cracked in
you know if I can
so try to avoid that whole
ahead cracking yet head tracking thing
in the morning I
like and you know change the world
without in my head cracked open on do it
whose first um
paid like it both ears opinions
as far as the Internet far you know
you said with in a couple years that we
would have it is walking distance is
only
and %um just him argue that that's a
good thing as far as free speech goes
things like that but I E I'll had the
overwhelming feeling that
the people there sure there any engine
and one for the rich for the reasons
that the one for the TV
to promote consumerism and and have you
go to you know
coca-cola's web page so that you know
people in countries that don't have the
internet now can learn they can order
cialis call over the Internet
or some other product and not to demean
talk whole earning
and I've also shelf sure a while
that %uh the hacker community the
problem the hacker community
they don't not against anybody here
but but a generalization is a lot of
times
I don't feel like a lot of the are very
active weather involved in any issues
in a minute I feel like it takes a
hacker related specific issue
trainee hackers to say we issued streets
in protest like the kevin Mitnick edge
and until what you think we should do or
try to do too
a keep the internet about free speech in
about communicating
not about corporate consumerism and to
get
hackers involved in social issues
regardless in
right-wing lettering anything like that
that or ingest
related to selfish hacker ideals
um I want to address the first point and
then
mountain chains on second point um are
there a lot of vested interests that
want very high internet penetration on
I think you know big business has a very
good reason for wanting
everybody on the trees were planted able
to to you bands
or buy stuff ASI de om
but that's fine I don't care about that
as far as i'm concerned.
ninety percent other traffic on the
internet can be purely commercials far
as I'm concerned
but their last 10 percent is two-way
communication its me being able to
put up information for people who are
interested in it
and it's unlike any other medium that we
have except maybe
if you have a printing press or us you
know
shortwave radio you know um its two-way
and it's fundamentally different from
television so I don't care why they do
it
I'm just I'm I'm voting for
total internet domination I E
I wasn't in it was like television has a
%uh I'm under the impression that
they would like to make it like hell
only to try like both
but I one knows what you think should be
done to try to prevent things like that
I'll try to get people more active well
I don't think we have to do anything I
think you know
the the simple two-way nature net
scandia
it's a huge insurmountable problem for
somebody who wants to completely
dominate
unless they had a governmental level
decide to block access to
everything but specific sites and from
any problems selection which we already
have on
but in terms of getting hackers
politically conscious and ideas I would
like to respond to the first boat
arm I think that internet is mostly I
mean
on look at who owns the phone lines mean
it's not just you know
people in this room probably don't own
the phone lines it's no lawn a
constraint
you know is he's big chunk conglomerates
that only a
the the phone lines in this system said
its run on
arm and they don't do that you know
me be nice to hackers are be nice to
people who want to communicate d do that
so they can make money
and that's what they're about they don't
care about free speech and
things like the MPAA like 2600
distributing
arm you know reporting on an issue and
they're being attacked for that
armed or not about free speech they're
like the the own
what the medium that is being arm you
know the medium that the information is
going on
and they can control it and they
dole they will try to control it as much
as possible on a deal
come up with every way to control but
thats that in their interest to
there something that challenges their
their authority than
no day on the phone lines they can
noon that's pretty much there there
government in their system
to play with I can see it that way only
because I think
we women shut down a long time ago strip
but the yen used or other a civil to the
signs everybody but I think the
on the reasons that you know that their
trying to make it like TV
trying to use it is because it's a
money-making I enterprise for them in
out rather see the Internet be about
communication and yes about
communication
personally if I think we got River
things like capitalism
unit would be great by
freedom of the press is limited to those
who own one AJ liebling
all now now we can all in one for mine
and for monthly
take um but back to
some getting hacked to hackers into the
social issues linden's
you know you guys wanna come to the RNC
protests I send about two weeks
you're more than welcome to come
introduction in philadelphia
are you can visit our website on yes we
do have a website
it's the party's over dot
ordered arm no punctuation
so you can check us out and we are
offering trainings from everything outta
like yourself to a giant pig with the
box a donut inside
or on search
that actually happened arm
ought to like you know dewey
communications work on the street how to
get better communicate amongst people
who are like
across the city and try to figure out
you know what they should do
because the police a cheer gassing
pepper spraying over here and there
there's all these republicans impress
over here they're all trying to
you know get to the the fuck center
as for the having a convention
and no one point out that was cam porn
here noticed he had this thing is you
actors in terrorism more new hope for
something
on a new hope n observed for yeah
anyway %uh you going to church in other
words view of the Act web pages for
activism
they the very very similar to regular
activated
still say you know attacked by some
really do preach to me
Bob joanne's month ago Anne
in the autumn black backgrounds and
Asian in front page
but kindest the point is that they look
very very similar a buzz
I don't blame the differences in
together I mean
they both very very similar me I see
mean every now and then you'll see one
that just has the message that won't be
signed but thats
100 I think it's really a problem in
tactics
if you're really trying to get your
point across and
you choose to do that by interfacing web
page
you're sort of throwing yourself in with
all the people who defaced web pages
before
Thomas its clever home
um I think that's inevitable home
but then again there's a lotta room on a
web page for all kinds a text so
if you really want to explain what you
were doing you certainly could do
arm I'd like to come back for in sick
into the
difference between and then a action and
directoral in action when you name it
cuz
I said in the beginning that I don't
want to be in the same part of
like group people who do you terrorism
or whatever
arm and when we have
political issues we have in the internet
the ability and that's that
10 percent were talking about and I hope
it's getting more
to have our own organization and to use
these netbook is a structural
amplifier power our activism but this
freedom
we have um will be um
did is more under control is more
shit happens in in the meaning if is
more people DP's
web pages on make disability knowledge
service to take the mall the government
has reason to say hey we need to speak
alone system
we need this police everywhere and and
so on
and and this what I mean is we're is
the freedom we have by saying by having
too much tolerance to people just doing
bullshit just defacing web pages
is I mean we are here under our own a
little bit and
we can face it ninety five percent as
teenagers doing bullshit
mean it's it swept perfidy okay it's
nice but
it's not be a political issue it's fun
yes but
excuse me it's its teenagers fun so
and and it's not real political issue
and also its
its there for about a few minutes then
it's a way and then you have the police
investigation and then we have that
kevin Mitnick shit
and I mean as a computer free im sorry
I'm
needy little bit too convenient and
running around on the street
it's so I'm convenient you have that
rain outside you have the policeman
handed are in that and ingeniously tree
protesting
then you have these again provocateurs
doing except the same thing
throwing the Thursday least and giving
the police a reason
to hit you and I don't want to get into
exec that situation in the Internet
because I have been on the street and
its for me it's too inconvenient
everyone can make his own experience and
I'm appreciate you do still thinks that
I am
get too convenient I'm sorry but so I'd
like to keep their freedom on the net up
and I think we really get to be careful
on where we say that's okay that
activism in but we say
tape disk is the that's bullshit um
I think it's good point
it's a good play especially in regard to
the idea that
Tom you don't want to give to government
more excuses for more restrictive laws
more funding for
probably overzealous investigations and
prosecutions
for what amounts to you know somebody
renaming a text file and Canadians
on the content on but on the other hand
I think
I think that's inevitable least in the
westernized countries that
they're looking for it an excuse whether
it's
a result of hacktivism or just downright
delicious attack
and they upon you examples I don't think
I think if all the action is a night out
tomorrow they would still find enough
justification for
you know increased internet police state
um so I think the only real effective
organization against that is you know
trying to contribute to things like
ripped off her she's trying to
contribute to things like
in well and I want to endorse freedom
that
to be
his
right um so the comment was
was as time goes on the government is
increased encroaching more and more on
our rights
I think that's what you're saying and
eliminating the possibility that some
they were gonna have a very good
solution
for most people and I i think thats true
so
but I think that's true regardless what
happens
with all activism I think we have to
work hard to
to help reinforce those people who are
trying to do those things
I say you know go renew your your first
membership tomorrow
home its lawyers are activism goes and
say
like you know some people you think are
terraces up arm
I think about activism I think that a
lot of them anti-choice people
I don't consider them activists I
consider them arm
for me an activist social justice
activists yet to be against
all forms of oppression not just on you
know
not just one issue or like be against
you know
the to the denial like free speech us to
be against all forms of oppression
sexism homophobia racism classism
arm so I think you know we consider
define ourselves that way
and for the night there's %uh against
the anti-globalization movement in
europe
their movement was actually coopted by
the the left wing
movement was coopted by the right-wing
movement because
the right knee movement there basically
fascists and their national is so
they're against the
globalization economic system because
they're all about nationalism but
they're also
you know arm draws a racist in cute
sexist in
there also you know classes as well but
just in a different way
hi um just like to make a comment about
one of the dangers
activism as a concept
thats because it's such a new word
for this kind is this kind activists we
shouldn't let
the word stray too far from its route on
activism generally implies
not only tactical protests but
strategic approach toward making social
change
when people think of hacktivism the
generally think a website axe
and people defacing things and other
tactics
they're not do not necessarily strategic
if you want to use activism is a means
to change things you need to take a
strategic approach as well as
a series a tactics and
you know one thing to note be like gun
let the Internet and you know is is a
medium for communication
but it is when when when you love
something happens and there's more to it
than just
just the media most people just see the
medium they don't see that it's also
a different audience you wouldn't go in
protest the year
you know I have a street protests a
direct action protest
about dad India injustices against Falun
Gong group in North Dakota
you wouldn't do it the audience is wrong
it's the wrong place to do it
however you know people seem to make the
same
mistake on the Internet one thing to
remember is that your audience is
different
the things that you protest it's a tool
is very valuable
you wanna miss use it to the wrong costs
you know it's really is know it's true
it's pretty hard to make a mistake was
something like direct action is it's a
it's a physical thing
everyone has a physical representation
every person on this planet the joint
interface
the joint influence has has a physical
manifestation body you can go to that
person
she and talk to them on the Internet the
people that you're talking to
you know I'm not the earth on done
Chinese they're not the
the people you're dying of AIDS in
Africa that they don't have access to
not there
was not that's not your audience anymore
and that has to be no
yes to be taking note the people you're
talking to are the year
you know the by the white bread American
families who let me
I am TV raise the children the people
who don't go outside not gonna see the
street protest
and if they do they just gonna think
it's a nuisance visits making noise and
get your television
Sony be aware also the changing audience
as well as the change in medium when you
apply your tactics makes you have a
message
and dreaming at the right place now just
firing blanks up in the sky
by
one of the problems that I think arises
is the
sendak by the confusion mean the
confusion between activism in terrorism
is on
really when it comes down to terrorism
by definition is instilling fear 3 some
action
and what we're saying before about on
you know when you when you see for small
how similar they do appear
and a lot of times a anonymous
with defacement were arm
which seems seemingly unprovoked to the
corporation
that does it might be seen as an
anonymous unprovoked attack
which will typically it's still more
fear then
knowing who's protesting their purposes
why and when that's when it's that
perceived unprovoked attack
instilling fear it's much quicker to
call that a terrorist action
then peace activism and once
depress for the government for the
general public whatever powers maybe
have labeled something
an act of terrorism people are less
likely to look
at the intent and the people who did and
thats
the more important when people don't
claim don't take credit
for their actions and doing it so I see
the anonymity
as the perceived anonymity as
only a good point because
as we said before it might allow more
people to feel like they can get
involved
it's also kinda
in a way setting oneself I'll to be in a
situation where they're installing more
fear
and creating more friction between the
company
or the group worthy you get the idea
people supporting the idea and the
people who don't support it
I mean it's it's a situation what is
use fear leads to hate and
hate leads to suffering as you notice
yeah possibly also asked about this a.m.
in a different way I agree I think I am
anonymity is sort of a double-edged
sword
if there's no explanation for what's
happening is
is just another webpage hackers just
another
internal service or whatever the tactic
happens to be
if if it comes out the blue there's no
explanation and there's no
clear reason for why it would happen
then
the speculation always runs wild and I
mean
I think you're gonna see people and we
may have seen it already where
I'll a group perform some sort of
activity and somebody else to size take
credit for it
adjusted further kearsarge
you know whatever reason on it
nothing to prevent that night I suspect
it's already happened
the last words she alone this is
something about
terrorism in as people can sometimes is
further
from the activism first reaction direct
action
on as you know a lot of times like
a sick the police prayer example of the
police are being trained
National Museum preparation for the
protest happening this summer at the
Republican National Convention & in
philadelphia and felt Los Angeles
on the Democratic National Convention to
being trained that
the activist they don't care about the
they're not there for any issues
they're only there because they want to
confront the police and that's
absolutely not true that's totally false
but
what it does is and makes the police
think that were out to get them
and that makes it sort of like they
think that we're terrorists and it's
easier
to crack the head 0 they can't open up
somebody who think is out to get you
into somebody who's like says that are
not out to get you but they're
here because they don't agree what's
going on so
assist another example of how people to
me
on the misinformation Mb turn people
into
but people call terrace
in last week's Lee
well other than that I just like to
thank 2600
31 putting this together I think we've
had great range
opinion discussions great it's like yeah
me too
oh yeah I just if anyone is interested
in a social justice
work on the ruckus society that each
active is how did you pull a
high-profile actions had
to bang hangs off buildings they want to
do a cyber camp
and teach on people who are interested
in cyber activism how to do
more high-profile actions and how to
talk to the media so if you wanna check
them out you can I look up rocky start
or on the web
and up on how to cause a ruckus
alright trapped in the hall