Elte I'm layers one two and three with
Matt is an engineering walk home working
on cellular security research he's
welcome back thank you all right
yeah like he just said we're gonna sell
your security research and
countermeasure so to answer here's to
common questions just be real quick six
foot eight and I didn't play basketball
I played volleyball and then also what I
was just talking about broadcasting a
licensed spectrum is against the law you
doing it
use a Faraday cage and or a bag they
work pretty well and also this
presentation is just information that's
public already no there's no new secret
sauce here it's just all other it's like
a collection of other people's research
so everybody else everybody's research
is sourced on the slides I highly
suggest you go and look up the stuff
that I'm sourcing so anyway a brief
overview of LT architecture for people
who are not familiar with cellular we
just think we were just talking about a
particular slice of this the full
architecture so we don't to talk about
the whole backhaul but just this I have
this this little model here and we have
also a couple acronyms we use or a
couple terminologies we use in cellular
so it's good to go over this so when we
say UE we're talking about user
equipment so your foam IOT device
anything that has a modem you know B
that's the base station and then we have
this concept of access stratum that
deals with everything that has to do
with the UE and the e node be
communicating over the air and with the
radio and then there's this concept of
non access stratum that's anything that
the U is communicating to the backhaul
to the actual back parts of the network
not dealing with the radio and the
backhaul you have this important thing
is called the mobility management entity
this is that the system that tracks for
your your UE your cell phone moves
around so the network needs to know
where the phone is at all times to be
able to deliver service at it
MMB handles that and then HSS the home
subscriber server that has the
information about are you if subscriber
for this ah for the cell you'll never so
if you're if you pay forty bucks of rise
in a month
you're in that server somewhere saying I
pay 40 bucks I'm a semi subscriber
this is the evolved packet core you Tran
is there is the technology of the access
to the radio so we evolved UMTS
terrestrial radio access network and
then the last thing MZ I know if you
guys are familiar with MZ catchers or
EMC leak MZ is the international mobile
subscriber identifier so a lot of these
attacks have to deal with getting the a
user's MZ so anyway we got the LT
protocol stack here so this is just like
a really quick overview of LTE so we're
gonna be mostly talking about physical
layer here and then we're gonna be
talking about the packet data
convergence protocol here and then
lastly we'll talk about radio research
control and not access stratum don't
worry about what these are just yet
we'll talk about it when we get there
so LTE is actually pretty secure once
this completes once the authentication
key agreement completes so we're dealing
with an over-the-air protocol so we have
to start from a place that's not secure
and then eventually we we authenticate
each other the user and the network and
then we set up encryption so essentially
fast-forwarding through this the UE here
decides to attach to the network sets up
an RC connection so RC is radio resource
control radio control then we then we
send a non access stratum attach request
with the subscriber identifier the
network goes and checks if you are valid
subscriber and generates some
authentication vectors here sends I back
down and the the ue gets now a
authentication request with this token
there's there's a shared secret key on
both ends of this so in the SIM card
it's not your MZ it's called K it's a
cryptographic key that is used to set to
check this authentication token that the
network generated also with K at the
very end K he's never transferred but
numbers are generated from K
yes sorry I skipped a little bit ahead
and that so because of the Ueno's k and
the network knows k that you is able to
validate that this authentication token
is correct when it does a response it
generates its own response to the
challenge and now we have mutual
authentication both ends have just
cryptographically verify that they both
know this the shared secret k so a
symmetric key that allows us to set up
encryption so you actually have two
layers of encryption and integrity
protection LT you have one that actually
deals with Nass the the network so the
backhaul and then you have one that
deals with with access stratum RC so
there's there's encryption between you
and the tower and this we Crips in
between you and the network so anyway
before the aka completes this is all of
our tax base so while you're while
you're attaching and you're
synchronizing and you're and you're
getting the aka ready an attacker can
send any kind of non authenticated
message to you and actually control you
e behavior so this is this is bad this
is why all these things become possible
anybody is able to send this message to
your phone over the network in your
phone obeys following protocol the
people who made the protocol 3gpp they
had a primary objective of
interoperability first and security
third fourth something so that's bad I
mean you you kind of have to make it
something that works first and it's also
it's also amazing that we have these
devices that can beam data out of the
sky I mean it's really crazy how do you
think about it but we just take it for
granted
but security is not possible in this
initial attack space you can't
immediately start communicating with
somebody over the air and have a secure
connection you have to negotiate first
so anyway and lastly this is the last
part of the overview part there's
numerous actors in this in a space and
it's a tax base so there's hobbyists
there's research for I'm at an
increasingly amount of criminal and
we'll talk about this in the end
software-defined radios are getting very
cheap people who have some very little
know-how can start making money using
these exploits so we're seeing a lot of
increase in criminal activity
law enforcement and espionage you guys
are familiar with empty catchers all
that stuff you hear about on the news
that's mostly those things are a hundred
thousand dollars apiece stingrays and
stuff like that that's mostly you know
law enforcement CIA whatever you'll see
these a lot around airports federal
buildings
DEFCON and yeah embassies so yeah big
news I think on April the Department
Homeland Security was was complaining
that they were finding MZ catchers or
surveillance devices around the DC area
and I made like national news people
that work in this space were like well
duh we already know this but it was like
big deal back then lastly we're going to
talking about jamming so jamming is
technically under like the realm of
electronic warfare so you know in an
actual like hot war you can deploy some
of these techniques to to bring down do
your LTE in an area or stuff like that
so that being said we'll start with
layer one so we'll start with Jamie I've
really simplified this part and it's
actually not my expertise so apologies
ahead of time but we'll try to get
through this so the goal of jamming is
to inject interference into the into
your target into the receiver so when
you inject interference you drops what's
called signal-to-noise ratio it makes it
hard for the receiver to extract the
signal from the noise and interference
so LT in the downlink uses this
technology this is this amazing
technology called orthogonal frequency
division multiplexing or OFDM that
allows your like very very efficient use
of the cellular or the the
electromagnetic spectrum it allows for
you know these crazy bandwidth that we
have on our phones like your phone
basically like broadband speed most of
the time hopefully right all that stuff
really really cool technology but it
relies a lot on synchronization and
click your phone and the network are
constantly optimizing and synchronizing
with each other that makes it a problem
if you jam or if you interfere with this
this constant negotiation that's
happening on with the net
work that you can break LCD pretty
easily so there's different types of
jammers there's like a barrage jammer
all these other type of jammers with LTE
but since the since we're using OFDM and
all these other modulation techniques
all the stuff you have you actually need
to build a smart jammer
you can't just well you can but it's
very inefficient
you just have to broadcast with like a
huge amount of power trying to jam LT
because LTE is very very resistant to
like to try to sorry excuse me
so you want to build a smart jammer
because essentially it allows you to
synchronize through those control
signals and then you Jam them and then
you break you break the there's like a
cascading effect keeper will see what's
going on there's also so your phone is
actually usually in what's called RC
Idol the modem is usually turned off and
waking periodically to wake up to see if
I have any traffic and then go back to
sleep
so when you're if you keep the modem
from going from RC Idol to RC connected
state you effectively Jam as well as you
keep the motor you can't get to connect
the state you can't get data you can't
get any can't get any service and then
if you really really Jam something you
could cause radio link failure you'd
best this basically we have to start
over from scratch radio link failure is
bad so okay well just quick slide or
thing I'll freaking see people you have
you have these uh you have all these sub
carriers here and this is in the
frequency domain this way right on this
platform or on this this is a time
frequency lattice so you have multiple
sub carriers that are orthogonal to each
other
we won't get into the crazy but but
getting the signal out of this out of
this time frequency lattice use for you
for three a fast transforms pops the
signal out you're able to decode bits
out of a signal essentially what you're
trying to do so when you're jamming LTE
so this is this is an actual sorry about
this is probably small but this is what
it actually looks like and see the time
frequency domain so right away when your
phone's turning on it needs to listen to
this what's called the prime
synchronization signal and the secondary
signals a stream signal and that happens
here that's this initial burst of it and
then you see it happens here again and
this just repeats on and on and on
forever so it's constantly this constant
like here's my signal here's my signal
here's my signal measure it measure it
measure it and you're able to the U is
able to decode what's called the
physical cell ID out of those two
signals and once you know the physical
cell ID you can then decode this next
thing which is the cell specific
reference signal which are leased we're
called pilot channels so these are the
pilot channels are very important they
guide the ue back into the back into the
next stages so we can we can start
decoding the signal out of the air so to
jam it you'd you actually have to sniff
the PSS and SSS first and then you can
find out where in this see these white
bars you don't know where that where
those little red boxes are until you
decode those first and then you can know
okay that's where this is where the
pilots are Jam those and this keeps you
YZ from attaching to the network not
taking people off the network by keeping
you from attaching up onto the network
so that's first then there's what's
called a physical broadcast channel so
physical broadcast channel after you
after you decoded all this stuff you're
able to decode this this is on the very
front end here and it's repeated every L
every everything every beginning of the
subframe or beginning of the frames it's
repeated you Jam this guy and you keep
the you ease from decoding the master
information block and master information
block has this very very important like
timing information all stuff like that
that keeps the you east from camping
onto the network again but if you sniff
this master information block and start
decoding information from that then you
can actually open up more attacks so
you're starting to basically we're
building a smart camera now you're
starting to basically be like a ue
starting to attach and synchronize to
the network and starting to decode
information from the network that'll
expose the network's vulnerable the the
towers vulnerabilities so i pre we've
decoded the master information
block we can actually then decode these
system information blocks which have
configuration information so identifying
information about the tower we can we
can see who the tower owner is the
operator we can then also get these
parameters I you know be I Alzheimer's
important the parameters to access the
physical random access channel that's
the that's the channel that if you jam
that you II can't attach as well but
then also you have paging channel if you
Jack if you can jam that paging channel
you can keep the UE stuck in our RC Idol
sorry I was talking about going from RC
Idol to our C connected you can't hear a
paging channel the paging channel is
what wakes up the UE out of out of RC
Idol so yeah this one this one is kind
of weird but basically this is an
example of an effect where if you jam
this PC of this physical control format
indicator channel and you you stop the
you east from decoding this this control
format indicator it breaks the next
channel so this is like we're having a
cascade effect now so it's just a
example of that but so let's say we want
to jam the entire tower kick everybody
off the tower keep the like earlier
we're talking about kicking off target
you ease you can actually jam in the
uplink direction so damming the uplink
direction makes the tower not be able to
to see anything coming from all of its
servants all the people all the clients
so if you if you jam this a physical
uplink control channel there's this
uplink control info stuff that's very
very important for the network to
constantly synchronize it's like you
know you're you're you east constantly
going like oh I have this kind of
measurement to you I have this kind of
signal I'm moving in this direction this
kind of stuff and that's constantly used
by the by the the cell tower to retune
and calibrate this stuff so if you jam
that you actually Jam the entire tower
so and so that okay all the stuff is
source on this paper at the bottom and
the end of this paper they have a
discussion about the cost of the
effectiveness of jamming you have this
uh I like this number here J over s so
what that is is basically jamming how
much
power you used over the signal received
at the receiver so if you're very very
inefficient you're using a lot of
jamming power and to get minimal signal
degradation on the on the endpoint
you're very very efficient you're using
if you're building a smart jammer you're
using very little jamming power to just
break everything
so we rate rank everything based on
efficiency and then also complexity
complexity is you know how much of a
smart chambered you have to be how many
- how many signals do you have to decode
to be able to jam this then it may come
it's more and more complex because
you're actually implementing you're
starting to implement a mini cellphone
it once you once you're really building
a smart amber you're basically building
a mini cellphone and that's it for
jamming so okay now we're moving on to
layer to the alter attack this was
disclosed I think in April by
researchers in Germany and it's kind of
a theoretical attack and in the regard
that you have to you have to intercept
and having a relay in between the UE and
the network so intercepting and holding
on to that is kind of difficult we'll
see why but for for to pull off this
attack you have to you have to have a
malicious relay you not a man in the
middle
technically what we're seeing on the
relay since the device earlier the
authentication key agreement we can't do
a man-in-the-middle because there's
mutual authentication so you're going to
fail you're gonna feel that crypto
challenge and all stuff but you can just
forward the traffic the encrypted
traffic to the actual network and just
act as a relay so we're not a full
man-in-the-middle that were a partial
now in the middle and then since your
encrypted traffic you have to we're
targeting DNS packets so you have to
deduce which what is that what traffic
is DNS packets and then you have to
alternate the DNS destination IP and
like a DNS redirection attack on an
encrypted packet so you don't know a
contents of it but you're able to reduce
what it is and also you know we're in it
where it is and and we'll see why why we
can we can do this so we're and this
part we're talking about the packet data
convergence
call what this does is actually
converges user plain data and control
plain data to to the radio link control
and all these other lower layers the the
DNS actually DNS requests actually will
be going up to use your plain data up to
the IP layer so this is what handles the
the DNS requests it actually encrypts it
all that stuff and so okay and just a
I'm sure you guys are familiar with DNS
redirection so we have a destination IP
address we want to modify that and so
the packet here is actually encrypted in
AES counter mode which is not a it's a
es as you think of block block cipher
but a s in counter mode is actually a
stream cipher so since it's a stream
cipher where a the the were able the the
packet is malleable there's no integrity
protection there is a checksum we'll get
to that but there's no there's no
nothing stopping me from flipping a bit
in the message and changing the message
we need to manipulate this destination
IP address to target our malicious DNS
server and the you @ue will will
redirect I noted this really before the
talk but I if you use DNS SEC or TLS
this won't work because your your the
next layer is gonna okay anyway so so
there's just a we have the holding
they're holding this relay and actually
delivering the authentication key
agreement here is a theoretical thing
and not detailed here but if you did get
this which it is possible then you're
able to manipulate the DNS packing going
on going here and you have you mean they
play the destination IP to your your
malicious DNS server and then you have
it being relayed by the actual network
by the way this has to go through the
actual backhaul and then back to back to
the to the relay which then which then
the UE gets that the incorrect source IP
or the source IP to your malicious HTTP
server
so notice HTTP you not HTTP anyway so
you have these DNS or you have these you
don't
if there are dns packets or not because
they're encrypted so how do you find out
well you can buy their length narrow it
down to about 96 percent and then you
can actually forward it to a DNS server
and if you get a DNS response than it is
a DNS packet and we're manipulating a
malleable cipher text so we don't need
to manipulate the whole thing just we
need to create this manipulation mask we
need to make believe just the
destination IP so if we can change the
view to the DNS redirection you have a
plaintext M and then you and then the
cipher text here this is what we got
we're manipulating a cipher text to
actually have a manipulated ciphertext C
Prime that will generate a minute
manipulated in plaintext M Prime how do
we find out the manipulation mask how do
we find out what bits and the keystream
are being applied to the original
destination IP to pop out the original
because we have the original ciphertext
C that's not that's it what we know
where the the IP is because it's it's a
certain offset and we know that phones
and all stuff have a default DNS server
you can find that out through other
analysis but let's just say is set to
Google 8.8.8.8 or whatever so you can
actually know what the original just for
the manipulation mask if you know what
the original data was there and then you
manipulate that to what you want the
target to be and you take this
manipulated plaint that the output you
take them away the plaintext any and you
bring it with the original plaintext use
orme together and out pops the keystream
writes or is an inverse of itself so
it's a it's a chosen cipher text attack
you can find out what bits in the key
stream are encrypting just that DNS
destination IP and then encrypt your
manipulated one to that knowing the
knowing the bits so anyway so we've
manipulated this destination IP address
but we're now violating checksum because
we've changed the bits so let's say we
change the bits from 8.8.8.8 to quod
nine nine point nine point nine point
nine it's not a malicious dns but let's
just say we've just added four extra
bits right we had
you know eight in binary but now we have
nine so we have an extra bit so we just
got generated for extra base the
checksum in the IP header is gonna be
off it's gonna be off by by uh by those
four extra bits so what you do is you
can you can manipulate any of these
other fields and the an IP header that
don't deal with routing or anything that
you would break a good candidate is the
TTL field so a time to live you know
number hops until we drop the packet you
can manipulate the TTL field to get
those four bits back to not violate the
checksum same problem we don't know what
the TTL field is originally because it's
an encrypted packet well
phones have a default TTL value you can
find that out too you know it's like you
know 500 or something like that
and it also it helps that our relay is
only one hop away so we're not changing
it we can just anyway so the TTL field
is a good candidate to use what has to
happen is that the manipulated IP
addresses and it's arted plus the
manipulated TTL field all has to pass
did not change the checksum so we need
when you do that when you you know you
change this destination IP address and
you check to make sure that checksum is
not violated you're you're successful in
the in the regard that you hope that the
thing when it's being delivered by the
network actually gets there because
you've manipulated the TTL so the TTL
actually can be decremented to make this
this math work out here on the bottom
and then your your thing won't actually
get there but if it does it works and
they were saying that they were like 94%
effective
so they actually showed it to be
feasible with it with a test harness and
all that stuff so yeah you just have to
make sure that the everything sums up
correctly and it works so anyway moving
on a layer 3 so this is more or I mat so
our RC & nass are these radio resource
control and non access strata messages
like I said you're able to send these to
the you II before authentication so
these are these are message
just that you can send and actually
control Yui behavior so I already talked
about why is this why is this possible
well because of the nature of an
over-the-air protocol because the way
they specify the 3gpp specified protocol
that they needed they needed basic
interoperability primarily and security
later
so in also yeah I have to note so I've
been reading the 5g security spec and
it's slowly trickling out they are
narrowing this attack space so they
realize that there's a problem here and
they're there they're moving up
authentication and you you can't be
issuing these kind of messages without
being authenticated first and 5g so very
very good that that is being so how do
we how do we trigger so the UE your your
device is constantly like constantly
like evaluating other cell towers and
trying to find the best signal and so
you're the kind of example is I would
say is you know in Wi-Fi you have like
your home network you attach to it and
you choose that and you choose every you
know you I want to connect to Starbucks
open Wi-Fi I want that to this you user
has control over Wi-Fi on cellular they
don't so that the device is constantly
reattaching to other networks by on its
own and you don't have any visibility to
it Android doesn't draw anything I phone
even less it doesn't tell you other than
like you're on AT&T network and you have
four bars that's all that's exposed to
API is really I mean so your ear UE is
constantly switching to other towers and
occasionally it's actually turning off
encryption and rebuilding encryption
when it's switching sometimes that has
to happen so it be like your Wi-Fi is
got a little padlock padlocks going on
and off like turning on and off and and
and you're like why is that happening
well cellular it happens and it's all
behind the curtain you don't know about
it but it's constantly uh it's
constantly a thing so where as an
attacker we're able to intercept you
because of the this for a very moment
forgets to talk about this
attack window so how do you do that the
simplest and the easiest way is to
transmit at higher power so you come you
come in with a tower that's like hey
guys I got amazing signal everybody come
to me and all that all the devices will
go old thing is if the device is happy
where it's at if you got four bars where
it's at it's not gonna reselect you can
broadcast as your tower under the system
information block so it's talking about
earlier you can broadcast as your your
tower you could say my tower is 18 T and
Verizon and Sprint and t-mobile like all
all in the u.s. they're you know four
big operators you can actually broadcast
as your being a multiple operator of
cell tower and your device wants to
attach to the network that's its home
network so if you're moving on to your
roaming if you're going to like say
you're going to another country and
you're roaming on to other networks the
device actually struggles it goes I
don't want to go to any of these other
networks I want to look for my home
network first and it eventually gives up
and again it attaches to the busy
networks so if you're broadcasting as
the device is home network your your
even your even better there's also this
thing called tracking area code and
tracking area update so if you remember
the mobility management entity that part
of the backhaul that constantly is
handling the the knows where the where
you are and geographically and as you're
moving around to other areas so as
you're moving around to other cell
towers the networks constantly doing
this process called tracking area update
once the tracking your update is
completed you're giving this tracking
area code if you broadcast at any other
tracking area code that's other than the
tracking area code in the certain area
let's say our tracking area code is 1 2
3 4 and I just broadcast a tower with
the tracking area code for 4 4 4 or a
different tracking area code all your
uese are all gonna think that they're
moving into this different area and
they're gonna start communicating your
tower talk start trying to do this
tracking area update procedure so this
actually is way easier than the first
two bullet points so you can just do
this and it works the you eezol switch
to your tower going oh I need to do
tracking area okay because I'm moving
into a new area and that's how you get
them you can also configure attractive
reflection parameters so there's this
constant load balancing parameters at
the network's do the
there was this backhoe that networks
actually really cool it's a self
optimizing network this song they use
the easiest thing so when one cell tower
is being overloaded and other cell
towers parameters will become more
attractive so the device is load
balancing salsas kind of cool well you
can just maximize all those parameters
and make your make your tower even more
attractive then likewise once you've
attracted somebody to attach to you you
can do these techniques called cell
imprisonment where you make it hard for
the device to escape from you so cell
towers always broadcast their neighbors
they go this these these are the
neighbors and these are the different
frequencies that are available these are
the different areas that your device can
reselect too they get they always give
you a way out they always give you like
like if you attach to me but you're
moving that way you know if you're an
attacker you just say I don't have any
neighbors there's no there's no towers
here I'm the only guy sorry
stay on me that's still imprisonment
likewise you could Jam other towers what
I was talking about earlier so if the UE
is happy on its tower you can jam it and
it'll just release select yours the more
sophisticated so the stingrays and the
stuff I was saying about they were more
expensive they are combinations of
jammers and fake towers so they Jam all
the other bands and they keep their bear
band open it's a you know it's more
sophisticated attack what you can you
can you can combine all these attacks to
make you more effective more effective
then lastly we're going to talk about
channel hijacking this is a theoretical
thing that's pretty new research and
we'll talk about that in a second
so what I just talked about that last
slide
it's just triggering Reis election how
do you trigger the UE to start talking
to your tower here they always attach to
the real network and from whatever how
we did it from this previous slide we've
triggered a resolution probably the
tracking area code different or whatever
so the and this is actually in a
scenario that the UE is thinking that
it's performing tracking area updates so
it's saying track the area update
request and we all this is super simple
all we have to do is reject with
specific cost code so the cost code is
in this case I think is causing nine all
it does is says you we cannot be
identified by network per protocol
through per 3gpp protocol that Yui then
sends attach request with its MZ so it
just getting the getting the victims MZ
the subscribe
identifier is trivially easy when people
are like oh these MC catchers all these
sophisticated things it's not they're
not sophisticated they're just simple
they go track of your update reject
cause nine
give me your identifier and then per
protocol that Yui follows that then they
just simply just benignly reject you
they go up and they've captured your MZ
so this is an example like a
surveillance device simple no no like
attack here just a privacy leak we can
actually deal it more nasty here so same
call flow and the MZ is leaked again you
know what nothing you know nothing stops
you from also getting the MZ on this
attack as well but then we send this
special attach reject at the end we
don't do it benign at at reject like the
the previous example we do an attach
reject that says EPS and on EPS services
are not allowed that means for G and non
4G services are not allowed that means
your phone's modem starts a timer like a
10 minute timer and turns itself off and
essentially you've just tricked the the
modem into down to its own denial
service the only way to get out of it
without waiting for the timer to expire
is the power cycle of the device so now
the modem turns off so airplane mode
turns off the modem but a modem goes to
a low power mode and yeah if your phone
is Sims hot swappable some phones the
sim is not hot swappable you have to
reboot when you put the sim in but if it
is this the sim can get loaded then you
you just pop this in back in and out and
I think the the since the sim is being
read it'll turn the modem back on and
like I said it's a 10-minute dose it's
it's super easy to do this one just like
the previous example because this is
happening in the protocol there it's not
like if you were doing a jamming dose or
a lot of stuff you'd have to get more
sophisticated but the the modem turns
off it it starts this teeth for three
one two timer or something like that per
protocol perspect yeah one thing I
forgot to mention all these messages all
these things ever send
these layer and layer two layer three
attacks are all valid per protocol
we're not we're not like doing any like
remote code execution or any like
exploits here we're just sending a
malicious certain licious sequence of
messages and we're controlling Yui
behavior like I was talking about
earlier this message coming down for the
network turns your modem off they can go
they the network can go turn your modem
off remotely and they're not your modem
goes okay I'm following protocol I'm
following the rules so now we get a bit
more nasty we could do a downgrade so
like I said for G he's actually secure
for G has mutual authentication once
mutual once the authentication key
agreement is passed and all stuff we're
good TG does it 2g has one way
authentication the network
authenticating the UE and they even then
that's optional and then two G has Nolan
Krypton support so you can not have
encryption or it even has weak like
certain to GE Krypton algorithms or weak
there's there from the like Cold War era
or like like we didn't want to give the
thermal country strong encryption so one
was like global as an encryption scheme
that was for export and the other ones
were actually used internally in the
u.s. in the UK and all the stuff so
there's actually there's actually like
ete a1 and ee8 I forget are actually
weak encryption and at Def Con I wish I
had brought my I wish I had brought the
kids at the data sharing village or
whatever they were if he brought like a
six terabyte drive they had the the GSM
rainbow tables for the for the weak
encryption so I was like I wish I had I
wish I brought that yeah so anyway um so
when you have no one to no integrity or
no authentication and no encryption what
do you have a man in the middle like on
cellular so this is bad
one thing to note here is that this
downgrade actually so this downgrade is
not the best in the I think is that it
says actually EPS service is not allowed
which means 40s out loud so technically
the modem as a way out that they can go
to 3G and then 3G service is there
the modal actually will attach the 3G so
I don't I don't think this is actually a
feasible downgrade in most cases because
of 2g here in the US to G is deployed as
a backhaul there's only there's no like
2g towers broadcasting as in like you
can attach to me
2g towers are still here and they're
using what's called circuits which fall
back so LT is a packet only so LTE
doesn't have lt's packets which doesn't
have circuits which circuits which is
the old you know patching cables like
hello hello you know pts PSTN correct so
when we are making a phone call and
voiceover LT is not available we have to
downgrade which is called circuits which
fall back to either 3G or 2g so 2g is
still deployed here in the u.s. even
though it's not it's not being
broadcasted like if I'm like sweeping
around I can't find 2g towers I can find
3G and 4G towers they're not they're not
broadcasting their existence but they're
still there as far apart the backhaul so
your modems will support 2g for a long
time getting ahead of myself but yeah so
people are like well to geez not there
why why is 2g downgrade so possible so
ok this down right here actually may
allow you to just like to 3G it's not as
good
this downgrade though so after our SC
connector set up an RC connection setup
is complete we can actually send this
message at any time but in this example
we leaked the MC first and then we sent
this message but you can send this RC
connection release and say redirected
carrier info so what that and specifying
G ran specifying the GSM radio network
and that what that does is forcibly
switch your modem it says redirect to
this radio technology redirect A to G
and even listen to this frequency so
it's really specific it tells that
you'ii go straight there and then you
have the no encryption and also bad very
bad
why is this possible so and redirection
is a very important thing for 3gpp when
that people designed this protocol they
always wanted to have this redirection
capability and it has to be as
lightweight as possible because in like
an emergency situation say there's a you
know a big catastrophic emergency
and everybody's trying to use the
cellular network at once and the okay
also the cellular network is also the
primary emergency communication system -
so all the emergency infrastructure all
relies on the cellular network and if
you if you have an emergency situation
there has to be emergency services
available there's like the primary thing
and we're not caring about security or
anything like that we're caring about
load balancing and interoperability here
so the and when they were doing that
protocol spec there they were like in a
case where one towers being overloaded
in an emergency situation they're
allowed to redirect to other towers and
other radios to low balance and to
spread to spread the the service around
to other other parts of the network
that's their justification that being
said we have to deal with the mess it's
very bad the the the unauthenticated
message coming down to you saying
switch your modem to 2g and unless your
modem had some sort of countermeasure in
it they will they will switch the 2g on
this particular band even so you don't
even have to do any trickery about
having the motive switch to 2g and then
having your tower there with like select
Reese elective like highly attractive
tower you just say go to the 2g band
that the tower is already there so you
have you have to you have a like in my
lab I have a an LTE tower downgrade you
to a 2g tower and it works
so okay this is a example for something
from my lab once your downgrade to 2g
it's actually really simple to do
fake SMS you have a you have a full
man-in-the-middle so you can do any more
malicious stuff you could do fake
emergency messages so this is that
emergency broadcast system or the CBS
cell broadcast system and 2g and that
and that's like you know Amber Alert so
even if your phones on silent phone will
wake up in go brain barrier and draw
this draw this toast notification and
just yeah it was funny when I do in my
lab I have like I have like a multiple
bunch of devices they all go off at once
it's like it's like we called the panic
attack so if a camera see messages and
it's
in here but you can actually put URLs in
there and it'll draw as a clickable URL
so you put phishing links in there and
you can do fake SMS so in China there's
a there's this rise of criminals using a
cheap software-defined radio all this
tricks I was telling you about
they they they trick you onto the down
accrete onto the 2g network and then
they serve what serve you up fake SMS so
I serve you up phishing SMS and the the
paper I read it was like for about 1500
bucks of initial equipment purchase and
then some technical know-how you can be
started you could you can make your
money back within like a couple days and
so it's pretty lucrative thing in China
another thing in China is a they have
were called authoritative number so the
bank the government like certain
entities have a phone number in China if
you're delivering a fake SMS you can
spoof I can send an SMS from 9-1-1
that's an example of an authoritative
number here right so you can say you
know the Bank of America Bank of China
is telling you that you have suspicious
activity on your account please click
here to go to account recovery you know
and then they have some phishing site or
something like that
so people don't get tricked by phishing
emails as much anymore but phishing SMS
and phishing emergency messages have
like a little bit more authority to them
so it works the people who like a text
message I have to click on this but
anyway the last thing we're going to
talk about is a channel hijacking so I
said this was more of a theoretical
thing this is brand-new research that
the University of Iowa and Purdue came
out with and it's really cool we're only
going to talk about what particularly
part of it but so this slide is about
the the tax procedure that we've already
gone over and then once you're attached
to the network the modem actually wants
to go into idle state and it has what's
called this paging cycle so it sleeps
and it wakes up on this paging cycle and
it listens to the paging occasion on the
paging channel sorry anyway
paging means that so I sent something to
your phone and that that you know
semesters coming over the network to
your phone and your phone sleeping it
wakes up that one time to hear the
paging channel and the network it right
at the same time to synchronize the
right Africa goes page for you I have a
message for you wake up then the you the
the device moves from RC Idol onto RC
connected and then we actually deliver
the actual thing
so paging channel is very important if
we were jamming it earlier like I said
we are tossing all the devices that are
listening the paging channel but in this
case we're going to inject traffic into
the paging channel so what's cool about
this attack is that it's a possible to
attribute or who's who's doing the
attack your masquerading as a legitimate
tower and you're like all the other
attacks I'll talk about earlier you have
like the other actual legitimate towers
and you have your fake cell tower and
you're trying to trick people to attach
to your fake cell tower to launch these
attacks
here you're injecting traffic into the
actual legitimate cell tower so it's
kind of it's kind of cool
so paging messages that come in the
downlink they don't have any kind of
encryption
they can't paging messages are purely
like networks saying you have something
wake up and get it so what you do is you
you you actually have to to configure
your tower to to look like the exact
paging channel of the other Tower you
have to actually like sniff these system
information blocks these two and then
you can figure your tower to have the
exact same paging cycle remember the
device waking up on that page a cycle
well now now you're paging cycles on the
same thing the UE only responds to the
first receive message it's actually
interesting when I do this when I do
this attack is that there's a there's a
there's a case where the the UE stamped
on the network and the network is
delivering these pages with this much
signal when you're when you're injecting
your traffic your traffic is actually
interference at the beginning so your
modem just goes ignores it and then
eventually your your signal will will
beat out the actual legitimate network
and then there's like actually a
confused period where we're not getting
any signal if you're not careful you'll
get radio link failure but then then on
the other side your signal becomes the
signal and the network signal becomes
noise so you actually are doing a dose
in this as well if you are if you're
hijacking the paging channel the device
can't hear pages from the
Network anymore - last Bowl I just
basically said that so anyway so there's
three different things you could do with
this like I said if you just paid if
you're hijacking the paging channel
you've just kicked the person off the
network stealthily they don't have no
idea that they can't because they can't
hear pages they'd have no idea they're
completely oblivious you can actually do
the panic attack so this is in 4G so the
other panic attack I showed you earlier
was a downgrade to 2g you can actually
deliver fake emergency messages in 4G
you send a page you have the emergency
bit flipped like this like in the page
that goes I have a burn C message for
you the device wakes up and it listens
to sip 10 11 or 12 and in there are the
emergency messages themselves so without
any authentication without any kind of
connection to the network the device
here's that bit goes and decodes your
your mercy message and then draws it on
the thing
like I said emergency messages have to
be very lightweight they don't have any
kind of authentication this is like an
emergency situation like explain earlier
than that this network has to broadcast
those things when the tornado is coming
or when the earthquake the tsunami is
coming or whatever and then the last the
last one is an energy depletion attack
this one is not so bad for your mobile
phone but it's devastating for IOT you
just continuously page the victim over
and over and over again so you make them
wake up try to attach the network and if
you can get them to do the
authentication key agreement every time
actually you're making them do some
cryptographic math on that processor so
you just you just continuously page over
and over and over again and you perform
that battery change the actual
effectiveness it probably is like you
know an IOT battery it should last like
ten years now you're killing it in a
couple days I think depends depends
depends on the DRX cycle other things
but anyway so that's pretty much it so
there's a little conclusion here and
then we're done so barrier to entry is
dropping rapidly I told you I told you
guys about how cheap software-defined
radios are getting and LTE it's got to
be around for a long time I know
everyone's like oh oh five g's coming up
soon
LT is gonna be around for a long time
yeah
GSM is around so like I was saying
earlier and okay in my lab I use I use a
software-defined radio and open source
software so open LT is alright SRS LT is
a little bit more mature you can't just
you can't just like how these things
work out of the box you actually have to
configure them to work maliciously but
once you do you're ready to go and then
lastly I have to have the the LTE tower
downgrade you to the 2g tower to run the
2g tower use open BTS and open BTS is
actually very mature gsm is older so the
open source software for the older older
stuff is like been around for a long
time so open BTS is actually really cool
if you have a software-defined radio it
doesn't have to be the ones that support
out the LTE bands but an older one is
that just has a duplex
you can run open BTS and that's your own
mini 2g network so like at Burning Man
they like had a bunch of the
software-defined radios and they and
they set up their own little mini GSM
network so broadcasting unlicensed
spectrum is illegal yeah there is what's
called broadcasting on the test band and
broadcasting as the tests operator test
P lemon so P lemon is the is the code of
the mobile country code and mobile
network code so 18 T is 3 104 one o you
broadcast is as a zero zero one zero one
you're technically the test P lemon and
you have to have SIM cards and have the
that that operator in them for that
weather device I think that that it's
it's home network otherwise it'll I
don't think it's roaming onto that and
then use the test ban which i think is
band two which is 900 so question is is
it legal if you're in the middle of
nowhere I think I'm not sure if anybody
cares but yeah you're technically
broadcasting on licensed spectrum so use
your own discretion but yeah at home
yeah so for LTE LTE has to be on USB 3.0
and one that when you're flashing the
the like open LTE or all stuff it so I
use a UHD USRP hardware driver it checks
it does clock tests and at the 10th if
the clocks speed is incorrect at all
then then it won't work so LT LT
actually needs to it needs to decode the
signal and do all this all this digital
signal processing to demodulate the
signal out of it into its bits and needs
to do that very very rapidly over over
like over very small like I was talking
about Roberto FDM so LTE you you can't
you do LTE on any kind of cheap SDR the
ones down here all support it so the B
to ten that's the one I use that one's
about a thousand bucks the hack RF and
blade RF so when I was at Def Con they
just came out with this new one it's
four hundred bucks and it's a pitch goes
up to 6 gigahertz and it's smaller the
USRP board at its research they have the
have use pretty mature software to load
load like these things are filled
program field programmable gate array or
FGP anywhere fpga so they they need very
good software to load the to flash the
that stuff and so the b210 i recommend
but it's also the most expensive gps oh
no don't need it those are external
modules that you can load but they don't
need to work they don't need me there
for the for any other stuff to to work
actually if you want to do that kind of
stuff you need them all you need the
physical module and you need the the
software set up to so getting started I
would just I would just one of these
that's or one of these these uh three
STRs and I would get started with just
the open BTS first and
and setting up that first so now that
that's the training wheels open BTS
isn't very mature and then move on to
the other LTE sit back specification
here's the sources of the jamming paper
highly recommended layer to attack the
the alter attack and then the paging
channel hijacking and that's it
[Applause]