all right so this is building breaking
blockchains with Merlin quarter
Merlin is a soccer and systems wizard
with a penchant for cryptography and
security who loves to share knowledge
and ideas with anyone who will listen
professionally Merlin is currently
working as an engineer for a blockchain
security focus startup called metal box
welcome Burlington 2018 thank you guys
thank you very much I thought I was
ready okay so as he said I'm Merlin if
you want a little bit more about me I'm
a bit of a crypto nerd I mean no space
labs keyholder I hang out at layer one
and the hardware hacking village with
milady kitten there and you can also see
me at Def Con in tamper-evident Village
I'm all kinds of places so you know find
me around so for this talk I have some
basic assumptions which are that you
have some cryptographic fundamentals and
a vague idea of a crypto currency is at
least and a passing familiarity with
Python or another language however if
you don't it's alright because we're
gonna take a little quick little lesson
to make sure we're all kind of on the
same page so the most important part for
the cryptographic fundamentals is going
to come down to hashing hashes are a
one-way function where you pass some
data and you get essentially a unique
identifier as a very large number and we
have certain properties of hashes that
we really care about ideally we want
them to be fairly randomized so that you
can't predict them we also would like it
if hashes had no collisions so that two
inputs did not ever have the same output
and you know for that we'd also like a
large amount of space for our hashes
generally you know you might think of a
cryptocurrency as magical internet
currencies you might think of it as say
a pyramid scheme you might be super hype
on it and think it's the future of all
the things
really it is though actually kind of a
bit of a really slow database and
there's a lot of different applications
not everything has to do with you know
currencies and and monies people are
doing all kinds of experiments but most
of what you hear about is definitely
gonna be around the currency token side
of things and everyone getting rich
going to the moon so whether you're in
that camp or you want to see everyone
fail this talk is relevant to you
because you want to protect your stuff
or break everyone else's stuff just for
the lulz
so you know I'm speaking to everyone
here so for basic programming
essentially if we look at this first
line here track a is gonna be equivalent
to some room there's a puffer fish on
the outside so there we go I'm Merlin
I'm equivalent to a speaker and for each
attendee in this room I'm hoping that
you're gonna listen to me and then now
you know Python basically Python is
almost exactly like the pseudo code it's
that readable so if you don't know
programming if you understood that now
you know programming congratulations all
right so there's a whole lot of articles
out there and some prior art so I would
be remiss in and not mentioning that for
example this first github link is to
this guy's example learn block chains by
building one which he wrote a nice
little article in 2017
and it makes a nice little web
application so you can kind of play
around with that the one below it is a
much more extensive complete coin so to
speak it has all the bells and whistles
of a real production blockchain and if
you want to experiment with stuff I
would say it's a pretty good basis
however it is unmaintained for last few
years Python - yadda yadda yadda so you
know take it or leave it
so with that the question is how hard
could it be and it's pretty hard to be
honest but we're gonna we're gonna keep
it as simple as possible and take our
time and of course at the end feel free
to ask me any questions I'll clarify
anything I must missed out on
or went too fast so from a high level
we've got transactions which are kind of
the basis of blocks so a transaction is
generally gonna be some kind of exchange
between one or more parties however as
we'll see when we look at the
implementation it could be any random
thing that your virtual machine will
implement and we'll talk about that more
later each block is going to be made up
of a group of transactions generally
every block needs at least one
transaction and say Bitcoin and
classical type of block chains that one
transaction is going to be what's called
the coinbase transaction we'll talk some
more about that a block chain is
essentially a graph or tree of said
blocks where you have a chain thus block
chain of blocks referring to previous
blocks and a node is essentially going
to be a minor device trying to mine new
coins or say a wallet where you're
tracking your coins and sending them
around or whatever the blockchain may do
like I said buck chains don't just have
to be currency but they often are keep
switching windows so a little more deep
on transaction transactions are
typically made up of inputs and they
point to outputs and as I said there's a
special transaction which is a coin base
so a coinbase transaction going back up
is the transaction that actually
generates the currency so what
distinguishes a coinbase transaction
typically is that it has no inputs it
comes from nowhere
it's just generated so it's basically
just a list of inputs where the stuff
came from and outputs where it's gonna
go so to create a coin you just have no
input comes from nowhere it's magic
magical internet currency
so a block is generally you're gonna
have all your transactions in there and
you're gonna sign them in some way
typically we use a merkel route or a
Merkel tree the root of the Merkel tree
specifically is what's used to kind of
give you a nice small hash of all of the
transactions in the block without
requiring extended processing for people
verifying I think I think is the main
motivation there let me restart that see
there you go that was that was the time
[Laughter]
all right
so also there's generally going to be
some kind of proof which is how
transactions are verified other nodes on
the network can take a new block that's
on the chain and essentially look at the
proof and very quickly determine whether
or not that block is in fact valid and
met all the criteria for the blockchain
so that's how confirmations and such
work is other nodes on the network are
doing that work using the proof to
confirm it and most importantly you have
the parent block because without that
you do not have a blockchain so as I
said block chains connected by parent
blocks this is just a you know very
straightforward list of children on into
infinity there's should be no limit even
in say Bitcoin where the currency stops
generating new coins there will still be
new blocks there's just that those
blocks will no longer have a coinbase
transaction that's going to be the main
difference so nodes as I said we're
speaking mainly of miners and wallets
you as a consumer you'll have
essentially a wallet node if you're
trying to mind coins you'll have a bunch
of GPUs or a6 or whatever it is for what
you're mining and those are all gonna
have their own sets of public and
private keys which is another important
part of cryptography
that's based on all this that's one
we're gonna touch on a little less
directly but essentially if you
understand say SSL or SSH keys you have
some familiarity with asymmetric
cryptography so what is the actual
network the network is just this
abstract collection of all of these
nodes who are in connection with each
other all of the blocks and then the
protocol that defines what exactly makes
that chain so one of the kind of issues
that not a lot of people necessarily
talk about that I here that I would like
to expose is for example on Bitcoin
there's no real standard of what that
protocol is you have to kind of discover
it based on the implementation of
Bitcoin so there's no like RFC standard
that can go to and read like what a
block should look like you have to
basically look at the code and if they
make a change
you have to make the same change and by
the same token as I said the network is
made up of the nodes so obviously the
developers have a lot of power but so
does everyone running the nodes if they
choose not to update to a new version of
the code it doesn't matter what the
developers push right so there's a
little bit of you know opposing forces
going on there and that's kind of what's
happening in the Bitcoin world with the
whole like size of the block issue you
may have heard about all right so we're
going to look at our first little bit of
code I wish I could zoom it in a little
more but it's pretty straightforward so
here we're defining a function called
make transaction in it or sorry make
transaction input and the important
parts about this function are that it
will receive a previous transaction ID
hash a previous transaction ID index and
some blob of data which we're going to
talk about in depth a little bit more
similarly for the outputs we're going to
produce a dictionary based on a value
and another blob of data so what are
these blobs of data in Bitcoin even
there's a virtual machine it's not as
extensive to say aetherium where they
have like a whole range of virtual
machine language stuff and like
facilities like memory so to speak on
the blockchain and things like that
it's much more simple it's more like a
basic calculator so to speak and it has
very few instructions the main
instructions are as you may have noticed
in this output it doesn't say who it
goes to
that's because who it goes to is a
script in the virtual machine language
and there are other things that you can
do in there for their example there's
kind of like null ish commands I believe
Opie return is abused by a lot of people
to do say data hiding in the blockchain
so essentially you can send a bunch of
data to nowhere because your script
won't tell it where to go which means
you can use that for other purposes for
other applications and that's also kind
of the basis of say sidechains and such
they send data to special addresses and
in special scripts and the coins are
then moved to the side chain all right
so we've got inputs we've got outputs
now we can make a transaction the
transaction is pretty much literally
just a list of the inputs and the
outputs there should always be at least
one input and one output but there could
be more you may have may have heard of
say multiple outputs or multiple
signature type things there's there's a
lot that you can do here it doesn't have
to be one-to-one it could be one too
many
is this kind of what I'm saying you said
take from one input place and say I want
to send it to three different outputs
for example and that's kind of why you
need a Bitcoin client you may have ever
wondered like why do I need a Bitcoin
client because it's got a handle of the
scripting language stuff and create
programs on the fly so as I mentioned
the coinbase transaction is simply the
first transaction in a block and it has
no inputs so here we've encoded that
very much straightforwardly we've made a
function called make transaction
coinbase it receives a value and I went
a little far thought I was in the other
window so it receives the same value and
data so that says you know how much
we're going to generate and then it has
no inputs as I said most importantly
also we make a special function here
just to make an empty transaction which
we're going to see why that's useful
very shortly and that's just pretty
straightforwardly making a transaction
with no inputs and no outputs which is
generally invalid so real quick I want
to look at which one is it five I want
to look at some hashing just to make
sure again like I said that everyone is
on the same page so in Python there's a
nice little library called hashlib that
you can import I'm gonna make a little
convenience function here called sha-2
which if you've ever used say the UNIX
shell or bash shell or whatever there's
usually a command similar to this
that'll just take any random data and
give you a digest that's this little bit
so for example if we send into sha to
the string test we get this unique
identifier if we do it again we get the
same unique identifier which we can
verify by asking Python to
if the shot to of test is indeed the
same as the shot to of test if we do the
shot to of test zero we get this value
and if we do the shot to test one we get
this value
and notice how very different they are
even though the inputs were just
different by one character almost every
character in the outputs is different so
that's kind of what I meant about the
randomized property of hashing being
very important so finally if we take a
bit more complicated data say your Bill
of Rights we can see hey here's the top
10 Bill of Rights I'm gonna make another
little convenience function which is
going to take a pair of data because I
have a short version and a long version
of each right and that's just gonna make
a shot too of both of those together and
so now I'm gonna write a nice little
loop this is very straightforward code
where we say hey we want to hash all of
these rights I'm gonna make use of a
convenience function in Python that will
easily let us enumerate them and then
for each right I will enumerate it so we
can see the hash for one here is this
guy so just kind of driving the point
home all very much unique data and it's
repeatable this is just a different way
to write this loop and we know it's the
same for the output and yet again
another way same output so hopefully
we're all 100% on the same page with
regards to hashing the reason why is
because oh I wonder if I can start it
from now I see it's already going
somewhere
hmm okay that's thank you thank you
perfect timing perfect timing let's see
if I can just cycle it no ah there we go
all right so with all that in mind we're
come back a little more concrete again
so I make a little function here to just
turn any random Python data into
something hashable and most Python data
structures are hashable already I went
too far
and so we just returned them as is
otherwise we'll convert them to a string
and strings are hashable so then I make
a little function sha-256 digests
exactly like that sha-2 function and it
makes sure that data is horrible and
returns the digest and then I make this
little interesting function that we're
gonna look at in depth in a minute
called sha-256 digest reduce and the
purpose of this is to take a list of
shots 256 values append them together
and create a new one why do we want to
do that because we want to sign our
transactions with a Merkel tree a Merkel
tree essentially if we start here at the
bottom these are the data blocks so each
of our data blocks is going to be a
transaction so we will hash each of our
transactions which will then allow us to
take each pair of transactions and hash
them together and then each other pair
and so on and so forth until you get one
overall hash value and as we saw before
each hash is unique so essentially this
is a unique identifier for all of the
transactions it's pretty clever stuff
from this guy named Merkel that's why he
got a tree named after so this is one of
the more complicated functions that
we'll look at and this is my calculate
Merkel root function and it has a nice
little dock string which is planes with
it
I will also explain what it does that's
my notes all right
so essentially as I said you know we
were looking at the diagram there we're
gonna take each of the hashes into pairs
I'm sorry we're gonna take each thing
make it into the hashes and then take
each pair of hashes and move up and up
until we get exactly one hash so that is
why we made an empty transaction thing
so that we can hear oh I'm so expecting
it to let me select it so here at this
line we test to see first if there's any
transactions and if there are we break
transactions into pairs padding with
empty transactions so if there's one
three any odd number we're gonna end up
with an even number just one of the
transactions is empty which is no
problem for us because that's our
algorithm that's our protocol we've now
specified our box chain protocol in code
oh and I have a debug print here nice
that's a good time for that once I have
made sure that I have an even number of
transactions I then hash each of those
individually and then while I have more
than two hashes I consecutively make a
new list of hashes by using that digest
reduce function that takes a pair and
makes one or takes any number and makes
one we do that to collapse it and
basically we end up with this tree so
the final value after we're sure that
there's only two is the root we return
that root and boom we have our signature
so the can you repeat your question I
just wanna make sure okay I get yes so
the question is every time you had a new
transaction do you keep recalculating
this and the answer is at least in my
implementation
no because transactions are part of the
block so you don't get a block until you
have a complete list of transactions and
so you will only calculate that route
once in in my case so we'll look at that
in a second and actually yeah for for
that
okay yes so that is the next slide so
now this is the next most complicated
bit and this is the mining process for
this blockchain that we've invented the
idea is that we calculate the merkel
route first was the very first thing we
do we calculate the Merkel route for all
of these transactions and then that will
be included in the block here so I have
an alighted function make block header
that just receives a bunch of data and
returns to you a new structure one of
the most important pieces of that data
is of course the previous block hash and
the route the medical route that we
talked about and then a little bit later
down here where we start the making of
next block that's where we add in the
transactions so we merge this header
which has the header data and then we
add in the transactions to the end so
that they're all in there and they're
signed by this route so that can then be
verified by other clients right like if
I tried to make a fake transaction go
into things it would need to have a
correct vertical route a little bit yes
we got one we got a couple more steps
here so there is also involved in it a
nonce so each block is gonna have a
particular like secret value that's
somewhat public in that it's included
with it and what happens is you need to
find a hash that combines in some way
their knots and your knots
which in my case I just add one to it so
let's say we're mining the Genesis block
right the Genesis block its previous
nonce is going to be 0 it's not gonna
have a previous hash because it's the
first block
and usually you'll do something cheeky
like the only transaction and it will
have some like news headline in it with
the date so you can prove like my
blockchain was created this day so we
need that nonce as I said and we need a
difficulty the way that difficulty is
defined in this blockchain and in
several others is basically the output
of your hash remember we looked at the
like the Bill of Rights each each one
had like a different long string the
output of your hash needs to have a
certain number of leading zeroes or some
other value that you decide it's
traditionally zeros so in this case for
the Genesis block we start out with a
difficulty of one which means it needs
to have at least one leading zero so you
take their nots you take your nots you
mix them together in this case I just
add them together in a string and oh bug
in my code oh no I didn't it's right
there and you add in the proof which is
just a random data so they're not plus
your knots plus some random data equals
a new hash that has some number of
leading zeros if it has enough leading
zeros you have found a correct block
which means now you can push to the
other nodes in the network saying hey I
found a new block it's got these
transactions it is this difficulty
here's my knots here's my proof now
other nodes can go and they can run the
same transaction they can take your
proof that you gave them they can take
the previous blocks knots and your knots
and they can get the same hash and they
can say yes correct that is a good block
now the next thing is what determines
the blockchain if there are say multiple
people who find the same block at the
same time
and that comes down to longest chain
wins however it's slightly a misnomer
because they actually mean the chain
with the largest amount of difficulty
summed up because otherwise you could
make a bunch of really really small
blocks with few transactions and low
difficulty and just kind of spam the
network and just take over right so
basically the difficulty is always
rising and there's usually some kind of
timing factor where you say you know we
want to generate X number of blocks an
hour on average so every thousand blocks
we're gonna check and we're gonna see
how many we generated and if it met our
goal then cool but if it was too many or
too little we're gonna raise or lower
the difficulty and that is pretty much
how mining works in completion it is not
any more complicated than that it's all
hashes proofs and a chain of custody did
that answer your question
cool so the transactions take as long as
they take you can't you can't really
estimate well you can only estimate I
should say because it could each time
that you're doing one of these random
things you're just guessing so each time
you have the same chance to find a
winning block right so just like you
could flip a coin 100 times and
generally it's gonna be 50/50 there's no
reason why it can't be 70/30 you know
what I mean so you could just get so
unlucky and just never find the block or
you could find two back-to-back it could
happen but that's why the difficulty is
checked at a goal at a goal point so
they say like okay cool we've made a
thousand blocks
and we wanted that to take a week but
actually it took two days
so now let's double the difficulty and
then oops we only generated 10 blocks
this week let's lower it and eventually
it comes to an equilibrium alright so
now we're going to attempt the live
untested demo so get that get that sound
effect ready okay you ready
we should be able to actually I'm gonna
make a little easier for myself
all right so now we should be able to
play with all the code that we were
looking at because it's all in here now
so for example we can say make
transaction input and we can give it a
previous TX ID hash in this case I'm
just going to put some not real data and
an index the index is important because
as I said you know multiple inputs and
multiple outputs in a transaction right
so you need to know which transaction
are you referencing that's that's the
purpose of the index and then finally
arbitrary data so in Bitcoin that's
going to be some binary string with a
bunch of like encoded data which is
gonna equal a program or a script which
is usually gonna say hey output goes
here or as I said sometimes it's abused
for other purposes like hiding data in
the blockchain in our case it can be
whatever we want so we're just gonna say
Genesis live because we're gonna use
this transaction I believe for the
Genesis block so there we go so now we
have a transaction we also are going to
need well strictly speaking we'd
probably want some kind of output and a
coinbase transaction but I'm more just
want to test the miner I assume that's
probably what you guys want to see too
so I'm not gonna worry too much about
the correctness of what I put in this
transaction we're just gonna see if it
mines okay so we've got an input so now
we need a transaction alright so
transaction is gonna be
make transaction and it's gonna take
this input and have no outputs all right
so recapping we've got a structure it is
a transaction or TX it has no outputs
and it has this input that we created
here it's attempting to be a Genesis
indication so I would normally put for
example some data here indicating what
today is and all that fun stuff all
right so now we should be able to
calculate the Merkel route on that so
let's try that oh that's wrong
and it has a problem ah thank you thank
you thank you let's see if I just give
it something I want to make sure it's
just broken okay all right so what
before it is not going to work with that
and I'm not going to live fix that right
now
so we're gonna move on and if you want
to see the mining demo see me right
after this and I apologize womp alright
so as I said there's a virtual machine
involved typically transaction outputs
are scripts
that's essentially one of the most
important takeaways that you can get
from this whole discussion of what our
transactions in the blockchain breathe a
sigh of relief though because we're not
gonna be implementing all that today but
you know you can listen to me ramble on
about it a little bit anyway what else
do we use those things for well in
aetherium they do smart contracts so
they have a much more extensive virtual
machine as I mentioned they have all the
whole lot of facilities like you can say
hey I want to source some data here and
it'll give you an address essentially
where you can store data and it's all
hashed and distributed over the
blockchain and all that fun stuff so
it's like a little mini computer like an
Arduino or something but in the box it's
pretty weird it's pretty weird so how
would we go about breaking this well you
guys think about what is controllable
and how exactly is a 51% attack executed
and what can you do there so if you have
more than more than half of the mining
pool of the mining power if you're
generating more than half of the blocks
then everybody else you can do some
nifty stuff for example the most famous
one being a double spend attack so how
does that work if my mining
demonstration had worked
we were then gonna do it but what we do
essentially
is you create a transaction with the
node you don't control and you say hey I
want to send these coins over here and
they're like sure no problem bro and on
the other side on your nodes that you
control you just start building blocks
because again the way that consensus
works is longest chain wins so in your
thing that you're doing you send those
same tokens to an address you control so
whoever is waiting on whatever service
to see hey cool I got these coins from
this person they're gonna see hey oh
this is confirmed great no problem and
they're gonna give you whatever you paid
for potentially here hoping and then the
hammer Falls and oh sorry your chain
with four new blocks and a few
confirmations is now preempted by my
chain with eight new blocks and a bunch
more confirmations sorry
those coins didn't actually go there
that transaction didn't happen and
that's a double spend you literally just
are able to do a shadow build of a block
chain and then say hey this is the real
thing and everyone has to listen to you
because you have the most work that's
the face I was hoping to see not too
often we're gonna talk about the
feasibility of all that stuff but it did
recently happen to a Bitcoin offshoot
blockchain and as if I recall correctly
they were doing something crazy like 24
or 26 blocks deep so people were like oh
no yeah it's cool this is confirmed by
13 blocks below oh no so it happens but
it takes a whole lot of effort and
money like we'll talk about it's more
later as I set mmm-hmm
so there are many attacks against smart
contracts these slides I believe will be
available to everyone after and that's a
nice little link with two nice little
article the most basic is under flow and
over flow so as I said there's a virtual
machine in here in aetherium you can
make a contract where you do stuff like
say okay I've got this public value it's
a variable imma call it zero and I'm
gonna set it to zero and you got this
other value which is au int that's a
like C language e talk for an unsigned
integer so that means it should only be
positive numbers so you're gonna say hey
there's gonna be max 2 to the 256 minus
1 that happens to be the largest integer
that that virtual machine can represent
so if you are completely unaware of this
fact or have never played around with C
and gotten bitten by all this stuff in
the past then you will be completely
surprised to find out that 0 minus 1 is
actually 2 to the 256 minus 1 and 2 to
the 256 minus 1 plus 1 over flows back
to zero so the numbers wrap around so
you would expect maybe some kind of
error like number out of range nope
it just happily processes the code so
it's basically an old-school seer alive
on the blockchain the next biggest thing
is the Dao hack so aetherium did a big
distributed autonomous organization
thing and a very smart person read
through the code and found an issue with
it and exploited it for all it was worth
to the point where they went back on
code is law and hard fork the blockchain
to say that that guy never got his money
so how did that happen recursive
function calls are dangerous especially
when you do work on either side of it so
if we imagine this is the code for the
contract and these are some breakpoints
let's kind of walk through so if we want
to withdraw money from the Dow we say
hey I would like to withdraw some amount
and it said okay cool it checks to make
sure that the sender has enough money
and if it does it uses this call to send
out the money and I believe I say and I
believe this is solidity for basically
saying return that amount now the issue
here is that this makes a recursive call
and this is where it actually subtracts
the money so the issue is that in a
virtual machine you often have a stack
and you may have heard of this website
called stack overflow well if you have
too many things on the stack the stack
will overflow and stop running so this
guy found out that basically for example
he could send in 20 30 whatever
transactions and most of them would send
out but then the stack would crash and
it couldn't unwind and subtract the
money so he basically was getting like
20 to 1 another interesting smart
contracts attack is the ERC 20 short
address attack so there's a standard in
aetherium for making tokens on aetherium
called ERC 20 and if you're not careful
with your inputs on that people can just
generate a lot more tokens than you
expected them to what they do is they
generate an address with a trailing zero
which is not hard to do you just keep
their own random data at it until you
have trailing zeros rather than leading
zeros same kind of concept as we looked
at with the mining and then you send to
that address
but you remove the trailing 0 this
causes a bug in the virtual
machine to say okay there must be some
magnitude error here let me multiply by
10 on your amount just so you can you
can essentially use this crafted address
attack to say hey give me orders of
magnitude more than you should so if you
have a node or a wallet you're gonna
want to make sure that your private keys
are protected make sure you use a
passphrase if your wallet is open also
gonna have to do is get on your box and
send those coins away or take the wallet
because then they they own the private
keys at that point if you instead have a
passphrase than encrypted they can't do
that also cold storage is a good option
if you can if you have the technical
ability which isn't too hard nowadays
there's plenty of tools that'll get you
started basically you can create an
address that you can print on a sheet of
paper and store that in a safe and that
is probably generally going to be safer
than an unprotected wallet sitting on
your computer that any random person can
steal make sure you read the manual
there's generally gonna be lots of
things in your configuration that'll
allow you to do things like you know
disallow certain clients make sure you
set a password if you have RPC all that
fun stuff if you don't people will just
find your stuff and thinking firewalls
and all that kind of basic stuff
monitoring and alerting if you're
running a service for example or if you
really care about your your wallet
contents you might want to have a
process that is watching that and making
sure that you know your funds aren't
moving unless you moved it right all
right so towards your questions sir
the economic feasibility of a 51% attack
is pretty not good in Bitcoin to do that
you're going to need millions probably
at this point billions of dollars in
electricity and gear so it's kind of
more
of a problem in smaller chains there's
any random quote-unquote coin or
altcoin is probably not gonna have
enough hashing power to stop a serious
miner who decides that they want to own
it
so definitely tread carefully in the
altcoin world make sure you look at the
difficulty rate the hash power all that
fun stuff and like any other software
there's gonna be patches make sure you
stay up-to-date with stuff just a few
days ago there was a Bitcoin dispatch
basically someone found you could send
it to crafted transaction because
remember the outputs of the transactions
are scripts that would actually crash
the client and then a gentleman over
there informed me last night that this
has actually been escalated now to a
possible Bitcoin infinite inflation bug
which has now been confirmed and given a
CVE number so make sure you stay up to
date and kind of as I mentioned before
the protocol here has changed the
protocol is different you know what I
mean there's no specification they just
made this big patch the protocol has
changed so that's that's the big deal
keep in mind to me so how do you protect
yourself in the smart contract world
avoid or interesting issues make sure
you think it all out make sure you do
all the work
before you call somewhere else because
you don't know what it's gonna happen
there you want to make sure you know all
your ducks in a row
be careful of overflows and under flows
think like a seed programmer be
defensive use a library there's a safe
math library out there that will take
care of a lot of this for you make sure
you're checking the links of addresses
and other data and there's a nifty
little thing called aetherium fiddle
which will let you build and test smart
contracts online and test them test them
and test them so any questions if you're
still awake if you want to talk to me
hit me up on IRC or hit us up at
null-space labs
starting at the end of October we're
gonna have a Halloween party hopefully
and of course you have me a drink
[Applause]
so does anyone have any questions or did
I answer them all during ha yes sir
I'm not sure offhand but I do know along
those lines that there is a fair bit of
work and research into partial use of
rework sorry reusing of your work so I
believe that there's probably a good
case for making those empty transaction
blocks getting you a good way into the
computation that you can then reuse to
be even faster at mining it sounds like
a very interesting strategy and I'll
need to look at that anybody else so
yeah so for Bitcoin you have to have a
certain number of miners keepers of
blockchain to agree as to whether the
blockchain to legitimate of them and so
one of the attacks is if you can get and
the majority of people's out out mine
the others then you win I guess that
might have happened in the past now as I
said there was a recent attack on
another Bitcoin like black chain where
they were twenty thirty blocks deep able
to rewrite transactions and as I said
it's just on the Bitcoin blockchain it's
just not economically feasible for the
amount of money that you're gonna make
doing that is gonna cost you probably
much more but at smaller that smaller
coins and off coins and stuff it's gonna
be a lot more risky so you definitely
want to pay attention to that where's
your question sir
sorry what was the end bit of that yes
so there's various enterprise-e bock
chain things that are coming out there's
a Linux consortium project called hyper
ledger it still got some issues like it
can't run multi region which is kind of
a you would expect to decentralized box
chain thing to do also I am under the
understanding that Oracle is going to
come out with one and the main things
that I've heard it applied to our things
of course like finance kind of like
settlement between banks as well as the
chain of custody type things where you
kind of want an immutable list of things
at the company that I work for we're
looking at this thing called unified
vault where they their pitch is that
they will bring all your security data
into a blockchain that will act as an
immutable log of what has happened to
your systems which can help you with
essentially remediation in the past and
you know due to the nature of the
blockchain that those logs can't have
not been tampered because if so the
blocks won't verify and such so there's
some interesting applications out there
that have nothing to do with currency I
would say
[Applause]