all right so we have thank you everyone
for coming we have building identity for
an open perimeter with Tejas Durham she
pages is a senior security software
engineer at Netflix Teja specializes in
security and is focused on corporate
Identity and Access multi-factor
authentication adapt to the
authentication and user focused security
of scale
please welcome page us to shell Khan
[Applause]
alright finally we are up and going so
yeah so my name is stages I'm a senior
security software engineer at Netflix so
basically net fixes and micro service
environments that we are building out
services and tools that focus on making
our like applications really secure and
safe and talking about safe and all the
issues that we've had so far I had a 32
character like password for my gmail
account so it just took forever to get
this thing going on
anyways so primarily we are the things
that I focus on are on Identity
Management Access Management single
sign-on and that includes adaptive
authentication and we want to make our
security story really user focused so
user focus security as well before we
dive more into the actual identity
landscape at Netflix itself I just want
to give a quick peek into what our
ecosystem is all about and see how our
story Falls align so we have apps that
are actually managing the entire
ecosystem of our Studios that basically
manages the Phils life cycle starting
from inception pre-production production
the online yards of a production then we
have applications that basically manage
our relationship with our device
partners so they to get the the to
basically get Netflix on all devices
then we have applications that manage
our relationship with Internet service
providers all over the world so that you
can get the most awesome experience on
Netflix when you go to natural
right and we have a range of engineering
applications that's helping us drive
really fast to help solve all our
business use cases and we have a range
of SAS applications so what we're
talking about is right now 700 plus
applications and the number is
constantly on a on a progression so so a
lot of applications and various use
cases like all of you we want to make
sure like we are making making Netflix
really safe especially if the apps at
which rate at which they're working one
thing that makes this different is our
culture and I'll talk about like how our
culture plays a role in how we focus on
security specifically so two years ago
this was a typical setup that we had we
had secure network parameter and and
then we had manage devices so anyone who
actually wanted to get connected to our
applications they basically jump on a
VPN and then connect with these
applications using their identity and
that basically protects all the
sensitive data that we have an ecosystem
that we but what used to happen in that
same time period is people connect from
any open network like you go to
Starbucks and you can freely connect any
only thing you have to do is jump on a
VPN and access applications so we
started questioning yourself whether we
really want to trust the network that
you connect to access our applications
and this is where our location
independent security approach helped us
move away from that mindset so if if if
if you guys are aware of like the
googles beyond Corp model this is kind
of aligned to that as well so we said ok
let's great let's let's not worry about
like what network you can come from
let's treat all Network as insecure and
treat them accordingly another
interesting aspect and this is where our
culture comes into picture is freedom
and responsibility so what we believe is
people people really strive with freedom
and they are really like worthy of the
freedom so you can go into any store
bile device let that be a laptop iPad
phone whatever in connector
connected the network and then you just
can access our applications so then we
were this is kind of contrary to what we
were in the set up in terms of manage
devices now we have any kind of devices
connecting to access our application so
we're like let's just not worry about
manage devices anymore and all we have
is in secure networks unmanaged devices
and people are just trying to get access
to our applications so how do we go from
the two year ago story to where we want
to actually reach so that's what today
I'm going to cover in terms of how we
have gone how do how have you covered
this particular distance so far but if
you just take a look at the from a
bird's eye view what it is is there are
users who are basically trying to access
applications and when they're trying to
access applications what we want is some
sort of a really strong proofing of that
identity we have strong authentication
and that needs to account for a range of
things and we'll cover in depth like
what are the range of things that we
look out for but but it needs to cover a
range of things once a user is strongly
attenti catered to these applications
then applications they basically want to
consume the same identity right they
might want to take that identity
information and use it for a whole bunch
of different purposes it could be giving
access you to access to sensitive
resources or it might be giving you
using those same information for
applying fine-grain authorization rules
right that can be anything so we want
some sort of way for for streaming this
medical identity information down to
applications and in all of this we would
have increased like the security story
around it but how can we make all of
this frictionless both from an end-user
perspective as well as applications who
are who wanted who are wanting to make
the application secure right so so
that's a really high level what we would
want to achieve by this so at the core
of this is the identity itself right so
in our in our ecosystem the the identity
landscape is broken down into two main
categories one is the corporate
landscape veteran
all our employees contractors and see
his folks who are basically bucketed
under so we term them as workforce
identity and then we have partners and
partners is quite wide in our ecosystem
and these are people who are responsible
for various facets that are helping
drive our business so they are basically
managing these our users or our partner
users who are basically helping us with
our localization subtabs
like pre post production these are
studio users who are actually working on
our productions are these are device
partners or open connect partners so all
of those we term them as partners and
how really high-level they're broken
down into these two main categories and
we'd really don't want this to happen
wherein we have identity so silos and
that just not leads to duplicate
identities but in general like how do we
go about securing all these underlying
different storage if at all that was a
roadtrip ended we went up going so what
we have done is streamline that again
into two different buckets at the very
top on the workflow side we have our
identities originate from our HR system
workday and they are streamed into
Google for which we use primarily for
our authentication purposes on the
Parden side if you have a homegrown
solution and we we put them into our
homegrown directory service and all
those identities are housed there so
great so now we have unified like these
two classes of identities and in general
if I talk about numbers we have 130
thousand plus identities in that
ecosystem overall and it's on a constant
progression considering the rate at
which our productions are growing so so
we are talking about like quite a large
population as such so now how do we go
about establishing like some sort of a
really strong trust in who in the
incoming authentication requests in our
in our Minar at Netflix basically
so the core of it is obviously the first
factor Varon basically you go about
using your user name and credentials and
and that's how you start like the
establishment of the trust process but
I'm guessing like we all are on the same
page in terms of how passwords are
really horrible things and there there
have been like a data breaches that we
can go about reading about in terms of
how a social engineering and malicious
software as well as credential stuffing
is so common right so those are the most
common practices father to get access to
somebody's account and if you see like
the top three breaches that have or the
categories of breaches you will see the
same character same things applying
there as well another interesting fact
is if you if you check out the this
particular research from Telus on like
54% of the consumers they are actually
using five or less passwords so and
130,000 plus identities and on a
constant progression and this particular
number just throws us off right so
clearly if the first factor is not the
only factor we should all be focusing on
we need to add some additional stuff on
that so and what do we use like what
would make sense for our business use
case considering we has such wide
diverse population of users so I'll just
talk through like some of the methods
and we use the range of methods
available and apply them based on
various use cases starting from starting
from again not the ideal methodology to
use is a one-time passcode that is
basically sent to your device using SMS
or a phone call
I'm guessing everyone is aware of like
what other risk associated with this
around phone number to take over sim sim
k covers man-in-the-middle attacks all
different possible range of attacks that
are possible using phone based one-time
passcode so clearly not an ideal silly
solution but it's still if you don't
have a second factor enable this is
still a good or at least an initial step
that would take you in the right
direction but obviously in our ecosystem
that clearly doesn't fit our use cases
so that goes out of picture then the
next progression is using the time-based
one-time pass codes where you have an
Authenticator app you set that up and it
spits out a code which are valid for 30
seconds right but still exposed to
phishing attacks still exposed to a
man-in-the-middle attack so it totally
not not the right thing to go about the
next thing and again like the
Authenticator based approaches again
like not an ideal approach for us so we
would like to make it more predominant
in our ecosystem there are some more
stronger methods so push notifications
these are great like deep row the other
methods they don't provide enough enough
context in terms of who and what kind of
operation that you're trying to carry
out right so push notifications gives
you that capability you can include as
much contextual information like hey
this is stages trying to access like
this particular sense of the financial
application from San Jose is this like
really you please verify that right so
that kind of contextual information it
helps make people perform the right
decisions right together to approve or
deny the transaction so so this is so
this gives you that capability so this
is this fits a large population of our
user base and where we want to go strive
towards is the next method where we want
to at least on the corporate landscape
u2f is what we would like to actually
make sure like all our employees are
using right so in this specific
methodology you have a security key you
would plug it into your device and you
would register that specific security
key strongly a phishing resistant like
there's absolutely not no way possible
for that as your credentials are really
bound to the origin where you registered
right so so really super secure and
establishes our really strong
in terms of who the user is and and a
great second factor option so we have
like all these different options
available we pick and choose like what
makes sense obviously security keys
might not make sense for a really high
sensitive production where people are
working on what other options we can use
so we we are basically flexible in terms
of what are the options we go about
applying alright so again like it's
something if you're if you're have the
second factor enable there are different
options available probably it'll be
better to make a decision in terms of
what fits your business use case but we
have second factor let's just apply it
for everyone right like that would have
just been so simple let's just apply it
for everyone
multi-factor out everyone every time any
application you go
let that be I'm a users trying to access
like a simple lunch many application
let's just multi-factor out them right
or somebody's trying to go to our kind
of sensitive like some sort of a data
application but you're getting data out
that might probably make sense but if
you're going to a financial application
absolutely yes
like let's just apply it for them so
their various application sensitivity
aspect as well as who the users
what kind of the sensitivity aspect of
the request that's coming in let's take
that into account to make our decisions
so this is where we have invested
heavily into our adaptive authentication
story so obviously we don't want to
multi-factor out everyone every single
time but let's how do we go about like
making it so dynamic that it makes sense
we're actually it's prompted so what we
take an approach is we start take an
approach of what our address rings we'll
think about when they are trying to
target us right what are the different
things or different patterns that they
would be looking out for to basically
get into any of our applications so we
start thinking about us us in that
direction and there are quite a lot of
things we take into account and we have
tried have made it more
for risk-based approach and we establish
a risk level associated with every
authentication request that is coming in
and what are the factors that we account
for one unique aspect that we have added
into our ecosystem is the likelihood of
a user visiting an application so how
that works is me as stages I have had
previous transactions going to
application a which is a launch many
application then AWS maybe and then some
severely sensitive application and what
kind of access pattern that have
established in terms of kind of
applications that I go about visiting
and what are my other peers actually
doing as well like what are the kind of
applications that these users are going
about so very we have a machine learning
pipeline where we taken all previous
authentication transaction and inject it
into that pipeline which constantly
re-evaluates what uses typical access
pattern might be right so that's
interesting now we can kind of predict
what is might end up going to and what
is the likelihood of that and I'll give
it a score all right so apply that score
and then we take into account more
things right so if I'm an attacker what
I might be thinking of doing so I might
be trying to laterally traverse through
different applications right so I'm
trying to fire off like different
applications and every place I go I'm
getting blocked by the second factor
prompt right I might not be completing
this transaction I'm just might be
abandoning those requests or I might be
initiating those push but there might be
failed or after even after the push it
gets a user gets a notification user
rejects the request right so there are a
lot of patents that can be detected
based on previous transactions that have
had and we use that into another factor
to apply a risk associated with that and
if we figure out like hey you abandon or
your fear like previous X amount of
requests we definitely think that we
should be stepping up for you for next
few transactions just to verify it's
really you right
so that's a that's another factor which
adds a higher score if he if you
determine that right then the device
itself so this particular aspect is
interesting so now I've used this
specific device like just to establish
my trust and I've done successfully
second factor so let's just trust us
give some sort of a trust to this
particular device so what we end up
doing is we create a session cookie and
we stick it to the specific device
itself so that gives kind of some sort
of an assurance for for for where I have
previously logged in from right so that
adds a little bit of score giving us
some extra assurance on where this
request is coming from
we still would want to keep it per app
as well if there are really sensitive
applications and and we want to regular
at a regular cadence we would want to
step up in that case we would want to
take into account like what is that app
looked like and what can be - so
application owners can go and specify
that hey I want my applications my
application to be doing step up at a
regular cadence or every single time
right it all depends what type of
application it is so but definitely
something to account for then the
location aspect where your
authentication request is coming from
and there are quite a few in things are
on this aspect as well we take into
account if you are coming from a really
risky location which we deem as risky we
would outright deny you will not even
like wait for you to step up with just
outright deny you but if you're coming
from unknown vocations previous known
locations and all of a sudden you're
going to a different location then it
might make sense for us to add some sort
of an extra score in addition to all the
other facets to it right and that would
basically add to the to our risk over
assessment and finally this is another
interesting aspect that we have added is
an app known as stethoscope and this is
open source so what we have taken is a
different approach to manage the by
so we the traditional managed devices of
collecting device information all the
time and crunching information doesn't
fit our use case we wanted to be more of
a user driven model wherein we want to
empower people with the right amount of
information and so this is a local
native application available for mac and
Windows where it will give it'll provide
users the right enough of information
and it'll guide people through like what
you would need to make your device
secure what we think are the right
things right so feel free to check it
out and give us some feedback and it's
it's on Netflix's github so but that is
so good like we have a native
application it is telling us some
information but how do we make it really
valuable to our adaptive authentication
story right so what we have done is we
have fired this off right and during the
authentication process itself we're in a
real time it'll query out your device
and it will tell us what exactly is the
state of your device and in this case
firewall is not enable it'll tell you
firewall is not an e-book it will give
you instructions on how you would go
about enabling firewall you do that and
yeah you click on a check again button
and there you go like your device is in
a state wherever you think it should be
and now you can go about like accessing
your application so a different way of
us thinking about how around the manage
devices aspect and and and how do we use
that information so now great so we have
so many different factors that we have
accounted for and those are some of the
factors that have highlighted but so now
we can make smarter decisions due to our
multi-factor re-and make it right but
it's super complex and how do we make it
simple that it's easy for people to
actually integrate into our into our
solution right all great security
offerings but it comes at the expense of
how we can make it frictionless so this
is the answer to that is mutual
you know the house of cards character
that's where its name from so it's
basically a federation hub which is
built on top of ping federate again like
ping Federer is something that we just
use because it helps us it fits our
needs but there are all there are great
identity providers out there and all of
them they offer great offering so feel
free to check them out but yeah so
that's basically a federation hub where
the previous winners showed where and we
have injected like the device hell jack
detection and all the adaptive a story
it's it's hooked up there so well how
does it go so we have the first factor
obviously Soviet radar to Google for for
the odd process and we fed right out to
the internal directory service right for
auditing our partners as well so that
and the other interesting aspect is
because we have so diverse population it
is important like we have customizable
login experiences to fit different use
cases so this is where the the hub also
comes into picture where we based on
different user population we can present
things which are which make sense for
that user population then the second
factor there are so many providers out
there again which one to use
so in our ecosystem we use a three
predominantly so far so Google obviously
when you're accessing or anything inside
G suite is when you use Google's
multi-factor options in there and then
we use duo to perform our own step up on
top of Google right so we use that based
on our adaptive what we will fire of duo
in that case and for our partner
landscape we use 2 leos awti right
because that helps because our partners
are kind of fitting in the consumer
space so it fits that specific model and
the entire adaptive authentication is
it's this real-time happening everything
happens real-time based on the
sensitivity of the requests that we are
receiving so it's act up direct directly
during the authentication process itself
so all of these things are hooked up
during the art process and these are
range of micro services that we fire off
calls to during the process
so as that dose when there are other
providers out there and it might fit
other bees need this is octaves
like rule-based definition of what it
makes sense for enabling like
multi-factor ah
looks pretty promising so for you to
check that out and even like one login
right so they have a kind of similar
risk based assessment approach in there
so you as an organization if if if
second factor is something that you have
enabled but you want to make it smarter
than this might be another great thing
to have as well so great now we have
strong up we have the our identity
provider in there but now how do we how
do these apps actually integrate into
into this particular solution we
definitely don't want to have central
admins who are managing these
integrations like working with all these
different engineering teams managing
these integrations with them we wanted
to make our engineers empower engineers
so basically carry out themselves so
this is where we have built self-service
tool which helps register open ID
connect clients and it kind of takes a
delegated approach model where apps can
define owners and every everyone can
actually manage those applications and
integrations so you integrate that this
way and it provides a range of
configuration options in terms of how
you would go about configuring your
grants how you do go about configuring
your redirect your eyes scopes and other
aspects which I'll go over in a bit but
yeah so this is this was one way for us
to help our engineers move forward
faster and not be a blocker for them
another interesting thing in our
ecosystem is any new micro service that
comes up there are certain base level
things that they get which we term as
base server right and one of the things
that they get by default is Apache so
now that adds an interesting twist to
our story is like we have a self-service
tool which is helping drive the
integration but that can actually spread
out Apache configuration automatically
which apps can take and add it to their
applications so we use morado
an IDC the passion module for helping
applications integrate and and make
their application secure so this is what
we use but obviously that would work in
an ideal situation where we cover a
hundred percent of the use case but then
we have a range of other applications
where Apache might not even make sense
right
we have no TAS app we have single page
applications and and range of
technologies and at Netflix you can
you're free to use any technology as
long as it helps you push the bar to the
next level right so in all these cases
obviously Apache doesn't make sense and
you end up having an Apache avoidance
syndrome right so so how do we tackle
this situation so in the past what we
have done is we have recommended
applications where is certified like
open IT connect client libraries and
that had worked great but it still
exposes us to different aspects one is a
it's some extra effort which engineers
have to do and they need to understand
the terminologies they need to get
themselves tuned to that and be is like
they need to configure it in the right
way without leaving certain routes which
an attacker can get through so it still
leaves us some room where things can go
wrong
right and how I can we close that gap as
well so over the last one year we have
worked with Amazon very closely on
pushing authentication right to the load
balancer itself so and great news around
that is as of May this year this has
been GA from Amazon and now you can
enable authentication directly at the
application load balancer itself and
it's quite simple in terms of what
Amazon today provides in terms of
certain base level configuration you
just inject there and and specify the
the port and route on which odd needs to
be enable and there you go like authors
enable for you right and it has two
different of flavors it you can hook it
up to your own IDP or you can hook it up
to Amazon's canítö as well so two
different approaches so far by
it's a great step forward in the right
direction but that's so tedious for an
engineer to go into an Amazon console
and taking all the configuration and
apply themselves where can we take this
to the next level so the answer to that
is vinegar which is our continuous like
delivery platform if you guys are not
are using or haven't heard of it you
should definitely check it out as an
awesome continuous delivery platform and
and it's a multi cloud provider as well
so check it out so what we have done is
we have strongly integrated with
spinnaker internally with the
self-service tool that tool that we have
so this is a snippet of how you would do
it on spinnaker you go and configure try
to configure the listener and there and
enable the authentication rule in there
and double configuration clicks and you
specify the base level attributes in
here all right so this is the OSS
version what I'm screenshots are
presented there's a different flavor for
our internal use wearin this is still a
few configuration elements that you have
to fill out but internally what we have
done is when you enable the menu click
on that specific button it strongly tire
integrates with our internal tool and
the only thing that you need to do is
just click that button and everything is
wired out automatically for you so it's
just and what we termed that as a zero
configuration where you just click and
things up working as expected so that's
that's how we have tried to take our
approach Apache works great for a lot of
applications if things don't work then
yes like load balancer is the way to go
and and if you don't care about anything
apart from just having authen able then
that's the way to go if you want like
some really custom configuration that
you want to do then yeah sure like let's
let's talk about Apache so so great so
now we have all enabled on pretty much
every application in our ecosystem and
that means I've done a strong are done
step up and required and I've accessed
this particular application but does
that mean that these
the engineer should be able to access a
financial application versus they just
say engineer trying to access some
engineering application right like do we
need to have some other level of
assurance around that and that's where
we authorization comes into picture so
authorization is also very crucial to us
in terms of who gets access to what so
at the really high level in the same
cell service tool you have you can apply
some authorization rules right there
itself indicating that hey this
application it's available for any class
of particularly any class of users or I
want to like restrict it down to like
certain class of folks right a certain
user base certain group base certain
other user attributes like totally you
can do that and it's the same
self-service tool you will end up using
all right this might work great to have
like authorization out of box available
but it might not work for pretty much
every class of application we would
still want some sort of a way to
communicate the identity information
down to these applications so that they
can actually apply some other fine-grain
authorization rules if they like to so
another interesting aspect that we have
added is hey tell us what attributes you
want us to package for you right
so when you are configuring a client you
would indicate what attributes you care
about and we will package that up into
an access token and pass it down the
application or you can if you're on the
client side you can just call out to the
user info endpoint and you'll get the
same kind of attributes so so yeah so
different classes of attributes and
everyone can just pick and choose
whatever they works for them so this
helps us achieve like some sort of an
authorization aspect as well there are
other other internal services that are
primarily focused in our ecosystem doing
even finer grain authorization but this
provides
applications in general authorization
that they can really opt into so so yeah
so the the story around like we were two
years ago we were at one state and now
we have no parameter no manage devices
and the core ingredients that we
for that aligns with our security
stories hey we need to have unified
identity make sure we don't have
duplicate identities apply single
sign-on and have authentication enable
for every application then make a strong
authentication including adaptive odd
authorization and range of other factors
so so that's our story in terms of how
we have taken our approach and made our
security story pretty strong so far and
that's about it I guess so one thing I
want to highlight here is we are hiring
we are outside as well we have a booth
so feel free to check out jobs at like
jobs on AFRICOM and if you have anything
that interests you feel free to hit me
up or reach out to us outside yeah take
questions there are different approaches
to that so far will not enable it might
not make sense to what type of
application that you're trying to go to
but if it's a really sensitive app and
we feel like all these ten factors that
we have is absolute must then we will
enforce a mandatory required yeah you
can totally we can we can customize
based on that but as it stands today we
it's a more more of an informational
perspective at least from a range of
applications that we have hooked up set
scope it but yeah the long-term vision
is we want to make our base rules
indicating like which what is mandatory
and when it's not required
right so totally yes yeah
any of them you mentioned if there's
multiple methods for mfa obviously some
of the Foresters none there's like
really by SMS is secure effect
did
yes I had it otherwise so I offer SMS as
any factor from anyone but we have kept
it as an option if there is a really
high profile user coming in and you want
to really enable it for so in a below
the second factor aspect and we don't
have to have that entirely compass on
aspect then we will still try to better
than nothing but as it stands today we
don't n able SMS for any any class of
population yeah
[Music]
uber lockdown
so we that's what we have moved
ourselves away from the entire manage
device aspect completely and the way we
we think that we should educate we
believe in educating people and this is
where a culture comes into picture so we
believe like as long as I tell you that
hey looks like your laptop is not locked
your screen lock is not enabled or your
device is not encrypted we will give you
informational messages using the
stethoscope application but if we think
that you're trying to access some
sensitive application and we think that
you should enable that before we can
trust your have a strong assurance on
your device we will try to block you
till you fix that particular aspect you
mean on the actual endpoint itself
so again with the business of encrypting
it but like out of the box obviously Mac
provides that device encryption aspect
so we will let people know that hey
please enable that particular device
encryption aspect in there and and
enable so we don't encrypt specifically
like devices like you can we don't we
don't care about that that much as long
as we so basically the way our approach
is a little different in that space is
we encourage people not to store
sensitive information on your devices
right we want everything on the other
cloud and and specifically in our
ecosystem use drives heavily so there's
no reason for you to have things on your
device even if you are working remotely
or even I know fine scenarios but having
said that there there might be outliers
who will be still doing it but our
approach to that is make sure screen
lock is enabled make sure device
encryption is enabled on your local
device and and that's how we would
recommend you during the live of
indication process yeah sure yeah
you mean to say in the end point itself
Oh
so in a way I will take cost as an
aspect but in a way of especially around
the securing the network parameter it's
just too involving to have that kind of
mindset available right in terms of
having strong tunneling available
between between our whatever like the
corporate network itself but our
approaches to that is regardless of what
I what the security parameter I have
within veneer within the net flix
boundaries that defeats the purpose when
you go outside the boundary anyways
right so so yeah is like why don't just
make our applications more secure and
and another thing is like getting on to
VPN is to conversing right it's just too
annoying to to be using that so why not
just go away from that model and why not
just make things available everything
available externally and there's no
reason for us to be worried about as
long as we can detect anything wrong
that's gonna happen and any wrong thing
that can impact us I don't think the
cost is a factor that we take into
account yeah so so yeah so we believe in
like having stronger detection using our
data more efficiently and cost is the
last thing that we care about
we I mean not an increase in attack
traffic or applications but we
definitely have more detection going on
now so and based on our metrics we we
can clearly identify like various
malicious patterns that we can out like
outright see and how successfully we've
been able to like block those outright
access completely so that just gives us
a more assurance aspect in terms of the
investments have been the right
investments that we have done so far
yeah any questions so interesting aspect
and a few colleagues on the back over
giving me a smile but a Lea is an
interesting aspect we as Netflix at
least on the corporate side we are our
vision is to move away completely from
ad and there are outlying like legacy
applications especially their tasks in
speed of apps that still rely on ad
specifically lookup so what we have done
is a different model where and we are
using Google as a primary IDP for the
for the employee side of it and we
stream that identity information down to
our core PD itself and that is primarily
used for lookups no more authentic
Asians carried out but yes so Google is
also working towards having Google LDAP
as a core thing it's all still a it's I
think be beta or something yeah that's
what yeah so we've been closely working
with Google on that aspect as well
in the office or probably come back out
like a stem career and begin or so you
can force it to away even if somebody
sits in one yeah yeah because as I told
you even our net even our Wi-Fi is
considered to be like a non-secure or
network itself so regardless you're
coming internal-external yes it's the
same policies apply yeah
to access it based on what you see so we
categorize or risk or is based on a low
medium high kind of category all right
and so each of those factors they go
into that low medium high category and
if for example let me just pick up a
location aspect if you're coming from
let's say a risky location let's say
North Korea right in that case we would
bump up the score really high and that
becomes the most factor of that account
accounts for the risk factor right so
every facet is gots a classified as low
medium high and based on that we rank
the scores it goes by app to app as well
so if you're going to a lunch many
application it should be like really low
bar right so and by default every
application is considered to be in a top
category and you can downgrade yourself
to a low category application so any new
application comes out it gets the most
secure option out out of the box and
then you can downgrade yourself based on
based on your decision making but yes
and the reason why I've kept it final
green so that applications can actually
make the right decisions using our
self-service tool itself so that they
can indicate like what kind of level we
think we should set for application so
that's why it gives us more flexibility
to tweak around but everyone just gets a
base level if you're not if you have not
tweaked out right deny
yeah all of this is homegrown solution
like what I just says Spectre and any
factor that he saw its so we have one
particular micro service that's doing
all the decision-making that talks to
our internal identity provide providers
in this case like Google as well as our
internal directory service to get like
user data as well so so yeah so there's
micro service that does a
decision-making and then talks to other
micro service to carve out like the
different multi-factor providers as well
yeah but everything is homegrown
solution another thing I wanted to
highlight like all of these different
passes that we cover like I'm also
looking for feedback if anyone is
interested in any aspect which we have
not open sourced yet we can chat about
it and what questions alright thank you
so much
[Applause]