all right so this is how not to suck at
vulnerability management with plugin
Chris help where's my plug is currently
a paranoid fire remember at OAuth he
started his journey in computer security
back in 1996 when he discovered a 2600
magazine that eventually led him to the
first laa 2600 meeting in 1998 from that
point forward he has been involved in
computer security his worked as systems
administrator security analyst and
security engineer in the finance and
telecom sector and it's pretty time he
enjoys building Legos and playing with
synthesizers and modular systems
impossible he volunteers his time to
computer security events chris is a is
currently a senior security engineer at
Verizon digital media services formerly
EdgeCast you started working with
computers in high school and having
older slower computers quickly made the
move to Linux and BSD is to improve
performance from Nenana he's worked with
Nick systems almost exclusively and a
couple of years ago made the switch from
being a systems administrator to working
exclusively in security we're not
working Chris and Joyce cryptocurrencies
his dogs and putting wacky stuff on
various raspberry PI's
please welcome plugin chris so morning
thank you for being here I know it's
early so welcome to shell con
so I'm plug grace and so today we're
gonna talk about bone management and
primary we're gonna talk about how not
to sucker bubble management so Chris and
I worked for a city and it's braxton
digital media in the past and what we're
gonna told you is our story working on
that environment which is pretty
fast-paced and we see seven to ten
percent of the internet traffic around
the world so there's a lot of data and
it's very important that we manage moun
that abilities at a fast pace so without
further ado let's talk about ball
management and so why we did this talk
well let's talk about the current
landscape what you can see this screen
is a lot of different brands and
companies and they all have a few things
in common the first one is that they all
have been breached and the second one is
that a lot of our data was part of the
breach data that was disposed and so
that is really bad for us it's really
bad for them on PR but also if you look
at the set of vulnerabilities many of
those vulnerabilities are tied into
basically bad
vulnerability management either you have
databases that were suppose you have
vulnerabilities and software maybe you
have things that were on buckets that
you forgot or credentials on github and
so forth so you know this is part of
your program and so this is the reason
why we're doing this talk we want to
hopefully help other people get better
at mall management now I like this
actually I think we just something just
happen here so I like this is light and
thank you for that little break so this
is a very important thing because dual
apps actually put this report some time
ago and they actually discovered there's
a lot of stuff on the cloud that is
really bad and they found a lot of
buckets open so if you're using the
cloud you know vulnerability management
it's important to you so you know we can
tighten laudable net abilities not only
from software side but also in the cloud
so that's where we are and this is the
reason why we're doing this talk now
before we get further we need to define
what vulnerability management is and
vulnerability management is not a
compliance checkmark if that's what you
think it is you're already doing it
wrong please don't do that and hopefully
this talk will help you have a different
approach so not a compliance check mark
also vulnerability management is is not
easy you know if it was easy everyone
will be able to do it so there's
challenges and we want to talk about
those when you begin with a
vulnerability management program you're
gonna have to set some goals these will
define your program and it will help you
mature that program in our experiences
these are the things that are important
and things you should consider so the
first one is quick identifications how
soon can you identify a vulnerability
and you know do something about it so
the sooner you know about a
vulnerability the better you're able to
respond to that so the goal is to reduce
the time to discovery
goal number two is triage now you know
that there's a vulnerability then you
have to make a decision the blue team is
due decisions and they have to do it
fairly fast
I said vulnerability management team you
should be able to do that as well so
triage is super important and finally we
want to talk about remediation so now
that you know that there's a
vulnerability and you figure out how
important it is to you you need to think
about how you're gonna remediate or
mitigate that vulnerability so those
should be your goals on your program the
things that you should target and try to
mature and refine now there are some
challenges and these are important so
first of all there's a lot of sources of
vulnerabilities if you work in an
environment where you have different
operating systems multiple Network
devices and so forth you get bulletins
from different places so it's difficult
to navigate that landscape also there
are times where double net ability
arrives and there is actually no patch
and sometimes you cannot even patch
maybe you are working on outdated
software and so you need to account for
these things so this is an important one
for me a lot of people doable management
they really think about the cbss system
which is the common vulnerabilities
current system and my beef with this
particular thing it's in the standard
that is very useful but if you're using
only this core system to drive your
vulnerabilities you're already having
problems because you need context to
make decisions you should not rely on
that score system to decide whether
something is critical lower or medium
you should add context and I'm gonna
give you some examples of why that
matter so does anyone know what these
symbols mean these so the first one yeah
okay so the first one is heartbleed
okay now heartbleed came out on 2014 and
at the time they had this core system
version 2.0 if you look at this core
it's a 5.0 yet most people treated like
really high so the question is if you
were by this core system what would
you've done what do you do and so this
is one example of a vulnerability that
might have been important for some
people and maybe not for others but it
was score very low now does anyone
recognize the other label on the bottom
so that is a general blue and so that
was an exploit of vulnerability in SMB
an allow
you know the Mirai bar tonight if not
mistaken um so the important thing about
this one is that by now we have two
scoring systems 2.0 version and 3.0 so
if you're going by the 3.0 version which
is the latest it was a score at 8.1 if
you use that two system it was the score
nine point three so then which is core
system do you want to use version two or
version three and then if you use any of
them you might have downplayed the
vulnerability so again context is very
important
finally it's it score out of ten
yes so another thing that is important
is there are sometimes undisclosed
vulnerabilities or vulnerable is that
get out of CSV right but they don't have
any score system like there's no a score
maybe there is even a patch out there
but you have no score so what do you do
again this is why it's important that
you try not to rely too much on the
scoring system and you build something
that allows you to take a consideration
the context how does this matter to my
organization and what am I gonna do
about it so that might be if would see
ESS score and again take it with a grain
of salt now when you do a vulnerability
management program you have to have some
prerequisites is they're very important
to help you get your program up started
really in a good state right and so one
of them is you need to know your assets
right if you don't know your assets then
you don't know what you're gonna have to
protect or patch or do something about
so it's very important that if you have
a spreadsheet and you have your IP
addresses host names and everything else
it that's fine
ideally moving to a CMDB there's a bunch
of an open source that totally free you
want to make sure you keep your IP
addresses space up-to-date and you you
know that's a very important thing
because you're gonna be scanning and
doing other things so a very important
concept if you have the cloud there's a
bunch of tools that are open source next
flicks is is down this you know down the
hallway and actually have security
monkey you can use it totally free and
you can get a nice inventory of your
assets on the cloud and then you need to
consider is the is this vulnerability at
play is it a play for the cloud does it
impact me so which is this is and so
forth another very important thing in
vulnerability management is attribution
so now you have a vulnerable
you know that impacts a system but then
who owns that system
who's gonna patch the system am I
responsible someone else how do I
coordinate all of that so being able to
attribute that system the ownership is
super important and it's super important
because you need to do a triage and you
need to decide who am I going to contact
to get it sorted out so make sure that
when you build your asset list you also
include who owns the asset is there a
team responsible and so forth another
thing that is extremely important in
this attribution concept is that you
never will be an expert on everything so
lean on your teams reach out to the team
and say hey I don't know this this seems
to be yours is this yours now does
anyone know about this it's okay you
work in security but other teams know
something's systems better than you and
so it's okay to reach out do it now
we're gonna get a little bit into the
theory and then we come back into some
other topic so there's intelligence from
the outside there's sort of external
intelligence and there's sort of your
internal intelligence how your
environment looks you want to kind of
merge those data sources together in a
way that makes sense that way you can
you can action the data of it oftentimes
you're gonna find yourself saying things
like hey go patch sometimes you'll be
asking other questions about like maybe
like what libraries are used in your
pieces of software but the most
important rule of like doing volt
management well is not to get bogged
down like if you're if you find yourself
spending two three weeks on each fold
you're gonna you're gonna end up you
know just you're gonna get a backlog of
poems that you're not being able to
action because you're gonna get yourself
bogged down too much so make sure that
you can you know be a little bit about
all lead and like stick and move a bit
[Music]
all right so external intelligence it's
a buzzword out there now but it can
include a bunch of different things so
like public CBE's a blog post security
Bolton's other other things you want to
be picky about these sources you know
there's there's a ton of them but what
you want to find is you want to find the
ones that give you the most
signal-to-noise ratio for your
environment so like if you're if you're
doing a bunch of stuff in the cloud and
you you're a big Java shop maybe maybe a
bone source from from Oracle that tells
you about new phones and Java is what
you really want to focus on as you as
your first choice you know if you're
like us and you run a big a boot to shop
bunch of a bunch of servers you know
maybe I'm going to security notices if
it's red hat maybe it's red has security
notices if it's Windows maybe you're
you're you know Microsoft security
bulletins but whatever it is you're
gonna record it's gonna require you to
do a little bit of parsing of the data
to really make sense of it and
understand how it works and like that
can be human but ideally you'd want to
make that as machine parsed as possible
so internal intelligence is kind of a
buzzword we made up I hope to see it
soon in every talk around the world but
the important things that you want to do
here is you want to you want to take
information about your environment you
want to essentially you don't have to
cache it somewhere but you should cache
it somewhere for use and you really want
to care about accuracy and and quantity
of the data that you're getting like you
want you want to gather most if not all
of the the data about your environment
you want to make sure that it's accurate
because when when you need to send this
data out elsewhere it later on for
people to do things you want to make
sure that you're not like having to go
back every time and you know ask
questions you want people to trust your
data effectively and this is the point
where it makes a lot of sense to build a
lot of your integrations your internal
external intelligence sources or into
your asset management databases or just
some of your control structures whatever
they happen to be so there are a bunch
of tools that can provide you internal
intelligence you can use like a bunch of
network stuff there's a network devices
you can look at like you could look at
you know your switches and parse out
like every active port you know there's
a bunch of different ways to grab this
sort of data flow data is something that
we've we've started to look at and it
actually provides very good intelligence
about what's sending stuff where so you
can figure out like what services are
actually active on your servers
we haven't done anything cool with flow
data yet but you know you should that
would be great and open source it so we
can use it metrics are important when it
comes to building your program you want
to collect your metrics to figure out
what's going on and you want to be able
to use the metrics you collect to to
improve the way that you do things and
you know graphs are great if you can
graph out things not only is it fun and
makes me happy it'll it'll make make you
a better person
maybe but it's very important to make
sure that you don't make like convoluted
graphs like this graph it has a lot of
great data in it and if you look at it
for a while you can figure out what's
going on but don't don't send this to
somebody and say oh yes this and then
you know expect them to really
understand what's going on like it's
it's it's not gonna do what necessarily
what you want it to do it's alright to
make your graphs a little bit higher
level this is something that a former
member of our team made about our our
network scan information that we got
back and it's actually very consumable
like when we when we handed this to
teams they were able to really
understand what we were what we were
getting not necessarily mad at but you
know mad at and you know figure out like
why what sort of things we were saying
out this is important so we're going to
talk about triage a little bit here cool
I'm gonna go back and I did this on the
previous talk but I really want to
emphasize these graph portions so tic
again a good look at that chart doesn't
really make sense it seems to make sense
but it's not it usually how you
quantifies that you could do that better
by just say iOS really it just
summarized that maybe version 10 or nine
and that's the end of that so this is a
much better readable chart that you want
your consumers to have so do take some
time to be better charge they really
make everyone's life easy they explained
the situation fairly good and upper
management actually liked them so please
do take care of your matrix and data
let's talk about triage so we remember
we talked about goals right the first
goal was to be able to do scorable net
abilities and you know understand that
you know whether we're you know there is
something that we should take care of
but then now that you know there's a
vulnerability you want to triage
so let's talk about that so in order for
you to be able to triage you need to
know your software stack so do you have
Java yes
do you have any other package so the
more you know yourself for a stack the
better you get at triage and stuff so
you know CMDB software-related merger
them you know use that data you need to
know your environment and sometimes you
don't know your environment because it
might be too large or too small but also
because there's other teams that know it
better than you again rely on your teams
I'm gonna go back again to the CB
because I gotta be with that don't rely
on this core because is not everything
that you should care about context is
important so when you're doing triage
this core system should be useful but
not the main point of your triage so
another thing is you need to understand
the vulnerability data you need to
validate the findings so let's say that
now you know there's a vulnerability and
you decided to explore the vulnerability
you know you want to test it does it
work does it can I can it be exploited
all my systems you want to validate that
because the last thing you want is to
create work for teams and it turns out
that you know it doesn't work so very
important to do that
triage you have to work with people
again very important we're hammering on
the idea that you need to build a
partnership in a relationship with your
team members it is difficult to be in
security but it's also difficult because
we create these notion of we know you
don't know I know you don't know so
eliminate that work with people ask them
questions right most important thing
about this is light is that when in
doubt is not only ok to ask you should
and really adhere to that idea it's
always okay to ask and you should do
that now we have a set of tool sets you
do will manage man there will be a bunch
of tools so let's talk about one that is
extremely crucial which is your trusted
spreadsheet it might sound like it's
like how data or not but really you do a
lot of stuff on the spreadsheet use it
maximize it if you're good at Excel or
any other spreadsheet you can do a lot
of really crazy stuff in there do this
for whatever but you know use it and
write to it at some point you want to
move away from that and you want to
automate and do other things but for now
hey it's in there for you
when you dual management you obviously
get into these scanning and you know
tools that do that so you have to
understand how you're gonna do a
strategy so first one if you're gonna do
any tool like next post a novel or any
of those then what you want to do is you
want to have a discovery strategy you
want to first discover things on the
network because you know things are
fragile so be careful with your scans
right it started small and then use a
small simple port list you can use the
default list and then start expanding
add more ports and start growing you're
gonna figure out the things that break
the don't break it will be much better
do not start your vulnerability
management program running a tool and
then doing discovery scans with you know
vulnerability scans
you're gonna break things and it's not
gonna be looking good you're gonna have
to deal with the seeds of fallout so why
start small take it easy you know stages
iterations this is a bit of a joke but
you know sometimes you use in it and map
and sometimes you can I have to scan a
lot of stuff and hopefully you pray that
you know it will work and nothing breaks
so choose to that that was in Spanish so
I had to modify it a little bit so you
know more about you know scanning so you
have to make a decision that sometimes
do what can I do about 10 tickets can so
anyways do anyone know the difference
between authenticated and not
authenticated scans yeah so often the
key piece cancer those that require
credential so you can you know you know
log on as a user and then testimony
abilities that way sometimes you can't
so do you have to make a decision
you know there's Bali on doing both but
you have to by the way that and also
very very important thing is that if you
build an infrastructure for scanning or
vulnerability management secure it
because is very likely that that
environment is gonna have access to a
lot of different things in your
environment but that becomes a very
critical system that actors can use or
even pen testers or maybe you have a red
team so make sure that that environment
is secure because it can be misused so
very important to do that as well then
finally there's a lot of considerations
on your tooling right technology is
changing all the time and so you need to
find evaluate
that were for you there's a lot of them
out there so make sure that you test and
figure out if they work for you before
you introduce new tools make sure that
you meet the basic requirements so don't
don't go and get them you know the
latest tool because if you don't have
the basic requirements you're just
wasting time so work on the basics right
you CMDB your software stack and then
you know then find new tools that will
help you improve that this is also a
very important thing there is no one
tool fits all so you know the idea that
you buy this one tool and that's gonna
be everything like you doesn't exist
you need to complement tools to help you
get there so there is no one told them
we'll do everything and manage your
program for you it's a combination or
tools that allow you to have a better
program so if you just buy the latest as
kind of tool you should rethink about
that and then figure out how you
complement that with other tools
especially when there are plenty of open
source tools like the one we're gonna
share with you today and also you don't
need to repent the will so if you don't
have the money or you don't have the
resources or even if you do there's a
lot of tools out there so you know it's
cool that you want a code and you want
to do a lot of tools but why they're
already out there and they're actually
very nice and ready to go so this is the
last portion with others we talk about
internal intelligence and so when we
talk about internal internal
intelligence we referred to like how do
I collect a lot of data to help me with
my vulnerability management like maybe
my inventory isn't good but there's
other devices out there that can help me
well maybe you're using I don't know I
always query or maybe Windows service
updates the well you as us I forgot what
it stands for but so well there you go
when the service update services so if
you're using them they have data that
you can use for your vulnerability
management just mine diet data and then
you improve your visibility on your
asset so you know again tools that are
there tools that you probably use on
your network maximize them and with that
we're gonna introduce you to Man O'War
we're gonna then do a demo Chris is
gonna work on that explain about what it
is how we use it and hopefully we'll do
a really quick live demo braid it works
so let's go
so mental war is a tool we build to to
profile our servers to kind of do the
internal intelligence side and then also
to do the integrations with the external
external intelligence so the the number
one thing we wanted to do was we wanted
to pull down and boot two security
notices compare them against our
environment to see which which which
hosts we're vulnerable and which ones
weren't we open sourced a tool called an
internally jellyfish but there's another
Python jellyfish project so we renamed
it Man O War which is like it it's like
a jellyfish yeah yeah so like if you
were looking at the the theory graph
that we had earlier and realizing like
where does this tie in maybe a little
little box it kind of covers both like
external intelligence and internal and
external intelligence stuff it kind of
combines those two things into audit
results and then provides a UI and an
API to let you add both the the parsed
external intelligence and the the
profiles that we record and then you can
use it to do your triaging and start
your remediations and all that jazz so
that's kind of like weird where it's
supposed to fit in so we're gonna take
you through an example of triaging
we're gonna we're gonna start with the
upstream phone coming in we're gonna
show you how it profiles we're gonna run
an audit and we're going to take a look
at us and three seven six five - one
which is a curl vulnerability that came
out earlier this week then we're going
to show you who can do some unstructured
data investigation using our passive
profiles and then I'll be the end of the
demo so I'm gonna exit out of here I had
a video in case I broke everything but I
don't think I did so we'll see how it
works out
famous last words all right
[Music]
and if if you actually take a look at
the code there there are a bunch of
a-what apology they're a bunch of
references of the old name jellyfish
that I still haven't cleaned up yet so
you know if you're looking and you see
something called jellyfish it's probably
just because I haven't changed it yet
because I'm a little bit lazy as a human
being it's a personal personal flaw I
guess all right see what I mean
I could I could yes
so yeah starting up the setting up the
UI here the API all combined into one
makes a nice little gooey thing
available for you these are the this is
a sorry typing and talking so this is
the one that we're gonna we're going to
search on here and then you can see that
a booty puts out a new new security
notices pretty regularly so you know
we're actually looking at the RSS feed
for this and we're parsing it and that's
how we're building down there's stuff
there's a tool that does that that I
haven't got open sourced yet it's we
call it bass internally but essentially
it builds a little files that get a get
parsed okay parson to each individual
audit and I'll show you how it looks in
the UI cuz it's machine made here and so
it looks pretty bad but uh yeah it
essentially makes these little audits
that we can then and take a look at so
I'm gonna start by showing so we have I
have a bunch of LXE containers on my
host yeah I got four of them and then I
used Ezio host to kind of simulate a
production environment where there'd be
like DNS entries so I'm gonna I'm gonna
go ahead and use what I call schedule
schedule - it's a second version of a
big ssh type thing that I wrote in
Python
[Music]
so what its gonna do is it's gonna reach
out to to all the hosts in my thing it
doesn't multi-threaded so you could do
it a little faster there's also an agent
that will push data back to the API but
it doesn't it's it's not it's not
polished so if you want to use it you
should definitely make a pull request
and I will probably accept it but it it
doesn't go multi-threaded so that it
does work pretty fast yeah so you can
see it uh you know it has a bunch of
threads open effectively it's just what
I want to show by going there I put the
verbose mode on and it has some
interesting logging because it was
before I really got into using blogger
as a module and now we're kind of
kicking myself about it it's one of the
first projects that I worked on in
Python so if you look at especially the
early modules there's a lot of bad code
there so pull requests will be helpful
but yeah yeah so it's it's gonna run
through here and this takes a little bit
and there are some like wait and see
stuff but essentially it's going out to
each host and it's it's SS aging on
running a series of commands pulling the
data back parsing it and then storing it
in our database and this is the awkward
part
yeah this is Asia's although the hosts
in profiles that the profiles of hosts
by running a bunch of SSH curb runner
running a bunch of bash commands on
those bash commands would send the data
back in like a formatted manner and then
I then I imported into my database yeah
yeah it's effectively an authenticated
scan and so honest fairly nice way to do
and so there's there's an output at the
end and show you like what what failed
what didn't fail and then a you know
some other things I'm gonna show you how
it looks in in the actual host let's see
let's go to host church and I only have
five hosts defined so we'll take a test
box two here which is the first LXE
container and you can see that I've
pulled back a bunch of results here so I
have some graphs that give me an
automatically sometimes it makes sense
sometimes they don't in this case they
do so this is showing you like the the
collection types I pull back I have the
concept of type subtype and value so
each type is a thing so like here's
packages here's Ellis mods here's users
things like that and you can add custom
collections in there and then to keep
things kind of space-efficient on the
backend I record the first time I saw it
and the last time I saw it in the
database and I just keep updating that
record every time I see it again that
way I don't have to like store a new
entry every time and it cuts down on the
storage space pretty significantly it
kind of keeps like the amount of storage
you need per host relatively static
depending on like how long you keep
things after they've gone cut out a date
but you can use this to like look at
like what what's going on or like what
so like if you wanted to find like the
bash version it should've worked
ah that's because I spell fast wrong and
I put it in the wrong thing but yes like
you can see that there's a batch package
in the version that it's at and you
could do this with like users too so
like if you wanted to grab the users bag
and you want to find all the users that
you had the bash shell like you can find
out and others there's three on this box
that have the best show and so the yeah
it's part of its kind of like how the
collections look so now we're going to
run the the audits themselves so you can
you can write custom audits you don't
have to use like the the past tool the
right audits but you you essentially get
to decide to bucket things in the host
and then do particular comparisons
against those hosts the primary use case
there is like different versions of
Ubuntu or different versions of Red Hat
will have different like major version
packages installed and so you want to
like when they put the back ports on you
want to check against that back ported
version not necessarily against like the
upstream version or standardized version
across the thing sorry
[Music]
yeah and again just recap what we talked
about in the past we actually were able
to get a lot of intelligence really
quick right so we can ask you very
important questions like users and you
know all the things that are related to
exploit so this is an extra bottle that
we gathered yeah so right now it's going
through all these hosts and it's it's
it's checking them all right all these
audits and checking them against all the
hosts this is also multi-threaded so
that's fun times there a lot of you know
things it does it does it's gonna do its
thing and then I'm gonna run what it was
called the kool-aid I broke those out
because it's our environment there were
enough host we're trying to collate
while you're collect or where you're
analyzing didn't work well but really
it's just it's just summing up all the
values and sticking it in so that will
happen shortly afterwards but when you
look at it you can see that it's doing
inserts and updates its kind of using
that same storage model where if I see
an audit pass or fail and and I see it
again instead of storing each individual
audit pass or failure I can just you
know update and say I saw I saw it start
to fail here and start end to fail here
so you kind of get this idea of like how
long it was without an ax store
different values across for for
everything collate
[Music]
alright so the kool-aid ran so let's
let's show you some audits here so there
there is a dashboard that hasn't been
open source yet it was made by our UI
team who's like their wizards but it's
in a different repo and so we didn't
have time to go get it open source and
it looks much better than this page but
you know this page is what I have at the
moment 765 I believe yes so this is the
Chrome open it up and you can see like
historically what's what's gone down and
tomorrow it'll have a different graph so
and this is actually something I could
show to like last night the automated
upgrade ran on all my LXE containers and
actually upgraded all my curl versions
because I have an automatic security
note things turned on for these LXE
containers because you know why not and
so now they all pass which is great but
yeah so you can see that I've bucketed
things it based on their version this is
but when you get by default I guess I
should assume into that make it a little
easier to read yeah so I did
things based on like what version
they're on there's a collection in there
that tells you like the uses LSB release
- a to figure out like what what a blue
- version you're in and then I've
checked against the thing and I check
each of these to see if the version is
greater than this for this particular
package or this collection type and
subtype
combination which it which matches what
you see here in in the actual audit
itself like each one of these it's like
it essentially it's just parsing and
making you audit that makes sense for
that alright I think the next thing I
was going to show is like how did you
some of the investigation said it's like
you don't always want to work off and
Aude it sometimes you want to just you
know you get a question like hey what's
blah for that we have two different two
main types of searches collect like
collected values and collected sub types
then we also had like by pop and by surf
set pop you can thief like a data center
and then like surf type you can think
about it so like I have a workstation
reserved type that I added here which is
just this workstation I literally SSH
into my own workstation and added
the collection but you could look at
like how many audits it's passing and
failing or like how many hosts are in
that that particular particular sheriff
type you could sort them down and you
you know you could click in and click
cloud and things like that so like let's
say you wanted to find see what was the
example that I put in here
I will go packages bash again right cuz
everything's gonna bash package right
now so this would pull back like the
versions of bash that are seen in the
environment and then like what host
they're on so you could look at you know
like here's here's the Pops or data
centers or here's here's the SERP types
that are there all right here's the
values this one makes a lot more sense
when you have you know differing set of
values but you know you get the idea
same thing with like the subtypes one of
those the general one we show is like
users so like you could look for
shooters at user users will find out oh
it's but you could look at like users
and users fun times but yeah you could
pull back and so you can look at your
environment you can say alright so I've
got across my environment I've got apt
user on everything all five hosts but on
one host it's been false one host it's
bit/s been to login that's mainly
because my workstation was an upgrade so
it used to be been full so now it's has
been no logging but yeah you can so you
could be to pull back and you could take
a look at like all the things there so
like you could look at all the users
that have you know bashes their shell
and you can see that you know me and and
my root user are on everything and then
the sublimity user is just on my
forehead like see containers like so you
could start to pull back data about your
environment and because you can add your
own custom collections in here it's not
just limited to what you can do security
was you could also do investigations
about like your own custom versions of
packages or settings that you've set and
things like that that's that's kind of
the the full demo there um so you take
you take the the USN the Kroll and then
you you look at it and say alright and
you'd start to start to do your triaging
right you'd say do we use curl on our
thing look it's affected here what's the
impact of patching
you could really take it and start to
use this intelligence instead of having
to say well how bad does this affect us
sort of there are I should I should
point out some caveats there are a bunch
of slightly broken things because we we
kind of took it out of the environment
and second into an open-source one so
there's like a bunch of helper scripts
that aren't there anymore that I thought
I'd need to fix and it was designed with
the boon to only in mind not only but
like we took shortcuts to make it work
with the pen too so if you want to use
it on RedHat you'd have to do some
things or if you want to use it on a
Windows you'd have to do things and then
yeah dashboard hasn't been open source
yet and there's lots of references to
jellyfish that I should go grab and fix
and I think that's the demo so we'll go
back to you alright so again I'm just
gonna recap on what happened here so
this is a tool that was being built
chris is the mastermind of the tool and
the main goal is these tool does the
coiling tilton Decatur scans were SSH
into things and we're mining the data on
all the systems we're actually able to
do a lot better than authenticated scans
because we can do these on the man and
we can do it on the fly we save the data
so we are able to do really fast
reactions that ability comes in so the
other thing that is not very clear on
this example is that since we're
grabbing the US ends as they come in is
automated literally our USM comes in or
like just okay is there new u.s.n oh
okay so new bull net ability are we
impacted maybe maybe not so it's now
automated to the point that we can
concentrate on other important things
like remediation and mitigation so when
you work on mitigation and remediation
which are two different things you need
to interact with organization and so
sometimes you need to cut tickets and
you need to basically time go and fix
that so be mindful of the tickets that
you create organizations make sure that
you test you know if you're gonna
provide some remediation instructions
that they actually do work do not shame
people that is a very bad thing about
our culture in security we're not there
to Shane we're there to provide a
service our services to secure the the
assets in the company or the company
organization it work for shaming someone
for not doing something
it might work but it doesn't pay off in
the long run so a boy that use the
shaming when you really need it it's a
nice tool but you have to be careful and
be you know not knowledgeable to want to
use that the data that you have has to
be accurate it's very important so one
of the values of jellyfish is that since
we're able to collect and aggregate data
our value of data intelligence that
internal intelligence that we call is
super high so because of the value of
the data were able to make very fast
decisions another thing that it was in
here is the idea of cell service at some
point you want to kind of let teams do
their own thing and be like hey here's
this tool go and find out there's blue
net abilities you know you want to
remediate then you can go on cell
service and as you pass you will find
out if you're passing the alloted yes or
no and so that way they're keeping track
and they're making sure they're doing
you know the progress in on the
remediation you know there's another
important thing that there is a concept
of remediation and mitigation you know
what are your patching capabilities can
i patch
you know how fast can i deploy a patch
how accurate is that patch is that gonna
work or is there gonna break certain
things the other thing is you might not
be able to patch so like maybe you can
mitigate something so this is why
knowing your network is very important
you can put some ACLs in place maybe you
decide to limit the users I have access
to something so remediation mitigation
two different things but they were
fairly well together sometimes you need
to mitigate something stop that bleed
and then you work into how you're gonna
owe me a tit you need to think about the
idea and figure out the best way to
address that is very important in ball
management that you document your
decisions because things could go bad
and you want to make sure that you
document them they're right you need to
let your organization know hey we're
gonna make the decision you're okay with
that yes
all right cool it's now documented so
something goes wrong you can then say
hey we asked for advice and we wanted to
make sure that you were aware of these
things because things could go wrong
document your decisions make sure that
people know that you're doing those
things again the relationship between
you and organization is super important
pitfalls it's gonna happen so what you
gonna do when the day where things go
really really bad well our advice is
that's gonna happen and one of the eight
things are gonna go to hell first do not
panic
just chill pause for a moment don't
blame and shame again it's no one's
fault things just happen right and then
the most important thing when things
goes out is that you need to conduct
lessons learn
figure out what why things went wrong
how what can you do different if you
take these approaches you're gonna be
able to one improve your yourself you're
gonna build a better relationship with
your peers and three you're gonna
improve your program so again this is
advice that we experienced and we can
tell you this so take this with the same
girl
with a grain of salt but use this advice
it's gonna be valuable to you so now we
cannot talk about the vulnerability
management program that's gonna like and
standard program so then most programs
should aim and do and again we're gonna
repeat the two goals so understandable
and abilities triage them fast and then
work on remediation and mitigation but
we now know that there are other things
out there people are using the cloud
people are using new languages and so
forth so we have next-level ideas so you
got your your vulnerability management
program mature alright let's let's get
to improve that so why don't you
Masek Alize start making games out of
that why don't you create a scoreboard
where you track who is matching faster
or who is the one that is able to work
with you better and maybe give him some
swag who doesn't love swag well we got
some swag in here that we'll share with
you for those that ask questions so you
know that good example of why you want
to do stuff like that
another thing is work towards automation
so the the stuff that we show in here is
all the words that Chris did has been
possible because there's a lower cost
efficient automation so if you can
actually move towards that level you're
gonna be golden so make sure that your
program moves towards that direction
it's better that you can let us can run
come back and those you know the self
assessment for you and just click a few
buttons very useful so but again make
sure that if you're using orchestration
you want to secure your pipeline because
you know people use Jenkins and Jenkins
is very easy to exploit and people like
to exploit that so make sure that you
take care of that as well finally a very
good thing to have any organization is
bug bounty you want to get into the bug
bounty program be ready if you're not
mature you don't have some of the basics
do not even attempt to do that it will
be a waste of your time it will be a
waste of forever
you're gonna get plenty of data be ready
to be able to respond to those reports
be mindful the people that are doing
that partnered with any other known bug
bounty you know entities that are doing
that so it's a recommendation a very
valuable one we had this is lightning
here which is how not to make sure your
program success the sex of your program
is gonna be made sure by you and it's
different organization you're gonna
define that goal the way that we define
how we make sure our maturity on our
program was early on with the three
goals that we define and as you are able
to see we're able to be very mature in
that regard we're able to get
vulnerabilities extremely fast we're
able to triage fairly fast and we're
able to provide the service on how to
remediate immediate remediated mitigate
things so we feel very confident that
our program has reached a really nice
maturity level your program might be
different you need to understand your
goals and then your goals will define
how you're measuring your program
finally we're gonna have some takeaways
I'm gonna let Chris also keeps kissing
put in that so the most important thing
for me in here is that there is this
concept of odor loop which is you know
you repeat something so iterations on
your program are very important do
something
figure out what did why didn't work
improve it get better and just keep
repeating and then Chris it's surprising
how much better like you get at full
management when you just start to
iterate and you say oh we didn't we
didn't handle that vuln esses airily the
best but we're not gonna like go and
super focus on it and like have sixteen
continuous Sprint's of like we're gonna
fix this foam instead going and saying
all right well let's just go to the next
one because that one's just as bad
you do want to do I said it before but
you got a stick and move
yeah get a little Muhammad I'll be in
there and then always always make sure
to evaluate your data like if you're
working with junk data you're gonna get
junk results and you're gonna get you
know garbage in garbage out essentially
so so make sure that the data that
you're making decisions on actually
makes sense and it's actually useful for
your department yeah and with that we
get two conclusions we have a we have a
different jacket and this one there's a
bunch of tools that originally we want
to share with you there's a lot of open
source and they're broken down this time
you wouldn't take the picture of that so
what we have is now this cool she that
covered is a bunch of open source tools
that you can use we're gonna have the
link to talk in there as well you know
and so you have an opportunity to test a
bunch of the tools out there we tested
many of them we know that they work we
suggested them for you so is your turn
to investigate them and use them again
they're free and the tool we just
provided you to you is free so with that
any questions how easy could your system
be ported over to a Debian system
probably probably fairly simply the
biggest kind of a boon to specific
requirement we use we use the the apt
package like Python module and I think
boom to distributes that but I mean we
should be able to drop and replace some
other we use it for for process or for
parsing version data and there's there's
there's stuff in the standard library
that I could have used if I were more
intelligent
so like install Debian system
so like it you definitely get it going
fairly simply all that simply but like
with a small amount of elbow grease
so comedian or large I told you we're
gonna its left so
this is one of the things that everybody
into is when I'm continuing do you but
to eighteen point oh four stall there's
this little process so the insulation we
have like salt that we use at our
company for like handling like config
management type stuff it's like it's
like ansible or puppet and that's how we
handle kind of the config side for each
server like making sure the like the SSH
keys on each server and making sure that
like even though like the what we call
the jellyfish servers by themselves the
making sure that all the right jobs are
in the right place and all the right
code landed in the right places but I
have an open source like we have an open
source like are what we call bundler
like our packaging system so it would be
a lot of manual work at the moment oh
okay yeah
kind of painful if I'm trying to
research them like definitely see how
that that works what some awesome things
you do any like or ideas of what we can
do to make a better self remediation
security might have recommendations on
how to do it but there's a lot more not
security people to actually get the
things done um oh so the I guess the
question is what what sort of things
should you be doing next
oh yeah so what sort of things should
you be providing to your organization to
help them self or mediate essentially
the data that you're looking at it's
something that you should provide to
your work and you excuse me you might
want to like limit who has access to it
because it you know it kind of tells you
how you can attack your environment but
it for that for the people responsible
for administering your boxes handing
them data that says hey you're
vulnerable to X is very powerful to them
and AH and like they can go and they can
they can fix that themselves if if they
just know that they're vulnerable to
something and it helps them make make
the case to their management that they
should really be handling X like higher
up on their to-do list right maybe maybe
this gets in in front of some other you
know improvement or feature requests
because they know that hey it's security
has they see us they're like let's go
fix it before they get mad at us yeah I
would like to do that question that we
talked about garbage in garbage out
your quality of the data that you
provide to someone is really important
right so if you go to the nitty gritty
of hey this is the package you need to
fix this is the one that is bad this is
the one that you need to replace it with
and here's how you do it sometimes it
just is just super easy you want to get
like three bullet points on how to solve
the problem if you are able to do that
then you're basically the part where
everyone to do it and over time people
will realize that they can just make it
even simpler you tell them what to do
and they
they just follow but if you send them a
report like many people have done so
there's even pen testers do this they
have a report out of their tool and it's
not really meaningful right if you just
give them a report scan that says here
these are all the vulnerabilities like
who's gonna read that you'd have to make
it so it's like bullet points this is
one letter bill everyone this is how you
fix it
well number two is how you fix it that's
how you actually do things and use
polite things
[Music]
we reached a point actually at about
thirty thirty thousand dish shows twenty
thirty thousand hosts well we started
running into problems with with
performance on a fairly beefy single box
at that point you're gonna want to look
at like splitting out your collections
across multiple hosts we did have some
ideas about how we'd rewrite the Manowar
to be like more cloud native so I use
like RDS and API gateway and stuff like
that but we haven't built that type of
stuff yet but yeah there is definitely a
limit at which you have to start you
know splitting your work up into
multiple hosts and there's not
necessarily a lot of tooling to help you
do it so once you reach that point by
pull requests and I will accept them
I've never turned down a pull request so
I think we're running out of time so
we're out of time thank you for being
here one final note is that you can
actually carve a lot of queries so you
can use this phrase to response blue
teams so we got any questions where
we'll be out there thank you for being
here it's out in the morning and joy
shotgun