all right welcome everybody this is
where do I start the first 365 days of
building a security program with Hudson
Bush that soon as the seniors
information security architect at k2
Solutions Inc in Southern California
we're not home brewing' Hudson spends
his time assisting small and medium
businesses with securing their networks
please welcome Hudson del conte 2018
thank you having one second slight
technical difficulty that's better okay
so before the talk I was good I was
asked how deep do I plan on going this
talk is a mile wide and a few inches
deep there is there are a few points
where I really dive deep but the idea
here is that there are a lot of talks
that I feel like are either beginner or
advanced there's not a lot of the middle
there's not a lot of okay so now I've
actually started well what do I do in
the meantime before I become an expert
who can actually give my own talk and
this is this comes out of obviously this
is what I do I work with a I work with
mainly small businesses but companies up
to honestly about six seven thousand
seats but mostly with no security
posturing so an anti disclaimer this
talk does represent the views of my
employer everything that I say I more or
less run the cybersecurity division at
my employer so everything when I say you
can quote me on and a big focus of this
is how to prioritize I've seen too many
people who when they start this they
they have their priorities oh well I
heard someone say that the most
important thing is multi-factor
authentication so that's the very first
thing I'm gonna do that maybe it also
may not be so this is helping choose
your Intel sources figuring out who is
who are the good resources what things
to ultimately Google because you in 365
days in the first part there's going to
be a lot of research and it's it's how
to prioritize so I covered a little bit
of this this is scenario but it also
could
read my biases or my background i i'm
ainlina in businesses that are privately
owned i think that's important to say
privately-owned because i think there is
a special focus from apts and corporate
espionage on public companies that's not
to say that private companies are not
targeted they're just targeted in
different ways I work at an architect
and manager level but because I work
with a smaller team I do a lot of
engineer responsibilities so this has a
good mix between actually doing things
and documenting and planning most things
and then I have a strong preference for
open source but anything in here can
scale out of open source but the
technologies I'm going to talk about are
mostly open source same with the small
to medium business point anything here
can scale to a large enterprise the
companies I work force are mainly in the
military manufacturing room which means
that the compliance regulations that are
on them NIST 801 71 are mostly a joke
anyone who's worked with that realizes
that it's it's for example when it talks
about Paolo's password policy it says
implement a password policy and you
could literally say my password policy
is to have users change their password
every 300 you know is 300 years and one
character that's a password policy so
there's a lot of room to play around so
while I will talk about compliance
there's also I'm gonna talk about
choosing your own path because if you're
having to do PCI or NIST 853 there's
obviously you have to follow this
because otherwise you might lose your
business
as always management does expect some
sort of results in a year so that's why
these 365 days and then with few
exceptions the companies I work with are
all Windows endpoints and servers so
there's going to be obviously a huge
focus on Windows again certain things
will scale certain things won't in kind
of the scenarios that I envision here
are maybe you're an IT and suddenly
management for whatever reason because
they heard about the target breach or
Equifax or something they suddenly care
about security so hey
you're the only sysadmin you're
responsible for 300 users you're also
helpdesk
you you you manage everything but now
you have to get us secure enough to not
be breached we want you to tell us how
you're gonna do it in a year or maybe
you've previously worked at a level-one
saw Kemalists you've got brought into a
company that bait and switches you and
finally says oh by the way you're not
working in a stock you're only you're
the only guy in InfoSec so you're also
the manager you have to run all this so
then you ask yourself oh I have to
do what I've broken this up into four
phases the the boring stuff if you want
to sleep now is a good time planning and
discovery it is also the single most
important part and a little disclaimer
in this part I'm not I know that this is
typically in the manager level the
people who do the planning in the
discovery a lot of times you know
engineers if that's where you find
yourself you're a level one security
engineer you're an analyst you might
think oh this is management and I'm not
gatekeeping and saying that the only
people who can do this type of work our
managers but I am saying everyone who
does high-level security work needs to
understand what and why their security
and I feel like that's a gap too often
while there may be a few slides in this
that does not mean that every slide
needs to take three weeks some of these
slides could take a day you may just
talk to IT get your answers move on so
where I would start is pick a framework
you need to understand how you're
securing you need to understand you
don't want to just reinvent the wheel
and think I think this is important I'm
gonna do this i iso is is great for
certain things I work with a lot of
companies that use ISO four for QA so
they're already familiar with it it's
almost the nobody gets fired for buying
Cisco if you propose ISO management's
gonna like it but it does cost to get
certified it cost us to use so for a
small org maybe that's not where you
start one benefit that I have been
pitching to companies when we're working
with an a small app developer on this is
using cybersecurity
InfoSec as a sales point put the we are
ISO 27000 certified on your website
don't just retro actively say oh yeah we
didn't care about your security but we
got breached
you know we care now at the beginning
when you're getting customers train your
salespeople to say we this is how we
protect your data do this from the very
beginning and I think that getting a
certification as a company is a great a
great way to prove that instead of just
empty words we're unhackable this is the
closest you can really get to proving it
in an easy way without fluff words
there's a NIST CSF it's a lot stricter
than the CIS controls but what I would
recommend for most companies if you
don't have some sort of compliance need
start with your CIS controls there's a
lot more flexibility there's a lot
there's a lot more you can do in there
and since there's mappings from the CIS
controls to pretty much every other
framework it's an easy place to start
like I just said if you do need
compliance for you know regulatory
compliance that substitute for a
framework because your path has been
chosen for you you can still pick what
you prioritize what you do first because
obviously you're not going to check
every box in a year if you do then you
have a bigger team than I generally work
with and then use this as basis for the
system security plan essentially find
your framework find your compliance
needs and translate it into a way where
it for every control you can mark what
you're doing about it what your plan is
and I'm gonna talk gas analysis a little
later I know that a huge part of your
framework in SSP are is the gap analysis
and while while I'm not necessarily just
a CIS fanboy this talk does ultimately
go through through eight of the CIS
controls it goes through one through six
and then 17 through 19 and I want to
pause for a second all of my my notes
and my slides will be online I'll have a
link to that at the end so if that helps
you taking your notes good
and I backing up for one second if you
do have questions at any point you can
me or tweet to the hashtag I will be
monitoring that so easy way to ask
questions so you don't forget them at
the end resource assessment I put I put
this here do I start buying things now
I'm I know I'm probably preaching the
choir here but I'm gonna say it anyways
I have seen environments where let's buy
everything let's buy a sim let's buy a
new next-gen antivirus let's buy DLP
let's buy a finless buy everything at
the same time but we have no resources
no plan to implement them and then
suddenly three years later you've been
paying the licenses and none of these
tools do anything um
so spoiler alert you do not start buying
things now it's gonna be much later
there's a lot you can do with the tools
you already have but the the knee-jerk
reaction is oh I heard that Splunk is
awesome I'm gonna buy it or I heard that
you know silence is awesome or something
there's gonna be some exceptions to this
that I'll talk about when you buy things
but right now I want to talk about how
you assess your resources and what you
have so to start you need to understand
your financial resources another spoiler
alert chances are you're gonna ask for
the InfoSec budget that's not gonna
exist then you're gonna ask for the IT
budget and if it exists there's gonna be
nothing for security because chances are
when you ask for what security spending
has been done management is gonna say
well we think that antivirus and
firewall is security so we just want you
to mail those two things down because
that's all you need for security I've
seen that over and over again so chances
are less what you're gonna see when you
ask for your budget so that probably
means you're not spending any extra
money this year what do we do with that
well that's that's a huge part of this
talk that's also why I have a strong
preference for open source again that a
second IT infrastructure you may want to
implement elq
you may want to implement something that
requires terabytes of data you may not
have that understand what sort of
resources that you can dedicate to the
tools that you want technical resources
if it's just you in InfoSec if there's
maybe a sysadmin figure out who you can
who you can borrow what what people are
interested in hacking what people are
interested in these things that you can
talk to their managers figure out maybe
I can use these people a little bit here
and there this all goes into
organizational OSINT
figuring out what resources what what
all is there and then which probably go
at the beginning is meet and greet you
need to meet department heads you need
to start figuring out what their pain
points are and what it is well and
honestly the disturbance that you can
give to their resources because
ultimately most people are going to view
security in any of the controls that you
implement is hindering what it is that
they're doing so start making friends at
the beginning before ultimately you
start breaking the systems that they've
the very insecure systems that they've
used for 10-15 years start to make
friends before they're your enemy sorry
about that
and I put OSINT in here open source
information open source intelligence
that could really be added into every
slide everything in here you you're
going to need to go on and ask people
because chances are the documentation
sucks if I sound like a pessimist or
nihilist I've in you're not we might
work in different industries I don't
know the this is another boring part
this falls into the meet and greets but
understand your business objectives if
you're if you're a numbers guy if you
enjoy doing risk assessment that's very
important you may have a legal officer
who can help you with this but it comes
down to figuring out if this if this
system is down for this long how much
money do we lose do we have those
numbers maybe availability isn't
important at all because maybe you know
we don't have those those firm of
deadlines I worked with the company they
said everything could be down for three
days and all we would lose is some
that's your you're probably never gonna
find that that was that was weird but
and that ya know it is and it was a
manufacturing company but I don't know
the way that they worked they said
everything can be down for three days
and we wouldn't lose a penny you're
never gonna see that now the thing is
because you don't have a large team
because you you can't dedicate months to
these things and these are month-long
tasks or three month or year-long tasks
chances are you're going to have to stop
these short of what is what you'd
probably want to but it really comes
down to and I'm gonna reiterate this is
understanding what you have to secure
and what you're securing against and
what's the risk if you don't secure it
business impact assessment is exactly
what I was talking about with the risk
assessment just a little bit of a
different spin on it and then evaluate
disaster recovery capabilities if you
ask IT they're gonna say oh we backup
every hour we backup every day we backup
whatever we can recover at this time
they they have not done a dr simulation
do that force them to do that whatever
chances are you will find that the only
that they're their backups are failing
every few days because they don't have
enough space so your are your recovery
point objective is down your RTOS are
down because chances are they've never
recovered it so they realize that it
actually takes a week to restore because
they're using backup exec from tapes
something of that sort and then I've had
where the the boot sector is corrupted
on every wit aperture don't ever use it
del ruins everything they buy we could
talk about that later if you disagree
I'll win that argument well the then
you're the last one that no one really
talks about with disaster recovery is
work recovery time just because you got
the system up because you know it ran
and it may be a random five minutes if
you're using a good dr system but if it
didn't then you just spent a you just
spent fifteen minutes every pc for 100 i
mean if every server for 100 servers
twenty servers whatever it is fixing the
boot sector you know doing something of
that sort you have to figure that out
and do this again and again and again
until you actually know what it would
take a big
part of data of business objectives is
your data classification like I said
understand what you're securing if
you're a manufacturer maybe it's part
numbers you figure out that a part
number is you you know has a certain
pattern you search for that pattern
maybe it's anything that has eight on it
if you if you do shipping and exporting
to for military things you can look for
credit-card strings but data
classifications figure out where your
data is chances are no one has no one
knows department by Department I have
been surprised certain times you talk to
a manager and they can tell you this is
exactly where it is and then start
securing it then metadata tags or
changing in the you know putting
watermarks things like that are good for
keeping your data classified but I'm
gonna get into the the policies of that
in a moment also very important in the
Dr simulation is documenting it because
maybe the entire team that you use to do
your dr simulation half of them are gone
or they've forgotten because i've done a
hundred other tasks since then so
document what worked what didn't what
weird tricks you had to do it really
comes in handy a recovery time objective
recovery point objective and work
recovery time i tried to expand on most
things that slide would have been a
little too long if i did that and they
were somewhat minor points gone is the
point to which the business needs to
recover so let's say that they need they
want to recover every hour but then from
the actual disaster recovery in the
backup side of it is how often we have a
backup that we can recover to then
recovery time objective is how quickly
we need to have this recovery done in
and then into that recovery time
objective the work recovery time the
time it takes to actually be the
technician resource that it takes to get
that system up after the system has
actually done its restore i probably
explain that somewhat poorly because it
is not the primary thing i do but
this is a bit untraditional at this
point evaluate user education I'm gonna
do it even before I get into threat
modeling and the reason is another
spoiler alert you are going to find out
that your users are your biggest threat
you're gonna find out that that is your
biggest gap no matter what you do your
your users are going to find a way to
get around it so phishing simulation
sans securing the human free tools great
they also have some paid stuff but fish
me has a has a free tier they have a
paid tier very good no before it's
pretty much the industry leader that I
from from what I see say what you will
about kevin Mitnick that is not the the
topic here but no before is a is is a
good tool a caveat with no before and
this is a nun an unsubstantiated story
that I that I overheard at besides Vegas
this year but I'm gonna repeat it
because it rains true or it appears to
be true if you've worked with no before
any of these phishing simulations you
know that there are templates that you
can use so her story of an organization
that checked every single check box send
all emails then you know randomized it
so the CFO gets an email saying you have
been accused of sexual assault click on
this link to see the to see he does not
click the link he runs screaming into
the HR department what the hell I did
not do this who ever said it you need to
tell me right now the HR department
knows nothing about it so it's a
screaming match for a while now the
company is no longer allowed to use any
fishing simulation because they think
that that's what fishing simulation is
know that is being an idiot that is not
that is not testing your tools test
every single tool before you implement
it don't just you wouldn't install an
IDs on every single or an IPS on every
single box and then start blocking all
of your traffic no you wouldn't you
wouldn't you know blindly enable every
single firewall rule test test
everything like you would test anything
okay surveys and quizzes stay safe
online has
some really good ones these are a good
way to figure out your users other
knowledge and then what I would do from
this point once you've gathered this
information do target a user training a
formal user awareness training could
take months to evaluate but if you find
out in an organization of a hundred
people that you have five people that
you know click on every single thing you
send to them and never forward to IT sit
them down for a day and explain things
then test them again and again and
figure out you know there those are your
biggest risks so focus on them and like
I said this is really untraditional
people this is usually step 100 because
no one wants to talk to users no one
wants to do this stuff if you don't want
to actually do the training for for
someone else to monitor the training and
force them to go through some classes if
you're if you're not a public speaker
but I think this is your number one
benefit we have an organization that has
been fish that we work with that has
been fished three times in the last year
one time they were minutes away from
sending $60,000 to the wrong company
okay so they bring in they they bring in
a manager of InfoSec to to replace us
long story there but I tell him that the
number one thing you need to do is user
awareness training he says yeah that
that's in my plan we're about six months
away from that and it's gonna be this
long thing and I'm like no no no right
now you need to do fishing simulation
he's like yeah I'm like no no no you
don't understand you are going to keep
they they have compliance needs and they
have they have had customer information
breached and two of the occasions that
that that that's completely intolerable
but they're they because however he
wants to do things he's not willing to
put the user training at that moment I'm
gonna tell another very interesting
story about that same person in a bit
but and and then you'll you'll see I
said planning and discovery here but
then I've already implemented a
remediation into this phase I I done
that intentionally I think that if all
you did for your first six months or
even six weeks even six days was
documentation
you're losing opportunities so I think
mixing some of these things up and
figuring out what's most important and
doing it earlier than I prescribed is is
great this may be a point you if the
targeted you if you don't think targeted
user training is enough that you may
really think about MFA because that is a
while it is not a silver bullet it will
help a lot of things here this may be a
point where you consider MFA I generally
like to put MFA much later because it is
one of the most time intensive things to
implement correctly and I again I can
get into that later back to
understanding what it is that you need
to secure you need to understand what
hardware and software you have there are
a lot of tools for this any helpdesk
system that you have if you have
SolarWinds helpdesk it does automatic
scans if you don't have anything
automated for this using nmap um then
map cookbook is a great resource you can
get a lot of this information a VA s
system talk about that a little later
can will give you a lot of this it is
not meant as an asset discovery tool but
it can be a poor-man's asset discovery
tool also Active Directory is is great
because you will figure out a lot of
what's in there you will probably cringe
at certain things that shouldn't be in
there but it is not enough unless you
cross-check it because there there may
be you you may discover that you have
50% of your your endpoints aren't even
in Active Directory I am working on a
PowerShell tool that will eventually be
on github that does a an IP scan of your
entire range and then checks if anything
is in Active Directory because that is a
huge pain point for me so follow me on
Twitter if you want to see that
eventually and then Mike and Microsoft
baseline configuration and our analyzer
a lot of the same things a little more
information and a little more resources
I would say none of none of these except
for Active Directory PowerShell scams
should you run just blindly in the
middle of the day sir certain VA s scans
you know if you use open bas you do full
and fast ultimate that can brick your
system don't don't DDoS yourself
and then this is a you know a good play
something that I didn't include because
again I'm a pessimist I didn't include
OSINT in this piece I did not say go ask
IT because in my experience one or two
of the many organizations that work with
actually have proper asset lists so you
you could you should still ask but
chances are you it won't be fruitful
so threat modeling um this could be an
entire talk and ultimately this is what
drove me to give this talk is know what
you're protecting what you're protecting
against the same story I was just
telling well phishing the the gentleman
when he came in and I use gentleman
loosely he was obsessed with encryption
and yes encryption is great but he was
not talking about disk system encryption
he was not talking about in Kranz
encryption he was talking about
encrypting hard drives no certain threat
models that might be very important to
encrypt hard drives the problem is you
could not social engineer yourself into
this building you cannot get it is
almost impossible to get in this
building I've cried I've tried I've
tried other people it you can not social
engineer your way and there's only one
entry way they do not allow tailgating
so physical security isn't is much of a
risk they also don't have any laptops so
no one can get into the building to
steal a hard drive which is technically
the use case you're protecting against
but he's really worried about this but
what he's not worried about is the fact
that they do not close or lock the
server room door ever to me the number
one thing that you would do to protect
against stealing someone stealing your
server hard drive is lock the damn door
or close it but the reason that they
don't lock the door is because two
reasons one the thermostat is on the
wrong side of the wall the thermostat is
on is where the the sysadmin the sits so
he leaves that door open now he's also
he's the
to be the facilities manager so he would
be the one that would be able to move
this but okay fine so just lock the door
into his office no he leaves it open so
that the so that the cleaning crew can
come in and take out the trash at night
so very easy mitigation here now what I
wish I had said to him was why are you
so concerned about physical security
that wasn't in my threat model I could
have been sarcastic I dropped it because
he wasn't having anything and I'm not
going to waste my time on a fruitless
conversation but he he was protecting in
something because maybe that's the first
thing he implemented or maybe he thinks
it's so easy um
it's not necessarily hard drive
encryption well it can't be easy you can
just deploy BitLocker by GP if there's
any key mismanagement all of a sudden
you lose a bunch of hard drives and your
system in now has to resolve issues with
25% of your pcs because they can't get
to any data because they don't have the
encryption key again smaller use case
but it is possible so know what you're
protecting know what you're protecting
against Intel sources for this you could
use you you could use common and common
sense potentially you could say maybe
I'm a private company so I might have
certain attacks this is that but they
this is a good point to start asking
questions look at the the youth us-cert
will give you a there is a website on us
site a database on us cert where you can
look up previous data breaches and you
can say you know in this industry this
sighs blah blah blah
you can set parameters so find similar
companies how they've been breached
protect against that go to CIS so around
people's find people in your industry
because chances are if you're the only
an IT person uni or the only you know
InfoSec person you aren't getting good
information so go get as much
information as you can find out ask
other people what what it is you know
that they've found what do you need to
protect against and then look in your
own network see what attacks they've
there have been if they have kept
incident reports look at that see maybe
they've been fished six times in the
last year protect against that first
so um and then I place this after
information-gathering steps because you
need to understand what it is you have
before you can even know what it is
you're protecting so and then gap
analysis use the framework that you have
does not need to be with an auditor at
this point unless you're using ISO but
do do a gap analysis look at all your
steps look at all the compliance needs
figure out where you are and use this as
a and use all the information up to this
point for a plan or POA M I hate the
acronym I don't know why you put an and
in there but it's government acronyms so
they do weird things
a P om is plan of action and milestones
so project plan is a good thing to do at
this point so you know what what are
your doing things in also quick point
pen test is not a gap analysis everyone
people very often here pen test red team
they want to do this at this point your
gap analysis will tell you as much or
more than a red team will you're not
ready for a red team they can get in
anyone can get in they you know they
could look you up on LinkedIn and get in
just what the information off of
LinkedIn chances are so do not waste
your time or money on a pen test at this
point if anything if you're gonna waste
the time bring in a proper auditor to
come in and tell you your gaps but just
don't waste the money this is this is a
self-help thing this is me preaching to
myself rest someone said this to me
recently I don't know where it came from
but I like exhaustion is what our
culture abuses courage know being
exhausted is not bravery it is it is not
what we need to do now chance there will
be times that you're going to be
exhausted because you have a huge tasks
against you ahead of you but one tip
let's say that you have a framework you
want to be 25-30 percent against that
framework reduce whatever that is by 25%
if you want to remediate 60 control
go down to 40 controls set your goals a
little lower so if you pass them
everyone looks good but you also don't
have to at the last minute work on
remediating a bunch of things in writing
a bunch of documents try not to take
work home it's not always possible but
but try and then take your vacation time
if you have it also try and negotiate
for vacation for a reasonable amount of
vacation time now at the end of this
space talk with management
I recommend that every three to four
months every quarter let's say you meet
with management now you won't always be
able to but getting your cause getting
security in front of them is very
important they need to know what it is
that you're doing what it is that you're
securing what threats are out there give
them news in this now avoid fun fear
uncertainty in doubt I am NOT a fan of
it
don't just say all Russia is gonna
attack you chances are it if there's you
know the chances are they're not
directly targeted Russia has enough
targets if you if you're not working for
a big firm in my experience not as big
of a target present the findings you
have to this point you know all the
documentation that you have is ready do
that discuss potential costs at this
point you might know what sort of
resource issues you have maybe talk
about bringing in MSSP I know that it's
somewhat of a bad word I work for what
might be classified as an MS sp I don't
think it has to be a bad word but and
for who doesn't know whoever doesn't
know that acronym that's managed
security solutions provider essentially
an IT provider the posted focuses on
security so this would be a point to say
hey you know that I have this this and
that that I think I need to buy this use
this to increase buy-in and then again
talk about what I've what I mentioned
earlier with ISO as a potential security
is a sales tactic so now I know the some
very similar to the information
gathering but its analysis and
documentation this is where you put your
plan a step farther you start gaining
level two information you don't just
have this is what I think you really
dive into the network and start figuring
things out so know
you don't start buying things now either
you can if you don't want to use open
source that is fine you don't have to I
know the resource you know you may not
have the resources to work on open
source but open VA s is open VA s is not
as difficult as you think to implement
in my experience it can take about 20
minutes if you have a good system it
doesn't take a lot of resources if you
have the ability to implement elk elk
that's the elastic stack for as a sim or
maybe even not as a sim yet
vulnera spur is great for open VA s it
will you don't have to use it with open
BS it actually has missus and Qualis
plugins as well but it's a great way to
visualize and then I I put this before
patching because that's one gonna be one
of the number one ways that you reduce
your vulnerabilities so by by doing this
before patching you can show a pretty
chart and say we have reduced our
vulnerabilities by 30% or hopefully much
more show that to your show that to
management and it'll be a shiny report
generate differential reports exactly
what I was just saying and then showed
an lookup for external ports hopefully
you're able to see your external ports
former firewall rules maybe you'll find
something else on show then patchy just
talked about this um I should probably
go without saying but don't don't
automatically deploy patches to your
servers that's probably not a great idea
maybe you have them set to install you
know on Friday something of that sort
and then you check them the next day but
I really I do them manually but you can
do them automated for endpoints that's a
little less of a pain point in my
experience you can also if you're using
WCS you can release passes patches
slowly to certain groups so that you
reduce especially if you're just now in
implementing wsus and you have 260
patches per machine that does happen
then maybe we release them slowly try
and gather a team of
who can help with server patching wsus
while it is the easy choice it can be
really high maintenance there are great
resources to get wsus working but maybe
you use another tool come if you don't
want to work with an MS SP komodo
actually has a tool you you have to sign
up as an MS SP but it's free and they
you can if you deploy it to all your PCs
all your servers you can patch them
there I know Komodo doesn't have the
best rep but trust me it's good like I
said every MSP and MSSP will have
patching software that could be a
security risk as well because then that
comes with an AR mmm most the time and
then suddenly maybe a hundred people who
work for them have a backdoor into your
system you need to figure that out but
and reiterating when I said in the last
slide this is placed right after
vulnerability assessments you can
document your results I'm not going to
spend too much time on this because I
talked about it a bit but widespread
user education this is when you start
not just doing your targeted this would
be a great time to actually deploy
widespread user education so stay safe
online I've already talked about Sam
security human has a lot of free
resources they can also send teams now
this also security policies are huge
acceptable uses you're number one to
knock out that's what every user has to
sign accept excessive acceptable use of
you know IT resources but there's
probably 3040 policies you'll need by
the end of it sans has some great ones
but they're in my experience there's a
little more customization that you need
to do Charles Creston has ones I think
they're about 1,500 bucks those are
really good and though that's on
security shield if you aren't
comfortable customizing security
policies you're not a writer work with
legal HR have someone else kind of
outsource this if you can now I mean at
this point hopefully you haven't had to
do any Incident Response you may have if
you work within the organs that I worked
with
but use this time to start figuring out
your policies and procedures maybe maybe
do a tabletop exercise start figuring
out with your threat model what do you
think you might need to protect against
important is to work with legal HR PR
everyone to figure out when do we report
to when do we report to law enforcement
I know that nobody wants to do it but
sometimes the compliance needs you have
to a side note there is that you have
ransomware there is a very very good
chance that the FBI already has the
decryption key I know you don't want to
call them but they don't actually have
to mandated report this and the FBI will
help you decrypt I know it's not a fun
call to make but it is it is something
to have there and like I said like I've
said many times compliance requirements
will kind of force your hand in breach
reporting but maybe have some canned
letters things like that establish a
cert team computer emergency response
team where the t's redundant but you
know try and involve people from legal
HR maybe even different departments you
know PR marketing management obviously
InfoSec and then IT this is a bit early
to do this like I said but nothing will
tarnish the image of your department
like poor Incident Response change
management can go through this fairly
quick because I mean ultimately it's
logging what you do and chances are
there's two of you
there's IT and then you it's not
necessarily your job IT or management
should have already mandated this but it
will be if change management doesn't
happen if weird changes start happening
even track changes that you don't think
required approvals restarting the backup
server in the middle of day track it
easiest way is Excel it's harder to do
approvals that way but you know don't
over engineer Internet or SharePoint is
great don't just create a SharePoint for
it because then your SharePoint admin
but if someone's doing SharePoint log on
you know tack on to that if you're
already using G suite use Google Form
that's easy and then if you have a
helpdesk system chances are you could
just create a change change control
a change control tab in there as one of
your incident types now that we're we're
ending this face talk with management at
this point you've already partially
implemented a number of controls without
doing much not all the sub controls but
that is a wind show them what you've
checked off incorporate some training
talk to them about a few more high-level
things that you have so far
get some feedback on the user pain
because management's gonna know they're
gonna have heard complaints and you
don't want you know you you want to
hedge that before you can review the
security policies if you've written them
yet and then get and get approval on
them so you can start implementing the
security policies you've written now
we're gonna jump into what I think
everyone wants to be the fun part
mitigation and remediation you start
actually doing the real implementation
do I start buying things now maybe this
actually may be the time that you do it
but chances are like I've said you don't
have a budget
so first mitigation at least privilege
if you have Active Directory that means
Active Directory delegation with file
servers same thing with you know use
PowerShell to get all of your Ackles so
the discovery use like I said use
PowerShell figure out who has what
resources who's a domain admin whose
enterprise admin schema admins things
that you may not check talk to people
figure out if they're supposed to be
there who yeah who can approve you
removing them maybe you can just do it
and then bloodhound is a tool you can
find on github that is really good for a
numerating complex ad relationships an
ad is Active Directory I'd assume anyone
who's in here knows Active Directory but
if not props for sitting around so long
proc Mon process monitor manage process
monitor is great for removing local
admin you you can you there there are
plenty of articles out there on how to
do this but you can see what it is when
you have gotten rid of local
administrator privileges what it is that
breaks on
whatever application they're using s AP
they're using solid work whatever breaks
you can see it in process man monitor
what it is that it's trying to access
and then give the proper permissions and
then you know reproduce that on multiple
pcs or automate it by group policy and
I've already kind of talked about the
reduction of privileged ad accounts it's
good I am again a little to my empty
github a little bit of a shout out I am
working on finalizing some scripts that
I use for creating a essentially a
golden image for a delegated
organizational unit structure with the
proper permissions it's just not pretty
enough to to show yet so easy wins each
of these could have their own slide but
that's really not my focus here so
firewall rule closures you could fairly
easily determine that port 53 from your
exchange server does not need to be open
to the internet never does guarantee it
certain things you may be able to close
you can test these on the weekend okay
and but I mean while I say easy win that
doesn't I don't mean any disrespect it
may not be easy but the these these are
things that can really help you secure
with a small potentially small impact
session lockout you know so that your
pcs don't just stay open for forever
actually you know 5 10 15 30 minutes
have your pcs actually lock a pre logon
advisory doesn't really make anything
more secure makes management a little
happy because it's visible by logging
into the system you agree to company A's
security policies and you've signed the
acceptable use policy that legal will be
happy with you let's do it this is as I
talked about encryption it might be hard
for you to push encryption all pcs but
added into your PC build list maybe you
know add a few other security things but
that's a big one
just enable BitLocker when you build
every new PC it's already there
cool account auditing I talked about
this a little in the last slide but
chances are from
I've seen you have a bunch of computers
that or a bunch of users that haven't
changed their password in three four
years force password changes maybe
incrementally so that everyone doesn't
come in and they can't get in their
email tomorrow but you can do it by
basically by last logon Active Directory
you can just filter by last logon date
and greater than 90 days and then work
with HR to figure out if those users
should actually have access replacement
in renewals this is the first slide
where I talk about potentially buying
something chances are you have licenses
that you need to pay for so this is a
good chance to increase security with
easy wins if you are already paying if
you already have to pay it it's not all
it's not necessarily that much more for
next-gen antivirus mjv but but you know
something like silence can greatly
increase your security posture can
protect you against zero days not again
nothing I'm saying is a silver bullet
but it does a lot more than typical AV
with out much more money
someone from silence called it poor
man's app whitelisting you can just you
can you can block TeamViewer with a
click of a button you can also restrict
any changes from being maintaining
applications on the PC with a click of a
button so app Locker is not that
difficult but this is actually easier
you can do removable media removable
media control pretty easily you can
restrict by you can restrict any new
ones you can own you can whitelist you
know only certain serial numbers or
vendors or something of that sort but
next-gen antivirus silence I said I
wouldn't talk too much about you know
commercial tools but silence could be a
huge win Network refresh there's a very
good chance that you have a network with
all layer 2 switches and maybe even you
have an old cisco a si that is
throttling you at 10 Meg and you're
paying for 300 Meg and everyone's
wondering why it's slow
if that's painful then you've you've
you've experienced this network refresh
you know maybe you have the money you
see you're still paying licensing maybe
it's not that much more expensive to
replace with four than that Palo Alto I
would recommend for Dan that you can
fight me later and then access points
with radius I every place that I've gone
I have tried to put in Wireless last but
Wireless always into being one of the
first things because I see a bunch of
commercial home access points can't even
call them access points a bunch little
dumb net gears that are terrible and
Groff connections all the time and
Wireless ends up being a huge pain point
from a usability perspective so when we
come in and replace them and replace
them with something that will do radius
so that you can authenticate against
Active Directory and please don't be
using WEP even though that is pretty
widespread here's some maybes there's
very good chance you're gonna do none of
this but consider it change service
counts and admin passwords this should
be one of the number one things you do
because you know you may have all
lowercase no numbers for all of your
service accounts and for all your
firewalls but it could be very
time-consuming you can break a lot you
may not have enough information this is
the number one thing you could do but I
understand if you move it to later
principle release functionality and
hardening block ports that aren't needed
uninstall apps that are needed hard to
do good sim Elk spunk spunk expensive
elk is great but probably hard to do
ids/ips network based or host based you
can do it with brows something of that
sort
but also maybe not immediately and then
laps local admin password solutions so
that you're not manually managing
passwords on every end point it's pretty
easy to implement for Windows you'll
notice I don't have DLP fin web
application firewall or web filter those
aren't in my threat model you could put
them in and these aren't in any order of
priority your third and probably least
eventful
talk with management but reiterate that
just because no money has been spent or
little money has been spent that's not
the expectation going forward there will
be costs associated with InfoSec let
them know that because at this point
they've gotten used to 3/4 of you not
spending any money that's not that
that's not going to be the case going
forward or release you hope so and then
get their input on the potential budget
because you're reaching the end of the
year it's budget season so figure out
how much money what their priorities may
be and then talk to them and even think
yourself if you want to use an MSSP for
a sock because there are some huge
benefits with that there are also some
negatives but outside of the scope here
so I'm gonna looking forward this is
gonna be kind of prioritizing your
budget
so maybe redistribute your survey from
the beginning where you start seeing
your user if your user awareness has
improved start ask them questions like
their perceived the the perceived
improvements that they've gotten maybe
they've gotten less spam because you've
tweet spam filter rules measure their
user pain maybe they're really pissed
off because now they can't access it
file the way they used to or they really
loved RDP from home and now they have to
use VPN figure out what and figure out
how you can kind of you know massage
their back a little bit um allow
suggestions give them a suggestion field
you probably don't want to read it
because it might not be great but yeah
and then use your own self-assessment
figure you know think about what you can
do look at your differential reports
there's been a lot of reports I've
talked about so far perform another gap
analysis vulnerability scan where you
distribute the survey ok and then now
that you've gathered information prepare
your budget set your priorities based on
the findings in that last slide
reevaluate your threat model do you
think that next year do you think that
the threat model that you establish at
the beginning is still true have you
seen things that you didn't know about
at the beginning do you have certain
risks that you weren't aware of you
found some you know some data somewhere
that's really important and no one told
you about it you might have to kind of
change your priorities
for the suggestions next year like I
said MFA is very important I think a sim
could be very important think about it
network overhaul like I talked about
before and all the suggestions from
renewals and replacements those are good
wins those are great things to put in
there so now you're gonna talk with
management this is fairly
straightforward because you're gonna
present the budget
you're gonna reiterate InfoSec as a
potential profit center I know anyone in
accounting will kill me for this but
Infosys that can be a profit Center if
you prove that it's not just costing
money that it is saving money and maybe
even bringing in money by people
realizing that you care about their
security it can become a profit Center
it takes a ton of work but it can and
ultimately management will love you
accounting will argue that it can never
be a profit Center but it can at least
in it can at least in semantics be a
profit Center present your compliance
improvement goals for the next year
again I would I would probably bring
them down by 25% because you want to
under under commit and over over do my
brain set off for a second thank you
over-deliver thank you
under commit and over-deliver present
your differential reports and then maybe
at this point used a little bit more of
some advanced training talk to them
about what MFA is what some of the
things you're doing maybe your
management doesn't care maybe they do
I've seen a good mix so in conclusion
the TLDR
too long didn't read i actually was very
surprised recently to find out that a
surprising amount of people did not know
what TLDR was I spend more time on
reddit than those people so this is
essentially if you've been asleep for
the last 40 minutes this is what I've
talked about set your priorities based
on your business objectives threat model
everything threat model all the things
discover everything know what you're
securing educate the users backup
everything because ransomware and then I
would say open source all the things you
may not so don't necessarily open source
all the things like I have said
oh and then by all the things eventually
don't do it this year don't spend a
bunch of money and then just have a
bunch of system sitting around yeah no I
can tell too many stories on that so if
I actually have it on my Twitter handle
so if you if you follow me or just check
me out on Twitter you can see the link
to my website with the talks if you have
questions I'm not gonna have time for
questions right now but if you find me
after or tweet them to me I will answer
but yeah thanks for being a great
audience thanks for listening
[Applause]