[Music]
yes so first of all I want to give food
crops to Alec by the way so if you've
never looked into Alex's work I know he
spoke at quite a good detail but um like
it that is some of the most important
work being done in the community to
bring testability into what we're
accomplishing is there's so few people
if not maybe one of the only ones doing
it so I just really want to emphasize
how important that work is into the
future of what we're doing because most
of us like me fly by the seat of our
pants and if you think I've got it
figured out then you have a lot to learn
because I just make it up as I go just
like this presentation so the the thing
I want you to understand is that when I
joined Microsoft my mother said I
thought you hated them because probably
like everybody else in this room if
you're an InfoSec professional you know
you probably have a very very bad taste
in your mouth from many decades of some
very challenging events but I I want to
say that I walked into the company
three-and-a-half years ago no longer
with them they were very kind enough to
let me continue to give this
presentation one because I think it's
really important that this community at
least see the inner workings of
something like this and this is the
first and only time publicly this
presentation is going to be given but
that of how amazing the company is
actually and and I want to give you a
little bit of an insight on how this
works because unlike many places in the
world including inside DoD there's very
few places in the world where you can
literally change the world in InfoSec
because you know Microsoft has over a
billion customers and it I like you know
my my former general manager John
Lambert says Microsoft controls the
physics of the problem on most computers
in the world bad guys cannot do anything
except what Microsoft products allowed
them to do and so it's really powerful
to be in a company and literally change
the physics of InfoSec and it's
absolutely
the astounding and so I'll show you a
little bit of what that means so I
walked into Microsoft and and they're
like oh well so we're going to do this
thread Intel thing now here's first of
all to understand Microsoft's actually
been doing tried Intel for about 15
years they just don't really talk about
it like a lot of things inside of these
really big companies right Apple does
some amazing stuff and Google and Amazon
and stuff and but honestly like they
talk very little about it and there's
some good reasons for it but you know so
Microsoft had been doing threading tail
for a long time very very long time so
that they walked in because I had a lot
of experience product typing thread
Intel in the government meaning I
understood how customers meaning Intel
customers wanted intelligence and how we
needed to kind of improve how that
worked so they brought me in so I walk
in so how many here I work with a stock
raise your hands
cool I'm gonna here work with two socks
okay a few how many work with four or
more okay how many work with more than
12 so Microsoft has 12 over 12 socks
inside the company because each so while
we while most companies you think of IT
that's just one of many networks inside
Microsoft because every product is its
own production Network because Skype
does not run the same way as a sure does
not run the same way as Xbox does not
run the same way you know just keep
going down the lines they cannot operate
in the same way and the security teams
it would be ridiculous to think that a
single security team could effectively
manage the security for all of those
various domains and so while it sounds
absolutely ridiculous it actually makes
a lot of sense when you think of what
that what it would mean to actually
operate and manage security in those
domains so I walked in and they're like
oh so you're going to coordinate the
you're going to coordinate all of the
threats between all of these various
products and services so now I've got 12
stocks I have to effectively kind of
Corral and then as I get further into it
I don't even know if I'll get to slide
but as I get into it right the the
challenges oh and now we want you to
bring that intelligence that we
we get that we were able to produce from
our very unique telemetry in the world
we want you to push that out so that you
can protect customers not just our
company the one of the wonderful things
about Microsoft is that it lives a very
very wonderful philosophy which is first
of all that you should be secure just by
using two limits just by using
technology that security should be
transparent to you generally now they
don't always get it right but it's
something that they continuously try to
do so just by using office 365 you get a
whole bunch of really cool stuff in it
just by using as you get a whole bunch
of really cool stuff and it just happens
and it's completely transparent to the
users the other thing is that Microsoft
does not compete in the security space
it has some products but from a
protection perspective we have no
compete I work freely you know I worked
freely with Apple and Amazon and Google
and all the ones you would think that we
would hate we work really really close
together because guess what their users
are my users and my users are their
users and it's a bit the bad day for the
users it's a bad day for my users and so
we don't compete there we freely share a
lot of very very important and sensitive
things amongst each other to keep the
internet safe and it's amazing to be
part of that community and it honestly I
think that's one of the things that that
makes me I would say one of the very few
InfoSec optimists because I've seen big
things happen in amazing ways and I know
that we can do this so the you know so I
can break what thread Intel is it might
so I want to give you a little insight
into how we do that and what that means
I don't think enough people talk about
by the way how they do their work it's I
think that's very rare and I think we
need to talk more about that I think we
saw a little bit about that from IMF
earlier so break down a couple of things
here for you so first of all data right
so you know I got to be a threat Intel
analyst for you know Microsoft actually
has a huge amount of payment processing
if you think about it so I get to do
some financial work Xbox is the largest
gaming network in the world so I got to
protect the gaming Network the large
void network in the world so I got to do
telephony you know second largest
consumer email service in the world so I
got to do consumer email large business
female servicemen also got to do
enterprise email second largest cloud in
the world so did cloud security I mean
it goes on and on and so you just you
look at the immense volume and variety
of telemetry from all of these sources
and there's really almost nothing
there's almost no bad thing that
Microsoft can't see and so it now it may
not see all of it but it's likely going
to have a part of that picture so you
think of all of this data right exabytes
of data like I it's weird it's like I
don't people used to work good data
unless you actually have a physics
problem I don't believe you have big
data because it Microsoft we have
physics problems right like we have so
much data we cannot even physically
write it fast enough or read it fast
enough and so when I talk about it we
were running security analytics on
petabytes and exabytes of data that's
data its security its security at
literally a global scale and then you do
it across all those all of the sites
globally so your security analytics are
running across you know data centers and
data lakes that are distributed around
the world so you have a lot of various
interesting problems to solve so you've
got to collect the normalizer data we
then do analytics now analytics is a
unicorn of a word so very clearly I'm
going to this is a very important point
in one of the important things about how
threat Intel has done at Microsoft we
consumed indicators of compromise only
because we had to because everyone would
think we were stupid if we didn't that's
literally the answer um but almost none
of those indicators were of any value to
us in fact they were of negative value
if you've read my blog post about what
the value of indicators bring instead
almost exclusively 100% of our tracking
our finding of bad guys and such all
came out of what we call behavioral
analytics and this is not some unicorn
these are very simple things and the
cool thing about analytics is that they
have what I've learned security
analytics have three properties and
they're very simple to understand
the first is transpose ability meaning
when you write an analytic you should be
able to transpose it across the various
data sets meaning if I'm getting hosts
telemetry from Linux I'm getting hosts
telemetry from Windows as many of those
analytics as possible should be able to
run equally across them
I should write I should have to minimize
the number of Linux analytics and
windows analytics I write if it's so if
it's a file right I don't care if it's
Windows or Linux it's a file right in an
operating system now I'm not saying that
that's going to work perfectly but you
can maximize that way another property
of really critical security analytics is
composability meaning if you are out
there and you're trying to write a
security analytic and you're frustrating
with you're frustrated with yourself
because you're getting bad false
positives or you know you're not getting
what you want it's probably because
you're doing it wrong and the reason is
is because you should be writing very
small atomic analytics that you chain
together into a composable analytic what
we would call ensembles that actually
gives you a huge amount of power and you
can compose them and you can reuse these
analytics the third property of really
good analytics or shareability
meaning if I write an analytic that runs
in the Xbox environment I can share that
analytic with Skype and so I can read it
in their environment now that's much
more of a unicorn problem I'm sharing
analytics is really hard because every
environments a little different but we
could do a little bit of it and that's
that's definitely an area for
improvement so basically almost almost
all of the bad things we caught not
almost nothing out of indicators almost
exclusively out of these behaviors and
the cool thing is that I was adversarii
agnostic I didn't care if you know it
was Stuxnet or high net or you know
whatever high kid or whatever right it
was if it did something bad
that's all it that mattered to me so I
was not I was not focused on any one one
adversary and again this don't think of
it in terms of this is this is Microsoft
protecting itself all of these analytics
by the way apply to every customer in
the world
Microsoft is its own user of its own
products so to protect the corporation I
had to deploy these analytics inside our
products protecting everybody including
Microsoft at the same time because a
threat Tork our customers was a threat
to Microsoft and the threat to Microsoft
is a threat to our
summers so there was no distinction
between threats to our company and
threats to our users they were one in
the same that also brings the point
earlier Rob made which is a a property I
learned at Microsoft which is when you
are a service provider in a cloud
provider you have a very unique problem
in that every customer you onboard you
onboard their adversaries - we call it
bring your own adversary and so in that
case if you brought on a new major
customer in the world you know like a US
government agency everybody who was
targeting that agency is now targeting
you as well and so we we had hundreds
and hundreds of adversaries that we were
we were we were managing so this very
simple graph right shows that you know
data down at the bottom the data flows
up we collect it we normalize it that's
very very important if you're going to
do transpose analytics you have to
normalize your data if you're writing an
analytic for every type data type you
have it will destroy you and a company
of this scale you can't do it it's just
not feasible so you have to normalize
the data once you normalize it then you
can do some really really powerful
things that blue box at the bottom 90%
of your work should be spent there if
you're not spending 90% of your time
data data wrangling you're not doing
your job because the rest of its super
easy at that point there's no magic
beyond that really we have a so
Microsoft has also so I got in there and
there was a we started with a team of
about let's see was two of us and three
of us I'm a left I left behind a team of
35 full-time hunters and thread analysts
now we that did that team didn't include
anything but basically threat people
because Microsoft has hundreds of
malware reverse engineers and forensics
analysts and stuff like that so if we
needed additional support we could get
it from anywhere in the company and we
did it was it was very good we all the
security teams really work together so
in that case those were 35 dedicated
threat analysts effectively looking and
so our job as threat analysts were three
functions our job was to find and track
threats our job was to understand those
threats what's what is the scope and
scale of that threat to our customers
and then the third part was to develop
new analytics based on our knowledge
which is hey if you're seeing a bad guy
do something new and unique and we don't
have coverage then build a behavioral
detection for that so we can find any
adversary doing that and so here's just
another example I'll skip the I'll skip
over this quickly but you know we have
you know Microsoft we detonate I don't
know it is a large one hundred tens of
millions of malware samples a day
so our detonation simple systems you
know very very large and scalable very
expensive by the way to run detonation
and you know tens of millions a day but
so yeah you can see one we also brought
in threat feeds we spent you know a very
large amount of money looking for you
know looking to see what other people
can bring but on the sleeve here it's
very little most of the value we get is
by by getting it by using enrichment
sources not threat data we generally
could we could generally produce our own
threat data sufficiently and so the key
was one behavioral analytic eyes like I
said earlier if you're looking to write
that one analytic to rule them all
you're going to fail the key is to write
these in a very small way that you could
compose and you could apply across the
entire kill chain because again if
you're it's the analytics are the same
as defense and detection is the same as
defense and depth you have to detect in
depth too and so we apply analytics
across the entire face so yeah we might
miss it in the delivery right so oh
three six they might be you might go
through go through sixty five but we
might catch it when it hits the OS right
before you know either before
exploitation we may miss it there to it
we will have maybe have to catch it
installation right and but that's how
this works right if you think you're
going to you think you're going to
prevent everything then you know I have
a bridge to sell you
but you know and now you've recon right
so now Microsoft gets to leverage the as
we heard earlier LinkedIn for adversary
reconnaissance and then leverage that
telemetry and visibility into the entire
system the cool thing about this is you
get hurt immunity right a threat against
one of our customers that we'd that we
develop detection again applies to all
of our customers equally and so it's not
just everybody you know working in the
silo it's literally herd protection
across all of our customers so how are
the head like I said we have about a
team we had a team of a team of hunters
right
and so they were matrix to cross service
and threat so I'll talk briefly but you
know some Microsoft tracks let's see
when I left about 129 129 was the number
those are just targeted threats by the
way so that's what we didn't really call
them a PT's because I don't believe in
that word so they're basically targeted
threats that doesn't cover the hundreds
of researchers we had in the commodity
threat space so and we matrix our
analysts in two ways first across
services so certain analysts were
responsible for responding and managing
the security analytics and different
services and then they were also matrix
across threats
the cool thing about this is you
stretched your workload very well you
spread your capabilities analysts could
move around it decreased single point
failures of one analyst left you didn't
lose everything you had and it
integrates really really well with other
teams because the other teams could
literally join us on these effectively V
teams right so if oh three sixty five
really wanted to understand helium they
would their security engineers were
joining us on the V team and so they
would be literally working with us as we
were doing threat analysis and then they
would be able to learn that way so we
could easily onboard and off-board other
teams into this model so it worked out
very well to create a cohesive community
of security analyst within the company
we organized within Microsoft we
organized a targeted threat
using the diamond model which you can
read the paper about so I'm not going to
go into and we but we logically group
activity Microsoft does not do
attribution we don't care to our
customers it adds no value to them we
care about the malicious activity and
the malicious activity alone if it's bad
I don't care who you are
we're going to do something about it and
so we basically labeled activity groups
by the periodic table honestly that's
it's a six-month chore to find a good
naming scheme so so a couple of tools we
used inside Microsoft so obviously
you're not going to just like as much as
I love Splunk as a product to do you're
not going to just pick ups one can put
it in here when you're talking about
exabytes of data and so you we it is one
of those roll-your-own scenarios and so
we have massive day
Lake of securely as security telemetry
scuba is a what we call scuba pivot is
one of the tools we use that allows us
to select running run analytics test
indicator test analytics and check
output and stuff like that and track
threat we we built our own threat
intelligence management tool that's
because all the ones that exist now
we're pretty much non-existent when we
started on the other problem with that
is scale again when you talk about this
kind of scale of what you need threat
intelligence management becomes a very
challenging problem we also also of
course love to use the tool that runs
every security team in the world excel
it is the tool to rule them all right
every team in here uses it so if there's
one single unifying factor that's it
and we and so basically we built Excel
plug-ins for our sick for our security
analysts so of course you know we we can
do that but it works pretty well a
couple of examples right Platinum so
you've seen a little bit come out of
Microsoft right honestly it's very hard
to publish outside of Microsoft on
threats of course the company got bit
very very hard many years ago by bad
things and so the company is is
legitimately shy about about talking
about some of this stuff so in fact this
in this presentation was very difficult
so platinum a threat in the Southeast
Asia region active since 2009 lots of 0
days this is a great example of what I
want to just one point I want to make we
talked a lot about some of the you know
so because first key another great
company was up here earlier talking
about some really cool things and we all
get inundated with the Bears and the
pandas and the cicadas or whatever
animal we're picking this week and the
the challenge though is that most of the
threats in the world from the targeted
threat space are regional not global the
only reason you're hearing about them is
because you're most of you are from the
US honestly and you have a significant
bias on but the majority of my customers
in Microsoft they don't those those
generally don't affect them there's more
regional threats to them doing more
damage then there are these massive
global threats and so when you talk
about oh it's you know
sérgio about Microsoft was tracking 129
threats there's actually my personal
estimate this is not Microsoft's number
so but I'm pretty confident in this
there were at least over 300 actively
operating in the world right now and you
won't see almost any of them and so in
that case this is an example of we're
working in a global company you have to
have a true global perspective meaning
yeah the Bears and the pandas are all
great but the majority of the work we
did were in these types of groups
because that's where the damage to most
of our customers was coming from so
whatever is hitting the news it's really
a significant amount of bias that you're
that you're receiving if you think that
that's where the biggest threats are and
so simply we would then we also produce
reporting and so our reporting is not
available publicly and the route there's
a good reason for that because we
honestly don't believe that pure Intel
reporting is of any value
broadly speaking so these reports are
only served up on detection so when
something is detected in your
environment through one of our products
then we then basically you get served in
the Lord to provide you context around
that alert so when something happens
you're like well what the heck was that
well we have it every single alert has
documentation and if we can tie it back
to a specific threat we have a report
for you on that so we have thousands of
Intel reports because we didn't believe
in delivering a single detection without
appropriate context so that the security
teams could make guess what the right
decision which is ultimately what we're
all here of doing and so these again
reports you won't find a Microsoft
threat Intel library right or things
like that because these are detection
this is detection context not for you
know you to read and put into PowerPoint
for your CEOs so that's threaten tell at
Microsoft in 20 minutes
you
[Music]