[Music]
[Applause]
okay so first and foremost before I get
started I wanted to share with you all
the life of a speaker and what it's like
to speak at the CTI summit this year in
particular and I'm gonna start off in
August 13th when I got accepted to speak
here and I can't tell you the level of
excitement that it has like I'm gonna
bring this information and then
recalling tweets in November guess who
the keynote is Cristal and I'm like
awesome I got to speak at this event too
I got a lot to live up to here there's a
lot going on and then the schedule came
out and I was like okay I can do this I
can handle this and the schedule came
out and then I found out hey Matt we're
gonna put you in between the sugar and
warming seats for Ronnie and Ronnie's
one of my favorite speakers so I'm very
happy to be here and get you all amped
up and pumped up for Ronnie's talk but
hopefully in between now and then we'll
we'll have some fun talking about email
scams all right so here's an agenda I'm
not gonna ask you to read through it I'm
not gonna read it to you because we're
actually to go through it live straight
Bill O'Reilly style so first and
foremost this is the most boring slide
in the entire deck by the way my name is
Matt Bromley as Kyle mentioned I'm from
Dallas Texas I'm originally actually
from this area could not be happier to
have left it especially now I work at a
company called Kroll anyone here heard
of Kroll before I mentioned it all right
a few okay who here heard of coal when
they looked me up on LinkedIn right
prior to this talk okay all right
luckily we got away I also do a lot of
work with sands I'm a forensic 508
instructor I work with the secure the
human program and also our analyst
program as well my hobbies well I'm a
big family guy got a little two-year-old
at home was wondering where I am right
now I'm a huge foodie I can't live in a
barbecue state and not enjoy the food
that we've got there I'm however being
from this area I got a hankering for
crab cakes every now and then and then
really I'm one of those I don't work a
day in my life because I love what I do
yes I do dfi are on the side that is
what I like it's my passion so like I
said most boring slide all right let's
move on to the fun stuff why does this
matter
I have to apologize I don't have any
fancy bears to throw your way I'm not
slinging pandas over my shoulder I am
here to talk to you about emails
exciting right emails and then cliff
shows up and I'm like I really need to
find a way to make this exciting all
right let's start in January 2015 I
apologize for the size on this we had a
little bit of a sizing issue but that's
okay I can read it to you January 2015
we had an alert from the FBI that came
out that in about 14 months 214 million
dollars was stolen because of this scam
fast forward to August a whopping seven
months we're now up to half a billion
five hundred eighty five million dollars
stolen about eighty one hundred victims
let's go even further now we're in April
2016 and are up our amount is up to 1.5
billion dollars stolen since October
2013 and then last but not least in June
2016 we got another alert from the FBI
we're now up to three point 1 billion
dollars stolen via this scam between
October 2013 and June 2016
pandas may be cool you know what's work
or than a panda 3 point 1 billion
dollars definitely cooler 3.1 billion as
of June 2016
daily average of 3.1 million dollars
anyone here making that daily if so I'm
hanging up this microphone and we're
gonna go have a chat most successful
month was 400 million dollars in one
month ransomware sounds kind of cool
that's alright state-sponsored attackers
interesting
I'll go escape with 3.1 billion dollars
off to the side if I can who here thinks
this is probably the most sophisticated
attack they've ever seen as well a
little preview of what's gonna happen
right 3.1 billion dollars I mean does
anyone here looked at the list of
non-extradition countries lately there's
a few island nations on there just
saying just saying alright let's talk a
little bit about what these business
email scams actually are hopefully this
is going to seem fairly familiar because
you folks have read on it and I know
don't deny it for some of you it's going
to seem intimately familiar because you
had to deal with it inside of your
organization I already see one head
nodding like yes that was me I had to
deal with this it's not fun few key
ingredients you're gonna see like this
sounds a lot like fishing Matt okay key
ingredients I need a smaller kind of
business
we not see so much of a small business
as opposed to medium to businesses that
operate in the millions that doesn't
mean big businesses don't get hit though
your fortune companies do get hit with
this as well can anyone think of two why
I'm going after kind of that middle tier
I'm not going after mom-and-pop one-stop
grocery shops I want the people who do
maybe 1015 million in revenue a year one
of my big banks have in place very good
for our detection what's that exactly
they're used to the amounts that I want
to steal I don't want to steal 3.1
billion at a time because someone's
gonna come after me anyone remember that
that um Swift tack that we had where
they were poised to steal billions and
billions of dollars how did that work
out for them not very well right one
little typo and you lose yourself a
bunch of billions of dollars in this
case though we're just gonna chip away I
also need an incorrect domain we're
gonna talk about that in just a second I
need a CEO name and a CFO name those are
hard to come by right really tough to
come by those ones and then I need some
random person in the county who doesn't
want to piss the boss off really
straightforward my last three bullets
where can I get those from yeah I mean
Google maybe maybe this stuff is being
indexed and stored somewhere maybe my
business has accessed this kind of
information so that's all I need
like I said non-extradition countries
there's some really nice ones out there
we've got all the ingredients let's make
some soup all right you've got two
seconds what do we got on here anyone
tell me are these the same someone shout
it out
what's that I heard I heard lowercase L
it looks like there's a space in between
the the the m the I and the C right you
guys agree there's a space there
sorry loaded answer it's actually a one
that was in there mmm really hard to
tell to be honest with you I flipped
through about 40 different fonts before
I found the one that made the image that
I wanted however its it the hype is real
this really happens this makes sense to
us in this room every person watching
this presentation says yeah of course
I'm looking out for this kind of stuff
ones instead of eyes or elles zeros
instead of o's so on and so forth it
makes sense extra letters letters for
numbers transpose anyone catch the
second line there whiskey versus Vova
iski that one likes to slip people up a
lot I like that one because you
especially those of you in the back it
just kind of blends together
and then another thing too is infos busy
owns all the different sites I have a
dot-com and a dotnet not or graduate for
my organization do I have the rest as
well if not I need to go see what's
going on with it
guess what these are not trained eyes
let's go back to this slide real quick
does anything on this list say InfoSec
IT admin CSO no this is a group of
people who we know do not know the
difference between these different types
of things how do we acquire these
different types of domains few resources
available first and foremost there's a
lot of companies that actually target
these types of businesses and they say
you can purchase a domain really easy
really cheap I'm gonna give you a 30
days 60 days 90 days free and you're
gonna be able to test out my services
I'll give you a free webmail 500
business cards to get your business off
the ground risk-free $0.99 if I'm
someone sitting in a country that wants
to steal some money I'm thinking to
myself awesome all I need is one stole a
credit card number and I can run all
types of things through it there's a
reference at the end Ronnie who like I
said I'm warming the seat for here
actually has a really really really
awesome blog post on that vistaprint we
can allow an account set up with not
even a charge took a card with a penny
on it and tried to use it to register
and it worked
one-month free trial all I need is one
month onion is one email
to get in and I can get it for free not
a bad entry vector the account set up
and this is my favorite part I used to
have like a little walkthrough on here
but we're not doing a live demo but
Vistaprint you actually used to be able
to set it up and they would give you a
free webmail account to go with your
domain so now I'm asking you how skilled
are my attackers right they register
this fake domain they get these
transpose letters they find a way to
fool you then they've got to set up this
this hidden email service right they've
got to be super smart at setting up
these things nope mr. print does it all
for him for free in 90% of cases
vistaprint is our purveyor for this
particular one and this is not a this is
not a jab at Vistaprint they actually
run a legitimate business they've got
great commercials I want 500 business
cards for free if I'm gonna start my
business definitely but I don't want
someone attacking me and coming after it
all right I'm gonna do a count in the
back of my head I don't ever want to
take a look at this email okay that was
8 seconds or give or take a few eight
seconds is the average time the human
being reads an email when it comes into
their inbox how many errors did we see
any one one which one
alright good catch the from address
we've got some transposing here did
anyone skip over that part and go right
to the subject or right to the body yeah
they didn't focus on that whatsoever
guess what everyone else does especially
in the accounting department there's an
email coming in from my CEO yeah I know
who my CEO is I'm gonna go right to the
subject part did anyone catch this one
Friday it four minutes to five I just
want to go home at that point believe me
this happens for a particular reason how
about this one anyone pick up on that
it's not an actual forward how easy is
it to fake a forward just take the text
from the email throw it into ASCII paste
it and you're done that's it that's what
a forward looks like I like that they
took the extra step here and actually
made links because then it looks a
little bit more legit as opposed to just
raw text and then last but not least we
got a PDF attachment as well any malware
in here doesn't look like it right mmm
any any princes Kings send me money I'll
do this no it looks like the CEO is
asking the CEO looks like Jim is asking
Jayne hey do me a favor
then why are some money to this vendor
and then gym passes it on to John and
says hey John do me a favor take care of
this for me I'm busy there we go there's
another catch as well we don't focus in
on that one but Mike is definitely right
there's other things here that should
trip us again a roomful of trained eyes
not a room full of accountants who at
5:00 to 5:00 on a Friday just want to go
home important takeaway good catch
though all right so now we know a little
bit about what this scam looks like what
this attack actually looks like let's
talk let's define this campaign let's
build this out let's have some threat
Intel fun I think that's what we're here
for so we have some indicators right we
have a transpose domain could I do
anything with that domain any thoughts
I could write I'd go buy a million
dollar-a-year threat Intel service and I
could pump that domain through those
indicators and see what comes back
definitely where am I going to get
registered at Vistaprint three days ago
next doesn't do much for me how about a
PDF any use in a PDF it's not malicious
right we already talked about this
there's no malware inside it's just a
text document yes there are we have a
title in md5 anything out of those hmm
no not really
fairly arbitrary change a bit you can
change one how about machine information
now I'm starting to understand a little
bit of the person who created this PDF
what version they use how they wrote it
did they export from word did they
export from Google Chrome
did they have use Adobe Acrobat
timestamps what a time Sam's tell me my
domain was registered then my PDF was
created then it was sent then and then
it was money was sent out now tells me
how quickly my attackers are actually
mounting and building this campaign if I
have an attacker who did all of those
steps within four minutes of each other
what does that tell you about the recon
phase of this attack it is definitely
happening way beforehand and the author
author is the important part I'm gonna
focus on who here actually I know the
answer but I'm gonna ask anyways who
here when they publish a document uses
office inspector to clear out all
metadata from the document everyone
right I know you guys doesn't want to
raise your hand sugar rush and whatnot
from brownies and cookies that's okay I
know everyone does but unfortunately
I've at guys don't
and then bank info we'll talk about
banking phone a little bit let's start
with our PDF metadata we got an author
here he goes by the name boss laud B OSS
LOD well I wonder if boss lot has
written any other documents anyone here
familiar with Mal war.com take away the
last two valves right malware come what
is malware com the cuckoo sandbox lying
upload your stuff and see what's bad
what do we teach all of our people to do
if you think it's bad don't click it if
you think it's a bad document upload it
and check it look to see if it has
viruses inside guess what the average
accountant does they upload this
document it comes back with a zero score
and they say oh this isn't malware I can
do what it says how did a letter not
being malicious turn into you can follow
the instructions inside that's a common
problem that we see between there so
let's do a little search and see if boss
lot is written anything else it's been
uploaded to a source by the way I just
focus on malware for this discussion
there's a lot of other open source and
I'm calling them open source
intelligence sources but quite frankly
it's not really what it is we're just
using it for that 17 different results
came back so boss laud it looks like he
has written 17 different documents I'm
gonna go through and take a look and see
how many of these we actually have how
many are actually authored by boss laud
how many people wrote a document just
through the term boss lot inside I don't
know what boss a lot means I don't know
what it is I'll know what it does but I
know some guy like 2 likes to go by it
we start to profile this what looks
familiar here yeah I think boss law it
has a pretty static document naming
convention that he uses when he sends
these out
RNR engraving oriental wiring they all
finish with wiring instructions what's
the problem with following this as an
indicator though remember that what's
that it's gonna change this is a user
uploaded document the user may rename it
to whatever they want so we've got to be
a little bit careful with this luckily a
lot of our users stuck with the former
name and uploaded it that way so now I
can start to profile well let's take it
a step further I filtered on what boss
law does but now I know that they also
like to name their documents the same as
well let's do a search for wiring
instructions
we're on Google search number two we've
worked for about three seconds at this
point we'll bill a couple hours because
that's what we do as consultants but you
know well it's a three second Google
search
fifty-five results now I have to put in
a disclaimer here this is going to get
very distracting very quickly for the
sole purpose of the term wiring
instructions does not mean it's related
to this campaign so we have to do a
little bit of digging so we did a little
bit of digging in fact I did about three
minutes of digging for you three minutes
and here's what we came out with sixteen
different authors 29 different documents
nine different banks in about three
minutes of searching and just hopping
from term to term to term to term now
again we haven't discussed how much
money each thing brings in because I
don't have that content but all I have
is how prolific is this campaign or is
it a one-stop shop is it a lot of
different folks out there
what's my chokehold here what's my choke
point yeah
thanks we'll come back to that in just a
moment but I'm looking at this and I'm
like okay I got a lot of different
authors problem with an author I can
change that field we found a few
different authors we found folks like
Compaq Houdini again our our friend boss
Claude does make an appearance in there
as well ray kills Kovas mu Rizwan Khalid
this is a fun looking gang I want to
hang out with these guys where hey kills
do me a favor put together that the that
that's that phishing campaign and let's
send that off to ABC industries if you
want so some really interesting names we
had a couple of empty documents as well
maybe they got smart think about what
you're talking about when you see an
attacker drop their author name into a
PDF document and then all of a sudden
they don't - six months down the line
maybe they're learning a little bit
maybe they're getting a little more
intelligent maybe they got a brand-new
computer they don't know how to use it
we actually saw a couple of these
authors move from Windows to Mac's and
they very clearly did not know how to
use a Mac what banks did they like to
use banks were all familiar with for the
most part right HSBC Bank of America TD
Canada I've never heard of China
Construction Bank I have a sneaky
suspicion as to what they do but you
know things I haven't heard of before
Texas Bank that one hit kind of hard
when I found that one I was like come on
stay out of my state go away and then
Citizens Bank as well again none of
these right off the bat they're not
legitimate banks these are legitimate
banks that they're using to launder
money through
some banks may only own leaves once I'll
go back real quick you'll see like HSBC
hang sang in Bank of America get quite a
few mentions they like to use those they
like to funnel this money through Hong
Kong that's a big one because it's very
easy to set up an account hire someone
to go pull it out for you but sometimes
they got to stay stateside
as well sometimes we'll see things like
HSBC China Citibank International
Limited which I think just really really
wanted to be an official name and
through as many adjectives as they could
in there JPMorgan Chase first trade so
on and so forth so we're starting to see
not only the banks that they commonly
use but then we start to also profile
why do they step out of their comfort
zone if Rizwan Khalid is very familiar
with the process of setting up and
stealing money through an HSBC account
why does Rizwan Khalid all of a sudden
move to using Bank of America why does
he move to using some of these other
more local banks that I may not be too
familiar with did they get caught are
they starting to get you know people
starting to understand the campaign are
they not getting money if they use one
bank so now we're starting to understand
a little bit more about how they start
to progress through the different banks
that they use my attacker is getting
smarter are they learning more or
there's some banks that are that are
more vulnerable to this type of scam so
we profiled these attackers out we've
identified some banks seems like fun
stuff we've talked about some of the
data that they sorry we've talked about
some of the accounts that they use we've
talked about their usernames we've
looked at the different banks that they
do banking out of we've got a lot of
indicators here we started with one PDF
that had nothing inside of it whatsoever
it was fairly benign and we extrapolated
that into a campaign with a lot of
different things and that was in three
minutes of searching I promise you all I
do not want to convolute this slide but
the research i've done over the past
three years this thing is hundreds and
hundreds of nodes wide it goes out there
3.1 billion dollars ain't easy to come
by you got to do a lot of work for that
one but let's focus on the more
important part in the big takeaway from
this talk we started with one PDF we
branched out to all of this now everyone
wants to know how do we get better how
does an attack that stole 3.1 billion
dollars from us over the past 60 or
sorry us four years how do we start to
get better and defend against this
anyone recognize this maybe I think Mike
recognizes it just a little bit here as
threat Intel we're meant to use models
such as this this is not the only model
but we're UNT use models like this and
fill in these blanks right how do my
attackers recon my environment how do
they weaponize how do they deliver how
do they exploit how do they then achieve
their objective and steal money from my
environment what happens when my
attacker starts to wreak on one - skips
a few and just steals money out the door
there's no malware dropped there's no
Account privilege there's a lateral
movement there's no zero days there's no
fancy meterpreter shells they literally
sent one email and walked out of the
door with $200,000 for and $1000
$700,000 how do we get better how do I
defend against this let's look at our
evidence we had a PDF fairly benign PDF
just a bunch of text inside help me out
here because I really want to know is
this gonna defend it's an internal email
right what am I gonna do block email
anyone tried to block email in the
firewall before if anyone wants it you
could try right now it's gonna be
interesting we'll watch you run out with
your hair on fire how about this that's
gonna help we're actually focusing a
little bit how about this AV helps right
maybe he's gonna catch everything that
was a really big wolf from I'm assuming
someone who works with an AV vendor over
their heads hips he's gonna help nudes
nips how about this email prevention is
gonna help right we're gonna detonate
that PDF inside of a sandbox and then
pull out its indicators and block it all
going forward what indicators well
you're gonna launch a company that
operates off of the author field of a
PDF not gonna work really well this is
why this attack is so dangerous because
as InfoSec folks as CTI folks as
responders we rely on these things to
tell us when something doesn't fit right
in our environment and now all of a
sudden there's an attacker who's found a
way to circumvent all the things that
don't fit right we're gonna talk about
where they're attacking in just a moment
as well alright so we're gonna come back
to our kill chain here and once again
I'm gonna ask you as a as CTI folks as
incident responders how do we deal with
an attacker who just says forget the
middle steps I'm gonna go right to the
end how do we deal with this particular
type of attacker well
some folks may say focus on the
reconnaissance not a bad idea tell you
what we're gonna set up some LinkedIn
visitations scraping scripts and every
hour we're gonna scrape LinkedIn and see
who's visited our site are we able to
actually do that
no but yet it's all public and tell you
what then you've also got to scrape your
financial statements you got to see
who's scraping every article that's ever
been written about you okay alright
recons not gonna work
got it make sense how about our actions
on objectives let's focus here and this
is where I'm going to challenge my
threat Intel folks to think about what
this means usually as an incident
responder this is where you're at hole
crap we're gonna need to shut something
down things have burned for CTI I'm
gonna ask you to say how does this turn
into an opportunity for me how does this
turn into an opportunity for my business
let's take a look and see how this goes
what happens in this particular phase of
this attacker life cycle of this cyber
kill chain an employee gets an email the
employee initiates the transfer and then
money goes out the door that's right
three steps really simple how do I
defend against this how do I protect
against an employee doing this some of
they look at this and say this is futile
there's nothing I can do or my favorite
statement which I'm going to ask
everyone to never say again this stupid
user clicked on stupid XYZ ABC and then
stupid event happened and I'm going to
ask you not to ever say that again
because your job is to protect the
organization and if you think that by
sitting back and reading feeds every day
you're gonna do that no we've got to
expand our branches take a look at this
here three different steps right money
walking out the door do you see info
second there no definitely doesn't cross
the IT admin do you see anything that is
going to involve anyone in this room not
necessarily but I'm gonna tell you this
is where you can get involved number one
you do have a choke point you do have a
choke point in this process where you
can ask and talk to your accounting
department and say ask yourself when
transfers come through is this normally
how I receive requests we're a
multi-million dollar business do you
normally get transfer requests in a
forward from the CFO to the CEO or the
CEO to the CFO that says hey sorry I'm
golfing can you send this out real quick
I forgot to tell you about that $400,000
payment we're making to hang seng Bank
is this who I normally receive requests
from I've met a lot of CEOs and satin a
lot of boardrooms in my time very rarely
am I am i interrupting a discussion
where the CEO is like hey Jen did you
send those invoices out um I just just
want to make sure that the accounting is
on top of things you may have a super
micromanaging CEO in that particular
case
very rarely though is this coming from
them here's my other choke point as well
this is where I'm gonna work with my
accounting department say do we normally
work with these banks I'm a small
business that runs in Texas I do ten
million dollars a year in revenue let's
say an email comes through hey do me a
favor send half a million over to hang
seng bank in China what I don't do
business with you I don't know who you
are
the best thing that can ever come out of
these types of attacks is ask someone
what happened here this doesn't make
sense and then set up a do not transfer
list we already went through a list of
banks that need to go through we went
through a list of banks that we are know
our attackers are going after guess what
I'm doing if I work in threat Intel and
I've seen this campaign I'm going to my
accounting department and I'm saying hey
here's a list of ten banks we do
business with these banks know okay good
in the future if we ever do I need dual
signatures and I need to be notified of
that request comes through because my
job is to protect this organization and
I don't want to sit back and watch you
send bulks on the money to HSBC and then
all of a sudden the security department
which already has ridiculously low
funding gets an even bigger cut because
the county needs more money to make up
for their mishap realize where your
frontlines are again I'm gonna go back
here and tell you all that all of these
choke points this is your accounting
department how many people here think
about their accounting or their account
or their marketing departments as their
frontline right once the malware gets in
the system I'm gonna find it somehow
right I'm gonna detect that lateral
movement I'm gonna find those shells why
don't I go back to the frontline and say
hey stop clicking on stuff don't open
things and and that you want to talk
about an exercise in futility ask your
marketing department it cut stop
clicking on things it's a very very
tough thing to go through but I'm gonna
say at this point guess what if you have
a go go have a discussion with your
accounting department and you stop a
million two million dollars from walking
out the door
there's brownie points and then there's
what you just got inside the
organization I'm telling you it's a next
level of stuff so think about where your
front lines actually are if you fit into
this type
business that is most likely gonna get
targeted for these if you have a
department with not very strong InfoSec
around the accounting if you fit into
one of those we don't have a really big
fraud detection mechanism but we do
transfer millions of dollars a year then
you need to be thinking about what your
different front lines are and once you
identify those armed them with
everything they need to be successful
hey accounting department here's a list
of ten banks we never work with do not
send money here put on a post-it note
put in a little Excel table print it out
put it all inside their cubicles boom
guess what like I said you just stopped
a bunch of million dollars from walking
out the door notice we haven't talked
about any sort of animal whatsoever
thank you all right for the business
take this document to them hey
accounting is this what this looks like
this is what a normal wire transfer
comes in as someone's half-ass attempt
at drawing up details inside of a Word
document than converting a PDF do we
work with them does it match our details
does this vendor information look
familiar the best way to stop this is to
ask our accounting department to stop
and think again looking to get about
where our front lines are sharing is
caring as well and this is where I'm
gonna tell you all right now if this is
the first time you're hearing out
business email scams we're in trouble
because something that steals 400
million dollars a month should not be
news to us by now it should be a big
event that we're aware of
CREB should not be your IDs it's this
ridiculous meme I see thrown around the
internet Krebs as my IDs that is the
worst IDs you can have is a journalist
publishing your data breach trust me you
do not want to be in that particular
state admitting to being fish is not
embarrassing trust me we are all being
fished right now in one way shape or
form it's okay to admit increases in
decreases and it's okay to share those
indicators take that list of banks and
share it with your competitors there's
nothing wrong with sharing and admitting
to what's going on here don't use this
as a leg up and I'm gonna take it in a
couple minutes and just focus on this
and luckily this has actually already
been said today so I get to kind of lean
and stand on the shoulders of giants
everyone in this room already has three
thread Intel source you all know that
right yes what is it
your own environment everyone here is
your own threat Intel spunk folks did a
much better job of summing it up so I'm
just gonna leave it at that if you're
protecting an organization and you're
not keeping notes about the things going
on in your environment there's something
wrong with what you're doing we get
better by learning cumulatively not
resetting the clock every day and I know
this crowd is not doing this but I'm
gonna say it just in case someone's
looking for that branch to grab onto
tracking your own threat Intel can be an
easy start don't fall into the trap of
I'm a small medium-sized business I'm
already having enough time trying to
keep unpatched Java an unpatched flash
in check start with notepad no plus plus
record your indicators again this is not
a sophisticated campaign I'm not asking
you to buy any sort of expensive feed to
protect against emails include enough
information that if you read this again
in the future you would remember the
event fully who here has ever said to
themselves I will definitely remember
that in fact I'm gonna give you a bigger
challenge record enough notes that if it
happened in 1986 you can present on it
in 2017
level up your life use Excel we've
talked about Excel being the best
analyst tool who's mind here just went
that's right this entire campaign
everything I talked about today was
recorded in Excel I know there was no
fancy thing behind it it allows you to
maintain relational data but more
importantly it lets you as a human do
what you're best at I am NOT the best at
reciting md5 s not the best at reciting
file names I am the best in taking a
split second look at that document and
saying HM there's a lot going on in
Queens Road in Hong Kong that's what I'm
good at
so put the information in a way that I
can look at it or if worse comes to
absolute worst and you can't stand Excel
but you need something a little more
powerful then use the tools that are out
there anyone here using any of these
threat note crits
miss these types of tools are out there
to help you track this information you
can do it for free
and if you say to me Matt I don't have
time to prop up a Linux server and do
this I'm gonna say guess what you have a
lot of time for a good learning
opportunity it does get better every one
we talked about colbus mu as one of our
attackers and I'm done after this I
promise everyone remember this name
colbus mu was tied to one particular
document that came through one
particular document that was uploaded on
malware mr. mu and I had quite a few
run-ins on an investigation side he's
actually responsible for quite a few
documents you may be wondering why am I
looking at this picture of colbus up
here
well colbus was pretty prolific and
active from 20 2013 up until 2015 and
then in August of 2015
he stopped anyone know why because of
everything that we do as threat Intel
sometimes here who feels like giving
information to law enforcement a one-way
road sometimes you do right guess what I
promise you it's not in August of 2015
Cove assume you got arrested for cases
that we investigated and accidentally
proved him as the author of these just
so happened to be in Dallas which was
really cool it was nice to do that
happen there but the takeaway from this
is all this work we do all this research
that we do and everything we go into
sometimes you don't see they'll the
silver line at the end but it's there I
promise you keep doing the good work
keep doing the research keep finding
these attackers we'll catch them
there's a good reference slide the
slides will obviously be available this
is all the different points I've talked
about for you to go through and I do
give Ronnie a shout out for his
presentation on vistaprint as well but
with that everyone thank you very much
for attending the presentation a lot of
fun
[Music]