and so when we think about humans one of
the things we often struggle with is why
do people make bad decisions and in fact
we say this off and we say bad decisions
is if humans aren't capable of making
good decisions right why are they always
making bad decisions and bad is a polite
word that we're using because what we
really mean is why did they make stupid
decisions this that's what we're telling
ourselves now that's also not nice so
let's let's tone that down a little bit
and let's instead ask ourselves why did
it make these decisions that are
incomprehensible to us because the
person making the decision doesn't think
it's stupid or bad although there are
times that I sometimes question you know
if I climb the top of a bridge whether
that was a stupid decision and so let's
look at those conversations right in the
security field we often get into topics
where we're a business owner comes and
they're gonna have a conversation with
us and what if the business owners think
about us right they walk in and they
think we're a bad guy right yeah we're
we're dressed in the black hat I
appreciate the white hat in the room you
know that all that we care about is
making their life hard I once had the
pleasure of sitting on a panel with the
CIO of Bechtel and he said you know to
me risk is anything that impacts my
schedule or my budget so you are risk
now we on the other hand as the security
profession will see this business owner
coming in and we know that they want to
you know launch a product that's
horribly insecure they want to do
something dangerous so we think of them
as this bad guy right they're coming in
they're gonna violate the rules they're
gonna do these things that are horrible
well this is modal bias
anybody here cycle one couple people or
pedestrian walk right what do you think
about drivers they're idiots
right they're rude they think they have
right-of-way they're gonna cut you off
we do these mean dangerous things and
they're in these armored vehicles
anybody here drive what do you think
about bicyclists and pedestrians they're
idiots they're self-centered they're
going to cut you off they won't right
away you know the best part is next time
that you're driving somewhere think
about that is
and what do you think about pedestrians
and then the moment that you get out of
your car and start walking recognize
that you don't think the same way about
the auto drivers and that's natural this
is modal bias we preference the mode
that we operate in and we immediately
forget all of the reasons why that other
mode might behave in this fashion so is
a security person we say look before you
deploy a system you have to do these 855
things and then how often do we follow
that list of things when we deploy a
system never right we switch modes and
we're like god I'm not gonna follow the
rules I know better well maybe they
think they know better too in fact
really important here is that in this
model each person told the story in
which the other person was the villain
and the reality is nobody is the villain
in their own story right sometimes we
think we're the superhero sometimes we
just think we're a normal person trying
to go through our life and there's these
villains that come in and they're trying
to stop us and keep us from doing things
but nobody thinks they're the villain
like Darth Vader didn't even think he
was the villain right he's got
motivations right figure out what his
motivations are but the moment that I
cast you is the villain it's easy for
you to cast me as the villain and we're
certainly not going to be a team not how
the Avengers gets created by having
everybody thinks each other or villains
so how does this instantiate itself
let's look back to that conversation
about villains and we see the business
owner comes in and they said look I want
to launch a product is it safe now safe
is a really dangerous word sometimes
they'll say it's secure these words have
no meaning right these are words that
every person brings to a different
context the best way I can put that for
folks is casper weinberger former
Secretary of Defense was once asked
about communications difficulties
dealing with the military and he says
look here's my problem let's say that I
give the order to go secure the building
and if I give that to the Marines they
will kill everybody inside the building
and probably blow it up for good measure
not a bad plan if I give that to the
army they're going to go put up
concertina wire and barricades around
the building have unfolding fire zones
to prevent anybody from coming in and
set up a checkpoint where you have to
have the password of the day to get into
the building and if asked the Navy to
secure the building they will make sure
that all of the lights are turned off
the windows are closed and the doors are
locked when they leave and the Air Force
will get me a three year lease with an
option to buy
is it safe what does this mean so what
do we say we say something like this
look here's my checklist of everything
that every idiot has ever done wrong in
deploying the system demonstrate to me
that you haven't repeated any of those
mistakes all right that's what I saw
when t7000 - really is now they look at
this and they say oh my god it's like
875 pages it uses words I don't
understand could you fill it out for me
awesome guaranteed employment act now we
get to be employed filling out the
checklist that we handed them so we do
and we fill out this checklist and we
talked about as a tear at risk we say
things like god you're using the RSA
1024 and you really should be on the Ed
25 519 or you know we want to have a
hashing algorithm that's no longer sha-1
it's your poly 1305 chacha 20 like these
are the real words that we put in front
of people and they look at us and
they're like wood does this mean I can
go ahead now this is a trap why is this
a trap because they're absolutely yes/no
binary question if you say yes this is a
showstopper you should not go ahead
they're going to overrule you and go
ahead and if you say no this is not a
showstopper well you're the one who did
the risk assessment whose fault is it if
there was risk but it wasn't mitigated
this is a horrible conversation to have
and this is the conversation that 10
years ago we told everybody in security
they wanted to have that you want to be
the gatekeeper we're not gatekeepers
we're advisers this is a gatekeeping
conversation so let's think about that
let's look at prisoner's dilemma for a
moment - me too
try to understand what happens with
people here so they're very familiar
with the prisoner's dilemma if not quick
refresher we have two people they have
committed a crime and they have been
caught almost in the act so we are the
police where the district attorney we
have these two people and we can nail
you on a misdemeanor or maybe a small
felony but we'd really like to get you
to rat each other out because we want to
get you for the big crime that we know
you committed but we have no evidence so
we need your testimony that's the model
for the prisoner's dilemma so we say to
each one look you have a choice you can
cooperate or you can cheat um or give
the other person has the same choices
now so we'll save to Alice look if you
cooperate with us and by cooperate or
safe or operate with your partner then
you'll get the top set of penalties or
the left side if you cheat which is you
rat them out you'll get the right set of
penalties now notice you have different
penalties depending whether the other
person cooperates routines so if both of
you cooperate with each other we'll send
you to jail on your minor crime if one
of you cheats we'll let you off you'll
go to jail for a year the other one gets
ten and if both of you chief you'll both
get five relatively pointed this week
because this is what it has what's known
as a Nash equilibrium named after John
Nash who just died in a taxi accident
and what happens here is you look at
this you say ah well no matter what the
other person does I'm always better off
cheating so I should always cheat and in
fact when we study this on grad students
we discover that people will cooperate
with their buddy only about 13 percent
of the time that both people choose to
cooperate but that they will effectively
net cheating 40 percent of the time
that's pretty impressive that means
about two-thirds of the time any given
person will choose to rat out their
buddy
this is going to come back and we'll
come back to this in a moment boom but
that's it that's a case of historical
paranoia we know these stories we tell
ourselves these stories research done
apocryphally in the 50s they didn't
actually write down any of their results
just published a paper so we're not sure
it actually happened but take five
monkeys to create strain right take five
monkeys put them in a room put a table
in the room put a novel object on the
table doesn't matter what it is monkeys
are inherently curious animals just like
humans so what do you think the monkeys
do right they go interact with the novel
object or they try to as soon as they
get close to the novel object the
researchers use a fire hose to spray all
of the monkeys to keep them away from
the table repeat until the monkeys have
learned novel object on the table don't
go near it what they should learn is
researchers are bad Rise of the Planet
of the Apes is a great movie instead
take a monkey out of the room and
replace it with a monkey that has not
observed this before put a novel object
on the table what happens that monkey
heads for the table what do the other
four monkeys do attack tackle that
monkey beat it into submission so that
it never goes after the object on the
table repeat doing this until there is
no monkey that has ever been sprayed
with water in the room and allegedly
they will continue to beat each other up
every time a novel object comes into the
room they have historical paranoia we
are afraid of the object on the table
because we have always been afraid of
the object on the table that's how we
operate the ISO 27000 too has controls
in it that are meaningless or worse that
are actively harmful to our security
today but it is the way we have always
done it you should have passwords that
rotate every 90 days why because at the
time we wrote that that's about how long
we thought an online password cracker
would take the reality is either you've
got about 90 seconds with your passwords
or you have forever either there is no
Oracle or there is and designing around
this 90 days means we're not protecting
the to cases that actually matter
what's our goal here's our goal is to
increase value so value is the resources
that we have finds the capabilities that
we apply them with and this is important
resources is easy it's your time it's
your money to a CFO they're all the same
but the mythical man-month does apply
time matters
now capabilities is interesting this is
the things we go do and what are the
three factors that go into that well one
of them is our skill how good are we in
doing a thing one of them is our effort
how well do we apply ourselves and now
this isn't an argument that people are
lazy it's an argument that things like
if you have developers they tend to work
in four hour sprints and if you schedule
them for a meeting every two hours to
ask them how they're doing you should
expect them to exert zero actual effort
not that they're not trying but you have
made it impossible for them to write
code and effective this is about an
organizational dynamic right did you do
a thing that the organization will take
because if not it has no value and did
you present it in a way that the
organization will like it and consume it
if not it's not going to provide value
and value is what we are paid for right
it is our organizations believe that we
produce ongoing value they made an
investment in us and as time goes on so
risk perception it's what's going to
move upwards and our value is what moves
downwards that is none of those on we
get these impulses of new risk that the
security value we've invested in we'll
push that down and so we get to have a
constant level of risk in our
organization that's what your
organization probably believes I'll come
back what organizations believe in a
minute but if we don't believe that
there is risk well you're gonna have low
investment and if we don't think that
you have good capabilities
we'll say that there is less risk right
if we don't see how you're possibly
providing value yet we're not getting in
trouble then clearly we're not in a
risky world and therefore we don't need
to pay you as much this is a really neat
cycle to get into and in fact we see
that cycle happen all the time when
people
ask the question well can't we just be
good enough and so we have to ask well
what would it mean to be good enough so
let's pause it
some tract of security value just to
confuse everybody I've reversed my
directions now so good security we'll
just put that in the middle this is not
to scale there's a reason there's no
numbers here and I would pause it then
if I wanted to attack your company today
if you had good security I probably
can't get in by the end of the day
you're sufficient against the casual
adversary that somebody who decided
today to do harm to you who is not
necessarily the best adversary out there
doesn't know anything about your systems
probably can't just walk right in that
seems like that's a reasonable standard
you should at least be better than that
now we're probably also going to say
that if they a sufficiently advanced
persistent adversary is probably going
to be good security right good enough is
not good enough to stop the NSA or China
should they really take a liking to you
I need to do something different in that
world okay
now let's think about perfect security
we all love to be better than that
Voltaire said it best the perfect is the
enemy of the good you do not get to good
enough by aiming for perfect you get to
perfect by incrementally aiming for good
you want to get better but the path to
the best is not a straight line if
you're at the bottom of a cliff and you
want to be at the top of the cliff the
fastest way to the top of the cliff is
not to start climbing it's to look for
the path that is in a different
direction that will take you up there in
much the same fashion you're going to
have that case here so I would assert
that you have to those using the
assessment not a community or who hire
them good Assessors should tell you
where you're good security isn't good
enough and can marginally get better and
this is a place that you'd love to live
in is where you can assess your security
either internally or externally move
forward that said most people we talk to
on their outside our companies are not
Assessors um in fact they're auditors
but they're people people that we pay to
give us passing grades right if you have
a PCI Auditor
you pay them to give you an F no right
you pay them to give you a 100% perfect
any auditor is affected that's what
you're paying them for so we have an
incentive not to actually hire great
ones but we try to hire serious ones and
they're probably behind the times by a
few years they're not specialists in the
craft and so they're probably not going
to actually keep you above that line of
the fit of this casual adversary and
sadly you get what you pay for most of
the times we're not even paying for the
standard auditor and we're mostly trying
to fool them so we can hang out really
down low very easily and when you hang
out in that world you start to have
enterprises that think they can get away
with being even worse than that it will
just fake it a little harder when the
auditor shows up I'm not going to ask
for a show of hands four people work in
one of these companies I know they exist
and so we can think of this is one of
the three categories odds are most
people want to live in that middle
that's where they ought to live we'd
love to get to that top and the bottom
unfortunately is we're all too many
people live Wendie neither coins the
term the security poverty line
Dominic would say that's the line at the
bottom if you want these slides by the
way I linked to them off of Twitter so
you can get them as well so you have a
higher resolution than just the
screenshot but I'm happy that photos are
great too so security is something
overtime right we don't just implement
it once that we change the adversaries
change so if we look at how all of these
move you know as time goes on what we
actually see is that the auditors and
the organizations that are trying to
fool them are falling farther and
farther behind in fact for all intents
and purposes the organization's might as
well just Park on the side of the road
they might be better off in that state
now I said what the organization thinks
they can get away with and now that's a
really interesting way to phrase it
because organizations don't think but
before we get that there's a thing
called the peltzman effect Sam peltzman
economist at the University of Chicago
when we were debating national seatbelt
laws for those of you who remember that
he said look if if we make everybody
wear seatbelts they will kill more
and so according the term killer
seatbelts and if you go look at NHTSA
data over the last 40 years it turns out
Sam peltzman might be right that in fact
the advent of safety technologies in
cars makes people drive faster fewer
drivers are dying 400,000 mine per
100,000 miles driven on the roads but
the number of pedestrians that are
killed in vehicular things is not
falling right we are transferring the
risk on to pedestrians because drivers
are taller look I can do 70 miles an
hour I can plow into things and live
where's 170 miles an hour and you're the
pastor in that I didn't see you're not
going to survive and Sam peltzman said
look there's one safety technology that
we could put into cars that would
minimize how much harm people would get
into right if I put this in your car how
many of you are going over seven let
alone seventy right if I make you a bird
aware of the risk you'll react
appropriately that's a really important
thing to remember people who are aware
of risk modify their behaviors when I
first got to do the first version of
this talk two years ago here at source
right before I got up somebody came up
and I think it was GPA actually and did
a public service announcement that the
prior night somebody had been mugged
walking around the corner to the ATM if
you have gotten money out late at night
or walk you back and some said hey nice
money you just got there can I have it
probably not quite that polite she gives
this public service announcement
everybody's like oh my god what am I
going to do like to check their pockets
they make sure they're safe they became
aware of risk and their behavior
instantly changed it's interestingly
most Empire would not going to go walk
to an ATM at night but they became aware
that you know you're in Boston to the
theater district this isn't the safest
place in the world now I did say what
your organization thinks it can get away
with
contrary to what lots of people would
like you to believe organizations are
not human organizations don't think
people think organizations behave in the
way that the people
work for the organization believes that
the organization would want them to
behave and very convoluted right we
model our organization's almost like
deities and we've behaved the way that
we think the day he wants us to behave
and therefore the organization behaves
that way
now people think or do they Daniel
Kahneman economist got a fish university
he's at posits that the human brain is
composed of two systems and most of the
time one of our systems is doing our
behaving for us that is our fast lizard
brain it doesn't think it is an expert
system all of the tasks that we can do
that computers can very easily do for us
are done by system one for instance if I
say what is two times two everybody just
thought for you didn't do math if I said
what is 17 times 85 you might have to
start doing math before you'll get to 14
45 for that one right system one
answered the first one for you it's why
we do multiplication tables is so we can
learn very quickly how to do things and
we don't have to waste resources because
our attention is a valuable resource and
we don't want to spend it doing mundane
tasks system one does it for us what
system one does is it takes all of this
input that is coming in from the world
and at some point it decides to do
something it has rules and so you go
take an action based on those rules
everybody who raised their hand because
they were a driver his probably at some
point gotten home and realized that they
don't remember driving home system one
can drive a car this might explain why
we think about a lot of drivers they're
not really sentient when they're driving
they're letting an AI drive their car
Google might be better at this now
system one is also a bigot very
important for people to recognize if you
happen to walk out of here at night and
you see large man in an alley you
probably think danger that's okay that
system one saying it's dark there's a
person there bigger than I am let me
cross the street even if they're not
bigger than I am let me cross the street
it's important to recognize that this is
where much bigotry comes from is from
system one
making judgments based on inputs that it
has now we do a little exercise partly
cuz it's already the morning people need
to make sure they're awake so I'm gonna
put words up on either side of the line
just a left side and a right side all
that I want you to do is say left or
right depend on which side of the line
the word shows up on now to practice
it's really easy
I love the humor it is not the point
that are just like Oh God where is he
going with this let's clear it out okay
okay so what happened there this is
actually one of the best friends I've
ever had a system to over writing system
one here's the thing that's interesting
left right decision-making is not
something system one can do but it can
read so your system one's like oh I got
this the words on the left stay left the
words on the right stay right I will
just read the word aloud you get fast
you get resigned to it and you're going
through and then all of a sudden I throw
something on the wrong side and system
one is like oh hey wait a second
something's wrong they're most proud
than the other half the people to say
the first one wrong but you notice how
forceful everybody was that was system
to coming in and saying system one shut
up I have to think about this I have to
take an extra half second and come up
with something but we're very good at
this it's sometimes overriding our
system once but that's a very easy
example for you of how system one works
now system one trains itself it learns
things right you just saw it learn how
to do a task well guess what we take our
system 1 and our company systems 1 and
for instance we send them to
computer-based training
it'll say something like you have annual
security where it is training is
required of all employees because bla
bla bla bla bla and what do they learn
out of getting messages like this oh
right it's that annual check
last thing I gotta do let me click the
button god I hate this and think they
actually improved in their security
awareness at that point or did then then
did they instead say god I hate these
people who make me do this work they're
evil and why do we employ them
so let's come back to the prisoners in a
dilemma remember this one now it turns
out that all of our knowledge about how
people behave with one another is based
on doing Studies on grad students now it
turns out that grad students are a very
poor model for humanity all models are
flawed some are useful it turns out
they're incredibly not useful for
understanding how people will decide to
cooperate or cheat with one another so a
university in Australia said well that's
great why don't we do this test instead
on actual convicts we have these people
in prisons we can model behavior in the
same way like the test that we do to
simulate aren't with actual people who
are we suspect were convicted or have
committed a crime we actually is a
rewards based system to model it instead
and all of a sudden what happens is this
that the cooperation rate jumps up to
30% of the time they're both cooperating
and in fact they're only both cheating
about 19 percent of the time we just
flipped from about 65% cheating to 65%
cooperating like that's phenomenal
what's the difference here the
difference is you convince a grad
student that this is a two-player game
but no way you ever going to miss a
convict that this is a two-player game
they recognize that the researcher is
the authority and that they're a player
in the game different model of humanity
and a different model of the world right
they recognize that they are not the
villains to each other but Alice and Bob
you two when they were grad students you
could totally convince them that each
other was a villain and his villains
they became remarkably non-cooperative
we don't want to be villains
there's my demand so when we talked
about organizations considering risk
it's important to understand that
everybody in the organization thinks
about risk but they think about it
differently so for instance we'll take
these the people in that organization
and let's take you know any business
owner they're responsible for a P&L they
want to understand if they're doing well
at their market share to them risk is
all about product launch and product
failure and are they capturing enough of
the TAM to work forward you know we look
at the CEO and in a sense in a lot of
senses the risk they're looking at is
based on quarter to quarter or
profitability alright are we doing well
as a company we can look at folks in
sales their risk is you know my income
is entirely based on how much I sell I
got to make my quota am I going to make
my quota selling this product imagine
that you have one product that you have
say 25% margin on but sells for $1,000 a
month if you have another product that
you have like seventy five percent
margin that sells for like $20,000 a
month most sales reps will go sell 20 of
that $1,000 a month deal even though
it's less profitable for your business
because they're going to fill quota so
you have a business owner who cares
about P&L and a sales rep who cares
about quota that are now adversarial
we've incented them to go solve
different problems very important sorts
of things for us to pay attention to we
look at the CFO and they worry about
resource allocation we've got people who
can actually predict how much money they
will spend and you know actually come on
budget under budget is a bad thing in a
public company for those who have not
had the joy of being in a public company
or managing a budget at the same time
the oh I should save money is a horrible
idea if you're going to save money you
have to tell the CFO you're going to do
it before you do it because if they
thought you were spending ten million
dollars this quota up this order and you
only spent three million dollars that's
seven million dollars of money that they
allocated in the wrong place that they
don't really get to get back because
they're reporting quarterly hitting the
budget is more important than saving
money now if you can save money and hit
the budget they're really happy
employees often ask the question Wow am
I gonna have a job but I've got sales
reps that are selling things that aren't
profitable I got the CFO is taking my
money back because I didn't spend it is
this well-run company am I gonna sell
the job next week and of course you know
and the security we ask questions like
is this safe all right those first five
questions are all seem answerable don't
they but those are very tactical real
fears
this isn't this safe comes back to that
earlier conversation about safety now
let's be honest I use the lizard brain
here a stereotype to everybody in those
fields including our own that's not
always the only thing that people will
think about now let's go back to risk
tolerance so the oh you have perceived
risk over time and now I hypothesizing
and kaanum in this economy's belief is
that we basically have a set point of
risk tolerance we will tolerate so much
risk that we accept and so if you
increase it something comes in and
scares us we will then act to decrease
it push it back to where it was and that
in theory this repeats all the time in
our lives now you assume the other
direction if risk goes down you will act
to increase risk we see things like the
mandatory bicycle helmet laws looked at
first like they would had decreased risk
they broken this rule because all of a
sudden more bicyclists are surviving
until you go and looked at all wheeled
vehicles and discovered that all of a
sudden a whole bunch of the riskiest
bicyclist had all moved off of bicycling
onto more dangerous vehicles
skateboarding you know the the rip
boards etc because they could get that
thrill and so the the head related
injuries had gone up in other wheeled
sports now you saw in there that I had
perceived risk and so there's perceived
risk and actual risk these are in theory
and harmony but not necessarily so at
any given point you're somewhere here
and hopefully those line up in a decent
fashion and you can move without point
around so your actual risk can increase
but you're not aware of it
thread ignorance probably not a great
place to be in I would assert that
almost all threats to start out with
this and then hopefully you learn about
them at some point to get back onto that
that beautiful dotted line you could
have known vulnerabilities or risk
happens you're aware of it you assess it
correctly
therefore your perception moves out the
same way your actual risk does there's
FUD which is what you know us vendors
will start all of our slide decks with
slides 2 3 & 4 of almost every extra
slide slide when is the title slide to
is about the company slide 3 is the
headline scare flood slide slide 4 is
the case study of somebody being
breached and slide 5 is how I'm going to
save you from this but pretend that
that's not what this slide really is so
I'm supposed to go through 15 more
slides but it's what sells right now
fear is good we buy stuff because of
fear but you want fear to be aligned to
a real risk if I show you a headline for
company that's not yours probably not a
real risk now we can improve things
stealth improvements I always love when
people are so embarrassed that they
haven't fixed something in years that
they fix it and don't tell me and then
it takes me another couple years to
discover that fix that happened I'm
thinking well you know I thought you had
more risk so I was pushing you to fix
other stuff too great but this is not
actually a great place to be you don't
want your perception and actual to not
align you can reduce risk you can also
do security theater hey look here's this
thing we're doing to reduce risk
it doesn't actually reduce risk now I
left out two directions these are the
fun directions because one of these is
blind to compliance we do a thing
because we are told this will reduce
risk we believe it and it turns out it
doesn't actually reduce our risk at all
one of my favorites I was in the UK a
while ago was in a hotel and in the
shower there's the sign which is hard to
read it says you have for your comfort
and safety before showering
please ensure the bath mat is securely
in place and the shower curtain is
inside the bath now you can envision
when they created this sign that had
some people slip or fall in the bathroom
and their lawyer said oh my god we have
a risk here where you
we'll be accused of being negligent so
we'll make up the science we'll put them
in every one of our bathrooms so that
now it's the customers fault if they
slip and fall right so that they think
they have reduced their risk but what
wasn't in that bathroom a bath mat or a
shower curtain right so now they've gone
for it instead of going down in rhythm
on up in risk if I slip and fall they
have gone from negligence to
recklessness they knowingly created this
risk for me now I had somebody pointed
out to me they said yeah but I think you
were really safe in that bathroom
weren't you and in fact I was because I
had the opposite I had awareness like
there was this risk that it always had
now it's oh my god I'm really aware of
it and I'm going to change my behavior
because I'm so aware of risk like I've
overreacted this is a great place to be
like you kind of want people to over
react in a good way and then say okay
maybe I overreacted a little but hey now
I feel safer but that feels good right
being in that axis that feels really
awesome so the downside is sometimes we
don't mitigate risk and what happens
when we - what story do we tell
ourselves so we're going along we have
some perceived risk something new comes
in we get scared we take some action and
the action doesn't actually fix our
problem and so our lines don't match up
and that's really uncomfortable for us
and so we have to tell ourselves some
stories about what we might do at this
point now an ideal story would be we'll
go push the line down somewhere else
that's probably too simple for us so one
story that we might tell ourselves is
that well that was just my perceived
risk my actual risk was always up there
to begin with when a retroactive
continuity anybody who reads comic books
is very familiar with this technique
that's also pretty uncomfortable and
hard for us to really don't get with
either/or we can tell ourselves a
different story
and so our different story goes
something like this you know i was here
and i got told about this risk and i
took an action maybe that risk wasn't
really
bad as I thought it was and in fact we
who was it that told me about that risk
always Bob the Oh Bob's told me about a
whole bunch of other risks that were in
my system too maybe I could even order
those also and so now all of a sudden
hey I'm doing much better than I was
before
in fact I'm doing so much better that
I'm at such low risk that I can go do
some cool risky things I've got this
risk budget that I can go spend to get
back to where I thought I was I've
actually worked with folks who verbally
squawked me through that that change of
thinking kind of scary where we want to
be is to train people we say look the
risk that we know about is not what our
organization knows about so when new
risks come in what we actually want to
do is get them to mitigate that risk and
so that might have been a risk that's
new to us but what we'd like you to do
is mitigate that risk in a way that will
bring down our overall risk so that
while we look at it we're back to where
we were they might see themselves as
getting better or they might not believe
that what we do and as we go on you can
train this so hopefully it was a great
example for this right if all the people
didn't heartbleed was rotate their
certificates they weren't actually
getting better but if what they did
instead was say things like oh wow you
know why do I have my open SSL compiled
with heartbeats because all that I'm
doing is TCP base TLS and I don't need
heartbeats boom you just mitigated a
risk that had been there the whole time
and you got better but all that you
thought you did was fixed one
vulnerability right so taking
opportunities to respond to an impulse
with a systemic fix and these feel
really good people start to feel good
about themselves because they're
actually able to respond to hard
problems and they might tell themselves
the story that they're on the bottom and
we might tell ourselves the story were
on the top I don't know who's right but
we can train risk management and risk
response so better conversations we'd
like to have is to do hazard and safety
analysis with our business owners when
they ask if something is safe tell them
you
no help them do the analysis it's really
scary the first time because they don't
understand this you know here's how we
think about safety you tell us and you
write down the risks that you have and
if you will do that if you will write
down your wrists and advertise them up
to your management then I'll say yeah
you're good to go to with a lunch
because you understand your wrists
because now they are aware and because
they're aware they're scared and they
will act better in the next product
Persia and possibly even in this one we
find this works remarkably well so very
quick said I'm running tight on time how
do you get better because you're all
overwhelmed with work right nobody here
is underemployed you were hired you had
three things to do take care of desktops
take care of servers take care of you
know data security then you have to
worry about adversaries you have to
worry about monitoring you have to worry
about internationalization and
globalization and innovation and all of
these other things 17 things on your
plate if you juggle you know that
juggling three balls is moderately hard
juggling five balls is really hard and
juggling 17 balls is impossible if you
have 17 balls to juggle the way to
succeed is to put 14 of them on the
ground and juggle three balls and pick
your three balls wisely and pick the
ones that will give you another arm or
get you another person speak of getting
another person we're hiring we've got a
booth right inside the vendor hall I've
had to throw that in sorry so if you
take away one thing is if you want to
improve increase your value there are
two strategies to increasing value over
time one is trying to get more money
right and I would shut the cert that
that's beating your head against the
wall right getting more money to
increase your value is hard what you can
do is focus on increasing your
capabilities get better skilled right
align your work so that you have better
effort and figure out how to make your
projects effective within an
organization so they return more value
to you over time
thank you I'm not sure if I ended up
with any time for questions but no I did
so you can catch me somewhere I'll be
wandering around for a couple hours so
thank you all for your time
[Applause]