who here actually so show of hands to
start off who here actually keeps an eye
on social media for security purposes
checking Facebook at work doesn't count
all right that's a lot more than I
expected alright so by the end of this
talk the idea is that everyone should be
convinced that they should keep an eye
on social media and that's for multiple
reasons a because I'll go through sort
of some of the things that you can get
out of that and some of the reasons you
should keep an eye on it and B hopefully
I'll be introducing a new tool it's open
source that should make it really really
easy to do so so the costs are low at
the very minimum so I'm a junior at Olin
College that's the whole thing is about
300 of us now how many people have heard
of it so I always got a point out so I
hopefully get the word out a little bit
I'm also an intern at Black Hills
information and security so standard
disclaimer nothing I do is their fault
unless it's awesome which case it's all
them so all right so we're gonna talk
about a couple of people in this talk
the first guy is Mike Mike is a pen
tester you know like a lot of us here
and he's a physical pen tester a really
really good one and on the other side is
Sean his physical security I in charge
of this place which Mike has been you
know given the task of breaking into of
testing their security in case you know
recognize that this is Apple
headquarters I picked it as a case study
just because there's a lot of tweets
about Apple and it's really convenient
and also because it's a well-known
company so if anyone hears from Apple my
apologies I'm not picking on you just
you know your convenient so there's a
lot of things that Mike is gonna have to
worry about to get into this building
right and there's a lot of things that
sean has to worry about to keep Mike and
people like him out you've got things
like guards you've got things like sort
of the cover stories that might need to
get Mike that Mike will need to get in
and the things that Shawn needs to sort
of defend against to know what sort of
stories would be coming in there's the
layout that Mike will need to worry
about or you know on the other side
Shaun sort of making the layout sort of
difficult to get out so you know Mike is
really obvious when he's just wandering
around the building you're worried about
policy Mike is one reason of what sorts
of things will he will will he do that
when we can stand out or what sort of
things can he do that he can you know
fiddle around with a little bit and used
to get in there's the classic locks
right like Mike's gonna have to get past
these there's names if you can name drop
that's certainly a valuable thing on the
way in and also the classic badges how
important are they what do they look
like are there security features you
know all of these things are important
to Mike to get in so the
question comes up and where can you get
these kinds of things right you can do
it the old-fashioned way where you
actually go to Apple headquarters you go
to wherever it is you're going you know
you wander around you look for things
you maybe Google a bit but this is
really expensive it costs a lot to fly
out there it takes a lot of time and
it's sort of difficult to poke around
all this and it means that you're
actually on site it means you're at risk
right what if there's a better way to do
this and it turns out there is people
just tell you all of these things they
just tell you on the internet you don't
even have to leave your desk and this is
just a long way of saying of course
social media right people put all this
stuff up and it's available but it's
still a little difficult to get to and
that's sort of three main reasons here
the first one is variety right there's a
lot of different types of media and
there's a lot of really difficulty
instead of gathering it in any sort of a
reasonable way so you've got videos
where you don't have any text search at
all you've got pictures we're sort of
again difficult to find what the picture
is about you've got things like tweets
right where there's only 140 characters
so just doing a text search for like
Apple or Apple headquarters or apple HQ
might not necessarily net you what
you're looking for because people are
working with short character limits or
people are working with you know sort of
weird things like that it makes it very
difficult for you to get the right sort
of information you need this has made
even worse by the fact that there's just
so much of it I mean you guys have seen
social media right there's so much data
out there it's just impossible to deal
with all of it and and also there's a
third term that starts with a V that
means origin I couldn't come up with one
and the idea here the idea here is that
it's spread out right there's no one
place you can go and get all of this
data there's you know some of it's over
in Twitter some of it's in Flickr some
of it's in YouTube and it's kind of a
pain in the neck to go gather it into
one place so the thing that we found
actually ties most of this together is
location so it turns out if you're
trying to defend Apple headquarters
you're trying to break into Apple
headquarters tweets and Flickr photos
and everything like that this around
Apple headquarters is probably about
Apple headquarters big surprise there
and so it's really really useful to be
able to gather the stuff around the
headquarters the stuff that's geotag the
stuff that's actually someone has told
you it's there which means it's very
topical it's very informative it's very
relevant and that's the sort of stuff
you want to look at and so a tool
that have been working on to sort of
help with this sort of stuff is called
pushpin web we're gonna be talking a lot
about that today the basic idea of
pushpin web is that we gathered
geotagged social media data and then you
can sort of go through that you can view
it and you can use it for whatever sort
of things you're looking at using it for
which we'll get into in just a moment
whether you're on the Mike side or the
Shawn side this is a really powerful
tool this that lets you gather this data
in a way that doesn't even require you
to leave your desk so brief overview of
the talk we're just gonna talk about
what pushpin web is real quick and most
importantly what it can do for you why
it's useful I will skim over how it
works and then we'll skim over how to
get started and then we'll go for
questions at the end one of the huge
things I actually want to get from you
guys at the end of this is I have a lot
of questions about what's most useful
for you or sort of features are useful
what sort of directions we can take this
that will be most useful for you guys
all right so we'll start with what it is
so the original pushpin was written by
Ethan Romish at Black Hills information
security and then rolled in to recon n G
by Tim tomes if you haven't used recon n
G I thoroughly recommend it it's great
but the basic idea of pushman web is
that you put in sort of latitude and
longitude in a radius you just give it
an area it wants to look at and outcomes
tweets Flickr photos Picasa photos
YouTube videos showed end results and
also whatever modules you guys add so
it's designed to be really really easy
to add modules there may be 50 to 100
lines of Python and you're ready to go
you're scraping a new new API a new data
source you got whatever information you
need and it rolls right into the rest of
the framework so I've been talking about
push pin but push pin web is
fundamentally the same thing it's these
same scripts is the same data sources
but slightly different it's different in
a few ways firstly it's more flexible to
deploy it's a web application it means
you can deploy it wherever you want you
deploy it you know out on a digital
ocean server you can deploy it within
your own infrastructure wherever you
want to put it and you can visit it in a
web browser you don't have to install an
agent on every machine you know just
whatever as long as you people have web
browsers they can access it as well it's
easier to use again recon energy is a
command-line tool and that means that
there's a certain group of people who
can use it you know probably most of us
in the room and there's also a certain
group of people who can and there's a
lot of people who can't use the command
line but still need to know these kinds
of things they still need to know the
kind of information that physical
security is really reliant on and having
to push that over to you know sort of
the people who are more likely to be in
this room to the security people to the
command line people makes it a difficult
proposition right
you have the physical security people
relying on the command line type of
people and that's not a great place to
be and probably lastly and most
importantly pushpin webs meant to be
sort of fundamentally friendly right
again it's not a command-line tool it's
something in the web and it should be a
very easy thing so that anyone at the
company who needs to know the sort of
information can just go find it it
shouldn't be difficult to get and of
course you know it can be in the cloud
if you wanted to be right so web
application so if cloud is in your
mandate there it is so the bottom line
is pushpin helps you see it helps you
see a lot of things helps you see not
only the physical things that you're
used to right pictures or where the
locks are where the guards are but
social things as well I think that this
is really really critical so there's the
classic physical stuff right sort of the
locks on the building the layout of the
building kind of things you need to know
but there's also sort of an overlap
between the two right guards badges
cover stories these things aren't purely
physical constructs you know sure badges
exist in physical form but they're
carried by people and a lot of how
badges work and a lot of what happens
around badges is determined by those
people and this is really really
important because pushman can give you a
lot of view into the people side of this
that you just can't get from just taking
pictures by itself or just going to the
place and looking around and then of
course there's the purely social things
as well right you're not going to get
very many names by just standing outside
a building and taking pictures from a
distance this is the sort of thing that
pushpin can give you really really good
recon about without ever having to leave
your desk and without you know going to
site so what can it do for you perhaps
most importantly what can it do for you
so let's say you're Mike right and
you're trying to do recon on Apple
headquarters before heading in here's
the main screen of pushpin as it exists
right now you've got a sort of Apple
headquarters right there in the center
with a whole bunch of social media sort
of poked around it right and this is
just Google Maps on the top so you can
also go to satellite view which is
interesting I don't know if that's
readable up there but there's a sort of
a view of what one piece of social media
looks like right you've got the picture
there you've got the person who did it
and you've got sort of the actual
content and you can also see down here
in the corner that there's actually
multiple locations so as many things as
you need to keep track of you can the
push pin as well it's fun you can
actually go down to Street View so if
that's something you're interested in
you know you can go take a look actually
what it's going to be like from ground
as well as well there's also a ListView
so again these aren't particularly
readable but the basic idea is that
there's just a list of all of the social
media data that's been pulled from sort
of this location around Apple it's got
you know sort of big-ish data that's you
know 8,000 entries over the past little
while which is really really exciting
because it means that there's a lot of
historical data there you can comb
through and look at and then also so I
was writing this talk in in late March
and actually new data was coming in as I
was writing the talk it's not quite
real-time it's about hourly but you know
new stuff will be coming in pretty
regularly it's really exciting to
actually see things come in as you're
working on it so there's a lot of useful
information in this getting back to sort
of how this can be useful you guys is
this you know these pictures aren't
particularly visible but everything from
here on out has been pulled out a
pushpin in about half an hour of work
just fired up pushpin told us look at
Apple waited a couple minutes for to
gather data and then for about a half an
hour just poked through and see what to
see what I could find so first off
there's you know the locks on the door
if you zoom in a little bit you can see
it's a proxy card reader you could
perhaps find the model if you kept
looking as well as there's a security
guard standing right behind the window
there it's really hard to see in this
there's some of the reflection off the
window but there's a guard standing back
there you can see the badge hanging off
his belt so it's kind of interesting to
know where the guards are and that's not
necessarily something you would get from
from normal reconnaissance at least not
off Google images right it's also
interesting to note there's a guy just
sort of loitering outside the door and
the guard is standing in there with his
arms crossed behind its back like it
doesn't seem to be moving or reacting in
any way just got interesting if you want
to go loiter outside Apple apparently
that's acceptable right this is sort of
insights you can glean out of this sort
of data without really doing much like
work there's also a sign about restrooms
outside sort of interesting like maybe
you can ask them about the restrooms
maybe that's the way to get in and then
of course you know there's the the
classic everyone has to wear their badge
sign right so so on the topic of badges
like badges are difficult right where
would you get a badge so there's I you
just type in badge and there's a whole
bunch of tweets there with people who
are talking about their badges we'll
just go right down the line so here's
the first guy right there's your badge
you know it's literally the first thing
that after you put in badge more
interesting than that right you can see
actually where he works again it's a
little
got to read but he works at the Arden
Fair Mall at the retail location so
that's good to know and perhaps more
interestingly is another Apple employee
saying you know I still need to do that
apparently apples badging policies
aren't particularly strict and they sell
you know fairly easy to not rebadge on
the rig so that's interesting to know
and as well there's all these names here
right all of these are links to people's
you know Instagram people's Instagram
accounts his Twitter account up there on
the top like all of this is information
that you can be pulling then in addition
to this sort of initial information
source so next one down the line here's
two badges right and also interestingly
you can see they change color over the
years so the one on the left looks like
you know badge photo for the new year so
that must have been the last year and
then this one as of January 6 2015 is
the new Apple badge so you know that's
interesting as well and if you know full
actual nice badges aren't your speed
here's also a temporary badge this guy
said you know my friend printed me this
badge so apparently you can actually
just go in and print badges and here's a
picture of one and if that one isn't
good enough here's the second one right
and so you can do things as well like
you know since June 27 and June 27th
down there as well so it's interesting
to cross correlate things it looks like
if you want to create yourself an Apple
badge here's probably how you would do
it so going back to the things that sort
of both Mike and Sean are worried about
you can see we've hit on almost
everything here haven't hit layout very
much but just about everything else
we've seen already in you know roughly
half an hour of work sitting at your
desk you know nothing particularly
strenuous in any way so you can get
cover stories we've got the bathroom
thing you can find where the guards are
you can find what the guards are worried
about you can find sort of policy things
you got to wear your badge put loitering
near the entrances all right you can
find things like locks you can find tons
of pictures of badges all sorts of
people's names social media accounts I'm
sure if you dug deeper you find the
phone numbers everything else right so
all this data is just out there and
pushpin is a great way to aggregate it
so let's just cover real quick how it
works if you guys heard of docker it's
horrendously insecure but also really
easy so for an F we're going with it
and it makes it really really easy to
deploy anywhere
one thing that's you know really worth
emphasizing
right now this is in pretty heavy alpha
it's not very secure I wouldn't deploy
it in any kind of critical location but
right now I'm just tossing it up on
digitalocean servers and it's real great
and it will be much better in roughly a
month through the next cycle so here's
just a quick diagram of how it works
essentially all it is is just a web
server on the front with a task queue in
the back and then going out and pulling
from api's regularly as tasks come in
throwing in a database and it's ready
and available for you as you go on so
it's designed to be incredibly easy to
get started so all you have to do is
just basically clone the repository it's
it's in take a look see what the scripts
are doing for a critical step umm and
then actually just run the start script
and all it'll do is pull down a docker
image and set it up and it'll open it up
on that port and you're ready to go
that's the whole process so it's
designed to be incredibly easy to use
again if you're gonna want to put this
into you know quote-unquote production I
wouldn't put it in any place incredibly
critical yet you can you know set things
like not using default password in the
start that Sh so again it's you know
once you've got to set up basically you
just run that you add some API keys you
add the locations that you're that
you're interested in looking at and
that's it you're ready to go it'll keep
the data up-to-date it pulls hourly and
takes a look and and just come back and
check whenever you want you know put
five minutes a week intuitive just
looking through this or see what what
has come in new this week and see if
there's any risks that you guys need to
worry about as physical security so the
whole point of this is that it's really
easy to be used by anyone right like
there's a lot more people than just
command-line people that are worried
about physical security and pushman web
is designed to make it so that anyone
can actually get this data anyone can
actually look at this can actually
mitigate these risks as part of their
job without having to resort to sort of
the more arcane tools the more difficult
command-line things so the next up
things are to actually spread this out
and make it more scalable and more
secure in multiple docker containers so
right now like the the web server the
static web server is just the Python web
server not very good that's already been
fixed it's using nginx in the new
version but there's still a few bugs
you'll still a few things being worked
out this should very soon be available
is sort of a ready to roll open source
tool it's available right now if you
just want to go poke around do some
testing with it I was going to do a demo
but the Wi-Fi doesn't work very well
so unfortunately couldn't get internet
access and show it off but it's really
easy to go use so I thoroughly encourage
you to go do it I'm gonna give some
special thanks to Tim Tom's for writing
great code again a lot of the actual API
pulling code is pulled directly from
Recon ng and then just rewrapped in in a
web shell and then even rubbish resort
of getting a thrill out of this and of
course John strand and Black Hills
Information Security for paying me
through all this and keeping me off the
streets so that's me and I've actually a
few questions I'd like to ask you guys
as well as being open for questions
myself which is sort of what is most
useful about this for you guys you know
what sort of applications you see other
than your the one that I pointed out
already and then also what should I add
sort of where to go next with this of
course there's the obvious ones right
like it needs to be used in sort of a
production capability but also like
what's the most useful what should be
added thank you
[Applause]
oh I require some setup unfortunately
it'd be like five yeah so
yeah so right now it's just based on
geolocation which means that if you
don't geotag your tweets they want to
show up here so we don't actually go
scrape metadata right now all it is is
is off of the api's geolocation features
basically what it was was that going
through every picture in Flickr and sort
of scraping that metadata off of it was
was way too much work
theoretically that's definitely
something that could be done also I'd
assume that Flickr
I think Flickr does that scraping for us
actually I think any image uploaded with
that metadata automatically gets
processed by Flickr I could be wrong but
yeah so we're using the geo locate
basically you send an API query that
says give me all the photos within this
area and then it returns to the photos
so that's we're doing here
okay so one of the things are actually a
couple points on that so one of the
things that was that was down that path
right was that there's already a lot of
tools that do that in fact there's a lot
of already really specialized tools that
haven't worked on for years to do that
so it's just sort of like shrug oh I
really want to work on that that hard
and so then today ting security instead
which is a really underserved area for
this sort of thing and then the second
reason being that it looks to me like
the geolocation was a little less useful
for that because all of the tweets are
on Apple headquarters aren't necessarily
about Apple as a company a lot of
there's sort of you know Here I am at
Apple this is cool or Here I am at their
front gates which is useful in one
respect certainly that people are
willing to go there but if people aren't
willing to go there you know if you're
not Apple if you're you know some
database company that isn't you know
quite as sexy to the public then I think
it'd be a lot less useful to sort of
look at tweets in a certain location and
much more useful to look at tweets more
to sort of about your company by keyword
or by some other search that I haven't
thought about yet rather than you know
people are necessarily going to your
headquarters to be like oh man databases
are great
all right sort of event notifications
around a certain area automatically okay
nice all right
happy hour detector all right
absolutely so I actually looked at NSA
headquarters just sort of on that right
and there's nothing from within NSA
headquarters so sorry guys okay
sounds great we should talk yeah by the
way I'll be here for the rest of today
my contact information is up there just
come talking around I'm an intern so
like I don't have any of that
hi mighty stuff dude who's here yeah
anyway alright anything else
yeah so I thought about basically
looking at spikes in certain area so if
there's a lot more tweets than usual or
a lot more you know whatever than usual
in a certain area and a certain time and
that's certainly indicative of that
there's more people there there's
something interesting going on that
they're that they're you know posting
about one of the reasons I didn't do
that was just well a time but B because
right now there's no sort of external
processing it pulls down the data it
puts it in the database and then just
doesn't worry about it
there's certainly another level that I
think could be done where actually then
goes back and looks at it and does more
post-processing on the data not there
yet but certainly interesting I don't
think that there is
okay yeah okay I don't think that's in
the API but that certainly shouldn't be
too hard to add as sort of approached
post-processing feature on to this so
actually let me go back just a little
bit there's already a volume graph down
here going all the way back yeah yeah so
there's this guy down here in the bottom
that already does these volumes but that
certainly could be added as a
post-processing step where instead of
just displaying it it actually goes
through and flights it as well sons like
fun
got it okay so common place is to go out
to lunch or go to a play yeah so that's
actually a really good question I
noticed when we were or when I was
digging through the Apple data that
there was this place right here it's
like some restaurants and pub right so I
can only assume that this place has tons
of Apple employees at it all the time so
it's wondering about that but I I
couldn't think of any way to actually
flag that those employees are going
there regularly without then going back
and pulling all of the data for a
certain person which is actually another
thing that I'm thinking about doing is
basically you just feed in like a
person's name or a person's media
account and it just goes out and spiders
as much as they can and pulls back sort
of a dossier which then yeah it's
actually a really good point that you
could then fine you know wow I've found
five Apple employees and a lot they go
to this place pretty frequently yeah
that's a really good point that you
could sort of cluster them outside of
their headquarters where do you where do
the employees here commonly go