so I do I work for core security I run
security there I run strategy I do
whatever marketing tells me pretty much
that's a joke so so one of the things
that we do as we do vulnerability
management and I don't mean I don't mean
that we provide a bowl and scanner and
sell that in the marketplace instead we
look at what are the risks to your
critical assets and how can you best
secure them when you consider the
threats and vulnerabilities that you
face and that's where this the the
perspective that I'm going to give you
comes from a having done security for
years and years and years and B now
being in a company that focuses on how
do bad guys break into your networks so
they tell me that if I'm gonna be a good
public speaker I should always start
with a joke so I guess I'll give it a
shot
a duck walks into a bar walks in hops up
on the bar top bartender looks at the
duck and then he's like what the heck
are you doing dude you're a duck part
the the duck looks at the bartender and
he says I know but I'd like a glass of
milk then parts tenders like okay look
first of all it's a bar
second of all you're a duck third we
don't serve milk
get out but the duck leaves next day at
the exact same time the duck comes in
the bar hops up on the bar top the
bartender is a little ticked off now
he's like look I told you yesterday
you're a duck and this is a bar what do
you want how about a glass of milk
bartender looks at him he said I told
you it's a bar you're a duck we don't
serve milk get out the duck leaves third
day in a row he comes in this duck he
jumps up on the bar top
and the bartender looks at me says all
right we've been through this you're a
duck this is a bar
we don't serve milk if you ask for a
glass of milk I'm gonna nail your stupid
duck beak to the bar
tuck looks at him thinks about it for a
minute goes get any nails bartenders
like no I don't have any nails okay how
about a glass of milk hey it's a come on
that's a security joke that's pretty
good right he did a risk assessment okay
it's not the greatest joke in the world
but all right so the current state of
affairs in security when we think about
threat and vulnerability management
let's let's get past the duck bad guys
can go where they want and do what they
want right when's the last time you read
about somebody saying we detected an
attempted intrusion and we stopped it
yesterday we found out that the IRS
couldn't keep a hundred thousand
taxpayer identities secure right the two
days before that we found out that
CareFirst had been a had an intrusion
going on for 11 months the week before
that it was primeira the week before
that it was anthem etc etc etc the good
guys are just fixing damage right that's
all we're doing now the costs is in the
billions in one particular case that I'm
going to show you in a minute one
incident is in the billions CEOs are
getting fired boards are recognizing
that they have fiduciary risk the
president's talking about cybersecurity
in a State of the Union address as our
keynote speaker as Jim said this morning
would you have imagined a year ago that
a nation state was going to attack a
private company
in order to prevent a comedy from being
shown in a theater that may not be
exactly what happened there but publicly
anyway I mean can you we wouldn't have
even imagined that right until it
happened that's how bad it's gotten
we're not in a good place right now
if anybody thinks we are raise your hand
so I figured how did these things happen
in the first place let's talk about that
for a minute
talk about Adobe does anybody know how
Adobe got exploited how they got
breached actually it was cool it was
cold fusion but Fergie closed so they
they had a server with a known
vulnerability with a patch with an
exploit in the wild there was a
development server was never supposed to
be connected to any production networks
or the Internet
accidentally miraculously one of the
interfaces on this server got turned on
so that it was accessible via the
Internet and a production network so
then it got exploited and then the
attacker was able to pivot into the
production networks warm his way around
until he found credit card data flash
source code
cold fusion source code Acrobat source
code and harvest all that data but the
main point I want to make is that it was
a known vulnerability on a system that
was never supposed to be accessible to
anything but test and Dev
how did homeland security get breached
last summer and turned into a botnet a
known vulnerability in this case a
default password that they elected not
to change
because it was on a test system
community health systems exploited by
heartbleed six eight months something
like that after heartbleed had come out
they thought they'd patched all their
heartbleed systems according to the
Verizon dbi are something like ninety
seven percent of all incidents in 2014
we're due to known vulnerabilities with
published exploits why am i hammering
this point because the problem today is
the same problem we had ten years ago
we're still not patching systems and
what is the real cost of that targets
publicly confirmed internal cost is two
hundred and thirty six million dollars
as of their q1 SEC filing which is a lot
of money okay but the credit card fraud
estimate and this is according to the
Charlotte Business Journal the credit
card fraud estimates between one point
two and two point two billion dollars
the card replacement costs are about
four hundred million dollars the card
brands and the banks have filed lawsuits
against target to recover that money
they're sick and tired of paying all of
that costs themselves and they're tired
of retailers not securing stuff and then
the fraud and the and the card
replacement costs get fall on to the
card brands and the banks if they win
that lawsuit target's going to be liable
for as much as three billion dollars
that's a lot of money even for target
so this is a real this is this is not in
the past your boards your CEOs weren't
too worried about it
seriously when they were talking about a
few tens of millions here and there they
could fix it after the fact
but when they see themselves facing
hundreds of millions even billions you
know what it just I'm not sure if you
know but to simply defend against that
lawsuit will cost target a couple
hundred million dollars in attorneys
fees internal costs producing all the
records that need to be produced all the
time of executives in court etc etc and
that's if they're successful and they
win the lawsuit couple hundred million
dollars that money comes out of net
income that money doesn't come because
nobody plans on four hundred five
hundred six hundred million dollars
worth of operating expense that they're
just going to set aside in case there's
a breach so that's month that money is
being taken off the bottom line what's
leading to our inability to patch so now
that I've established that we have a
really big problem why can't we patch
it's not because we don't want to write
anybody in the room who doesn't want to
patch vulnerabilities I love it when I
don't get hands up anybody in your IT
operations group who doesn't want to
patch vulnerable systems but no no no no
seriously they want to patch them they
just want to do other things too right
it's not that they don't want to pack
them they have lots of competing
priorities so there was this time where
I finally was able to run a
vulnerability scan of my now
work and I worked for a hospital system
that had 32 hospitals 70,000 employees
right hundred thousand-plus end points
when you counted them all up we ran a
bone scan and we got this thing that
said we had four hundred and ninety
thousand vulnerabilities and if you
printed the report it was like that okay
so can you imagine me the C so I take
this to my guy who's the VP of IT
operations works for the CIO and I set
that down on his desk and say hey could
you patch that stuff by Monday IT
operations wants to - but they don't
know what to do with it so he says he
says to me well what you want me to do
is scan and detect all the
vulnerabilities you want me to
prioritize them somehow for you and then
you want me to patch them by Monday I
don't know how to do that I don't know
how they relate to my business this is
what he's telling me and I turned it
into bullet points for you I don't know
how they relate to my business I don't
know how to prioritize these problems
these vulnerabilities because you say
that it's a critical vulnerability but I
asked one of my team and it's sitting on
a test server we've heard this before
right
and so what happens is and then on top
of that you show up with heartbleed
screaming and yelling about how bad
heartbleed is the noisy news this is the
problem that not only security but IT
operations faces
it's a big data problem I know we've
heard it a million times right but it is
thousands of computers or more I had a
hundred and some odd thousand endpoints
imagine if you're like AT&T with over a
million endpoints
how many vulnerabilities how many
different ways can you be attacked
are they exploitable or not only
something like 5% of all vulnerabilities
get commonly exploited does that attack
pathway actually lead to sensitive data
or does it just end in a test network
this is a problem we have to solve
because otherwise you don't know what
the patch and what what the patch first
I'm not gonna say that something should
be left unpatched but the truth is it
probably will be if it's not critical
and we just have to live with that and
focus on the critical stuff remember I
said I took that stack to the so so it's
the same thing I just said but now you
can visualize the problem you're handing
that off to this IT operations guy or
whatever whoever it is responsible for
it and he doesn't know what to do with
it this is why we need to change what
we're doing we need to actually grow up
and be mature about how we deal with
vulnerability management we need to know
these are the questions we have to be
asking do we know what vulnerabilities
threaten our business I'm sure the folks
at Adobe wanted to know that that
ColdFusion server was not patched and on
a attacked pathway how about scanning
are we doing it half hazard Li are we
you know actually doing it on a routine
normal basis do we know when things
change in our networks do we know at the
top hundred top ten ten threats are in
our network do you know where your
sensitive data is and how bad guys will
get to it
where does it fit in your security
program a lot of times we don't even
know that right so this is my concept of
a security program yours might be
different but the goal is just to
support the business objectives of the
organization threat and vulnerability
management is clearly part of assessing
risk so you assess risk then you design
your control systems your security
measures and you implement them and then
you monitor them to make sure that
nothing is going wrong and finally you
have wrap all of that up in security
management which is policy and procedure
and that kind of thing and and that's
what your security program looks like
right well the thing we sometimes forget
about certainly all the breaches that we
think of forgot about is to continuously
monitor because things change test
servers get hooked up to the wrong
network new production servers get
brought online new vulnerabilities are
known etc etc so I come from a computer
engineering background system
engineering background I worked for ETS
for a long time and I like the Carnegie
Mellon maturity model so I used it as a
framework for vulnerability management
you know the concept right level zero of
means you have no program at all level
five means you're mature so something
like this non-existent you you don't
even scan maybe at best you do like
Microsoft Patch Tuesday which is going
to go away sort of all the way to I'm
doing my vulnerability management within
the context of risk to my business
so I'll talk a little bit about each
step and then you guys can grill me and
tell me how I'm wrong or or challenge me
or whatever you want to do first thing
to do is get the basics in order right
if we are non existent we need to get to
this point we need to start we need to
have some kind of vulnerability scanner
because you have to know what the
vulnerabilities on your network are this
may include adding in web application
scanners etc depending on your scenario
you have to create emerging processes of
some sort for patching it could be as
simple as we're going to patch known
Microsoft vulnerabilities once they
release their newest set of
vulnerabilities on Tuesday it could be
that simple but you've got to have some
kind of a process and hopefully you can
gain some agreement from IT operations
on that process IT operations is very
processed driven so if you show up with
a process they're likely to pay
attention to you if you show up with a
fix this they're likely to say can't do
it moving from there we want to start
actually managing vulnerabilities so as
we get more mature we're moving we're
moving along that line right so now we
want to build real processes not just a
identify vulnerability patch
vulnerability but processes that have
some sort of a driver to them that tells
me what to patch first and what to patch
second and I know compliance is a really
bad word in security but honestly at
this stage very immature adopt a
compliance framework because it gives
you something to work with them PCI
HIPAA
next I don't care what it is
pick something so that you have a place
to live within seriously because if if
you're at least patching all the
vulnerabilities with a CVS s of seven
and higher you're patching something
right yes I know you can be exploited
off of four but patching somethings
better than patching nothing whoops
sorry
I meant to hit the and that helps with
that data overload because at least now
I can sort that report by CBS s or
whatever my compliance framework says to
do right and I can create some sort of
metrics around it metrics are a good
thing if you happen to do vulnerability
management work even if you're not the C
so you can create metrics that say last
month we have four hundred and ninety
five thousand vulnerabilities of those
four hundred ninety five thousand
vulnerabilities one hundred I'm making
the numbers up one hundred and thirty
two thousand of them had a CVS s of
seven or higher that's what we had last
month we did some patching we did a new
scan now we have four hundred and eighty
thousand vulnerabilities and only a
hundred and twenty one thousand of them
have that cbss of seven or higher we're
improving
thanks Paul
the it well it's happened it does happen
yes yeah I'm talking in the abstract no
it happens it absolutely happens I could
tell you the horror stories about the
other side of this trying to get people
to recognize that there's
vulnerabilities and systems etc I won't
get some kind of a management lifecycle
going some sort of recognition that we
have to scan assess prioritize patch
measure right and do a penetration test
find out if there's an attack path into
your network I'm sure there is but as we
saw at Step three now we're starting to
get to a moderate level of maturity this
is where a lot of people want to be they
they have solved they are solving their
data overload problems at this point
they may not be getting to optimization
in the high-end risk management but
they're starting to solve the overload
problem and they're starting to do risk
based patching so risk based patching
says instead of patching because it's
the CBS s of seven because we all
because sometimes you can write to mitre
and get that score change and sometimes
your CBS s is four but there's a known
exploit and the system has a pathway to
a critical asset so patching the 7 and
higher didn't help you right so now we
want to be risk-based this vulnerability
leads to a critical asset regardless of
the score and this vulnerability over
here leads to nothing so I don't care
about that one I care about this one
that's and that's that's getting your
prioritization to a more advanced stage
right and your metrics now focus on
improving security not just measuring
how many vulnerabilities I had and do I
have less or more than I had last month
but now we want to focus our metrics on
things like this vulnerability by
eliminating it killed an attack path to
a critical asset how many how many
assets did I have with vulnerabilities
that led me to critical assets and do I
have less of those than I had last month
right that's improving security not just
patching stuff and you want your
processes to actually be measurable so
how many people worked on how many
vulnerabilities over what period of time
things like that at this point you start
using pen testing for validation
so a IT ops guy says yep I patched that
and I broke that pathway so now you come
back and you get with your red team guys
or your external pen testers whoever
does that work for you and say could you
check could you validate that let's
prove that we actually fix that problem
that make sense
as we start thinking about the attacker
instead of ourselves we're really
starting to get to a an advanced level
of maturity not everybody is going to do
this necessarily that's okay it's not
the end of the world but if you do you
start doing things like continuous
processes all right so instead of I
scanned this week I patch this week I do
my metrics this week I rest on this week
and then I start the whole thing all
over again instead it's going to be
something more like I am running a
continuous set of activities I'm
scanning patching measuring all the time
on a routine basis and every time
somebody says I patched stuff that kicks
off a new cycle of scanning and
measuring instead of doing it in the IP
scan on Monday sort of way of doing life
that process now ties together security
and operations IT operations it's not
two separate processes anymore it is
security identifying the vulnerabilities
sending a data file off to IT operations
IT operations receiving it in that
kicking off a process with NIT
operations to patch the most critical
things immediately and we start picking
on other threat vectors besides just our
network right up to this point we've
probably only dealt with network threats
but there's a lot of other threats or
social engineering there's Wi-Fi there's
mobile devices there's web de network
there's web develop there's all kinds of
threat vectors that you need to take
into consideration so we're going to
start adding those in
hopefully you can contain the social
engineering at the client device right
away that would be ideal but if you
can't it would be really good to know
that that once the you know so what
happened at primeira anthem and probably
a care first from what we know is that
they had a social engineering attack
using typos squatting that enabled the
client machine to be compromised and the
client machines had they were
compromised down to a operating
system-level and then they had pathways
to servers inside those networks and the
databases did not have multi-factor
authentication and in place see how that
so we had a vulnerable browse we had a
vulnerable user vulnerable browser
vulnerable operating system and then we
had weak authentication security on our
database and that's how they did it it
well if you had done what I just talked
about which is under stuck her
social engineering was not a valid
threat vector or if it was then breaking
it at the operating system level of the
client machine or enabling multi-factor
authentication on the database for
privileged access any of those things
would have broke in that attack pathway
but you didn't understand how all that I
don't mean you guys I mean the the
people that happened to didn't
understand how all that stuff gets
strung together in order to compromise a
database and now we're moving into
formalized penetration testing that
shows us that that can happen to us
right
if you get to this really if you get to
this point you're really good most
people won't but if you do you have now
built business goals into your
vulnerability management program so you
understand that your business has a goal
of growing same-store revenue
year-over-year and specific IT assets
are involved in supporting that business
goal so those are going to be more
important to me than sharepoint over
here that's not involved in this
business goal right so I want to support
my business strategy by making sure that
I reduce the risk to the things that
support my business strategy first I
want to make sure that I've aligned what
IT security and the business are doing I
want to make sure that all threat
vectors are considered now so I named
off most of the threat vectors I want to
make sure I'm looking at all of them now
not just limiting myself to let's say
social engineering and network because
that's pretty common but what if I have
a you know sequel injection flaw in my
web server and it's supporting database
and they can get in that way and I
haven't considered web to network I've
only looked at the social engineering
client Network attack as an example or
mobile attacks or you know I need to
look at all of those Wi-Fi
man-in-the-middle etc and vulnerability
metrics those metrics we've been
building over time they now become risk
indicators if I'm not patching so I've
got us I've got this business goal of
same-store revenue growth year over year
and I have cash management systems that
are part of supporting that business
goal and the number of vulnerabilities
and attack paths on my cash management
systems are going up not down I have a
risk to the
business at that point right and that is
the kind of thing that actually makes
non IT people pay attention so I'm just
going to show you a couple of ideas of
what it can look like in practice it
takes work it takes products it takes
processes and it takes people to do this
I'm not going to advocate any of those
things to you but I'm going to show you
some of the ways that this that that it
could look like for you
building prioritize the tak paths into
your network so this is a web
application server with that sequel
injection flan and from there directly
connected to it as a database that has
an operating system vulnerability that I
can get to this thing and I don't get
along
etc etc and that pathway leads me to
this critical business asset let's say
it's your credit card database that
seems kind of simplistic considering
some of the things we've seen lately but
but let's say it is right so so
understanding what this attack path
looks like is important to understanding
where where and how to protect yourself
all of these are vulnerable systems but
only these lead me to here so those are
the ones I want to worry about first
because that makes a significant
measurable risk difference I want to
continuously monitor why do I want to
continuously monitor because because how
many examples did I give you of people
who were breached by changes they didn't
know about or vulnerabilities they were
unaware of
so static one-time scams static one-time
Network diagrams are not enough and by
the way your network
the way you diagram it and the way IT
operations diagrams it not how it looks
to the attacker so you might want to
consider really the thing you might want
to consider this because this is how it
looks to your bad guy you guys are
laughing oh man my slides aren't you
alright and the last thing and I think I
have about five minutes right the last
thing is you want to connect with the
business you want the business to
understand that there are critical
business assets that have to be
protected and that can be protected I
just had dinner last week with a guy who
used to be a senior vice president of a
multi-billion dollar business unit of a
large healthcare system a friend of mine
had dinner with him he's retired
semi-retired he does it comes the
consulting thing now and I said you know
our perception and security is that CEOs
aren't all that worried about or aware
of the threat and the risk and he said
no that's not true but they think that
their security guys are taking care of
it so you need to connect with the
business and make it clear that that's
not always the case
so the last thing I'll and and I believe
that we can make this all these slides
available if not you guys can all reach
out to me and I'll give them to you no
matter what this is how you figure out
where you want to be and what you want
to do and then you set about doing it
whether you're a practitioner or a
manager or a director or a security
executive you figure out ways to move
yourself along that maturity model
because it makes things better for your
business and at the end of the day it
actually results in some really cool
things like more operational efficiency
if you're figuring out what if you've
figured out which priority which
vulnerabilities are a priority and
you've solved that data overload problem
there's some operational efficiency
there right because all of a sudden
instead of sorting spreadsheets you're
focusing on taking care of risk to the
business which is what you're paid to do
just to give you and of course that
bottom line right I'm afraid to touch
this now but that bottom line you're
much less likely to be these guys all
right however much time we have I'll
take questions two minutes so that means
probably one other than Paul's question
about sending emails to mitre yeah
right so security and IT offer essential
EIT delivery to the business right so I
was just having that conversation this
morning actually it's a great question
so the if you think about this there's a
point so if i if i patch something and i
create a problem for the business that's
a risk if i don't patch something and it
creates a problem to the business it's
also a risk and what you need to do is
determine when one risk outweighs the
other one not easy to do but this is
where we need to start involving the
business in the conversation saying if i
patch the server you're going to lose
some functionality however i will reduce
the risk of a bad guys stealing credit
cards which one of those ways higher and
lower for you that's the that's the
question that has to be asked and that's
in somebody else's hands but you need to
put it in the right hands that's the
real and give them a real honest-to-god
measurement of risk not not a throw my
hands in the air
fudge sky is falling but look this
servers on an attack path to this yep
that helped great I think that's the end
of my time thank you for paying
attention thank you for putting up with
my slides if you want the slide deck let
me know give me a way to recontact you
and i'll send it to you