security analyst with OpenDNS I
previously worked as a threat analyst at
NASA protecting the NASA against threats
for about five years or so I took a
little break and with the mandiant for
about a year and then I went back to the
NASA sock but I left for OpenDNS because
I it's amazing the company so things I
like to do just so you know I like to
ride motorcycles I make music and I like
cats I have two of them so this is about
building an intrusion detection system
in in a virtual server space to protect
other systems that don't really have
protection actually to offer monitoring
and detection more than protection but
I'll get into all of this all right so
cloud hosting is really cheap and easy
you can set up a server for about five
to ten dollars a month or twenty if you
want to spend it it's you can have a
server set up within a couple minutes
and have a website in the case of what
I'm looking at set up quickly you can
also set up other servers too
the problem is that security options are
limited just looking at the providers
that I'm going to be working with today
the options are limited to reporting of
vulnerability reading about how to
secure a server and just reading other
documentation but they don't really
provide anything in the way of
monitoring order detection so what kind
of people would do this sort of thing
I'd do it you might do it if you have a
good long week and nothing to do but
probably your average website owner is
not going to be interested in doing this
they just want to set their side up and
usually they're going to forget about it
if they use content management systems
they're gonna probably leave it and
forget about updating or not even think
about it
why bother during this well obviously
well it's kind of fun and security is
really important
using data from fish tank which is a
website that is run at Open DNS people
can submit fishes they believe that our
fishes and people the community a fish
tank can vote on them
so over the life of fish tank or at
least to the last database refresh I
don't know what that has happened but
there's been there have been over three
million submissions to fish tank there
were total of 1000 1 billion 1.7 million
basically fishes verified as valid at
the time of this snapshot which was last
week about we can half ago there were
thirty thousand seven hundred
sixty-eight online valid fish that means
that they were verified as valid and
currently online at that time I took
that data and I did some processing on
it and look at the unique domains there
were over 10,000 unique domains with
these of these 30,000 and those were
attributable to over two thousand unique
asns so looking at those asns this is
kind of a pain to look at but this is
just a text file of the SNS so I want to
look at a different way to put it into a
graph so you can see there these are
kind of the the worst providers that
have phishing content whether it's free
hosting or compromised hosts or actual
registered domains we see a lot of stuff
obviously it's Cyrus one PayPal fishing
and things like that
GoDaddy is a big big one they also put
some as far as I've been able to tell
they put so they have some servers
through Cyrus ones so there may be some
cross-contamination looking at the oh I
forgot I did that looking at the
registrar's just to see who the top
registrar's for domains maybe this
doesn't indicate which ones are
compromised domains or which ones are
registered for more targeted
spearfishing type things but we have
GoDaddy is most common of the fishtank
data it's pretty cheap you can see the
network solutions is in there that's
more expensive but the I would imagine
it may be some targeted stuff might use
a more expensive option to look more
legitimate but the idea is that domains
are a constant are often compromised
because for fishing usually
fishing is very deep inside the site and
the host owner doesn't know about it so
that's one reason you want to might want
to protect the server
additionally sites are just hacked in
this case you might know this the hack a
lot sooner and fix the problem but the
fishing situation you usually don't know
about it for a while but looking closer
at content management systems which are
the most common ways of compromising the
site and specifically looking at
WordPress sources where I'm going to be
using today in my demonstrations the
WordPress has a lot it's up to version
for something but it's got a there's a
database you can look at all the
vulnerabilities that have been reported
so far and this doesn't even look into
the plugins plugins are a great way for
an attacker to get into a site and
compromise it which I'll also be showing
you in my demonstration you can use tool
like WP scan this is specifically for
WordPress it can enumerate you're a
wordpress instance and tell you what
version is running what plugins it's
running and hopefully maybe some other
stuff I'm going to show you a really you
probably all know this a really
high-level view of how it works when a
visitor visits a website so you have
your cloud which is just a network it's
your hosting provider up in this case
and you've got your ISP and you have the
internet which we know is made of cats
so the person the visitor of your
website is just gonna they want to visit
it and this super super simple view is
that they go they go there and that's
that's how it looks
a hacker version very similar you have
your attacker and ISPs maybe their proxy
maybe they're going it doesn't matter
how they get there they have an endpoint
before they pass over to the website
visitors go there and we don't have any
clue that anything happens so I'm gonna
be showing you a hack of the slider
revolution WordPress plug-in about a
year and a half ago I think there was a
major vulnerability with it and it it's
a little plugin that makes it so you it
can present some pictures like a little
slide on your WordPress page and a lot
of people use it but what we're going to
be doing is exploiting
local file include where I'm gonna be I
have this domain JP or calm which I
registered for this demonstration I'm
going to be trying to get the WP admin
config file which contains my database
username and password for WordPress you
shouldn't be able to get this but the
local file and could let you do this so
this is the text I'll be pasting in and
also I have a snort rule that I will be
using to to catch this just to show you
this is my my dashboard for my WordPress
domain and I'm running running an older
version of WordPress and it doesn't
really matter I'm not working on
exploiting WordPress itself I'm going to
exploit revolution slider this is the
vulnerable version here that I have
installed and I did it WP scan of my
system that's kind of hard to read them
sorry but you can see down at the bottom
got rep slider I think I actually yeah I
got Rev slider it doesn't tell me what
version but I can like well there's
something from you look for as an
attacker I have this one video here
because it was this easier in this case
to do a video but I'm opening a web
browser I'm going to JP or comm and this
is this is actually hosted at Hostgator
right now I'm pasting in that field that
you saw before and I'm gonna press enter
and when I do what I would like to see
is a download of a text file but I got a
non acceptable message a message from
mod security which is an Apache module
to do some security features so mod
security protected us that's great I
didn't know that Hostgator had that they
don't announce anything about any kind
of security feature they have but we
don't have the idea that it actually
happens it wasn't successful that
doesn't mean it's not nice to know it
someone tried for a moment us take a
sidestep and look at the neighborhood
that I live in with this domain sitting
on host Gators Network I've got this
domain JP or calm and looking at it I've
got an a record my IP address basically
if where JP or com lives is this dot 97
address which I'll refer to a few times
as I demonstrate you can see some DNS
requests this is a while ago this is
needs
and stuff and it's through the open DNS
Network these spikes so looking at it
another way here's here's my domain and
here's the a record you can see there
are some name servers or the top is at
Hostgator name servers so whenever
someone types in their browser
J furie com it goes up the chain through
DNS and eventually gets the hostgator
and hostgator says it exists at 97 but
who else is at this IP address well this
is a list you don't have to read it you
can't read it too small but this is a
list of all the domains on my shared
hosting that I pay I think 11 dollars a
month for I don't know who any of these
domains are maybe I do but I don't maybe
someone else is interested in attacking
them I haven't really heard much about
people attacking shared hosting
laterally moving once they did like from
the one site to another getting to the
base operating system but I don't know
it's just that I'm just sitting there
with all these people also what else is
at this IP address doing the nmap scan
of the IP I can see there's a lot of
filtered ports there's some open ports
there's at least something for
exploration for a board attacker maybe a
dedicated attacker but I think you could
just explore this quite a bit so talking
about the classic model of intrusion
detection I have this boring corporate
network diagram that I worked up maybe
this is kind of theoretical but it's
it's practical I've seen it before in
environments you have your router you've
got IDs systems in between different
firewalls things to segment and you've
got a mail server the web server
everything is under your control you can
see when an attack happens if you have
the right signatures for it you can also
get log files protecting your Active
Directory all that stuff that's great
you've got full control hopefully but
the cloud model the security perimeter
is averting a lot of people are putting
their servers out there not just web
servers like I'm showing in this example
a lot of people are printing becoming
anything out there and you may want to
protect it in this case I'm just showing
protecting web servers but you can
protect a lot of other things but what
I'm doing here I have an IDs @ly node
it's a
private server service it's a Linux
system and I'm able to I have control on
it so I was able to install whatever I
want and I paid no $20 a month for that
thing and the idea is up going to be
sending traffic to JP or comm the
Hostgator through the ids aligner using
some proxying which is old news and i'll
get into how the proxy works and how
dangerous it kind of is
so but this is the basic idea well I
note is the dot one eight nine address
so I'm gonna show you a little bit about
the lye noticed it's running Apache
proxy and I'm doing some mitigation on
the proxy with the IP tables and fail to
ban and I'm also running to snort for
monitoring and detection I'm doing TCP
dump for packet capture I'm running some
other tools which I think I get into
this is my control panel when I log into
lino this you can see I'm running a
Debian just kind of a low-end system it
doesn't have much going on I've actually
used what I'll be showing you to monitor
multiple sites and services but I
imagine if you wanted to do this as a
service you would probably want
something be here or you'd want an
actual system somewhere which kind of
takes it out of the cloud ID ID idea but
this this works for me for the
configuration talk about the DNS seems
like I've been talking about DNS but a
whole bunch but I have to keep going
with this this is the another kind of
high level or review but this is the
basic routes a current route user says
where's jpoa com we have Tron guy who
represents the Internet
he says it's over at dot 97 that's that
Hostgator address and then they go to
the website well in lion ode I could
figure a DNS record so this this updates
line owns name servers their public name
servers and says JP or e.com can be
found if I tell the registrar that can
be found at this address 189 so that
that sets that up and then going into my
registrar this is where I actually
purchased JP or calm down at the bottom
you can see I've got Hostgator as my
name servers right
I should change this I mean anyone who's
dealt with web servers knows how this
works but change it to lino calm their
name the servers and within almost
instantaneous but usually they say 12 to
24 hours it's updated and the whole
internet knows that this is where JP or
comm is so the modified route won't look
like this
they say where's this website Internet
says it's over at 189 that's the line on
hosts and they're gonna pass through but
a little slow on the animation here
sorry they're gonna pass through the VPS
the IBS virtual private server and head
over to the Hostgator address and in my
example I'll show you I'm gonna switch
from Hostgator to digitalocean on the
fly but we'll get there the actual
website location this is the Hostgator
control panel and we zoom in we can see
I've got some add-on domains option this
Hostgator account I have a I have a
domain there doesn't really matter what
it is but you'll see it in a second and
all out on domains become subdomains so
you'll just you'll see that and when I
show you that the configuration but the
files live in that that domains JP ory
location I won't talk about the open
proxy that I'll be using open proxies
are really bad for the Internet in a
dedicated attacker or not dedicated
attacker can connect in to the open
proxy which are constantly being scanned
for and found very frequently and use it
to pivot off and then hack some site or
do whatever kind of activity they want
and it looks like it came from my system
so that's a really bad thing you
shouldn't run it open proxies this is
just the initial proof of concept of
this project and I've got some
mitigations in place which you'll see
let's put an intrusion detection system
in there so I'm going to show you a demo
of how its configured and I'm it's a
little technical but hopefully you know
can't you okay with that I have some
cheat sheets or a cheat sheet over here
for me to make a little quicker of it up
so I have a some shell scripts that log
me into my servers
this is me logging into the IDS at the
very top window you can all see that
okay
looking at the they attach the config
file I have I'm listening on port 80 and
443 80 is for now I'm just working with
port 80 HTTP traffic because most the
attacks gonna be over HTTP but I'll get
in other protocols later any thing going
to JPY comm port 80 will be sent to this
sub domain this is what I mentioned
before JP or e about absent fifth column
I also have a 443 a SSL site or the I'm
using snore be to look at alerts as they
happen then you'll see that too and then
looking at this is the proxy comm file
this proxy requests on is what makes it
so that it's an open proxy so that's
that's bad but in the case of this it's
good and I'll show you I pee tables what
the rules I'm going to use I'm not gonna
go too much into IP tables but let me go
in is more privileged user right now I
have no rules
I have some rules from last night I was
testing so
I have no rules and my IP tables I'm
gonna add some I'm going to add an
output and input these will allow
traffic to and from the Hostgator
servers not the dot 97 I mentioned
before and also a reject at the end that
will reject all port 80 traffic to
anywhere else making it so it's not
usable open proxy it's still able to be
checked as I will show so I'm adding the
output chain and I'm adding the input
chain and then they reject and then if I
list it again you can see I've got I'm
allowing HTTP traffic in and out and
rejecting the rest of it so it's kind of
difficult to follow the line breaks but
and then I'm gonna start Apache and
we're going to test the open proxy I'm
gonna show you how it how it works first
I'm gonna run a streaming TCP down
possession
well it'll be found or easy but you'll
just see stuff happen and I'm gonna tell
net on the bottom window is my local
system right here I'm not connected to
another server outside I'm gonna tell
that to JP or column port 80 and I'm
gonna actually try to get what I'm
supposed to be able to get at this sub
domain press ENTER a couple times in a
second we'll see it passed through you
can see down here at the bottom proudly
powered by WordPress I got the index
page and that's great that's how that's
the way I want it to be but let's try
again real quick we'll tell that again
and we're gonna try to use my tapas
sorry
we're gonna use my telling that session
to that's gonna cancel me out okay tell
it again we're gonna try to use this
Telenet so get the index from the otter
calm maybe we wait and we got this error
so actually we didn't get the error I
didn't make my iptables is not in effect
one second demo God strike like I my
medium I reject again
sorry about this
let's try that
she sleep it up on the top
damnit well normally it blocks it I'm
not gonna worry about that because
that's not the point of this talk the
demo gods is just not working with me
today I've been having good luck lately
but anyway I'm gonna go ahead and attack
my site so we can actually see it in
process first I'll show you the rule
that I'm using I have one snort rule in
place at the moment is a local rule I'm
watching for any Content going to been
looking for this kind of thing right
here this is what I pasted in before the
local file include and if I look in in
this directory I've got just as barnyard
to waldo file i'm gonna have unified
files up here a snort is running it
saves it to a binary file and then i'm
use bar nard to barnyard to insert that
into a database which will over you so
I'm going to start snort I have a script
that I wrote that does that for me
and
open proxy things bother bothers me
sorry
alright I'm going to connect in on the
bottom window again to the IDS I need to
start a TCP dump session that will save
peek packet capture so I have a script
it's go save to a file called Hostgator
pcap in the temp directory that's
running I'll show you the last alert
that we had that's this is gonna be
snore B which I'll be logging into in
just a moment and while that's waiting
so this is JP or e.com hosted on
Hostgator here's the snore B dashboard
over here you can see these are my
alerts I've done a lot of testing on
this I did this last night got something
from yesterday so that's the last of our
alert that we have though so over here
on JP or EECOM I'm actually gonna paste
in that same thing that showed you
before and we get that modsecurity error
that we showed before now going back
over to here I'm gonna stop TCP dump I'm
gonna stop snort and let's take a look
you can see I've got a unified file
right here it's 621 bytes so it's got
some data in it I'm gonna run barnyard
which is going to take that unified file
and insert it into a sequel database it
found something it shows me what it
found right there I can go ahead and
quit barnyard real quick I would go back
over here and refresh snort II go back
to the alerts seems to be the best way
to do it and we've got a new one does
not am because my clock this server
whatever looking at the alert you can
see this is B this is the alert that's
fired and snort but we don't know if it
was successful or not if we have our
system set to email us or contact us we
know that someone tried to do something
but we don't know what happens so we
need to look at actual actually look at
the pcap file so i'm going to copy that
pcap file to
system I'm going to exit the server at
the bottom now I'm back on my local
system and I'm going to use SCP to get
it
thank you it's like there's no oh yeah
thank you and looking at this hostgator
pcap okay we can filter it on HTTP
traffic
[Music]
that's actually the initial get of that
I did before let's go down to the bottom
here
we get them not acceptable well this is
part of it in in this traffic I can see
that they aren't successful there's one
of these lines is going to have the mod
security error in it I will show you
that because it's not as exciting as the
next one where I'm actually successful
attacking it so quit player shark
and now we're going to go back to the
demo go back to the slides
alright so we're gonna try another
hosting provider this is this time we're
using digital ocean and we're gonna
succeed in the attack in this case I am
changing it to digital ocean the changes
are going to be made on the IV s and the
traffic will flow the same way I'm not
gonna change the registrar that's going
to stay the same and I have setup this
is my digital ocean control panel I have
set up a local DNS zone telling digital
oceans name servers where I where my
domain is it doesn't matter cuz I didn't
actually change the registrar's DNS I
just did it just because but this is the
address we will be working with I'm
actually gonna be pasting this directly
into my Apache config file to proxy and
over so the dots order to is the address
so here's another demo this is a little
bit shorter demo but we will actually
see the attack I'm going to modify IP
tables now I don't have to flush the
akha tables but I'm going to and I'm
gonna add the stuff for digital ocean
the dot 32 and output input and then the
reject for everything else I could just
keep adding rules though as I have more
sites to protect or monitor now looking
at IP tables up I just left it
sorry about this
this time I'm gonna show you it not
gonna flush it
all right I have this input-output 4.32
and the reject for everything else on
port 80 and I will modify my Apache
config file I'm gonna change this this
mmm is going to go now to the IP address
for digital ocean
and then I need just restart Apache and
then looking over kind of the bottom
window I'm gonna log into my digital
ocean sorry digital ocean server
it's a Linux system hang ten no I'm
paying five dollars a month for this
thing but I have full root access to it
I so I think I've secured it pretty well
and I'm stoked but I'm running the same
WordPress same revolution slider plugin
I'll just show you real quick the patch
a config file this is a more normal
looking file no proxying going on so I
have anything going into this IP address
I could have also set this up as a
domain name but the port 80 will go look
for the files in there www JP or e and
then I'll show you real quick the files
in here if this is the WordPress stuff
this is in my files that I'll be
accessing so I'm going to exit the
digitalocean tope actually mean to start
apache before i need to exit let's
starting apache on digital ocean so
it'll serve up those files for me and i
can go ahead and exit that now and now
we're going to run
we're gonna run snort again starting
snort on the top on the bottom I'm going
to connect into my IDs again and go in
as root and I'm gonna start the pcap
file for digitalocean it's been
digitalocean dot pcap which we'll look
at after I'm done so that's running and
then we're going to visit Jai peur comm
again you can see this one that was a
digital ocean so we're passing through
and going to a different server I'm
going to paste in the exact same
as before now this time when I press
ENTER we will actually see it successful
it's going to exploit reps letter and we
get this pop-up asking us to download a
file it's going to save that file and
then we'll take a look at it
this right here is sorry for the second
though you can kind of read it you can
read it okay okay you can see here's my
database username right here WordPress
my password is hello there so this is a
great this is great for the attacker
they've got my database information it's
a good starting point to compromising my
website now as a website owner we don't
have any idea that it happened except in
this case we do because we we are
watching it with snort so let's go back
to the server stop snort I'm gonna stop
the TCP dump packet capture and I'm
going to start barnyard and it will grab
it windows it will grab that file again
the newest one it actually it keeps a
database of what it has seen and what it
hasn't seen so it found them an alert
I'll stop barnyard and I'm gonna grab
that tactic capture file in a second
I'll show you the alert I'm exiting on
the bottom window is my local system
again I'm gonna SCP that digital ocean
key cap to the desktop
and then I'm going to go back over here
to the snore be refreshing
okay and then going over to the alerts
we have a new one 907 a and this just
happened and it's the exact same that
has the previous one we know something
happened we don't know if we're
successful so of course we have to have
packet capture so let's go ahead and
look at that pcap file that I just got
and this should be a little bit cleaner
to look at following this stream we can
see this is the get request at the top
up here and then down below we got 200
okay message and then we got we can see
that they got that WordPress
configuration file
there's the databases password know that
we need to go in and change our
WordPress information and update our
server and maybe wipe the whole thing
actually it's probably the best option
so that's showing that and showing the
visibility into it
and so potential problems with this
whole configuration it messes up visitor
statistics quite a bit
looking at the Hostgator control panel I
got a double your stats or whatever this
was I can't remember I've got these
visitors at the top it's kind of small
but it's the line owed host and the
other two hosts are me doing some other
stuff before I had it all configured as
liner host as the primary visitors so a
lot of people might be upset by that
not knowing where their visitors
visitors are coming from so if you're
doing this as a service you might want
to modify or whip something up on the
IDs you to get the proxy logs or some
kind of logs to show proper stats this
video is a video here they will show
kind of looking at those log files I'm
just watching the log files and I'm
gonna be visiting my domain it's kind of
way because you can see it you can see
that 67 the 204 address was me visiting
that works but when I tried the same
attack I'm doing that I'm gonna do the
local file include it's actually it
looks like I came from Lion owed so
there's some work to be done on this
part that's the download right there
looking at it you can see this dot 189
to the dot 132 I guess this is going to
digitalocean
but I so there's some problems with the
stats and people logs you might have to
program that other protocols I've played
around with with HTTP most in most cases
I mean pretty much all cases I've seen
it with watching stuff on the intrusion
detection systems at previous
organizations it was all or it wasn't
sequel data it was HTTP but to web
servers HTTP but you could watch sequel
data in a slider to talk about future
research that would be able to capture
more stuff like that but I've actually
put a certificate on the IDs which sort
of man-in-the-middle myself to watch the
traffic but I think that'd be a bad idea
you were offering this as a service you
would just want the HTTPS to pass
through and hope that someone isn't
trying to do something through HTTP the
open proxy I'm using IP tables as you
saw to to do some mitigation on that I'm
doing some other protection stuff like
failed to ban here you can see I blocked
myself from my server while doing some
testing that's my that was my home
address at the time and I was blocked
for an hour 10 minutes kind of annoying
future research what I'd like to do what
would be more robust is to have some
public name servers almost like your
hosting provider hosting provider review
we're all situated to actually build
this system and they probably should do
something like this to offer it as a
service and he sent stuff through a
router through the IDs and out to the
website and no proxy needed proxies are
good idea even more future research
which I find much more exciting is to do
this process in in addition to honey
pots and distributed honey pots all over
the place and you maybe have a server
that is watching reporting on everything
you can send the idea to look at the
server too that way you get some more
insight into what kind of traffic you're
seeing on these honey pots I think also
especially Khan pod which is like a I
believe it Swiss takeda systems it would
be really interesting to see the kind of
network traffic so this would be fun I
think that's that's the end of it I
don't you don't have any questions yeah
here
well his CloudFlare they do that for DNS
of I think they initially did this with
the proxy I've heard I don't know that
for sure but they they're just doing the
DNS traffic and you know the block
Dawson temps I don't know about about
this specific thing I haven't I didn't
see it so I thought well I'll try to do
it see if it happens
I can see that yeah they wouldn't they'd
have they'd have no idea they would just
see your traveler coming from one place
so yeah yeah yeah it's me
and you had a question yeah basically
you had a question in the back I didn't
know that was hostgator they did that
that was hostgator the hostgator have
modsecurity as part of their their
security you know and i didn't configure
it on the digitalocean host because i
wanted to actually be successful in the
attack
yeah I know that would be amazing I
don't know what there are and since I'm
not developer of yet at least but I'm
working on it but it's a that'd be an
awesome project
it'd be great great as he wouldn't have
to have a separate server just install
it right in your place but of course in
the case of Hostgator you don't have
access unless you pay a lot of money for
your own servers you don't have access
to that level I can't turn I could
actually I I checked in so I could have
them turn modsecurity off for me but I
have to call support yeah oh go ahead
I look at mr. previously at my work at
NASA I would watch all the I would not
one of my main jobs was looking at all
the fishing females that were reported
to the sock and and fighting to mange
the block and things like that and I
would see so many worth compromised
domains of course there were free ones
like Rick's and dine dienes subdomains
and that stuff but then my current work
at Open DNS I do the same kind of thing
I look a lot of I don't look at the
phishing emails because we don't get
reports of that but I look at
compromised domains constantly and it's
almost always I don't know a percentage
but not ninety something percent people
people's sites they didn't know they
were compromised are blocked by us
automatically or by an analyst or a
security researcher and they don't they
just don't have no idea they were
compromised so it I figured there's got
to be some way that people could protect
or at least see when they're compromised
and have some proof and have some way to
tell who did it I I imagine most hosting
providers aren't going to do this this
is more of a service kind of offering if
if someone wanted to do this and charge
customers an extra fee they could be bad
but as I said before the average website
owner of selling widgets is not going to
be interested in knowing this yeah but I
feel like it has a lot of room for
exploration
what's that I don't know I don't have an
answer yeah any other questions all
right well thank you very much for
[Applause]