okay well thank you all for coming back
and staying for the best part of the
symposium as you know to keep people
around we always pack the best to last
unless you were to speaker earlier in
the day and we have to make sure we keep
everyone here throughout the entire
thing but no I think this is a really
interesting and exciting topic that
we're going to be talking about today
again dealing with one of Purdue giant
leaps of securing the giant Leafs and
health longevity and quality of life
we've got for hopefully interest for
hopefully differing perspectives to
point out issues and we I've asked the
panelists to give some brief statements
for five to ten minutes so there's
plenty of time for lively discussion
because I know myself I prefer either
when I'm on a panel or listening to want
the discussions always generate the most
interesting things and people prepared
slides but everyone seems to have a good
perspective on what we're going to talk
about and so we'll just start by having
Jim Ralph like so yeah yeah I was gonna
say I want to make sure I was getting it
in the right order Jim rouse talk who's
the chief security officer for CVS
health thank you very much
so I share our actually just stepped
down from the chair of the health
information sharing analysis center to I
sac and as such I've had a broad
perspective on health care now I'm a
reformed banker I have to admit that so
joined healthcare about six years ago
and I'm still kind of learning the
nuances I guess of applying
cybersecurity practices to healthcare
the biggest challenge that healthcare as
an industry face is that HIPAA has a
dominant presence throughout all of
healthcare and that's generally a good
thing
Hiep is pretty light from a security
standpoint
it's primarily about privacy so when I
compare it to financial services which
is a little heavier on the cyber side
the biggest challenge that we as an
industry face in healthcare specifically
healthcare providers is that security is
thought of as a compliance thing meaning
that if you comply with the regulatory
requirements all is good and that there
was a time where that was absolutely
true that time was several decades ago
it's not true at all today
and so being compliant with regulatory
requirement is a critical path but it's
not the end game and it's not sufficient
and what that means is if you think of
the alternative what's the alternative
to a compliance based security program
it's a risk driven security program well
what is that well that's studying and
understanding intelligence about threat
actor tactics and then changing and
adjusting your controls based on that so
I work for a large enterprise today we
change our controls in terms of our
control procedures 1.5 times a day
that's an indication of resiliency for
an enterprise today there was a time
where never changing your controls was
thought of as resilient so I'll tell a
story my first day in cyber security you
know it was a long time ago
please don't rub it in my first day in
cyber security I actually was a C so now
I was an IT professional for a long time
but that was back when that I worked for
American Express they didn't have a C so
so they said oh we need a C so you know
you do it you know and so my first day
on the job I'm looking at my calendar on
the second day there's this meeting with
the OCC now I knew enough to know that
OCC is officer of the control office of
the controller of the currency right
these are this is a heavy-duty regulator
right the title of the meeting was a
presentation of the information security
strategy for American Express
it's when it dawned on me that's why I
was selected as the see so for that
point of time because my boss the CIO
didn't want to give that presentation so
I had 24 hours to prepare a presentation
without being cybersecurity
professionals
now fortunately I had bumped into a guy
who's a heavy cybersecurity guy wrote a
bunch of books named Mark Mirko I and he
gave me a piece of paper he said when
you get well over your head call this
number now I was pretty cocky I looked
there that's like I I'm not gonna need
that I just stuck it in my pocket never
thought another thing about it until I
saw that calendar entry for the OCC I
realized I was well over my head so I
immediately pulled out the number and
called Steve Katz Steve Katz with the
first C so ever in in ever like ever for
a Citibank and he was consulting at the
time and this 20 years ago and I called
him up I said Steve I got this meeting I
got a present to the OCC I'm you know
the new CEO for American Express he said
don't worry I'll be right over
so I said well let me give you the
directions click well sure enough 45
minutes he comes over he comes over with
two other people he introduces me to him
there are two other C cells from other
financial service firms that compete
with American Express they dropped
everything that they had to do that
afternoon and they were gonna help Steve
help me prepare for this presentation so
they walk in my office one of them goes
right to my workstation didn't have
laptops back then so it goes my
workstation says what's your password
I'm thinking this is an initiation right
they're testing movie that security guy
right they said no you idiot I'm doing
your presentation for you I got to get
into PowerPoint so I can put it together
right so literally they spend an hour
and a half going through all the papers
on my desk in my office you know I had
four different security functions I was
all bringing together into one and they
prepared the entire presentation I did
nothing when when I'd start to offer
well I think that they said shut up
they read the whole thing and then they
said okay now you give the presentation
to us we will roleplay that we're the
OCC will pretend with the OSI
and you give the presentation to us so I
went through and I gave the presentation
and they'd sit there and say no you
idiot you can't say that you have to say
this and they're very very prescriptive
so this went on for like two or three
hours and finally they said okay you're
ready boy and I was like battered by
that time I'm like I really don't feel
all that confident there's no know
you're ready just stick to the script
the next day I came in I gave the
presentation the occ the end of the
presentation the occ said I think you
have a good strategy looks solid we're
all set we won't see it for another year
now just to translate that's as good at
it as it ever gets
like that that is like a high bar if you
meet that right and the reason that I
survived that was because they use the
formula and they used a formula that
back then was the formula you choose a
risk framework you identify control
objectives in that risk framework
you are lying your business and IT
management practices with the control
objectives that are clearly in the risk
framework you get a third party to do an
attestation of the efficacy of your
controls against that risk framework and
you declare victory
that's what cybersecurity was 20 years
ago and it was it worked like it was
okay today the boundary with
conventional controls and a risk
framework and what you actually need for
resiliency is getting farther and
farther apart and it's why compliance to
so-called industry standards is totally
insufficient if you want to avoid major
business impact of security incidents so
my challenge in healthcare as our
challenges in healthcare it's to move
from compliance driven security to risk
driven security
thank you very much and so now we'll
turn it over to Chris Reid who's a
director of product cybersecurity at Eli
Lilly yeah so I can't agree with Jim
more and and I think so just to give you
know I think what I'd like to bring to
this it's a little different is just the
kind of highlight how fast healthcare
starting to change it's an industry that
I think's been hasn't really been
affected as much as many other
industries by the digital innovations
that have happened out there but all
that's coming and I think if you need
any further evidence it's that I sit you
know I work for Eli Lilly a drug company
and I'm sitting here building a product
cybersecurity team because we're gonna
have a lot of digital products that sit
in patients hands and on their bodies
very soon and it's to me it's a really
exciting time the way I try to relate
this is you know I think about the
healthcare I've been through and a lot
of times it's you know when you're
healthy you might go in the doctor and
get a test every few months or once a
year so the medical record is literally
this little spot checks of how you're
doing but there's a lot of things that
happen between in those gaps and with
all the all the technology all the
wearables and sensors and honestly the
cost of coming to a facility to even
manage that
you're gonna start seeing a lot of that
pushed out to the patient to the edge
and the cool part about that is we'll
have a lot more data points but the bad
part about that is a holler duration
which so for all that the risk
management perspective you know it does
get really difficult and simple
compliance is not going to keep all that
data safe and and make it have a lot of
integrity that's going to be used to
treat people and make serious decisions
you know one of the things I think is
interesting as well as you know as a
pharmaceutical company we're starting to
use what we call digital biomarkers to
look at whether or not our medicines
work so this is if you think about even
example of a Parkinson's patient with
some type of gyroscope device
on them you could actually see it is the
medicine that they're taking effectively
reducing the amount of tremor that they
have over time and so you're gonna see
actual digital data not just biologic
data I mean it's it's it's
representative of something that's
happening but a lot of that's going to
be used in the space in the future and
of course all the AI applied to all this
and the big data work in the back you
know Lily specifically and I can share
this you know we're working on the
concept of artificial pancreas this
insulin de pump that will by itself
watch your glucose and give you lot
smaller doses of insulin when you need
it and act more like your actual
pancreas would operate so you're gonna
start seeing technology really get into
a lot of sensors and data analytics to
help patients you know live healthier
lives and hopefully increase the value
that we're getting out of our healthcare
I guess to make a point about the
regulatory and the risk management you
know the FDA is actually in my opinion
they're doing a pretty good job in this
space in the medical device world they
haven't come across with a list of
here's everything you need to implement
to be compliant and get your product
approve but one of the things that we
struggle with is how to integrate you
know medical device companies typically
are pretty good about safety risk
management they're not good about risk
management on cybersecurity and so we're
working hard on how do these two systems
live next to each other and have an
interplay but you can't just throw
cybersecurity into your normal risk
management process because safety will
always win and security is a lot more
than just safety we need to make sure
the data has integrity and obviously you
want to keep your personal information
safe because there's a lot of personal
data flowing through the system you know
I think as I think further in the future
too we're gonna have a lot of
interesting privacy issues around who
pays for things so if you think about
the commercial models of how all these
services we use how they work today a
lot of its advertising and driven and
you get to use your Gmail account for
free it's going to be interesting to see
what privacy we have to
up in order to fund the development of
all these tools going forward
and then I think lastly and it'll
probably help especially to Georgetown
at the end here talking later one of the
biggest concerns I have is we have a big
legacy device problem and I'm worried
about that problem impacting the trust
and all these future technologies and we
have a really almost an intractable
problem in the legacy space there's just
a lot of old devices in a lot of
organizations that are understaffed and
under trained and we're trying to do the
best through things like H I SEC to tool
everyone up and help them get the
funding they need but you know you can
walk into any healthcare environment and
just see devices all over the place and
if you know anything about those devices
you start thinking like oh when's the
last time that they got patched and what
networks is it connected to and you
probably don't ask too many of those
questions right now so but yeah it's
it's a it's an exciting space right now
but it is it is very fun and complicated
okay well and when you're talking about
all those digital sensors it's a great
transition to VJ raghunathan who's a
professor of Electrical and Computer
Engineering here at Purdue and works on
embedded systems in IOT thank you David
so I sort of bring the academic
perspective - I guess this panel and one
of the benefits of being an academic is
that I have the luxury of being able to
dream up cleanslate solutions right
without being hampered by a lot of the
you know legacy baggage if I may pull it
up and so we my I lead a team of very
bright students and researchers some of
whom are in the room here who over the
past 10 years or so I've been looking at
essentially cleanslate
approaches for hardware and software
architectures for next-generation
embedded systems and the medical device
area right we're talking about variable
medical devices and more a plate of even
more interest implantable medical
devices things that actually go inside
your body
and ways in ways to design these systems
to make them more energy efficient and
secure and there's a number of specific
systems that we've that people looked at
and worked on including sort of the
artificial pancreas sort of system where
we try to design a bunch of what we call
last lines of defense into the endpoint
or the medical device itself such that
you know if even if there is some kind
of a security attack or there's some
kind of a malfunction in the device you
know can be put in sufficient safeguards
and make those safeguards you know well
locked down and small enough that they
could be verified statically it could be
you know sort of verified using formal
methods for example where we can
actually prove that look you know under
these set of assumptions these these
devices will actually do you know
perform the way they're expected to
perform or if there is a security attack
of particular time that you can actually
say something intelligent about you know
what the device is basically going to be
doing and if you can lock down the
device to prevent any any any damage and
so my take on sort of based on that line
of work is I think implantables you know
looking forward you're 15 or 20 years
I think implantables are going to play a
very very key role in this whole space
of medical devices I think it's sort of
continuing that trend of pushing sort of
healthcare down to the patient and down
in fact into the patient in the case of
an implantable and I think that lets us
do two things right one is it lets you
get a you know at least in most cases a
lot of real-time feedback right so
you're sort of closing that loop in
real-time as something happens to a
patient you know if the patient you know
has in epic seizure patient has a heart
attack or something right you know the
the the loop gets closed much faster and
second is it allows us to move towards a
realm of personalized medicine and again
as
mentioned you know that aspect of
personalization right you know you want
to be able to figure out if a particular
drug is working well for a specific
patient or not and sort of that aspect
of personalization really comes to the
forefront if you now start thinking of
all of these variable and implantable
medical devices you're not sort of
providing you personalized real-time
feedback the challenge with a lot of
these devices in terms of security as
I'm sure my co-panelists will do as well
is the fact that you know it's one thing
trying to design a large cyber cyber
system and trying to secure that right
as complex and as difficult as it is but
you also these systems also have the
computer resources the sort of
architectural safeguards in place that
as a security engineer or a person who's
worried about the security of these
systems you at least have the tools that
you can use in order to enforce security
policies and stuff the issue with a lot
of these implantable medical devices is
that they're you know clearly for mostly
for energy consumption reasons or for
form-factor reasons they lack a lot at
least hardware components in their lack
lot of the architectural safety
mechanisms that we are typically used to
when we think about security and
conventional car types of computing
systems right and that makes it a real
challenge in terms of actually trying to
secure these devices right and can often
even something as simple as you know you
put something into a patient you put a
pacemaker into a patient and you somehow
want to securely communicate with it
right this thing is going to be
wirelessly enabled how do you exchange
keys with an implanted device in a
secure manner right it's in a scalable
way right and not do something crazy is
having sort of a preset key that you're
going to use for the same key for all
the other devices in stuff right so
that's one aspect the last challenge
that I'll that I'll mention in my
opening remarks here is security in
these implantable devices also sort of a
it's it's a double-edged sword
because under normal conditions imagine
again a patient for example who has a
pain
under normal conditions you want to lock
down this patient pacemaker as much as
he can I don't want anybody talking to
it except perhaps you know in a very
secure way a device that a user owns or
of course we enter a secure environment
like a doctor's office like a
cardiologists office and they we have
that magic wand over here for your heart
but the instant something goes wrong
with you the instant you have a heart
attack and you know you call 9-1-1 and
that emergency responder shows up you
want all your safeguards to basically
just vanish because you don't want to
impede access you know access to your
device and access to care right in any
kind of way and you don't want to have
that emergency responder even delay by a
few minutes or a couple of minutes
trying to actually get into your device
right so it is really strange thing and
by the way that emergency responder will
probably use some kind of a special
device to top ear to your implantable
medical device which and these two
devices have never seen each other level
never had a chance to sort of exchange
keys before or sort of collaborate with
each other right so it's a really
strange problem where you really want
your device locked down except when you
don't in which case you need to just
throw it open completely and sort of
solving that dichotomy I think is one of
the most interesting sort of challenges
in power you know things that I'll stop
with that and our last speaker is Church
Bailey who's a senior advisor for health
IT security with Purdue health care
advisors Thank You professor Ebert so I
come from a different perspective I'm a
security practitioner who has the
benefit of actually working with
delivery health systems doctors nurses I
keep practitioners in health systems of
all sizes down to your one doc three
employee clinic all the way to multi
Hospital health systems and I get to see
the whole gamut of good practice bad
practice and anywhere in between and
I'll concur with these three gentlemen
right HIPAA I think is is very
misunderstood right so as an industry
we're being promoted for
interoperability we want data sharing
because we want to get data in the
patient's hands so that as they bounce
around to the various care providers
they have the data that they need to get
optimal care however providers who are
under this regulatory constraint of well
can I share with that other care
provider can i how do I do so securely
right so HIPAA allows it because it's so
misunderstood people error on the side
of caution and inhibits care there are
things we can do securely to to enable
the patient for sure so I think HIPPA
needs some significant rewrites right
think about when HIPAA was established
right it was enforceable early 2000 was
written in 1996 as part of a health
insurance modernization right so
security was a byproduct of HIPAA but
because of it we have now had two
decades of facilities and healthcare
delivery systems just not understanding
how it implemented and you know the way
that I describe it is health care today
is in there dot-com boom where most of
us back in the early 90s late 90s
adopting public facing systems right
those first DMC's you rolled out because
you had services you want to get to the
public healthcare is just now in that
space and we wouldn't be in that space
if it wasn't for some incentives at
least us-based health care facilities
right since 2011 health care facilities
have been incentivized to adopt
electronic health records and to deploy
patient portals and to get information
in the hands of the patient right so we
we've had these organizations that were
purely paper-based pen-and-paper
very next week oh my goodness we have
electronical system we're you know we
have computers everywhere and we don't
have a formal risk management strategy
to deal with IT issues you know we do
you handle compliance the OSHA
infectious disease those kinds of the
shoes fairly well in healthcare but
managing the security of data and
systems those processes although other
industries have have gotten very good at
it we don't have the personnel in
healthcare to address that most security
officers in that medium
Health System and smaller there security
officer is probably their h-i-m their
health information management person
right they were the person who managed
the chart room right they they were
charged with keeping patient privacy and
now oh well you dealt with data you
dealt with information where this other
hat in the reality is they're only
wearing that hat
whenever Health and Human Services pays
them a call or their payor wants to know
how their securing data right they don't
have the luxury of wearing the security
hat every day every hour that they're in
the facility and then worrying about it
right you ask an hie in person what
keeps them up at night it's not data
security because they're they're just
not informed enough to know that so
these poor risk management strategies
which is required by HIPAA but it's not
prescriptive HIPAA will say look to NIST
use the NIST 853 for controls and how
you would protect your systems look at
834 how you would assess your IT
environment you give that type of
framework to a person who's used to
managing paper files and and it's it
doesn't get implemented then not to
their fault they just don't understand
it they don't have the resources to go
and get it figure it out
so these risk management practices leads
to poor technology life cycles so as
Chris mentioned right the FDA is
providing decent guidance and medical
device manufacturers are implementing
right they understand they've heard the
consumers people were afraid when Dick
Cheney turned off his his pacemaker
right that that was world news and was
he paranoid
probably not he's a high profile person
he travels internationally right if he
was a target and someone got close
enough to him their potential
vulnerability there certainly is a
threat there right someone like myself
low risk but it's the it's the legacy
devices that really we have the issue
because in most care facilities if it's
not a revenue-generating
right so you hear the commercials on a
radio get yard scan $49.99 right that's
a revenue-generating service yeah at the
end of the day your doctor is running a
business right so you keep his door
open they need to have revenue so if
they have an $8,000 EKG machine that
they're about 20 years ago and the
function of it hasn't changed it's a
diagnostic device it doesn't really make
them any money they're not going to
upgrade it but this networked it is
networks aren't segmented so if you are
in the clinic and and you have access to
the network that device is vulnerable to
you know anything else that may be
vulnerable from that state that age of a
device so it's a big thing and
eventually that will organically solve
itself these devices break down as they
do turn over but it's gonna be a long
time so a couple other things just the
the situation of awareness of the
vulnerability threat landscape
healthcare providers are in the business
to provide care right they they're not
in the business to be up on the latest
whatever the latest one it really might
be right so a couple years ago when we
were dealing with heartbleed and poodle
these SSL issues SSL is one of those
things that we should have solved a long
time ago right we shouldn't be using SSL
version any SSL versions right we should
be on TLS version 1.2
I see SSL version 2 everywhere right
because our health care folks their IT
consumers we've we've programmed them to
look for the padlock all right so in
their EHR system and their patient
portals they see a pedal oh it's secure
they don't understand that there's
there's levels of security there and
they don't know that they should be
reaching out for the most modern right
and that that goes through all layers of
the system other talking points security
awareness of all levels right so you've
got folks that are your senior
executives of the healthcare system all
the way down to that medical assistant
right and the medical assistants
touching the patient they're interfacing
with infusion pumps they're they're
they're interfacing with the Pyxis in
order to dispense meds for the for the
RN there's there's all kinds of things
that they're interacting with and they
have
no awareness of anomalies right so if
they see a message on the screen they
click through it if there's well it's
time to reboot right so things like
ransomware is why health care is it's so
vulnerable to those things because
people in the industry just they don't
know to stop and they you know we were
telling folks to have a zero trust but
they don't know not to trust physical
security it's it's not necessary a cyber
issue but because we have legacy devices
Windows XP is still very prevalent at
least here in the Midwest in health care
delivery systems I would imagine it's
it's prevalent everywhere and why is
that because there's a there's a mobile
ultrasound machine that plugs into it
and it and it's purely because the
driver only works on XP and in order to
retool that it's a turnkey solution and
I got to spend another hundred thousand
dollars for whatever the latest and
greatest and the latest and greatest
doesn't give you any more diagnostic
capability within that whatever the test
that device is for so they live with it
but it's on the network they access the
EHR they print they do other things so
and the the physical aspect of that you
could walk up you could touch these
things as a patient you could walk them
touch these things as a as a
representative of a patient and there's
not a lot of scrutiny when you're
walking through a healthcare facility
right you if you want to do harm a
hospital is where you need to go because
most people aren't going to question you
all right they're busy they're
overloaded and you can you can touch you
can touch a PC you can touch a Pyxis
machine amid dispensing you can touch
medical devices and you know something
as simple as a rubber ducky right a key
keystroke injector device you can you
can have a cause a lot of damage
other talking points I think I'll leave
it that
leave that for questions okay well I you
know I was thinking of this in my terms
of where we're going with the change in
medicine and the change in new implanted
of
Isis and personalized medicine and all
the new security concerns in that and
not thinking as much about the legacy
systems and the integrated patient
health exchanges of information in the
privacy of all of that and so personally
I things that I just consider normal
cyber problems their information
security or information privacy seeing
the way that they're getting transformed
today from that individual small device
up through you know citywide statewide
health information exchanges is a little
illuminating and a little disconcerting
as well it's one of those things where
when you're talking about what people
are pulling up on their systems twice
now recently seeing a physician he
googled a term and then pulled up pages
off of Wikipedia to explain what was
going on on this terminal with my
medical records and you know my entire
personal health record they're on the
same device that I have no idea how
secure that is but you're just thinking
of you know he thought nothing of it and
he said you know did your rash look
exactly like this and it was like well
yes it did you know these things where I
think you're right you bring that human
in I think there's also you know these
emerging challenges as you talked about
in terms of the individual implantable
devices and in terms of their some
interesting work colleagues are doing
here at Purdue and actually using the
bioelectric field of the human as
identifiers of who can access that
device to control that device so you're
using your personalized electrical field
to make sure that you don't have someone
spoofing it so there's really creative
solutions to some of that but then when
you get into the sharing of information
that no CVS being an example that is
also now providing prescription plans as
well as being the person who's selling
the drugs so now you've got more
information collected uniformly and sort
of I guess for privacy side the good or
bad of our healthcare system now as most
of your health care data is fragmented
and so it's very hard for anyone to
really get your life
history of your medical history because
some of it are with the drug companies
over what's the different providers
you've seen over the years etc and you
know if you have more of a system like
in Canada provincially you've got all of
the data sitting in one place which
opens up potential for more accurate
health care which is one trade off
versus the vulnerabilities attack yet so
I think there's a whole range of
questions for that we can talk about
here and so please step up to the mic
and address those as well as we're
waiting for someone to come up I guess
you know the one question I pose to the
panel is what are you most concerned
about in looking at security of the
future of your personal health care so
I'll give it a shot so there's a trend
that has some toxic ating attributes to
it which is cloud computing and the
intoxicating attributes is that you can
store data in one place use it for
hundreds of different purposes with
different entities using that data now
that's the promise and the economics to
that equation or what's intoxicating
because instead of storing data a
hundred times you're storing data once
and you're using and sharing it with all
sorts of different entities that could
be competing with each other in certain
cases but have very different needs but
need access to that data right so
there's two approaches that give us some
hope for being able to realize that and
protect the data effectively in all
scenarios one is called differential
privacy which is it's an obfuscation I'm
gonna butcher this in the interest of
time an obfuscation technique that
basically allows you to get multiple
people to access the same data without
sharing data from a compliance
standpoint so that's one dimension the
other is homomorphic encryption which
allows you to offer an encryption
capability on the data that served up as
well as the queries that go in
simultaneously so if different
competitors are using the same database
neither one knows what the others
and they're only seeing the data that
they're entitled to see so you combine
those two trains of Technology
deployment development evolution and now
you have the promise potentially of
storing data once in the cloud and using
it for multiple purposes including
consumer purposes with lots of different
entities it's still relatively new but
this is a perfect example of where HIPAA
gives us guidance today that says if you
D identify the data you can share it
with multiple entities all right let's
just assume that one of those entities
that you share it with has a wealth of
consumer data at their disposal and a
number of data scientists with pretty
decent tools at their disposal what that
means is you share de-identified data it
doesn't know that part of the data
element says Jim you know in that and
you share that with the the entity and
they can identify it very easily using
the data science techniques and the data
that they already have the from a HIPAA
perspective this is cool this is okay
this is this is compliant from a risk
standpoint not so much right and by the
way there is no answer for this from a
compliance standpoint and I think you
pointed out what was it George you
pointed out HIPAA started in 1996 right
took a long time right to iterate so the
legislative process around healthcare is
that an efficient process don't answer
that that's a rhetorical question right
so it's gonna be a long time before
regulations solve for this so we as
practitioners have to use risk and our
concepts of risk to solve for this and
that means designing controls that don't
necessarily exist today to be able to
solve this problem because technology
marches ahead
anyone else want to say something or
should we take in another question I
think we should go ahead
so as working for a DoD contractor I see
a lot of similarities between you know
what I'm hearing here and what what we
face as well I mean you know there's no
profit in cybersecurity right it's
you're protecting against something
you're hoping to limit a future event
that may happen so it's difficult to
sell right and we're all up against the
same problems that that George described
limited you know limited resources to a
task the tsunami that's hitting us right
so but and Jim
so you described essentially what is
what we use in DoD the risk management
framework is what you used right but and
and we're getting further away from
being able to usefully apply that to get
resilience right so but what what and I
think you just started to describe what
my question is what what's the next
steps what are the next steps to narrow
that gap or to start to you know reduce
the risk yeah so the genie is out of the
bottle we're not gonna narrow it that's
not in the cards but there is hope
because there actually is profit in
cybersecurity there unique examples but
but it is there so for example I
implemented something called D Kim and
SPF you're probably all familiar with
and D mark is the standard does anybody
from a day so we're talking about email
so basically trusted email D mark
basically prevents any entity from
spoofing a domain which used to be a
common technique for phishing attacks
and in my case I implemented it about
40% of our e mail volume dropped most of
it coming from
Russia and Eastern Europe and the volume
that dropped was basically
pharmaceutical spammers that were
selling you know products to our members
through email and so when we dropped all
that traffic the click-through rate on
our email campaigns and about two
billion emails a year went up 10% every
year and this has been going on for last
four years so what that means is our
email campaigns are driving people to
have healthier behaviors and that drives
profit to the company so we put a
security control in place and it
increased profit for their company so
that's one example of profit can drive
there are other examples for if any
large enterprise build software and
spend a lot of money to build software
if you build software and get somewhere
between 20 and 30 percent improvement in
productivity in the development hours
and building the software well then you
build software at a lower cost so that
also will drive profit you can also take
the productivity gain and invested a new
functionality or capability that also
drives profit so from an economic
standpoint never try to sell software
security because it's lower risk
that's that you'll never win that
argument because it's there's no way to
attribute defects and software security
to an enterprise because the consumers
that get hosed when they browse a
website and get infected with malware
that's on the software you know in terms
of the vulnerability they never know
that it's your website that it does they
find out six months later when the fraud
hits if no I there's no attribution
whatsoever so there's no incentive for
an enterprise to have quality software
but there is economic incentive in terms
of improving your productivity for
building a software and harvesting that
benefit any way you wish but that's
economic dollars and cents so in most
security cases it actually there's an
economic argument to implementing
security controls the variable is you
have to look at the total cost of IT Oh
and total cost includes the patching and
vulnerability management which is often
not captured anywhere on a balance sheet
for any enterprise but that's actually
where the value is so if you look at the
total cost of IT ownership I can
influence and I and I've said this
publicly I'll say it again I have no
problem getting money for cybersecurity
I never have I get as much money as I
want for whatever programs and projects
that I want I know that sounds like
that's counter to conventional wisdom
I'm telling I've worked for big
companies I never have problem because I
used the economic benefits now there are
some security things that it's difficult
to do that I grant you that but the
majority 70% of information security
controls are in the delivery of IT so if
you change and alter the delivery of IT
to be more effective and most
enterprises that are large spend a lot
of money on IT and that's cost savings
that you can use to invest so the
economics and the profit motive actually
is alive and well you have to be a
little bit more creative on how you do
it but that's what I do and I encourage
everyone to do that does that help yeah
I can't agree more I mean I think you
have to have that a little bit of
business acumen to help deliver help the
biz the business understand what that
risk is but how taking an approach is
going to help bring some money back to
the table for them and I'd say what I
try to do a lot of times I'm looking for
opportunities the reality is we have and
this or I think it comes in to risk
management we have more problems than we
can solve on any given day but I try to
match like what are our biggest risks
with where do I see where we can move a
business process forward so your example
making things more efficient a lot of
the big terms that you'll hear today in
agile but met with continuous
integration hey you should implement to
compute continuous integration in your
software dolmen process and by the way
when you do that I'm gonna plug in all
these security tools and the developers
can't move to the next phase until they
close things out you start to show them
advantages in
but at the same time you're getting
controls built in there and everyone is
coming out better on the other side so
there is a savviness I think to get
security done well so I think it is
getting hard because you can't just say
hey this is an awful problem we have to
solve it that's not gonna ever get you
funding or very rarely unless it's just
obvious so I would just emphasize that I
think that's really important the one
thing that I would add to that again
sort of from the perspective somebody's
building technology is I think even
those that security can often be an
enabler for you know new usage models or
new use cases right for example if one
were to solve the security problem of
you know how do I securely you know sort
of bootstrap and medical the implantable
medical device from my own smartphone it
that could and you know I think that
potentially drives a very powerful
message that it now enables users
potential users to keep track of their
own implantable medical devices and
their status and their operation of
those in real time and that could
potentially drive up adoption rates
right or people are using these
technologies so security I think could
also play the role of an enabler sort of
indirectly driving the economic side but
I do agree with them that it is the
economics which which which now can you
continue that discussion yeah cyber
security can be a competitive advantage
but it has to be linked to reimbursement
I tell medicine we can do a lot
serving disparate populations of sick
people with telemedicine but if
providers can't be reimbursed for that
encounter they're not going to invest in
new proper cybersecurity to protect that
telemedicine session all right so it
goes back to again if it can't generate
revenue the the smaller medium-sized
delivery system is not gonna be able to
invest in it
hey thanks follow y'all for coming I had
a kind of a broad question in a more
context was it a question the broader
one being I've worked in health care a
number of years myself and seeing a lot
of the problems that a lot of you
discussed like even in some of the
bigger hospitals that implement more
security protocols like a doctor has to
have their token on them they usually
leave it on their badge but then they
say hey nurse I need this file go get
that for me and then or a nurse may
leave their their token i they leave on
their badge at the nursing station which
is open and you could just reach over
the counter and grab it if you really
wanted to a number of other ones being
like the monitor and a doctor's office
face in the window you could very easily
look at personal health care information
it's like with all of these types of
little examples one of the panel's
thoughts on solutions potentially being
do we want to focus on training our
current healthcare personnel giving them
another workload of learn a new you know
privacy protocol trying to implement it
into what you already known you've done
for 30 years or do we want to focus more
on having the new blood and
cybersecurity have a more focused
context-specific view of healthcare or
whatever vertical they're gonna work in
like oil manufacturing or something yes
it's either/or is what you're suggesting
there's our possible solutions but
together those sound couple things first
of all if we could just get rid of all
the people in healthcare security be
fine no problem flawless okay that's not
likely so maybe we ought to be training
or teaching people a little bit more
effectively in terms of security
awareness but what we've done
historically for less a couple of
decades is we teach people of the risks
of cybersecurity it's it's totally
insufficient first of all today most
media outlets do a better job of it than
any enterprise or provider would do just
read the paper I mean there's always
that you can't pick up a paper today
without reading about cybersecurity it's
in mainstream today it's made it if you
will
what's not in there is focus on the
technique
that you as a consumer need to
understand that as a professional and as
a individual as a you know in terms of
your personal needs and there's kind of
a blending in terms of you know
smartphones that cross the gamut there
but we have to teach people how to be
better consumers and here's and and what
does that mean here here's a couple
examples if you use a digital platform
that you don't pay for it means someone
else is paying for it so you're not the
consumer even though you are made to
feel like you're the consumer for Gmail
as an example
who's the consumer or who's the buyer
the buyer who's funding that is funding
that because of the information you
provide into the system you're not the
consumer the digital consumer you're the
product or more specifically information
about you is the product and therefore
you're the product manager so if you
think about being the product manager
you've got a fighting chance for making
decisions on which platforms to use if
you're paying a lot of money for a
platform I'm just using an Apple iPhone
as an icon here because I think it's a
lot of money and if I use iCloud to back
that up there's a lot of money that I'm
spending for that but your information
is much better protected because you're
the actual consumer but when you use a
digital platform that somebody else is
paying for and you're the product and so
you've got to act like a product manager
which is deciding what the trade-off
value to use an individual is to give up
your information and and if you think
about giving up your information in that
context you've got a fighting chance how
to be a digital consumer and have some
level of protection in what you do but
that is anybody hear that message I mean
you know unfortunately because
platform owners aren't telling us this
because yeah a pretty good game going
right now right so it's up to us to
figure this out yeah the way the way we
think about it a lot is in the way I've
I've thought about it for a number of
years is you've got to teach users how
to know when they're walking down a dark
alley because no amount of controls are
ever gonna stop that intuitive sense of
something's not right here I need to
slow down and pay attention and have my
guard up right telling a user that there
are dark alleys insufficient yeah
telling a user how to walk down a dark
say how to choose at which one yeah
right so so that's where we focus a lot
of our efforts but I agree totally you
you've got also make these things easier
for them make it easier to see the dark
alley you know even things like tagging
email in a certain way when we think
it's suspicious just a you know and
obviously getting a lot of that out with
you mark and things like that is you've
got to take the workload off the user
because there everyone's trying to get
their jobs done and yeah it's got to be
both unfortunately sure more consequence
if aquestion with the advent of like
wearable health technologies like the
artificial pancreas like even more
simple insulin pumps that have a lot of
sensitive personal healthcare data the
move and from a security view will that
may be a solution to securing that data
would be maybe encryption in the device
or having some secure means of storing
it at a hospital but then that could
potentially get into the area of do we
want to open data centers and hospitals
huge data centers where they're already
having a lot of funding issues the way
with the way it is and then we need to
potentially hire more personnel to with
the cybersecurity focus to manage those
data centers like well what kind of
ideas yeah I'll start first of all I
think this is where I was saying I think
the FDA is doing a pretty good job they
have a draft guidance out there they got
released in October and if there was any
doubt of whether or not you're supposed
to encrypt data at rest it's it's gone
they you know not only do they say that
do that kind of thing I mean they talk
about cryptographically verify
the software that's running you know on
the device and things like that
so I really applauded them for it's not
a checklist and there's some there's
some work to do as a draft guidance
that's gonna that's getting reworked
right now but I feel like you know
there's no doubt all these devices are
gonna have to solve these problems but
just like vijay mentioned it is
difficult though because if some of the
you know we want a device that's gonna
operate for a week without recharging
how many people's phones operate for a
week without recharging right but you
don't want to have to recharge your you
know hey I'm I'm going away for three
days I gotta remember to charge my
insulin pump I mean you know we've got
to come up with ways to manage the cost
not just money but computation and
things like that on these and then as
far as that you know the integration of
all these environments is definitely
gonna main interesting area like as it
comes up I definitely don't think
anyone's gonna expect a hospital
provider to fill data centers that's
that's not going to happen but I think
you're gonna see data start to get
layered like where there's like the
primary EHR system but then there's hey
there you use this type of device and so
I can go get all the details of that and
it's stored somewhere else and and it'll
get abstracted from the physician but we
can't expect like if we're generating it
can't get by at a data per hour per user
that a hospital's gonna be able to you
know take in all that data like so
there's gonna have to be really strong
integration and strategy on how to do
that to go back to Jim's comment I think
in a scenario like that will be the
product the patient would be the product
the device manufacturers will be
identify the data and write it so if my
device gave me a boost of insulin right
it knows it knows what my body was doing
prior during and after treatment right
that data can inform researchers make
the device better all policy issues a
privacy issues aside right so I don't
think it'll be the delivery system the
healthcare provider have any manage that
data
someone will if I could tell you or
trend that's driving a lot of us right
now that I think is really good is it's
the outcome based payment so a lot of
you know you hear even in the media or
big insulin manufacturer price of
insulin is a big topic even in Congress
right now and all that there is a drive
to a model where outcome will be what
pays so if someone's glue if someone's
blood trader is managed in range you get
paid this this amount if it's not you
basically maybe get covered just for the
cost of the product but no profit right
that that that's starting to shift in
the background but we need a lot of
these data systems in order to actually
show that so to me that's a really
exciting trend but we still have a lot
of work to do but I'm hoping that that
so hopefully it's just a little bit from
the product but it just it does the
motivations become still like hey we're
getting good outcomes and we have the
data we need to do that and that's
actually what's funding a lot of the the
research and keeping things up to speed
my 15 second ending to that will just be
that when you're talking about a lot of
these devices you know variable device I
think security ends up being a whole lot
more than just cryptography and the data
because the security the attack model or
the attack surface is just so broad and
so diverse right I don't have to do I
don't even need need your data right i
but all I need to do is to just drain
the battery on your system that does not
need me to actually even read a single
piece of information from you I can just
keep transmitting the error to you and
just keep keep your radio on and let you
burn your battery out right so a lot of
the security attacks can be you know
sort of non cryptographic and stuff and
so the solutions also will have to be I
think so uniquely tailored and
out-of-the-box to address some of these
unconventional non cyber security
attacks perhaps okay thanks
let's take one more question so we have
time for a short break before the final
session okay so going back to this
problem
like the wearable devices so what do you
think about the issue of you send these
devices out and there's of like a
vulnerability found in these and some of
these systems may be very hard to pass
like the user might not know what
they're doing or like pretty much
impossible with like an artificial
pancreas where it's literally in your
body so it's really hard to like pageant
so what do you what do you think about
that issue how do you think we're gonna
solve that issue going forward well you
say it's hard it doesn't mean we have
the option not to do it I've I was gonna
give the example earlier about how you
get security controls worked in and
every time I brought up how are we gonna
update this out in the field everyone
looked at me like we can't do that but I
managed to tie it to other priorities
that we had for the program like
updating our algorithms that run on it
safely and things like that and all of a
sudden it became they saw that was the
solution and it totally got funded and
supported and taken through I do think
there will be devices it's going to
depend on the safety impact some devices
won't be updated and that there's still
gonna be an interesting problem in that
space but we're gonna have to I mean if
you look at the FDA guidance and their
expectations you have to be able to
update these devices in the field that
isn't it's not going to get through FDA
approval coming into the future without
that capability
and that you've done it well which kind
of makes sense cuz it's software we
foolin software it's never perfect
they're never I software always has to
be patched so if we're putting software
in devices hey you got a patch it that's
you know because some vulnerabilities we
discovered years after the software's
release absolutely you got to be able to
patch it I mean that's the way software
works I think it works that way with
planes now I think that the West Coast
companies wrestling with that set right
now software update right I think
there's no question that we'll have to
update these devices what scares me is
how right so these devices are gonna be
in you or on you so how are they gonna
be updated Bluetooth personal device
will it be a dedicated device that comes
coupled with the device not likely right
because that increases the expense
they're going to use a device that you
already
in your possession right so you're going
to make a very sensitive very trusted
transaction to update your pacemaker on
an Android device that's five years old
way behind on its updates and patches do
you trust that device you trust your
pacemaker because maybe it's been
verified cryptographically and and with
formal methods but you trust the Android
device that you're using to communicate
with your pacemaker right so consumers
probably gonna know but but certainly
device manufacturers will have to take
those ecosystems and mine when they're
developing these patch routines for a
recall yeah and I think again from my
vantage point this is a really
interesting space from a research
perspective right and you know so for
example some of my students are looking
at specifically something that George
you just mentioned which is you know how
do I interact with an implantable device
from an external device that I don't
trust you know perhaps there's a health
server that I trust but if in order to
get to that health server I need to go
through this Android device which is
five years old and unpatch and is there
some way that I can actually talk
without trusting this intermediate party
right that's a really interesting you
know sort of research question and
hopefully something that we can get a
handle on very soon hey do you have a
short question or a short answer
so it's interesting what you said about
how to sell security how about selling
it from the standpoint of resilience
some availability so we know that every
system will be hacked you know you can't
prevent it eventually it will be hacked
but how about building in some
redundancy so that the system hack
system will continue to operate and
deliver it that may be another angle may
be easier to get itself well yeah all
those all those failure modes will have
to be looked at yeah sometimes it's
redundancy sometimes it's failing to a
safe state a lot of that is is
definitely considered a movie expected
there's not really this is
where the risk management gets really
important is there's no there's no list
that's gonna make it right for the
device that you're working on like this
you have to really do a lot of and the
FDA is again push this a lot of threat
modeling to understand what your attack
surfaces are and how you respond to
those and how you fail safely there's
not a really simple answer that we need
more research in this face for sure I do
agree I think the availability angle is
sort of could potentially be a
differentiator right you know you're
gonna be offering a better you know sort
of SLA or service level agreement or
somebody saying that your systems gonna
be up so with a higher percentage of
time that could potentially be a yeah
I've made a pair of pacemakers in you
know heart I mean yes something like
that
I'll take a slightly pessimistic
approach resiliency and redundancy is
absolutely key but in your lower
maturity organizations right when a
system fails open or fails over to a
redundant node they don't have the
monitoring place to know that it
switched over so from a incident or a
compromised detection mode sometimes
that hard failure although it's it's
hard to deal with is is there indicator
that something bad has happened let's
call someone who can fix this
so certainly an implantable devices
resiliency and redundancy is absolutely
key because you failure is not an option
right great
but with traditional networked systems I
for anything smaller than like a six
hundred employee health system it would
be problematic okay thanks well let's
thank our panel for a lively discussion
you