so this morning's first panel is on
securing giant leaps in space
exploration
you heard from the last speaker that
Purdue University is the number-one
non-military organization for producing
astronaut so I think it's very fitting
that we're exploring this today I even
wore my space tie today if you notice
it's a it's keeping with the theme so
we're going well we've got another I
think outstanding panel today set up for
us that the moderator is known to
anybody that's worked in this field
before professor Dan DeLaurentis he's
the director for the Institute of global
security and defense innovation and a
professor of Aeronautics and
Astronautics here at Purdue University
he's got a long list of accomplishments
behind him and I know that he's been
sort of the go-to guy in in everything
Astro Aero here on this campus so rather
than dwelling on that I'm just gonna go
straight to the panel I'll let Dan
introduce his colleagues on the panel
and we'll take it from there
thank you great Thank You Gerry how's my
microphone working good all right well
welcome everyone and it is a great
opportunity for me to be chairing this
panel what I found in my faculty career
over the years is that I've gotten
better and better at asking questions
rather than answering them sometimes and
so I have the pleasure of putting a
little context out there for the panel
and then asking some questions of our
panelists to get things going but
certainly want to get vigorous
participation from from all of you in
the audience
so speaking of cradle of astronauts you
know my childhood dream was to be an
astronaut I was
besides being so fascinated by space I
know my colleague here and I share a lot
of this background
besides being fascinated by space from
really as early as I can remember it was
one of the only careers in which my
height was optimized for that occupation
so that was good so actually I just just
a little background in context here I
went to the Florida Institute of
Technology
shoutout to fi T in Melbourne Florida
for my undergraduate program because I
was convinced that the only way I could
become an astronaut was to go to the
University that was closest to the
Kennedy Space Center so that showed you
sometimes my narrow thinking not
realizing that for a Chicago kid down
the road here in West Lafayette Indiana
was this wonderful place called Purdue
but life and serendipity did bring me
back here and it's been a fabulous
journey for me here in Purdue aero-astro
department the wonderful heritage but
also I think the wonderful
forward-looking aspects that we have for
Space Exploration and everything about
space obviously you all know from the
format of the panels here at the
symposium that we're celebrating our
150th anniversary here at Purdue we're
celebrating the fiftieth anniversary of
Apollo and probably X number of other
anniversaries that I'm missing but
certainly the heritage in space
exploration at Purdue beyond not just
our aero-astro department some of those
wonderful astronauts that we've had and
some of the innovators that we've
generated from Purdue come from varied
departments and so that's another
testament I think to produce role in
this space but we also I think because
of this great history we have always to
make sure that we're not focusing too
much on our history but we're also
focusing on the future and so
anniversaries are those kind of
double-edged swords if you will or
opportunities is a better word for us to
also look ahead and so thinking about 50
years in the future while the title of
this panel is on space exploration I
think it's fair to say that all the
evidence shows that the next 50 years is
likely to be what really people thought
we were going to get to 50 years ago
after the great Apollo successes and
that is not just sending astronauts into
various places in
cislunar space but actually as a society
as humanity becoming a species that
lives and works outside off of the earth
so that's the lens I would like to use
for thinking about this panel and for
the discussion we're going to have
ranging from commerce and space commerce
on earth that's generated from space
using resources in space to enhance life
on Earth and again ultimately finding a
way for us to have a regular presence
for humanity off of this planet and when
you think about it with that lens at
least the way I think about it and when
I think about that lens we have to do
all the things that we do with every
other aspect of our civilization here on
earth and that is have robust
infrastructure have economic and policy
constructs that make things work or at
least work as well as possible and part
of that of course is making sure things
are secured in a manner that's
appropriate while also being flexible to
responding to new opportunities new
demand signals from the market and all
of those things that we care about to
have a vibrant societal asset in terms
of a new place to do things that we love
to do as humans so that's the very broad
lens that I'd like us to think about in
terms of space exploration and I think
we have a panel here that comes from
each of them come from a distinctly I
would say different background which is
exactly the point of a lot of enormous
panel and so what I like to do is is
briefly introduce them really you have I
think BIOS in the packet but I want to
say a few words about them and then I'm
going to follow that with an initial
prompting question that will be broad
enough to generate I think a lot of
reactions on the panel and then
we'll move on from there and certainly
hope to get the audience participation
as well so sitting on my left is
professor Barrett Caldwell professor of
industrial engineering and again one of
my closest colleagues here ever since I
joined Purdue and we've worked on
several projects in the other Barrett as
you know in in the space exploration
area and and so again I think you can
see from Barrett's background he brings
a really amazing perspective in my
humble opinion in terms of the human
factors part of these new activities
that we're going to do in this big
vision for space but also I think a
critical look on how information sharing
and information processing plays a role
in that and so I think what you'll find
from Barrett is very much of a
stimulating set of ideas that are going
to cause us to think sometimes less
about the physical things that we'll be
doing stuff in space but in many ways
the interactions between them least
that's my hope
Dalene Qiu is deputy for technology
programs at Sandia National Labs I had
the opportunity to meet Alan very
recently in person at Sandia and and I
just know from that short interaction
that he has sort of a deep background
in areas that relate to national
security in terms of the assets that we
have in space especially some of the
electronic and related components of any
of the systems that we're going to be
using in fielding but I think his
research background in his research
leadership at Sandia really is going to
be a great value add to the conversation
here because of some of the issues that
he knows are out there but some of the
mitigations that are on the horizon as
well next I believe this Carolin firm my
colleague and aero-astro she's an
assistant professor and
in our department and focusing on many
different sort of technology areas in
and around space situational awareness
and our ability to diffuse information
to protect assets and to understand
where assets are etc so again think
about space traffic management just like
air traffic management will be a
critical infrastructure and a critical
activity that we're going to have to
accomplish among many other reasons I'm
wonderfully happy to have Carolyn as a
colleague just before this I saw her in
the back of the room and I said Carolyn
are you ready to be smart and quippy and
she said aren't I always
my point was proved and finally cliff
Macklin who I'm very excited about
having on our panel because among the
all of our panelists cliff is someone I
haven't met yet so I'm looking forward
to a wonderful set of new ideas from a
colleague that I think is gonna be able
to share a lot for us as you can see
from the bio cliff as an engineering
fellow at Raytheon as any of you know
from our companies that have thousands
and thousands of employees he's donating
an engineering fellow means that you are
one of the very select few within the
company that have produced a
distinguished record and really beyond
the record it's a person that the
company relies on for new ideas and
charting a course in the future so I'm
sure cliff will be sharing some of those
ideas with us so with that introduction
of the panel here is the first question
I would like to put on the table and
that is in short in this wonderful world
that we are will be entering in for many
activities in space what could go wrong
let's start with the depressing part
professor Caldwell thanks for starting
with that so when we were talking during
the break said I'm not going to talk
about shooting at things I'm not going
to talk about
snicking flash drives in my three words
are unresolved stacked over we just had
a GPS talk roll over that not everybody
got the memo literally and so there are
people who are not appropriately reading
their GPS things that's a bad day I mean
we go back to the years and we've got
our men kneel flying around trying to
land and we've got alarms their date up
the walls fortunately it's a really good
pilot flying a really robust machine
with a few extra gallons in the tank and
so that stack overflow got there what
happens if we've got a cyst owner
program where people are not in
continuous coms worse yet if we are
two-thirds of the way to Mars for 62
Sol's into a Mars exploration you have a
space forward architecture so that most
of the problem resolution gets solved by
the crew and by the onboard intelligent
agents if they have a stack overflow
they have to start thinking about which
data do I support
and ground will help that's a very yeah
so I would say again you try and foresee
the unforeseen but again in a billion
dollar payload ok satellite payload
you're dealing with latent hardware
component failures that or just despite
your best efforts for qualification and
screening you're dealing with a very
harsh environment so some of these are
you know detectable and through
qualification but many times actually
you're dealing with just small
quantities of components right and we
all know how Intel and the semiconductor
business works is its massive volumes
but when you're dealing with very small
quantities you're dealing with
components that could possibly fail and
they have failed so certainly that's the
major concern okay and your customers
don't like hearing you know if
something's not working and again that's
the idea we try and figure out ways to
fix that likewise I would say flight
software again despite your best efforts
to make sure that your flight software
you've exercised various different
scenarios again things happen right it
to the extent that you gets locked in a
particular mode where you no longer can
point your telescope at a particular
area of interest to the extent that
again you do your best to do ample
testing but things go Murphy's Law
things go wrong
so I thought when I first heard dan
asking a question I thought one thing we
have to realize that space is a
different domain than what we are used
on earth who won autonomy is not a
choice okay so we are relying on highly
autonomous systems sometimes in the
percentage we have onboard astronauts
and they can do a few things but they
are extremely limited so we we are
relying on an autonomous system and in
order to run that we have to communicate
with it okay it's not a choice my
admission is not gonna successful if I
just send it up and never communicate
with them that's our definition of space
debris that so we have to keep a
communication channel open and that
automatically makes the system
vulnerable we know so as we are so so
far away from these things
scenarios as for example software
updates are very different it was maybe
the first time we had a similar scenario
on earth when we were talking about the
Nike shoe failure right the self tying
shoes I was a software update to start
them and that destroyed your I don't
know $300 sneaker and that was a big
shock for people here but that is kind
of the dimension of economic failure
that you have this is not an unknown
failure in in space that you change the
software you have to update something
and then there is no way of recovering
it and that that that leads to two
physical failure of your system to the
death of your of your satellite similar
to the Nike shoes that is not as rare
scenario as we have it here on earth but
a more common scenario the other thing
we have to keep in mind is we already
heard kind of the physical environment
it also means we are operating boxes
or computer towers flying around with
several kilometers per second okay I've
kind of bullet speed that means if
something goes wrong something breaks
off it's gonna damage or maneuver into
something else it's gonna damage wrong
that's a failure failure impact and
things like that and my saying is
usually you know nothing works unless
you make it work everything comes broken
right nothing just just starts to work
right so if you say nothing what what
can go wrong the first question I would
ask it's similar to what they what he
was discussing earlier with that green
and red slide seems like everyone paid
attention to that slide so those first
two steps being super critical
so my background again is embedded
systems a lot and cyber security in
terms of getting cyber security and
weapon systems and things like that
the first step is understanding what is
what are you expecting to get right and
I think that's a just to reiterate was
talked about earlier is that's the
critical step is to understand if you're
what are you what kind of risk are you
willing to willing to take on this a lot
of the contract that work that I do
you'd like to believe that cyber
security on on some of our systems is
gonna be like you're gonna spend you
know billions of dollars it is the
government after all so they must spend
they'll be willing to spend billions
dollars on everything and that's not the
case right these contracts are very cost
and schedule sensitive and cyber
security very often is a at this point
is a unwelcome guest very often right
then you're trying to put a radar in the
radar in a plane the idea is that it
finds targets and it helps you maneuver
and so on and so forth the idea isn't
that I have
function on there to text an intruder
and and that's not the really the focus
of what that product is for so again it
comes down to when I look at that even
in space whatever those systems might be
what are the what is their what is your
risk appetite and what are you trying to
accomplish you know some of the things
when you look at space from a cyber
curious cyber security perspective and
you start talking about I mean putting
people on another planet and things like
that and interacting you know one of the
things that we take advantage of
obviously in in everyday life and that
we're used to is the paradigm of being
able to authenticate when I can reach
out and touch that person right here
that that physicality is a is a huge way
of how we make sure things are real
right everybody's heard of the red what
red pill blue pill well if you have a
whole society somewhere else and all
your connection is through this network
of Technology and so on the
possibilities of what could go wrong or
that seem to be almost endless when you
start talking about the motivations
relative to financial nevermind the loss
of life and and what's going on and you
talk about with the elections and
undercutting confidence you could
imagine the impacts of attacking a
system like that when you talk about the
magnitude of investment as well as the
the national pride and all the other
things that are wrapped around that so I
would talk about what can go wrong I
really say okay what are we looking what
are we expecting to get first right
so speaking of sort of understanding you
know what could go wrong and what's
expected to go right I'm thinking back
first
to the Apollo this really fascinating
feature out right now called Apollo 11
it's in the movie theaters anyone anyone
okay
not once not many I strongly recommend
it I took my six-year-old son to it I
think fascinated and a focus it is not I
wanted to find the right word okay it's
it's not a dramatization it's not a
Hollywood flick it's a basically an hour
and a half long compilation of real
footage from the mission
you know from the from the capsule and
what the astronauts were doing and prior
to launch how they were getting ready
they're only really sort of voiceover is
Walter Cronkite but that's act his
actual voice over from the so really
fascinating and just time after time
every critical function every critical
part was actually going as expected now
we know later Apollo programs had
something different but even though they
were going into a relatively unknown
environment of course we we were at the
moon before Apollo 11 right he just
didn't land on it there was a very
well-defined I think in a lot of
Engineers and a lot of people
contributed to that one of the reasons
actually as an aside we're so proud of
Neil Armstrong as a Purdue alum is that
as you saw from when he returned from
the mission and the rest of his life he
always deflected the praise to the
people not only his fellow crew mates
but the people on the ground the
thousands of people in Houston and
everywhere else and the corporate
community that contributed anyway so
everything went well so take that and
building on Clips comment about how do
we deal with these
so now let me imagine 30 years from now
we have a permanent commercial presence
on the moon I want you all to visualize
this because you're on them I have to
react to it here shortly we have
multiple corporations and some
government operations taking place on
the moon there's a mining operation
that's the core of this vibrant
commercial activity and there's a
vibrant set of hotels in cislunar space
that are transiting people there's
Torres there's workers coming to the
surface lots billions and billions of
dollars are being made and prosperous
things are happening and then all of a
sudden on a sunny side of the Moon
Monday morning they discover a strange
black object 1 by 4 by 9 I expected more
laughter and shortly after that it
really didn't get reported anywhere but
shortly after that all called the
critical communications between that
presence on the moon and the earth
although many of the operations and even
the economic transactions of all go
haywire and there are multiple countries
operating also on the lunar surface at
this time and so how would you bear it
go about figuring out what went wrong
you owe me a beer after well I think ok
so one of the first issues that that I
would say is that everyone on this lunar
Enterprise Zone if you will had been
issued as part of their standard
deployment pack a copy of Heinen's the
moon is a harsh mistress
and one of the reasons is that actually
it's not that far off from one of the
scenarios that it's being played out in
hein ones book and this is obviously a
few years before
Kubrick took his shot the people who are
up there we'll start out with
representation and alignment with the
corporation or the nation that they
started with they will evolve fairly
quickly into a different orientation to
being whatever phrase they use lunatic
comes to mind to say we're in this
together and no one down there is going
to help us as much as us up here even if
you're from a competing country even if
you're from a competing corporation
especially if you then tell us that we
are not going to get any more edicts or
insights or recommendations from the
Home Office as long as this obelisk is
here they are going to have to figure
out how they're going to work together
how they're going to do local comm local
interactions
I don't know putting together regular
with for a little standing stone signals
but they're going to have to work
together and they're going to have to
have that sense of a local culture that
transcends wherever they came from
specifically to deal with these sorts of
interruptions
you still get culture well I guess again
with a kind of more of a nefarious mind
you know one would want to make sure
that all communications of all countries
are knocked out and it wasn't maybe a
suspicious implant by an adversary so
again you know you're dealing certainly
with any number of possibilities you
know could have been an EMP event that
could have knocked out all the
electronics so again provided let's say
you get the benefit of doubt that it was
something of an alien nature certainly
there would be in lines formed and we
certainly would want to interrogate it
and make sure that if it's giving off
certain emissions that disabled all the
you know capabilities abroad
yeah III would agree we would take a
unified front to certainly understand
and figure out what can be done and
maybe perhaps communicate with it to the
extent of maybe scenes out of you know
yeah I mean you put out these scenarios
so for one I think we do not have to kid
ourselves even in that scenario you're
not self-sufficient on the Marinette at
that point sure you're looking if
communication and transportation of
goods cannot be established in that
scenario we're looking at death of the
community on the moon I would go briefly
into kind of a philosophical viewpoint
here I would say no alliances formed but
more with Thomas Hobbes that life is
brutish and short and that kind of the
strongest ones will survive I think
there will be a very nasty time on the
moon
weaker parts are suppressed hunger games
yeah it's got some kind of more
tech-savvy small alliance of a handful
of people will trying to solve it on the
technical level maybe most or the
best-equipped ones from their home
country will take all the other ones use
this eaters at this point so I have a
bit more kind of negative view on that
when we want to tie it to kind of
nowadays we are looking into making
further moon missions as it looks at the
moment and maybe it's worthwhile to make
a comparison the computational
standpoint I mean we have even on the
old phones which were not start forming
similar computation power that what we
put on there on the Apollo mission okay
so that means the computation that that
we did and the software that we employed
we're very different the time we were
still did computing on the cards and
remember okay when we're doing missions
now it will be very different and I
think it will also make us more you can
do more things we can do that much
better in a sense but we also see we
make new mistakes if we're looking at
the Boeing max at the moment I mean that
was a way of giving more autonomy to the
system and we can do that because we
have better computational power but then
we are leading also into new failures
that the Apollo mission could not have
computation we're on such lower level at
that point we're also going to do that
not with one big spaceship but most
likely we will do that
was kind of a swarm of smaller
satellites kind of one bigger part
carrying the ass
swarming satellites which are supported
that's a much better way of doing it if
it works properly it's more robust
however it also makes it a lot more
vulnerable any communication I mean I
have wireless communication between the
parts of the satellites that means that
also communication I can kind of tap
into small satellite has very limited
capabilities Hey
makes it also harder to put on more
security on the other hand I have a cube
in space maybe you can maneuver a little
bit it has a large velocity so I can
still use it kind of as a physical
impactor if I want to just do damage to
it so I think thinking about the old
Apollo days is it's good but we're in a
much different place nowadays so what he
said this thing shows up there's no
communication and what do I do now right
so this is the kind of conversation that
that you would have before you've
actually put people on the moon
hopefully right so this would be the
this would be the state of trying to
figure out what what you need to go
right alright so if if we were having
hopefully this conversation if it just
happened once you've already up there
I will send everyone else first - right
if this is this this is the approach but
if if you've had this conversation
already it really comes down it's really
similar to what I consider you know just
regular architecture when you're dealing
with CPUs and things like that you lose
communication but in and of itself
that's information for people on earth
so you have an idea of you a protocol
between I would expect that you haven't
had this conversation a priori right
that you have a you have the idea of a
protocol right you'd have to you'd have
to know if you're not gonna be
self-sufficient with a certain
particular population you can limit the
population size based on what the
resources are you'd have a projection of
how many days you can actually survive
and your protocol would have 15 layers
of redundancy in other words I'm sending
things up there or physically making
that connection within a within a
quarter of that time if something goes
wrong right so I think it really you
know if your original question was how
do you debug the kind of what's
why'd you lose communication probably in
that kind of disaster recovery situation
there's probably another protocol of
survival first and then figuring out
later or just re-establishing
communication regardless if I have a
bunch of junk flying in the air that I
was supposed to be using to communicate
re-establishing that communication right
so I think this this is the it's it's
it's the it's the perfect question to
ask beforehand and it's often when I
work with customers sometimes and they
come in because cybersecurity is off
obviously something that people can't
easily measure often it really comes
down to what you expect to happen
correctly and the risk that you're
willing to take it's it's exact exactly
that question that I'll have with them
about well this is your architecture and
this is your this is how you think the
system's gonna run and they haven't
asked questions like that a priori
sometimes and you go and they tell you
how it's gonna work you say well then
you're okay with this happening well no
of course not I'm not okay with that
happening if all the communication comes
out and everybody dies in a week I'm not
happy with that well that's what your
architecture has right now built into it
I mean it's just you're not trying to
architect for this specific scenario so
it is a good place to start even from
when you're looking at cybersecurity and
trying to help somebody with their
system and you ask them what people
don't know about lease privileged access
you know protecting access and all these
it's defense-in-depth
and all these are basically a different
language to people a lot of people who
don't deal with cybersecurity but that
kind of question right there when you go
they know what they want to protect
though they know what bad behavior looks
like and if you if you pose it that way
very often okay you have this
information and it may go away for three
days because of X Y Z or you you may
lose this capability completely when
this goes out you're okay with that
that's alright and then that
conversation starts talking about
building that protocol and building the
systems and responses at the at the
detailed level and at the CPU ASIC level
in terms of what you what you're doing
from a system standpoint all the way up
to the strategy for the overall system
right so hopefully there's a plan before
you get there
so as I'm listening I do want to add one
more piece and Caroline I actually now
understand how dark dark can be and also
so I'll ask you again the next time I
need
but but no but know that there's a
really serious issue here about what do
we do and do we try to solve the problem
do we try to detect an isolate and
recover the problem according to our
standard mechanisms or do a bunch of
people go out and kick dirt until it
says okay land food here in the dust and
you can still have a telescope that sees
that and so when we think about what is
our response our response should be to
set up robust alternatives not just to
dig down into whatever we had before I
think you know we kind of documented
there's a lot that could go wrong I
think the word infinite was used and
that's probably the case but then cliff
and then embarr it started talking about
what are we gonna do about it you know
be prepared look at your architecture
and I think what you were trying to say
is also there's the robustness to the
scenarios you haven't thought of right
barek anything else the panel wants to
share I'd like to add one more point on
what to do about it and that is I think
this future in space will be one in
which no single entity owns all the
assets and so a strict sort of command
and control and operations model you
know it's probably not going to be
present so with that lens any thoughts
on what we can do better in terms of
mitigations and adaptations
harsh radiation environment so you know
redundancy helps but probably you would
also be interested in you know
collecting data analytics what are the
symptoms of the other you know
counterpart systems to arrive at whether
it might be specific to you know the
nature of the architecture or some other
parameter with respect to doing
Diagnostics and again you know if the
failure modes are all common then you've
got a serious problem
you know maybe they alien nature
well alright why don't we have some
audience participation start off some
reaction for questions they could be I'm
sure the panelists would field anything
from technology questions to philosophy
questions to science ok thanks for a
very interesting discussion of this
space domain so the problems that you
are defining fairly generic
you know early robust but these these
are genetic problems so are they what
would be a research agenda let's say I
want to start a new program research
program can you articulate a few
fundamental problems that are specific
to space in this area I can start yeah
thanks we don't know how to launch
Mission Control right now
every C cert every response team every
group we have is very human heavy we
don't know how to create intelligent
agents that are effective teammates with
a small number of humans that we can
split out some of the functionality but
we are not having a fight over control
so one of the questions is if I've
gotten actually I'm thinking about this
right and now for some projects how in
the world am I going to get agents that
know how to communicate with the crew
in reducing a whole bunch of data and
turning it into effective teammate
information and it's really hard to go
it's really hard to stay on Mars if we
don't have that capability because you
cannot rely on the ground to save you at
12 white minutes one way thank you so
when you say you know what's the weather
there's some research areas I mean we've
talked about some kind of generic
problems too right so one of the things
I would be asking first you know is what
is the specific problem that you're
trying to deal with right so if we
specifically talked about the
communications issue right in terms of
the availability of communications and
then there's the other aspect that he
brought up about that being working for
the aerospace and defense the idea of
sharing sharing isn't as as as
comfortable for me as far as
infrastructure and things like that in
space so if you if you tackle for
example the sharing of infrastructure in
space how do you give in a particular
functionality that you support assuming
it's not national security-related
as far as you know detecting missiles
and these kind of things intelligence
and those kind of things how do you
share infrastructure in a trustworthy
manner and what are the aspects of of
how you'd go about doing that I think
there's some very positive things about
it because obviously as far as this
example that you flew out from a
communication standpoint there's a and I
think someone else had mentioned there's
a vested interest in everybody making
sure it still works but there's also the
aspect of being an it being available to
everybody as well and you've got code
from possibly multiple different places
that are different levels of trust and
things like that so how do you how do
you create a an infrastructure that is
shared but at the same time trusted to
provide the service that you're
expecting out of it I think is a would
be would be a bit of a challenge and
this is best victim space this arises
this provides saying specifically the
reason why I think space is
is a is a big deal is like I said I
think you know one of the one of the
things that you do in networks a lot
right is for authenticity you well
there's two aspects of this for for this
particularly I do not deal with system
I've never I don't see a lot of systems
that are mission-critical like this is
mission critical in some fashion right
that as far as the defense and aerospace
where we we share even if we do share
there's other ways if that doesn't work
right generally right so if you're gonna
actually be in a situation where you're
sharing and it's mission-critical
there's there's a high level of trust
that's going to be required and that's
hard to achieve in a situation where you
don't control all the aspects of that
individual that piece right so that's a
how that works how you make that work
exactly I think would be a pretty hard
problem right so in and space I think
adds some new new challenges to that you
know one of the things that is you know
having a de band like certificate
authorities and things like that to do
authentication all these kind of things
you know it's easy to say well I got a
fallback of physical the physical aspect
of getting things to where I need them
to be but because everything is not you
don't have that physical aspect and
you've got this other party sitting on
your on your machine that can now
subvert maybe the functionality and
things like that it's a it's a different
problem right so for example if you
think think of like Spector and meltdown
right specter and meltdown are issues
because people can running code on the
system can do things to the system to
take advantage of the shared resources
on that particular system and not the
system itself but the processor itself
right in this type of environment you
could very easily see having code of
multiple people and now that that that
particular vulnerability becomes more
relevant than if only my code can run on
that system right so these are the kind
of things that you there's a lot of
problems I think to solve with shared
infrastructure especially if it's
mission-critical yeah and I'm just gonna
add also I think to do it in a
cost-effective and insertion ease
standpoint I mean right costs and time
in terms of you know designers wanting
to incorporate that because I mean the
whole thing about trusted systems is
there's an insertion cost right
and the bottom line is is that you've
got scheduled and these billion dollar
programs that again exceedingly just
have extreme pressures so so again you
know we look at our commercial
counterparts right SpaceX and so forth
how they've been able to expediently
deploy their their systems so right so I
think there's there's a lot that you
know government can learn probably from
how the commercial side is getting more
in the business on the other hand I
think there's a lot of government
regulations imposed on safety and I'm
not saying that commercial entities
don't have to do that I'm just saying
they don't have as much of the red tape
and bureaucracy and I think again
elements of automation in terms of
flight mission planning because again
these take months to years versus
incorporating more autonomy to have
things that could be done in a quicker
timeframe because because again it boils
down to cost and money thinking about
inter satellite communication just
cannot just have a specific what are
ways of communication that work under
those extreme constraints of
computational power very small processor
specific range more batteries what
communication works higher autonomy on
that as was mentioned before another
specific problem how can we have
external information on it if we are
losing
communication telescopes radio or other
systems and figure out things about the
satellite so let me know okay which
direction is not pointing that we can
okay thanks I just like to say wonderful
presentation I love the 2001 references
that's excellent enjoyable but
terrifying mr. Magwood I talking about
in regards to cybersecurity applications
on say theoretical human mission to Mars
you know back and forth you're not so
worried about someone sniffing reports
you know breaking in stealing your stuff
you're for my meds from Earth it's not
gonna happen but how would you go about
designing a system architecture that's
designed less to protect from outside
influences and more to protect the
system from itself while working while
presenting a way for highly-trained
laypeople who aren't necessarily cyber
security experts to correct system
errors when it goes about basically a
self-correcting you know different tools
for self correcting problems within the
system so a catastrophic meltdown
doesn't happen and everybody dies so
yeah so as far as I mean there's a lot
of issues I mean I understand the idea
of you're saying for sniffing ports and
things like that for entry right but so
you're worried about integrity is huge
right for what you're for what you're
worried about there so how do you keep
it up and running and not have a cyber
security expert sitting on board
analyzing everything as you go I think
it's kind of what you're saying just
reiterating okay okay so I think from an
from a from a from an architectural
standpoint you know you're talking about
trying to build in a kind of aided
resilience kind of thing right so it's
not like it's completely autonomously
gonna continue to run on its own and
monitor everything and and be able to
self-heal and and and move forward and
you're saying just with some help so I
think the keys in that kind of
environment is first of all from an
architectural standpoint
you want to be able to create some slop
is what I would call it I'm relative to
your ability to to fix things so you
definitely going to have to deal with
some level of redundancy and things like
that anyway the the the challenge with
redundancy right is that if people tend
to use it right and you fail over but
the problem is then what happens when
you fail again and then you can't fail
back over right so reconstitution and
things like that are important right so
right right at some point you're running
out right and there are state size
weight and power concerns and things
like that you can't make this thing a
bus right so in terms of the amount of
stuff that you drop on it so obviously
you what you need is you could say you
have tools and things like that my
approach probably wouldn't be this but
I'll tell you what I would probably
think you'd want to do but you could
probably have like things like tools and
things like that to do analysis that
obviously would have to take this
information and make it actionable
to to to do reconstitution I think if
you have laymen and things like that
you're probably going to break things
more than you're gonna fix things and
you don't need people trying to think
too deeply when they're in those
environments so in in most or as little
as possible right there's enough to
worry about as it is so I would probably
take the approach as some level of
redundancy probably more than one
depending on where you got for for size
weight power and your requirements and
so on and then reconstitution would be a
start-over type of approach and the tool
the the tools that I would probably say
you'd want are the kind of tools that
kind of rebuild you from a known state
versus trying to analyze and figure out
and things like that if you assume that
the environment is one where you're not
actively being attacked because you say
well you're too far away and things like
that if that's the if that's the threat
model you're working with you know one
of the challenges might be that if
you're running into things that if you
don't have an inherent problem which
you've developed then you might have a
supply chain problem which could be
which could be something you can't
really subvert after at that point you
might just be in bad shape you're just
trying to keep it limping along until
you get somewhere but again thank you
all for for presenting today it's very
interesting
thousands of years ago I worked on the
city and what we were worried about it
was being spoofed on earth you know like
you know crop-dusting I mean that crop
duster circles in the fields and the
electronic equivalent of that is
somebody spoofing us and making us think
we were getting readings that weren't
really coming from up there but having
said that I would urge you also to think
about I haven't heard people talk about
software and I don't I don't see any
breathtaking breakthroughs in software
yet these days and you know formal
methods they'll kill you if you try to
do it for something unless it's the
absolute smallest most critical code you
have and so I I would urge you also to
think about folks from the reliability
world and what they're saying in this in
this venue as well and the other ideas
about supporting autonomy of the
individuals of space it's a lot similar
to medicine and supporting a physician
with information about how to make you
know they typically have just a set of
symptoms but they need a lot more
support for more complex decisions and
so I really think the idea of supporting
the autonomy of those individuals there
with AI and other kinds of things is
really crucial but my main point was
about the software I'm you know NASA has
done tremendous work in the area in this
area but it's still a tremendous amount
of code that's unbearable on unknown and
you really have a Black Swan issue and
all that and rat's nest of software
that's been written decades ago and is
still functioning out there
well like it's yeah I mean it again I'd
your point about legacy code is a good
one I mean it's very expensive to you
know for that matter more expensive to
revamp the code and then frequently the
hardware so typically it's not touched
and and again it kind of boils down to
budgetary constraints as far as again in
the ideal world if you had infinite
resources you would try and address all
the possible scenarios but again even
for folks that we work with I mean they
always say well we'd like to kind of
know what your ROI is in terms of again
if you're dealing with a trusted system
what should we look at across the board
on our system that gives us the best you
know reassurance or resiliency given the
insertion costs because you know at the
end of the day I mean there's a number
of different circumstances where
including the trusted foundry right I
mean where there was a mandate that all
government defense electronics go
through that and it was yeah exactly
it's it's exuberant in terms of the the
ability for folks to adopt that because
Asics are very expensive BGA's or
essentially what everybody prefers to
use right and in that environment they
they deal with you know rat hard you
know platforms or triple mode redundancy
platforms to afford more of this
reliability again because you know at
the other day you're dealing with harsh
radiation environments you're looking at
things that you can put into your system
that inherently provides more resiliency
against failure but but again you know
still even in that circumstance you
could deal with a component issue where
there's just the latent issue with
capacitors so one other thing that I
would point out and if I think about my
experience working with NASA they spend
a lot of time on flight rules and flight
rule change
one of the big problems with software
that I I remember my mic coding days and
don't want to go back but what is it
that coders really don't like to do
document what is it that coders really
need to do document what do case tools
need to do even better is document and
version manage and self-updating
archives of here's the config we're in
now and here's how we got there and what
is the human interpretable documentation
and interpretation of our software and
to the extent that that documentation is
not available it becomes increasingly
difficult to even do state
identification so we've got to be able
to identify it we've got to be able to
archive it we've got to have human
interpretable libraries of where we are
right now I apologize if you talked
about this but you considered defenses
against the Independence Day attack that
notion that they're gonna insert some
alien is gonna insert JavaScript in your
platform it caused the problems right
but so that's kind of open e's are do
you guys have a sense of how you could
restrict software engineering for space
platforms such as a simple rule like no
interpreted languages has to be compiled
so I cannot imagine that NASA could
actually say you can't do this because
it's so complicated so many different
groups so many different software
projects that have to come together to
make a platform work do you can have the
ability to restrict languages coding
techniques methodologies and things like
that or is that something that we all
dream
oh there's lots of issues to think about
consider right so so but you guys are in
a position where you have an overarching
mission that has some really great
justifications for restrictions okay
it's hard to say that in many say in
f-35 type platforms you can say I'm only
gonna have this language in this
platform because I only have these
processors and these architectures but
you guys have a very hybrid architecture
in space especially in a sense on Mars
you can end up with lots of different
platforms lots of different modules lots
of different languages lots of different
things but could you guys come up with a
method to restrict the software
engineering techniques are being used
say from a security perspective no
interpreted languages is that feasible
or is that just beyond the capability
for the government to do it is that a
reasonable question you guys are all
kind of looking at each other I just
wonder if I'm asking there any question
yeah that's right yeah
harsh kind of radiation requirement that
that puts requirements on okay well what
kind of hardware do you actually fly and
connect so why there in that sense you
also have software requirements one of
the strictest requirements is kind of
computation power and speed and many of
the speed come requirements need you to
the interpreted languages as they are
just faster in that sense so I don't
think it's impossible to make a mission
requirement there I don't think we can't
have control about the commercial
missions that's difficult because I was
going to say frequently will will carry
government payloads and commercial
systems and despite our box being secure
in all efforts I mean if the you know
rocket blows up you know again you're
only as strong as your weakest link so
the issue is there's multiple players in
the whole space business right payload
providers to the
carrier and not everybody necessarily
has the same requirements so there's
kind of a black box I mean unless it's
again it's a critical system that the
customer requires requirements across
the board that's likely but but again I
think getting everybody on board and
again dealing as we talked about
cost-effective launches those are
challenges yeah I've been mean I think
you probably know this too actually
I'm talking earlier that there's
contracts obviously for different
different government contractor they'll
dictate the the languages that you can
and can't you use for sure but doing it
more from I think you're saying more
from a higher higher policy type of
approach in terms of everyone having to
do that and maybe trying to I guess in
my mind I'm trying to think what that
would look like and maybe coming up with
categories of different types of
software and then limiting those
different types of software possibly at
certain particular languages especially
the kind of length the kind of
functionalities that are required for
security critical type of things and
stuff like that I would I would expect
that that would be doable for sure in my
mind but again it would go back to those
first two steps of understanding what is
your strategy and so on and so forth and
really defining what is it what is it
you're saying you're accomplishing by
that right because if you don't say what
it is you're trying to accomplish with
it and so on and so forth it's hard to
tell what's good but but it can be
simple things like only ipv6 on the
platform so no ipv4 from the internet
could ever get onto the platform you
know that those kinds of restrictions
actually you're very protected and very
architectural restrictive which gives
you some control right no Windows
software on the platform no windows 98
you can't get rid of that right it's
easier to restrict old stuff off but
dictating new stuff and that ends up
being old stuff is the problem well a
long time ago was thought that ATM was
gonna solve a lot of these problems cuz
it ATM was the only thing running on
these devices nobody keyed in right cuz
there's no bridge but so these ideas of
building real protective platforms that
are income
Hannibal with external infrastructure
did can't use any of the same binaries
they're in the same interpret language
types work you know but but they're
difficult because it cost more money in
all I'll just interesting here one of
the big problems though is the testing
and advanced development you need to
develop will always put you in a watch
state that is several years behind what
is going to be state of the art and so
you're always going to have a
heterogenous architecture and the
watched architecture may be the oldest
one there so it's kind of hard to say
keep the rest of your platform in you
know the relative Stone Age my
experience with government regulations
on kind of technology is as it has to go
through the process it's kind of when it
comes into effect it's kind of outdated
at that point so I would rather argue
against it because I think it in many
cases the intention is good but it's
actually holding us back sure quick
philosophical question how are you going
to manage the conflict between the
architectural perspective of engineers
and programmers let me illustrate that
after a series of satellite failures in
2002 the GAO published a report
indicating two classes of threats to
satellites class one were unintentional
acts which included solar wind
meteorites in class two were intentional
acts like somebody trying to knock down
a transmission tower what they ignored
were bad software architectural
decisions and poor coding practices both
of which have caused problems with
satellites system Socrates said two
satellites we're gonna pass within five
hundred sixty four meters the actual
value was zero
the collision 2009 created 2,000 pieces
of debris when you hear a number like
564 you would think there's a precision
of plus or minus half a meter they were
off by 564 the architectural decision
I'm thinking of is that 10-bit week
counter which rolled over on Saturday
and it turns out that some 777s actually
had some problems with the date as a
result of that rollover that's an
architectural thing these are neither
intentional or unintentional threats and
I'm thinking that the did people who did
the GA report came from an engineering
mindset not a programming mindset and I
believe that would seriously jeopardize
any long-term space mission I'd like
your thoughts hardware software
vulnerabilities vulnerability yeah I
mean trust a supply chain right I mean
that's a given for any type of
government furnished equipment you
always worry about that and it's part of
the reason why there are captive fabs
because again with offshore suppliers
you aren't certain about the pedigree so
yeah I know within our industry there's
definitely things in place to obviously
not just verification but software
assurance and things like that a lot of
things that were that that are worked to
try to deal with those kind of things
and it's kind of neat that now even
though I'm pretty young guy as far as
I'm concerned you know they didn't have
cyber security I tell my kids that sound
like an old guy but cyber security and
all these things weren't a thing or they
you know Software Assurance wasn't even
a thing but you know all the
universities have it now right and
hopefully it only grows right so most of
the people writing the code still didn't
grow up with any of that stuff either so
in my mind I'm hoping that you know
through schools through the colleges
like Purdue and so on that this kind of
the practices that lend themselves to
avoiding those kind of things will be
will improve I mean you have to admit
it's pretty amazing that they got it
exactly to zero though I mean that's
pretty
it's pretty impressive you couldn't do
that twice absolutely
[Applause]
you