good afternoon and welcome to this
week's episode of the serious security
seminar today we have a guest speaker
who's had a wonderful I think a number
of meetings with some of our faculty on
on campus and excited about the
collaborations that could come out of
that for those who are watching on video
please take a look at the serious
website as the 20th annual serious
security symposium will be coming up but
April 9th and 10th of this year and if
you happen to be viewing this in the
future take a look at our website
because annually we hold this event that
it is open to the public so our speaker
today is Professor menu from Roosevelt
University welcome professor okay thank
you okay thanks for coming everyone and
it's my great honor to report on my
recent research work to professors
students here so hopefully I can get
some feedback from you and further
improve our research work so I invested
in years and Malay or our research group
Malay worked on ARM processors and also
security problems arm-based devices so
the major reason is the popular IOT
devices and i2 computing Internet of
Things cloud computing so the rest of
the computing trend those major trend
that will bring in more and more
arm-based devices so the security
problems are becoming a very important
issue on those devices so we have worked
on several security problems one of them
we think is very challenging is how to
protect the applications when the
operating system is compromised so
basically we can think about the
challenging problem I think I'm thinking
my career so I think more than ten years
ago when I first heard of
of challenging security problems well
the problem is how to run our programs
in a malicious environment we're in a
hostile environment how can you
guarantee your program your app is ok in
that hostile environment so this
question where this problem has not been
changed in the past decades we proposed
a lot of solutions but it's the hotel a
new problem
so today we just pick this problem
particular problem we talk about one
possible solution ARM processors ok so
that's the whole background so for so
why we pick ARM processors it basically
is mainly about the the recent trends
especially if you go to Home Depot
Walmart or Lowe's so Best Buy those
popular stores you will see smart home
demo area to go to that area you see a
lot of smart things like the Arlo or
smart doorbell Smart Switches
so those are all Internet of Things I
think every one of us already learned a
lot of it and they are becoming more and
more popular in our daily life like it
or not when I look at my home routers I
see 30 or more devices connected
including the Chromebook issued by my
kids like elementary school and the
middle school so we have everyone has
more and more devices those devices are
mainly based on ARM processors ok so
this is the major trend so if we look at
this picture also this picture is
probably in tonight so I didn't make it
so I poured this picture this picture
shows the family of Internet of Things
or smart devices and you see how many
categories how many different Internet
of Things or smart devices we are having
now and we are having more and more of
the daily life ok so this picture see
you can see a lot of movies recently
right
so sci-fi movies so the robots are
becoming smarter and smile
we have fighting with them so a lot of
people are really worrying about what
our future will be if they are getting
smarter and smarter
especially security plus the recent the
advance or development of AI technology
right so someday probably the robot may
beat us so if we took the act quickly
so that that's the one view of Internet
of Things or smart devices but this
picture is more realistic this is
nothing like movie so this is real thing
so many many years of not many so lot
like five or six years ago the vehicle
the first vehicle was hacked is cheap so
the Jeep was hacked is by researcher
unfortunately noted by the real hacker
the researcher hacked the Jeep and the
steering the Jeep into like off the road
and also the researchers demonstrated
how to shut off the engine when the trip
is running on the highway so it's very
dangerous so those are real threats
through our real life and recently and
Tesla this is very popular name right a
lot of young people they are considering
Tesla as their first car ever so that's
a big trend so Tesla was also hacked
okay so because the whole vehicle has a
lot of smart devices and the more
computer or the more processors or
bringing into the system then more
vulnerable is worth more threats we have
to face so that's very realistic
problems so if we look at the Platinum
platform so what are supporting those
IOT devices or smart vehicles or smarter
things the most of them
I'm not saying everything but most of
them are using arm plus Linux platform
or even if they're not Linux in some
kind of Linux or customized Linux so
that's the major platform supporting the
Internet of Things were supporting the
smart devices for smart vehicles that's
why we pay great
to the security problems of these
devices so this platform look at the
list here this platform are supporting
so many devices like digital video
recorders IP cameras like RO system a
lot of Motor Assist and Chromebooks so
my kids bring home Chromebooks issued by
their schools I didn't buy them but they
are bringing Chromebooks home and also
smartphone Android systems even iPhone
so I have phones daughter using Linux
but iPhone is using like similar
technology sharing the similar
vulnerabilities I'm talking about here
so those are that platform being used
being used by many IOT devices smart
devices and we are looking at those
platform and see what we can do to
improve the security so this figure
shows basically how many problems are
being discovered in each year and the
trend of those one our beliefs and next
figure
next slides summarize the major problems
so if we have security breach on those
platform because they are serving like
mission-critical or life supporting
devices like medical devices if the
medical devices is using arm plus Linux
platform they're compromised then that's
life supporting system
so let's life-threatening problems so
for smart vehicle either Chi also be
life-threatening problems so so the
major threats we're talking about here
will be once the system is compromised
the sensitive data is gone then once the
kernel is a compromised
oh the data on device is gone so think
about the smartphone as example I'm
using my smart phone for like a half
theta sensor data and also my bank
accounts so a lot of like sensitive data
and the critical applications in my life
the the solutions so now we think about
smartphones example I think was very
funny simple if I worry about the app
I'm using for example chase bank account
so transponder app or you a app so I'm
using you a app to purchase our tickets
so it will be connected to my credit
card anyway so if I'm using this app
under platform monitors so automatic so
are on the platform compromised that
there is no way I can protect the
sensitive data okay because think about
orbiting system if the operating system
is can romance that then there is no
security for apps there is no privacy
for apps operating system is serving as
the manager or serving as the god of the
whole Condor system once the kernel is
chrome resin no secret is hidden right
so all users privacy exposed then Oh
control flows can be modified so that's
a huge problem
so there are existing solutions so if
you're working in security area probably
you have heard the overshadow in attack
those are the popular solutions I mean
there are two examples of the popular
standard like it more than 10 solutions
okay so these solutions proposed if you
look at the right top red top the figure
shows the major ideas how to protect the
compromised operating system so I select
the damage from the compromised the
operating system I mean to the
applications because we want to protect
the applications in the situation when
the operation kernel is compromised
that's the goal okay so basically you
can see here we have here some solutions
you see the right top of the slides so
we can think about the motorisation
motorisation so the water ization idea
runs a hypervisor
whereas
whether below the operating system okay
so that's how we use cloud services so
if you rent if your rent Amazon ec2
services you rent a virtual machine but
your virtual machine is running on top
of a hypervisor okay so that's the cloud
structure or recorder ization structure
so that's great so basically if you
think about that structure now we have
layered software stacks so even if the
operating system a kernel is premised
it's still good we still have a
hypervisor below the operating system
okay so as long as the hypervisor is not
compromised we have something ok with
the higher privilege level then the
operation is the kernel to manage
everything okay we're still good so
that's the goal or that's the main idea
of protection so as writes we have
something with higher privilege level
than the operating system kernel we're
good ok so basically that's the key idea
of oh let's go back of resident proposed
technology so what relized running
environment we run the guest operating
system if the gas turbine system is
compromised
we have hypervisor so the hypervisor can
protect the application in the
compromised operating system that's the
key idea ok so any questions ok so the
idea is very simple and many approaches
are sharing exactly the same idea but
using different implementations or using
different implementation details ok so
that's the major work in recent years
for example overshadow is one of the
very popular solution using hypervisor
to protect the applications against
compromised the kernel so even better
even better so if you look at here Intel
SGX this is a very hot term in recent
years as yeah
provide hardware protection so the
processor has included additional
hardware okay so building a link called
isolated hardware area in the memory so
even if other part of memory is
compromised the isolated part will be
untouched ok so that's the idea of xgx
basically we don't use hypervisor but we
use Hardware additional hardware so
basically the earliest paper of icx was
published as we title have it it was in
OSD i/o 2014 so that's the earliest idea
using as Jack said SJ has become very
popular but the requirement will be the
processor has to support us GX and
another problem we don't talk about too
much about that problem today but just
remember we still have the citation or
problem for us GX so basically when you
interest reacts you leave something in
the cache when you get out the menu try
to utilize the information left in the
cache so it can create a set channel for
the attackers so it is still not a
perfect solution but it is much better
so basically I'm talking about
okay hypervisor based in solution or
hardware based the solution and the
third category is split split okay so if
I want to protect application the hub
but we build the application differently
or in different ways from other regular
applications so like you're building
additional shell additional protection
mechanism into the application that's
the third way and so basically these are
the three major categories to support
the protection okay of application
against compromised operating systems
that's the existing solutions so
the problem of existing solution is most
of them are based on Intel platform or
Intel Architecture so Intel Architecture
is being used by Intel AMD and many
other like server manufacturer they use
this platform okay but for mobile
devices like I said is ARM arm doesn't
have a CG X well arm was built it
doesn't support hypervisor okay so now
it supports but we have to port a
hypervisor idea in unto the arm platform
so we don't know whether we can do that
and is also a very high V solution
running on an arm think about hypervisor
if you are installing a authorization
class were like waterboxx okay when
we're on your laptop running water
machine it will be much slower okay so
it will significantly affect the
performance of your personal computer so
it's not a solution for high performance
computing or basically if we bring in
the hypervisor idea onto mobile devices
then it may be too slow too so for smart
phones or for smart devices okay you
specially think about the Smart Switch
how can we have a hypervisor smart
switch that's too heavy so not a good
solution so basically here the proposed
the solution is like we called trust the
shadow we build a protected application
area on the ARM processor so it's called
a shadowed area shadow area so we trust
that area so we protect that I really
guest the normal operating system so
this project is collaboration efforts
between Microsoft Research UTSA I was
from you can see I just the
muros built last fall so this work was
done when I was at UTSA and also Penn
State Florida Institute of Technology we
worked together to develop this idea
and they implement the system ARM
processors so we want to support the
applications without and the changes
modifications because that's important
if we want to change the applications
the our production will have very
limited applications so then the vendors
were the software developer they need to
change their application to adopt our
structure or technology so that's that's
a lot of efforts so basically we are
saying okay our protection should not
require any changes to the existing
application and also we want to use we
want to use existing operating system we
don't want to change anything to the
average system okay so we want to use
the existing application existing open
system so basically it's easy it's very
easy to be adopted on the existing
mobile platforms so before we go to the
full technical details or complete
solutions we let's look at the
background of ARM processors so in case
you don't to work on these areas so
probably you are working on AI so this
picture will give you some DeGraaf ok so
how the ARM processor looks like and how
much difference it is from the Intel
processors okay so here the ARM
processor so this figure is mainly for
ARM Cortex a series so our arm has two
series so cortex a is for mobile devices
cortex-m has last computing function
less powerful computing power then
cortex-m is really for devices like note
that smart so cortex a easy early for
mobile devices still doing some
computing and doing some a graphical
things so here this figure shows this is
the structure for both cortex a and
cortex am but if you look at the details
we mainly use this structure for cortex
a cortex a because cortex a has more
powerful processor than cortex-m so
basically we if you look at the red
color here the red colored red line here
be white the processor mode into two
separate world we call word so the red
part in green color you see that's a
secure word okay so insecure word the
change of memory can be anywhere can be
anywhere of the processor connecting the
memory space but in the normal world in
a normal world the access to the memory
is limited he's removed so now let's
think about a computer using ARM
processor electron book okay so for the
whole memory space some space can only
be accessed by the secure world okay but
oh space all memory space if if if the
secure word secure word configure allows
all space can be accessed by the
processor from the secure word but a
normal word normal word can have very
limited access okay they are not allowed
if the processor is in normal world the
processor cannot have access permissions
to all the locations of memory so
limited access so that's the permission
design by the ARM processor so basically
when we entered the secure word when we
entered a secure word we can do
everything we want if we go back to the
normal world we have very limited
functions okay
so that's the short summary just our
summary of it
so given this security design in a
normal word if you look at the table in
red color here this level means okay the
operating system kernel
is compromised okay so in the normal
word we have operating system kernel
compromised by the attacker already okay
so basically if the attacker is here in
the normal world like I said before the
attacker can not access the secure word
okay so the damage will be restricted to
the normal word only okay so that's the
hardware design by the ARM processor so
here on the right side if we have a
trusted component like trusted OS here
I'm writing trusted OS here but later on
I will explain is really not a complete
OS we don't run two operating systems
here so these trusted always just show
it serves the operation is no function
but we really don't have to operate
systems here okay so think about the
right side so if in the secure world the
attacker compromised
any component then the whole platform is
gone okay that's the situation we do not
want it happened okay so basically here
given this figure I'm saying the
hardware supports secure isolation
between the secure with a normal world
if any thing bad happens to the system
we wanted apply this thing to be
isolated to be contained to the left
part to the blue part okay so that's it
let's the go so given this hardware
support given this hardware support now
we can think about some possible
solutions so if so where is
straightforward very straightforward
okay so okay so the secure word sounds
really good
okay so anything we put in the secure
word it will know to be touched or
accessed by the attacker okay that's
really really good so why don't we put
the operating system and applications
everything into the secure world
then nobody can touch it all of them are
protected okay anyone tell me why don't
we let so does that sound a very
straightforward solution and then the
problem all south why not yes okay like
I repeat so so basically he is saying if
we install the application to the secure
world we're going to change the
application design right that's her
point okay so basically the installation
of application will also change the
operating system right yeah okay when we
try to bring everything to the secure
word actually we already changed the
application the operating system there
right
very good point so basically he's
absolutely correct and think about if we
are moving everything to the secure
world well in other words secure room
secure room we think this room is
isolated this is trusted the room then
we bring over here then this room will
be secure actually not probably bringing
some bad people here all right I'm not
saying you're a bad people but when we
bring in everything here everything to
the secure world we are bringing in
risks problems everything we are
bringing to the secure world ok so that
it's a guest our initial goal we cannot
do that so we must leave untrusted
component to the normal world we only
bring in trust the component to the
secure that's what we can do about it ok
so another comments for operating system
we absolutely don't want to move any
oberon system the Horace's me into the
secure what's the reason of that so for
software engineering perspective for
security perspective and the orbiting
system I mean except except the
the the customized I rinsed them more
especially the bad properties like ice
for most operating system they are too
large to secure
we have several millions lines of code
there is nobody to make sure they are
won or ability frayed absolutely secure
no way to do that
so so we cannot move with a whole
operating system into the secure world
because we are bringing all the problems
to secure world ok so that's why is not
a simple or straightforward solution so
we cannot move everything there we can
only move what we want to protect there
so only trusted applications ok so here
these solution erosion basically ok so
you bring the first point so can't
protect the legacy code ok
so if we want to move operating system
their application there there must be
some changes either to the operating
system or to the application right very
good point so that's the first thing we
cannot move everything in the secure
world and also additionally like I said
too large to secure and also doesn't
support memory encryption so I expand
this later because so so currently we
can think about was the when we access
was the kernel is compromised and the
kernel can access anywhere it can access
okay so like the normal word kernel can
access all space in the no more so if we
have trusted data in normal it will be
disclosed to the attacker okay so if we
have commenced kernel in the security
that is close to the whole computer
platform so that's the problem so let's
see let's look at these figure first
then we go back to the summary okay so
this figure shows you can see here okay
so we only move trusted application to
the secure world
okay then you see here at the bottom of
the transit the application the previous
figure shows the complete operating
system to carbonate but here
like I said complete operating system is
too large to be brought in here okay we
only have a random system so nothing but
a rental system as very small component
is a proxy is proxy it's just the
forward so okay so if we were making a
system call let's say ivory so as a
computer science major or a major as
long as you do programming a system call
even though here so applications will
make season come right open file close
file or send message here season call
then this random system will serve as
proxy okay is not a complete operating
system but it serves that proxy you see
here forward the request that would the
colonel outside the secure word so
basically I don't trust the kernel but I
trust the random system so please
forward my service request then the
service will be done by the kernel
outside the secure world so in the
normal world okay so this is the key
idea how we solve the problem but now I
have a question for you
so note that simple so looks like
purpose out so my question will be okay
so every application will make a lot of
system cost right so anyway I'm not
saying we do all system comes here
because I said already we don't have a
complete abilities to me in the secure
world so now all the work what most of
work will still be done outside secure
order so here
Liam's kernel but I'm marking the kernel
has compromised so we may ask what I'm
saying there you're still standing the
worker to a compromise the kernel
how the job can be done
what do you think
so I'm sending a Java to a person I
don't trust okay
so it's possible like I said open the
file then these compromise the kernel
will not open file
okay but the he tells me I open the file
for you but actually not okay what if it
happens
let's okay okay so I don't care so the
protection go here is I don't want to
guarantee compromised the kernel still
do the job I don't care whether it does
his job I only care my application here
my application is protected so in the
case of compromised the kernel my
information is not disclosed that's it
let's make oh I don't guarantee the
functionality of the kernel but in the
case of a compromised kernel I want
security
I want the confidentiality I want
integrating ok so that's my security go
so basically this is the protection
structure so basically ok I want to do
some system call i standard a SIM card
to random system then these proxy will
forward my request to the kernel okay
so regardless the kernel is compromised
or not is doing the job or not I don't
care ok you need to do the job do it or
not reply that's it okay so that's the
protection but in the case now we look
at the figure again so in the case that
the kernel is compromised you see here
the current comrades it's different from
existing system it different from any
existing platform this kernel can only
access normal world okay so this kernel
cannot access anything inside the secure
world that's it that's our code that's
the goal of our editor okay so it cannot
steal anything from our app it cannot do
anything to harm the integrity
of our application that's it my super
secret number is protected my bank
account is protected my transaction is
protected that's the goal so in case of
compromise the operating system my app
is protected that's it okay any
questions yes
so does it so where is the runtime
system actually is it running in like a
kernel mode state like where it has like
Sapir like a lot of power to it like
operating power what how does that work
okay let me repeat your question so he
asked where is the runtime system
I mean running here and how the
basically you're also asking how the
services are done like the addition to
the kernel functions what are the
processor mode and the water privilege
levels right mm-hmm your very good
question so I'm sure going to show you
hit you next okay very good very good
question so you must be in this field
okay very good so let's go back to look
at the quick summary so we have limited
time so a quick summary of our design
goals so basically we want the isolation
we want isolation okay so we want a
strong isolation using the hardware
facility to isolate our applications
from the compromised operating system
secondly we want to reduce the trusted
computing base so this is important like
I said there is no way to secure the
whole operation that's too large several
billion lines of code so now we want to
reduce the TCP will only guarantee renta
supported the protein if we secure it
proxy proxy has only five thousand lines
of code
so in our vertebral development so
that's a small amount of code we can
secure okay so it's lightweight so I'm
sure if you know ih0 attack io2 attack
so these are famous attack compromised
operating system kernel can use
manipulated return values return values
from the system call to compromised
application
so this is very smart so I do attack is
like serious threats made to
applications if the kernel is
compromised so our design can defend
against this type of attack because in
our workflow we can add additional
integrity check before we return the
values to the application so additional
security is added so not back to your
question so let's go to see okay so this
workflow hopefully I can answer title
our most of your questions so basically
you can see here now we have more
detailed view to both words okay so for
every processor design our acts 86 I
think most of us can remember the ring
levels right ring zero ring why ring two
and three those are four different
privilege levels or we can also say
those are different processor modes okay
so if you look at it here so we have SVC
that service both so you make a system
call ARM processor goes here apt that's
a port so basically if you're accessing
page note in the memory where invalid
page access that's abort mode so irq is
the interrupt processing mode here so
that's interrupt so that's the user mode
if you look at the dash line here above
dash lines user mode below that line is
privileged mode so actually if you look
at the arm reference manual so it goes
so fast if you look at the arm reference
value depending on the model of the
processor it may have more processor
modes here but here I'm just using busy
example to show for differing the
presence or most of a different
functions of processor how we arrange
how we arrange the privilege levels here
in our design okay so basically here you
see normal word if we
sir if we serve the application in the
normal word using the serious mode of
processor here we are going to have a
problem because like I said if the
kernel is compromised then everything is
compromised so instead here once we move
our trusted application to the secure
where you see here that's the monitor
here we have in the secure word then you
see the service we will be done in the
secure world so once we have a service
request or a system call it will be done
in the secure world using this path in
this path but the accurate service like
I said we'll go back proxy wheel forward
okay so you see here the secure does
have all the presenter mode like the
secure world will handle paging
separately from the normal world so
paging is about virtual memory
management basically you access a memory
page if he is not in the memory we need
to map with whom map or loads the memory
contents and update the page table after
the page table so basically here you see
here so in the secure world we manage
the page table you see the abort abort
mode handled and the normal word abort
so these two page table management are
separate they are separate so in case we
have compromised the kernel in the
normal world that secure the paging will
not be affected so the memory management
will not be compromised okay so this is
very important so yeah and even to the
presence remote isolation we also need
to think what a memory memory how memory
is protected in the case of compromised
the kernel so here this figure shows
better like I said these are secure this
normal world and like the manage the
memory management unit and
you am mu is for paging right so M mu we
have a two side of paging so once that
is for secure word one side is for
normal work so you see the different
color here as these four secur secur
word and in shadow so so you see here
that some isolation we can say they're
like no more area PZ is for trusted zone
they secure secure word is called the
trusted zone so trust the zone runtime
trust the zoom app so basically you see
that's how we map how we map the memory
space in the secure word and in the
normal world how they are overlapped how
they are divided you see we don't
overlap the secured and normal world but
we will need we need a somehow overlap
so I will explain what so the reason is
we we don't want to absolutely clean
isolation the reason is think about
system code what do we need forces of
God we need the parameters in the
parameters if you have this open a file
you have to tell which file you're going
to open right that's part of parameter
so basically so let's so let's play that
size here but oh so attached it starts
that's keyboard here so
so basically when the try tool let's
let's let's go to here here okay so from
here from this figure we showed we
isolated the secure water number work
but like I said if we consider system
across we have to transfer some contents
as the parameter and we have to accept
the result of system cost the result
sometimes is not only a single like
number sometimes is the contents in the
buffer okay so it's not easy there is no
easy way to just encrypt decrypt or know
to share the parameters using like
registers use you know fixed like a
restructure or something like that so
basically we have to overlap overlap
only a little bit a specific area of
memory between the normal warden secured
to transfer the system cop rameters and
the result okay so that's necessary so
here what you look at the figure is not
that I was truly isolated between the
secure with at normal world we still
have something okay so some area will be
used to transfer parameter and dirt
replies okay so remember that the next
step next step because we are having
trusted applications we are protecting
the parameters protecting the replies
now we need to have additional
protection about the application so
think about vacation because when we
double-click application the operating
system the operating system is the guy
who loaded the application but I'm
saying something something like paradox
or contradictory we don't trust our
buddy system
now I'm asking everything to load the my
trust did the application
how can we do that what a year for the
operating system changes my application
during the loading process that's
disaster right so we want the integrity
of the trusted process so here you see
here so we create a problem for each
trusted process okay
you see here that's the example so this
is example so this is the date structure
so if a programmer you probably want to
see it right the bottom part that's this
structure but the general idea is here
so basically we generate the hash value
we add a signature to the application so
one application is loaded we check the
signature to make sure the integrity of
the application is fine it's good okay
so no changes okay no two compromised so
at least but of course IDing the
signature adding hash value will require
additional verification in the
calculation when the when the program's
wrote it okay so that's the key idea of
how we protect the application of course
there are other issues so memory devices
interrupt handling
Paigey but we don't forever have very
limited time so I can let you know to
give you the references you can read the
further details there but that's the key
idea okay any questions yes so you said
like you load the entire app into the
secure world or which means it's a
memory slot which is like not accessible
to the user space basically sort of
right right so so like - you load like
the entire app like the app memory into
your earth
take your world memory or like only some
pointers or like some information of the
app into the secure world or for example
like some important files or like the
password file or you load like the
entire memory into the secure world how
that's very cool fashion so there are
lots of issues involved here so first we
still follow paging we don't load the
whole I said the whole application I'm
saying one never any part of the
application is needed it will be loaded
so we still searching when I go to
memory man I'm not like the entire
memory oh yes that's right that's right
that's right
correct and also you asked a very good
question because you mentioned the
keyword function function so for
security purposes there are some
critical things or critical functions
that cannot rely on an a untrusted
sources like random number generator
random number generator so if you want
this function we don't even think about
a compromise the kernel forget about
that so some functions so well I explain
the basic ideas I said oh the system
costs go to the outside let's go to the
normal world okay we don't trust I don't
care but actually we care we have
several identify the secure functions
say good not many
so only several we rely on them for
security work were for secure computing
so like I said random number generator
so we don't rely on the outside world we
rely on the secure word so we included
that function is that secure word so
that's very good point so we do consider
those functions so they are separated
from the operation kernel then they're
in their protected very good very good
question and thank you where is the
process actually verified is that in
like the runtime or
is it in the actual oh okay that's so
Papa to Wes Wes when we load the
application we were if I was but after
below that is already in the secured we
don't right so because due to
performance issues if we keep running it
so we're wasting our time right yeah
any other questions yes you made a great
point that it's highly desirable not to
force applications to be changed in
order to be ported what language should
I use for application for your platform
obviously whatever language you are
using now to develop applications
because like I said these platform is
supported like say applications no
modification is needed so keep whatever
you're using
so it's language agnostic that's really
great because this this is only platform
that adds it the enforce I mean
introduce a digital requirement to the
application that's really great okay
very good
so just quickly show you the evaluation
so this is the very popular benchmark to
see the performance we really need other
experiments but it's just through this
is the major major experiments to see
there is some other popular protection
mechanisms like link tag there were
popular were to coast so you see the
overhead here 2.0 and and you see other
numbers so our system has like you can
see the overhead here but the compared
with other system is is lower is much
lower and these figures shows for web
servers that's the overhead HTTP server
overhead and this the HTTP in red color
so basically the highest overhead you
can see one point one zero so that's
pretty much acceptable I mean
considering all the security benefits we
have right and actually even better if
you think this episode
who is going to read my super arm fried
worms so basically I mean look to me
it's pretty acceptable to me so so
basically our experiment is showing so
for those popular benchmark programs or
applications we are proposing or
implemented very practical security
mechanism on the ARM processors so okay
I think we have all right just I think
several minutes left right so okay any
other questions okay so just as a quick
me just gives them information so what
we are continuing on this project so
like I said before it's never be a
perfect solution so because trusted zone
is still isolation between two words so
when you're inter tries to access the
tribes own you are going to left some me
leave some information in the cache
somewhere else in the memory those
information left when you interacts it's
the I mean transiting between the two
words
will create set channels so attackers
may utilize those information left by
the application then to get some like
information from the application so he's
never absolutely secure so our solution
is only about the straw isolation it's
memory isolation but is not a solution
for set channels so we are working on
some channels basically we look at what
information are left after we inter
TransAm then how they can be utilized so
that's problem probably you are also
interested in so that's what possible
research problems okay so any other
questions okay thank you for coming
you