thank you for your introduction yes
I'll pronounce my own and my name is
Roland fungi strike day so that's why I
said Roland it's kind of hard to
pronounce for non Dutch speakers I'm
going to talk to you about the use of
elliptic curve cryptography in DNS XO a
completely different topic I work for
surf net as the national research in
education network in the Netherlands and
I'm also a part-time researcher so I
have a night job at the university of
twente which is one of the universities
on our network so very brief
introduction unless you've been sort of
hiding in a closet somewhere you will
have seen that DNS take has been going
on for a while now and deployment has
sort of taken off most of the big deal
the operators have deployed it and lots
of second-level domains are starting to
deploy it as well in some teal these
more than in others and I'm kind of
proud that in the Netherlands almost
fifty percent of domain names are now
signed with the in a sec but they still
has operational issues there are two
sort of operational problems that are to
do with response sizes and one is
fragmentation and the other is
amplification I'll give you a little bit
more detail about those in the next
couple of slides and the other one is
that the management of a DNS SEC signs
own is kind of complex and there's
complex key management involved I'm not
going to go into details but there will
be some pointers at the end towards some
more information about that now
fragmentation fragmentation is an issue
with many protocols on the internet
especially protocols that use mostly use
UDP like DNS sick and again just like
with TCP fast open there are nasty
middleboxes that stop your fragmented
packets from reaching their destination
and we did the study a couple of years
ago where we found it up to ten percent
of DNS resolvers may not be able to
receive fragmented responses and that
results in a degraded years experience
because people have to wait longer for
the names to get resolved and there are
already some solutions out there you can
configure your authoritative name server
a little bit differently if you're a DNS
zone operator because of course you are
affected by the
a bad behavior of the resolvers that
can't receive the fragment of responses
the fallback behavior in resolver
software was improved over the years and
the RFC that deals with how you transmit
large dns responses which changed in the
update 689 one where they said that if
you are aware that our firewalls on the
path or other middleboxes that model
with your packets then you should not be
asking for big dns responses so what
happens if you turn minimal responses on
what that pays off this is a graph for
one of our authoritative name servers we
had lots of problems when we first
deployed the NSA with people being
unable to resolve names in our zone and
that was mostly due to the large
responses and we change to minimal
responses and as you can see the average
response size from our third age name
servers dropped by about sixty six
percent but even if we turn minimal
responses on we still see fragmentation
and about Oh point one percent of
packets that go over ipv4 the red line
in the bottom graph still get fragmented
because they don't fit in a single
packet yeah the other problem with the
NSA of course and that's been in the
news a little bit lately with akamai
saying that this is now getting abused a
lot for d dos attacks is that DNS SEC is
a potent amplifier we did a study in
2014 because there were lots of claims
out there that the NSA had this huge
problem that you could use it for
amplification attacks but nobody had
actually measured it at scale and what
we did is we looked at all the NSX
signed domains in not condone net and
org and a couple of other T of these and
measured what kind of amplification you
could achieve with these domains and
what you can see the result in this
graph on the left hand side are our sort
of control group of domains which are
not DNS SEC signed and what we did is we
sent in this case this is the data for
any queries we send a two and a half
million domain
names that were not signed and any query
and then the average amplification
factor that you could achieve is run
about 5 we did the same for two and a
half million DNS excite domains and the
average amplification factor is
somewhere around 50 with outliers going
up to 180 times so the NSA is a potent
amplifier but is there a reason behind
this well we argue if the button helps
me oh sorry one more slide yeah so any
queries we could suppress right any
queries is something that you use for
debugging your DNS and there's actually
a draft circulating in the IETF to
deprecate the any query in a sensible
way such that you only give a very
minimal response as an authoritative
name server if you receive in any query
but if you do d in a sec you have to
communicate the keys that you use to
sign your zone to other people otherwise
they can't validate your responses and
that is done with a specific record type
called dns key and unfortunately if you
send all your key material that's going
to be a big response and what this graph
shows you is for those two and a half
million domains for which we did the
measurement study almost 40% of those
give you an amplification factor of over
23 and the 23 is sort of a magic number
because that is the amplification that
you could achieve theoretically if you
used classic DNS packets of up to 512
bytes and we deem anything that you
reach above that any amplification above
that as bad and forty percent of DNS key
responses that we got back exceeded this
limit and we argue that the root cause
for this is our essay RSA is the only
mandatory algorithm in DNS SEC it is
also the one that is most widely
deployed and the problem with RSA is
that the keys are large say a 1024 bit
RSA key already gives you hundred and
twenty eight byte signatures and every
DNS response may include several
signatures because you have different
record types in there or because you
have additional information in your
packet that also needs a signature and
then if you go to 2048-bit RSA the
signature size double
because the key size doubles and you may
have 256 bytes signatures in your packet
which means that if you have two
signatures you've already filled a
classic DNS packet with data another
issue with RSA is that we have to keep
growing these Keys there I think there's
going to be a talk about this in the DNS
session tomorrow the root zone is going
to migrate its zone sign zone sign in
key size to 2048-bit RSA and the key
signing key is already at that but the
majority of signatures in the DNS song
will be done with the zone signing key
so if the root moves to 2048-bit zone
tiny keys that means all the signatures
that you get back on the TLD referrals
you get will also have larger signatures
in there so is there no solution to this
problem well we think there is because
there are good alternatives to RSA and
the most obvious one is to use elliptic
curve cryptography now ECC has very nice
properties because it gives you much
smaller keys and much more cryptographic
strength as the slide shows you a
256-bit ECC group is equivalent in
strength to 3072 bit RSA but the
signatures are four times smaller than
2048-bit RSA signatures and actually it
turns out that ecdsa which is one of the
elliptic curve signature algorithms was
already standardized for use in DNS SEC
in 2012 with two curves one with two and
56 bits and one with 384 bits
unfortunately it's still used very
little in practice 98.2 percent of
signed dot-com domain still use our
essay but there is a lot of buzz around
it if you go to icon meetings or if you
go to the IETF then you will see people
talking about using elliptic curve
cryptography in DNS SEC and actually
there is one large operator that has
already deployed this at scale and it's
CloudFlare and they are responsible for
the one point eight percent of signed
domains and calm that
ecdsa and apart from ecdsa there is in
there are additional algorithms that are
currently getting standardized for use
in DNS SEC they're called ed DSA and
they have some even more favorable
properties in terms of mainly key size
when you transmit it across the wire so
what we wanted to do was to measure the
impact of if we switch DNS SEC from
using RSA to using a cc overnight what
would happen what would the impact be on
operations so we revisited all those
domains income net and org that are
signed we looked at in the amplification
study and we try to estimate what the
effect of switching to ECC would be and
actually that's very favorable if we go
back to the DNS key response sizes then
if you look at this figure from right to
left then the current situation is the
dark line on the right-hand side of the
figure that shows you that round about
the top 10% of DNS key responses that we
get for comm net and org zones don't fit
in the minimal MTU size for ipv6 and
round about 1% don't fit in the minimal
MTU or in the usual MTU so 1500 bytes
for Ethernet which is what you see for
ipv4 mostly but then if you would switch
to ecdsa then even if you use ecdsa with
a conservative scheme so you don't
change the dns tech mechanics you just
change what algorithm you used to sign
the zone then your responses will become
a lot smaller and all of them will be
below 1024 bytes or they'll easily fit
even into the minimal ipv6 empty you and
you can do even better because the keys
in the ECC are a lot stronger you could
choose to sign your zone with a single
key rather than using the current scheme
which has a dual setup where you have a
key signing key that only signs your key
setting you have a zone signing key that
signs that the names in your zone you
could move to a single key
in which case you could fit your dns key
response in a classic 512-byte dns
packet so the implication is of course
that amplification will be way less the
the red bar at the bottom shows you the
span of amplification that we saw with
the original measurement that we did and
if we switch to ecdsa obviously
amplification becomes less and as I said
we could argue that any should be banned
anyway if you look at the amplification
that you could achieve with DNS key
responses as I said any we can block DNS
key we need to do DNS SEC then the
takeaway is that if you switch to ecdsa
or EDSA then DNS key amplification
Israel is no longer a big issue because
you cannot achieve more amplification
with DNS key responses for this
algorithm than you could with a classic
500 of white DNS packet and I think
that's good news and maybe if we go to
ecdsa or a dds a based signatures we
could go back to classic 500 DNS because
we also looked at the bread and butter
of DNS so the a and quad a responses and
what you can see is that all of these
would fit in a classic fiber in 12 x
packet which if you were to use RSA
together with DNS SEC would not be the
case and there is of course always one
little problem unfortunately the
standardized ECC schemes in DNS SEC can
be a lot slower when you validate the
signatures and this is actually
something that they mentioned in the
RFC's they say there that validation of
ECC signatures may be up to I think they
quote something like five times slower
and it's actually a lot worse than that
the majority of sick RSA signatures that
you encounter today in DNS SEC are 1024
bit RSA signatures so what we did in
this table is compared eval
dation time for 1024 bit RSA signatures
to the smallest ECC group that that was
standardized which is P 256 and if you
use current software so current openssl
to do the validation validation of a
single elliptic curve signature can be
up to 26 times slower than a 1024 bit
RSA signature and that might be a
problem because you might be pushing the
effort towards the edges of the network
so right now validating DNS SEC
signatures is not an impediment for DNS
resolvers if validating resolvers can
run on just the same kind of hardware
that you were running your DNS resolver
on before but what would happen if you
switch all of the nsx over to elliptic
curve cryptography can we still do that
or is the CPU penalty on resolvers going
to be so extensive that we can no longer
do that and we need to upgrade our
resolvers and we wanted to find out
before we recommend people deploy this
at scale on the internet so what we did
we studied resolver behavior and we
looked if we could predict how many
signatures we have to validate and what
kind of cpu we would need to do that
validation what you see in the picture
here is the chain from the DNS resolver
towards authoritative name servers and
the number of signatures it needs to
validate so clients we took completely
out of the picture because the cache
takes care of that what we want to know
is what kind of responses does a DNS
resolver get back and if you look at the
picture from top to bottom you see that
the DNS resolver will send a query to
authoritative name servers and not all
authoritative name servers will respond
so we look at that factor first that's
number one the second thing we look at
is which fraction of responses contain
signatures because not all the domains
are DNS SEC signed so we need to figure
out how many signatures we get in anyway
then we measure the average number of
signatures / signed response and finally
we look at which signatures the resolver
actually needs to validate because if
it's Val
the signature before or if there is no
chain of trust the resolver doesn't have
to validate the signatures so it doesn't
expand CPU cycles doing that what we did
was we measured this on production
traffic so certain it is a medium-sized
network operator we have about 1.2
million end users on our network and we
operate resolvers for these people and
what we did was we took the traffic that
is flowing towards one of our production
resolvers and we sent that traffic to an
instrumented DNS resolver and what we do
is we measure the number of outgoing
queries we instrument a resolver to
measure how many signatures it validates
and from that we try to predict what
happens if we switch it over to elliptic
curve cryptography and we observed all
of this behavior for the picture that we
had with the ditches one two three so
oldest the various variables that are in
there and what you the takeaway from
this picture is that it's mostly linear
behavior so to take an example diagram
number one on the top and left side
shows you that the number of responses
that come back for every query that the
resolver sends to towards authoritative
name servers on the internet and it
turns out that about ninety percent of
queries that an authority that the
resolver sent out to authoritative name
servers get a response and because this
is mostly linear we can use this to
predict future signature validations so
we wanted to evaluate two scenarios and
the first scenario is for current DNS
SEC deployment if we switch that to ECC
overnight what would happen well it
turns out that on a moderately busy
resolver and our busiest resolver
processes around 20,000 queries per
second we require about 150 signature
validations per second and that is
easily doable on modern hardware the CPU
won't sweat if you do that however what
if dns egg becomes you
success overnight and one hundred
percent of domains on the internet
enabled the in a sec what would happen
to resolvers in that case and we wanted
to study a worst-case scenario and the
worst-case scenario is where popular
domains and we measured what popular
domains are so let's say google com
deploy DNS SEC first right because that
means that the majority of responses
that we get we will need to validate
signature zone now if you look at what
is popular you this is a plot of the
popularity of a query name so how many
queries we see for it versus ranking and
popularity and then what you see is that
his disease was called a zip or a long
tail distribution and that means that
the most popular domains are responsible
for the vast majority of queries and
this is a log-log scale so it becomes a
line but if you plot this it looks like
a curve that has a very steep drop-off
towards the end and we looked at two
kinds of DNS resolver software to see if
we could predict what the impact would
be if people switch to ECC we looked at
two kinds of software we look at unbound
from an outlet labs which is the
software that we use it's a dedicated
open-source resolver only package if you
you've never heard of it you have never
looked at it please have a look at it
it's really good software we really like
it and what you see in this graph is a
prediction what would happen for various
amounts of DNA sick deployment the plane
that you see is the threshold of how
many ecdsa p38 for signature so those
are the signatures that require the most
cpu time we can validate on a single
core so and on a single core we can
validate about twelve hundred signatures
per second but then if you look at how
many signatures we would need to
validate then you see that if dns a
deployment grew to a hundred percent
based on the real world measurement
later that we have we would still be
able to validate all those signatures on
a single CPU core so that means it's not
an issue we can deploy ECC overnight and
it wouldn't kill a resolver which is a
great result but then we also looked at
bind which is still I think the most
used software for DNS on the planet I
think their market share is still around
about fifty percent if I remember a
presentation by Jeff Houston correctly
and what you see there that there is a
slight problem if the nest egg
deployment were to grow from its current
state where it's at now to round about
ten percent deployment and we're
currently about three percent bind would
struggle to validate the signatures on a
single CPU core but that's not the whole
story because it would struggle to
validate the signatures for the most cpu
intensive algorithm that we have which
is P 384 and actually in practice people
will most likely use the other one p 256
because it it is more than strong enough
and actually if you look at the large
operator that currently deploys ecdsa
CloudFlare they use p 256 and there are
other lines in the graph you can have a
look at them in the slide deck the slide
deck will be online show you what what's
the case for p25 sick and even bind
won't struggle with be 256 so again the
takeaway is we can safely switch to ECC
without killing resolvers so what does
that mean well I hope I show to you that
twitching to ECC is highly beneficial
and tackle some problems that we have in
the NSF and both amplification and
fragmentation are a result of DNS SEC
responses being much larger than classic
DNS responses but if we go to elliptic
curve cryptography that's no longer the
case and it could even bring that good
old 1983 512 by DNS back because we can
fit most of the responses that we would
need in a smaller packet the impact on
resolvers is well within reason in there
impro many improvements being made to
elliptic curve implementations and for
instance cloud fair who have deployed
DNS SEC on their infrastructure have
contributed an improvement to openssl
that speeds it up by about a factor of
four there are still some open issues
and the biggest of these is resolver
support for ecdsa so not all dns
resolver software currently supports
ecdsa and Geoff Huston and George
Michaelson from a Phoenix have done a
measurement on this and right and now
about eighty percent of resolvers out
there support this but that still means
that twenty percent don't support it and
that's mostly due to intellectual
property fears some linux distributions
such as redhead in older versions do not
include elliptic curve cryptography that
they were going to get sued because of
intellectual property on elliptic curves
but fortunately all modern releases
support ECC so what would it mean for
you as operators well what I would say
is DNA sick deployment currently is
around about three percent of domains
worldwide so that means ninety-seven
percent of domains are not yet d NSX
signed and if you're planning to deploy
DNS SEC then my recommendation would be
don't go with RSA sign with ecdsa p 256
or if you're waiting a little bit longer
go with one of the ed dsl algorithms and
if you have an existing deployment you
should start thinking about switching to
ecdsa unfortunately that is not trivial
because it requires you to do something
that is called an algorithm roll over I
don't have time to go to the details
look up the RFC it gave me a headache
but we will be doing this in 2017 so
hopefully we'll post a series of blog
entries about that that will make life
easier for you if you want to do this if
you operate the in estrus over so if
you're a large network operator you
operate the NS resolvers for your
customers check and if you do the nsx
validation please check if your resolve
or support
ecdsa if you don't yet do DNS SEC
validation but you're planning on
deploying it make sure that the software
that you pick and the platform EU
support elliptic curve cryptography this
is therefore for reference the slides
will be up as I said these are some
papers that give you much more detail
about all the issues that I discussed in
the talk I would like to point you to
our blog DNS a surf netanel which is
currently horribly out of date but which
we will be updating when we do our
algorithm roll over so when we switch
our infrastructure over to ecdsa we will
be posting entries on our blog about
that so that you can learn from our
experiences and hopefully you won't have
to learn from our mistakes that's it I
would like to acknowledge the work of my
master student Casper Hagaman who did
all the measurements and with that I
open the floor for questions like
Sinatra yes net a nice talk thanks for
that I think one other thing you're
going to have to look at as a signers
whether your registrar supports ecdsa
not only are there a lot of registrar's
out there that do things like common net
but they still don't support DNS SEC at
all but even a lot of the ones that do
don't support the elliptic curve
algorithms unfortunately there are three
or four or do I know Google domains does
and godaddy those are just the ones I
know that do support it so you have to
be careful with that as well yeah that's
that's actually an excellent point we
just submitted a paper about that
particular issue to a conference and
unfortunately I wasn't able to include
those results but it's an excellent
point yes your registrar needs to
support the algorithm which you sign
with and for instance for cloudflare we
see that this is actually hampering
adoption so about from the top of my
head forty percent of the domains that
were signed with their surface don't
have a full secure delegation because
the registers don't support ecdsa
delegation so it's an excellent point if
you sign check for that
Ryan Ryan rotten conversent what is the
failure mode when resolvers don't have a
note version of open SSL or their crypto
library that supports ECC validation the
failure mode in that case is that they
don't validate the signature and you
will get a response without the
so-called ad bit set so you will still
get a valid response it won't be treated
as bogus but the signatures won't be
validated either any other questions
okay thank you very much for your time