wait I'd like to invite two of the three
winners of our hackathon so we hit a tie
for second place and we're going to have
both both of the teams that tied for
second with 15 votes present today I'd
like both of them to come up to the
stage and then tomorrow we'll have the
first place hack presenting in the
plenary session
alright and first I'd like to invite
John Kristoff representing team black
hole route monitor to give us an
overview of his hack thanks Sean so I
should first say one of our teammates
created a presentation yesterday which
I've messed up because they use a
different application so I had to kind
of recreate that but hopefully I
captured the the highlights of that but
we we had perhaps a nicer looking one
that I'm showing you today but so there
was an idea that I had for the the hack
yesterday involved something that
derived from a research paper that i had
read a few weeks ago where some
researchers were trying to study
patterns a behavior for black hole
routes at a few internet exchanges and i
thought that well that was interesting
wouldn't it be nice if we could examine
black hole routes from not just in
exchange providers but from all ESPYs
who provide some interface via looking
glass or a route server and could we do
something with that data if nothing more
than just some sort of feed or view of
black hole routes sort of being
announced throughout the world at places
and points all over so my present idea
and a handful of people seemed
interesting that for one reason or
another not actually for the same
reasons that I was and so we came
together and started hacking away on
this so that was our initial plan was to
first go around and find where we could
get these black hole routes from so some
some places you can get them be
examining next hops other places you can
examine community tags and so I
initially thought we would be doing a
lot of screen scraping and parsing very
unique and distinct interfaces and then
pulling that data out and putting in
some database and then doing something
with it building tools and so forth it
seemed to be a little complicated a
little bit hacky to try to do that but
it was a hackathon so I thought that was
a good place to undertake that effort we
I'll skip over a few slides because we
have a few but we had when team member
who might say is a little bit of a
ringer who came to it to us with a
product that they literally had helped
develop a woman from kada
must have found this idea intriguing
because there was some synergy between
the tool that she had worked on called
be Jimmy stream and the idea that we had
of pulling why call routes out of GDP
data so this in fact ultimately was
going to save us a tremendous amount of
time because this provided us an
interface into routing data that kada
collects and aggravates for multiple
places including ripe and route views
and some other places and that allowed
us to literally just build very short
pieces of code that would tie in pulling
out information based on again either
community tag or a next-hop address and
so just showing you some sample code
literally there was not much more to
some Python code than what you see on
the screen there so that seems a
tremendous amount of effort and it was
almost like we were partially done for a
lot of that back-end work so that was
very cool so we once we started
collecting that we started putting it
into database we built a simple schema
that just simply had a tag of where this
data came from whether it came from
addie kicks or a level 3 or whoever the
timestamp the origin ASR the actual
prefix that was announced as a black
hole and then we could do things with
that data then we can create text-based
feeds and top 10 reports built to a web
interface and a couple of people on the
team we're thinking of using this data
not so much just as sort of insight and
as a curiosity but to build something
that they could use on behalf of their
customers when a customer calls them
about questions whether the website is
down or why they can't get to something
or why traffic is not being delivered to
them so most likely many of you heard of
The Who am I command on UNIX and so we
came up with a am i dead command for our
black hole route server so you could
check if to see if something is actually
being black hold somewhere the internet
or not so we have this nice cool fancy
logo that has the spinning wheel of
death just I don't know how well you can
make some this out but just a quick
screenshot of like what the database
looks like this doesn't come off very
well the fonts real strong but here's
some top 10 reports that we were doing
there was a web interface and I think
this still might be accessible I don't
know how much data is actually in there
but you can you can try the link on that
and see if you can
at up for at least the next couple of
days or so so that's kind of what we
came up with and it's not fully done but
it was something that we felt we'd made
some progress on and hopefully you'll
see some more of this from me and
perhaps the rest of the team so if you
have any questions about it you can come
fighter or I'll point you in the rec
shin of one of our team members down if
you want to talk more about how to make
use of this data okay thank you great
thank you