alright close your eyes and imagine with
me if you will you've just finished a
major router maintenance you've just
finished all of the upgrades you've
needed you plan this for months you've
got everything just right and you jumped
on the plane and you flew to Hawaii or
Tahiti for that much-needed vacation
you're ready to relax everything is
great you just finished your massage and
you walk back into your hotel room relax
as ever and then you hear that sound
your phone buzzing and vibrating oh they
took out all the animations and just
then you look at your phone and you see
this that string of text messages that
all of us dread hey Peter I'm getting
some weird alerts oh crap something's
wrong I need you right now 48 missed
calls answer your phone right now
everything is on fire the site is down
what did you do how many of you have
been in that position before raise your
hand if you've ever walked out gone home
from work and the router went down
afterwards for those of you who've never
had that problem please come talk to me
I would love to talk to you but I want
to know what you're doing that I'm not
well that is our motivation and the
impetus for the tool that we wrote
during the hackathon yesterday called
take off its pre-fight validation and
verification before bringing a router
back into service which chris will talk
about now hi I'm Chris so we all have
preflight checks we bring a new route
into production generally if you you
bring your new device you turn the
routing protocols or or cost them out
you do something to make sure this thing
is online but not taking production
traffic those pre checks is like those
pre flight tests most of them are
performed by human beings you have a
checklist you log into the router you
run commands you check the tables make
sure things look saying interfaces up
what have you why is this work being
done by humans right there we go so what
lessons do we can we take from say
software development software
development has continuous integration
and unit testing you
to make them change to a code you run a
standardized test harness which runs
through a set of standardized test
modules and tells you if anything is
amiss so take off is that idea applied
to operational state so we built a
harness a test harness framework now I
put the word unit testing in quotes here
because I'm not using any of it we're at
work we're developing in Python but
we're not using any of the standard test
case modules I've heard this morning
that one of our team members is actually
working on doing exactly that so
hopefully next time represent this there
won't be any quotes there so we
developed a standard a standard class
signature a superclass that a module
that you would write would inherit from
you can so anyone can write through our
modules and add them to a test suite you
can run run the test stand alone or as
part of a automated device turn up so
you've got a script that hits your
device and removes is is overload you
can have it load this module and execute
the test runner immediately before that
and stop if anything comes back false
use it to augment your manual manual
checks automate your final sanity checks
immediately before so if you tested it
in the morning and things look cool
something broke between that time in
your test window hopefully this can help
you catch that so here's an example of
what a sample test class looks like
there's a standard method signature
standard methods that get called based
on the success or failure of the test
you've written and your tests can do
anything it gets handed an ssh session
to the device that you can execute
commands on you can compare router state
to your offline source of truth run ping
tests whatever whatever you want to do
here so if one were to write a test you
know develop your code here's a gamma
file to the test runner references to
use standard python class class pat's
classpath syntax here to point it to
your tests and you can write device
specific tests or
device nonspecific tests it'll run it
will run both the common and whatever
platform you give it there's a fake one
then there too just for testing get that
in and then run your test you give it a
platform name and a router name it it
runs through the tests reports reports
wit past reports what failed get
additional debug info if you like so
take the code and let's go so obviously
Chris and I are peer talking about this
but this was the work of a team and the
team was actually folks with varying
levels of programming experience from
just beginning or just out of school too
many decades worth and I think one of
the things that we really learned about
this is that even in just seven short
hours we could build something that was
actually meaningful and can make our
lives better so if you haven't done this
before if you haven't programmed before
you should definitely join in and learn
some ways you can do that so you can
joins the the net engine code group on
facebook the tak take off at nana group
on facebook or you can download the code
for this specific project on github it's
proof of concept now but we can keep
making this better with help from people
like you and maybe just maybe in the
future your next vacation won't be
interrupted thank you
you