tears okay folks so I know how hard it
is post lunch so we're going to try and
perk you up a bit and make this as
interactive as possible because I know
how sleepy i get after lunch okay so who
work for a security vendor okay infosec
teens okay sis admins and what what are
the rest of you a side of humans no okay
you're very quiet okay cool so first of
all a bit about me I like to scare
people this is another key post-lunch
technique scare people with a giant face
so I'm lead data scientist at a security
company called sensor net we do we're
working on a unified platform for web
multi-factor and email and water come
I've been a longtime community organizer
and presenter mainly in the sort of
Microsoft at don't hold it against me in
the microsoft and the our worlds and for
my sins microsoft made me a data
platform MVP if you're for the people
who
came to the our session today I'm
starting to we're starting to organize
worldwide conferences kind of similar to
the London b-sides and the whole besides
franchise and they'll be free on
Saturdays very cleverly named as
consequence I put a lot of stuff on
github so all the materials from today
including my workshop earlier and
various other presentations can all be
found on there I blog you tweet so you
know if you want to contact me
afterwards you can and I have little
business cards down there as well here's
what we're going to cover today because
I wanted to look at ways we can improve
how we're doing things with our security
data so we're going to look at the
actual data problems that we maybe have
right now and then look at people
processes and tools so the key things
that make up how something gets handled
okay so data
we have an increasingly large amount of
devices between BYOD and Internet of
Things there are there is more bits of
data traveling around and with all those
disparate streams it's getting quite
tough to actually bring it all together
and analyze it so that's one of the key
challenges for me is how do we get stuff
in a consistent format and how do we
even get things like consistent date
times together software then come out to
our but the cyber security software
market is massively growing and we've
got new vendors all the time so it's no
longer you're never just going to have
one bit of security software you're
always going to have multiples and you
need to get that data out to those
different systems and into something
where you can combine them together cuz
yes many attacks are on a single front
but that's not always true and being
able to get data and provide that
broader view point to supplement the
information from one friends with
another very handy and we need to be
able to access that from our software
and then grab the World Economic Forum
produced like a Gartner Magic Quadrant
of risks
and one of them is cyber attacks you
know it's a leader in world risk so we
need to be increasingly vigilant and I'm
sure I don't need to kind of be bang
bang glass eyes on that point otherwise
you will not be here learning how to do
your jobs better ok so what people
should be or can be involved in helping
your organization get better with data
so one of the key people is actually bi
analysts the people have business
intelligence departments or report
chimps or you can call them any
disparaging name you like but their job
is to make numbers look pretty yeah okay
so these people their job for a living
is to get data from different sources
and put it into a consolidated format
and build reports and get insight out of
it so if you're stuck and you want to
get more value out of your data then
it's worth going and feeding them some
cakes bribing them and getting them to
help you because they are experts in
what you're trying to achieve in terms
of getting the data consolidated and
then you've got data scientists like me
you know I'm missing my mac and my
blazer and I'm not from San Francisco
but they're statisticians data miners
these are people who can help you get an
expected in sight out of your data
but they generally need the data to be
consolidated in some format because most
data scientists are not data engineers
yet another hip term and they find it
difficult to bring that data together
and it's always worth remembering that
when we're when we're actually working
on being better with how we're
processing our data is thinking about
who the specific audiences are the
information I give to my sis admin is
very different to the information I give
to my CEO about the latest level of
denial of service attacks that are
coming into the business and again this
is actually where a bi person can help
you get and get more practice at
pitching the right level of
notifications and content because it
says admin needs things that they can
act upon to make the system safer yeah
infosec people usually need to be able
to verify their actions are taken and
work in a often an audit type capacity
and you see EXO's needs high-level
reassurance or their pants being scared
off so that they give you plenty of
budgets I
so the process is I really like coffee I
wish we had more coffee you all could do
with some right now because like me
you're feeling that slump that's trying
to get you to just snooze but to be able
to get better with data we need
processes in place that actually help us
a make sure we don't miss anything B we
do it in usually in a compliance and
auditable fashion and we need to be able
to actually ideally move fast and do
that whole agile bi agile development
type stuff so the first thing is how do
you construct that YW from a process
perspective and the aim is to get is to
have a regular check that says can I get
some data that supplements my existing
information so gives me an added
dimension like if i get if i can manage
to get have I been pwned data via the
API can I be combining that with my ad
to be looking at potentially compromised
accounts and be able to act on them so I
can supplement my existing data with
another source to get something that is
really difficult otherwise can I get
data that compensates for a flaw in my
existing process so with sensor net we
have proxy we have agents that sit on
machine on people's machines but that
doesn't help when people are trying to
get to assets that are
from machines that aren't on the network
or known on the network so we can
compensate by adding in the access logs
from those assets to identify the gaps
in a agent deployment process and then
informed so if we've got lots of
activity about that a specific person is
performing then they might look quite
dodgy you see this person going to box
Dropbox and a whole load of ever FTP
sites and things anything what the hell
are they doing why are they going to
these sites and it's only when you
actually bring in something like their
ad like the ad schemer and see that they
are that they work with partners or
brokers that you see that actually
they're just disseminating information
as they'd expect so being able to give
that added dimension really helps okay
when you're building that view
there's a few things that you really
need to focus on one is the ETL pipeline
to us extract transform bloat standards
like database jargon what your process
needs to take into account is how do you
get data ideally programmatically what
transformations do you have to perform
to get it into an acceptable format and
then where are you storing it and of
course when you're producing all this
information there's a lot of potential
for personally identifiable info to be
going through so with sense that stuff
we monitor application actions so we
actually get a lot of email addresses
and potentially sensitive comments
between people in the details so we have
to be very careful about how we secure
that data and your own internal data
sources need to be thought about in a
similar way and then time it's actually
it's really hard to get an accurate
chain of events when all your servers
are reporting different times okay it's
actually quite hard and you should give
some thought to it as to how to make
sure that everything is reporting the
right time
and acquisition and prototyping so as I
said earlier there are a huge amount of
software vendors out there now and
there's more of us every day what is
going to have to become more important
is avoiding vendor lock-in but also
always being ready to pick up a new one
so instead of going I am a Microsoft
shop and they're never ever buying
another piece of software and less
Microsoft have shipped it it's being
able to work out what works for you I
would say the open source solutions are
always a great place to start so if
you're worrying about security try the
metasploit open source edition or the
community edition and use that to pen
test your stuff don't use open sources
and community editions a lower cost of
acquisition to be more willing to try
stuff at it gives you more data it gives
you more insight and hopefully it gives
you better security by being able to try
a lot more and that comes with the thing
of prototyping even big vendors will
depending on your size and how much you
can use them will usually give you a
proof of concept time if you can work at
trialing stuff to see what data what
insight you can get out of it and then
if it doesn't work out be willing to
dispose of it that's a good thing I have
seen a lot of companies though that
because it can take a long time to
implement a piece of software they then
feel almost obliged to
to stick with it it's a sunk cost
fallacy it's much better to jettison
something even if you put a lot of
effort into it than it is to keep going
with something substandard okay on to
some of the tools you need a database
this doesn't have to be a relational one
so if you're a no sequel fan it doesn't
have to be tables but when we're
bringing data from lots of different
streams together you need a place to
store it and you need to be able to add
the supplementary information so if
you're looking at if you have your web
locks and you're doing something pretty
cool like keeping an eye out for
vulnerabilities noted on twitter with
hashtags or if they get a cool logo and
a nice website then you need to be
getting that twitter pipeline and then
having an etl on a process that then
says these are the things i need to look
for in my logs and then go through and
look for them it's a lot easier if that
data is all in one place and ideally
well thought about I'm still very
dubious I don't know is anybody heard
the buzz word data lake well there's
this great new concept dump it all in
and index later okay the developer
mighta left you three months after
setting up the dun Fionn now nobody
knows what on earth that data means but
it's okay we'll get the schema that's a
bad idea you need to know what's going
on with how your data is collected how
it gets stored and how we get shipped
you you need that provenance you need
that metadata it's all very well having
a non-relational database but you should
spend the time when you set up the data
inserts into it to actually specify
what's likely to come from the source
that you're working with dashboarding
dashboarding is really important for
being able to get stuff out part of it
is being able to distill your alerts
down so especially if you have a
consolidated system but even you know
things like scar man's blanc and stuff
and with cabana with elasticsearch you
have the ability to integrate alerts
from a load of different systems picking
which you know charts and things to see
is quite important and again this is
where a bi analyst can come in handy if
you have one laying around because if
they're a good bi analyst and they
should know solid data visualization
principles and should be able to help
you inform the audience for the
dashboard so if it's if it's a dashboard
for you and your tacky who doesn't like
charts and you really like your tables
of data then make it that way but if
it's for your info SEC team what do they
need how do they need it represented and
if it's for you CEO you need to use
release trip away as much detail as
possible and just leave some gauges I'm
not too cynical about them I hope
so that you can buy them in I'm actually
quite a fan of the Microsoft power bi
stack at the moment it has this
fantastic Q&A capability so once you set
up your data and you have some
visualizations people can actually write
queries against the dashboard so they
can say how many 500 errors did I get on
this page yesterday so you can do a lot
of exploratory analysis just from the
dashboard so people don't you widen up
the audience of the people who can
perform the analysis and then if it's
something of interest something that's
worth tracking then you get to you can
pin it to the dashboard so you can
evolve dashboards without making code
changes on the flip side I actually
quite like code based dashboards so I
use a lot of our and there is a package
called shiny which makes interactive
applications without you ever having to
code HTML CSS or configure apache it is
run on pixie dust I don't understand how
it works but it is super impressive and
all you need to be able to code to use
it is our so you can set up your data
sources bring them in memory your dump
csv es you can produce regular reports
in it and you can have a whole lot of
different parameters to make life easier
so people can do exploratory analysis
and they can do configurations and
things like that that's great if you
want to specifically target a view of
your data
okay elk I should I kind of felt like
instead of showing that the web page
that i should show an actual picture of
an alch anybody working with
elasticsearch logstash cabana at the
moment okay so for those of you who
aren't if you need log data at last the
elk stack is really handy it can do
streaming data and it can do bulk
uploads so log stash is your log
shipping tool it's the bit that get to
your data from a to be in the format you
need so if you need a correct if you
need if you have a weird date-time stamp
because some developer thought he wasn't
gonna do epoch he was gonna do second
since 1900 for some crazy reason you can
specify that so you can solve a lot of
issues as the data is in transit then
you've got elasticsearch which is it
basically builds indexes over your data
that you can tell tell it which indexes
and make it a very fast search so it's
great for exploratory work and then
Cabana is a dashboarding system that
sits over the top of it and gets data
real-time and shows you does more
dashboarding stuff and it's quite easy
for people to build and configure their
own once you set up the right
connections to elasticsearch it's
anybody using docker I am working on
hitting all the buzz words by the way
okay well docker is a great tool it
means I never break my machine it means
I just break my docket container and
that's okay because I break it and I
start again so dr. is like a very light
beer
and you can get a docker container with
the elk stack in and just basically say
hey I want to play with elk in a command
line and it will spin up and you can
play so it can be really easy to get
started with and prototype you guys know
about splunk and stuff Microsoft are
actually doing some interesting things
very they're keeping it quiet but their
operational log stuff is quite
interesting and they're also fishing in
the same space that sensor net up
because you can upload logs from what
your users have been doing and identify
what cloud applications they've been
using so that that can be quite handy
and you can set it up to automatically
ship the logs to and then there was no
way I was going to cover the myriad and
plentiful tools that are available that
help you manipulate data better into a
form that gives you insights but there
are many and there will always be the
right one for you whether you have
operational constraints about whether
the data can go on premise or uncle on
the cloud whether you have technological
constraints budgets things that are new
and shiny that you want to play with
they'll be considerations okay
I left it as the data deluge so it's
about time for me to wrap up get off the
stage and I've generally kept you all
awake which is good I would I'm
impressed for myself and nobody's died
yet so this is good so there's a lot of
data and if you're not using it then its
of no value so if you're not using it
lose it save yourself the storage costs
or get using it put something simple
over the top of it to begin with try out
an open-source tool a little prototype
can be a real use case as to whether
some things of value to you people in
much the same way that everybody bribes
the sysadmin with cakes i highly
recommend bribing your bi people to help
get that knowledge that and get that
helping hand developers can actually
also help in this respect because a lot
of them will have been working with
non-relational search capabilities so if
you're looking to do elasticsearch which
is based on leucine then a developer
might come in handy focus on who you're
the shoe you're delivering the data to
and in what format don't overwhelm
people with the wrong info and the wrong
level of detail always make sure you're
right at management decisions are being
made on it okay you will lose so much
it's really important to be right when
you're providing people with information
so
if you can script it and write unit
tests and things against it that is a
fantastic way to go and that's a big
reason why I use are as opposed to any
GUI based solution because I can code it
I can test it and then tools there are a
lot of tools out there ones that help
exploration are very useful you need
somewhere ideally with your data to be
consolidated into and then you need or
you don't need but specialized tools
that help you do specifics can can be
very they can save you a lot of money in
the long run if they help stop something
big okay so this is available online and
a lot of my other materials are as well
so they've all got linked so if you want
to learn a bit more about our or
Microsoft or this and that then you can
go and do it and I present a lot of
links to other things just try it get
prototype something run metasploit give
it a go see see what you can break see
what you can solve and do keep in touch
this is my first security conference I
come from a finance background
previously and I never wanted to attend
their conferences so yeah I'm always
looking to make new contacts in a very
fun industry so thank you all very much
for listening to me for staying awake
and have fun for the
to the day