thanks everyone hear me okay yeah mom
did nodding heads as cool okay want to
talk today about Laura it's a radio
protocol that's actually taken a lot of
interest and a lot of investment
recently so I wanted to talk about a
little bit just to introduce it to you
and also just to understand it from a
security point of view so if you were to
run into it or consider it what you need
to actually think about so first of all
just obscene you to explain what on
earth this is and talk a little bit
about the security features of it and
then actually try and look at okay if we
understand security features how do we
attack this system or you know how do we
build a system that can withstand attack
introduction to myself first and I've
been with MWR since 2011 you've probably
seen me here a couple years ago I've
done a lot of work on Android and so
it's awesome to be moving on and talking
about something new I run our company's
operational technology practice where
we're looking at embedded systems
industrial systems and radio technology
another quick pro tip if you're
considering starting a research project
make sure there's a hilarious talk title
you can get from it and Laura the
Explorer was the obvious choice but you
can be really really difficult when
you've got a presentation and you can't
come up with a title for it so let's do
the other way so back in 2015 in the
autumn we decided to go to a conference
that's not a security conference we try
to branch out and we went to a utility's
conference and this was a European
utility week this this is masa this is
kind of like an infosec for the
utilities area so everyone from Siemens
right through to a small sort of Chinese
startups selling and smart metering and
things like that everything in this
space all the new technologies and we
were there to just talk to people to
understand okay what you can to you
bringing up what new protocols are you
using and we had to obviously brush up
on the kind of protocol we expected them
to use and so we we kind of have these
kind of assumptions okay well we're
going to go to this conference so let's
make sure we
understands agree security that okay
Epis in VT le that we totally get that
so we got there and on the on the first
day we we actually found I think maybe
two vendors using any of those all the
others were using completely different
radio technology which was quite awkward
but also really exciting so the first
evening we went back to our rooms and
just sort of reading as much as we can
so we could have a conversation within
the next day so why is this happened and
we not already kind of solve radio
they're not already protocols out there
why of everyone now jumped in this
sector at least two different ones and
you can break it down fairly quickly
like this so if we have sort of the
range of the protocol at the bottom of
how usage at the top okay if we want to
send things long range if we need this
to work over kilometers okay we'll
probably use a cellular network will
probably maybe need to satellite if it's
you know there's no cells house nearby
if for a little bit closer to home and
we maybe want to improve the bandwidth a
bit okay great we have Wi-Fi we have
Bluetooth very established technologies
nice and easy well recently we've seen
this area solved and this is ok what
about sort of personal range or sort of
within a small building that's very very
low power so this kind of home
automation side of things that now you
don't need to trail power cables or
through your house because you know it's
a wireless isn't runs on a battery of
the years which is great the gap is
obviously here the utilities for
transport this is a really exciting area
if you could solve it could you come up
with a radio approach call that works
over many many kilometers but doesn't
have the the sort of drawback of needing
a lot of power you know constantly going
out to replace battery needing some kind
of maintenance connection it just
doesn't work all the time and this is
lpw pair w am so LP one is low power
wide area network this is sort of the
brand name given to a whole bunch of
technologies that essentially have these
kind of these features that's the
battery life and it is extreme battery
life should be able to run on a triple a
battery for ten years that's and these
for the end nodes range has to be we're
talking across cities across you know
hold wide
riaz bit rate we're not actually worried
about will sacrifice that we're only
going to be sending metrics small
information small commands so we're not
worried about bandwidth this has become
possible using one of several
modulations which are going to in a sec
the other factor is it must be cheap
that these chips these transceivers
these whole devices were going to build
we're probably going to want hundreds of
them the kind of typical solutions will
go through in a second need these remote
nodes to just be across a city and if
one gets run over by a car who cares
that's just a few pounds if it you know
so you can imagine it gets very very
expensive very quickly otherwise and I
mentioned a couple areas already smart
city you know if you can actually
measure pressure on the water pipes you
can get any sort of critical
infrastructure that you don't want to
run cables across you don't want to plug
into your network well now you could
just have a node that just reports back
metrics to you I live in revving one
area that Laura's already being used for
is to measure river flood levels so
these things are distributed around the
river when they sort of obviously
measure that the water levels up for
certain it they then report back
actually logistics is another one that's
kind of interesting I didn't think of
until I was talking to people in the in
the area but there's a lot imagine if
you've got like the containers like
reefers selectively refrigerated units
and you know they're being carried on
shit they're a truck there across the
city but you actually want to know what
the temperature is well either you're
going to have to have a lot of power
draw or you can just have these small
devices now that are using lp1 so
there's a few modulation technologies
and it's pretty much at the moment
between ultra narrowband unb and Laura
Laura is actually a spread spectrum so
ultra wide and then you have
ultra-narrow that sort of the two
competing modulations narrow band is
just coming in and I'll have a look at
sort of who's investing in what in just
a second but the idea of narrow band is
could we use existing cellular
infrastructure to offer this kind of LP
one solution a little bit more
theoretical not as mature and as the top
of the bottom one that
we're looking at companies weightless is
a UK company ultra-narrow van sig Fox is
pretty much the sort of big player in
ultra narrowband couple of others that
are using it as well cellular it comes
across as a whole bunch of different
names so narrow band LTL Randy IOT
companies like Huawei are getting super
invested in this great idea we can offer
IOT and you know solutions using our
existing infrastructure great laura is
pretty much solely owned by the Laura
Alliance there the count there the
organizations that are really pushing
this link labs are also doing something
using a similar modulation so we have at
the moment this kind of situation of
this VHS versus Betamax kind of thing
the big two players are Laura Laura lamb
and sig Fox they are the one that are
grabbing all the headlines getting huge
amounts of investments but ultimately if
one of them was to become the mature one
then everyone would just jump to that
and the other one might die off so the
big difference with six boxes sick box
build you the network they have a build
it and they will come kind of idea
that's you that they will go to say
London install all the sort of cell
towers or the equivalent for sig Fox
have all the back end all done and then
just offer you the customer the ability
to buy a node by a licensed and access
web services so you kind of access
either end of it great because now you
don't need to worry about installing all
that middle kit they do it all for you
Diego argument a gangster bow is what
happens if they go out of business
tomorrow well all my kids going to stop
working so they got to worry about that
laura is the kind of a bit more open
source news that preys carefully and the
Laura modulation like the Phi layer is
actually licensed by sem peck but the
layer above it loads of companies are
doing this kind of middle and kind of
the cell towers the servers and the
services so it's a bit more you kind of
owned that but obviously you need to
make the investment big players in the
air you can kind of see how it's a
little bit split up but a lot of
companies are announcing they are siding
with
one or the other in terms of
semiconductor manufacturers also the
telcos are super interested in this
because it can offer a whole new service
you've already got all this networking
infrastructure how about you can now
offer an IOT service on top of it so a
lot of companies are either kind of
signing up as alliance members or
actually investing orange weirdly if you
see they're actually doing both they
invested something like 60 million euros
into Laura wan to install it in several
cities in France but they publicly said
we're only doing this until our MV IOT
gets off the ground so there's a lot of
companies kind of hedging their bets
generally Laura one part from sk telecom
is very european-based cellular envy is
kind of pushed by the Americans and cig
box is also Europe that's spreading
through to Asia so that's the idea of
this kind of LP one so why choose Laura
there's there's a whole bunch here why
not go look at sick box or one of the
MBI OTS well as there's a few advantages
first of all Laurel and the the mac
layer and the a player open source
anyone can go on their website today let
me get typing your email address Dylan
you can download the full specification
so for a research point of view that's
awesome it's not a theoretical thing
it's had a huge amount of investment in
a lot of cities in Europe including
London so it's not just a theoretical
thing there's actually sort of value in
helping people at this stage also it's
not just turning off your lights and
I've seen talks on that before and it's
great turn off your lights that's mildly
annoying Laura when laura has already
been talked about being used for
actually quite safety critical things so
there's already been a paper produced of
how you would use this to automate
railway level crossings how you and I
looked at one system and that was being
demoed it's the European hoods news
conference there was a burglar alarm
based on this and also a lot of people
saying this is great you can put this
into your crash pad your national
infrastructure critical infrastructure
and you don't have to run wires isn't
that
brilliant well yes potentially yes but
we need to know about the security of it
so walking around the conference and
obviously you start trying it big but
just like going to infosec you can't
really talk tech to the people all
stands normally because it's mostly
sales stuff and so when I was asking
about it's like a Laura this is great it
was what's the security is fully secured
how does it do that oh it sees it AES
one's way right yeah okay and so I
started going to them and saying okay
apart from using aes-128 how does the
security work and just the stunned look
that obviously stolen that only tangler
and they were using so at the moment
there's nothing really out there and as
I say you can just download the spec but
that's pretty heavy going if you just
need to be able to advise someone within
five minutes it is good a lot as a
consultant I kind of have to also expect
this kind of questioning i'm going to
have someone asked me we want to use it
for x is that fine would it work is it
safe or alternatively we got to we're
going to use two gateways we want to use
which one should be used due diligence
we want to look at security these
products which one's better so this is
the presentation on the research from
sort of october till now to say the
following and to say whether it's even
possible to use it securely to find out
if you are going to use it what's your
key controls and then to actually try
and say okay here's a white paper with a
list of tests and if you can actually go
and use and to look at a system so
that's how we work we looked at the
specification how to look at anyone
who's actually releases stuff yet see
how they've done it beauty paper and NS
you see if we actually need to produce
any tools to be able to test it properly
and that's what we've done so i keep
using the word Laura and Laura when
laura is the file layer that's just the
modulation proprietary license by semtex
m.tech will and license it out laura one
is the bit I'm actually more interested
in at this point this is the delay with
the security on it this is sort of the
mac layer and above and that's a no
standard so we can tear that one apart
okay let's say we actually on to build a
Laura system now we sort of talked about
these various components is only going
to be three according to specification
you have no do you have gateways you
have network servers nodes are these
small devices I've got one here which is
all cabled up and very very cheap this
one's made by microchip there that these
n nodes are going to be the things that
you distribute around they're going to
be things with sort of a real world io
kind of control they're going to be
monitoring stuff they're going to be
taking commands and maybe you know
looking service whatever they report
back to the gateways this is an example
gateway and they're going to be using
Laura Laura lamb to actually transmit
messages back and forth to the gateways
gateways there's going to be far fewer
of them they're going to be powered and
they're going to then report back to the
network server the network server is
your typical IT infrastructure at this
point some kind of interface for the
Gateway you can talk to how you want to
design that entirely up to you what you
then may have is if you're like
licensing this at service is you can say
ok company X you can have these nodes
and you can build your own application
server and I'll know to pass all that
data through to you and you can control
them so this connection entirely up to
you could be using cellular networks
could run cables anything you want
doesn't really matter obviously needs to
be fairly high bandwidth and then the
connection between the Gateway the node
that's what's using a lot at Laurel and
communicate it works on a cool reply
basis so traditional the class a setup
is that the nodes will depending on how
you program them send a message back to
your application server you know the
temperature is currently 20 degrees the
application server then has the
opportunity to reply ok it's 20 degrees
open the valve that kind of message to
understand how good the gateways are
this is a map of motion and the red pins
are gateways the green area is the area
that you could put a node in and it
would make it back to the network server
so they've covered most of a city using
just six gateways so it's pretty
effective as you can tell we sort of
move into this deeper heavier area built
up the the the range drops quite a lot
I'll see out in the countryside a little
bit more much easier so that's how it
works there's only these three
components only two of them actually
talking Laura Laura one so what does a
spec actually say about security and
imagine you were given this write your
pen tester hat on so that's how much
have we finished we've built this it's
got a thousand nodes and ten gateways
we've already built all the networks
application service their parties can
connect in we've got all the instructor
in the meantime the attack vectors on
this are kind of mind-boggling this is a
huge huge project you can go off to the
radio you're after the devices you got
to the servers then um internet-facing
areas what be the effective in denial of
service attack there's there's quite a
lot so we wanted to break it down a
little bit the way encryption works this
whole aes-128 this is the way it works
it's using symmetric encryption so every
node has its own unique keys should have
its own unique use according to the spec
it'll have two of them it'll have an
application session key network session
key application session key is
highlighted in red network session Keys
highlighted in blue now what would
happen is the node encrypts using the
application session key and then signs
makes the message integrity check using
the network session key goes through the
Gateway gateways completely blind it has
no ability to decrypt message it's got
no access to keys it just dumbly Ford's
everything on that it sees that is a
legitimate Laura packet the network
server can then it's only got the
network key so it can check yes that's a
official message yes it had the right
key pass it on I know which application
service send it to for the other fields
telling me which one send it to the idea
being it doesn't matter the network
servers owned by a telco only you can
then decrypt it that's the idea
of course there's other issues of what
if there are two like Laura solutions in
the same area you can actually ship the
channel slightly although it shouldn't
affect it too much and then these are
command messages command messages are
only sent by the network server the
network server only has one of the keys
so it's going to use the key for both
encryption and signing so this would be
a reply this time said by the network
server to say app could you actually
shift channel X interesting where it
starts getting a little bit more gray
around specifications how exactly do you
join a new node to the network you don't
just want me a terrible person
connecting into your to your Lorelei's
system you only want your official ones
connecting when you want them to so
joining you have two options one you
could just program the keys when you're
manufacturing them put them into the
nodes throw the nose out into the field
they start working they've got the keys
immediately so they can just start
talking that's fine the other one is
more complicated is where you put you
just still put a key onto the device but
it doesn't have the session key set up
yet so what you need is some kind of
exchange when the node starts up using
the one key it does have to establish
the two other keys so we have how node
it has a unique application key on it
again a yes once we've so and this is
the nodes going to send this to start
off with mrs. our evil person in the
middle trying to listen in working out
what the keys are so the nose going to
send a join request it's going to send
okay I belong to this application I am
this device number I've created a random
number and I've signed it with my
athlete not encrypted just sign so okay
he can get those that's fine so aes-128
H max to sign those the server then
needs to generate and another another
month and using those value that
calculates what and the application
session here the network session piece
should be it should also this is where
the specification doesn't really talk
about it much it also check that that
node should even be joining or sending
that message at this point
and so it's kind of consideration needs
start adding usually formulas ears again
this is all in the specification so the
server is going to work out this way
it's going to take the app key which it
also knows take the nonce the element is
just produced and actually produce the
two keys it will then send yes you can
join and it's going to send its app
nonce back but this time actually
encrypt it with the application he and
signer so now both sides have the
information and man in the middle is
completely stuck without that so that's
we can now join network safely to our
network which is great how about the
messaging itself I will get it as i said
in the diagram is going to be using
application session key in the network
session key for application messages
encrypt with the app send with the net
bandslam of the network the network
messages we can only use the one key
that's fine ok let's get a bitmap see
it's actually using AES in counter mode
which means it's going to be producing a
key stream that key stream is then
getting X sword with our message and
that then gets sent across the idea is
that the server can produce the same key
stream because it has the same
information hex or it and get the data
out again a key point of this is
obviously you don't want to produce the
same key stream twice quite dangerous so
what it's going to use as these counter
values the idea being that when a node
starts its on zero every message its end
it's going to be incrementing its
counter and then on the server side the
server can do the same ok I've received
one from that load increase that though
it's counselor so it can always produce
the same key stream as the node but it
should never produce same key string
place the actual message goes into this
that frm payload is our data the metric
you know it's 20 degrees whatever that
gets encrypted we then sign it with the
message integrity check using the
network key so that's pretty simple we
can add nodes these mosca message us we
can check the signing we can check you
know has it been tampered with we can
decrypt it great class b is to what
they've done when
to some of the customers have put their
hand up and say that's not going to work
for us what if our nodes are inside
containers that are constantly moving
around the city what if they're in a car
or something like that how does the
server know to send a message to that
particular gateway to know that it's
going to reach that note if the notes
now moved on well okay so Laura Laura
when added Class B systems similarly
you'll have times where the network
needs to message you where you want to
contact the node first you don't just
want to wait and reply so that's what
this solves gateways at this point
suddenly become active they suddenly
start doing stuff they're going to start
sending out messages to say hey I'm a
gateway I'm getting number three this is
my GPS coordinates and the time is
currently this the node that way can
then receive all of those messages which
are sent synchronously and pick which
gateways the closest if that one has now
changed it will send a message to the
server and the server can say okay came
from that gateway this time right I know
to talk through that gateway to talk to
it so useful to update the time it's
then received in the node the node now
says okay I'm now synchronized with the
time sent from that gateway message I
now know at X seconds I should listen
and because you only have this short
listening windows you can sleep for a
lot of the time and obviously far more
efficient for battery life also allows
multicast messages so now you can send
one message to all the devices because
you know they're all going to be
listening at the same time so all of
that that's that's all for the technical
side of it is actually secure you can
imagine these systems are going to be
far more complex than that you can have
engineers pulling stuff out all this one
broke this one's parrot you know the
latency let's redirect everything all
the network service for all over it's
going to be incredibly complex so how do
we test it let's break it down so
messages some things we can do very very
quick first of all obviously check
signing for encryption this is the kind
of stuff that's in the spec
and to have an official lower Alliance
device you must have passed their tests
that ultimately it's probably on you
depending on your role to develop this
and implemented securely so if we don't
check the signing before the encryption
there are several attacks we can do if
we're not incrementing our counselors
properly then we're producing the same
key stream that can be dangerous if
we're sharing keys around and yeah again
a lot so that please don't do this it's
up to you to actually implement that so
what happens if we were to decrypt
before we check signing well given that
we're XOR announced using a key stream
it's possible to start swapping bytes so
if I know the structure of the message
as an attacker it roughly that those
bites here will always be 24 is you just
sex or again so if I just start flipping
bits then I can charts changing the
values without knowing what the key was
obviously the mixture of a signature
check should just catch that straight
away but that's up to you to implement f
counter manipulation so denial of
service attacks with these kind of
systems is probably going to actually be
quite expensive and imagine the kind of
cryptolocker attack is also the big
point is with counselors is they should
always increment if you get one lower
then that's out of sync or you know it's
rubbish discard it so if we were to be
able to send a message with the counter
set to the maximum value you've just
bricked that node that node will just be
ignored from then on so pretty dangerous
obviously check the link first and if
the council if you replaying that using
the same key stream then you have the
opportunity to X or stuff else because
you're saying keystream being XOR
therefore if you're to encrypted
messages and you know the plaintext of
one you can get the plain text of the
other jeep your keys is pretty obvious
there's big message say please don't use
them but it's up to you or again
guessable keys and if you're basing it
off you know the mac address or
something equivalent been then it's
possible to start just sending your own
messages as anna packet
Mac only messages so were these are the
network messages change channel do this
do that only uses one of the keys so
again we actually if we do get that one
key then what then we're in an extra do
quite a lot of damage the commands you
can actually send to mention some of
these you can get the status you can
change data rate transmit power channel
at all proprietary so yeah potentially
these messages are less secure you're
using one key now and there's a lot you
could actually do to damage your system
now that's really interesting because
some companies clearly don't get the
fact that network keys by themselves are
and sensitive they've obviously assumed
well you've got an appt session key and
I don't know it so it's fine so the
things network is hobbyist thing so
totally fine they're doing this as is in
London as well but for the hobbyist
community you need to know the network
session key that the network is going to
use so that's on their website so anyone
right now could produce something to
knock over brick any note that's
currently on the things network in any
country ok the over-the-air signing and
some when it no joins we could try and
do that as well you know we need to
worry about whether we could rejoin if
we can send it again produce new nonces
get new session Keys you leave the
actual no doubt in the dark because it's
got the wrong ones and a server would
just think it's delicious and ignore it
similarly if we're able to guess the
keys we can get a whole bunch of attacks
on listening or start spoofing messages
key management is not talked about at
all in the specification and this is
where some of the most interesting
attacks are you've got to have a server
that the network server and potentially
application servers can access to get
those keys to be able to decrypt and
read the messages but also to send
replies now that's a potentially a
single point of failure and then a
really critical asset that you want to
worry about who's got access to that
database what
so that database was cryptolocker your
entire IOT network running a Laura that
doesn't work it's it's a really really
critical thing that you need to isolate
away the other thing is a device is the
nodes themselves we've had quite a play
with these I'll show you some of the
work we've done on this but physical
attacks on these nodes these nodes are
going to be out in the city there are
people's homes and their cars you know
various interested in thusi asts hello
we'll probably pull the part at some
point in try and work out how they work
allora know is probably going to have
something like this the antenna you're
going to have your transceiver that does
all the encryption and signing so that's
going to have all the keys in it some
kind of connection the one I've got so
you are connection it goes to a
microcontroller that then does all the
sort of business e logic that's sort of
reading whatever measurement it is
that's sort of producing a message sends
it to the Laurel and transceiver and
that's then gets sent out so the nodes
must have these keys they should be
unique per node that would be an
interesting one to test yeah this is the
transceiver I've got here and so
normally your microcontroller we're
connecting to these pins and then you
can actually use this to send so so
potentially we can steal the keys from
the node we can also try going after the
firmware because it must be pausing the
bilayer at least or the microcontroller
might be pop doing pausing on on the
actual application data that's being
sent so it could be interesting so could
we just pull the keys out what is its
transceiver what is this magical black
box well if we took the shielding off
but you can actually see it's a picture
pic18 LF that's gots debug ports so we
can connect our picket debugger to it we
can try and actually look can we pull
the keys out have they set the registers
correctly to stop a Packers doing that
yeah actually annoyingly they have one
interesting thing is you can write to
individual code blocks so these pictures
let you write to one sector and leave
the rest of the code in fact you can
they have made a mistake on the flags
and to set that one block can read the
code from another blog so if anyone
smart enough and I would be interested
to talk to you afterwards about
can you write code flash to one part of
the block with some kind of not sled
that then reads out the memory from the
other sections and then we'll throw that
one away to get another device right to
another sector and that way you get all
four sectors of code out who bigger
we're dumping the firmware there's
nothing in the datasheet say there's any
kind of protection against this or side
channel analysis and these devices
actually have a way of measuring current
draw exactly to that and chip so should
be fairly straightforward and to do
power analysis to work out crypto unless
they're using a secure AES library maybe
we can go far far cheaper and dirtier if
this webs if the server the network
server and application server is just
expecting data back and then putting it
into a database we have all the classic
Network attacks SQL injection actually
put together a demo that does cross-site
scripting through this because the
values are just being displayed in the
engineer's web app so if we just replace
the microcontroller part we can just
sending anything I want and the great
thing about that is if the transceiver
has the keys it will just start
encrypting and signing it for us very
very useful so we need to worry about
those obviously internet-facing
components are pretty straightforward
chances are it's going to look like that
that is the implementation for several
of these solutions these gateways are
just talking out 3g dongle out over the
Internet to a web service that web
service again single points of failure
what happens if you just deduced it you
know suddenly the nose wouldn't be able
to communicate anymore it's pretty big
full and we could start looking a brute
force attacks against the mick but 4.3
billion messages you have sent probably
a little bit extreme so probably
something you'd want is more like a
private APN you can then actually VPN to
make sure that only the gateways are
going to talk so the web services again
you might need to worry about what's the
physical security of these gateways if
they have assets like this
Class B is where things really start
falling apart a little bit on Laura
security and essentially to be able to
send a broadcast you need to share keys
and the Laura specification just
straight up says like and we don't
really know how you're going to do this
we just kind of support that you can so
please when you're going to send a
broadcast magically change all of your
nodes app keys and network keys to be
the same because we're going to send the
same message to all of them and then
please magically change them back again
so they said they're not allowed to send
Mac messages using this but again highly
up to you how you been loads of that so
class be generally is be careful
multicast messages yeah good luck trying
to do that securely it's going to be
really really tricky gateway beacons get
properly interesting because there is no
security on them gateway doesn't have
any keys can't do any sighting can't do
any encryption they're going to be
sending their GPS coordinates and a sort
of a network time to all of the nodes so
first of all was an attacker that's very
easy to war drive because you've got the
GPS coordinates all the gateways that
potentially have a secure connection
back to the server the other interesting
thing is that the nodes are using these
values and I've seen some sort of stack
overflow type chats about it everyone's
actually now just setting the node
system time to be the message sent by
the Gateway ok i just received the
message is currently twelve o'clock noon
set the time to that no encryption
authentication so i have no idea what
would happen if you just start sending
you know first of January 1972 these
things so in summary having read through
this i think it is perfectly possible to
build a secure lauren network there's a
lot of onus on you to put the spec
properly and to implement the spec
properly that was obviously ridiculously
quick going through this the spec is
pretty big and so what we did was put
together a white paper on this but
you're interested in this that's really
downloadable from all
site it goes through each of these areas
in far more detail and the test cases in
far more detail as well the last thing I
want to do is to say obviously we were
looking at producing tools so one thing
I wanted to do is say well okay if you
can get gateways to gateways are just
packet sniffers we don't have to do any
kind of software-defined radios on this
because we the bilayer is black box but
what we could do is take a gateway just
have it record every packet it ever sees
and then we can use that to try and
inspect to work out what informations
being leaked could we can actually maybe
test the keys that we've stolen off the
device or a server so hopefully this is
all still running so I've got a gateway
here and what we can do is I'll just
send a message from a node I think this
is something like a AAA so I'm just
setting all up and just going to make
you go through a BP quickly sign up and
the Gateway is going to listen now this
no I've sets to just use a key of all
zeros and that's sent the message an
hour nice little web interface in front
end we can actually now inspect and
start parsing this traffic s'okay it was
Center 1037 yeah it was so I get all
this information which band width which
port it's going to so that's to do the
application I can then look at that
encrypted payload as well and if I know
that the key is all zeros in this case
and okay let's just random data on them
so they look okay so obviously going to
pick up random messages as well
interestingly this is going to be
picking up every message I've just
realized and we're currently in London
so that might have been an actual Laura
system in use cool and so we can you
prove this one nope that's someone
else's system as well live demos you
gotta love
okay i can try and someone later on if
you're interested in this kit I'll have
it around for the rest of the day but
it's essentially using a node so we can
generate our own messages and and sort
of handset all the keys so we can start
trying to inject messages into a network
we also have a gateway so we can go
wardriving or actually try and passively
and decrypt and read these messages
that's everything I wanted to cover and
does anyone have any questions