hi I'm Steve Lord and some of you may
have seen me on Twitter our apologize in
advance for not looking like my twitter
avatar but most people are grateful that
I wear more clothes than my twitter
avatar and in case you don't know me
which is probably most people in this
room I'd like to just tell you a bit
about myself the obligatory once lied
about me so I test pens a small but
perfectly formed pen testing company and
I co-organized a small event called
44.com that a few people turn up to now
and again I also run a little blog which
is a blog that teaches people how to pen
test but this talk isn't about any of
those things instead this talk is about
some of the things that affect us all
and will affect us all going forward and
you know basically I like to think about
IOT as a solution in search of a problem
but one of the most important things
about IOT is its ability to change lives
for good with meaningful things that
really matter it can really affect
people so you know we have over here
smart plate which is backed by signs how
does it work it's backed by science
smart socks because they don't want you
like many priests I'm not priests they
wouldn't let me in they said I was too
corrupt but like many priests I always I
always feel that you like the really
black socks not the dark blue ones but
the really dark black ones and then of
course there's the egg minder as a smart
egg tray which is my favorite IOT device
a device so smart that people who made
it couldn't come up with a use case for
it
but they still managed to sell it to
another company who also couldn't come
up with the use case for it there's
something very similar to IOT and it's
in this industry and it's the thing that
I like to call the cider industrial
complex which is a lot like two guys
fighting each other trying to argue the
loudest over whose solution is the best
and the reality is that there are actual
real threats that are facing us inside a
space for example i'm defending cider
space now i have two cans for redundancy
purposes but there are many threats to
side a space okay for example there are
bad things inside a space which is good
for me because i like bad things but
some of these bad things that we're
looking at now our side of weapons that
could seriously affect the quality of
our cider but what if we were to mix the
side of weapons of tomorrow with the
quality assurance processes over the
internet of things with literally no
budget what could we achieve and it's an
intersection of the two i like to call
the internet of wrongs which are devices
that are incredibly petty would still
constitute cider weapons now everything
I'm going to do in this talk is crap
in some cases almost literally but all
of the things that I'm going to show you
today use frameworks that are pretty
easy to pick up and you could easily
build your own things we hardware
implants things to change stuff and I'm
just going to go through some different
technologies and talk about some things
that have happened in my quest for
discovering the journey into junk
hacking for bad stuff or the internet of
wrongs so I'd like to take you back to a
happier time for some a couple of years
ago I tried to move to Berlin and failed
um very clearly I'm not Apple bow me
enough but this is mark but it's not
really mark I've changed names to
protect the innocent here so let's
pretend this is mark now mark lives with
my friend Vinnie in Berlin also not it
not his real name was stayin at Vinnie's
because I was bouncing back and forth
between Berlin and one day mark comes
back from paris with a brand new shiny
macbook and he says you know i really
like this macbook i had a lenovo there's
something wrong with it you know all i
had was like a zillion different
variants of candy crush and the thing
was as slow as a dog and i'd get an hour
of battery life out of it but the
macbook what i can do is i can leave on
charge overnight i can wake up in the
morning go into the living room have my
breakfast nothing plugged in go home so
we go back to my bedroom close the lid
go off to work come back from work in
the evening open the lid and it's got
ninety five percent of his battery left
that's why max a superior so after Vinny
and I realized that mark doesn't
understand the concept of power
management we thought could we educate
him with a practical joke a practical
joke that would go horribly horribly
wrong now I took it as an opportunity to
engage what I like to call the side
accrual chain
any resemblance to anything that's been
put out by anybody else is purely and
totally coincidental but the site okrill
chain consists of sitting on a bench
drinking cider watching the thing that
you're going to go out in this case we
didn't need to sit on a bench and we'd
already drunk a load a side of me and
Vinny and we decided that what we were
going to do was go and do something to
his laptop to make the power savings
fail in a way that would cause hilarity
weaponization so we need to develop a
cider weapon which is hard when you're
drunk if you've ever tried cooking when
you're drunk you try writing code when
you're drunk and you try building
hardware when you're drunk delivery
which was relatively easy because we
were already in Vinny and marks flat and
we already had access to vinian marks
Wi-Fi network and we already had
physical access to marks laptop for most
of the day but exploitation was
potentially quite difficult because we
didn't know marked password and he's the
kind of fastidious person who would have
chosen a good one mainly because I went
and pound him a few weeks beforehand
when he said I bet you can't hack into
my email account installation the
deployment of the package onto the
device well that's going to be
potentially shaky and this is where we
were too drunk to carry on with the
cider krill jeng see to command and
control yep grossly went wrong there
this was the fatal flaw and actions on
objectives which is in sort of laymen
speak is a way of saying did we get the
effect that we wanted to achieve so we
thought about some different ways that
we could do some stuff to play with
marks laptop we thought maybe we could
hack into his laptop itself to some
extra school extra cool neat stuff on OS
X no one ever hacks OS X is gotta be
secure and then we thought mm maybe you
might notice that maybe you might find
something like caffeine installed and
remove it so whatever we took a part is
laptop and then disconnected different
bits response
for power saving and then we like well I
could cause some permanent damage if
you've ever tried opening a macbook
without the right tools you can also
make it very difficult to reassemble and
I didn't want to pay for macbook so in
the end we went for wake-on-lan now
every Mac has support for wake-on-lan
not every wireless network has support
for wake-on-lan and the reason for this
is the way that wake-on-lan works it's a
very simple protocol and in Macworld all
you do is you just send a Datagram
that's UDP with a destination port of
nine you send it to the broadcast IP and
mac address there's a sink stream the
payload at the start that's just a load
of and then the target mac address 16
times quite why it 16 times I don't know
it's just something to do with the spec
but realistically if you look at apple
remote desktop which is the apple admin
utility it's not just a remote desktop
this is the type of packet that it would
send out and you'll be able to see up
here you can see the sink stream you can
see the mac address repeated it's just a
single Datagram it's really easy it's
really lame is really weak so this is
going to be a great practical joke the
plan is simple is that we just go and
send wake-on-lan packets to his laptop
and it will just stay awake the battery
will run down what could possibly go
wrong and you will be surprised Oh
viewer now because I was bouncing
between London and Berlin a lot I didn't
want to take a lot of stuff so I had
with me a macbook and I didn't feel it
was appropriate to take out a macbook
with a macbook but I also had an Arduino
and a dicc 3000 Wi-Fi shield so if you
want to put one of these things you need
an Arduino Uno r3 which is about eight
pound fifty off Amazon you can buy them
for cheaper from Aliexpress and you'll
need a TI CC 3000 shield which is about
30 quid but realistically if I was to do
it again I would use a completely
different set of microcontrollers
probably an esp8266 which is a much
lower cost package that has Wi-Fi built
in and this is what it looks like which
is actually I fished it out this morning
that's what it looks like
and the software that we use is the
Arduino IDE which you get from arduino
CC there's multiple versions but the CC
version is the genuine no support the
Adafruit CC 3000 library and you're good
to go of course if you to use your own
wireless device you probably use an
esp8266 or would wire it onto an arduino
now because it's cheaper and you
wouldn't need that CC 3000 library
instead you need to communicate with the
ASP so if you've never used Arduino
before hands up everybody is used
Arduino quite a mix yeah that's good
cool farold amount of you arduino uses a
simplified superset of C so it's see all
the way down and then there are extra
things to handle things like string
handling and stuff that's generally
considered quite hard for beginners and
there are two main functions in what's
called an Arduino sketch that is an
Arduino program the first one is called
set up which is where you set all the
bits up you set your pins to be input or
output and then how they're going to
communicate with the other bits like
this Wi-Fi module and then you pass over
to a loop function which is just
something that loops around continuously
so the code is relatively simple all is
is if I may have even nicked this from a
sample thing and bastardized it for my
own means I don't know it's quite a
while ago but you just define various
security settings for the network you're
going to connect to and then you tell
the CC 3000 to delete any save profile
so it doesn't connect to the wrong
network and then tell it to connect to
yours get an IP address it's all fairly
simple and then in the loop all I did
was I had a little Wi-Fi status thing
that would feed me an update / cereal
because the connection kept dropping a
problem it was easily solved by moving
the Arduino from the top of Vinny's bed
to the bottom of Vinny's bed and then
you're pretty much good to go the actual
code itself is tiny it's really easy to
build something like this realistically
you could probably do this in a lunch
break but because Vinny and I would
monk it took hers most of a day and then
the next day actually a load of stuff
didn't work so by the time I'd got it
finished Mark had already gone to work
his laptop was there but I had to go and
get a flight the resulting packets look
like this and then you know I looked at
it and we thought well there's no real
way to tell other than the fact that
marks macbooks on but we've pushed the
button on there to switch it on so we
can't tell I got go at the airport
packets look okay I'll be back in two
weeks that'll be fine should be great
and the kind of reaction we were hoping
to get from art with something like this
it's a great great practical joke
nothing could ever go wrong the problem
with this is I'm a douche bag so
remember that cyber cruel chain bit that
c2 bit I had no way to shut this thing
off because i thought the obvious way to
shut it off would beat you unplug it
after all be back in two weeks so that
first week mart went to the apple store
saying that the power management on his
apple sucks the apple store had a look
they couldn't find the problem
tomorrow at home and his macbook was
still messed up mission accomplished
right our side a weapon is successful
then Vinnie's had a family emergency and
he had to go back to England for family
emergencies two weeks later I go back to
Berlin and I stay somewhere else and
Vinny and I forget about this device in
the interim mark went to the apple store
he said my macbook is kaput the apple
store kept the macbook overnight it was
a hundred percent charge when he left
the next day he comes back it's about
ninety-five percent charged it's all
working he's like great this is
fantastic I'm going to head home so you
went home got the macbook came back home
following week Vinnie still in England
goes back and he says my macbook hist
sacker poop and they said well we've
actually taken a look at it twice
there's nothing wrong with it can't
really do anything about it and there
was a back-and-forth and apparently mark
was getting further and further
exasperated with this and in the end
might went to the apple store and they
said because we've had it overnight and
found nothing wrong we can't swap it out
we can't give you a refund because it's
all working but if you were to go to the
apple store that you bought it from then
you'll be able to go and possibly
convince them because they won't know
that we've kept it overnight so mark
went to the apple store in Paris
and he said excuse him 11 macbook no
marche pas excuse me my macbook doesn't
work and they said no problem we'll keep
it overnight so he got a hotel and they
kept it overnight sure enough it was
fine mark went home six months later I
went to Berlin and I stayed at Vinnie's
and I walked into the living room the
marks there and he doesn't have a
macbook I said what happened and he said
well you know Steve ever since you came
last time my macbook's been totally on
the fritz it just doesn't work the
battery life is terrible so I had to
share the macbook to some other
unsuspecting chump and i bought a
fucking death
there are some important takeaways from
this firstly CC 3000 shields are
expensive I think there's a moral
question somewhere in there I have
trouble distinguishing it but
realistically we should only use cider
for good not for evil and we should
always remember the side to kill train
crow chain because ultimately if there
was a way to remotely switch this off if
it was pinging a box I on there was a
chance I could have remembered and gone
oh shit but I couldn't and consequently
someone got a very very good price on a
MacBook and poor mark yeah got a lot of
suffering for it but I learned some
important moral lessons about not doing
bad things from that exercise which
which helped me a few months later when
tragedy struck in Cape Town I went off
to Cape Town to go and see some friends
and as I left to board the flight
everything was great they were just
chilling out in the garden by the time I
arrived there had been some weird
passive aggressive stuff going on and
nearly a full scale fight requiring the
cops to turn up so these are my friends
Nicky and Eddie of course it's not
really Nicky and Eddie it's actually
stock footage and and this is their
neighbors i'm going to call jeff and
drop bags again not their real names so
Nikki and Eddie and their friends which
is chilling out in their garden in their
apartment and they were just chatting
away it's about 8pm it's not
particularly late they're not showing
particularly loud they were planning on
having a bribe but they never actually
got around to it and then their
neighbors their upstairs neighbors
started saying something strange and
almost a strange kind of Weasley thing
and rather than just saying hey guys
you're a bit loud could you turn it down
well they came out with was well drop
bags apparently said Amy so do
it is the guy and he's the man in a kind
of rhythmic chant and then a few minutes
later they did it again he's a dude here
is the high he's done man now I don't
feel my life often resembles the League
of Gentlemen but in this case it did and
I arrived the next day and there's
nearly been a full-blown fight why have
you sighs it's ready all right
realistically how can we mess with the
neighbors I learned an important life
lesson earlier in Berlin and I think we
can operate here and then I remembered
I'd come back from a from a conference
in New Zealand a key week on where I'd
show nothing about how to go and deal
with people particularly hipsters from
coffee shops it's a problem that
massively effects Wellington and
Melbourne there's an absolute hipster
plague there but I thought why don't we
just take the code that I did before and
modify it rather than doing selective do
your thing based on keyword we just do
off everyone on the neighbor's Wi-Fi
network and I call it thunder blade
although the register called it a selfie
slayer and that's basically all there is
to it and realistically to build one of
these you just need a Raspberry Pi such
as an a B or a 0 a 2 or an equivalent a
microSD card you did require a USB hub
for configuring because of the you know
you need a keyboard and mouse from one
of you until recently when with the 0
you can actually just connect over
serial via USB and I'll use a tp-link
wn7 22 net and wireless card because
they're bloody good and they do decent
injection and a USB power bank so i'll
just show you the code for this because
originally i wrote the code using scatty
hands up anybody who's ever use Cappy
excellent hands up anyone who's ever
used gappy for something at production
speed on low power doubt way nope it
doesn't work it's it's really really
great for analysis but because of the
layering and the splicing there's huge
amounts of objects flying around in
memory
and it involves huge amounts of context
switching to get stuff out of it so it
slows down so I found the DP Katie
python library which was massively quick
and just converts pretty much packets
into Python objects and that's it so I
would suggest that if you're looking at
doing something it's worth checking out
and having a look the one thing that
didn't work with this in DP Katie was
actually disassociating clients and that
wasn't because DP DP katie is no good
that's because my Python sucks so you
can see here for the original code I for
Kiwi con we have a series of target
keywords and that we're filtering on UDP
port 53 4 dns so we just rip that out
but we have a thing about doing some
sniffing seeing what's going on we're
going to pass any packets that come in
see if they match our targets and kill
so we just replace that past packet
section and say if it's from is that our
bssid of interest is in there then kill
the packet and then because my DP Katie
deal code was terrible I basically just
shell out to where replay what could go
wrong right but there was one small
problem with this which Eddie pointed
out and I'm glad to have a moral guide
in my friend Eddie south african jails
are not fun places to be so I decided
that maybe do your thing was a step too
far but what wasn't a step too far was a
project i like to call pupal now if
anybody here speaks Afrikaans they may
know what that means but I just like to
talk about what goes into a football
first what you're going to need is an
esp8266 so this is a macbook keyboard at
the top that's a no Dempsey you on a
mini breadboard at the bottom there's a
is it it's a ESP 01 so this is a the
node MCU on the breadboard it's pretty
small this is actually the ESP 01 they
about a pound these ones or the ESP 12
the no Dempsey use about five quid and
basically it's a programmable MCU with
an IP stack on Wi-Fi built-in and you
just leave one of those the Arduino IDE
the extensions installed to be able to
program for the SPE to esp8266 and a big
battery pack to power off so now we know
what goes into a football what comes out
of a purple now I know you're thinking
and if you're thinking what I'm thinking
you're one sick puppy but if you're not
thinking what I'm thinking then maybe
you are if the answer is crap over 80 to
11 because the esp8266 has a fantastic
function in earlier versions of the SDK
that allow us to go and send raw frames
now I done about you but something that
cost one pound and let's be send raw 802
11 frames has my interest and the pupal
POC is pretty simple we're going to
algorithm Utley generate SSIDs saying
that Jeff is one of the man the dude or
the guy with an ID and we're going to
broadcast them at a reasonable rate you
can't broadcast them too quickly because
you'll take up the whole channel and
then nothing else on that channel could
transmit but that's not what this is
about I mean you could create something
that did that very easily but that's not
what I'm demonstrating here but
effectively the reason we have the extra
ID on the end is that if you just have
Jeff the man just the dude jeff the guy
it doesn't matter if you channel hop
where we change bssid or SSID or
anything like that some of the operating
systems that you will encounter will
have this appear once so you'll get a
total of three networks by putting an ID
on the end that's randomly generated
each one of these can generate up to 256
different SSIDs that will all show up in
the list giving us a grand total of
seven hundred and sixty-eight reasons
why you should not call Eddie demand the
dude or the guy so i'm going to show you
the code
which unlike the other stuff I've
actually got with me so let me see I
don't want to pop that there they'll
spill everywhere you see if I can bring
this up mmm there we go I'll pop this
over here so I just do your bit of a
walk through what the codes about it's
not very hard actually most of this
stuff came from elsewhere so you see if
I can even begin their know okay so what
we've got over the top is we have a
basic header that says we're looking at
the ESP stuff then we have random
generator usual bits and pieces that's
the structure of the wireless beacon
frame for broadcast that we're going to
put out that's the setup part for it and
then down below here we construct the
packet and then we construct the insult
and then we send it all out and then we
wait a bit and that's all it is is
really really really very very simple
now assuming that this doesn't cause my
macbook to reset when i plug it in okay
there we go and I'll just fire up oh no
wait and we got that that area is fire p
nessa cider which of course is an
essential tool for saving cider space
go away
there you see what we can pick up area
so Jeff's the dude just the dude Jeff's
the guy if I go over here it's a bit
blaming it's a bit weak but the thing
that I probably wouldn't want to show
you for risk of censure something like
wassenaar or anything would be that all
of the code here is just as easy to
integrate into the esp8266 to do deals
attacks and if you were particularly
malicious one of the things that you'd
be able to do would be to have one
esp8266 listen and then another one do
the transmit so you have one that just
scans for things that are connected and
then you send the deals the other way so
I've done this because I slowed it down
although the original device that I
built wasn't slow and it had the side
effect of causing minor problems with
network stability but I'd learned from
Berlin always have a way to switch you
off so why is this a wicked toy it's a
bit of a lame thing oh shit I've ever
done plug that um but we have the Wi-Fi
send packet freedom command and we have
raw injection for a pound an implement
deal with two devices and we can also
implement a Michael failure so the WPA
TCAP process has a countermeasure called
Michael where if it receives too many
authentications it will shut down the
wireless part of the AP which was for
some reason a security feature but it
has the added side effect on some
rooters of or some ApS of resetting the
WPS time outlook so that you can brute
force WPS so some lessons learned from
this device esp8266 is good and cheap
but not exactly what we'd call it
it has a tendency to leak memory it's
not particularly well if you find
yourself coding on one you'll find
yourself coding functions to handle
resets fairly often it's a fiddly
platform because it runs at 3.3 volts
and has a limited input current so you
end up inevitably if you want to hook it
up to us be having to go and do
something either with voltage dividers
or with a low dropout type a sort of
regulator and finally Eddie's neighbors
are assholes so the next toy i'm going
to show you is a toy that's over at my
house so is anybody here ever used SD
ours ends up rtls dr's quite a few
people okay so basically you can get
these very cheap USB TV sticks that you
can use to go and listen to radio
signals way outside of the scope the
frequencies they were originally
designed for and there are a lot of
tools that will allow you to use these
and for various purposes some of which
are more legal than others so one of the
big problems that people who use radio
equipment face is attenuation loss or
loss due to attenuation basically from
having an aerial go into a cable go into
receiver because we can use an SDR which
is not as good necessarily as a normal
radio that's tunes for specific set of
frequencies we can actually go and cut
the cable out stick the SDR on something
portable Wi-Fi powered connect it
directly for the antenna or through some
boost circuitry or something that have
for whatever signals were getting and
then have Wi-Fi and then access it over
Wi-Fi the SD ours aren't exactly perfect
they have clock drift they have lots of
problems because they're very cheaply
designed and we're using them outside of
the scope of the thing that the design
for so what can we do and the answer is
this which for about roughly 20
5 30 pounds gets you an SDR that you can
just plug in connects to wireless
network plug in somewhere and off you go
mine's plugging plugged into my TV
aerial at home because I don't have a TV
and basically what it's made of is
anything that will work with open wrt so
if you have a home broadband router and
it's not far from your TV aerial for
example you can do exactly the same
thing with that using open wrt my
personal thing of choice at the moment
is the GLI nat64 16a or the AR 150 which
is a clone of a device called the
tp-link WR 703 m which is a very very
hackable device the GLI nets more
hackable it has lots of GPIO pins on it
for you play around with but also
there's quite a few devices this is the
hutu trip made mini which is uses an MT
5350 chipset and that basically lets you
go and do all the same stuff but it's
low power the wireless technology on the
board is not as good as the GLI nets but
because we're not worried about that
we're worried about USB it's fine so we
install the open wrt firmware on our
device there are two ways to do this one
is to build the firmware so everything's
baked in and I'm going to go and go into
a lot more depth about that at bsides
athens so if you're coming along to be
sighs athens and you look my talk then
we'll go into it in extreme detail about
it step by step but you install the open
wrt firmware if you just want to build
this while you messing around run a
command called opkg update opkg install
RTL dash SDR set up a program called RTL
tcp to list on a socket and then you
connect your relevant wife SDR analysis
tools over Wi-Fi to the device so I'm
going to do a demo which may or may not
go as intended because I'm going to do
this over 4g it's not that I am I don't
trust the Wi-Fi here but
um yeah I don't trust the Wi-Fi here All
Right see how I can get this working oh
no honey go my bag no
I'm reaching in my pocket for cable I
promise
there we go all right
ok
you just pull this off it
cool okay so
yeah di da da okay so there we go and I
should pull this back over here
Oh
nope
there we go
so you can see that okay there we go so
this is what the open wrt prompts like
let me just do RT oh crap yeah
okay rtl tcp minus a 0 0 0 s okay so
what I've done is I've start the RTL tcp
program and that will allow me to go and
connect to it obviously because i'm
using 4g it's nowhere near as good in
terms of speed and in terms of latency
so i'm going to try and see if I can
pick up some radio but i'll be picking
up radio from my home in hampshire not
here okay
all right now i'll pop over to GQ RX and
if we pop this down to see 7.5
there should be something popping up in
a minute nope okay all right my demo
sucks so but basically what you can do
is if this was my home wireless network
it would all run perfectly smoothie and
the advantage of this is that you can
run your at your radio tools and just
use something like neck cap to pipe the
audio into a fifo and pull it out and
meanwhile you've got your actual radio
and you've not got the attenuation loss
now you might wonder why this is useful
but if you ever doing any large-scale
signals analysis that would be why okay
just bring this over here a moment
stay home
now obviously the reason that that
didn't work was because it was for g and
the bandwidth that we've got isn't a
grade my upstream bandwidth is and also
so great either so I'm just going to go
over on to the radio and there we go we
stopped and bring up a Firefox session
and I'll show you something else that
you can do now another package that is
standard in open wrt for some reason is
i think all dumped 10 90 which is an ad
SB receive a tool which all sounds very
boring until you realize that you can
actually do some interesting stuff on it
start-
ah
because I believe you
ok
all right sorry are at some stray ltl
processes running okay
okay so it should come up there there we
go alright so I'll just bring this over
okay
there we go
right so if we zoom in on here we can
actually track aircraft flying over
quite a distance all the way up from
milton keynes pretty much all the way
down the south coast and around Heathrow
and although this doesn't look very
clear what this is is you have the
actual flight reference a squawk code
which tells you better about what sort
of light it is and what it's doing the
altitude the speed attract and then what
happens is with this tool it's got very
nice little web interface if you click
on a fly you can then go and look the
flight up on a tool like flightaware or
in this case possibly not that flight
let's try this one there we go easyjet
that'll do for some flights fight or
where we're at the info for because it's
private but you can see here that this
is an easy jet flight going from
somewhere to somewhere I can't really
see the screen very well but um the
reason I wanted to do this at bsides
Athens is because they get some really
interesting flights coming in it turns
out that European Urich rats um all use
various different types of chart jets
for official troika business and it's
the sort of thing that you could run in
Greece to go and track those flights and
then you could see where else those
flights have gone because all the
flights have to log their flight history
so you could see for example but perhaps
when a distinguished member of the
troika is visiting to go and ask receive
it would have mind bending over that
that person or at least that plane had
come from Germany but it also flown to
Portugal so it flown from Portugal to
Germany to Greece and that if you check
the news you'll see that there was a
negotiation in Portugal a few days
earlier so I'm quite interested in
correlating some of that information and
just having a look and seeing how are
great European democracy works
so that's um that's that now that's kind
of the boundary of what I would legally
be able to show you not to call which
side entirely let me take that out there
and then here we go why is this a wicked
toy well first of all you could go and
fit something like a d/s 1307 RTC module
via gpio especially if you add something
like a 64 16 a does anybody know what
happens when you give a software-defined
radio a real-time clock okay you're able
to start sniffing frequencies within the
range that are very time sensitive and
you can then start looking at time slots
and start analyzing when those things
occur down to fractions of milliseconds
which is the sort of thing that you
would need if you were going to do any
work on GSM and because gsm broadcasts
very loudly you would be able to put one
of those devices in say a friend's flat
in Berlin
and have it listen to and stream data
back of course I chose instead to use an
Arduino and basically make somebody's
macbook fail which shows what kind of
skills I've got I enon so software
expansions dump one hour 94 adsb login
which I've already shown and then
there's a thing called multi Mon ng I've
put other in air quotes because i'm
fairly certain if i showed a demo of
that then that would pretty much
definitely be illegal it allows you to
do things like pox AG which is pages
which you would be surprised if you were
ever to go and actually go and look at
other peoples recordings of these
messages and AF any a FSK 1200 signal
and various other types of encoding a
king so i'm going to say no to any other
demos because the wireless telegraphy
access so you can also put a 4g dongle
in for streaming over the USB port i
wouldn't recommend streaming the RT all
day to the roar IQ but if you can
analyze the stuff on the box itself and
send useful data up then you could
hypothetically have something like a
multi lon ng node that sits in a
friend's house and looks at pox egg
traffic and then relays the results over
tool to a web service on the dark web
I'm not aware of such a service existing
so it's a hypothetical thing you could
also use a micro SD card for data
logging if for example one of these
things were to turn up at an airport in
Athens so to have a bit of a recap these
toys are side of weapons they are crap
but they're still technically side of
weapons they can still do damage in the
wrong hands and the thing about it is
none of these things are difficult and
rather than show you a I did something
really cool and leet that's quite
complicated i wanted to try and
encourage people to start experimenting
with this type of hardware because just
because you're no good at something
doesn't
you can't do great things I'd say I'm
living proof but I'm not but it's called
garbage can and not garbage cannot so
drink up your cider and build naughty
toys for cyber security because the
implant of tomorrow could come from you
but build an exploit responsibly don't
make people screw up their lives for
macbooks now before I go I've got one
final thing that I'd like to show you
over at 44 con over the past few years
we started doing badges that have had
circuits on them and there are two
complaints that we commonly get the
first one that we commonly get is these
badges don't work and I have a refund
the second complaint we often have is
that these badges are quite hard to
assemble sometimes requiring custom
cable adapters sometimes requiring
circuits impact by sorry of chips and
packages that are really hard to
actually put together so we started
looking at this and we started bouncing
some ideas around and we're hoping to
have it ready for this year if not we'll
have something else that is equally easy
to put together but I want to talk to
you about what i call the minimalist
electronic learner and that is basically
seven bits of equipment but it's seven
things that when put together you can do
all manner of stuff and the design of
this thing is designed specifically to
enable you the user to modify the IOT
hardware that you have to make it do the
things that you want it to do so let's
say for example that you had a smart fan
but the smart fan requires you to use an
app and sign up to a whole load of T's
and C's and costs 100 pounds but instead
you went to a shop and you bought a dumb
fan for 20 quid and all you really want
to do is to come on when it's warm while
using one of these devices and relay you
could prototype of a circuit very easily
to go and switch the fan on with a TMP
36 sensor or any number of other
temperature sensors to say when the
temperature goes above this level switch
the fan on another example of a thing
that we've actually done is build a
Raspberry Pi off switch which is using
one of these to go and connect to a
raspberry pi over the GPIO port
connect over serial issue login issue
sudo shut down my own SH now and then
when the serial connection goes down
flash a light so you know it's safe to
unplug so the principle behind this is
modifying stuff and also enabling cool
research in Hardware buses and things
like that so although it doesn't look
like much on a breadboard will have a
PCB hopefully by 44 Khan if not then
we're going to do a different circuit
that we've already got but it supports a
thing called universal serial interface
which is amazing it basically means that
anything that you can send down it you
can write library for and then go it
will emulate any type of bus or signal
interaction communication type thing you
want and because of that it supports USB
now we can use these devices to do USB
head attacks we can use these devices to
impersonate mice various other things we
can even impersonate USB 1.1 mass
storage can also use ITC and spi either
a slaves or masters and start messing
around with chips so if you wanted to go
and build the device to pull the flash
of a specific chip then this would be a
really really interesting thing to use
to do it it's got a whopping 8 kilobytes
of flash memory so we're talking 1983's
finest technology here 512 bytes of RAM
and 512 bytes of that problem but in the
end in the embedded hardware world is
actually quite a lot to work with for
very simple bus type projects and there
are six pins including an old digital
controllers a breakout board area in the
badge is going to be all through hold
soldered and i'll be doing a demo of
building the badge from scratch at
bsides manchester on the 18th of august
so in conclusion I'd just like to thank
Adafruit for the CC 3000 library crip
thorities is Wi-Fi jamming code the
b-sides crew and also host unknown and
all the for concrete so thanks very much
guys
you