my name is samantha and i am the pit
coordinator at the innocent lives
foundation
before i go a bit more into what i do at
the ilf and what the ilf does i wanted
to just introduce you to what we're
going to be talking about today
we are going to spend the next little
bit talking about something that i like
to call impetuous investigations
otherwise known as impulsive
investigations
the ultimate goal of this presentation
is for you to walk out of this with a
basic understanding of how cognitive
psychology especially biases affect our
decision making and ultimately our own
investigations
my primary role at the ilf is to oversee
the success of our pit the predator
identification team
that is our team of volunteers
investigators that help us unmask online
child predators
we are a non-vigilante non-profit
private predator hunting organization
so we actually seek out anyone who is
requesting or trading child sexual abuse
material that's thinking that they can
hide behind anonymity online
in addition to that i also teach ocean
to
law enforcement officials with heavy
focus on understanding predatory
behavior as well as terminology and
their digital footprint
if i'm not teaching osint specific i'm
also teaching darkweb of research and
tactics
again specifically related to internet
crimes against children
when i'm not with the ilf i hold a
position on the board of directors at
the idaho internet crimes against
children's coalition
so as we go into this presentation one
of the key factors throughout the entire
thing is something that's called
metacognition and stopping to think
about how we think
helps us work towards actionable
intelligence
metacognition is
just that it's intentional thinking
about how you can think and how you
learn
some observations you can make to
yourself about yourself is i'm seeing
i'm feeling i'm thinking i'm noticing
now i'm wondering
so what does psychology have to do with
open source intelligence
well behavior and overall cognitive
psychology
teaches us about the blind spots that
our biases can cause
having blind spots in this line of work
and in overall decision making can lead
us to improper conclusions
you definitely cannot stop yourself from
having biases but you can stop yourself
to think about how
they may be affecting your investigation
and how they may be persuading your uh
overall decision making
this is exactly where metacognition
comes into play really stop and think
about how you are thinking and how is it
affecting your current decisions
there is an entire sea of biases out
there as well as
much more educated books on cognitive
psychology but these were the ones that
i found very interesting that i could
squeeze into the small amount of time
that we have together today
so we are going to be discussing
confirmation bias
anchoring bias
automation bias projection bias
overconfidence bias and then last but
not least the halo effect slash reverse
halo effect
so let's talk by or let's start by
discussing a confirmation bias
confirmation bias is when you're
favoring information that supports your
current preconceptions of something
while you disregard opposing evidence
that you might find
you're ultimately ignoring objective
facts and evidence and seeking out
things that evidence that supports your
current personal beliefs
i'm sure you see news outlets playing to
confirmation bias all the time and
that's why you see various information
that is
correct to their perspective
and not the others
so how does confirmation bias impact our
ocean investigations
well confirmation bias can cause us to
provide incorrect data incorrect data
leads us to improper conclusions
improper conclusions can lead to damaged
lives whether it's your own or someone
else's
someone may be terminated from
employment they may be improperly
convicted
or they or you may suffer overall
reputational damage
so again you cannot
force yourself to absolutely get rid of
this but you can stop and ask yourself
does my evidence only support my theory
have i considered opposing theories and
have i sought out those opposing
theories and have my searches been
specifically seeking validating
information
next is anchoring bias anchoring bias
sounds
in concept similar to confirmation bias
but it's different
in the effect that you're actually
anchoring onto a single piece of
information and allowing that to
overshadow any new information
where confirmation bias is when you are
actually actively seeking out
information that validates your current
perspective
anchoring bias is also known as the
focalism effect
it causes us to get tunnel vision on a
single piece of information anchoring us
into that persistent state of thought
and usually it's the piece of data that
we receive very early on
okay how does anchoring bias affect our
investigations
well when we get tunnel vision on single
pieces of information we lose our
ability to see any new data or pivot
points
so document that anchor point that you
absolutely cannot get out of your head
but be sure you're keeping an open mind
to different perspectives
so some of this mitigation can include
asking yourself have i been disregarding
information just because i deem it
insignificant
how different is this from what i
already originally knew
and what judgments have i made based on
my initial perception
another huge one that we see especially
in this industry is automation bias or
the over reliance on automated decision
making systems now this can be
applicable to all sorts of aspects of
life but i'm going to talk specifically
about um
even infosec oscent
anything that uses automated tools
so as humans we tend to take the path of
least cognitive effort it saves our
brain power there's nothing wrong with
that
and while automation has proven to be
useful in speeding up processes and
finding new data points definitely does
not replace the need for a human element
so how does automation bias impact
investigations
well basing our judgments strictly from
automated results leads us to skewed
skewed conclusions as well as
false positives especially if an account
doesn't actually belong to your target
whether it's a person or an entity
whether they share a similar username
business name
whatever it may be
multigo is excellent but it does come
back with false positives still a great
tool still incredible for finding new
data points but you definitely need to
be sure that you're sitting down and
actually going through that and seeing
what actually belongs to your target
so ask yourself
or be sure that you are always reviewing
and verifying your automated results
keep in mind tools are excellent to
supplement your thought process
but it's definitely not something to
replace your overall thought process
especially not your decision making
and then question if results are
actually related to your person or area
of interest or entity and then document
it if you can't confirm that it is
projection bias this is the assumption
that other people think feel believe and
behave
like you currently do
this can also be your future self and
assuming that your current self
thinks feels believes and behaves
exactly how your future self will
this type of bias is a self forecasting
error
we underestimate the influence of our
current mental states on our own
behavior causing us to make decisions
that need instant gratification
it's a projection of future preferences
or our projection of future preferences
depends on our current state this is
also known as an empathy gap
but overall projection bias is the
unconscious assumption that others
share the same beliefs thoughts or
values that you do
failure to acknowledge this bias can not
only lead to impulsive decision-making
but it can also lead to missed data
points operational security areas
or
errors skewed results and
overall being unprepared
so be sure to ask yourself
what's my current state of mind or
emotion and how is it affecting my
current
decision making throughout my
investigation
am i judging the situation in a way that
only suits my current needs
or am i considering my potential future
scenarios or needs that i may not
currently be prepared for and how might
i prepare for those
the next one is overconfidence bias
overconfidence bias can be especially
detrimental it's when we overestimate
our own
abilities overconfidence can be
influenced by behavioral factors
emotional factors cognitive factors and
even environmental which i don't have
listed here
inflated confidence causes us to take
certain issues lightly some great
examples include ethics communications
especially skill level
the higher the level of overconfidence
the higher the level of risk
there's definitely a key difference
between overconfidence and confidence
when we start embellishing our abilities
or our capability to understand a
certain situations both to ourselves and
others we run a pretty heavy risk of
having distorted perceptions and when it
comes to osint that puts us in an even
higher risk for operational security
mistakes
or even ethical mistakes some of the
worst ethical mistakes come from
overconfidence
so just keep in mind
no one can know everything and there is
a ton of strength in acknowledging what
you don't know and even more strength in
seeking out the opinion of somebody who
may know about something that you don't
currently have the right
knowledge on
but just be sure that you're not
revealing any details that you're not
supposed
to and what i mean by that is you can
seek out help in ocean investigations
but be sure that you're not revealing
who the client is who your target is any
pii things uh surrounding your target
and or client and so forth
overconfidence can pretty heavily play
into the halo and reverse halo effect
now these effects are when perceived
characteristics of a person cause us to
have positive or negative bias towards
their overall personality
so with the halo effect it's when you're
viewing the person as an angel so a
positive impression equals higher trust
that we place in them which leads to
further positive assumptions
so the if you know somebody or an entity
like a company has a positive quality
you're more likely to come to the
conclusion that they have other positive
traits and let those overshadow any
negative traits
whereas the reverse halo effect is the
exact opposite it's also known as the
horn and or devil effect
so if you know a person or entity has a
negative quality you're much more likely
to come to the conclusion that they have
other negative traits and allow that
impression to define your overall
uh
judge of their character
so a negative impression equals lower
trust which leads to further negative
assumptions
both of these can heavily cloud our
judgment in overall decision making and
our osint investigations
the halo effect is part of why social
engineering can be so effective
especially if you're creating a positive
rapport with that person
but you have to be careful to not make
that person start to question
those positive traits
overconfidence bias supplements both of
these because we're pretty prone to
believing that would never happen to me
i would never make that call
i would know if this was a
if this was a fake person
i would know if this was a bad person
so it's fairly easy to see how that can
really heavily influence
our decision making and other people's
decision making
unfortunately i don't have time to go
into
in depth on each of those biases um
hopefully by now you at least have a
basic understanding of how cognitive
psychology influences the way that we
perceive things and how we react to
those things
remember that no one is immune to biases
and you can't force yourself to not have
them
but you can be aware of them and you can
be aware of the impact that they have on
your decision making
but when we let impulse guide our
decision making we run into much higher
risks especially when it comes to
investigations and social engineering
i am happy to answer any questions
in the chat or wherever is applicable
there are some ways that you can support
the innocent lives foundation and learn
more about what we do as i mentioned we
are a non-profit group that actually
seek out anyone who is hiding behind
anonymity online while they abuse
children
but that is all for now thank you