hi welcome to percent personality based
open source intelligence gathering an
approach to intelligence gathering that
focuses on the human
element my name is richard davey i'm a
red team lead at the home depot my focus
is in social engineering physical
penetration testing and open source
intelligence
in this talk we'll briefly cover what
social engineering is
what sc attacks benefit from open source
intelligence and personality based open
source intelligence
what open source intelligence is why we
would gather it where we might get it
and the importance it plays in social
engineering engagements and red seeming
engagements
and then we'll cover what
personality-based open source
intelligence is
where we might find it and why we might
be looking for it
so first what is social engineering well
michael tyler says in his book brain
hacking that at its core social
engineering is the building and
leveraging of influence in order to
persuade others to act as you want them
to
or put another way to get someone to
make a decision that benefits you
now i like this definition as it relates
to social engineering engagements or red
teaming engagements
but when i social engineer my best
friend and they're telling me about
their plans or whereabouts for their
birthday so that i can throw them a
surprise party that doesn't benefit me
or if i'm social engineering my teenager
into telling me where they're actually
going to be on saturday night so that i
can make sure that they're safe or not
getting into trouble
that benefits them sure it helps my
peace of mind but
ultimately it benefits them
but when i social engineer my boss into
giving me a pay raise or an extra week
of paid vacation that benefits me
if i'm performing a social engineering
engagement where i social engineer
someone into letting me into a building
or clicking a malicious link in a
phishing email that obviously doesn't
benefit them
it benefits me
so
social engineering is the building and
leveraging of influence in order to
persuade others to act in a manner that
is for yours or their own best interest
the practice of influence or influencing
or persuading an individual into taking
some action based on some input
so what social engineering attacks
benefit from the use of open source
intelligence or personality based open
source intelligence well first we have
phishing we have to know the email and
then if we perform a spear phishing
attack we're going to need to know a
little bit of information to make that
look legitimate
and then phishing which is voice
phishing i'm going to call you up but
first i have to have your phone number
and i have to know what i need to talk
about or who i need to be when i call
you
then smishing i have to have a phone
number again and then i need to know
what kind of text message it is that i
need to send to have you interact with
it
we have impersonation which neat it
requires a decent amount of open source
intelligence i need to know where the
office is i need to know who i need to
be when i show up and what i need to be
talking about or wearing or or how i
should approach
and then we have pre-pending if you
don't know what pre-pending is basically
this is the act of tagging someone on
social media to gain more interaction
well first you have to know their social
media handle and then you have to know
the topics that they're talking about
and what it is that they're interested
in so that you can engage them and build
that interaction
so what is open source intelligence well
from the office of the director of
national intelligence it is intelligence
produced from publicly available
information that is collected
exploited and disseminated in a timely
manner to an appropriate audience for
the purpose of addressing a specific
intelligence requirement
the focus here is that it's intelligence
produced from publicly available
information
we're gaining this information from
public resources open social media we're
not going and stealing it from a
computer or a file covenant
in today's world a large portion of that
data can be collected online but osim
predates the internet so it was
previously collected from newspapers
physical bulletin boards magazines and
still can be today
so why why might we be performing an
oscent exercise well attackers and
offensive security researchers alike are
looking for pieces of intelligence that
make targeting a business or an
individual easier attackers for
malicious purposes and offensive
security researchers to educate
companies and individuals on what might
make them vulnerable
such as social media sites that are
leaking user names or leaking sensitive
company information or maybe they're
leaking details of office spaces or
computer systems maybe in pictures
or news that details recent developments
or if the company's doing well or poorly
or have they been breached or do they
announce technological advances
and then the people the individuals in
the company the team the structures the
culture what that might look like these
are just a few things that an attacker
or an offensive security researcher may
be looking for to make them sound a
little bit more legitimate which is why
this is important we want to sound
legitimate when we are approaching a
company for the purposes of social
engineering or red teaming we want to
drill down on our target acquisition who
am i targeting what am i going to target
so i'm not all over the place and just
acting sporadically
i need to know the language what phrases
or words or technological details should
i know or speak about
the location where am i going what am i
looking for when i get there especially
if i'm going to perform an impersonation
attack
the vendors who can i be to get in the
building or if i'm going to send a
package from a vendor who doesn't need
to come from
the people who works there how long have
they been there who do they talk to
outside of work or at work or who are
they close to that they work with
these are all valuable pieces of
intelligence that get me closer to my
goal of appearing legitimate as security
personnel if something looks as if it
doesn't belong it's probably wrong
attackers and offensive security
researchers want to appear as legitimate
as possible to keep suspicions low and
prevent an incident
so what first
right when i first start an open source
intelligence exercise
what do i do first well first i set some
goals
why do i need the intelligence in the
first place
the next is scope who's off limits who's
not what facilities are assets or
off-limits and what se attacks are
allowed and which ones are not because
that might actually determine the type
of intelligence i seek and the depth at
which i choose to seek it because if i'm
performing generic phishing i only need
email addresses if i'm performing spear
phishing
i need a little bit more information and
if i'm impersonating someone that should
be there i'm going to need a lot of
information
the next thing i need to do is identify
the gaps i have in intelligence so we do
a brief gap analysis what do i know
today
the company name hopefully
maybe some people inside the company
versus what do i need to know where the
company's located who their vendors are
phone numbers email addresses etc
so once i've gotten my goals and i've
defined scope and i've done a brief gap
analysis now i can look at the where
where am i going to get the information
that i'm seeking
so
we can look at social media facebook
twitter instagram
myspace
i think it still exists
we look at vsco.co or radio.fm or maybe
we could go and look at
foursquare
professional social media such as
linkedin linkedin is a great place to
get information about a company and the
individuals that work at the company
their specific roles or responsibilities
the tools that they use
company job wrecks are posted on
linkedin that detail what the company is
looking for because of specific software
tools that they have internally
we could go to blogs and community
platforms
online databases search engine
manipulations such as google dorks we'd
also look at public hearings and sec
filings or professional and academic
publications academic papers
all of these are great places to find
information
what we're doing is we're approaching
these public forums and locations in a
methodical format
so that we can gain strategic pieces of
intelligence to answer specific
questions
so we've defined our goals our scope
what se attacks we can perform
we've done a brief gap analysis we know
what we need to know and we know what we
already know
we know where we're gonna find that
information so now we get to do some
intelligence gathering
we head over to google we start digging
we find social media details company
profiles job wrecks
news articles
what does it look like
this is xyz corp
they specialize in sales and marketing
we located several high-value targets
including their ceo joey bates their cfo
mark asensa head of operations
head of security jack ryan don't mess
with that guy
their internal teams include i.t finance
and marketing inside of it they have a
team working on a custom crm and erp
software so they can get away from
salesforce and sap
they have custom hr software written in
c-sharp and then custom databasing tools
written in java
they recently partnered with aws to
migrate all of their internal
microservice infrastructure to the cloud
currently they're looking for sap
engineers and experienced salesforce
users until their custom tooling is
complete
they have several associates who attend
a company get together at a local bar
and grill on friday after work
they have a company reddit and facebook
and twitter page that have no
restrictions allowing anybody on the
internet to see them
and then their marketing department has
a public instagram page where they like
to share pictures of their calendars
detailing holidays and birthdays and
days off pictures of their desks and
their office spaces and then pictures of
their associates wearing their rfid
security badges and their corporate
polos
on that instagram page we were able to
find grant grant hofstede is a project
manager he's been at the company for a
year so he probably doesn't know what
information he should be releasing and
what information he shouldn't be
releasing
he reports to a senior manager named
sean delaney
sean is out of office on vacation for
the next two weeks according to the
marketing department's leaked calendar
on instagram this gives us a way that we
can spearfish grant
grant has three direct reports all of
who have been at xyz longer than he has
he uses a well-known project management
tool called smartsheets you may have
heard of it and keeps a personal board
of work tasks on trello that he forgot
to make private
he has two social media handles that we
found grant hof rocks hyphen bang bang
and de hoffenader
he leaked his corporate username format
on reddit when asking questions about
specific tools used internally
g.m.hofstead
and his company email g.m.hofstead
emp.xyzcorp.com
so we have really good intelligence here
chunks of information that could
potentially lead to a compromise
or at the very least give us enough
information to build a pretext that
could lead to compromise
so what did i miss
here's the deal this is a great stopping
point we answered all of our
intelligence requirements we were able
to successfully close the gap between
what we knew and what we didn't know
many successful social engineering
engagements and red team operations have
been run from this level of osun so
honestly nothing we could stop here
but what if i told you that you could go
a little deeper down the rabbit hole
and the payoff may be an increase in
successful social engineering pretext
execution or at the very least a better
understanding of the people that you're
dealing with on the other end
to do so
we answer some basic questions
starting with who is my target
what does my target want me to think
about them how do they want to be
treated what do they desire or need what
are their likes or dislikes
how do they view themselves and others
ultimately i want to know who my target
is and how i should approach them
so how do i find that information well
percent
personality based open source
intelligence
is open source information that you
would gather by studying
and understanding a person's social
media or their professional social media
blog posts and professional articles or
even the way that they comment or remark
on other people's posts
and articles
the purpose is to build an idea of the
type of pretext you may use to engage
them
if i wanted to engage a target at a
coffee shop how should i talk to do that
what should i say
what topic should i focus on
this isn't what they do or when they do
it or even how they do it this is who
they are when they do it
so what
you might actually be thinking so what
why do i need this phishing emails have
very little to no emotion associated
with them i can play on fear of missing
out or authority or maybe even fear of
loss i can impersonate a vendor without
this information
why do i need this
so two things in my opinion humble
opinion as it is
the first
success
the ability to successfully approach a
target
or bump a target from a few steps away
and get their attention
captivate their interest and get them
involved
we want them to interact we want them to
talk how do we do that the second we're
not the bad guys at the end of the
engagement or the interaction when the
target finds out that they were indeed a
target
they need to remember that you did not
leave them feeling horrible we should
always leave them feeling better for
having met us
we do this by helping them feel more
connected we're like them we speak like
them we have similar interests
there was a scientific paper titled
highlighting relatedness promotes
pro-social motives and behaviors
in it researchers noted that when giving
tasks if they highlighted relatedness
the result was higher interest in
volunteering
and intentions to volunteer
additionally they found
that when participants wrote about
relatedness experiences that action
alone promoted feelings of connectedness
to others
when we find that others are like us we
want to be around them more it gives us
a sense of being a part of a group or a
tribe and helps us feel more connected
to the person
the next thing is our target should feel
accepted we as humans have an innate
requirement to be socially socially
accepted for who we are
in the paper the need to belong roy
ballmeister and mark leary
leary stated in their conclusions
we found evidence of basic desire to
form social attachments people form
social bonds readily even under
seemingly adverse conditions
people who have anything in common who
shared common even unpleasant
experiences
or who simply are exposed to each other
frequently
tend to form friendships or other
attachments
they go on to say that forming or
solidifying social attachments generally
produces positive emotions
whereas real imagined or even potential
threats to social bonds
generate a variety of unpleasant
emotions
next our target should feel appreciated
for their points of view their
uniqueness thoughts and opinions that
they have
feeling appreciated makes us feel more
connected and deepens our sense of
purpose or meaning in life
and then lastly
we're there to make them feel heard
give them permission to speak
it's a weird statement i know so let me
explain
nothing feels worse than trying to talk
to someone who is looking at their phone
or doesn't seem to be interested in what
we're saying
it literally makes us feel as if we
should just stop talking take our
thoughts
and go elsewhere
why
because we love being heard we love
being listened to we speak about
ourselves and our desires and our needs
and the hopes that someone
will listen
so actively listening and engaging the
target because you have an idea of who
they are and what they need
can literally open the conversation and
offer them a platform
to be heard on
so we know why we should be doing this
where do we look
social media sites professional social
media sites blogs personal web pages
professional web pages
it's not really any different than the
tools we're already using for oscent
the approach is different
what we're looking for is different
sam gosling
a professor of psychology spent years
snooping through people's things
knowingly i think
to discover what their personal space
tells us about the
big five ocean personality traits
openness conscientiousness extroversion
agreeableness
and neuroticism and he said this in
regard to snooping people's personal
websites
websites are extraordinarily to include
social media good places to learn about
people perhaps the best of all places
our site snooping yielded information
that was at least as accurate as what we
learned from the bedrooms offices and
music collections
we studied
and accurate across a much broader array
of personality variables than most other
domains
he goes on to say that websites proved
useful for learning about all five
traits
so in this
nice blurry graph here you can see that
websites
offered as accurate if not more accurate
information than the bedroom did in all
five
trades it offered more information in
the office and more information than the
music top ten
now
i want to point out that these are
places we spend a large amount of time
our bedroom it's where we feel
comfortable this is this is how we are
are
comfortable our bedroom is set up in a
manner that suits us our office we spend
seven to nine hours in the covid world
we spend 10 to 12 hours
and it's in our home
and websites and social media sites
offer as much
or as accurate of information
and what's even better is in today's
world with selfies and and pictures and
the rate at which we take pictures
because we have a camera in our pocket
at all times
personal blogs websites social media can
also give us insight into
bedrooms and offices
that we didn't have before
you can't just break into an office
that's not open source intelligence but
when it's open source intelligence
because it's on social media it's open
source intelligence the bedroom
you can get an idea of what how they how
they act or how they're comfortable or
who they are from their bedroom and they
probably have pictures of it on social
media
so
what are we looking for when we're
perusing their social media trying to
get an idea of who our target is
language
how do they talk about themselves about
others about life or work or current
topics the pictures
who's in them where are they at
and then their interactions
how do they interact with people how do
they respond
you've probably heard the saying words
create worlds
so when focusing on language we really
want to focus on the words how they're
put together
how do they speak do they reference
themselves a lot do they speak about
their teams those outside of their
circles why is that important it gives
us an idea of how they view the world
and themselves in it
people who speak about themselves a lot
may be self-involved or more concerned
with how they fit into the bigger
picture so approaching them with verbage
that focuses on teams or their groups or
their families you're probably
alienating them and they're going to
stop listening
people who speak about the team or the
group or their clubs or their
affiliations may be more interested in
how the team or the group or club is
viewed overall so pitching an idea or
discussing at length their individual
accomplishments or achievements or
individual goals or ideas may alienate
them and ultimately leave them feeling
as if you're not listening
if they're self-focused you might hear
things like i me my
what i have what i've done what i'm
doing this affects me or this is mine
you may see this in their actual written
language on their social media sites
team focused language might
look like we are all working really hard
here or our success is really a team
effort or so and so and i the they're
always referencing uh
their group of people or
their relationships as opposed to
themselves
outside verbage may be things like that
group or those guys or that company
anything that's not directly referenced
to them or the people that they directly
associate with
another thing that we could look at is
the satur communication types
so virginia saturn in the 1970s came up
with these communication times and there
are five of them we have the blamer
always finding fault never accepting
responsibility
always blaming someone else or the
placator who all who's always out to
please or never asserting or disagreeing
and always seeking approval
the computer personality or
communication type very correct and
proper with no emotion or maybe masking
or feeling uh vulnerable but trying to
cover it up
and then the distractor seeking
attention to compensate for loneliness
or inadequacy or whatever it may be so
they're always telling these big bold
stories or they're always blaming or
yelling or creating disruption and then
the leveler
usually assertive with the goal of
mutual problem solving they don't mask
their emotions they're very comfortable
with who they are
these details alone might help us better
associate with the target
if it's always someone else's problem
you can be that person relate to that
with the target
maybe they need attention can you
provide that what type of attention are
they looking for
maybe they placate and getting them to
fulfill a request wouldn't take very
much effort once a connection has been
established
next is how much or what are they saying
are they super chatty or don't say a lot
at all do they use abstract language or
very direct and concrete language just
literally the differences in
extraversion and introversion
in a research article titled when
feeling speak
camille bucaboom
i think that's how you pronounce the
name and a group of researchers
discovered interesting notes on the
distinguishability between extroverts
and introverts language
finding that extroverts when describing
what they see in photographs tend to use
more abstract language
while introverts appear to be a lot more
specific about what they saw
jordan peterson and jacob hirsch from
the university of toronto
asked students
to write about past experiences and
future goals
in the written language they discovered
that the more liberal a person was
the more words they used pertaining to
senses
the more neurotic the more they referred
to the emotional angst of the situation
and the more conscientious the more
language is centered around achievements
and work-related phrases and terms
another study
tell me a story and i will tell you who
you are
took a hundred students
and a group of german researchers led by
albrecht kufner
gave the students five word pro words as
prompt plane crash parlor made fireworks
middle ages and supermarket to write a
creative story they found two things
first
open-minded participants
produced more creative stories and the
more agreeable participants created
stories with a higher social vibe to
them
the second thing they observed was that
when having a second set of participants
judge the traits of the authors
they were fairly accurate in doing so
and the last study i'll cover here is
taliyarcone and his paper personality in
a hundred thousand words
researched and analyzed
694 blogs over the course of about two
years
the group of individual bloggers was on
average predominantly female with an
average of age of 36 he then compared
this reading to answers given in a
personality questionnaire by the authors
what he found was that contrary to the
belief that we
get to tell people what we want them to
believe on the internet the choice of
words by the author consistently alluded
to their personality types more neurotic
people used more
words associated with negative emotions
and more extroverted people used more
words pertaining to positive emotions
those scoring high unagreeableness would
avoid swear words and use more words
related to communality
and the consciences blogger
again
mentioned achievements
and wrote in terms of works accomplished
all things that tell us about this
person we can gather from the words that
they're putting out on their social
media
james pinabaker says this who would have
ever predicted that a high school
student who uses too many verbs in her
college admissions essay is likely to
make lower grades in college
or that a poet whoever uses the word i
in his poetry is at a higher risk of
suicide
he goes on to say that by looking more
carefully at the ways people convey
their thoughts and language we can begin
to get a sense of their personalities
emotions and connections with others
having that insight
to understand someone's emotions or
their personalities can be the
difference in connecting and not
connecting
next
what do you see in their pictures
are they celebrating or partying maybe
they just like to have fun are their
pictures dark
hoodie hood covering the face or are
they creating barriers even in their
images maybe with a pillow or a person
because they're uncomfortable
what does that say about them maybe they
only want you to think they want to be
left alone there are several groups and
cliques that exist in the world today
that resonate with that style of
interaction and just like all humans who
need to connect with someone this is a
statement to connect
what does the body language represent
are smiles fake
if the
target is at an event where they're semi
unaware of the photos that are being
taken
how do they look are they enjoying
themselves
what do their selfies say about them
remember
selfies unlike the embarrassing photo
your friend posted of you from that
crazy night at the bar
are user approved
the message in the image
is exactly what the target individual
wants you to think about them
they're after all
the messenger the creator and the owner
of the portrait and very rarely do we
put a selfie on the internet with the
intent of generating a negative response
this is a person seeking a personal
positive response
what are what are some tag lines that
we've seen in selfies
maybe their approval seeking with a
caption like
one of my photos always looks so
horrible
or i'm always such a mess
i wish i was more put together
maybe they're taking selfies with their
new car or their new clothes or their
new accessories because they want you to
think that they're successful or
fashionable
that may be something you could build a
conversation off of
hey that's a really nice watch where did
you get that
if that's the response they're looking
for they're going to engage
most of our images when approved by us
and posted by us are meant to affirm
something for us whether we're a good
person with good intentions or
fashionable or successful this gives us
an idea of who that person wants to be
seen as
in some cases they're actually posted so
that others will make those affirmations
for us to make us feel better
the added benefit is that we don't have
to stroke our own ego somebody does it
for us
next where are they
in a papal paper titled personality
place transactions sandra mats and
gabrielli gabriela hirari
commented this
researchers found that places can draw
out certain aspects of people's
personalities their data also showed
that people with certain personality
traits
are drawn to certain places
for example
people who tend to be more extroverted a
trait that reflects how sociable a
person is
spent more time in public places
compared to more introverted people
the findings also show that spending
time in a particular place predicts
people's momentary personality states
and their short-term trait expressions
over time
for example people reported feeling more
extroverted in the moments when spending
time at bars or parties cafes or
restaurants or friends houses compared
with when at home
so we relate this back to the group of
people who go out on friday night to the
work gathering for xyz corp we may have
some introverts
online
that are more extroverted at the bar we
can use that
and then lastly who
are they alone
maybe they're self-involved or maybe
they prefer being alone and having
social interaction at a distance which
we'll cover in just a few minutes
do they prefer pictures with friends
or groups of friends
does this accurately portray their
personality when compared to their words
and language yes we have to do a little
bit of comparison to get a full idea
is there a lack of images
not because they don't
interact on social media but maybe
because they prefer to experience life
rather than documented
all these things are discoverable in the
imagery on a on a social media site or a
website or a blog
or even in the lack of imagery
we just have to be looking for it
and still
says that selfies help people portray a
version of themselves to the world this
is state this is a statement that says
look at me this is who i am
she goes on to say that in real life
people are constantly trying to stand
out
whether it is by what they say or the
clothes that they wear
and the selfie is no different it's a
statement to the world it allows people
to stand out among the masses
so then lastly is interactions
how does the target handle conflict do
they rant how do they communicate over
overall
in our article the psychology behind
social media interactions leraz margalit
a customer experience psychologist
points out a few things about our online
behavior
the most important one to me was this
studies have found that day-to-day
interactions are based almost entirely
on non-verbal communication
when we interact with others we
continuously process wordless signals
like facial expressions
tone of voice gestures body language eye
contact and even the physical distance
between us
and the other person and you might be
thinking up i knew that
but she goes on to say this
people in online interactions
are much more casual because they do not
have to be attentive to each other's
signals verbal and symbolic feedback is
not immediate so there's no need to be
constantly aware of the other person's
responses
to me that's important because it says
that in online settings we have the
ability to communicate without the
direction interruption or even the
social guidance of others being in our
way
we can act and react and interact the
way that we truly see fit
in some cases removing the world's
influence on our personal behavior
that allows us to
express a stronger sense of who we are
to the core and allow that to shine
through
la raz finalizes the article by saying
this interactions via social media make
visitors feel connected
without the difficulties and
complexities of face-to-face interaction
now remember what i said about the
images if they're always alone in the
picture maybe they value interaction but
they don't have to deal with the
difficulties and complexities of
actually engaging you face to face
that's an important personality trait
that we need to be looking for
next is excitement
what excites the target what makes them
eager to talk in a positive or negative
light being angry is just excitement
just in a negative direction
do they like to drone on about subjects
that excite them do they like to rant
about things that anger them if so can
we use that
and then finally emotion
how do they react to emotional posts
whether it be positive or negative sad
or happy
what emotions are portrayed in their
imagery their words this isn't an
exact or accurate science but we can get
a sense of what makes them tick by
reading and studying the ways in which
they communicate with others on social
media
and even
how they want their onlookers to see
them through that communication maybe
they want to appear as a an empathetic
person
maybe they want to be seen as
emotionally connected or intelligent or
knowledgeable or helpful maybe they want
to be seen as the purveyor of political
and economical knowledge
maybe they like being known as the
person who doesn't take anything from
anybody
those are all important things that we
can pick up through their interactions
their imagery and their language
so we know why we should do this
but why is it important to our social
engineering engagements
well
elicitation influence persuasion
techniques all of those things that you
use in a social engineering engagement
they become much easier to use when you
better understand the target's needs
wants and desires
while it isn't always going to provide
the fullest and most accurate picture of
the target we can at least begin to
understand them
with an understanding of personalities
likes dislikes and interactions we can
build a more effective pretext
and as we become more effective at
identifying engaging and connecting
with our targets in a more efficient
manner
we have the opportunity to first
understand a bit about who they are and
how they want to be seen and a little
bit about how they want to be treated
and then build an effective pretext or
an effective engagement off of that
overall we can build that advanced
communication profile that we're looking
for
based on the information discovered
during percent
and have an upper hand when it comes to
engaging the person of interest
raising our chances at a successful
engagement
so here we are
we know what we're looking for we know
who we're looking at and now we've asked
these basic questions and we're going to
start digging
so we dig in we scroll through facebook
and instagram we understand the pictures
and the personality
what does it look like
meet grant he's an open guy he's
confident and sure of himself he accepts
the consequences of his own actions he
takes ownership
he looks to resolve conflict and issues
quickly
he loves going out and meeting new
people but finds comfort and comfort in
the quietness of his own home
he's an animal lover his dog recently
passed away so he loves sitting at the
dog park on sunday
dog park on sundays to watch other dogs
play it makes him feel better
he's a member of the local country club
and a running club and enjoys getting
together with his local conservationist
group
he loves to rant about his job when
angered he'd tell you all about the
company process and how horrible it is
he uses phrases like my team the guys my
group relationships
he only takes a selfie if friends are in
it
here's a personal blog where he likes to
talk about the amazing experiences he
has when he's traveling the world and
things he's learned from his new job
his pictures show that he's kind of
messy
and doesn't value organization
leads to believing that he has a he's a
bit open
he's a visual communicator he uses
phrases like i see what's going on here
or imagine this
he loves to be helpful sometimes to his
own detriment he likes to show others
that he's in control and really knows
what's going on
it makes him feel better as a person and
he wants to share that with the world
this information gives you insight
into who grant is
not just what he does or how he does it
but who he is when he does it
we could most certainly use this to
to get an idea of how we should approach
him this individualized information
gives us an idea
of
how to connect with grant and gain
further information or at the very least
gain interaction
i'll leave you with this because this is
one of the most common questions that i
get about any se technique and that's
how do you practice it well like
any other sc technique or ocean
technique or tactic it does require
practice and you can practice in almost
any setting
you have friends with social media take
a scroll see if your ideas of their
personality line up with what you find
when you're around them listen
see if you can pick up on the social
cues that you've seen in their online
interactions
matthew lieberman in his book social why
our brains are wired to connect says
this to the extent that we can
characterize evolution as designing our
modern brains this is what our brains
were wired for
reaching out
and interacting with others
these social adaptations are central to
making us the most successful species
on earth
and with that
i'll take questions