hi everyone welcome to our recon done
right talk a guide to a successful
physical we're super excited to be
presenting here at layer 8 and share our
stories and knowledge with you
hi i'm rob curtinseifer director of
services here at in guardians and it's a
pleasure to be speaking to you guys at
layer eight today
i'm zlata pavlova i do social media and
marketing here at dan guardians and also
assist in various oceans and social
engineering engagements at inguardians
so just a quick disclaimer before we
start
this method works for us you may need to
make some small adjustments or big
adjustments depending on your situation
and your style of work
uh for me i spent years
inside of various reconnaissance units
inside the military uh specifically the
us army
and zalata well she's just russian and
you don't mess with russians
awesome so an overview here
of what we're going to talk about first
thing first we're going to
define what recon is uh from a
military's perspective uh versus an
infosec perspective
and
it's really important because
reconnaissance really started with the
military
then we're going to dive into
pre-engagement intelligence gathering
ocean
as some of you may know
and then we're going to talk about
establishing a pattern of life this is
the first phase in which we are setting
foot
on client side
uh phase three is analysis and planning
uh that's where the bulk of the majority
of the work is going to happen
phase four is breach
phase five is sensitive site
exploitation and exfiltration
and then we're going to have a
conclusion
so the first thing we want to define is
the military
definition of reconnaissance
very basic
it is at the observation of a region
to locate an enemy or to ascertain
strategic features for example
do these insurgents here have air
defense capabilities so we send the
reconnaissance team in the ground
observe them do they have air defense
capabilities yes or no
do we they have
this very specific style of fighting or
you know what what is their pattern
where do they move where do they come
from where do they hide
it's a very
very
narrow view
and
when it comes to
reconnaissance and the infosec world
it's uh
basically everything that you can
collect on a specific target um online
uh when we talk about reconnaissance
specifically for
the physical engagement physical
penetration tests um
reconnaissance
phase also includes um establishing the
pattern of life uh getting familiar with
the target location uh so similar to the
military uh definition of reconnaissance
the main goal of
any reconnaissance is to be is to
correctly uh
is to covertly collect all of the data
on
the target you want to make sure that
the client has no idea that you even
gathering um all of that awesome
information on them
so
phase one
intel gathering ocean
um this is one of the most important
phases uh
when you're preparing for a physical
penetration engagement
and ocean is really your best friend for
um any engagement including social
engineering engagements as well
uh why ocean matters uh it matters
because
you wanna get familiar with the
target the client um you wanna get
familiar with uh the company culture you
wanna find out who the employees are
yeah you wanna see where uh the targets
um like uh location you want to get
familiar with uh surroundings of that
location you really want to have a whole
picture of what you're going to be
working with on your uh
physical engagement uh there are various
resources available where you can
collect all of that data
and it's all gonna depend on your goals
and objectives it's also gonna depend on
type of industry that your client or
your target is in
because certain industries have
less of the let's say social media
presence or an online presence therefore
collecting the intel sometimes is kind
of uh tricky it's a little bit harder
versus you know let's say like a major
retailers that are constantly
online on various platforms and it makes
it a lot easier
to
collect information same goes to
employees because certain
government organizations or government
defense organizations
they have specific policies of not
having employees let's say on linkedin
so have to take all of that um
into the consideration
also with any um ocean investigation
you have to check multiple sources
going on one side and you know
copy pasting something from there it's
uh it's not enough
you need to verify your uh
data
always because
things are changing what was on one side
yesterday is no longer there today
so
verify
all of your data and take lots of notes
while you
uh going through the process of
data collection
intel gathering because again
oftentimes
sites gets taken down or
users deleting their accounts or
whatever it might be so taking
screenshots taking notes to make sure
that you can include that in the report
you can show the client how did you get
from the point a to point b uh in your
reconnaissance phase is really really um
important
again i
don't
underestimate the power of
manual
search
we all know that when it comes to osen
there are thousands of different tools
available they all do different things
some of them are amazing
but some of them are not particularly
useful when you're collecting
data collecting ocean for
physical penetration testing therefore
manual search
although time consuming but it is
important step in every preparation for
the engagement because
you need to look at pictures uh you need
to
find i don't know badge pictures or
workstation setups and unfortunately
tools can't really
make that happen for you
and divide responsibilities divide
responsibilities with your
partner if you're on the team
with your teammates because first it's
going to save you a lot of time second
of all everyone's thought process is
different so
you can really
um you can really find a lot of value
and
others ways of you know thinking and
searching and together you can
really put a valuable data in your
pre-engagement
absolutely
the the first thing uh the
pre-engagement intel gathering
uh i want to talk about it is
just
print a map right that if you could
print a map of your target you could
identify the target's location in
surrounding areas
right um
it's important because you're able to
see the
train features uh can i approach from
the back is it heavily wooded
is there a creek
blocking
this ingress point is there fences
um
what are some of the surrounding
businesses right that's also very
important um
and also you get a look through uh is
there any doors uh where the doors are
uh is there gates is there guard shacks
is there
um large windows
um
if you get a really good map such from
uh google earth
um or google maps you could zoom in and
and try to pinpoint where the cctvs are
using street view
um
you also get the ability to find
visible physical security controls
do they have rfid badge readers next to
the doors
um
are they push doors are they pull doors
are they just regular knob doors
right all this is stuff that you could
do pre-engagement intel gathering so
that you have a better
assessment
an idea of
what the client has once you get on site
yep uh also something to um to add to
that uh when you're looking for
when you're looking at maps whether it's
google maps or
bing maps or whatever
um
the reason why you want to look at
various resources is because every
single
map has a different time frame on
when that specific street view or
pictures were taken
oftentimes you can see how certain
terrain certain area looks like in
various times of years
and you can do that with google earth
app if you have that installed you can
go back and
access the archives and see how a
certain area looked like you know a year
ago or in the summer or whatever if they
have that data
available you can also often see uh
delivery trucks or third-party services
pulling in into that location so that
will give you an extra piece of intel
uh maybe this is the company that they
are contracting with
or whatever else might be so
always
important to check
multiple sources when it comes to
maps and really like walk in that street
view get familiar with all of the
surrounding areas because you're going
to need that
on one of the engagements that we
rob and i went
we identified a bunch of access points
we identified surrounding areas with the
fences and everything else so that give
gave us um a good idea of how we can
approach and
where can we start
our you know
descending so to say to um a physical
location for our uh target
so use multiple yeah
if we would have used multiple views
on that engagement
uh and looked back over time we wouldn't
have to have to wait through that swamp
and creek because in the image it looked
like the creek was
you know
a literal small couple inches deep creek
but once we got there
and it started raining uh
um that is pretty deep and it would have
saved us you know having to go buy new
clothes and waterproof clothes just to
try to get across that so
uh that's really important to do and to
look historically over it and forecast
weather
yep absolutely always check the weather
always plan for any weather changes
uh when you're going in unfamiliar
territory so to say
you might also want to look at various
uh company filings
or government records
and the reason behind it is that
sometimes in those filings they use
specific corporate language
that is specific to a particular
organization so some organizations refer
to their employees as associates maybe
or team members so if you're coming up
with the pretext
you want to make sure that it matches
the corporate
lingual you can also see sometimes um
other uh like key people that are in
that specific organization and also
sometimes see like the copy of their
signature or at least the signature that
they use to sign
certain corporate papers again you can
also use that in your
pretext
um
also never
underestimate the power of not so
popular um resources to look at uh
some
location data and that could be yelp if
you are going to like a retail or like a
small shop
because oftentimes yelp would contain
photos of interior exterior and
sometimes people just uh not really
paying attention to what they are
floating and not thinking about the
risks but it's good
for us as
physical pen testers because we can go
on those websites and
have
literally um a good
picture of how
the property looks inside without even
being there
and one of the engagements rob and i
were working on
i found out um
i found a
news piece from like the local news
company
that recorded
pretty much
everything
on the targets location like the inside
every office every hall everything so
without us even being there we already
knew where to go and how the building is
going to look like
on the inside so multiple sources always
some
not so popular ones like youtube yelp
can really um
help you find the specific
information on the target that you're
looking for
um another thing that we
also always check is various job
postings
and the reason behind it is uh
besides of course you know the company
culture and kind of like the inside look
into
technology they use you can also find
out the schedule
or the shift changes and it's important
for us because when we go on the
physical uh
physical engagement we want to know
when
certain departments are in the office
when people come to work when they leave
whether uh the specific business have
any guards are those guards armed so you
want to be prepared as much as you can
also pay attention to uh reviews from
unhappy employees because they would
often
name drop
you know managers or other co-workers
that they were
upset with
and that will give you a lot of
good intel that you can use in your
pretext
or
already on the spot during your physical
engagement
a good example of that is during one of
our engagements we found that one of the
employees there
was complain that they brought dogs in
right and we're thinking
right are they guard dogs are they drug
sniffing dogs and we reached out to the
point of contact and
it turns out it was uh bed bug sniffing
dogs uh but it brought up a valid point
we had a concern hey you know we're not
gonna do a physical if there's guard
dogs we want to have noticed that if it
wasn't for
digging through some of these reviews
um from from employees
and so that i just want to underline
that a little bit but
yep sorry um
and um also with um a lot of other
resources like you know linkedin company
page or
facebook company pages oftentimes
employees would comment uh they would
over share without even thinking that
they saying something that or sharing a
certain information that should not be
shared um so pay attention to those
comments really like look through to try
and find um as much information as
possible
again an example of one of our
engagements uh we found um a business uh
facebook page however uh it was made by
like a few of um
a few of the workers from that specific
location it wasn't like an actual
authorized uh social media page by the
business
um and that happens a lot because not
every company has like a good uh social
media policy in place
uh explaining if someone can create a
business page or not
um
so
we found this page and since it was
uh ran by the employees only employees
shared a lot a lot of information about
like an internal you know hiring process
they shared their emails uh direct lines
with extensions so we really hit the
gold mine with uh that facebook business
page and we collected a lot of our intel
from that and we used a lot of it uh
during our pretext when we were on site
again it almost felt like you actually
knew everyone when you're walking into
that building because you saw them
on facebook and they really did
uh
share a lot
when it comes to badges um our go-to are
usually um instagram
sometimes facebook
but instagram
has
the geolocation search feature
and if you know your target address
you can type that in and see if anyone
is posting pictures in that specific
location and you can find
a lot of good
badges good pictures of badges
workstation setups and things like that
again you can find out who the employees
are you can even match them later on on
linkedin or
i don't know facebook whatever your
goals and objectives are for that
specific um
engagement
again
youtube
lots of videos
i will have an example in the next
couple of slides um check everything
that you possibly can when you're
getting ready for um
the physical engagement do you have
anything to add to that rob
nope i think he covered it all
awesome
so um here i have just uh an example of
a simple
ocean
uh
mind map so to say
um
it helps you to uh
filter and narrow down uh all of the
various resources that you need to look
at
uh before
starting your
phase one reconnaissance digital
reconnaissance
um
the map is gonna differ by you know the
industry again if your client work uh if
your client is in like really super
secret industry of course maybe they're
not going to have an extensive
social media presence or they're not
going to list their employees on the
website
however for
the major
for the major clients uh
this applies
uh and that can again you can make it in
any way possible but it kind of helps
you narrow down um all of the
areas of search um all of the possible
results maybe that you can
come across and there are
a lot of them are available online that
you can use kind of like a mind map when
you first starting out uh and then as
you start to um
do more and more of those physical
engagements or social engineering
engagements um you can create your own
and find out uh what resources
works best
for you
on
you know of course mine is my favorite
is the social media because i think i
find most information
on people's profiles um
that are like that like to over share
um
that
business facebook page that i talked
about earlier one of the employees um
also checked in on facebook to that
business
and posted her badge that we copied and
then we used uh on our
physical
engagement and
she also posted
another picture and her profile is set
to public so anyone can see
everything
and she also posted a picture of how
the inside of one of the work areas
looked like
with the table that contained a bunch of
folders and that's how we were able to
find out who their payroll company is
security company is
and
another folder even contained password
so later on when we were actually on the
physical engagement we went there and
the folders are still on that
table
so
never yeah underestimate the power of
social media searches
and uh
here are just some examples
that i found on
google
the first image here with the blueprints
um this is actually from the government
defense building
locally here in
california and i believe the picture was
uploaded by the person who
did the remodeling work
because that business does not have any
other
reviews or checkings because it's not
the building where civilians check in
often so to say but
here we are with the blueprints
um
i also have the screenshot of the
call center it's a video on youtube and
the call center employee decided to
share her work day
with the world
including the sensitive patient info
that i redacted on the screen
um
also multiple workstations multiple
employees the company that she works for
the call center that she works for so a
lot of
a lot of this data is out there and you
don't really need to like dig deep to
find it it's literally just like on the
surface
um
google reviews for
business pages are often useful because
you can find specific names
specific people who works there like
distribute if you're picking up or
dropping off you know you need to talk
to so and so
so
again manual search
is super beneficial with your um oscent
process and
collect collect a list of names
and
and try to
to draw them out
um due to the fact that uh you know i
was doing a physical once
um and as we were breaching the building
uh we weren't able to see the other side
which contained the janitor um the
janitor was startled and who were you
uh
oh bob sent us uh to work on the it
problems that we're having these
computers over i'm rob at i.t this is
so-and-so and i.t and uh he really
wanted us to work after hours today oh
so-and-so sent you okay cool right and
then later on during the engagement we
we um
we we met him again when we were trying
to hit another one of our objectives
and uh he's like oh you guys startled me
again i forgot you were here and we're
like hey man can you let us in our keys
aren't working right we found some keys
and we were trying to get in and he was
like yeah no problem
and just let us in for our objective so
having that list of names
and knowing when to use them and
gathering them is very very important
yep
all right establishing a pattern of life
all right so why do we want to establish
a pattern of life this is the first part
of the engagement when you're setting
foot on well one we want to validate
that the oh cent we have collected is
accurate
99 of the time it will be it'll be
accurate but we just want to validate
right we want to validate the maps we
want to validate the terrain we want to
validate the shift changes we want to
validate everything
you know we just want to make sure that
we have the most accurate
and up-to-date intelligence as possible
right and while we're doing that we're
also going to start developing our
initial attack path
and
you know well
we see this door there doesn't seem a
lot of cameras here just got maybe some
good egress points
and we'll start developing and having
that thought process
we also want to get familiar with
surrounding areas in real life
when is the other businesses surrounding
their when are there hours of operation
right when do they have people coming
when they go
uh the last thing you want to do is be
caught by an employee of another company
while trying to breach
your actual
contracted target
right um so the best way to do that is
just get familiar with the areas
find out where employees like to go to
eat all right
um this
you know where's the restaurants where's
the gas stations where's the police
station uh surrounding areas like
where's the nearest residential area
you really just really want to start
working all that around
because and visual representation is the
best so
when we go on site we print off a bunch
of maps and we start jotting notes down
on the maps right
um
for example when we're starting to do
shift changes when we drive by a parking
lot in the beginning of the day uh we
usually jot down two or three cars that
stand out to us hey a lime green jeep
um and there's a corvette parked over
here that's a lot of cars kind of stand
out a little bit right uh there's a
lifted truck over here and we'll drive
by
periodically and try to find out when
those cars are no longer there
um
right so what does that do well that
lets you know when employees are coming
and going
um
right we also want to go in after hours
and watch the the security guards work
um when do they do their rounds to do
the rounds on it on a very
you know
by the book mentality like every 20
minutes i'm gonna walk around this
building every half an hour i'm gonna
walk around this building do they walk
around the building or do they have uh
the pole that they tapped to the magnets
to signify that they were there
right it's very important to
establish how the security is is being
done do they even have 24-hour security
do they even do patrols these are all
questions you should know before you
even attempt to breach
um another crucial
um
important thing to find out when we're
establishing a pattern of life is where
do the employees hang out where is the
smoke area how do the
employees get from the parking lot to
uh the place of employment how do they
leave the place of employment to go back
to the cars right do they have to go in
through funneling through a desk uh
through a reception area
right to get in or can they use multiple
doors
um when they leave do they do they go
hang out in the smoking area catch up
and then leave
these are very very important things to
know
uh you also want to conduct training
terrain analysis right
um
while we were on site uh we identified a
fence line um but what we didn't realize
that earlier before we arrived that
someone drove a car through the fence
and there was a giant hole in the fence
uh and next to the client that separated
the client site from a mobile home park
so we could park in the mobile home
area walk through this gaping hole in
the fence and skirt up the fence line
um and observe in relative darkness and
obscurity
um
the other thing you want to look at is
get
look at their cctvs right if you can
take a picture of their cctvs
and ma map on a point where they're
located uh if you should have
um
you know your map that you printed out
we keep talking about the map um you can
look up the model number if you get a
good picture of it find their angle of
view
um and actually draw that out on the map
so you could actually see and visualize
um
the
angle that the cameras record uh another
thing is lights right we all know that
sometimes lighting is an issue in the
parking lot so you could actually map
out where the lighting
ends and where it starts so you could
stay on the edge of that lighting
um
and one of the most important parts here
is communication and notes and actually
drawing it on a map
you know have one partner if you're
driving around and collecting uh have
one person that's you know dedicated
taking consistent notes
uh you can never have too much
information
um and you know by taking consistent
notes you will have a full picture
and also to uh to add to that for the
note taking make sure you take notes and
then you start populating it somewhere
like in the word doc or whatever uh
preparing for your report because
putting it till the last moment thinking
that you're gonna remember it all it's
not gonna happen like that so make sure
you take notes and then you save it
somewhere it would be ready to go to
your clients report
correct
um tools for establishing pattern lab uh
pattern of life i've said it once said
i'll probably say it a billion times one
of the best tools is printing off a map
uh this is an example of a map pouch
that i carry actually i think it's the
exact map pouch i carry um where i can
actually print off the map slide it in
and annotate the map as we go to fill it
in um
another important piece is a dlsr camera
with decent zoom and the ability to take
good shots and poor lighting that allows
you to have that standoff
from your target while still being able
to get those details zoom in on those
doors
um zoom in on those
uh cctvs right zoom in on those rfid
badges and sometimes when you take
pictures of those entrances
you can see stuff for example
we had a clear shot to one of these
doors but we realized that the door on
the other side of the door was an alarm
panel
we realized that by taking a long
distance the lsr shot with good lens so
we knew right then and there that hey
it's alarmed this is the alarm panel and
if we watch and record the first person
in maybe we could get the alarm code uh
so that it doesn't actually go off um
and this is very important you should
never bring your breach kit until it's
time to breach so you don't bring your
full breach kit at this point um
one it's cumbersome too i mean you kind
of look suspicious if you have a
backpack full of underdoor tools and you
know we can data intercept tools and
you know lock picks and
et cetera et cetera so at this point in
time you do not want to have your full
kit with you
good next slide
awesome
uh analysis and planning this is the
most important phase
uh to us right um so with this one we
always remember the five ps prior
planning prevents poor performance
right um
you should at this point in time you
should you should have enough
information to sit down
and have multiple ingress points plotted
and planned
right you should have multiple breach
points identified
you should know where all the doors are
the flow of the people the shift changes
the security patterns for the security
patrols if they have any um so this is
really a good time to sit down and have
these breach points identified right um
you should also have a breach time uh an
established time
frame for each breach right
for us if you roll up onto a door you
should
already know hey when we get to the
store it should take me no more than 90
seconds to get in here it takes me more
than 90 seconds i think we need to roll
onto another door right whatever your
time frame is you should you should
know it and stick to it um and identify
that out right through your intelligence
and and your recon that you should do
um
you should have exit strategies uh for
how to get out of the building if
you guys are going to get separated once
you're inside if you have multiple
you know objectives but uh you should
always have a good clear
exit strategy and you should know where
you're going to rendezvous with your
partner because you will get separated
and you should have we will be here no
later than at this location
um
that's that's very important for us um a
communication plan with your partner
your project management and the client
pro point of contact is crucial um it's
not uncommon for people to have earbuds
in their ears 24 7 365 nowadays so i
just have
earpods in your ear one ear so you could
hear have the other one put away and you
can swap the batteries one in while it's
charging and you can have that and be on
the phone with your partner
you don't have to say anything
but just having an open-minded
communication is important
we like to have a bug out word it's a
word that you will not normally use in a
course of conversation
and that allows your partner if they
hear it um to be okay
i gotta i gotta peel out of here and go
to rendezvous point or if you have one
of your partners is looking as a lookout
and the other person is down doing the
preach um if they say this word it
allows the person on the ground to know
hey stop what i'm doing and let's peel
right
also
equipment checks uh learning a new piece
of equipment should not be done when
you're trying to breach a client right
finding out that your equipment is
broken
that you need to hit this objective
should not be done on
all right when you're trying to breach
the client you should have all make sure
all your equipment is functional
and know that you know how to use each
piece of equipment before you arrive on
site to conduct a breach
thanks remember uh one of them that's
not on here is always have multiple
plans
in place
for us we like to have three to four
different ingress points plotted out
because
everybody knows that the first plan
doesn't survive initial contact
also have three to four uh different
bridge points identified just in case
you need to peel or you can't breach
your initial door you have alternatives
um
always plan for the what ifs
sit down with your partner
and i think this is one of the most
important parts
go through the what ifs
right what if we get stopped by an
employee what do we do
what if we get stopped by law
enforcement how do we act what do we do
what if we get stopped by security what
if the alarm gets tripped uh recently we
were talking to other employees and
somebody asked me well rob what is
you know
the farthest what if
all right you should plan for
just under alien invasion is what i told
them uh
right um
just because you know we have these
far-fetched well what if
you know you get stopped by law
enforcement or or something along those
lines well we had a real life
environment where uh we were trying to
breach a a client and there was a very
important political event happening in
the same town at the same time
so stopping and saying what happens if
we get stopped by the secret service may
seem a little farfetched to people but
in reality uh was the possibility there
um or the fbi or something along those
lines so you know always plan for the
what ifs
um rehearsals
is also important we're not talking you
know military style like here's a stick
house there's a replica this is breach
mental rehearsals what we're talking
about
just talk through these objectives talk
through the what ifs
um
for example hey um we we we we're
hitting breach point alpha you know i
can't get in what do we do okay we roll
the breach point bravo right um and
where was breach point bravo well it's
this door right here okay how long do we
have on target right blam okay we breach
in here but now we're stopped by
security what do we do
and just talk through that until it all
becomes second nature
right um
and most importantly stick to the plan
right you have a plan for a reason we
understand plans are flexible uh you
need to have flexible plans while doing
this and you can't be super rigid but
that's why you have multiple plans
that's why you have the what-if
scenarios so you can branch down these
paths
as you hit these objectives or to get
these objectives as you're hitting these
obstacles uh but still stay on track uh
to the plan um
one of the most important things that i
think i took away was uh you know after
action we were doing a physical and we
had to sit down with the client
um
and we're sitting down there and
there we wanted to talk about the
planning and the analysis and this
they're like but we want to talk about
you know the actual breach but we're
like but we really think you should hear
about this
and once we presented them with the sure
amounts of data that we provided them
they were just 100
taken aback like
wow
we didn't realize that that our opsec
was so bad that you know
that you could get the badge from the
internet that you could just sit in the
tree line
and get this and watch this and
you know uh that you even knew the
layout of our building by watching
youtube videos they were just blown away
that by the time i got to the actual
breach
um
you know they were they were impressed
by that but they were more bothered by
the amount of data we presented with
them that was leaking from their
environment that they didn't even think
about
um so this is why i say analysis and
planning is the most important phase
yep i agree i also wanted to add um a
little bit on the equipment checks
my funny story of me
first time ever using the glasses with
the cameras on and
i nod a lot when i talk to someone
so
when i was on site i was talking to uh
this person
and uh i kept nodding and you know in
the conversation we actually had pretty
long conversation i was there a while
and
i was nodding a lot and then when we
came back and we watched the footage um
like one of the most important things
because i was actually standing behind
her and like looking at her screen to
see like
what she was using you know what type of
like email client and things like that
and
you know a lot of things were a blur
really because everything was just
shaking so really get familiar with
everything find out how everything works
because you don't want to
you know
you don't want to
try and learn that on site and then at
the end when you need to present the
video to the client
you want to make sure that it's a nice
video and everything is okay
so
correct
awesome we got two more phases to go
through
um before we get to our conclusions
oh don't forget your get out of jail
free card now we meant we call her to
get a job free card in this industry
into each other uh but in reality don't
call it get out of jail free card if you
call get caught um
call it a letter of authorization or an
authorization letter right um
people don't really like it when you
used to call it a get out of jail free
card especially law enforcement officers
i just wanted to stick that to it
breach
now you could bring your gear right
part of your gear is the authorization
letter letter of authorization
um know your plan
stick to it
right stick to the time frames that you
have set up
there you put them there for a reason
um trust your gut know when to get out
right uh it's very important uh we have
the sixth sense around us not
means a lot of but everybody so if you
just have a feeling
time to bug out right you've done it a
couple times
trust your gut go back watch
and go from there
lastly remember your car keys
i say that because i didn't and
after trying to breach building and
having to go back in
and and reassess i realized i left my
car keys and our uh
rental truck and had to break into the
truck at two o'clock in the morning
after not a successful attempt uh first
attempt after preaching the building and
the car alarm was going off and drawing
mass amounts of attention to us so uh i
put that in there always remember the
car keys
not a good idea to break it to a car
and also for the authorization letter
make sure that you print out a separate
a lot of copies of that and
make sure that you have them somewhere
on you where it's
easily reachable
not only by you but also for example for
like the law enforcement officer that
you know exactly where it's at in case
if
you know
the operation goes south and you would
be stopped
um so make sure that you have
a lot of them are out there and also
when it comes to the authorization
letter make sure that
your client really knows what's
happening when is going to be happening
and make sure that they are uh on the
phone so if something is
not going the way that it's supposed to
be that they are available and they can
really like they escalate the whole
situation it is
important
so
talk to your client talk to your project
manager make sure all of the what-ifs
are discussed not only with your partner
but also with all of the decision makers
and everyone who is involved in the
engagement
right
correct
last phase this is the one that often
gets glamorized in the movies and tv
shows
site exploitation
to us it's
okay it's the last thing
uh we hit you're already inside the
building
hit your objectives
get out the longer you stay in there the
longer your uh the greater your chances
of being detected the greater chance of
things to go wrong so hit your
objectives
get out don't linger and stick to the
plan
if you do those things it'll be great
get in get out
all right
yep stick to the plan always
always right
and now
our conclusions
right good oceans
does equal higher success rate right if
you just go up there and yolo it
you're not going to be able
you may work one time two times but as
your clients
uh increasing difficulty your success
rate's gonna plummet right
make sure that you have proper
documentation
not just for you
uh but most importantly it's for the
report remember you're not doing this
engagement just for the pure joy and
rush of it you're doing it to help
better your client and the more
information you give them in the report
the better they're going to be
communication is a must every step of
the way
right make sure that your client knows
hey we're about to attempt to breach
right so stay
stay awake have your phone on maybe not
stay awake but have your phone on be
ready for a phone call something goes
away i like your project manager hey
we're about to go on the breach stay on
right um
multiple scenarios always plan for the
what ifs i cannot underscore this enough
just having that mental exercise one
helps prayer you prepare you for those
what if scenarios but also helps ease
your mind
all right always remember your get out
of jail free card for your letter of
authorization
always check your gear
always have proper attire
right you don't want to be wading
through a swamp at two o'clock in the
morning
and you know
nice slacks and and dress shoes
uh
always
rehearse before you do anything right
we're talking about a mental rehearsal
here not a physical one stick to the
plan
stick to your time frame
know when to disengage trust your gut
and don't be leroy jenkins
um for us
of the engagement is intel gathering
pattern life
establishing a pattern of life and
analysis and planning only ten percent
of the engagement is breach and site
exploitation
right so let that sink in ninety percent
is is the work that goes in prior to so
the stuff not shown in hollywood and
then 10 of the work is the stuff
hollywood shows you
again
don't be leroy jenkins
absolutely um and also
another thing to add when it comes to
proper attire that goes not only to
like the clothes that you wear for you
know uh physical engagement and let's
say there is
no possibility to like run into any
people so you'll find but also if you
have to kind of like think on your feet
or if you have a certain pretext make
sure that your appearance matches the
pretext and you
you know fit in this image of who you
pretend to be because uh it matters we
all look at people in our initial
reaction you know when we're trying to
kind of like put everything uh together
when something is slightly off
our brain automatically rings all sorts
of signals notifying us like okay
something is
not right so make sure when you prepare
for um
physical engagement especially if it has
uh some sort of like a social
engineering component in it when you
know that you're gonna have to interact
with people multiple people uh make sure
that you dress
appropriately uh caveat there if you're
a sports fan do not wear your sports
attire
there because that will will
you know
place you out of there right for example
uh we we went on site and there were
cleveland browns fans and i'm a 49ers
fan for football
um and
the day before we showed up sight the
49ers just beat the browns horribly and
it was a dead give
more
and do we have
any questions
and i think
thank you guys for uh
letting us talk to you guys later right
yes thank you
you