but um so without any further ado
uh i'll turn it over to david ruddock
with his presentation on prepare for a
data breach
thanks um thank you very much uh
so just uh my topic today is yeah how to
prepare your smaller midsize business
um for a data breach on a budget uh the
reason
for this is uh you know six years ago
when i started coming to osert
i didn't know as much i'm still a
beginner but i know a lot more than i
did then and it made me realize there's
a lot of other people out there who
they don't know what you don't know and
it often ends up getting you into
trouble so our goal is to uh
to try and um maybe give some
foundations
for those people who are sort of
starting out in the industry and uh
because the number of incidents is
increasing um
as mentioned i really liking interaction
and engagement um
and because i can't see you uh if you
would enter your questions into the q a
box as we go i'll do my best
um to answer them just a little bit
about me
uh i started my company at 22 years of
age 2000
in 2000 so 20 years ago
consulted with and worked for a large
range of local national international
companies
um certified professional by the
australian computer society certified
information systems security
professional member of the australian
information security association
and more recently a gx certified
forensic examiner and forensic
analyst a little bit about my company
about two years ago we were engaged by
cfc underwriting which are one of the
big
cyber insurers uh to provide they're
insured
with incident response digital forensics
data cataloging services
uh and to
their they're insured so i was reading
the q a at the same time so
what this has done for us is really
provide us with first-hand knowledge
of the type of things that lead to an
incident
and also the typical challenges that
occur
uh you know when an incident occurs um
and for campbell yeah i'm more than
happy to provide a copy of the slides
i'll leave my contact details at the end
and i'll also give them to the oscert
guys
um the screen i've got on at the moment
i i kind of like because my little
company
uh which up until recently had about
eight staff we've now got about 20
uh is pictured here with the likes of uh
crowdstrike kpmg and symantec and i
think that's kind of um
a big uh call of fame for us as a tiny
little gold coast business
so just to set the scene let's look at a
typical incident response scenario
uh first of all business notices that
they're having some it issues
and they give the help desk a call
the it team begins investigation and the
team discovers that servers or a user's
mailbox has been compromised
the team continues to investigate and
discovers they've had a cyber incident
so the business calls the insurance
broker the insurance broker
lodges the cyber insurance claim and the
insurer then
responds and inside assigns an incident
response team
and this is typically where things go
really well
or really badly the ir team typically
will come in and find
very little logging is enabled and uh
funnily enough murray's presentation
before me was talking about you know
getting more telemetry out of the
logging and making sure you're logging
the right things
what we often find just trying to do
incident response is
uh either the logs have been blown away
or they were set at the very bare
minimum
um and there's really not a lot to go on
we also find the threat actor has been
in the system for a considerable amount
of time
and in performing their own
investigations the it team have kind of
left their own footprints
all over the digital crime scene and so
now we've got a problem where
we've got to try and discern between
what is actually
the threat actor activity and what is
you know regular activity
post-incident this leads to a series of
unfortunate events
uh the forensic investigators are
therefore unable to confidently
determine
whether the threat actor gained access
to any sensitive personally identifiable
information
and or personal health information and
then the business
uh has to notify under the uh notifiable
data breach legislation which is not a
position we really want every business
to end up in it's
it's uh it can be avoidable and today
i'm going to try and take you through a
couple of things to try and help you
position yourself so that if and when
you have an incident
you'll be in the best position to to
walk through that investigation and
hopefully come out the other side with a
fairly confident result
so what can you do first of all and it
seems so simple but create a cyber
incident response plan
and i i was talking to uh the uh the
guys from oscer
and also the acsc uh on the various
slack channels prior to this
there's a lot of good resources online
to give you a
boilerplate starting position uh
victorian government has one the
queensland government has one
and actually a lot of cyber insurers
will offer templates so
there's really no excuse not to have
something
bottom line keep it simple list out who
your primary contacts are
vendors and their responsibilities make
sure everyone understands it
and then run a tabletop exercise at
least once a year so that people
actually have to go through a scenario
where they're experiencing an incident
and i know ben demarco and steph lurz
went through a really good one the other
day
um there's people you can engage to do
those and it'll just
kind of like a fire drill get you into
the habit of of
knowing the actions you should take if
you have an incident
so there's two scenarios that i really
want you to focus on and
the number one type of or not two top
incidents that we
see that result in a cyber claim
uh and as a result of data breach the
first one which i'm sure everyone here
has talked about is business email
compromise and this can happen through
phishing
um through password stuffing uh or a
whole range of different ways
legacy protocols but it is probably the
most prevalent
cyber incident that we investigate and
the second one is ransomware
and even though we deal with a lot of it
providers when we go in to do our um
incident response and they're all
focused
on the rants and we're coming through
via email these days ransomware comes in
because people left the door open uh and
i know there was another presentation
earlier where they were talking about
you know the change in the landscape as
a byproduct of covert 19
and and that's really true some of the
big incidents we worked on
post everyone going into iso were
because businesses had to move really
quickly
to enable their workforce to go remote
and
they would stand up remote desktop
servers and not securely lock them down
and as a byproduct you know users have
basic passwords and and they get popped
with your response plan as well we i
cannot stress enough about how important
it is that
before you start your investigation or
if when you get into your investigation
you realize it's a cyber incident
try if possible to make a backup of the
system that you're looking at before you
go too far
if you do this then at least you've got
as close as near to
the incident as possible for the
investigators to look at um
quite often you know we will find that
the whole system has been encrypted
but because there's a backup taken every
hour and it was taken just before the
system was encrypted we've got something
to go back to
um this takes time and there are ways to
do it uh which other presenters have
talked about
and there's a lot of really good
resources out there and i'm happy to
share a couple of others if anyone um
pings me on it the other thing is too
and and this is probably um teaching
some people here how to suck eggs but
don't rush to pull the plug the old
mentality and we still face it with it
support companies managed service
providers is
this rush to oh my god we've had an
incident pull the plug on those systems
before
it spreads too far and what we've you
know what we all learn
over time is that if you do that you may
actually
first of all you can't investigate
things properly um
because you've stopped it midway and
second of all there may be something in
memory that you've just lost
and yes there are forensic artifacts
that store parts of things in
in files uh parts of memory and files
but
if that system's still online um we've
got a better chance of pulling out the
full memory and
investigating it
and uh also saying going on with what
murray was talking about dial up your
logging
um you know one of the biggest things we
found in office 365
is that um
yes thomas i would say yank the nick
instead in some instances
um but yeah coming back to the the
slides dial up your logging uh
ensure the unified audit log is enabled
for office 365. the amount of times
we've gone in for an investigation
for an office 365 business email
compromise
and the unified audit log isn't enabled
and without that
you've lost half of the information to
be able to perform an investigation you
cannot tell
how the threat actor gained access
to the mailbox what actions they
performed what was the method of access
which a lot of reports we review
of other incidents they don't record
that and it's really important the oaic
really wants to know if you if it's been
accessed by imap because you've left a
legacy protocol open
that's really important because it could
mean that the mailbox was potentially
synchronized
there's a really good tool called log md
that will do in its free version an
audit of your windows service security
and logging baselines and it'll baseline
it against
nist and the asc essential 8 and all the
rest of it and give you an evaluation of
what you should turn on
you can go further with it and we'll
create a some actually good forensic
information as well but the free version
is great and it will just give you a
really good starting point to work out
what do you need to change in your
environment
and then the final thing on that with
your logging is is make sure that the
at least the windows security log is
sitting at 2gig
uh in previous versions of windows the
windows logging the bigger it was the
more memory it consumed
that hasn't been the case for a very
long time it's
um you know people still believe that's
the case but turn it up as big as you
can because as much logging data that is
available in the system itself is really
really useful
uh for for a forensic purpose
obviously if the threat actor has gone
in and reset the logs that doesn't help
most threat actors will go in and delete
the volume
shadow copies but if there is something
there at least we've
you know we can deep dive into that
the other thing is as well because they
will reset the logs
um is implement some form of log
collection and it doesn't have to be a
full-blown
seam um i would uh
i would i would hazard that even
something as simple as elasticsearch
can be leveraged as a really good
low-cost log collection solution
keep it on a separate system and aim for
12 months worth of
log collection for your firewall servers
and other key devices
and again there's some really good
resources which i'm happy to share which
you know will teach you what
specifically to monitor for like the
certain event types that you really want
to look for the
log on to system log off from system um
administrative privileges used
changes to active directory it's all
there in the in
the public domain it's just that most
people
aren't using it and if you want to go
all out and implement a full-on scene
that's great but again we're talking
about doing this on a budget and you can
do this for
for next to nics
and always secure the end user um
this is such a silly thing to be having
to be say but
um you know we log into some websites
and they don't allow us still in this
day and age to have passwords longer
than eight characters
um we encourage not to have regular
password resets i know there's
a constant flip flap on this one but
uh you know a friend of mine when she
started working for us she came from
travel
her original password was holiday one
then when it got rotated
uh it was holiday two and then it was
holiday three and so on and so forth and
if you force people to constantly change
their passwords
they're gonna get tired and they're
going to make it really simple for them
because passwords are hard
um love password managers some banks
don't love password managers
um but that's one way of really ensuring
that you are
helping your team to better their
standards
and of course multi-factor
authentication and again i've heard a
lot of presenters today talk about
you know when they were doing red
teaming exercises that had multi-factor
authentication being implemented or
configured properly they probably
wouldn't have gotten as far as they did
we get a lot of pushback from insureds
when we we go into an incident
particularly when it's an office 365
mailbox compromise and we say to them
okay well you need to go
and immediately enable multi-factor
authentication and
quite often the scenario we get back is
well we're actually in the middle of an
evaluation of that
and there's a pilot group of people who
are testing it out but
we're getting a lot of pushback from
from our end users because they don't
want an
application installed on their phone and
it
it's such a painless experience now to
install
think something like the microsoft
authenticator
it's i was talking to one of the big
insurers the other night and they said
they have statistics that prove
if multi-factor authentication was
enabled on office 365 mailboxes
the number of claims would go
significantly down
um it's it's such a brainless thing but
still we're doing investigations where
very large prominent organizations
don't have multi-factor authentication
on and even if it's just they're
high-risk users
people who are you know dealing with
finances or
keeping copies of of highly sensitive
information um
and yet they still don't turn it on
because the user feels that it's it's
not frictionless
um and of course empower the users like
the the it department has typically
and i come from the i.t world has
typically been the department of no
and so users have been berated
every time they sort of say hey is this
this and this is that
by the it team and we want to get into a
a world where we actually encourage
people to come to you and say hey
i just got this before i click on it can
you check that it's okay
one of the things we did with a lot of
our clients is um
we actually started sending them
chocolate bars and
everyone likes chocolate and what we
would say to them is if you sent us a
phishing email
that legitimately had was a fishing
email we would send you a chocolate bar
and a chocolate bar cost two bucks
um but as a byproduct we we didn't have
to go into
you know helping them whether it was a
virus or you know male box compromise
and all this is
five ten years ago and it significantly
reduced the number of incidents that
we're having because people were
motivated to um to get the chocolate bar
and uh
really good question paul um i haven't
done any research uh the question is
have you done any research on password
length tolerability
on the part of end users from a cost to
crack perspective 12 characters is way
too low nowadays
yeah look it is um the we always try and
encourage people to use a passphrase um
obviously a new
unique one for every single system um
but if multi-factor is also tied to it
and you don't have things like
legacy protocols enabled so pop3 imap
and everything has to go through a
modern authenticator then
uh the the
the chance of a 12 digit pass getting
popped is a lot less
i guess the problem is a lot of people
have been allowed to get away with four
and six-digit passwords and and we just
want to keep raising the bar up we don't
want to set the bar
so high no one can attain it we want to
start
just chipping away at that bar and and
making it more difficult for the the
cyber criminals
so uh as i said as well secure remote
access um
everything either needs to be behind an
ssl vpn
uh we repeatedly
end up in a debate with it providers
who when we get into involved in it do
you guys have remote desktop
open oh yes we do but we've got it
running on a non-standard port and as
some of the people in the room are aware
i'm sure there's so many open source
tools out there that you can use that
will identify
what every port is and finding remote
desk at
desktop these days is trivial plus you
can go to showdown and it's probably
listed anyway
so just using you know the old security
through obscurity
is only fooling yourself
talking about the legacy protocols uh
inside office 365 there is an option
which can be done globally on a per
mailbox basis
pop an imap which for those that don't
know is an old way of accessing your
emails pop3 was sort of a bucket
situation
imap is a little bit more intelligent in
that it was designed for
synchronization between multiple devices
before we ended up with what we have now
but they're enabled by default and these
things don't support
multi-factor authentication and quite
often when we do an investigation into
an office 365 mailbox compromise
the threat actor will move to using imap
to access the mailbox
and as i said at the start um
that means that the threat actor has
potentially synchronized part or all of
the mailbox
and as it stands currently office 365
does not log
what part of the mailbox they actually
downloaded so you've sort of got this
throw your hands in the air situation
where all we know is they could have
potentially synchronized it we just
don't know
how many uh which of the native windows
vpn options would you recommend
to be honest um i always go for
something that's ssl vpn based which is
the open source open vpn a lot of
uh commercial firewalls support
that as a basic um
sometimes you have to license it some of
the more high-end firewalls have their
own version
but you know if you go buy i won't
mention brands but most of them out
there will have support for ssl vpn
and uh yeah i'd head in that direction
what is the replacement for imap if you
if you haven't moved to office 365
or something like google g suite um you
need to
and the replacement is generally it's a
web-based synchronization so it's https
uh and you know office 365
and google g suite use that natively if
you're using office 365
with um outlook then it will uh it will
use https um as opposed to imap
but yeah they really should be very few
reasons to continue using imap unless
you've got some legacy
uh contact relation management system um
then i'd be turning it off globally
the other thing too um put your vendors
on notice
uh we're finding a lot when we go into
engagements that
you know the a certain vendor of a
particular
uh provi a particular client uh has
essentially been
responsible for putting the client at
risk
uh you know we deal with a lot of uh
third-party software vendors who
because and not no offense to everyone
out there but
some software guys think that they know
everything about
it and networking and technology and so
they'll encourage
clients to enable rdp and they won't do
it with ip white listing or any sort of
protections
and the client doesn't know any better
they just assume that these people are
professional um
and and they'll do what the provider
says
the other thing is too you know what
happens if
uh how are they protecting you from a
cyber attack
you know specifically we had an incident
with uh
with a piece of software that uh was
modified
to change the banking details of a of
you know someone that they were going to
pay and when we went to do the
investigation we went to the vendor and
said hey
um does your application log homemade
changes to that part of the system
and their answer was well only if it's
turned on and we sat there and thought
that that should be something that's on
by default
and then we get to the other end of the
scale where we also have vendors who
tell us no we don't we don't have some
sort of transactional or audit log in
our
and our software and you as the consumer
need to really
put pressure on the vendors and say well
you know what are you doing to help us
because at some stage something will
happen
another one we dealt with uh whenever
you walk into the rsl clubs or a lot of
those clubs and they scan your driver's
license or
you know how is that stored and up until
recently it wasn't stored in a very
safe and secure way in fact one
engagement we had
we asked them and they said oh it's
stored on the client server and we went
to this client and said well
do you know what it's on and they said
no it was just installed for us
and what had happened is the the vendor
had gone and just mapped a share on it
on a
on a drive and essentially was storing
these files um
yeah on the system now if that system
got
hacked it just it had copies of people's
driver's license all over it and there
was just sort of a
you know pointing the finger in each way
the other thing too is like does that
software if it stores sensitive pii or
phi enforce
mfa and a lot of the accounting software
is doing that now which
is great um but there's still a lot of
applications out there that
don't and and this needs to be a bare
minimum and the final thing with the
vendors on that aspect is
do they get an independent penetration
test
performed on their softwares
particularly if it's web
facing uh there's been a lot of
incidents with schools and and
a few other groups at the moment and the
question is you know
are they actually testing the code or is
it just something that
you know they've put together and
they're hoping for the best and
a lot of vendors are really really shy
to answer this question
another thing we see a lot as well is uh
you know the managed service provider a
managed security service provider
do they enforce multi-factor
authentication
when their staff access your system via
remote support
so things like teamviewer screen connect
splashtop
all those sort of things we have seen a
huge number
of incidents where the managed service
provider
got hacked and then as a byproduct the
threat actor was able to leverage their
remote support tools to then deploy
ransomware across all of their clients
so instead of just getting one client
they've got 10 or 20 or 100.
um which then is a really interesting
question so
you know does the managed service
provider have a cyber insurance policy
part one
part two if all of their clients were
hit with ransomware as a byproduct of
them being compromised
would their policy hold up and i'd
hazard that most of them won't have a
big enough policy
to do that question is
is it's worthwhile keeping the remote
worker off the network use of splashtop
teamviewer etc would isolate a remote
workers machine
which may be compromised um
yeah i mean if you have a quarantine
vlan or or something you can put the
machine in so that
you know remote work can be done to it
and it is
unable to touch the network that that
would definitely be preferable
um it seems silly that we have to see
that say this but
everyone needs to make sure they've got
an automated off-site
backup and we had an incident the other
day really
big business um they obviously got hit
with ransomware
and we said them okay well what's your
backup strategy i will we replicate to
an offsite location
okay well replication isn't backup
if you replicate the ransomware system
you have a backup of a ransomware system
you need something that looks at and
it's not a one
size fits all either you know certain
parts of data for a business
are more important than another certain
things you could probably
lose and the business can continue to
operate whereas there's other things
the business desperately needs and if it
lost them it's in a
really bad position and either has to
pay the ransom or
or worse uh and a business needs to sit
down and assess that
with their it person provider and work
out what is the right
strategy for them and make sure it
actually goes off site and it's
automatic
and it should allow you as well to
roll back to previous versions too and
that as i said earlier that's become
really useful for us in investigations
having the ability to roll back
to try and determine sometimes just how
long is the threat active being in the
system if we don't have the
you know the the live systems to
investigate because they've been
encrypted at the disk
disk level not the file level the whole
vm the virtual machine has been
encrypted and there's just nothing for
us to look at
um and of course again i shouldn't have
to say this but
if you're not testing your backups
they're useless it's kind of like
not having not doing a fire drill you
know people won't know what to do when
it happens
um
yeah when you do the pull the nick the
initial analysis
take time and things are not obvious
until you go in and look you create
fatigue if you cry wolf every time you
see something funny of course you do
um but there's going to be a small step
where you do a little bit of an
investigation
and i would there's going to be certain
incidents and this is something you have
to work into your incident response plan
and whatever consultant you're working
at where
you know some pull the network cable out
is acceptable um other things might be
an a temporary isolation into an
isolation network so it can continue to
be investigated without
impact to the operation other things
might be just leave it until someone can
look at it
but uh you know it is different ways to
approach every situation it's not
as not a one-size-fits-all
and the last one is get cyber insurance
the number of businesses i talk to
because we do a lot of speaking
engagements for insurance brokers
and these businesses they're still not
getting cyber insurance and i'll be
honest when i first heard of cyber
insurance i thought it was a bit of a
crock
um i couldn't understand why we needed
it but now that i've
done a couple hundred investigations in
the last couple of years
uh i can see where it pays for things
and
you know i've i've seen some very very
expensive ransoms
i've seen some very expensive uh
notification campaigns you know the cost
of investigating the cost of
legal the cost of uh having to notify
the
potentially affected individuals the the
pr campaigns around it
and and we did a job for a business
recently
uh which was through a broken network
they didn't have insurance
and you know it's not a fun conversation
to have
have a chat with someone saying well
look you're gonna have to put your hand
in your pocket
and pull out a significant amount of
money that you're never gonna see again
and cyber insurance isn't that expensive
in the grand scheme of things and
there's some
awesome uh vendors that you essentially
get assigned to
uh when you have an incident it's it's
more than a typical insurance policy
any other questions
you mentioned yearly tabletop scenarios
do you have any advice for really small
teams can you effectively create it for
yourself
um so what we're actually looking at
internally because we do some training
with our consultants is group exercises
so for those really small businesses
particularly when they're in the
financial sector at the moment they're
under um
scrutiny after the asic um thing
recently
is maybe bringing a group of businesses
together who
can't afford or don't have the numbers
to to do an individual a
table top exercise or training exercise
and have them do it all together
it at least still lets you play it out
and understand and you probably get some
insight from working from other
businesses because
you're collaborating
cool excellent well look thank you very
much david
um we're going to convene for a little
uh for about 15 minutes have an
afternoon tea break and then we'll be
back at 2 45 for the afternoon keynote
speakers
thanks very much david thank you