so next up we've got james and scott
from advante so this is the last
presentation that we've got for today
so just a bit of background on both of
them james has been working on computers
next
end user computing nexus for 15 years
focusing mainly on securing the user
workspace
and shane's been around since computers
were the size of washing machines
uh he's been part of three startups
since 1995 25 year
plus career in different areas of cyber
security so very well credentialed as
well
so the topic that they have is
protecting against powershell attacks
and malicious insiders so i think we're
going to cut
straight to them thanks welcome
people to the avanti presentation today
at good old oscertz today we're going to
be speaking about implementing
essential acsc controls and protecting
against powershell attacks and malicious
insiders
my name's shane westcott technical
evangelist with ivanti
and i'm joined by my good buddy james
lane you want to introduce yourself
jimmy and say hello happy to be here
james lay
a pre-sales security engineer with
ivanti
looking forward to today's session both
of us have got lots of experience with
these products so it's going to be
something that you'll get the benefit of
that experience and it should be a good
little session for you to learn a bit
and see some cool technology
so to enter the competition to win our
sphero
rvr programmable robot please email
gabrielle kingston at evante.com
with the subject win with evante
security
yeah so today we're going to look at
three common threats
that we speak to customers about a lot
we're going to have a look
at blocking controlling managing macros
and the control over powershell
because they often come hand in hand
and also looking at malicious insiders
within your organization how we can help
to manage some of those threats
now finally give a little bit of summary
about what we've talked about and
some of the next steps that you can take
right all sounds good all sounds good
i'll let you go through the three common
threats that we have
yeah so the three thefts we're going to
focus on today is
ransomware seems to be getting a huge
amount of attention
uh this year has been 150 increase
in ransomware attacks in the first half
of this year i came out as part of the
oaic data breach notification report
that came out in july
there's been a number of very high
profile attacks
um on organizations that have been hit
multiple times
this year we won't mention any names i
think we probably all know who they are
um but data exfiltration has been the
number one extortion i'd say
of 2020. i saw another ransomware issue
this week where
um just a little bit of data was
released
on the dark web to say look we do have
it we are willing to release it
time to cough up um but also powershell
misuse powershell sometimes comes in
those ransomware
fileless type attacks but also how you
manage powershell within
your organization and manage the misuse
of it
the malicious use of it accidental use
and then finally threats do not always
come from outside your organization
and i've had lots of interesting
conversations with customers over the
years talking about
the malicious insider and how you manage
it and
in lots of ways it's very difficult but
in some very basic ways
you can do uh the best you can to
protect yourself
it's interesting on that one that when i
did a bit of research before i did some
presentations recently
uh the number one step to
control malicious insiders we're going
to talk about that and show some
uh technology around that and also this
one to add in with powershell misuse
is that the way our
industry is working at the moment in it
you know you can't really get away with
totally blocking powershell you've got
to use it for something it's done for so
many things these days the automation
and all sorts of stuff that you've got
to
work out a way of successfully managing
it to make sure it gets used for what it
should be useful
but they're uh you're minimizing the
threats as well so safety
absolutely safety in it on there yeah
so i just want to go through this just
to put a bit of context around
where we are and why we're talking about
these particular things if you'll be
familiar i would imagine with the asd
slash acsc
uh security measures that they recommend
we have a back to basics type approach
we look after the boring stuff the
pouring basics
things like app control patching you
know restricting admin privileges those
sorts of things we do all of those
we don't sort of look after backup and
multi-factor
the interesting thing is that the ones
that we deal with mainly
are the tricky ones so app control a lot
of people find that control app
whitelisting very difficult
to implement we have simple ways of
doing that things
like restricting admin privileges can be
quite tricky our technology makes that
simple
patching itself of apps and os pretty
simple stuff at the end of the day but
getting it automated so it takes less
load
unless manpower is something that we
walk with
quite often and then where we're talking
here today is really about configuring
macro settings because that's a
particular area where
you know blanket security people say oh
just block it
but you know it's virtually impossible
to just block it with
most organizations these days because
they will have an area there where
somebody's going to need to run those
sort of macro things user app hardening
also another thing that
needs to be done sometimes can be tricky
but again you've got to look at how you
can do that what sort of flexibility
you've got
that's all about context right we're
going to talk today a little bit about
context you hear the
context a few times
indeed you will okay so let's jump in
and have a little look at
uh macros and powershell and a link and
how we can help you
manage both of these so what i first
wanted to start with was a typical
attack chain something we hear a lot
about
so you can obviously have phishing
campaigns and
training users and they that's that's
all very very important
basic controls but then we start to look
at
how do we potentially control those
macros
what they do what they launch and what
powershell scripts can be running by
whom
when we look at that implementing things
like application control
to control the executable content in the
scripts that are running
configuring your macro settings so any
specified macros or signed macros
whatever it might be you're allowed to
run
and ensuring you're patching the
platform
and again all three of these items come
from
those acsc essential 8 controls nothing
smart nothing clever
basic security when we look at well how
do we
stop or control uh execution of
payloads or existing production code
application control there's the
microsoft maturity level
three recommended blocks again
users should never be running those
tools admins might need to run them for
specified uses but generally shouldn't
be running
when we're looking at that execution and
privilege escalation
privilege management controlling what
applications are running
and patching code vulnerabilities all
out of the acsc essential eight
and you guessed it blocking the
ransomware of the final payload
if we're only allowing approved it
software
then we're going to control against that
final delivery so
no edi here no threat hunting no
artificial intelligence just
basic cyber hygiene just a boring basics
mate but it's getting that foundational
steps
in place it's always you know you hear
about people you know
real to building a house you've got to
have good foundations doesn't matter how
pretty this second floor windows are if
you don't have good foundations the
thing will fall down
same with security it's multi-layer
everyone knows security is about layers
so you've got to get that boring basic
layer sorted out at the bottom and then
that will cover
most of your issues especially around
this subject we're talking now
an interesting conversation with a
customer last week who said
one of the real values he got from
application control
was the reduction in noise on his edr
platform
yes he can now see
uh a lot less information a lot less
volume to look at exactly what's going
on
uh away from application control and
basic
uh blocking of non uh corporate or it
approved applications
yeah because you're going to need those
platforms anyway anyone you know is a
layered security defense and a large
organization is going to be using ndr
what we're saying here is use the right
tool for the job and the right tool for
this job is those boring basics that
come out and
we have you know one of the best ways of
replicating those out and giving you
lots of
contextuality and flexibility in how you
allow things
and how you block things
okay so shifting a little bit across to
one of the topics of today's
conversation around powershell
so the acsc have a
enterprise guide for securing powershell
and a maturity model that goes along
with it and powershell
in itself is it's not an insecure tool
it's just very widely used and very
powerful
and when a threat actor
knows that an organization is almost
definitely using a tool or an
application
then they know there's going to be
vulnerabilities or there's going to be
misconfiguration
and it's a great thing to attack that's
kind of you know shame we talk a lot
about
patching uh third-party applications
they know
there's probably the top five that are
going to be in your organization and
probably unpatched
yep and that and that's very common we
talk to people about patching all the
time we always
come across people who say yeah we think
we're doing a pretty good job and
they are on the windows side but a lot
of those vulnerabilities that do get it
attack vectors
through them are all about the third
party products because people
they take a lot more work and people are
less likely to do them at the end of the
day
yes if you're if you're heavily using
powershell within your environment
i'm sure many of you are you've got to
look at how
you can secure and manage this in the
most
efficient way to not restrict your admin
users and
throttle innovation within the business
but do it in a safe way
so these are the three levels the acsc
uh
document within this enterprise guide so
level zero is just a default use of
powershell
now the level they recommend is level
one which is not typical for the
acsc they typically recommend all
organizations should be level three
but the documentation says level one
here and that just shows
that you should be whitelisting what's
running and you should be looking at
verifying scripts by the publisher
auditing everything that you're doing
and making sure you're using the latest
version of powershell
for a level two you should be locking
powershell down to specific users so
your specific users can do it
and making sure that you're hardening
some of the winram and other features
within powershell and finally for level
three
you should be constraining the use of
powershell
and looking at how privileges are used
with powershell and who's using
powershell
and locking it down that way also so
what i want to touch on now is just drop
a little bit
into how advanti can help you to
adhere to elements of these maturity
levels
we're definitely not going to do
everything within this but give you some
of the controls that can help you
further mature and get to where you want
to be
so level one uh it's all about blocking
and ensuring
that only approved powershell scripts
are running
so with our product out of the box
powershell is blocked
and what that means is any powershell
scripts that
are introduced in the environment by the
user that could be
accidental it could be malicious or it
could be targeted
be that via a usb key download them
writing the script
coming from a drive by download whatever
it might be
that's all going to be blocked by
default so that very very strong
position up front
when we start to look at that level two
we can start looking at how we whiteness
the scripts
uh based on specific publishers so
if you are signing your powershell
scripts which you can
definitely do and a lot of enterprise
organizations are doing these days
so we can start to help you to only
approve
signed powershell scripts to run and you
can see on the screen there a couple of
different ways
that we can start to allow these scripts
to run so you can see in the bottom
center of the screen
we're approving a script by a file rule
and we're adding in there a vendor check
on the file in a metadata to look for my
company llc or whatever your company
name is
and you can see a checkbox there for
verify certificate a runtime
so we're checking the metadata from the
file against the certificate that it's
signed with
to make sure that file is what we think
it is
and again we can control these
powershell scripts by file rules
have you got a folder full of powershell
scripts are they all signed
do you want to hash the scripts
to make sure it's the the specified
script running from wherever it's
running
within your environment and again
whitelisting anything is about
balancing you know the the manageability
and security of it you can have the most
secure
uh approach or hashed but it's not very
flexible
or you can have it far more dynamic yeah
i think one of the things we've both
seen over the years we're working with
this
sort of product and these sort of issues
is that you need the
granular contextuality that allows you
to
manage things in such a way that you're
going to secure
the operation to only be done by those
people from those locations that need
it and when they need it whereas most of
the time if people don't have that
contextuality or that granularity
their options aren't lock it all down or
open it all up and
in some cases they're just not going to
suit and then it falls into too hard
basket and they leave that vulnerability
open
yep definitely and you can see it at the
top of the screen
talking about that you know as i say we
can we can do things lots and lots of
different ways
here's the option to restrict admins so
by default we want we might want to
restrict admins
to say you can't just go around running
powershell but in this scenario in this
context you can we're going to touch on
that on the next side
we start looking at level three and we
start looking at
privilege and controlling using that
dynamic policy and the context we can
say for example
if the user is in the sou and that's the
admins oh you
and the computer is in this ou that's
the admin computer's ou
and the device is windows 10 and the
build is greater than 1909
and the day of the week is a weekday
between nine and five
and the user groups admins then they can
go for it
you know and you can use any ants and
oars blends of this scripted rules
who what where why when so total control
and it doesn't just need to be if they
fit that
jobs on go we can then say well for
everything you run
you can see in the bottom center there
we've got powershell.exe and ps1 files
you need to give me an audited reason
for what you're doing
and that gives people just do i really
want to do this what am i going to write
in that box
and everything they do is then logged
what the machine was who the user was
what the day was what the script was
what the hash of the file was and the
reason they gave
and the thing that also i've seen
customers do is
is this can allow people to have a wider
use of
powershell but when most people run it
it's actually de-elevated so it runs
powershell
in a standard sort of context it's only
elevated to full-blown permissions when
it absolutely needs to by the certain
people that need to do that
and that lets you use a very useful tool
which is powershell but
allows you to lessen the likelihood that
if it is
overtaken and that somebody is taking
control of that it's going to have those
those admin privileges that let it go
and do basically everything
yeah totally totally okay so
with all of that the the bit that
everyone's interested in
let's have a look at some live software
a bit of live software
yeah so we'll jump across now and show
you some of these concepts
uh running in one of our labs
okay so let's have a look at
demonstration now so as we saw in the
presentation
i've currently got powershell script
checking
enabled by default and this is set in
our manage tab
under advanced settings so we can see
powershell validation
is enabled so by default what we're
going to see
is all powershell scripts are blocked so
let's have a look
at our target device
and i've got a powerful script
that i've created for this presentation
and all this does is pop some message
say hey you're running could be malware
so if we try and run this script what we
see
is this script file has been blocked
we're presented with a customizable
message and the user is protected
now what that means is out of the box
where a user
runs a document as a macro
that uses a powershell exploit
then what we see is document opens
and the piece of malware or the
powershell that begins the attack
is immediately blocked so that's
fantastic
but there's obviously some powershell
that we do want running so let's have a
look at exceptions and how we
safely allow powershell right to run
under certain contexts
and what we're going to do is under this
security group i've created
for only group users in a specific
active directory group
i'm going to add a rule i'm going to add
a signature item
and i'm going to browse to that script
and there it is so when i open it
we get the signature hash of the file
so i'm going to add that to my policy
and i'm just going to save and deploy
this
to the test endpoint okay
with the policy now live if we try and
run
any powershell script such as the ones
associated with this macro
the powershell script is blocked if we
try and run this powershell script that
we've whitelisted by
hash then the script runs
and there's our this could be malware
okay so let's go a step further now
and let's look at how we can tailor this
down to a specific
context so we'll shift back to
configuration
okay so we've shown controlling
powershell through an active directory
group rule
we've also got what we call custom rules
so a custom rule looks at the context
that something's happening
so here i've created an ozer powershell
context rule if we look into this
it's checking to see is the device
windows 10
is it a remote desktop connection and is
the time
before 12 35 and this could be used to
make sure that scripts are only run
within business hours for example
but there's a massive choice of
conditions
that we can use uh to build out these
rules
and you can even use scripted rules as
well something more dynamic
so what we'll do we'll add our
powershell rule
in here so we'll just read this and make
sure
we've got the right rule and the right
hash so we just run a rescan there
okay and we'll deploy that policy out
and connect back to the endpoint
okay so if we come back to the endpoint
now what we're going to see
if we try and run the script it's going
to continue to run because we are on
windows 10
this is a remote desktop connection and
it is before
12 35 as we can see in the time in the
bottom right hand corner
so if i run this we can see our
powershell runs
okay now let's wait till the clock hits
12 35
and see what happens
okay so it's now 12 36 and my context
has changed
so if we try and run this powershell
script now it should be blocked
and there we go the script is now
blocked because the context has changed
so let's look at one more example let's
see how we can control
how macros allow powershell to run
so i've got two
documents here with macros in the first
one as we've seen a few times now
launches a mal ph.ps1 file from the temp
directory
and the other one tries to launch this
oddsser powershell script
and both get blocked
okay what we're going to do now is build
what we call a process rule
so this affects what is able to be
spawned as a child process
from any parent in this instance
we're going to create an offset
powershell rule so i'm going to copy
in our script again
there it is what we're going to do is
we're going to say
when word
is the parent process we can define
an exact file path we can do a file name
we can do
wildcards we can use the metadata of the
file
we can check the certificate runtime to
make sure that what
is running is microsoft word in this
instance
we just use the path
so when word.xd launches
it is allowed to run this hashed
powershell script i'm going to save that
and deploy it to the endpoint
and see what happens okay we're back on
the endpoint
first of all we'll run this
windward file and we can see the
powershell script is blocked
if we now run the ozer word document
and the macro launches
we can see our powershell is running and
our powershell script's been allowed to
run
so again here we're showing how
we can allow specific powershell scripts
based on a range of context who the user
is what the device is what the time is
what the configuration of the device is
so it's not
on or off we can be very very granular
in controlling powershell
so the last thing i wanted to show on
this one was part of our visibility and
dashboarding platform
and it's really i guess shows off a
little bit the the volume of information
that we gather so this is looking at
some of the powershell data within our
environment that we're capturing
so we have some real-time dashboarding
visibility capabilities
that can be used to give you insights
into what's happening your environment
and this powershell dashboard is showing
us you know
where when who
uh and what powershell has been run we
can see the top
users who've been executing powershell
in the last x days
and powershell blocks in the last hour
and everything on here can have
thresholds applied to them so we could
say if we see
you know 20 blocks of powershell on a
device within an hour
and go and raise a security incident uh
that someone can go and investigate and
look at why is that happening
is there a malicious insider who's
trying to do something
is there an external attack looking at
that machine
trying to execute something what's
happening so again it's all about
visibility
and lots of customers i speak to they
love all this information to suck into
their seam and go
and cross-correlate with other sources
of information
and get more value out of yeah and i
think it's important to have visibility
on that you know quite often our
products not just our products but all
products will have
details of auditing events sucked away
somewhere
but making it into a very visible
dashboard that's easy for people to
change them up a bit
even you know schedule an email of that
once a week to people so they're going
to have a look at the details from the
previous week
that just helps with accountability
management you can make sure that you
keep me on track of those things and
keep you on top of them
thanks for that james uh switch over now
to talk a little bit about
malicious insiders mitigating the risks
so interestingly enough
i hadn't researched this hugely with
the exact words that the guys at the
acsc come out with but when i did it was
quite interesting to find
that when you look at malicious insiders
who steal data if that's the risk you're
trying to mitigate their first
number one thing you need to do is
implement control removable storage
media and connected devices to mitigate
data exfiltration so that's before
you go and do all of the essential eight
typically controlling devices and
storage media doesn't roll up in the
essential aid if you look at things
like the sands top 20 comes in around
about number 13.
i think the cis in the u.s has it around
about number eight so it's up there with
those very important requirements to get
a good security platform happening
but down here with the ocsc if we're
talking about malicious insiders they
say it's the number one thing
if you think about that it is probably
the easiest way for malicious insiders
to get control of data
so there's a link there to the
document that i'm referring to there you
can go and have a look at that if you
like
this has been one of the things i've
looked at which is quite interesting
from a usb point of view you know people
think that our
data exhortation and data leak
prevention is all about usb
well in some ways it is only because
that
part of the market has expanded
dramatically but there are other devices
that are much more important than just
usbs very cool though there's a few uh
very cool little hackers tools that
i like to see this one is just looks
like a cable
so it's usb ninja cable 75 bucks you
loan it to someone
they kick it on it's got a wireless
remote and
very much the uh the james bond style
there's a little ring there when you
push the button that activates the
wireless
and you can use that to inject some code
when it's passed around so it looks like
a charge cable but actually a good
attack service
and then this one i thought was pretty
cool jimmy this is the
omg cable which has a built-in
wi-fi and web server
so basically you download the app you
then connect into your cable
and you then code on your phone which
talks directly to the cable and then
goes and injects things
into the endpoint that thinks that
they're just there charging up
their little phone it's awesome and it's
it kind of it all relates back to that
um
social engineering aspect of
i think i've heard it referred to as
juice jacking
everyone is so paranoid about their
phone running out battery and their
inability to go on social media
that they will use whatever cable they
find lying around they don't care as
long as it gets them online
gets them jacked in they're going to use
it and
yeah if you're if you're like that for
actor going around looking at people to
target and this is
still a great way to do it and then that
gives
a lot of ability to do a lot of things
so at avani we
are lucky to have a product called avani
device control
as part of our portfolio and this is
used by a lot of the
uh as i call them super secret squirrel
organizations around the world to
protect
their devices and protect their data
from exploration centrally managed
larger site we have in this country is
somewhere around 300 000 devices quite
large
it will centralize well and be able to
manage a very large
number of users role-based access
control for different functions in there
it's a quite flexible architecture
pretty good product at the end of the
day and will do
more than just your basic sort of usb
control
i often talk with customers about this
and i'll just say look if you just want
to block usbs you're probably talking to
the wrong people because
this is the rolls royce of device
control it's not
a i want to block usbs or not block usbs
there's a million ways you can do that
and people probably own
two or three products already that
include that sort of functionality
this is designed for those people who
have specific use cases around
things like data copy restrictions so
that you can
block certain types of documents being
copied onto usbs
enforce encryption those sorts of things
take shadow copies of everything that
goes out the door
even and up to it including doing shadow
copies of every device that's printed we
had a customer the other week we were
talking to
who has now got all of their agents
working
from home like a lot of organizations
one of the things i wanted to track was
i wanted to track how we're going to
make sure we know what they're printing
out on their home printer in their house
in this case yeah and if that's hooked
up to their
the corporate pc that they're using hey
we want to make sure that if they're
printing stuff
out of our applications we want to find
out what they're printing
so we can centralize that and i showed a
bit of a demo of doing that i set it up
myself
in my house and a little printer next to
me so i did a couple of prints and then
i showed them the data
that we can pick up from that the header
and the file who printed it where they
printed name of the file what was it
containing
and even you can take a copy of the
actual print
output to the printer and you can then
store that centrally
and someone could go in and say okay
exactly what is written
in this file that they printed out so
very very greatly control there but it's
something that
uh is something we've been doing for
quite a long years
and one of our big selling products down
it's uh
solves a lot of problems for people i've
got a customer who i was dealing with
who
has wanted it due to the granularity of
information it captured
so that they could use it as a post
incident tool to identify
how does data get out where did it get
out from what happened they didn't even
want to control
devices they just wanted to have the
visibility yeah into how data was
flowing
yeah and auditing wise is very very good
at that as well you could just leave it
in audit mode
and you'll get very granular things i
mean i run that on my laptop
24 7 on my little work laptop and i
remember
the first time i set it up i uh
tried to do some printing about an hour
later i'd set it up did a bit of testing
with usbs yeah it's working really good
awesome went to do some printing
couldn't print and
it took me a while to work out ah
actually i forgot to allow
my endpoint to do printing anymore
because it can stop
any printer or you could actually
individual printing you could say from
this particular endpoint or this
particular user group you can only print
that printer over there you can't print
to the other ones
and if you look at where we find
ourselves with covid and with so many
users working from home now
you know people are more isolated people
are working in what could be a strange
environment for many
and you know is there that temptation
there to just copy some data off
you know might need this my next job
might be of interest to have this
um things that they probably wouldn't do
if they were still working in the office
but it feels like there's no one
watching you here at home it feels like
a very different space yeah you could uh
you could imagine that people could
think they could get away with that and
then uh
becomes a bit of a danger to the
organizations
the ministers comes in all from
different forms right it's not just
people stealing data and deleting things
it can be more
more surreptitious than that yes
okay one of the other fun bits we love
is looking at
live software and i've got just a photo
here of my good mate uh
nigel from sloppy horror the skeleton
there he is uh he's in that photo i'm
not sure who the old guy is but anyways
that's you there could be a future photo
of you um
maybe it's me anyway let's dive into
some live software and go and have a
look
at how device control actually works
now i've got a little picture here which
i'll show you is of the keys i'm going
to use for this demonstration just usb
keys the blue one
is allowed to run pretty much whole as
bolus doesn't really matter
because of the brand of key it is the
red one has some special settings on it
and i'll show you those and then the
other ones are just two random keys that
i picked up
so let me first show you my blue key
and we're just getting in there there we
go and what you can see with the blue
key is it'll come up
and i can double click just like any
normal usb key and away i go
i can use that particular key
let's grab my random key that i found
lying around somewhere
and you can see that comes up as usb key
but
it's totally inaccessible i can't do
anything with that key
because it's not specifically called out
it's just a random count picked up
somewhere
let's have a look at our red key which
is the one that's got all the smart
stuff on it
so eventually a couple of seconds it'll
come up with
[Music]
password support the password in and
once i put the password in because this
encrypted key is now going to be
unlocked
i can go in and have a look it's
currently empty
now i've also got some rules on this key
if i try and drag and drop a word
document onto this key you'll see it
comes up says hey you need admin
privileges
i could put those in but even though
[Music]
i put those in it's still not going to
work okay so i've basically said
you're not allowed to copy word
documents onto this key you can drag and
drop this
acrobat one here and what that will do
is that would just work
now i've got another document here also
an acrobat document when i drop this one
on i get into the same loop as the
administrative permissions because if i
show you that file
it has the word secret in it okay and
i've set up a policy here for dlp
to say you are not allowed to
any folder has a word secret in it so a
lot of our customers
will do things like this for dlp let me
show you a little bit of the device
explorer and show you how that was
configured
under removable storage devices i've got
some overriding rules up here that say
everyone's disabled
that's a low priority rule so it can be
overridden by high priority rules like
these ones here
and what i've said is for everyone who's
using one of these type of keys
it's got to be encrypted i've got a
filter set
so you can only do acrobat and i've got
a dlp filter for acrobat
if i show you that just quickly up here
you'll see that my dlp filter says
contains
secret so if there's the word secret in
an acrobat document
it's going to get blocked and then this
one here this special key this is
actually my blue key saying it's got
free read and writing doesn't have to be
encrypted
it's a couple of cool things there i've
also in this example put on our
shadowing option for our printers
if we got our log explorer i can show
you a couple of things
denied users so you can see this is an
iso i was trying to access i'd forgotten
to turn on access for dvds
you can look at things like everything
today and you've got a stack of things
there you've got live streaming you've
got printing that's been done you've got
all sorts of things
turning on and off if i go to shadow
user per month and do a query on that
you'll see that shows me my file that i
printed earlier today
or when this when this log file was so
it tells the computer
the name the name of the file the name
of the printer
all sorts of things you can even get a
copy of that file so you can go and have
a look
and see exactly what it is that the user
was trying to print off
so let's move on now and just summarize
what we've been talking about
and i'll let uh james take us through a
couple of these and we'll just talk
about
sort of next steps and things yes i
suppose just to
map back to those three key threats that
we talked about at the start of the
session
first one was around ransomware and
powershell and macros
so again measure yourself against the
latest acsc
essential 8 and powershell maturity
levels and see where are you today
you know where do you want to be and
what
is going to help you move along that
journey some of it might be process
some of it might be technology what do
you need to
to move along and look at your
your malicious inside threat
threatenable you know
is has that changed has coverts occurred
has that changed due to other factors
is that something that you just never
really analyzed before or analyzed
potentially
in the realms of data and finally
we would love you to come to the avanti
booth
and have a chat with us about some of
our experiences
in all of the things that we've talked
about today
yeah that's one of the things that we
love doing is listening to customers
tell us about their challenges and
we can relate some of the stories from
the customers that we've been working
with as well
uh from myself and james between the two
of us we've probably got
25 years or so experience with
some of these security products between
us so it's been
a long road of talking to lots and lots
of customers and getting lots and lots
of ideas around use cases
one of the great things about having
products that have been in the market
for a long time helping customers
is you do get a lot of great features
that customers suggest
that get into the product so when we go
and talk to most customers
we're pretty confident that we're going
to have some ability to
configure it to meet the context that
they're actually after so it's been a
great pleasure to be able to share with
you guys
uh james well done on the demo and stuff
and some
some good points you've made in there we
will spend some time on the booth and
see if we get some nice people coming
and talking to us
yeah thank you very much for your time
and i'm sure everyone
will have a great conference
okay thanks very much for the team at
ivanti for
uh providing us with that and spending
some time to answer the questions
um that have come out of it so we're
about to wrap up for the day we've got
another keynote at 2 45 today
which you guys can attend but otherwise
have a good afternoon and we'll see you
all again tomorrow
cheers