hey guys welcome back i hope you enjoyed
the uh
sessions this morning our next speaker
is michael marriott so
michael is a senior strategy and
research analyst at digital shadows
so he's written numerous articles and
papers and is regularly published as
well
and he's going to be talking about
account tagovers targeting australia
so i think michael has just arrived into
the room and we'll switch over to him
momentarily
but if you guys have any questions just
post them up on the um the q a
thanks very much all right hello
everybody thanks for joining
i know it's it's getting towards the end
of the sessions now
penultimate final push so i appreciate
you taking the time
out of what's probably your work day to
come and come and listen here
um i i'm going to try and keep this
as educational as possible um
i know a lot of you haven't joined to
hear a vendor talk
so um there will be a small element of
digital shadows in its
solution searchlight but i'm going to
try and keep it uh looking at some
cybercrime trends that we've seen and
some
some free advice at the end and some
resources that you can take away because
i think that's all was a nice thing to
have so
we've got about 30 minutes uh i'm gonna
first outline why people care
about account takeover that probably
seems like an
obvious point uh but there's a bit of
framing that i think it needs to start
with
um we'll then move on to what i think's
the the sexy stuff
uh talking about what we've seen in the
criminal underground
um and some of the trends that we've
seen there and then we'll finish on some
tools to combat
credential exposure and this reuse of
passwords that we see as rampant
both from a free perspective and also
what we're seeing in terms of
how we can help clients solve some of
the issues that are associated with all
of this
this noise that comes from these
criminal forums
so i think just starting off at a really
really high level um we all
have been talking about the new normal
of cobid and whatnot and
we know that we've got a lot of remote
workers we know we've got a
expanding attack surface we know now
that
we've talked before about the the castle
walls and the perimeter
we've got loads of stuff that protects
that perimeter
but whilst we were talking maybe four
years ago about how the
the perimeter doesn't really exist
anymore and that was quite a novel idea
not really such a novel idea anymore
especially with everything that's
that's happened recently now
particularly with
brands and organizations that are quite
public facing
they're really understanding that you
can't delineate
how you look online with the type of
security that we're
trying to approach within the network as
well
so i've just flashed up some things that
we commonly see
whether that's misconfigured devices the
use of shadow i.t
vulnerabilities on all of these growing
end points
that you have we're also developing more
and more applications
so we're seeing a lot of leakage around
there we're seeing
developers or contractors with really
sensitive information
that's just being made publicly
available
and we know that attackers are just
absolutely loving all of this
and it's just making life so much easier
for the attackers who are
just surveilling for this information
and using it as part of their campaigns
and then you've got the impersonation of
your online as well so domains and
fishing kits and things like that i
think the one thing that always comes up
though
is the topic of this talk and that's
employee credentials um
especially now everybody's signing up
for loads of different online services
but realistically this has been
happening for a long time
um even on sites you wouldn't expect
people to be using their
their corporate email addresses um i
always remember we were pretty shocked
at the amount of corporate email
addresses we saw in when ashley madison
got breached for example
so this is something that is really
tangible
really really is something that
security teams can do something about as
well so it's a high risk
if those accounts get taken over but
it's something that you can actually go
into action and you can show some really
good metrics
in terms of the security team's
effectiveness
and this is another reason why account
took over is
just so much front of mind for a lot of
the security teams that we
talk to i one of my favorite activities
of the year is to read the verizon dbir
in this one very similar to in previous
years
the main way just the tried and tested
technique
of attackers is just the reuse of
credentials
and this is there was this is this
year's verizon tbi but i think
maybe eight years ago there was a great
quote
which was basically why use
a cruise missile when the front door is
open
so you're not having people generally
for most organizations the threat model
isn't a zero day or even a
newly released exploit for a new
vulnerability
it's just something really easy it's the
reuse of your employees credentials
that's just providing such an easy way
into the organization
and you may say well we've got to have
multi-factor authentication what are we
doing why
do we not have that um the reality is
that obviously it's a business decision
and it's somewhat more complex than that
and
even on top of that we've seen plenty of
attackers
bypassing um different second factor
authentication so
uh particularly sms based so that is
not unheard of but i'm sure many of you
listening in will be
familiar with that anyway
so given that this is such a
large area of interest we we conducted a
good amount of research
probably a month ago this is pretty
fresh um we've got
a repository of about at the time it was
15 billion
when we kicked off the research in june
this year
that has since grown by about a billion
and a half
so that gives you an idea of the the
rate at which credentials are being
exposed online so there's a lot there
and we thought well why don't we dig
into it and see
not all credentials are created equal so
what are the trends that we're seeing
what's most attractive
for threat actors and what can we
understand
about that that perhaps informs our own
defenses
so i thought i would take a snapshot of
that that was
australia focused um because it just
makes it a bit more interesting
and there is a surprising but not really
surprising there is
a significant amount of activity
targeting australia hence
the title of this talk i guess so this
one was just from a couple of weeks ago
um from a an actor on
a well-known russian cyber criminal
forum
called rot so this is this actor
he's logged on good evening fellas he
specializes in
australian stuff and particularly he's
got a poncho
for uh financial services companies but
doesn't doesn't stop there
there's plenty more um fish in the sea
that he's
seeking to sell access to and this is
in this case i think it was a citrix
logon
um he was or this individual was looking
to basically sell a username and
password that would provide access to
a whole ton of really sensitive
information and this is something that
we've been seeing
an awful lot of not just in australia
but
across the world so i took just the
australian examples
for this presentation and some that
we've seen in the last
few months in terms of the actors that
are selling access
um perhaps we have seen a big uptick
in the last few months um and perhaps
that's related to expanding attack
services perhaps it's just a trend
we've seen things like particularly the
selling of
rdp access or domain admin these are the
ones that are the
the sexiest the the best level of
credential that attackers have to offer
they go for the
the big bucks so while you can pick up
any
you can probably pick up a credential
for a dollar
on most dark web marketplaces you'll
find
that predictably these domain admin
accesses they go from
between two thousand and six thousand
dollars apiece
so these individuals they don't want to
take on the risk they don't want to be
actually going and looking to monetize
um
the databases or what you can get from
the access and do
lateral movement and things they just
want a quick sell so they've got the
access somehow maybe they've exploited
some
vulnerability or used some default rdp
credentials or whatever they've got
access and they're just selling it on to
the highest bidder
so they're often doing it on auctions
that tends to be a really popular way of
driving up the value but
this is this is really becoming
something that's that's pretty popular
um it's it's something that we've seen
changes in as well so previously maybe a
year ago
somebody would come on and say i've got
access to
such a such bank called such university
and then they would just have a bidding
war and it turns out that um
that people are monitoring for this so
they have to be a bit more cryptic about
it so
there's often a bit of a jigsaw puzzle
that you have to put together so they
give a
they give an alexa ranking number of
employees and they try and mask it like
that
but but still be as appealing as
possible so we've got our own close
sources team that go and
try and ascertain whether those belong
to our clients or anything like that
but these are these are absolutely the
some of the most valuable
that attackers seek and sell online we
did
as part of the research and you'll all
be able to have a copy of this research
after the presentation as part of it we
did a broader analysis
not just in australia but across the
world in 2020
what the average price is for different
types of industry
domain admin access were so we've broken
them down there
and the the highest cost of those were
for local government
and there were quite a few listings
there i think
that's probably in line with a lot of
the uh
a lot of the ransomware targeting as
well and there's i won't go into in this
presentation but i think there's
probably a
correlation between the selling of rdp
access credentials and the ability to
execute ransomware in different
environments so
these tend to be the ones that are being
traded
online obviously there's a big chunk of
other that tended to be
a mix of higher education and
a bit of retail as well from my
recollection
so just to give you an idea um when we
think of credentials we often think
about those low-level ones or the ones
that are just freely available floating
around but
there is a bit of a trove that is some
pretty high value stuff
and then the second high value thing um
now this was
this is a little bit further back this
is about a year ago but it was
something that has always stuck with me
um
because of its nature and i'll go into
it but
we our close sources team engaged with
a russian-speaking cyber criminal and
this one is across a
a messaging platform it was a jabber
conversation
so we were we were discussing with this
one individual
and they were explicitly looking for
um certain email address inbox access
so thereafter and you can see possibly
on the screen if you've got it
helpful accounts payable accounts
receivables
payables and receivables and
i think this now seems like a really
obvious point to me but
when i used to think of corporate emails
i thought of gym in accounting
or um just somebody else in
a different department than but it was
it was their inbox
and this really woke me up to the fact
that well actually why would it not be
these departmental
inboxes these have got way more valuable
information
if you think about the types of invoices
and
payment information that's available if
you were to have access
to these type of inboxes it would be
absolutely massive
so this this individual they
provided a list of exactly actually 100
companies that were located in both
australia
and in the uk and those companies were
generally manufacturing companies or
they were
financial services related specifically
to the manufacturing industry and those
looking at
a rental so it was an incredibly
targeted orchestrated attempt to get
these inboxes and the credentials for
them
and is even more surprising was that
we think in terms of the prices of
things going in the criminal underground
you'd think that
maybe getting a nice piece of malware or
an exploit for something would would
reach the highest cost and actually no
it was
somebody goes the effort to get
something
from an inbox with accounting
information in that's the thing that was
getting i think tens of thousands of
dollars
was was the offer for that so a huge
amount of money going around
and looking for these types of things
so this is i said this was in the back
of my mind so when we were doing this
research i really wanted to understand
well i wonder
just by pure chance of the people that
are using these online accounting tools
how many people have used these
corporate um
payments in boxes to sign up that have
subsequently been breached
so we had a little look in it turns out
there's an awful lot
that were being used in fact there were
two million
uh accounting inboxes that are exposed
online freely in circulation across the
criminal underground
and i i expected that to be a good
amount i did not expect them to be two
million
and you can see the distribution here uh
invoice invoices
partners vendors billing admin so on and
so forth
so this admittedly was based on a large
data sample
we were looking at about 15 billion
credentials here
i think still though two million
accounting inboxes
is is a number that we should definitely
be paying attention to
especially as uh about
90 of the passwords that we found within
those 15 billion
were already in plain text so
i don't need to emphasize the
significance of that that
just makes it so much easier for
attackers particularly as i'll go on to
the ones that are using these
credentials to brute force
to put into a credential stuffing tool
that then automatically goes and
looks up and looks a valid um credential
pairs
so incredibly easy for attackers 90
and even the rest of them the remaining
that are not plain text they're in a
format that
it doesn't need a a nation-state
side a nation-state adversary to to go
and actually understand
what that password is so awful lot of
passwords
awful lot of censored information and
it's a pretty low barrier to entry
we also distributed it um based on the
average number of credentials
per organization per sector so
you can see across a few of these we
have we did take a few of these out
of the data sample so particularly
telecommunications if you think about
those that have got
customers who would be using the same
email domain
as employees we tried to really focus on
the
employee um credential issue in this
circumstance so
we did remove those in this piece of
analysis
but you can still see just a lot
a lot of credentials that are being
alerted
47 603 for
a technology company on average and if
you think about
the good number of technology companies
that we sampled probably only have
5 000 employees this really gives an
idea of the scale
at which these credentials are being
exposed online
so this is something that obviously we
alert our clients to
a lot um there are a lot of credentials
flying around i said
there were a billion and a half in the
last month or so so
an awful lot out there and as i'll get
on to at the end when i show what we're
doing
we're trying to we're trying to find
ways
to help organizations triage those work
out whether it's relevant to them
and then actually go and
[Music]
validate them before they have to go
through the whole triage process so
we're trying to get to that validation
stage
earlier so that it will just save a
bunch of time
so um uh we'll get on to that
very shortly one of the the cool tidbits
actually that i always like to bring up
when i'm talking about credentials uh is
nothing on the slide but it's a nice
little
trick that i've learned for sort of
heads of security
that i've chatted to um that are trying
to demonstrate what they're doing
particularly to the the c level and
executives who don't perhaps understand
digital risk protection or intelligence
and what's going on in cyber criminal
underground
and so they're trying to make cases that
potentially
when executives travel they end up
exposing themselves
and how can they go and manage that risk
and get awareness of that
so whatever tool you may be using
whatever visibility
you have into credentials one cool thing
to do is when
executives get back from a business trip
to russia or china
um what a nice thing to do is actually
go and type in
their email address and show the
timeline of when that was exposed
because i feel that when you start to
bring that to the executive level and
you show that actually
tangibly for them here's what's happened
and here's where you're exposed from
that
vip level that really starts to resonate
with those individuals and sure shows
what security the value that they're
adding
not they're not just securing things and
devices
they're actually making a business
impact that should really have a
powerful message
um so just a little tip there that i
find
helps a lot of people and just from a
personal
career-wise
so there are a few things that these uh
these then get used for
um so if you think about all of these
credentials that are out there um
some of these can get used to
just like a straightforward reuse so if
you get these
early enough when they're at their
highest value when they've just been
breached
um then actually you can go and
potentially reuse those
for another account that tends to have
diminishing returns when those get
further and further traded across
different locations
and they get they start to get used
quite creatively
so perhaps many of you will be
familiar with credential stuffing tools
you can see one
uh screenshot that i've thrown up there
and there are a few
that are available so for many many
years
if any of you were familiar with
credential stuffing the name
century mba would would ring true to you
that was the
the absolute uh cool kid on the block
that everybody
would be talking about and getting
different configuration files for and
that's what people would be doing
so for those not familiar you
essentially have this piece of software
you throw in a load of previously
breached credential pairs that you know
has come from another site you then
point it at another website
and it just circulates through them
until it finds matches
century mba was really successful
because it was able
to on occasion bypass capture controls
so there was a huge trade in central mba
configuration files to make sure you're
going to
specific sites so that was so popular
for many many years
until this year um it's it's actually
we've got a new kid on the block
and that kid is open bullet
although central mba still is a popular
tool
it's actually we looked at the mentions
i may or may not have a slide on it
i don't um but open bullet was actually
far more popular
than center mba now so just an easier to
use interface
um that really appealed to people so
just want to be aware of if you do get
asked internally perhaps
you've got to write a report on
credential stuffing because that's been
in the news
send your nba absolutely still won but
don't forget about this
this rising star open bullet
that's one angle the other angle which i
think is
is possibly even cooler is
um one that's emerged in the last we
spotted it in
eight i think april 2018 was when this
market first emerged
it came out of the uh a very famous
russian
speaking cyber criminal forum called
exploit.n
this was was birthed from that community
and advertised heavily on there in early
just as with any tech company they went
through a beta phase
where they tested it with trusted
customers but essentially what it is
is what you would previously have to do
when you're committing fraud
and the maybe fraud folks uh
that are on the line now so i'm sorry if
i'm butchering
uh how you do your job but and
there's the concept of fingerprinting so
um you
can get a good idea if somebody's
legitimate by things like
their cookies browser information ip
address
um and other little nuggets like that so
what a threat actor has to do
is if they want to use an account which
perhaps the four team are monitoring for
suspicious activity
they have to then go and buy a ton of
other stuff so they need to go and buy
um different proxies they need to rotate
those they need to work out
what browser information they need to
work out the um the zip code or the
postcode of the individual whose account
they're stealing so on
and it's just a massive pain because
it's just a lot of work and
if there's nothing in there it tends to
be a bit of a turn off
for the the actual attackers that are
trying to monetize that
so genesis market essentially disrupted
this whole thing
and they said well instead of you
getting all these disparate pieces from
different locations
why not you just you can just rent an
identity for a day
so they provide this website it's got a
chrome extension
it turns out russian site criminals love
chrome extensions
and you just rent so you can rent
sebastian for a day
and they've got automatic injects that
they've got from
from botnets and different captures
online
and they all combine to form this
identity of real world
stolen stuff so instead of you getting
an account then having to work out where
they live and then getting proxies and
whatnot all of a sudden you have all of
that
you just rent them you have their screen
size you have their cookie information
you are there
you are impersonating them they already
have all of that so
this is a scary i said cool i shouldn't
say cool um
but it's a scary trend that has really
taken off
in the last two years so it is firmly
out of beta
stage now uh there's tens of thousands
of identities on
genesis market um and it continues to
grow
today they've got
even got other markets that uh copycat
markets
so tenebrus and underworld market
and the world market used to go by a
different name that i have forgotten
but those are now the three biggest and
you can see genesis markets still
absolutely with 65
of of the discussions that we we
analyzed online
focused on genesis market and that
certainly rings true with
its credibility and it's standing within
the cyber criminal community
so yeah that's just one thing um not not
everybody is familiar with so i wanted
to share that piece of information
about that that new trend in bypassing
fingerprinting controls
okay so um we've got about 10 minutes
left
so i i thought it was important to
finish on on actually what you can do
about this
now it's always lovely to chat to
australian security professionals
because
one of your own is of course troy hunt
who has done an absolutely terrific
job of bringing exposed credentials
um and breaches really to the forefront
of people's minds and making sure
that they have a way to actually
understand whether they've been involved
in these breaches
so often when i can flash up this slide
at the end there's a surprising amount
of people that don't actually
know about have i been pwned
i imagine this is slightly different for
this audience
but nonetheless if you don't already
know about how i've been poned and
you're not using that
within your business already would
really encourage you to go and check
that out it's something that
is freely available you can do it in a
personal level
so you can type in your own email
address in there and see where where
you've been breached and where they've
been reported to have i've been toned
but you can also do it on a your own
domain level so if you can
if you can basically prove ownership of
the domain in the second screenshot
there
you can actually pull back those results
and
get an idea of which of your corporate
email addresses have been involved in
the breaches
so it's not perfect but you for example
that you don't get the
password so it's quite hard to
understand whether it's relevant but
it's an absolutely terrific source for
security teams that perhaps
can't invest in getting a new threat
intelligence tool or additional risk
protection solution
this is a really really good starting
point particularly if you think about
you know those additional tips for
demonstrating
your your what you're doing in terms of
the business to the executives
so yes troy hun he is incredible
somebody chats in
and that is absolutely correct so check
that out if you don't know that already
would
very much encourage you to do so
i reference a lot of the material in
here
not all of it is available within this
report which goes into a lot of detail
about not only things like open bullet
but
also other tools we also looked into
um specifically dark web marketplaces so
looking at the different trades and
different goods
what's going on there essentially trying
to demystify
um the the dark web community
because i think it does need a bit of
demystifying there's
plenty of risk on the non-dark web
um that perhaps we can talk about
afterwards
and then i thought i'd just finish by
talking about what what digital shadows
and what searchlight are doing
within this and i just flash up this
again to remind people that
most of these 16 or 15 or 16 billion
credentials are actually in plain text
so this is a huge number and potentially
a little bit overwhelming for
organizations
but it also provides this it's enormous
opportunity
because if they're already in this
format and there's so many of them and
we need to reduce that to more of a
sensible number the security doesn't
necessarily have time to be going
through all of these we can actually go
and validate those
so as well as just alerting on every new
credential that we see
we realize that's just too much for
organizations and most security teams
so especially as if once one credential
is exposed
and that gets reused in reality
once you've reset a credential that risk
is already mitigated
and the rest of it's just noise so what
we
essentially completely changed our model
so we just alert now
on a credential basis so once you you've
done that credential pair
and that's been triaged and responded to
that's done
and you can still access that
information but you don't need to go and
actually go and action it and critically
we've done
we've done some really cool stuff around
automated validation
so we've got three main ways of doing
that um
first you've got the credential format
so many people
many security teams in the organizations
will
have a password format that people must
adhere to
so in this one it's 15 characters
lowercase
numbers and uppercase characters if it
doesn't
meet those thresholds we can actually
automatically
reject that alert because most people
they actually care about is this gonna
actually enable an account takeover
is this legitimate access to our network
so
actually you can still access
information but in terms of what you
have to go in action it can
automatically be rejected
we can also look that up against um
things like
octa are those email addresses valid in
your current directory
so can we actually understand whether
live
that's actually something that poses a
risk to us
and finally can you actually just go and
we'd like to talk about these advanced
tools but actually
um the majority of people correlate
newly exposed credentials with a list
and
an export of their known email addresses
from their directory
so you can actually upload a csv
into our system and again if that
doesn't match
um then you can automatically invalidate
that
based on the the email address so often
these things that get exposed aren't
even valid email addresses never mind
passwords
so we're really excited about this um
it's gone really really well with our
client base
and so if you would like to
actually have a deeper understanding of
this or a demo
i can take you through it live um and
see how that manifests
actually would love for you to swing by
our
booth on level or area one
and you'll see the digital shadows logo
and there's uh myself
philip and scott who'll be there to
answer any questions and
probably we can probably do a bit of a
live demo of these credential alerts as
well
if people are interested in that
just a question on the and the general
chat are the slides for this
presentation available
absolutely um they they can be
i will work out the best method for
distributing those i understand this
presentation is being
possibly recorded and uploaded to
youtube so you could have access there
and but if you if you send me your email
address i'm also happy to
send on a copy of the slides and answer
any questions
that you may have so i think that's
that's everything that i had oh just a
few screenshots of the type of different
validation
so you can see those there so that's all
i had
um we can expand the conversation if we
so wish to how we
try and get a bit more proactive so
looking at whether we can pick
domains that are impersonating trying to
harvest credentials mobile apps
smooth social media try and catch shows
before before they target employees and
customers
so we're trying to have that proactive
stance so
if you remember back to write the
beginning slide where i show you all
those different things that are
exposed online if we remove those
i think we can do a really good job of
just making
making life harder for the attacker so i
think
i can't remember who it said it may have
been the asd
australian signals director if that's if
i've said that correctly
they had a great piece of advice which
just like let's just in
increase attacker costs let's not worry
about these advanced zero days and
espionage campaigns and apts that are
all really interesting
but if we can just get these basics done
the asd essentially is fantastic
let's get get the basics reduce the
opportunity attackers have
and just give ourselves a better shot so
um
yeah i thought i'd finish on some nice
asd essentially material because that's
uh some of the best advice out there i
think
and that's that's everything i had for
today um i have left
uh about three minutes less than i
intended to so my apologies
uh if you do have any questions really
happy to answer these on any
any topic around a counter credentials
or anything else
mfa is is indeed um
is something that is awarded as the easy
solution for everything and
uh i appreciate it's not always
as straightforward as is made out to be
um
yeah any other questions
mike thank you very much it's fantastic
all right
thanks for your time everybody i
appreciate it and uh swinbar booth you
want to continue the conversation
cheers um thanks guys the next speaker
will be mikey perry
uh and he'll be talking about some
adversary emulation
um stops a really good way to end the
day so that'll be
in a couple of minutes time we'll see
you all then