okay our next speaker starting with the
first
oscer conference in 2002 he's become a
fixture
at austin event speaking on topics
including securing mobility securing
higher education
he serves as cyber cx's director
executive director of capability
security testing and assurance prior to
this he co-founded assurance in 2005
and served as its managing director
until 2020 when assurance officially
joined cyber x so a platinum
presentation from cyber x being our own
giants
ladies and gentlemen is neil wise
oh so let's see if i can manage to share
my screen
and
right uh i assume that's visible for
everyone
um hi everyone uh uh welcome to
uh uh this this uh presentation of mine
at uh oscert
um uh what uh uh i had a nice
introduction there you know i am
uh i sort of realized when i was going
through a bunch of pictures for this
presentation just how weird my life is
that i had a huge arrangement of nerf
toys
followed immediately by me wearing a tux
for some reason so
there you go um as uh mentioned i've
been at offset a number of years we've
run a bunch of wireless tutorials took
people out were driving in a bus
um several times um they've talked about
uh higher education and
uh uh high performance computing
security risk but before all this sort
of stuff i was uh
you know a a young miss korean hacker uh
as a kid um and uh um
this is me in about 1990 and um
i was moving towards what was going to
be a career in i.t i knew
um in all likelihood but uh i got
excited about these
sort of networking things and uh went to
to to school in the uk for a year
and uh got to use some real uh more real
networks and came back
and helped um uh with my small state in
america arkansas
bringing it uh into the internet age so
um uh part of that for me was this i
i've decided to show a bunch of old
origin pictures for for me this is uh i
love skating i love
punk music and i love munich's and uh
this was my
job uh getting public television in
arkansas onto the internet in
93 94 95 and um
that eventually though led me to
australia and in
rural america there weren't really a lot
of opportunities for
you know face-to-face meeting people in
hacker communities
um so it was something that was was
challenging for me to
when i moved to australia to to even
know how to start finding people and i
looked around
in instead of unix and security
communities and professional communities
and
and uh um uh realized that uh
um you know i had a lot of different
interests with it as a business hacker
um and working in the sort of uh um
stayed
ibm world looking like this feller here
um
with my proper ibm blue shirt and uh
um uh so this is what led me to
australia is this box that's behind
me there which is an rs6000 um uh
ibm r6000sp it's a parallel systems
platform and the tape drive to my left
was another thing that led me here which
is 3494 tape drives
so i did um uh i guess
high performance what was then called
scientific computing um
application uh computing
and really what a lot of we were doing
was consolidating unix platforms in
98.99 as part of year 2000 onto these
platforms that really were meant for
better things
so if you worked on one of these types
of systems or had one
in australia at this time i probably
installed it or i trained the people who
did
so it was something i got across when i
was working at a telephone company in
the states
but so uh what i
i found was when i went looking for
hacker communities all that really was
around victoria was 2600 which was great
but
i was significantly older than everybody
who was going to 2600
and decided that they were all going to
get me
in trouble in some way and
which is funny because i now see them
all as a 30-something year old adults
but uh so i i made that went around the
traps to the different
unix related um users groups
and um the common one was ibm's which
also then became interaction
later um but uh i i did a lot of
presentations at sage instead of 98.99
on hardening aix and using um uh
aix as a secure
application platform and um that led me
to
um to to join the australian unix jesus
group which i knew i wanted to be part
of when i moved to australia
and i had similarly had uh you know a a
a
a similar understanding of oscillate as
well because of many of us who worked in
the unix space
in um uh the 90s were familiar with
um oscert's origins as i guess cert
uh in and sert and
their advice on how to you know put you
know secure banners for example like
that was a
an advisory they sent out in 1993. um
but
um this is what i sort of viewed as the
proto thing that led me to assert
um the conference and led me to author
the community
of people who attend the conference um i
was invited
uh um uh to through participating in the
australian union excuses group to
present or i submitted i can't really
remember it was 2001
to the security symposium and at the
very bottom of this which you may be
able to see
it says uh wow and i'm thinking about
now how you're looking at your screen if
you have a full screen you can see that
it says
wireless and security near wise but if
you look further up you'll see a lot of
other names of people that you might
recognize and people that you know from
the illustrator community like there's
gary gaskell
there's mike cohen um so
okay um so uh
if i'll just really just summarize this
since i'm not expecting you to read this
tiny text
but basically that on this list is the
names of a number of people that is the
first time i've i've encountered
something that met some of them
um mark ames uh gary gaskell dr michael
cohen
um but also people from us are like mark
mcpherson
and uh jamie gillespie who had recently
joined oscar at that time
um many of us got to know each other
then throughout the year of 2000
2001 and 2002 because many of us went to
do
uh in 2002 is the first time the cisp
was offered in australia and a bunch of
us all sat that together
so there's a number of us who knew each
other from this sort of period of time
and every name on here just jumps out at
me like i see
rory brown um uh bob edwards
from uh anu um but uh oh really yeah
there you go
yeah jamie i didn't know he's on here
yeah so um
uh i remember when we took the cisp
jamie and
um you stayed for a good hour after we
were done
um doing us all of a solid of riding up
complaining about how terrible the um
uh um the questions were i remember that
so but so that led us to um
that uh that led us to to oscar 2002
many of the people who um were
presenting at uh
at the the aux security symposium and
this was even the second security
symposium that og had run um uh
presented at oscar 2002 there had been
some other security events around there
was a sands event in 1999 that a lot of
us went to
so it's um yeah like i really get
nostalgic about oscar
the organization the community of people
who attend the events and
um uh the things that we all sort of get
up to so
um another thing that's probably very
hard to read but it's a list of of the
for the very first oscillate conference
in 2002 um
there was a number of speakers who i
believe were probably more invited
speakers and then there were those of us
who did the tracks and here's the first
tracks of the first track
part of wassert and of course you can't
read that because my fonts change
but this is the the first um uh track
presentations and it's you know andrew
vander stalk and rob mcmillan and me um
on these and it's it's a
and michael cohen and bill kaley and
like there's all these people who i
i know and knew like across um security
in australia that we all
had started running into each other uh
then
so here we are right here this is
everybody who presented
um and and this is also impossible to
read yeah
and um the the uh but um the
the what was something for me tier two
on this i go back here
the three of us are presenting after spf
like eugene spafford who was a keynote
um which is just amazing so
so yeah so on that i i was really
thinking about then and now
and this is something that's always fun
to do with security and um also
apparently with formatting fonts
um since defensive is a little bit scaly
there
um but nothing really changes and we all
know this
and you know that this is probably where
i was going right here so yeah george
kurtz i i
taught profound stone so um george like
they were over as our
uh partner when i was at esec um so uh
yeah it's
it's yeah so i wanted to really
like draw the same nostalgia out for you
like i started to draw a nice thought
leadery thing where i compared then
versus now and how nothing's really
changed but it's all changed now it's
just more
nuanced and subtlety yeah yeah that's
true but more than that
um i looked at this and um started
looking at pictures and i just
remembered just how much i
uh even though there were lots of daggy
things about royal pines especially
before
it was redone by rcv um it was
definitely a place i look forward to
every year you know i didn't play golf
so i didn't miss golf sundays
but yeah um hey look at this the tennis
court
you know did i i really feel that that
would have actually been made
more interesting by having an actual
live game of tennis while we were out
there eating every day
but um yeah this sort of rubbery chicken
here and uh on the tennis court this
this
became is now been at least 15-year joke
between me and um
and chris gatford um but this
friends i also see and only see
generally at all sir
like there's pat gray there's a bunch of
the the uni security folk who i i hang
out with
uh people who are of utas and ex-utaz
and uh latrobe
and then we got you know always got up
to sort of ridiculous things
but in a nice tame sort of way so we
gathered up all the balloons
and um this was the only picture i had
of a few balloons on the ceiling i
remember by the end of that night we had
a massive
wad of balloons in the ceiling because
you give a bunch of us balloons we're
gonna act like
this so but yeah so
it's just uh the the events going out
like
uh i think this is that uh uh on the
right hand side is a
a movie world um when we have uh would
have off-site
um dinners in that and um
also to like all security conferences
everybody makes their own
event and so uh uh oscert uh for me
um this this was like this is the next
level um like
if i really want to want to get my
proper bond villain on
um uh it is um uh you you gotta at least
turn up with three pretty sweet
helicopters to pick up people so um
kaspersky wins that um but
we also had a lot more fun too like as
part of our this is one of assurances
and this is a bit of a now it can be
told
so we learned a lot about the the the
building av system
like the entertainment system in in the
rooms
and um uh this even just this ip address
here this 1060
24 i know that that's on level 20 of
that building because we we worked
they did some really smart numbering and
that so we you know created a bunch of
address conflicts and just generally
played around but years
we kept escalating this and we brought
we brought mice with us we brought
keyboards with us each year to add to
uh uh trying to to look at this so the
um uh
what we actually found out was that it's
this pretty complicated little doxus
modem
uh it has two two connections and it
actually did multicast streams
um and um yeah and here it is peter the
tank
exactly so um everybody has their own
awesome and um
uh that was definitely a a spectacular
stop by my buddy chris
um for that um i always tend to hang out
with the people in the back of the rooms
who were just busy staring at their
phones on twitter
um uh uh but um yeah um i i put this
this person playing uh where's um
waldo or wally uh up here for us who was
with
uh one of the vendors just because um
this particular vendor
um we had done a bunch of reverse
engineering on the client application
and worked out that there's a
there's a function that allows you to
submit debug information to a central
server for them and it turned out it
just did it over ftp so we sniffed the
username and password
and uh we tweeted that password in this
picture at uh the vendor
um during awesome and um yeah they
didn't really respond
that's fair enough but um even just by
getting to the gold coast um there was
always that that
um you know do i stay at royal pines or
do i stay on the gold coast because if i
stay at royal pines and i'm going to get
into the gold coast i want to do stuff
and vice versa
and we would swap back every year
because it was always whatever we did
was always the wrong thing
um many years i was stayed in what i
think is a holiday inn now
um but we would look out onto the the
slingshot and
uh mini golf place out here and um it
was just like having somebody just
yeah uh scream you know every uh uh 15
minutes as they're being flung around
with that until about 11 p.m every night
it was a little unsettling
um but uh uh yeah i i really like
a lot of tacky things and neat things
about the gold coast there's just
strange events that would coincide with
with us there was the year that there
was the furry conference
um after oscert so um uh
we all wandered down there and like can
you imagine wearing one of these
fursuits out on a beach
in the sand well here they were all
doing it and they all had minders
carrying them around and that
and um yeah so i got a picture of me and
my wife and
darren paulie and his wife in the heat
exactly um
uh uh hanging out with furries so you
know they were having a good time like i
love subculture so
uh you know uh uh good for them but as
always we were walking away from there
and we got swung past mcdonald's uh
walking past it saw what is uh
blood in the water for hackers like oh
my gosh it's crash
you know so take some pictures here i
love that i can see i hope this comes
through that you can see darren
reflected in this picture um just
because uh
uh yeah so on that um you know 2018 also
um uh two um playing around with the the
machine that you use to to print um your
your badge and that
and it's like oh it it well pop the calc
okay
so um and yeah so you know we're moving
away from
from royal pines and back to the marion
because that was where that hotel was
where the first officer was
um i really like these these little
creatures who come out and join you when
you're sitting there
um having a drink um and um they would
just you know sneak out
and um but i figured they also put
drinks and lunch on your room
um or going to the airport and um uh
messing with the
the people who are picking people up as
one of my customers
who was being picked up and so i decided
i'd wait around to see if they turned up
um and i saw uh still at a at a distance
so but um yeah so i guess really what
i'm sort of getting at is that that uh
we all make our own fun
and we are who we are and we are who we
were um and so
uh we can always be our own giants
because the standing on the shoulders of
giants makes us
know how we all build on on progress and
what we do
um and uh so i threw a couple of
mixtures of some some
uh uh security you know proper security
uh uh consultant from his aphorisms here
as well as um uh uh some beliefs that i
sort of followed by as well
um and um yeah i i i really
uh hope that everyone is is uh managing
to cope well with this
and i'm really looking forward to seeing
everyone um next year
um at oscert and uh you know we're
really
you know if if we're always around and
um you know
we're we're we're always happy to catch
up and chat
those of us from this community i'm
looking forward to seeing seeing people
i really only see around the oscar
community again
coming up but thank you very much
that was absolutely wonderful stuff neil
thank you thank you thank you
the uh chat line is going wild with
people reliving the memories
posting posting old conference websites
and things like that
what a ride it's been rubbery chicken on
the tennis court balloons on the ceiling
and the kaspersky chopper neil sincere
thanks neil that was a wonderful
presentation thank you thank you very
much
isn't it great in 2020 to look back and
think about the journey both physical
and metaphorical that we've all been on
as laura points out next may will
therefore be the 20th
oz sir quick little update i can tell
you bringing you now
very much into the current day the uber
eats vouchers are now good to go
apologies for that small glitch this
afternoon our conference organizers have
been in consultation with uberx all
afternoon
if you did put your name down for the
gala dinner tonight the 20 voucher
should be operational now so
knock yourself out
and a little update on the very popular
lucas are you married
uh question unfortunately the conference
moderators went through
and scrubbed all previous questions
before my request we could get through
to them could they please leave that one
up for the rest of the conference
because at the time that we are at the
time that they scrubbed it there were
82 people that upvoted lucas you married
which is great but if you think about it
there were almost 400 people
are on at that stage um and
and so uh that means that um
you know 82 had asked and you know that
was barely 20
um and so what yeah how does paul lucas
feel thinking that maybe only 20
of people are interested in whether he's
married or not so i've just asked the
question again
go to the q a there and see if we can't
get at least at least
half of the 380 people there so i wanna
i want 190 or more
i want a majority of people now watching
to be interested in whether lucas is
married
spoiler yes he has he's got a wonderful
wife but that's not important that's not
the reason we're doing it
neil oh dear now someone's asked neil
are you married
all things getting trouble it's like oh
2020 has turned into love
island okay