hello hello
everyone hopefully everyone's well fed
and nourished
um we've got a fantastic lineup coming
up now
so we'll kick it off with uh mr
pip jenkinson so pip works
and um for buying solutions so
biosolutions is a
information security and technical
solutions firm serving both state
and federal government and also private
enterprises in australia
basis in queensland he proudly he they
are proudly
indigenous owned reinvesting into their
local community regional communities
and help to bridge that gap that we have
um in itae um personally from on
personal note
i think this is absolutely fantastic
initiative and i think it's one that we
need a lot more of so i'm very very much
looking forward to
to hear from people who's going to talk
around indigenous and
and ict well without further ado we'll
bring people to
the stage and you don't want to see me
anymore
bye okay guys
um can you can everyone hear me okay
yes um this is the first time i've done
this
uh on any mistakes i make uh i'm just
gonna try and do the very best i can
um okay so i was asked to speak on
on this subject this subject is very
dear to
my heart um um
i'll just give you an understanding of
where this where this drive comes from
because it is
it is a little bit unusual for a
non-indigenous man
to be as passionate about this as i am
um
about two years ago my dad um
passed away he was married to my mum for
56 years
um he he he um
produced three beautiful boys and we all
stayed out of jail so i think he's
done a very good job there um but for
all the wonderful things that he
he was he was also a smoker um and so
it came to no surprise that uh dad
passed away from
stage four lung cancer uh about two
years ago and one of the things that dad
drove home to the three boys
um was this concept of legacy sun
leave the world in a better place than
when you found it and
and um you know i was really passionate
about it security i've been involved in
the industry for 10 years
uh and and like you know an event where
something is cataclysmic as a parent
passing away it really
caused me to stop and just have a little
bit of a 70 check and introspection what
i was doing in the industry and why
you know a way i could be responsible of
creating a positive legacy
and i started on this journey of um it
was just before the world cup
and we started on the journey of of
being able to rattle off with
relative uninterruption um notable
first nations sporting stars right and
it was it was across the it was across
the board it wasn't just rugby union
it's kirby beale uh it was it was rugby
league it was afl was tennis and it was
you know you start
looking into it there's horse racing and
there's darts champions
then i started to extrapolate that out
and looked at music and
activism and politics and education and
war
and i could find instances of really
really cool
first nations not just at a at a
representation but at the international
standard
and then i came to look at my own
industry
um and i was really ashamed to say that
after 10 years
of working in in it security i'm both
from a vendor and a reseller
and having touched some fairly large
accounts in federal and state government
that i couldn't name
an indigenous pentester or first nation
stock manager uh laurie i know you're on
the
uh on the call i hope what i tell you
you can
identify with i couldn't name until uh
finding laurie
an indigenous seeso um let alone a cio
and i thought that
thankfully my ignorance was being lifted
and now i can
name um and identify men and women
who identify as being first nations in
us in our sector i just think there
needs to be more of them i think that
our society and our our industry
needs to work harder at producing these
role models so with that as a as a
backdrop of to why i'm talking about
what i'm
talking about then i'll uh i'll crack on
so in keeping with the theme
uh kryptonite for me is is barriers to
indigenous inclusion diversity and i.t
security
i'm going to keep it short and sharp and
punchy i'm going to i'm going to limit
it to
to nine slides so rather than listen to
gender and just read off my powerpoints
there's going to be lots of
lots of talking i'm going to try and
keep my eye on the on the chat screen so
if there is a question
please um type it in or if you allow me
to
to rattle through this i'll answer all
the questions uh
at the end of the um at the end of the
presentation so
what does one ask you you men and women
on the on the call
like do you guys think that we have a
problem i mean i certainly do but but
i've done a bit of research on this i
certainly don't have all the answers but
i've got some answers and i wanted to
ask you
um if we had a problem and a way that
i've articulated this in the past is
just to ask yourself this question
right and i'll get you to do it
virtually but
could you just stop for a moment and
think of an indigenous
all right that you can name and picture
the face
and for those of you who can't think of
an indigenous sports style i'll just
throw a name out there ash barney
or or anthony mundine or jonathan
thurston okay so now we've got
that picture of that that smiling face
in our brain
so i'm going to virtually ask you to put
both hands in the air and say right
now keep your hands in the air if you
can think of an indigenous man or woman
who you've worked with
in it who identifies as being first
nations
and i'd ask you everyone on the court to
ask themselves the same question
except now if we can think of it being
the dart
during being the bullseye ask yourself
this how many
um men and women have you bumped into in
your career or even in the last 12
months
that have identified as being first
nations in it security
and and i think and i'm happy to be
challenged on this but i think that the
answers will be
will be in single digits if not zero and
and so i think that there is a problem
um so yeah we've got a problem and the
problem comes from
um what we've just played out there
stereotypes right
pigeonholing first nations men and women
into sport is a very very dangerous
uh pigeonhole and and it starts to
um it starts to put these
beautifully talented and creative human
beings into little
pigeon holes of what they can and can't
do to be successful and sports certainly
is is one of those ones
um and it's a it's a problem that the us
is experiencing
um over there as well it's and it's
something that we need to be conscious
and cognizant of addressing
here in australia um workplace culture
lack of role models supply diversity
i'll pull these apart in a moment
financial constraints
educational gaps reliable access to
technology um
ignorance um supply chain diversity or
sorry supply chain
consolidation and fear we've touched on
um stereotypes workplace culture is a
big one and
reconciliation action plans which i'll
which i'll extrapolate on a little bit
of this call
um it is definitely a barrier to
inclusion um
uh certainly there are some some
um sectors in
in the workplace or awesome um
some categories in the workplace where
first nations men and women feel more
welcome
than than than others and
by by consulting with traditional owners
uh nukemberland
and jager and tourable where where i
live um
we can identify that some of those were
those were places of the traditional
um what would be referred to as as uh
traditional
uh indigenous occupations things like
um arts arts and uh uh tourism
and hospitality and um you know cultural
events and indeed sports so
we have to really work hard around the
culture that we're exuding to
potential employees a lack of role
models um so we're bouncing around town
saying that we want to create the first
jt invited um i bumped into a wonderful
young lady in procurement recently and
she asked him why i was so
focused on creating the first justin
timberlake of
of it and i said no no the wrong way it
was the wrong jt
um the reason why we wanted to pick that
man out in particular was that there is
a guy that represents everything that's
wholesome good about sport
culture um mob um business philanthropy
um looking after his children looking
after his family clean living
choices all of these things that
personified in this
pinup boy uh for aspiring indigenous
sports stars who do you want to be like
when you grow up i want to be like jt
i want to be like mark ella i want to be
like seventh
and i think that um with the exception
of a couple of people on this call
specifically here
um that there is a distinct lack of role
models at that at that
uh cso level um supply diversity which
is really important because
um if if we if we if we
if we don't diversify our supply chain
then it's sort of like the meaningful
question how how can we how can we
encourage to perceive just being an
inclusive sector
when our supply chain is literally um
you know either either all white or uh
there are no women known business or
there's no veterans business i'm a
veteran myself
uh perhaps there's no uh australian
disability enterprise businesses
on in your supply chain so it's not just
about indigenous but for the purpose of
today's conversation
it certainly will be uh financial
constraints is something that i'm very
passionate about um
we understand that that what makes a
candidate also what can make a candidate
particularly attractive
for employment in in a sock team are
these international certifications
uh i can assure you after paying for a
number of them they are not cheap
and i put it to you guys that um that a
sans
incident response handling course which
would make
any graduate but if we're just going to
focus on indigenous graduates an
indigenous graduate from university
who then has a sans incident response
handling course
under her wing would make her more
attractive for employment
so there is a financial constraint that
that
i think our industry plays a lot of
importance on those c acronyms and
anything from osaka and anything from
sans uh educational gaps so
the two are linked there between the
industry
and the certifications and what we're
asking of our graduates when they come
through uni or through tables from high
school
we're asking them to to know more to be
more certified
access to technology so certainly
out west you know
in remote regional communities across
australia um there is a there is a
barrier to to to this idea about
regular uninterrupted internet now i
certainly can't
i can't provide a solution for that in
fact the three things that i wanted to
speak about today
um were financial constraints
educational constraints
and social constraints a little bit of
ignorance there around
um you know what
i think people in general um uh can do
and um supply chain consolidation and
and this is working very closely with
chief procurement officers and
understanding that what these men and
women are taught at university
um and what we are proposing around
supply chain diversity
it's almost um it's sort of like a a
flip of the coin where we where we would
traditionally think that supply chain
consolidation is all about cost savings
reducing risk
and providing benefits to the
organization counter that with
supplier diversity which is also about
being a more corporately responsible
citizen
being more representative of the
community in which we operate
that we support and and the final one
for me is fear
and um this is my opinion and i'm happy
to
be challenged on it uh in a nice way um
please don't believe that sometimes i
think
having done this for a little while um
sometimes i think that there is a
general fear in the community and in
corporate and
um private sector the fear of saying the
wrong thing
paralyzes people to say nothing at all
or or the fear of doing the wrong thing
and being reprimanded paralyzes people
from doing anything at all
and i think that that paralysis
is almost as as bad as
as the you know
what was going to be said and the way it
was described to me was that
if something you said or something is
done and it's coming from um
sort of a a point of of uneducation
or or benevolent ignorance
um it's not as bad as just sort of
sticking your head in the sand and
pretending that we don't have a problem
and
and there's a fear of putting your hand
up to say listen
boss i don't agree with that can we do
something different um that's that's
what i mean about fear
so is it a i mean is it really a problem
in australia in you know
itc security in 2020 and we just
bring you back to that original
statement um that i have done before
both here in queensland and and down in
melbourne in large audiences where we
where we we just play that um little
game about
you know identifying men and women who
we've worked with so yeah i i think it's
uh it absolutely is
um and there are two main reasons um
it's social and economic so
the advantages of of what we're talking
about are not
just the warm fuzzy feelings that we get
from from doing something that is fair
you know just and and morally correct um
ask any of the the ceos of an asx listed
organization and they'll be proudly
beating beating chests and saying yeah
they're we're all about creating
diverse organizations um you know
they might point to their inclusion
policy or the diverse people in their
workplace
support of local communities um you know
indeed three out of the
fortune 500 companies now employ a chief
diversity officer
um but there remains a critical area
that every organization needs to focus
on and and it's their supply chain
um over the last few years supply
diversity has gained a significant
amount of traction
um to become one of the the largest
trends in
enterprise uh procurement and this is
reflected in some of the stuff that
we're seeing
um having worked closely with supply
nation and reconciliation
uh action plans australia and i'll talk
about that in a moment
so organizations like um and it's not
exhausted by any stretch of the
imagination
there are thousands of organizations
that do this but you know
the big four banks um rio dhp flight
center
uh bank of queensland you know some of
the vendors who are
sharing this call with us now are
looking at all this but they've made
massive investments in supply diversity
um because i think today's organizations
need to think a little bit
differently about their supply chain um
procurement corporate social
responsibility programs and how the
three uh intricately you know what in
interwoven apologies i i believe that
those
who do this and and pay attention to csr
programs will have an opportunity to
change the world in ways that
you know our predecessors um could
could couldn't have never imagined uh
and and i also believe that those that
don't change
um will be left behind excuse me just
while i blow my nose
uh i don't have covert
simply understood supply diversity is
about your supply chain the supplies
that constitute this chain and
in in to achieve supply diversity
organizations must be
accepting and open to changing their
supply chain to make it more inclusive
and an inclusive supply chain just
doesn't start and stop with
indigenous business um we would be
talking about certainly indigenous owned
businesses
we'd also be talking about women to own
businesses veteran-owned businesses
australian disability enterprise owned
businesses and indeed
social enterprises um and why is it
important that we focus on these guys
well i think it's quite simple these
businesses are typically disadvantaged
for being different
um they
can be discriminated against because of
their differences
but by supporting these organizations
there's a valuable opportunity to
promote growth of local communities to
strengthen the economy
and to provide more opportunities for
individuals and businesses
and indeed the nation to grow and and
prosper
um so so there
that's that's what's at risk if we do
nothing and i think that if we do
something there
the advantages are pretty
uh pretty compelling so a lot of people
sit back and
and uh and wait for the government to do
something
it's um but after have working very
closely with the government
when we kicked this um this business off
uh we flew down and spoke to
some ministers and the um
refreshingly the the uniform feedback to
to us
when we flew down as a consortium to
talk about indigenous business was
the government's role was to be a better
customer and indeed there was a quote
there
from the then cyber minister um if we
want to transform the entrepreneurial
digital
government sector in australia the most
important thing we can do is to be a
better customer
um you know i believe that the
government's role is to embrace the
federally mandated procurement policies
and to enforce at a state level those
state-based procurement objectives and
then for individuals within those
state-based
organizations and federally based
organizations their role is to enlighten
themselves and to be accountable and if
no one else is looking just be
accountable to yourself
this is the right thing to do on on on
on so many levels um
it's not just enterprises that are
putting the spotlight on supply
diversity the commonwealth government
has made massive leaps of supply chain
diversity through the ipp through the
indigenous procurement policy
um the government is set to
to sorry has set its sights to achieve
three percent of every government goods
and services
uh to be consumed through an indigenous
business by 2020
and to ensure that there is a tangible
change to
to supply diversity from a government
perspective those targets are
enforceable
the ipp sets out to create opportunities
for it for indigenous businesses to grow
to drive demand for goods and services
provided by indigenous businesses
to boost employment to stimulate new
investment into indigenous businesses
and then there are the the sometimes the
things that we don't think about as a
sector and there are things like
creating intergenerational wealth so
wealth that's handed down through the
generations
uh opportunity employment pathways for
kids to follow as they leave uni and
they're looking around
to potential career opportunities and
starting to look at it security as a
viable career pathway
um and and and and i think that there is
a
you know a great responsibility that the
government has and i also think that by
leading by example
um it's showing that indigenous
adversary is showing that by including
indigenous businesses
uh in your supply chain can bring around
so many benefits
um the ipp not only demonstrates right
purchasing behaviors
from organizations that have a
significant amount
of money to push down through the supply
chain
but it also sends a very powerful
message to corporate australia
um and and i believe that that message
is that if all businesses get behind
the australian government's grow our
goal then the markets will grow
economy will thrive um and
and we will start to see um
and it certainly won't happen overnight
and i'm not proposing that there's going
to be a tsunami but there will be a
trickle
uh which will grow into a flood of
capable indigenous men and women um
that will that will provide those role
models for for other
for other kids to follow um
interestingly enough the difference
between the two slides between
private and uh public uh there's not a
great deal of difference and i think the
private sector needs to be a better
customer
uh i think the private sector needs to
embrace reconciliation action plans not
just as a tick box
so not just saying i've got a plan but
what is the
what am i going to do with that plan how
am i going to use reconciliation action
all those supporting frameworks that
reconciliation action plans provide
how am i going to use those for good um
how am i going to
enforce procurement objectives that
support social outcomes
and then from an individual level how
can i educate myself
as a private sector employee or someone
who buys or procures
uh itc security um goods and services
how can i educate myself and be
accountable to not only my business but
also my customers
and the community that my business
operates in um
our community is diverse our customers
are diverse
so let's make other parts of the
the corporate structure diverse um i
think that's
um that's that's that's really important
um i'm gonna steal a quote from the
chairperson supply nation
um supply nation by the way is a
not-for-profit organization
with the purpose of providing
opportunities for small
to medium enterprise indigenous owners
to enter into commercial relationships
with large corporate
government entities indigenous
businesses certified with supply nation
can
can get a lot of support from this
organization and as the chairperson of
supply nation
told a newspaper we educate procurement
officers to broaden their minds
now if they need high views workwear
security services or everyday purchases
like paper
we absolutely have a business an
indigenous owned business that we can
point you in the direction of
uh and that then opens up you know the
sort of the idea that indigenous
businesses are not
uh homogenous and they're not always
about culture
uh community or sport um
they're entrepreneurial they're
pioneering they're innovative they come
um they come with a different way of
looking at a problem
old problem new sense of bias so i think
this idea about
um you know and i and i keep laboring on
the point about supply diversity supply
diversity supply diversity
because whilst bathum solutions
represents queensland's
first and only uh supply nation
certified i.t security consultancy
there must be 50 or 60 non-indigenous
i.t security consultancies and so i'm
proposing that if the
if the sector in queensland can support
those 60
and one of ours then it it just goes to
show that
well there should be 10 of us there
should be 10 indigenous businesses in
queensland all all
competing um for for these projects
and and and hopefully putting back in
this community
um the other thing that i wanted to to
talk to you about
uh and to give you some education around
another way of overcoming some of these
barriers or kryptonite
to what we're trying to do around
diversity inclusion our reconciliation
action plans now i'm fairly certain
that we're all conscious of the concept
of
an iso certification framework is simply
a
framework for the way that the
organization holds information
a reconciliation action plan is is
is simple yet incredibly powerful it
outlines the steps an organization will
need to take to build strong
relationships and
and respect the key word their respect
between non-indigenous people and and
first nations australians
and it it lays down a framework for
tangible social
change in fact a recent report
shows that reconciliation action plans
are helping to close the gap in
employment between indigenous and
non-indigenous australians
a rat plan um
and i'll share the links with you at the
end of this speech but uh the wrap plan
helps to create more
dynamic and diverse workplace which
which is a more understanding and
therefore more tolerant and different
a different tolerance of different
cultures which can only be a good thing
for for australia right if we're just a
more tolerant in
in our workplace i think that
ict will start to present itself as a
more inclusive environment for first
nations participation
so what's the bloody solution to all
this kryptonite talk um
because i i do find that a lot of people
talk um
and there's not a lot of action and and
that's why a couple of slides ago
we sort of we had a quick chat about um
sometimes people wait for the government
to mandate something
and then we'll do it now please don't be
that person that waits for something to
be mandated before it becomes bloody
common sense
the same concept about getting in your
car and putting your seatbelt on
because it's common sense
that's where we want to get to and it's
going to need it's going to need a
combined effort
of everybody in the sector from from the
reseller
to the vendor that we represent to the
customers
to the disneys we all need to come
together and
actors act as the superheroes for
diversity and inclusion
um in keeping with the theme we can all
be superheroes and yes we can we can all
be superheroes
if we just do the little things right we
don't need to
um you know rattle the cage and put our
employment at risk by
you know challenging the status quo but
certainly from our
perspective um as being an an innovative
uh partner to state and federal
government and the asx top 100
we know only full well that we are
challenging the status quo
uh in in procurement and in in technical
teams
um but it's just really wonderful when
customers and decision makers
just give us a go because that in my
mind is being a superhero it's just
saying we'll give you a go
and we won't assess you on your culture
or the culture of the people you
represent
we will assess you on your capability uh
and i think that is
is what what we all want as human beings
just to be assessed on our capability
whether you're
black or white gay or straight um
regardless of your religious beliefs
just can you do the job that we're being
asked of you yes
is it within the budget envelope yes do
you have all the appropriate
uh insurances and and uh that we need to
to give ourselves some some some uh
some comfort that you guys can can cover
us yes we can do you have some
references yes
well then instead of instead of asking
why indigenous business
to provide the outcome i'd kind of flip
it on its head and i'd say well
perhaps we should be asking ourselves as
a sector why not
well why not the government's leading
the way and someone in some of their
procurement
policies cert certainly from a new south
wales government perspective uh and a
victorian government perspective
in black and white it's in the
procurement policy
that is is reported on an estate-based
level to say
services that that you're after as a
procurement professional
if the certain goods and services can be
found from an indigenous business
first then you don't need to test the
market
in fact you're you're well within your
rights
to start commercial negotiations with
that indigenous supplier
now think about that for a moment about
this idea about in i.t
security getting and from a cso's
perspective and a cio's perspective
getting the security control that you
want
today to fix the problem that exists
today not in three months time once
a testing the market process has
happened and once we've evaluated three
quotes from 15 different suppliers
we want a control to fit now there
aren't many organizations
in australia that can effectively
navigate
some of the procurement um processes
whilst supporting and encouraging
property every step of the way
there aren't too many organizations that
can do this that are welcome with open
arms and state and federal government
other than indigenous business providers
of goods and services and in this
instance we're talking about security
so in my mind growing up as a as a young
boy in my mind
um superheroes were always supportive
uh kind patient
knowledgeable and just like clark kent
they did the right thing even when no
one was looking
so i firmly believe that excuse me
that in many years to come we will have
an i.t
sector that is so supportive of
indigenous inclusion
and diversity that many of the
superheroes that have picked up
the challenge today and i hope that many
of you do
will pass on that cape and mask to the
next generation
of superheroes so we get to a stage
where this idea about diversity and
inclusion
doesn't take cognitive thought process
it just happens
i think that would be a wonderful place
for us all
to be um i for those of you who are
interested i i can share
uh sorry that that concludes the the
formal process of
of the uh of the chat um i wanted to
share some links with you
uh if you are interested links to supply
nation and what that organization
represents to reconciliation
org.iu uh certainly from a a
um from a state-based perspective i i'm
well-versed in queensland government
policy but i can guide people towards
um the state-based if you are a
state-based procurement
professional or a state-based security
guy i can guide you towards
some of the beautifully written
procurement policies that
set out to create a fairer and more
equitable
society they've been well written and
and sometimes i think their beauty is in
their simplicity
and also to draw your attention to a
program
in canada called connected north um
there is a fantastic program where like
in australia um first nations
communities are
affected by the tyranny of distance and
there has been a vendor
um collaborate with the canadian
government
to create a program called connected
north and through technology
we are starting to bridge the gap and
close that gap of distance between
first nations communities in canada and
um
and labrador and british columbia and i
just think to myself
you know guys if new zealand can do it
and canada
can do it then why the bloody hell can't
we do it of course we can
i just think we all need to be um you
know a little bit more superhero
and a little bit less let's just wait
for someone else to do it for us
i think we need to to all step up so i'm
going to um
i don't know what i'm going to do i'm
just going to stop sharing something and
click on something else
thank you very much for that pit
and if there are any questions please do
just throw them in the chat
or do throw them in uh in the q a
section
uh we do have a little bit of time but
first and foremost i'd like to say thank
you very much pip
it's not never easy kind of jumping into
a presentation very last minute
um so on behalf of us i'd really like to
thank you for that
and i like to kind of pick out a point
that you made
around the paralysis aspect of it so you
you're 100 spot on um the fact that
i think a lot of people don't know what
what the right thing to say is
or how to go about it so they don't say
anything at all so
i mentioned just before you talk that
this topic is quite near and dear to my
heart because my partner's indigenous
so um you know she's from uh the you can
be a nation
on the wall and around and around logan
um
and you know her her father's an elder
and
and all that kind of stuff so he is
involved quite heavily in the community
so on the paralysis perspective not
everyone's as fortunate
as i personally am to just go up to her
and ask a question it might be stupid
and most likely is
but you know not everyone is fortunate
enough to go up and have a person on
hand
you know through through which they can
ask those types of questions
so my question to you would be um what
would be
the the appropriate approach or are
there any kind of mechanisms out there
that people can ask those questions
without feeling a little bit silly or
maybe you feel
like they are naive
yeah oh mate i can say it's a it's a and
thank you for the vote of confidence and
thank you for the little story i
deliberately finished a little bit early
so we could have these
open discussions so um so so my go-to
guy
is mark ella am um i i
i have the ability and i'm fortunate
enough to to
if i have a if i have a a thought
process or a thought bubble that i just
want to reference check with someone who
has
uh so mark eller if he remembers on the
call don't know was the first
indigenous captain of the wallabies back
in the late 70s and early 80s
um rugby union um he wrenched the
letters low cut back off the kiwis
in 1981 the first time since 1947
um he was inducted into the rugby hall
of fame he retired from rugby union when
he was 25
and he played and the three boys uh ella
boyz played in an era where racism was
open
and so mark now is the executive
director of sbs
sports over the black dot nitv
and he's all about creating role models
outside of sport
because he knows that not everyone is
gifted at sport as the yellow family
but to answer your questions succinctly
so i'm fortunate like you
of having that go-to guy that that we
just ask a question over
over a phone call and say is this the
right way of framing or is it
not um i think that there's two things
that we could probably look at
i think the first one is i genuinely
believe
that there is such a profound uh sense
of ignorance when it comes to these
subjects that i think that every
organization needs to
invest in cultural sensitivity training
i think that we need to
really understand uh what it is that
first nations people
bring to this to the sector that's the
first thing
that's a formal approach right where we
educate ourselves to
to break down those um that ignorance
that's up here
the the next thing uh is up to the
individual and this is the concept that
if we do good only good will follow
right so
if we are someone that we know um
i mean i'm certainly not proposing just
going up on you know to a first nations
man or woman on the street and asking
them for their opinion
that's probably not a good idea but if
there is a way that we can we can
communicate
either through um you know volunteering
for for indigenous
organizations but i think that there's
this concept that
i think what you know it's not just
indigenous
people it's men and women in wheelchairs
you know
we don't want to skirt around the issue
we don't want people to feel sorry for
us we don't want people to
to um to jump around just just come out
and ask the question i think if it's
coming from a good
if if the question itself is coming from
a good um point of view or
a good um what's the word good angle
rather than being a a you know a
malicious question
if it's coming from a sense of hey look
i just want to know i want to be
educated i want to learn
i don't want to be like everybody else i
want to be better
can you help me is this the right way of
pronouncing jugembear is this the right
way of giving an acknowledgment of
country
what's the difference between an
acknowledgement of country and a welcome
the country these are all things that we
should know
australia should know like hands down
and it should be taught in school i hope
to god it is i'm too old now 44.
but i hope to god it is taught in school
i hope so too uh it wasn't taught when i
was going through school and that was
a little while ago as well um and a kind
of follow-up question as well do you
do do you see it improving from your
perspective from what you see
um you know particularly in queensland
um do you
do you see you know it actually
improving
um from that perspective do you see a
lot more indigenous than first nations
actually wanting to get into information
technology or cyber security which is
even more niche
yeah uh well look um
now wait man i'm not gonna suggest it
but um
i see it improving but very slowly um
you know i i i'm fortunate enough to to
to take that veil of ignorance off my
head once i started to investigate
um and and consult like you would with
elders i consult with
with traditional owners from juvent and
i consult with
you know the markels of the world that
represent um
this idea about overcoming diversity and
and building resilience and never giving
up and being a role model
for for jonathan thurston um
i i i think that we have a long long way
to go
but you know someone once wiser than me
um
said that if we don't you know best time
to plan a treat
was 20 years ago the second best time is
today and if we don't start today
and we've got all of these beautiful
policies and procedures in place to
support
capable indigenous businesses across a
vast array of
of capability not just technology
then when are we going to start and
that's a question that we need to ask
our customers and our vendors
and and resellers and the whole
community because it takes a
village to raise a child i'm not
proposing that baitum can do this on its
own because it certainly cannot
but in two years for us to be able to
provide the first
indigenous supplied scholarship to the
university of queensland
in two years i respectfully lay down the
gauntlet to many of my non-indigenous
competitors to say what are you doing
definitely well i have many more
questions i'm sure
other people have have some questions as
well but we'll kind of
run out of time there but thank you very
much pip and thanks again for jumping
very last minute and a fantastic
presentation
my pleasure lucas it's lovely to see you
mate
you