morning everyone welcome to
uh oscar 2020 day two so for those of
you who weren't here yesterday my name
is john
and i'll be hosting uh string4 for the
rest of the day
uh before we get started with our first
speaker i just wanted to get through
some
housekeeping things so if you guys are
using any browser try to use chrome and
if anything
crashes just refresh the browser and it
should be good to go
don't have too many tabs open at the
same time we have some q a functionality
on that right hand panel
there that you can see so if you have
any questions just put it there and i
think people have the ability to vote it
up
which is good there's also a raise hand
function at the bottom of your screen so
if you want to ask a question live or
have any issues just hit that
and one of the guys will get to you as
soon as they can and if you guys want to
go back to the foyer during the
presentation the link is in the general
chat
um window there so our first speaker for
today is ronald michael
from synopsis so ronald is a senior
application engineer
within their software integrity group
and he specializes in devops automation
and cloud security
so his topic will be a modern approach
to application security testing
so go ahead ronald
good morning to all the listeners today
my name is ronald michael
and i'm a senior application security
engineer with synopsis
i hope you are staying healthy and safe
during these unprecedented times
although it's exciting to be a part of
this new
virtual format most of us entered 2020
expecting a very different reality than
the one we currently live in
but what's great to see is how we are
navigating
and adapting to this new world speaking
of new
the presentation i have for you is
going to touch on a new innovative
technology
in the application security space i
would like to thank you
for joining and i hope i can add value
to you in this session so let's get
started
here's the agenda for this session
you'll get a background of why would any
organization consider i
asked in the first place by
understanding the latest
application security trends then we will
see what
eyes is all about and dive deeper
into the inner workings of our ass and
its different flavors
and try to make sense on how it fits
into the devsecops environment finally
we will look at in what cases it makes
sense
to use i asked for different
organizational needs
so before we jump into the main topic
let's try and understand the need
for application security testing and
focus on what's the problem
in application security and why would
organizations
care about this most organizations
are looking to adopt some level of
devsecops practices
into the development process for reasons
of improved speed
cost better development flow and improve
quality
through continuous feedback
this is especially true for
organizations
building web-based applications
gartner predicts 60 percent devsecops
adoption by 2021 and you don't want to
be left behind
the problem is that this move towards
devsecops practices
makes application security testing more
difficult than
ever gartner research has determined
that the traditional dast and pen
testing tools
which are commonly used to test
web-based applications
will struggle in these more automated
devops oriented
environments
for sure everyone knows of cyber
security attacks
many organizations have significant
network security in place
but it's not enough as 84 percent of all
cyber attacks
are happening on the application layer
this graph gives you a breakdown of
attacks
happening on different categories of
applications
and you will notice that microservices
and web-based
are on top of the list from this
we can understand why application layer
is the number one
attack surface for hackers
when we dig deeper into the state of
automation used today
the bulk of automation is still in
the early part of software development
lifecycle
that is mostly when developers commit
they code
and build the code
as you can see from the graph the
automation level
starts to drop from test to production
phase
nearly half of the development teams
still run
tests manually in test production phases
and guess what most of the security
vulnerabilities only show up
during the test phases
and all of this really compounds the
time and effort
that's needed to test troubleshoot
and configure the ci cd pipeline
not just for non-security bugs but
security bugs as well
this was another study performed by
google last year
on the state of devops we see that
elite organizations automate and
integrate
tools more frequently into their tool
chains
on almost all dimensions all the
automation may
be seen as too expensive to implement
automation is truly a sound investment
it allows engineers to spend less time
on manual work
thereby freeing up the time to spend on
the
more important activities as you can see
from this table security test automation
lags
across the board
with all the recent attacks and breaches
developers are definitely aware and no
security is important but they don't
have the time to spend on it
developers don't focus on security
because they are builders
not breakers
software development is more a creative
endeavor
than it's a rigorous engineering process
developers primary job is to create
features that
work not to worry about what might go
wrong
and also they haven't been trained to do
so
hence you might find some of these
questions on the slide fairly common
but instead of making them
change their methods and processes
application security
must align and adapt to the development
workflows and that's a better approach
as one of the endless number of acronyms
in software security industry
i asked doesn't have much going on for
it
it's awkward to pronounce and it's hard
to guess what it stands for
but what is important of course is what
a string of
letters does stand for and in that case
interactive application security testing
has a lot
going on for it
it is a tool that is remarkably
effective at rooting out potentially
catastrophic bugs
in web based applications during
software development life cycle
so what is i asked please observe the
keywords on the slide
while there are a variety of testing
tools and techniques
each useful at different times and in
different ways
one of the most effective is iest a
technique
that does its analysis from within
the application it does so
by using software instrumentation by
deploying agents
and merely observing the interactions
to identify the vulnerabilities in real
time while the apps are running
instrumentation is nothing new it's
already being used in performance
monitoring apps like new relic dyna
trees
app dynamics some of you must have heard
of them
you can think of it like a car dashboard
with its instrumentation it displays all
this information
in real time while the car is running
without impacting the performance
this way it's non-intrusive
but before we dive deeper into i asked
let's look at some of the other tools we
have
and the differences other tools
yes that means even more acronyms
which include sas static application
security testing
das dynamic application security testing
and rast runtime application security
testing
sast is the grand daddy of application
security testing
and having been in developers toolbox
more than a decade
it helps developers analyze an
application's
source code to determine whether the
security vulnerabilities exist
and to ensure conformance with the
internal coding
guidelines das
technologies are designed to detect
conditions that indicate a security
vulnerability
in running applications note
the difference from sas which tests
applications as
code not while it's running
the ios technology combines and enhances
benefits of
sassed and dust the accuracy of an ios
vastly improves that of sassed and dast
because it benefits from the static and
runtime points of view while it's not a
complete
replacement for dust or pen testing it
is superior to
both for finding vulnerabilities earlier
in the sdlc
with when it is easier faster
and cheaper to fix them
rasp integrates with an application to
prevent
attacks at runtime by analyzing traffic
and end user behavior
these tools should complement rather
than
replace your testing strategy each
apsec tool have distinct advantages
but you'll get the best results when you
use them together
you must be curious this sounds like a
great tool
but how does it really work
well at its core it's based on runtime
analysis technology
it means we are able to look at the code
as it's running
as though we were a debugger debugger
can stop
every line of code in memory and look at
things that are happening
on the server side
so in i asked the agent is doing all the
magic
through software instrumentation but
what does it really
see though the agent is able to monitor
pretty much everything http requests and
responses
calls to the database the data flows and
configuration information the tool then
shows the reflection of the source code
and
points out the location of
vulnerabilities for
developers since they are running from
within
the application as tools detect
vulnerabilities in the running code
whether be it custom code third-party
libraries
or even code generated on the fly by the
framework
let's look at it in action in this
animation
the two steps here happen before the
user gets a response
back from the server that is immediate
results
as you can see once the agent
analyzes the code and memory through
software instrumentation
with a key focus on security
many of the is tools stop at this step
however some advanced
ir solutions can go a step further and
replay the original http
or https request with a malicious
parameter value and verify that this
vulnerability can be exploited
this helps reducing the false positives
to nearly zero
if i were to zoom in on the magic that
agent performs
here's what it looks like at its core
it uses instrumentation which is
basically injecting code into the
running application without modifying
the binaries
on the right you can see the original
code flow
and further right you can see these
little
orange blocks these are nothing but
segments of instrumentation code
inserted
during the instrumentation process
languages like java.net have an
instrumentation api
that makes this possible to put
these orange code in place
so what we put there are the things that
we want to look at
and access variables and memories and
see what's going on
it's transparent and doesn't have
influence on the process
and this way it's non-intrusive
there are actually two types of highest
approaches
active and passive both approaches rely
on an
agent instrumented within the
application
let's have a look at the two methods
the active iest approach combines a web
scanner
such as dast also known as inducer
with an agent that sits inside the
application server
as you can see in the image two
different components are required to
perform the security
analysis the attack component and the
detect component
the attack component scans the urls of
the application
by sending a list of known attack
payloads
this process can be considerably time
consuming
and depending on the size of the target
application
and the number of attack payloads the
detect component
which is ios provides additional context
thanks to its visibility of the internal
response
of the application to the traffic that
is generated by the
attack component which is test
active ios does not suit
fast-paced development environments
since das requires full compilation
upon every code change and can only be
used
towards the end of the sdlc
whereas on the other hand passive i
asked
implementations do not require a
secondary inducer
to attack because any kind of legitimate
traffic is enough to perform the
security analysis
any sort of testing performed on the
application where the
automatic or manual will be leveraged to
collect and deliver
security issues on the running code
in real time that is why
passive ios is also known as full
and activist is known as partial
or light it does not perform
attacks and scans to detect
vulnerabilities
so active doesn't necessarily equate to
better here
in this case
ios bridges the gaps between sas dast
and pen testing you could even say
that the ios was made
for devsecops and closely allied
sdlc concepts of agile and ci cd
let's find out how
both traditional static and dynamic
testing
have limitations that leave a security
testing gap
in the sdlc especially for teams
adopting ci cd and devops
while sast can be used early in the sdlc
it doesn't detect many of the real
vulnerabilities
that only show up during the running of
the application
dust and pen testing are complex and
used
late in the sdlc and don't integrate
very well
into the workflow of ci cd pipelines
making it
costly and time consuming to fix
vulnerabilities that are found
there is a obvious gap with the
traditional
tools and they have their own limitation
ias addresses this gap by providing a
solution
that allows for automated testing of web
application
with the ability to provide development
with the specific location of
vulnerabilities in the code
ios can be used in all stages of sdlc
but it has most profound impact
and return on investment in the
development
testing and qa phases
any sort of testing performed on the
application whether
automatic or manual functional or
non-functional
will be leveraged to collect and deliver
security issues
on the running code in real time that's
the beauty of it
no additional config or setup
after all the primary goal of devsecops
is to have security practices baked into
the agile development process
rather than delaying testing until
just before release
in order to better appreciate the value
of ios
that it brings to the table let's have a
look at some
use cases and understand the many
distinct
advantages over traditional solutions
and why it's poised
to be the next big thing in the security
industry
we have some customers with few problems
and they're hoping to resolve let's see
how eyes can help them
well michael scott self-proclaimed
world's best boss wants to really help
his organization
his organization like many others
rely exclusively on an external security
consultant
to perform manual pen testing post
production the challenge for pen testers
is that they have
only a brief window to test what
is new in any new given release
however this would result in up to two
weeks
of work for developers and testers to
remediate the vulnerabilities
increasing the cost for remediation and
slowing down the time to market
this makes the process slow and
expensive
with i asked the developers within the
organization
can test while they develop
ios gives a comprehensive look at the
entire
application and its components once
any modification is made ios can be run
on demand so testing is no longer
constrained to a brief
window before go live it enables
substantial productivity gains versus
manual verification by security teams
this results in saving time and money
and reduces the reliance on an external
security consultant it's almost like
having an automated virtual team of pen
testers
to identify common security
vulnerabilities
dwight schrute from the same company has
a different focus
the last thing a security or a dev team
need is a massive list of
potential vulnerabilities that require a
lengthy tedious
manual review and triaging in addition
to being accurate
your developers need detailed and
contextual information
about vulnerabilities and where they are
located in the code
and how to remediate them the best irish
solutions can
also automatically verify whether the
vulnerabilities
they find are exploitable so developers
are less likely to investigate a bug
only to come to the irritating
conclusion
that it is nothing more than a false
positive
this saves wasted time resolving false
positives
so helps the team focus on real critical
vulnerabilities that
matter the most
morris who is the apsec head
is worried about the open source risk
with the prevalence of open source code
in today's software
effective ios tools need to be aware of
the open source composition
of the applications being tested
some ios solutions have this feature
giving teams
additional insight into vulnerabilities
license type version numbers of open
source components
libraries and frameworks used in the
code
security auditor dinesh is keen on
ensuring they are compliant with the
standards that are important to
his organization this technology
identifies vulnerabilities that pose a
real
threat to critical data including
complex vulnerabilities
and logical flaws no other technology
can detect
stealing sensitive data is often
the objective of malicious attacks
ios is a data centric solution
that is continuously tracking the flow
of data across
all application tiers and components
it identifies whether the data is
mishandled or insecurely stored
and exposes potential data leaks before
they become a
business risk for organizations this
enables
sensitive data to be automatically
tracked anytime they are
saved unencrypted in a log database
or file sensitive data tracking helps
organization achieve
compliance like pci dss standard or gdpr
etc gen baba
wants to make sure
this doesn't disrupt the existing
process developers or devops engineers
don't have to be security experts
or change the normal workflow no special
scans
no extra work required it's easy to
integrate ios
in ci cd workflows custom enterprise
specific tools
and developer tools it works with
virtually
any type of test method existing
automation tests
automated web crawler and a range of
pre-production testing from manual test
functional integrated regression and
user
acceptance test plus it has a flexible
deployment model
fully automated docker based or manual
can be deployed on-prem or in the cloud
different types of applications are also
supported
like microsoft services cloud-based or
even standard
architecture
so here are the key takeaways
iost has seamless integration it's easy
to integrate and
automate in the ci cd pipeline and even
easier to deploy and configure
plus it's optimized for security
development and devops teams
when it comes to privacy and compliance
is the only abstract testing tool
with complete sensitive data tracking
it's it also has the benefit of
integrated software composition
analysis for open source dependencies
ios ability of accurate findings
with real time verification
helps prioritize remediation and in turn
helps to empower developers
lastly is designed to scale it
supports large-scale modern application
deployments
keeping all this in mind iost is the
only
one element of modern
application security program we need a
combination of modern solutions
such as ios and traditional apps tools
like
sas das sca pen testing managed services
and what have you to create secure
software
in today's complex development
environments
at the end of the day the simple answer
is
there is no silver bullet no single
technology or solution
can solve the wide variety of
application security risks
you need to deal with in today's world
to succeed you need to take a
multi-layered approach
that combines a mix of application
security strategy
and programs with in-house and outsource
testing
if you already have that in place that's
great
but for those of you who don't synopsis
offers the tools and services to help
strengthen your security posture
investing in automation tools
and services from a trusted leader in
the apsec
environment could make the difference
between
success and disaster
with that we have come to the end i hope
i was able to add value and hope you
found this
session useful and i would like to thank
you
for listening and tuning in if you have
any questions
please feel free to ask them now
hey guys yeah i think i just
saw a couple of questions in the q a um
i'll just answer one that uh
that just came up um so in terms of
maturity right it really depends
on your objective or what type of
software
development and delivery framework you
have in place
if you're just starting out with
application security in your
organization even if you're starting on
a small scale
ios can give you a lot of value
and can give you the best bang for your
buck because it has these additional
capabilities
of detecting open source software as
well and
the value that you have seen right based
on the case studies
apart from that i see another question
come in which is
employer rasp solution that we have i
asked
um if you want to follow a more
proactive
defensive approach where you want to
block those attacks
then possibly you might want to um but
really depends on what approach you want
to go for whether you just want
to detect the attacks or really
go full force and block them now that's
prone to false positive as well
and rasp also has certain performance
issues so you might want to take that
into account and factor that in
as well um
yeah so do i have any stats around the
time
added during the development um that is
something that which we can
provide to you we uh might uh have that
for you
i don't have it on top of my head right
now um
but definitely you can visit our booth
as well um at the synopsis booth that's
sponsored level one and we i can take
that question up there
um also for the slides uh yes
feel free to again visit our booth or
even simon
has just dropped in his email and you
can even email him and he should be
able to provide that to you um
guess those are the questions that have
just come in but
thanks for joining i hope you enjoyed
the session and
if you think of anything else and you're
curious please feel free
to come to the booth or even chat on
this option here
thanks for your time guys
thank you very much for that ronald uh
next up we've got barry mcmahon from
lobbying talking about the value
of identity in the digital environment
uh so that should start in a couple of
minutes time we'll see you all then