[Music]
foreign
hey everybody oh that is loud I'm Stuart
Scott I work with the Cyber statecraft
initiative at the Atlanta Council and we
work at the kind of intersection of
cyber security and Technology policy get
through a lot of cool cross
collaboration and the past couple of
years we've had the privilege to be
working on a lot of software supply
chain security topics and so we started
trying to think in kind of a risk
management framework looking for sources
of risk and sources of security and one
that's caught our attention recently has
been kind of the ecosystem of
vulnerability research contributing kind
of disclosures to companies and and
libraries and and all those code bases
from outside of the projects I'm sure
many of you all familiar with the kind
of the growing market share bug Bounty
platforms kind of representing the
growing acceptance and uh kind of
investment in those programs and
Frameworks and it's it's a pretty direct
manifestation of the the many eyes
theory of security right more people
looking at a better chance of finding
issues with it and they get paid in the
process and we've also seen more kind of
government initiatives working to to
open up their kind of intakes for the
same kind of information and all that is
governed by what's generally called the
coordinated vulnerability disclosure
process process it's you know unique to
different organizations and we'll just
go with CBD for now
but what really got us interested was
some data that came out of congressional
testimony in February in the wake of the
log 4ja hearings in in Congress there is
some anonymized breakdowns of where
funds went from bug Bounty platforms and
what we were starting to think about was
was where did those kind of reserves of
expertise and research localize and
where are their kind of bottlenecks and
the the big question we arrived at was
you know can bad policy or a lack of
good policy end up breaking that
ecosystem interrupting vulnerability
contributions and significantly degraded
security as a result and can we detect
that happening in public available data
ideally
and the kind of perfect case study we
found for this was looking at the
process of disclosure behind log4j so
I'm sure many of you all are familiar
with Carnegie Mellon they have a pretty
comprehensive guide to CBD and this is a
little exhibit of how they describe it
as pathfinding between telling everybody
immediately when you find a
vulnerability and never telling anyone
anywhere anything at any point and
trying to find that optimal path is very
context dependent but this was a great
example of you know a researcher at
Alibaba Cloud figured out the
vulnerability and reported it directly
and privately to Apache pretty promptly
and they began patching
and pretty soon after he followed up
communicating that either on the 8th or
9th of December he'd started noticing
that the vulnerability was making its
way into more public forum which in turn
spurred on their patching process and
this is a pretty good breakdown of how
the kind of withholding of information
should work right you find the
vulnerability you don't want to tell
everybody just those who can best fix it
until it becomes more public and then
the utility of holding on to it
decreases and you need to get people in
the position to at least patch or
mitigate as best as they can and as
quickly as they can but what really
caught our attention was soon after all
of that started playing out there was
some reporting that Alibaba had been
sanctioned for how it handled the
vulnerability by China's Ministry of
industry and information technology they
were
suspended for about six months I believe
from a an information sharing for with
the government and it's not quite clear
from reporting publicly available what
the actual mechanism pulled was to pull
them off of that that Forum it was
either in the contract to be there they
had to share information and failed to
do so promptly or a law passed in July
2021 and taking effect in September 2021
requiring that Network providers in
China when they find a vulnerability
among other things I have to tell the
miit within a couple of days so we've
seen reporting claiming both of those
were the kind of legal mechanisms
involved but the actual specifics aside
the letter of the law the regulations on
the management of security
vulnerabilities and that's a translation
so there are a bunch of different
phrasings was kind of clearly violated
right Alibaba the network product
provider had the vulnerability and
didn't tell the miit within two days and
that's you know from the general
perspective of CBD how you should
proceed with that kind of information
right only tell those who need to know
until the information is more publicly
available and then tell those who need
to mitigate
so the majority of the reporting on the
rmsb is very focused on what happens to
vulnerabilities passed to government
early but our focus is on using it as a
really convenient case study to look at
this supply side question right can
something come up in either a legal
context or otherwise that will disrupt
that flow of vulnerabilities to those
who can patch it's very convenient
because as the the second slide showed
China is a huge producer of this kind of
research and work it also provides a
really clear timeline for us there are
only a few key dates we have to check to
see if anything happened and it provides
a nice kind of control group right the
law only applies to entities in China
although there's some some blurriness
around that but it gives us you know a
view into what happens in one location
and what doesn't happen in others and
the pathway for a chilling mechanism on
that research is pretty clear either
companies receiving information have to
rework their internal processes or the
researchers and research entities have
to kind of negotiate what the risk is of
following proper CBD what the risk is of
following the law or at least wait until
there's some more legal clarity
and to be clear this isn't focused
purely on China we've seen the same kind
of Dynamics at play all over the world
so for example in in Germany a
researcher found a vulnerability within
an election polling app reported it and
was threatened with legal action
similarly in Missouri a researcher found
in the HTML and I think it was of the
State Department of education's website
that they could pull Social Security
numbers for employees and they didn't do
that but they were also kind of
threatened for basically reading the web
page and there have been some good
developments as well with the doj
declining to prosecute good faith
research whatever they kind of consider
that to be Anisa in Europe is pushing
member states to develop as governments
their own CBD processes and sizza itself
has also put out a binding directive and
I think the the deadline for compliance
is expired at this point but for
government agencies to set up their own
processes
but that brings us back to what the the
question we wanted to take a look at
some data and try to answer is which is
did the rmsv create some kind of Supply
Shock by disincentivizing participation
in that pipeline of vulnerabilities and
vulnerability research and if so what
did it look like can we detect it are
there other weird things going on in the
data that we should take a look at and
does that Supply shock if it exists
trickle into the overall ecosystem or is
there some resilience built into the
system
and you know along the way too we get to
see a pretty cool insight into how those
vulnerabilities are reported by
companies and how that record making and
record keeping is done so to to answer
this question we started looking at
acknowledgment data in cve logs and
security updates from companies and we
focused in on Microsoft Apple F5 VMware
and red hat we wanted to get a nice
breadth of proprietary products and open
source ones and to kind of really span
between consumer-facing products very
kind of in the stack and on the racks
software Suites and everything in
between and there's lots of differences
in how those companies manage that
information internally so getting that
kind of diversity in there is very
useful for us
and to set up that kind of nominal
timeline of events to check against we
started with July 2020 which is the
earliest kind of public discussion
acknowledging that reporting requirement
in the rmsb
July 2021 when the law was passed
September 2021 when the law takes effect
and then possibly if we can get recent
enough data December 2021 where there is
a maybe incident of enforcement which
again we don't really know what happened
but the letter of the law seems to have
been broken
of course those events don't exist in a
vacuum right so Summers of 2020 and 2021
were also full of uh sanctions from U.S
government against Chinese companies
that may have done something to that
kind of Pipeline and there's also a lot
of cyber security regulation going on in
China at the same time so even if we
find something and it lines up nicely
it's really hard to tell what causal
mechanisms there are without talking to
actual people on the ground
but this is our basic process we either
downloaded things directly where they
were made available or used some simple
scraping scripts to pull those data sets
out and then the key things we were
looking at were cves the public
acknowledgment date and the publicly
credited entity and from there we just
tagged the entities to the country as a
proxy for their kind of operating legal
environment there was a lot of
information too about individual
researchers but we didn't apply that
same analysis to that part of the data
in part because it's a lot harder to get
location data and in part because the
law doesn't clearly apply itself to
individual researchers so much as large
companies but then we just batch them by
month and ran some civil tests to see if
anything happened on those key dates and
these are just the the inputted
countries to that process
the data set I cannot tell you how messy
it was but it was very bad um lots of
these things are hand entered there's
lots of typos lots of irregularities
there's really interesting things going
on with the dates so sometimes security
updates will include a cve that is
publicly knowledged afterwards but
somehow retroactively added but
sometimes they won't so there's lots of
fuzziness there and there's not any
Clarity really on the actual process
where you have a private reporting date
public acknowledgment date and whatever
kind of backtrack data filling is going
on it's also hard to compare between
these different five different
ecosystems we've set up partly because
of how they organize the data so some
are organized by pure cve numbers some
organized by effective products some
were organized by security updates and
that leads to a lot of overlap even
within the data sets so for example
Apple might update two separate product
lines to address one underlying
vulnerability and that would lead to a
double count
um and last of course having to batch
everything by month to keep things you
know manageably smooth makes it a little
fuzzier on the back end
but these are the data sets we came away
with um and we're going to run through
Microsoft and red hat today those are
where we had some interesting results uh
apple and VMware had a null finding
there was no Supply shock that we could
see and F5 didn't even have any Chinese
tagged entities in its data set though
it was kind of an order of magnitude
smaller than the other ones
so this here is a easy graph orange is
China tag contributions and blue are us
tag contributions as a Baseline and this
is representing on the y-axis their
proportion of that month's contributions
um and so over time you can see what's a
pretty typical story for all of our data
sets is early on the US kind of
dominates the ecosystem and then as
other it sectors develop and as the kind
of receiving entities become more open
to International contribution you see
China but other countries as well
contributing more and more and obviously
here we can take a quick look at the
quick
uh cliff dive that seems to happen
around one of our key dates July 2020.
so
these are some basic trend lines and we
see increasing Chinese participation in
this the Microsoft ecosystem
but a pretty noticeable and steep
decline there so we looked not just at
the proportions but also the raw counts
to get a bit more context and what was
interesting here with the Microsoft data
was that it was really the
continued like productivity of the
ecosystem despite what you could
consider to be the Chinese contributions
returning to some kind of meme that set
off that proportional drop
so this is not a no to our question of
is there a supply shot going on but it
doesn't seem to trickle out into the
larger ecosystem which is a little bit
reassuring
and then for the red hat data you'll
have to forgive some very spiky graphs
early on there's almost only U.S
participation because the timeline goes
much farther back than the Microsoft
data but we see again a similar kind of
increase in Chinese and other countries
participating in that kind of reporting
pipeline
and then again we have a drop off but
here if you can't see it is between 2017
uh February to April which is a date we
have no explanation for and then again
that kind of continued drop-off resumes
an uproad Trend but stays pretty
suppressed throughout
uh so here's looking just at the
contribution counts right the raw
numbers rather than the proportions and
this context is also helpful it seems
that that drop-off was sustained a
little more thoroughly than the
proportional data would lead you to
believe there was also just a following
drop off in overall contributions to the
ecosystem and what's notable here too is
that given that this is an open source
set of data points there's a lot more
credit given to individual researchers
that we didn't tag to any country so
there's a greater gap between the total
contributions and the by country
contributions
um and then finally for a bit of context
where you thought we'd throw in the
Apple data as well given it was our
largest data set and the one with the
strongest lack of anything you know
related to the rmsv possibly happening
so again early on we have that same
story of a lot of U.S participation and
we suspect too that a big part of what
leads other countries to contribute more
down the line is just the market
penetration of the actual products in
those countries and as you can see over
time China becomes a greater and greater
participant as well as the other
countries which are just not shown here
for a bit of clarity and here are the
raw contribution counts and you can also
see what's interesting about the Apple
data seasonality and you know every
other month and then every four months
there's a spike in the number of cves
addressed which might reflect some kind
of security patching scheduling going on
there but it's a nonetheless a really
interesting data point to find no no
affected product particularly given that
we've seen
products focused on at hacking
competitions like the tianfu cup but
that's another consideration to give
this data is because we're capturing
pretty much anything counted as a
vulnerability we're potentially blurring
those kind of high impact
vulnerabilities that are more likely to
be tailored towards offensive use
so our kind of key takeaways from this
where on the one hand there doesn't seem
to be what we expected to find which is
a clear drop off in any or all of these
ecosystems that affected total
contributions but we did find something
pretty clear in the Microsoft data just
not so clear what actually caused it so
that July 2020 date I mentioned on the
one hand it's kind of our strongest case
for for a drop-off because
um and we also have no idea what
happened with the red hat data I would
really love to know if anyone has any
insight but it's definitely something
worth looking into because our other key
takeaway is that the kind of reliability
of this ecosystem can't be taken for
granted you know I think generally it's
not thought of about as a supply but
we're finding that to be a pretty useful
way to frame how to build resilience
into it you know you can almost buy
security in that sense or you know
something close to it and we finish up
with a couple of recommendations for how
governments and companies without kind
of mirroring China's type of law can
invest in that ecosystem and and kind of
maintain its resilience to any localized
legal context shifts
so the first thing on those lines in
that kind of preservation front would be
to harmonize not super rigorously but at
least in spirit CBD processes between
governments
um and private sector entities so that
there's not so much ambiguity for a
researcher who finds something and
doesn't know kind of what the rules of
the road are for reporting in the
ecosystem that they're working in we
also figure that particularly with the
open source ecosystem investing in
vulnerability Discovery tools can take a
lot of that workload off of researchers
and can still be a way of investing
directly into security particularly
given that there isn't so much of a
officially set up bug bounty system for
the open source ecosystem although I
think there are a few initiatives just
starting up actually that are doing just
that and then the third point that we
wanted to recommend was
by keeping track of where kind of the
flow of disclosures and vulnerability
research is directed you can get a sense
of if things fall off where it might be
worth investing in more research so for
example if an ecosystem starts to kind
of dry up and they're not as many
vulnerabilities found there each
vulnerability found in that product or
code base is going to be more valuable
from a security perspective and you know
ensuring that the the kind of incentives
built around that line up and and funnel
researchers there before they have to
worry about how much they're going to
get paid for something they turn over
which is not necessarily clear up front
you can kind of build in not just
resilience to the supply but to how that
research Community is able to interact
with different companies and different
code bases
so that's kind of the you know the the
short story is though we're trying to
consider vulnerability research really
large as a Supply right a community that
has to be kind of invested in and given
some legal guardrails and protections um
and wanted to ask is it possible for bad
policy to shock that system uh to cut
off a large proportion of it from the
rest of the the community the answer we
don't really know but maybe it's
definitely a not no and there are
definitely a couple of concerning drops
that we would want to look into further
and you know given that those drops
didn't trickle into the broader
ecosystem it seems there is some innate
resilience built in and I can talk more
about the kind of specifics behind that
drop-off there's some really cool data
points about an increase in unattributed
um contributions in the same time frame
but finally there are also like
proactive ways to invest in this right
we don't have to kind of wait for
someone to make a copycat law of the
rmsb and then start worrying about a
fractured ecosystem and a lot of those
initiatives don't only protect against
those types of laws but they build up a
stronger research community
so we've got a draft report up we're
really hoping to kind of incorporate
input from a lot of experts in technical
Fields a lot of people on the ground I'm
hoping to talk to some researchers as
well so feel free to take a quick read
and get in touch with us if you have any
kind of notes or questions I think we've
got about 10 minutes left here where we
can do some q a which would be really
helpful from our friend but thanks so
much
really appreciate y'all coming
[Applause]
[Music]