[Music]
hey everyone
um so before we get started just out of
curiosity if if you could raise your
hand if you either run a bug Bounty or
have participated in a bug bounty in
some form
looks like maybe half half the audience
has their hand up I think the case that
we're gonna make
for the half of Their audience that did
not raise their hand that you may have
actually unwittingly participated in a
bug bounty in some form
through another security tester's
research and we're going to go through a
couple examples that kind of outlines
that
so first like why are we qualified to
talk about this um who are we
so my name is Dylan I'm a security
researcher I'm a Bug Hunter I was for a
little while
um top 100 on bug crowd but that was a
couple years ago these days I co-founded
a company called truffle security which
is built on top of an open source tool
called truffle hog and I do security
research on the side so talking at black
hat this is my second time and probably
third time talking at either Defcon or
black hat
hi everyone I'm Whitney
um I'm an attorney but I'm not your
attorney
um I work really closely with security
teams at various in-house companies that
I've worked at throughout the years I
helped build the coordinated
vulnerability disclosure program at
Electronic Arts and I support my current
security team at Asana in our various
bug Bounty programs
so in general if you look at most bug
Bounty programs they say don't touch
other users data
um like they say try not to touch other
users data they say only test with your
own account don't involve other users in
your in your testing so this is an
example of of
Uber's policy for their bug Banning
where they they outlined that in one of
the bullet points
um and you can see like this is pretty
common language it's actually in a lot
of different programs they say make sure
you're only testing your data don't
access other people's data
so
um this talk being about data privacy
and Bug bounties
um we're in a pretty good spot we've
told our hackers to not touch data that
doesn't belong to them and uh I think we
should be good yeah we're good
damn
so close we almost had it
um
well I mean this this was for me when I
was testing I accidentally caused some
problems
um hey Whitney
um listen I was I was testing a program
doing their bug Bounty and I
accidentally accessed some data that I I
shouldn't have accessed um I just I
wanted to check with maybe my neighborly
friendly lawyer is there anything I
should do here could I get in trouble
for this accident oh that's a good
question why don't you tell me what
happened
yeah so um I was testing this type of
vulnerability called Blind cross-site
scripting basically I just replaced my
username with some JavaScript and I
threw it into a system and forgot about
it and then that JavaScript what it does
is if anyone
executes that JavaScript unsafely by
rendering my user data unsafely it'll
take a screenshot of whatever that page
is and it'll send me a copy of that page
so what happened was somebody had
accessed an admin page that was
insecurely rendering user data and it
had a list of every user of the entire
system and all of that got screenshotted
and got sent to me and I accidentally
got a copy of everyone's user data
oh did you disclose everything to the
program yeah yeah yeah so I definitely
uh attached all the screenshots I walked
them through all the steps that I did I
was 100 transparent every step of the
way that's great since you told them you
had some of the data uh did you delete
the copy of the data that you had uh
no uh
uh yeah is that something I should do uh
yeah didn't the program ask you to
delete all of the data that you had in
your possession uh no no they never
asked me that and actually now that I'm
thinking about it it might be kind of
complicated to have to delete all this
data it's it's like a cup like it's it's
not super straightforward oh interesting
complicated how
yeah
um so about that um there's actually
like a couple of systems that I use when
I do my testing and um it probably
results in like a copy of this user data
ending up in like a couple of different
places some third-party systems some
systems in my control uh it's not just
like one copy of the data oh no it
sounds like the data's everywhere
everywhere uh what systems how uh can
you list them all uh yeah yeah I think I
think we can walk through this okay so
um basically the employee browse to that
admin page and that's where the data
started and then I use a third-party
testing system called xss Hunter to
manage that like screenshotting thing I
talked about
um so that from the laptop the
screenshot got sent to xss Hunter which
is not managed by me it's managed by
just like a a person yeah and then he
runs that in AWS so we have like AWS
that has a copy the a random person that
has a copy and then that emailed me a
copy of the screenshot too so I guess my
email provider has a copy and then I
downloaded a copy onto my hard drive and
then I run time machine so there's
another copy on my backup hard drive and
then I attached all of that to the bug
tracking system so there's another copy
in the bug tracking system I think
that's all of it wow okay
um let's try to delete data everywhere
you possibly can if your backups don't
roll off try to delete your backups do
some of the third parties where the
data's been captured allow you to delete
the data
oh uh that's a good question
um let me check
um so it looks like xss Hunter has a
button that says delete but there's no
like terms of service or anything like
that so I don't actually know if it is
deleting the data on the back end when I
click that button
um and then the bug platform itself
actually doesn't have a delete button so
I don't think that there's an ability
for me to delete that copy but I can
definitely delete the copy on my hard
drive I can delete the copy of my backup
and I can probably delete the Gmail copy
since Gmail terms of service says that
deletes the data when you click that
button
um
has this been resolved with a company
you know have they closed the ticket and
fixed the vulnerability
so uh yes
um they they closed the ticket but I I
still have access to the ticket
um and actually now that I'm thinking
about it um my my bug platform account
um like I'm scrolling through some of my
old submissions and I'm finding like
there there have actually been other
examples in my in my account where I've
accidentally accessed user data and it
looks like all of those old tickets
I can still log into them and still
access that data like none of it has
been cleared out of the bug system even
though the tickets were closed out as
fixed a while ago
wow I I have to imagine other bug
Hunters have this problem do they
um I can ask I know I know a couple
friends there are some proliferate bug
Hunters
um
so uh turns out I I talked to a couple
of friends that I know that are pretty
good bug hunters and a hundred percent
of them said that their bug crowd
accounts and hacker one accounts are
exactly the same when they log in they
just have like a ton of different
privacy issues that are years old and
they can still access those issues and
they can download the data yeah yeah
yeah even though the issues were closed
a while ago they still have access to
the data that they attached to the
ticket
um
maybe because these these bug tracker
systems have the ability to request
public disclosures I mean there's enough
of these examples maybe if we request
all of them some of them might actually
let us talk about this and share some of
these examples I mean it doesn't exactly
um you know it they might say no but I
mean we could try and then we could have
specific examples that we could share
with other people and bring some
visibility to this
um
oh
yeah that didn't work uh so they they
they did not allow uh us to publicly
talk about this okay well look there's a
bunch more researchers and a bunch more
tickets uh maybe if we just keep
requesting eventually we'll find some
programs that allow us to pop publicly
about these issues
I was not expecting that uh okay uh
looks like
um there there was a programmer too
that's actually going to let us talk
publicly about these issues
um that's pretty cool
neat okay so
um just wanted to maybe break the fourth
wall for a bit and highlight
um most of these requests got denied um
the vast majority of programs did not
want us talking about privacy leaks that
impacted their companies
um of the small number of companies that
approved these requests we just want to
give a huge shout out to these companies
for allowing us to talk publicly about
these issues we don't by any means mean
to shame these companies since these are
the ones that are allowing us to be
transparent and the vast majority of
these companies actually denied the
request
so with that being said
um here's a real world example of this
happening I was pen testing indeed the
job search company and a developer over
there had run a little one-off sketch
Notebook on their laptop that they had
written their own custom HTML to do some
research on some of their users and so
they pulled in a whole bunch of users
onto their local notebook it was maybe
on the order of thousands of users
uh and they insecurely rendered those
users and blind cross-site scripting
fires a screenshot gets sent up and I
accidentally end up with a whole bunch
of pii or personal data that I didn't
mean to access but I got a copy of it
and what's interesting here is that when
we requested to publicly talk about this
issue
um they said sure no problem just make
sure if you have any screenshots you
redact out any of the personal
information
um and that's super interesting because
they're kind of self-aware of the fact
that I still have maintained access to
the data through this ticket even though
the issue was closed out years ago in
this example
so three basic questions here was I ever
asked to delete data no
um do I maintain access to the data
through the ticket yes and then was
there ever a public disclosure or
notification about this data leakage not
to my knowledge and my email address was
included in the league so if they had
emailed all the people affected I
probably would have gotten an email
okay
um so here's another example um this one
is with Google
um basically a very similar situation
where an employee was doing a little
one-off
um on a script that they had written
locally they had pulled in in this case
tens of thousands of user records which
includes Pi personal information
um and in this case same deal they
insecurely rendered it screenshot got
sent up to xss Hunter and I end up with
accidentally a copy of tens of thousands
of user records
um what about in this case uh was I
asked to delete my copy of the data no
did I maintain access through the ticket
yes and in this case it uses Google's
issue tracker since they don't use a
third-party issue tracker and within
Google's issue tracker still able to log
in and access that data and do they do
any notifications not to my knowledge
again my email was in that
so that's what the story was until a
couple of days ago when I actually
shared an advanced copy of the slide
Deck with them and we got this email
back saying um we're going to actually
change some of our processes can you
please delete your copy of the data so
this issue is like two years old or
something like that and for those two
years it was never asked to delete my
copy so I had access to the ticket Etc
but as of a couple days ago as a
consequence of this talk Google is
actually changing their processes
internally and they're going to be
deleting data that's attached to tickets
which is pretty neat
okay one final example that I was going
to share with you all
um was another uh pretty large
significant company with a similar story
albeit it impacted a lot fewer user
records
um and when they got an advanced copy of
the slide deck they actually changed
their minds um they gave us preliminary
permission to talk about it and then in
the Zero Hour they said actually we're
not comfortable with you sharing this
publicly and they uh they said please uh
you know remove any information about
this book
very similar story to the others but um
can't I can't talk about this one
okay so we talked about some other
researchers
um so what's the deal there
um
I reached out to a couple of hug testers
that I knew and I said hey do any of you
have stories that you might be able to
share publicly and
um you know of those similarly most of
these stories no cannot be shared
publicly but I did find two researchers
who did have bugs that had already been
written about publicly that they already
had permission and it did impact user
data and so
um they said yeah go ahead include those
the first one is to repent tester his
name is shubs and he was doing some
testing against Uber and he found that
he could get access to others users data
through a bug in AMT script
so
um he was trying to just pull basically
like his user by putting in his name
Chubbs but as it turns out that is a
less unique name than maybe he assumed
uh and he ended up with everyone who had
the word shoves anywhere in their user
data um so he queried that name and then
came back a whole bunch of people that
just had shubs anywhere in their user
data and he ended up with a bunch of
user records unwittingly here is his
blog post that he put on asset note and
you can see he has redacted out the user
data but I asked him in the original
ticket was it redacted or did you have
the raw data and he said well the
original ticket had the raw data and I
said okay well um were you asked to
delete it he's like no I was like okay
well did you like do you still have
access to the ticket that has the raw
unredacted data and it was like I mean
yeah I can still log into it it was a
couple years ago but you know I can I
can still log into my old tickets and
then I asked okay well did they ever
notify fight the other shelves and he
was like to my knowledge the only public
disclosure that ever happened here was
the write-up that I did on my blog and
that the other services weren't notified
um similar story
um here with another prolific bug Bounty
or Sam Curry I reached out to him and
asked him if he had any stories and he
said yeah I did a write-up a little
while ago on Starbucks where I could
actually access 100 million customer
records
um and so maybe the title was a little
bit clickbait here I asked him did you
actually access 100 million records and
he was like well no I mean I proved that
I could but I didn't actually access 100
million records I accessed you know
maybe five or six people's records that
weren't mine
and it was a bunch of information that
came from those five or six records
um and I asked him the same question uh
but before I get to his answers I just
want to maybe call out here
um if it's not obvious
um I've been using Dolly to enhance some
of the imagery in this talk and I
thought this one was particularly good
uh it was basically Digital Data spills
out of coffee and I thought this was a
pretty cool image that came back from
that
um but I asked him
did you delete your copy of the data
um or were you asked to delete your copy
of the data and he said no I said if you
log into the ticket today does it still
have the unredacted data from the fiber
6 that you tested with he said yes and I
said were there ever disclosure
notifications that went out to the
people that were impacted and he said
you know not to his knowledge other than
the write-up that he did on his blog
so I think the takeaway here
um is that these are like not one-off
examples these privacy leaks in bug
bounties are actually really common and
for every example that we can share
publicly there are a hundred examples
that can't be shared publicly and so I
think it's time that we start a
conversation about it and see what we
can do to reduce the impact of some of
this
so why does it happen like why do we
have these leaks
um well sometimes uh it's an accident
right like in the example that I walked
through before with the cross site
scripting
um usually when you test blind
cross-site scripting you have no idea
where that payload is going to render
you throw it into one system sometimes
it comes out in another system you don't
really know what that screenshot is
going to be there are different ways to
test blind cross-site scripting but uh
in in general some of the most popular
ways can lead to data leakages by
accident
um so that's fairly common
but another another thing is like
sometimes it's it's not an accident
right like sometimes the researcher
um goes that extra step because they
either feel like they have to prove
impact or because honestly in this
screenshot the triager in the bug Bounty
requests that they go that extra step
and in this example this is a real
screenshot I took from my issue tracker
it said
um please prove that you can leak
sensitive information that I showed them
that you can you know have access to
this thing that's not enough please show
that sensitive data can actually be
leaked out of that
um and like have you do that without
accessing the sensitive information
um so I guess in those two Dimensions
like the first uh incentive to leak this
sensitive data is just because if the
researcher can show more impact usually
they get paid more
um so that's the way bug bounties are
set up the more impactful the bug is the
more the researcher is compensated and
so in proving that they can access other
people's data they might be showing more
impact and trying to get paid a little
more
the other incentive is from the triager
and this one is a little bit more
interesting I think the triager is often
inundated with a whole bunch of garbage
submissions basically a whole internet
of people saying I found some bug I
found this thing or whatever and the
vast majority of them are not actually
valid bugs and the triagra feels
fatigued they feel wore down and if they
were to actually run every single one of
these submissions to the ground it would
take more hours than they have in the
day and so oftentimes they'll just reply
to all of these submissions hey can you
give me a little bit more information
can you push that bug one step forward
can you show me a little bit more so
that I can get through these issues a
little bit faster because there's so
much garbage that came in so those are
the two main incentives that can play
both from the triage and the researcher
side that can lead to some of these
privacy issues
and then um you know like we mentioned
before thank you so much to the
companies that allowed us to talk
publicly about it but for every one of
those companies there are hundreds more
that will never allow us to talk
publicly about them and then beyond that
there's a universe of companies that
aren't even running bug bounties that
have these data leakages and they aren't
even notified about them because they
don't have a mechanism to have that
disclosure path
um so you know a couple things to call
out here the first is that we do believe
bug bounties are a positive force for
Change and that companies that run bug
bounties are in a better place than
companies that don't
um and the other thing to call out here
is we don't by any means mean to shame
any of the companies that we've talked
about
um because there are so many more
companies that are gonna never talk
about these things because they don't
want to ever talk about them publicly
um and in that same vein I think it's
pretty common for journalists to run
clickbait gotcha articles every time a
company does talk about an internal
incident
um here's an example of that if people
don't know um hacker one runs their own
bug Bounty for their own infrastructure
so they're a company like any other
company and they've got internal
services that they need to secure like
any other company except they've always
championed a spirit of transparency
where any bugs that they have they're
going to talk about them publicly they
believe that that's the best long-term
direction for the industry and so that's
kind of neat that they always publicly
talk about their bugs but it comes back
to bite them because every time they do
some clickbait gotcha article comes out
and says
um look look at the bad thing that
happened and that is a pressure for
other companies to not talk publicly
about their issues
and so a reframing of maybe what that
article could have looked like
um might be to say
hacker one Champions transparency and
shares an internal incident that other
companies wouldn't have otherwise shared
okay
so why should you care
um
you know data seems to be everywhere
what can we do about it can we even get
to fixing this problem the answer is
probably we're never going to get to
perfect but we can take incremental
steps to move forward
so here's one reason why you should care
about this I talked about xss Hunter as
a third party testing service that's
just maintained by a guy
um well that guy I happen to know so I
just pinged him and I said how much data
has leaked into your system like can you
just send me a screenshot of your
database so I have an idea of like how
big this is industry-wide that's the
screenshot it's 1.66 terabytes of data
that has been blind cross-site scripting
screenshots that have been sent up to
this service I mean it is a huge amount
of data sitting on this Central
point of weakness
similarly as a result of this talk I
realized my user account in the bug
systems did not have two-factor enabled
that meant that if somebody were to log
into my account
um you know the the bar for doing that
was a lot lower than it could have been
and that's probably the case for a lot
of other researchers probably a lot of
researchers run their account without a
really hardened authentication mode and
if these researchers have access to many
tickets that have many different privacy
issues
um you can see how that might be a
problem
okay
so we can tell it's a trend
um so let's try to clean up some of it
let's take some of that toxic waste to
make it a little bit uh less toxic
so let's start with the bug Bounty
program if you build it you have to
prepare for the worst so you can't go
into building a bug Bounty program
without making sure that you have the
fundamentals built first you have to be
prepared to receive the vulnerabilities
to address the issues
um to work with an attorney like myself
in your company if you have access to
one or other stakeholders in your in
your
um uh at your disposal so I'm a lawyer
I've said this already but I'm not your
lawyer so none of this should be
construed as legal advice and if there's
one thing that you take away from my
talk
to a lawyer it's not there it's not that
scary we're here to help
um and while we can't get to perfect
there are lots of opportunities for
prevention basic data governance
principles
um data life cycle best practices will
help get you there you have to think
about a bug Bounty program as a series
of data life cycle so
let's work closely uh with the privacy
and compliance teams to make sure that
you're building a bug Bounty program
with that in mind
so let's walk through where we can make
small incremental progress and steps in
each of the uh areas that Dylan outlined
in his example so first of all with the
researchers in the program create
policies asking researchers to stop
before pulling data and stick to it
right if the incentive to get paid out
is only if you're asking them to pull
extra data and you don't know what
that's going to look like you need to be
prepared for the consequences of what
that might mean for your company your
legal obligations as a company to
potentially do breach notification which
is internal
um examination that you need to do with
your legal team
think about what your end-to-end program
looks like and where data might leak and
consider that when you're communicating
with your stakeholders the first time
that your legal team hears about your
bug Bounty program should not be when
you have an issue so tell them explain
to them what you're doing there are a
lot lots of lawyers who are new in this
area who are and a lots that are
experienced if you work with them
they're going to help you build a better
bug Bounty program
so let's start with the employee laptop
first internal apps should have the same
level of security as external elaps the
type of data processed should Define the
level of security so even if it's
happening internally you need to make
sure that you're thinking about the
security on your internal apps also make
sure you're thinking about roles and
responsibilities right every time I am
the first person in my company whenever
someone's like do you need access to
this data I'm like dear God no I don't
want to be the person that causes a
potential breach or issue give me
temporary access whatever it may be so
really think about does the person need
access to hundreds of thousands of
Records do they need access to all of
the data tailor your access controls
accordingly now that's a big ask but
it's going to help in the long run and
prevent larger leaks from happening
second as we're looking at platforms
like xss Hunter and other platforms be
aware of what data they collect so as a
researcher when you're going through be
aware of what potentially might be
ending up somewhere else because a
company may come to you and say where's
the data who has it because I ask these
questions myself when I work with folks
on bug Bounty programs have you deleted
it so keep track of that so you're
prepared to answer those questions and
even if the answer is no I I don't know
if I can delete it or it's in this
program and I don't have the ability to
like fix it Etc
um so where you can go back and delete
relevant data and try to make it so if
possible you're not sending data to
places that you don't want the data to
go
for Gmail I this this is an obvious one
but it's shocking to me how many times
people just send stuff over email
um
in fact the number of times I'm asked to
send my Social Security over email is is
alarming but don't put stuff in email
just avoid it if you can
um delete the email so you don't have a
copy of in your possession if you're
thinking about how to share data with a
company you know stick it in a G Drive
Link and share the link so that the data
is not being perpetuated in various
email systems because you're going to
send it to maybe a security ad email if
there's not a bug Bounty program and now
we have data in who knows how many email
boxes because that email may have been
forwarded to an entire security team
um
in your hard drive you know as a matter
of course again this is an obvious one
but don't download anything to your
machine if possible you know if you have
to do it
um delete it when you do and delete it
after you submit it
um finally for backups have a good uh
data retention on backups let it roll
off
um Implement a data retention policy or
spot remove it from backup if necessary
I hate spot removal from backups I never
like to touch backups they're the
emergency so good retention on your
backups is really going to be the best
bet here
and then finally platforms we love the
platforms but they need to get better
um at giving their customers the ability
to do data governance in the program
um
you cannot currently delete attachments
it is difficult to automatically remove
the researcher from a ticket after it's
been closed out these platforms are
Treasure troves of personal data and
customer vulnerabilities if leaked this
could have major consequences and you
need to think through how they store and
manage this in a bug Bounty platform
and so companies if you use platforms
ask them to consider allowing you to set
a data retention policy to have more
control over your data so we're not just
adding more and more into a handful of
accounts like Dylan's where it becomes a
treasure Trove of personal data
um and then finally there are lots of
places the data could flow that we have
not mentioned here so this is just one
particular scenario the data could leak
to so many other places
so I mean what should this data flow
look like
um we talked about researcher using
access Hunter
um and that causing like a whole bunch
of issues and then there were a couple
other third-party systems involved I I
think maybe there's an opportunity here
for the platforms themselves to operate
their own testing infrastructure to be
able to consolidate all of the testing
data inside the bug platform where they
have total access to the data governance
and maybe even better usability like
push to file a ticket buttons that are
easier on the researchers as well right
now the researchers don't have what they
need to do their testing and in a lot of
cases they may not be sophisticated
enough to stand up their own
infrastructure so they're having to go
out and seek out these third parties
that aren't involved with the bug
bounties explicitly and then they get
inadvertently involved as a result of
the testing and maybe another thing to
call out is this is also an issue with
General Security testing whether that be
a
a pen tester from a professor firm or a
bug Bounty
um but we can at least solve for maybe
the 80 by consolidating the bug
platforms and having them run their own
testing infrastructure
I really hope we see uh the platforms
develop in this space it it would have a
large impact
um so maybe some of you are here to
understand what are the legal
obligations I'm sure this is what
everyone wants to know
um that's why I'm here I want to know if
I'm going to get sued well uh good news
I'm going to give you a very typical
legal answer and that is it depends
um this is there's no one clear cut this
is how you avoid legal liability you're
okay
um so let's go over a quick refresh
really high level of bug bounty in the
law so in the United States there's a
Computer Fraud and Abuse Act ooh yeah
um and uh as a result it has been used
to against security researchers in the
past
um generally bug bounties operate in
this idea of what is authorized
um so by asking and having a program you
are kind of allowing uh individual
researchers to be authorized to
potentially hack your systems in a way
that would be allowed under cfaa there
has has also been a new doj memo which
recently announced
specifically
um
that if you are hacking in good faith
the doj is not going to prosecute yay
but that good faith line could really
really vary depending on the current on
the situation so it's important to just
be thoughtful here because legal issues
happen when people get pissed at each
other that's just if people feel not
heard if they feel frustrated if they
feel like you're not coming to the table
and having a conversation with them this
is one of the reasons where like the law
starts to come into play and we don't
want it there so there are some
resources here
um that I recommend you know if you have
any questions or want to know more but
again engage your legal teams should you
have any questions or if you're a
researcher you know there are lots of
resources out there about you know kind
of best practices and I hope that you
will take some of these General
um guidelines that I'm about to give so
what are the legal obligations that's
what everyone wants to know
um
here are some company takeaways to make
sure that any data polled may not result
in any potential harm to an individual
or customer that's generally when when
somebody does do I have to do breach
notification It ultimately comes down to
um you know is there potential harm to
the individual that's the standard in
the EU that generally is what triggers a
lot of breach notifications we don't
quite have that same standard here in
the United States it has to be specific
types of data actually we live in a
53-state uh breach notification regime
um and I say 53 Virgin Islands Puerto
Rico Etc
um but make sure that um the date you
know that the data doesn't persist on
any system so you need to ask the
researcher hey please delete the data
and confirm with me in writing that you
have deleted the data you need to do
this you need to make sure that you are
mitigating any potential harm
because that relates to that legal
analysis of whether or not you have to
do breach notification and the reality
is no one wants to be harmed by this
data we want to keep it this program is
good so make sure that if you're being
asked to delete the data that you
actually do it so along those lines some
researcher takeaways Say It Don't Spray
it tell the company about the
vulnerability don't pull and spray data
to various third-party systems your hard
drive your backup Drive the bug Bounty
platform and if the company says to you
have you deleted all the copies of the
data don't say you did if it's not true
lying is not going to help you here it
is much much better to just be honest
and truthful hey here's where I think
the data is I've deleted all the data
that I can possibly delete there might
be a copy here but I I you know I can't
be sure
I guarantee those companies will work
with you to address the issue or close
out the ticket accordingly
if you used other third-party systems to
pull your data delete it we kind of
talked about that earlier but that's
really important in making sure as
you're building your kind of repertoire
of tools that you understand where data
might go and how you might be able to
govern that data accordingly
and finally the platforms you know
enable your customers to have more
control over their data in the product
um you know allow programs to set
mandatory 2fa for hackers this has been
a huge success apparently
um when implemented and we'd love to see
this more broadly used and then finally
accurately talk about your privacy
practices in your privacy statement or
in your privacy policy and if you don't
use a platform still think through how
you're sharing the data again to that
email example really make sure that
you're not spraying the data everywhere
so the general takeaways that we want
you to get from this is we love bug
bounties and we love the companies that
allowed us to talk about it and we don't
want to shame them but we're hoping to
get to a next level of conversation
about now that bug bounties are much
more prevalent that they are a must-have
for companies to triage and coordinate
vulnerabilities
um we'd really like to get to a 2.0 and
and make it a little bit better for the
users whose data is potentially leaked
so uh sounds like I might be sued if I
piss a company off but just try not to
piss anybody off
that's basically where we're Landing
I'll see you okay yeah I hope I didn't
piss any companies off by uh including
them in this talk thanks
um
thank you so much thanks everyone
[Music]