[Music]
hello black hat and thank you for
joining us on our talk on leveraging the
endpoint security framework for
Behavioral detections I'm Jaren Bradley
I'm here presenting with my co-worker
Matt benyo we both work at jamf threat
Labs where we focus on finding new ways
to detect malicious activity on Mac OS
devices over the past few years this has
meant leaning pretty heavily into the
apple and Point Security framework and
today we wanted to share a bit about
where we've found success with
monitoring for applications that are
behaving in ways that they shouldn't be
so if you're here there's a good chance
that you probably know a thing or two
about the endpoint security framework
but regardless of your level of exposure
we're going to take a step back and put
it into context so what is the endpoint
security framework
so if you're building an endpoint
security tool for an operating system
you really need two basic things the
first is a source of information about
events that are happening in the
operating system that feeds into your
analysis and detections
and the second is the ability to act on
detections to exert Authority that could
be killing a process or preventing a
file from being deleted or modified and
so on
and historically the kernel the heart of
the operating system is the place where
we would go to access this data and
exert this Authority
so until recently if you're developing
an endpoint security tool for Mac OS
you'd build a kernel extension and you
had at your disposal to do so the open
BSM audit Trail for your event
information you had the chaos kernel
programming interface for your controls
which was a bit limited and there's also
the mandatory Access Control framework
which had the controls that vendors are
looking for but it was unsupported
undocumented and ostensibly off limits
to anyone but Apple
so the thing is even by Apple's
admission kernel extensions are
difficult to develop and maintain and
ultimately they can create new security
vulnerabilities because even a minor bug
can lead to things like kernel panics
so these limitations really have served
as a big obstacle to innovation in Mac
OS security so
in an effort to secure their kernel to
give security vendors what they need to
build Tools in 10.15 apple introduced
the endpoint security framework
and in doing so they are effectively
serving up in user space and event info
Rich event information source and the
controls to act on detections all
without adding any additional
instability in the kernel
so instead of
kernel extensions vendors can now build
system extensions that exist in user
space
and the way this works is that when an
event occurs
the kernel sends information to all of
the third-party system extensions that
are subscribed to a particular event
things like process creates and exits
file creates unlinks Mount events that
type of stuff
most ESF events come in two different
varieties you have notification events
and you have authorization events they
both deliver the same information but
notify events are simply meant to inform
so they let the system extension know
that Something's Happened and the system
extension can use that information in
whatever way it sees fit maybe it pops
an alert to a console or maybe it's
forwarding data to a Sim
by contrast authorization events
actually hold up activity at the kernel
so the extension evaluates event data
with its detection logic and determines
whether this process should proceed
when an event fails the system extension
checks the system extension sends the
deny response and the operation is
terminated now of course this is just a
visual representation for illustration
as the window for all this to occur is
incredibly brief to maintain performance
and user experience
so static detections have been around
since the early days of antivirus and
they continue to stick around because
they're an effective means of detecting
malware based on the way the auth events
work ESF complements static base
blocking very nicely while the execution
of event is on hold a third-party
extension can quickly scan it decide
whether or not to allow it to execute
um so what are the some of the static
behaviors that can be scanned in this
small time window well it can be a
variety of things but if we're going to
prevent something we better be really
sure that it's uh not something I should
be allowed to run because once again the
last thing we want to do is ruin the
user's Mac OS experience so for this
reason uh traditional kind of indicators
of compromise work really well team IDs
or developers that have been identified
as malicious in the past uh is a is an
easy thing to quickly look up and block
file hashes you know file Fingerprints
of known malware and then of course Yara
rules work fantastic as well allowing us
to scan for byte byte patterns or
strings and and blocking if we see ones
that we don't like there's of course
other options such as machine learning
algorithms but again ultimately whatever
you end up testing against needs to
return a result almost instantly
so this leads naturally to the focus of
our talk which is behavioral detections
and this idea of a behavioral detection
has been around for a while and they've
increased in value as security vendors
have really refined uh developing a
baseline of what normal application
activity looks like as opposed to things
that are more suspicious or nefarious
so the downside to this type of a
detection is that they tend to have a
higher false positive ratio because
we're looking at a broader pattern of
activity as opposed to something more
objective like a file hash
but when these are executed correctly
it's a worthy trade-off because it
allows us to identify things like
malware that we haven't seen before or
activity patterns that really haven't
been seen before
so to give an example
um we'll call this one a fake file
extension and we'll start with something
really straightforward here so in this
example a user goes to finder in their
temp directory and they discover
a PDF called a DOT PDF now a single
letter PDF in the temp file is probably
weird enough to detect on on its own but
we can take a closer look at this and
when they examine this file they would
discover that this is actually a Mako
executable
so
masquerading file extensions using
contradictory file extensions in this
way is one of the oldest tricks in the
book uh attackers will use this method
to try and blend in with the user's
files or the operating system and
somewhat ironically these kind of cheap
evasive maneuvers lead to some of our
best detections because they're hard to
justify in a benign context
so as you can see all we really did here
was take the behavior of a file being
created or written to Temp and perform
some additional checks to determine if
it was actually of any interest so truth
be told like benyo said some of these
might be interesting by themselves for
instance a PDF extension on an
executable it's probably a detection by
itself but if we want to take additional
kind of odd behaviors like oh this is
this is in the temp directory or this
has a single letter file name these are
all just kind of strange things if we
want to further kind of enhance and
tighten up detections we could look for
multiple things like this to create one
detection
we'll demonstrate a slightly more
in-depth example of one of these
detections with something we call p-list
disguised as Apple
so inside of the system Library launch
agents directory a launch agent is
something that will run generally run at
startup on the system when your system
boots and here we have what a launch
agent should look like
This one belongs to the Mac OS diagnose
agent we actually tell this by simply
looking at the file name Apple
encourages developers to follow suit and
name all launch agents and daemons using
a reverse domain name notation so by
looking at the file called
com.apple.diagnose agent.plist we should
immediately know that this P list is
part of the operating system and belongs
to Apple so a long time ago malware
authors caught on to this fact as well
so they began calling their malicious
demons and
agents.com.apple.fill in the blank
causing those agents to blend in with
the operating system as well
so if we look inside this file we see
that this agent will launch this
diagnose helper this is an uh this
executable is an apple binary and
properly signed by Apple as it should be
so let's take a look at how this can be
counterfeited or abused by attackers so
what we'll be looking for is in the user
launch agents or launch demons directory
an addition of a new plist that's the
first thing we detect on but then we
look to see are they using a com.apple
identifier in the file name and truth be
told we could stop right here if there's
something that's outside of the sit
protected system launch agents directory
and it's in the users folder that's
probably suspicious enough to take a
look at but we have found some false
positives that hit this so we can refine
this detection by doing some additional
checks so what we do is we look at that
P list and we scope in on the executable
that this intends to run at login and
that's going to give us a path so we can
go to the executable at that path and we
can run a code signing check and if this
is something that's using a com.apple p
list we should hope or expect that this
is an executable that's also owned by
Apple and in this case the code signing
information comes back is unsigned and
that is highly suspicious something that
we can confidently trigger a detection
on for further analysis
so this has been a really reliable
detection over the years it is worth
pointing out though that when this these
days when we see this triggered it's
generally one of the newer Espionage
focused applications this is something
that adware used to do a lot but I think
that they spend so much time in the
trenches and they've been caught by so
many different security products using
this technique that's something that
they've moved away from
so so far we've talked quite a bit about
different behaviors and checks to
perform with file activity let's get
into a bit of background on what
suspicious process activity looks like
so we're going to give an example here
by showing off a single exec event let's
say that you're maybe a threat Hunter
you're in Splunk and you encounter a
process execution events in this example
we're just demoing with a simple cut
command
so for those that aren't familiar with
the cut command it's generally used to
splice data passed to it from another
command by itself it really tells us
absolutely nothing we're going to show
here how we can use other fields in this
event to get the context of what's
happening on the system
so next we'll use the parent process ID
and grab the process that ran the cut
command it it's primarily a tool meant
to be used within a shell so it comes as
no surprise that the parent is zsh in
this case where we really start to gain
some useful context here is when we take
this same event and we look up the
responsible PID which in this case
points to terminal dot app as we can see
this process ID starts to paint a better
picture so far we've determined that the
user opened a terminal their shell of
choice is the default zsh and they
executed cut however as I stated earlier
this still there's still more to this
picture and cut by itself isn't super
helpful to us but at least we know that
this was likely a user because it was
executed through a terminal GUI
application
but uh by taking the process group ID
value in this event we can determine
what the process group ID leader of this
command was
this PID value is fairly uh fairly well
known
um
but it gets less attention than it
deserves in fret hunting not only can we
grab what process was at the front of a
set of piped commands in this case
system profiler but we can also perform
a search to see all processes that share
this same process group ID essentially
rebuilding the exact command that was
executed so this approach can't always
be taken as we're demoing an example
here where a standard job control
behavior is in place but overall this is
a pretty good way to go about getting
the context of how a group of commands
was executed in this case we can see
that the executed command was one that
gets used to grab a Serial ID of the
device it's run on and it gets used by
both legitimate apps and scripts as well
as some malware performing Recon
a session is a collection of process
groups and a session ID points us to the
process that's in control of those
groups and this is where we can kind of
go and get some additional context of
what actually ran inside the terminal
so in this case it belongs to the login
process which the terminal runs upon
execution before the shell is chosen
so from a single event that shows a
simple cut command occurring we were
able to use all the PID fields to
determine the exact context of what's
happening and then with some simple
lookups we can even sort out the command
history that ran here in this terminal
so let's take a look at an attack
behavior that can be uncovered using
some of these techniques that we just
discussed
so in this particular demonstration
we're looking at a popular form of a
living off the land technique so in this
technique the attacker will host a
script on their server and they will
curl that down on the victim machine but
pipe it directly to an interpreter on
the system
the reason that this is an attractive
technique is because in doing so no
malicious files exist on the disk
therefore you can really sidestep most
static detections this way as the script
really only exists in memory
now while this doesn't create files it's
not entirely untraceable if you have
that URL and the server still up you
could go for example this is the Mythic
agent that would be hosted on This
Server by Cody Thomas that's still
available but you're creating that extra
step and really going to sidestep any
detections aren't looking for this type
of a technique specifically
so if we now look for applescript which
is The Interpreter in this case being
run and we check for it in the process
history
we'll see that it's running with no
arguments it's just running as Osa
script
so to use ESF data to track this type of
activity what we would look for is the
execution of The Interpreter in this
case Osa script or apple script and if
you look down below in the command you
would see that it has no path to a
script no additional commands which is a
pretty good giveaway that whatever is
running this the script was piped
directly to The Interpreter in this way
so the way that we can start to uncover
this of what piped to Osa script is by
looking at that process group ID so if
we follow that process group ID we see
that it leads us
to the curl command
and once we have this link we are
confident that this type of a living off
the land technique was being used at
least to the point of popping an alert
for further analysis
so let's walk through another sample
that drives home the use case of once
again the process group ID
uh Spotlight is functionality on Mac OS
that indexes files and documents as
they're created it does this by indexing
it does this indexing by taking keywords
uh found in those documents and making
them easily findable in a search so when
you press command and spacebar you can
punch in a keyword and easily find the
document you were looking for even if
you can't remember where you saved it
this is a super useful feature I use it
all the time but any feature that's
useful for us is generally also useful
for an attacker
so mdfind is the command line equivalent
of using this Spotlight functionality so
an attacker can easily search for
different keywords and attempts to try
and find files on the hard drive that
contain these keywords such as maybe
password routing and account or
confidential
so an attacker once on the system might
use a command that looks something like
this where basically they run mdfind
they get a list of files back that
contain the word confidential and then
they take each one of those files and
pipe them immediately to an archive and
now they just have to X fill that
archive and they have a giant archive
full of confidential files
so in order to detect this happening
what we would look for is the execution
of one of the built-in archive Tools in
this example it's tar so then the next
question is we ask what is the process
group idea of this tar execution and in
this case following this process group
ID would lead us naturally to MD find
and when this link has been made we can
be reasonably confident that tar was run
at a string of commands that started
with mdfine and this technique was
likely being used to the point where we
can pop an alert for further analysis
it's worth pointing out though that this
technique while interesting is limited
to what's available uh outside of the
full disk aspect asset aspect of the
transparent transparency consent and
controls there's still some useful
things we'll get a little bit more into
TCC in one of our advanced detections
so we've talked a bit about what we'd
call Standard detections now we'd like
to get in some detections that require
significantly more checks to determine
applications uh behaving Anonymous
anonymously all three detections we'll
talk about here were developed after we
discovered or learned about a zero day
vulnerability and then we went and found
a way to detect those vulnerability if
those vulnerabilities were ever abused
so everything we'll cover here has since
been patched
but we still wanted to make sure before
those patches occurred that we were
detecting them should it happen
so the first we're going to touch on is
a gatekeeper bypass from a while back so
a number of different bypasses have come
to lights over the course of this year
revolving around file quarantine and
gatekeeper these are both security
features built into Mac OS that exist to
help users ensure they're only running
code that's properly been signed by a
trusted developer and notarized in this
slide we see that a user is downloaded
and ran an app called toxic.app this
would result
um
uh in this gatekeeper prompt uh of
something like this primarily because
the app is completely unsigned and
therefore untrusted
so last year Cedric Owens discovered a
method that allowed apps to incorrectly
pass gatekeeper checks he actually did
talk about this here at black hat
um so we created a detection when we
heard about this vulnerability and soon
discovered a variant of the Slayer
malware abusing it in the wild
so before abusing this bypass Slayer
developers had to convince you to
override gatekeeper because they didn't
want to sign the malware they would
convince users to override gatekeeper by
literally providing instructions for the
override process within their installer
graphics
so this simply consists of
right-clicking the application selecting
open rather than double clicking on it
it seems very basic but we see users
fall for this all the time
we do see that this still results in
some prompts informing the user that
this app was downloaded from the
internet but ultimately they're given
the option to go forward with it if
they'd like to when right clicking on
the app
so that's what the old Slayer malware
installer looked like here's what the
Slayer malware with gatekeeper with the
gatekeeper bypass embedded in it looked
like
uh it's just a simple double click on
the downloaded application and it's game
over for the user they didn't have to
write click the application nor click
through various prompt warnings uh this
completely unsigned malware would
execute and perform a bunch of
background activities while the user was
none the wiser
an additional note to make here is that
although this looked like a PKG
installer it was actually just a
weaponized application that used a PKG
icon but how did the bypass actually
work it worked in cases where an
application did not contain an
info.plist file
uh and it used a script as its primary
payload so if these two things were true
it would be given a stamp of approval
from the gatekeeper Security check and
it would be allowed to execute
so let's rewind a little bit and think
about
how we could actually detect this so
first of all when an application is
launched by double clicking it sends a
message to launch D which then goes on
to open the application so that's the
thing that we would look for is launch D
being the parent process now obviously
most of the processes are running on the
system have a parent of launch D but by
including this in the detection we can
reduce false positives so our next check
is to be checking to ensure that we're
actually dealing with an application
bundle this can be done by analyzing the
command line while the app was double
clicked
but what we can do very easily is look
for this Telltale string in the command
line arguments of dot app slash contents
slash Mac OS if we see this string we're
confident that we're dealing with an
application
so next we're going to ensure that the
process that was running was actually a
built-in interpreter so what we did was
we essentially looked for any of the
built-in interpreters at the time there
were a couple more that have since been
deprecated but these are all the ones
that are available and in the Slayer
example it was actually bash that was
running
so the next thing we'll do is we want to
make sure since a requirement of this
bypass was that the executable was a
script we'll look at the executable to
ensure that it wasn't some type of a
macho binary that it was actually a
script so you could do this via API
check magic bytes whatever your
particular flavor is
and then lastly we want to make sure
that we're catching this at the moment
that it's being looked at by gatekeeper
and for this we relied on a particular
Quirk of Gatekeepers so to mitigate a
different vulnerability when you double
click on an application that's in
something like a DMG gatekeeper will
actually move that to a randomized file
path to prevent it from accessing
external resources and this particular
feature is called app translocation
so that's what we'll look for to ensure
that this is happening at the moment of
a gatekeeper inspection that will
incorrectly pass checks
so let's take a quick look at what all
this looks like from an ESF perspective
notice here that we can almost do all
the checks required once again by
pivoting around on a single exec event
so the first thing we're going to do is
check that the parent is launch d
uh next we're going to take a look at
the command line arguments and make sure
a application is referenced within them
uh instead of checking the command line
arguments we could also check the script
field that ESF provides on execution uh
but uh in this case we do see that the
application is referenced inside the
command line arguments so next we'll
grab the path of the executable being
exact to see if it matches an
interpreter language which in this case
it does we see that it's been Bash
and then we will take the application
from the command line arguments and
check to ensure that it's not a macho as
of course for this bypass we only care
about scripts because that's all that
worked
so finally as mentioned before uh we're
going to check that this app is being
analyzed by gatekeeper as we only want
to trigger at the time that the
gatekeeper bypass is occurring so you
can actually use a script as your main
payload in an application Apple does
allow for that uh but when when
something like this happens we want to
trigger on this at the time of bypasses
if the user still continues to want to
run this in the future that's that's up
to them
so this is the detection we put into
action when we heard the zero day
existed and almost immediately as we
pushed it out we detected the Slayer
malware uh dropper triggering in various
environments which tells us malicious
authors do see value in evading these
gatekeeper checks and do see value in
not having to take the time to sign code
or pay for any type of you know code
signing fee
so next we're going to touch on a TCC
bypass which we hinted at a little bit
earlier as we showed
um earlier TCC is uh is kind of a
feature where users can grant specific
applications permissions to do specific
things such as capture keyboard input
record the mic or record the screen so
when an application attempts to perform
an action such as record the screen the
user is prompted asking if they want to
approve this action for the application
so perhaps one of the more concerning
times where we've seen this prompt
bypassed was in the Wild by the XCS set
malware zero day usage isn't new for
this malware in fact it was using two
other zero days at the time as well
specifically we're going to focus in on
the Zero date it would attempt to use in
order to gain screen sharing permissions
uh the malware would start by looking
for a list of various applications that
already exist on the system and likely
hold that screen recording permission in
the malware code it referred to these
applications as donor apps
among these applications was of course
Zoom since at this point many users have
had installed zoom on on their systems
to remotely share their screens and for
that purpose it would have the screen
sharing permission already uh what the
app malware authors discovered is that
if they placed an application bundle
within an already existing application
bundle
we'll call this
update.app in this case they could
actually piggyback off the permissions
of that the existing bundle held
so if we go back to the TCC settings
this is effectively what would now be
taking place however the piggybacking
application would gain the permissions
it would gain the permissions but it
would not show up in this list of
software as able to do so so uh now all
the attacker had to do was record the
screen and no prompts would be displayed
to the user I think an important
takeaway here is that many don't think
anyone's going to take the time on Mac
OS to bypass these type of restrictions
when in fact malware has already taken
the time to try and find ways around
this to remain more stealthy this was
all also done via applescript malware by
the way which uh some some might argue
makes this even more impressive
so when this malware runs it will
trigger an endpoint security framework
exec event
and the way that we would detect this is
to look for that application being
opened and we'd look at the path to
First determine that we're dealing with
an application
and the next thing we'll check to see is
to see is that application nested inside
of another application
now keep in mind Zoom is just the
example here in theory it could be any
application that had the desired TCC
permissions
so now that we have an outer app and an
inner application we can start to treat
those as two separate things and it's
worth pointing out that it's totally
legal for developers to do this it's
it's a normal behavior to put one app
inside of another application however we
would expect that the signing
information of those two applications
would match so that's how we were able
to look for this being done illicitly so
you check the donor application give it
a code signing check in this case it's
the Zoom app it's a price surprise it's
signed by Zoom legitimately so then next
we want to check the inner application
and we should expect that also to be
signed by Zoom if this is a legitimate
update app and in the case of the XCS at
malware it came back as signed ad hoc
which was a huge red flag
so that's the detection we're looking
for an application being executed we're
looking for that application to be
nested inside of another application
then we check the outer application
signing information and see that it's
legitimate and for the inner application
when we check that signing information
if it's illegitimate we'd see one of
three cases a mismatched team ID that
doesn't match the outer app signed ad
hoc or not signed at all and if those
conditions are met we confidently pop an
alert for further analysis
so let's talk about one last gatekeeper
bypass that we were able to detect and
this vulnerability was actually found by
jamf's own for Dao seljuki and he was
attributed on a cve when this was
patched by Apple
so to understand this particular bypass
we first have to quickly break down some
of the basics of how Safari works so
when Safari is used to download a file
especially something like a zip file
with an application in it you may have
noticed that it hits the downloads
folder and is almost instantaneously
unzipped this is the default behavior
and this is part of a feature in Safari
called open safe files for downloading
it's what Apple deems to save files and
probably part of the thinking around
this is something like an application
while it feels like a file is actually a
directory bundle and can't be downloaded
directly so often you'll see
applications that are zipped up in this
way and using this Auto unzip feature
kind of abstracts that away so it feels
uh more logical to an end user
so if we quickly rewind uh once again
and then watch all of this in slow
motion using the endpoint security
framework what we would actually see is
that after the archive download occurs
Through Safari the Safari sandbox is
actually what's responsible for creating
a temporary directory and then handling
the unzipping of that archive into that
directory
so the Safari sandbox then takes the
quarantine extended attribute and
applies it to the newly unzipped
application
this part's actually very important
because when an application is opened
for the first time its extended
attributes are checked by the system if
this quarantine extended attribute is on
the opened application the system knows
that it needs to be checked by
gatekeeper upon its first launch
so while we're browsing the internet in
search of malware we encountered a
Gaming website that was hosting games in
application form via zip archives so
after we downloaded these games we
noticed that they were somehow bypassing
Gatekeepers prompts despite being
completely unsigned so after further
investigation we actually noticed that
the extended attribute was not being
placed on the application directory
itself it was only being applied to the
recursive contents under that app and as
it turns out gatekeeper only cares about
whether that application has a
quarantine mark on it or not
so we notice that this wasn't actually
happening if we downloaded the
application via another browser and then
unzipped it manually all the quarantine
attributes would appear as expected in
in this type of scenario
so this told us the issue lied somewhere
in the Safari Auto unzipper itself
not only that but we also noticed that
if we used Apple's built-in ditto
command to unzip our own archive it
would also result in the same quarantine
bug this told us the bug likely goes
much deeper on the operating system
somewhere as it was affecting at least
two different unarchiving Technologies
so as it uh as it turned out this issue
existed within the bill of materials
functionality a bill of materials is
think of it like a receipt for all files
that maybe an installer or archive
leaves on the system logically this
receipt technology ties really well to
PKG installers uh however Mac OS also
builds references builds and references
uh a bomb for zip files as well it's
just not very well documented anywhere
so upon unarchiving the application from
a normal zip file the bomb seen on the
right here will keep track of each file
that gets unarchived the unarchiving
logic then goes through each file uh in
the bomb and applies the quarantine
attribute fittingly
so one big thing we noticed analyzing a
normal zipped application in a hex
editor is that the first zip file header
starts at the root application directory
the quarantine attribute would always be
applied as expected in this case but the
zip files we are downloading from the
internet were unknowingly bypassing
gatekeeper
and on the other hand they were missing
this root level header
and instead they started at the
applications contents directory
so if we take one of these modified zip
files and remove the top level header
we see here that when the bomb gets
parsed once again on the right
the application root directory would be
missing from the bomb however the
application would continue to unzip and
operate normally
but when the copy quarantine function
gets referenced and it references the
bill of materials to apply the
quarantine attributes it ends up missing
the app directory itself since the bill
of materials at this point was out of
sync
so using the endpoint security framework
again is our foundation how do we go
about detecting this occurring
so we start by looking for a file rename
event we're looking for that moment when
the Safari sandbox broker is moving from
its temp file the new application back
to the downloads folder
then we ensure that it's actually the
Safari sandbox broker that's taking the
action
and then we make we make sure that it's
actually an application that's in
question that's being moved
then we make sure that the original
location is the temporary directory that
the sandbox broker creates when it's
unzipping the file and moving it back to
downloads and then finally we do an
extended attribute lookup to ensure that
the quarantine attribute was actually
applied
so this detection is interesting because
by looking over the shoulder of the
built-in security and ensuring that it's
doing its job as expected we can
generically detect when a gatekeeper
bypass has occurred even if we don't
know what the technique is all we're
looking for is an application that's
being downloaded by the Safari sandbox
broker and yet somehow came away without
a quarantine attribute and really I
think this highlights the beauty of
these behavioral detections because they
can allow us to pick up on techniques
that we haven't even uncovered yet
so that kind of wraps up our talk uh
what we show today is simply one piece
of tooling that feeds off events
provided by the endpoint security
framework but what's great about ESF is
that Apple can focus on providing
visibility into the operating system and
developers can get the power to decide
what should be done with this
information and build detections engines
as well as anything else they can think
of more than anything it's just nice to
have these events that we use come from
that that used to come from various
complex sources now be streamlined in an
organized fashion from Apple so we can
focus on using the events rather than
having to worry about creating them
ourselves and that's what we had thanks
so much for having us
foreign
[Music]