[Music]
foreign
you may or may not know it but you are
sitting in the largest lock note session
ever by far and we're all suitably
impressed that so many people turned out
for us so there's like no pressure here
[Laughter]
in our overseas events sort of as a
corollary to Keynote lock note and we
were really trying to create a nice kind
of anticlimactic way to wind down the
conference with some insights from the
people
who took all the time out of their
personal lives to actually review and
help select the content
and so it's a great way to say well this
is how you thought the sessions might
turn out or these are the trends you
thought were important now that you've
done it
how does it feel what what did you gain
as an inside you know what did you think
and the other idea is we're going to try
to run this like a conversation where
you're sitting there in the audience and
we're all friends and we're having a
conversation and you're sort of
listening in
and then further on in a session we'll
try to open it up we have a microphone
here in the middle and we'll take
questions from you and sometimes it's
interactive we'll ask people to raise
their hands if we're like trying to
argue over something one year was nobody
buys deception services
somebody else said no I think some
people so we asked the audience one
person bought deception services
don't invest in that
I think that's going to work out very
well
so I'm going to introduce our panel here
and then I want to kind of kick it off
with some questions and away we go ready
you bet okay on my right we have Chris
Eng from Vera code long time I'm looking
I think we switched so now we've now
we've messed it all up I'm sorry I kind
of look the same but I give that
confused as well it was just a test if
you remember stage right Zoom for so
long
um from Vera code long time contributor
in security space
um and on the United States on the U.S
briefings review board
okay and then we have Natalie solvanovic
from Google also on the U.S briefings
review board
uh we've got Justine bone from medsec
and she's on the ciso review board and
the US briefings review board and then
on my
my right your left
Matt swish from magnet forensics and
he's on the United States review board
and also our European review board okay
so I'm just going to quickly start
with Chris and just say a little bit
about like maybe your area that you're
really interested in like what you pay
attention to because you can't all pay
attention to the submissions there are
what how many submissions how many
hundred thousand a thousand to a
thousand yeah over a thousand
submissions and you can't do that
without your eyes bleeding right so what
is your approach let's start off with
Chris well mine was uh application
security it's been my focus in my career
for the past 20 years and so I've had
the fortune to be the track lead for
application security this year it's been
called app stack it's been called sdlc a
few different things in the past but
um just amazing amazing submissions that
we get in application security
everything which covers a pretty wide
gamut right everything from sdlc and CI
CD pipelines to web 3 and just standard
web attacks that's a big big category so
I spent most of my time during this show
almost going exclusively to apps track
abstract talks because uh you know
that's that's kind of what I want that's
your jam and I want to make sure we're
picking correctly and I think you know I
think how do you tell I mean is it based
on how many heads are in the room that
doesn't seem like a great metric or how
do you get a good feedback a feel if you
did right
yeah it's it's uh sometimes like title
selection is very hard yeah we find and
so you you know you can have the most
amazing technical content and then you
don't have a great title you may not get
a lot of people in the room but you know
the good thing is you can always go back
and watch those later yeah and and find
out and you hear you know I like to go
to Twitter and just find out see what
people are chattering about and see oh I
missed that one looks like it was you
know better than the abstract made it
out to be so I'll go back and watch it
on YouTube or watch it on the website
I'm going to make an assumption and I
hope I'm improved wrong but my
assumption is Google Natalie app set
uh yes
or cloud or what is it what is it you
you like to yeah so I leave the hardware
track so
um at Black Cat I really love going to
the hardware talks these will range from
subtle and interesting CPU bugs to
hacking crazy wild targets like cars or
satellites by day I'm on Project zero at
Google so I'm also super interested in
exploit development and how to get code
execution on all sorts of targets
so it's at variety like you're looking
for some uniqueness there right not
necessarily the micro optimization in
some exploit chain you want to see
something new and exciting yeah I always
feel like I get the best ideas for new
bugs and new exploits from black hat I
love seeing uh yeah new stuff
all right let's talk uh over to Justine
tell us a little bit yes so gone to my
hardware and upset days Once Upon a Time
sure but today I'm on the policy track
um and so when I look at this is that
another word for management wow story of
my life right here yeah um so it's it's
quite tricky though with the briefings
reviews because you know you've got a
very technical audience and you're
looking at policy submissions so you've
got to try to find that content that's
relevant to technical folks but is still
talking about policy so I try to look
for things that are disruptive ideas
um disruptive like I've got something
crazy here on fire and therefore or
disruptive but realistic but perhaps
slightly out there ideas not clickbaity
no I'll never yeah no no no you're never
going to get away with that and then but
um you know there were a couple for
example that
um once again Revisited vulnerability
disclosure but they were slightly
outside the box there was one
presentation about vulnerability
disclosure on the blockchain
yes yes so so things like that that
maybe bring together you know some level
of innovation and Technology along with
a policy idea but in addition of course
with the with the CSO Summit
um it's a lot easier to consider policy
or strategy or you know governance
issues because that's the audience so do
you find yourself
for the briefings focusing on sort of
like tactical policy and for the ciso
more like strategic exactly or a policy
that will impact
the you know in a in a tactical way a
more technical room you know so this is
a policy shift that might impact my my
role as a security analyst or as an
expert or as a security researcher as
opposed to a policy that might influence
a change in corporate governance or you
know regulation or something like that
right excellent okay I do miss those
Hardware on Epic days I'll get back
Matt uh with the word magnet forensics I
think I have a lead on what you're
interested in yeah I mean I've always
been involved with the dfil track uh but
as you all know like we often happen to
be in multiple tracks to help other
people to review the submissions because
we get so many yeah uh I mean the
exploit development one is cool like the
platform security one is pretty cool uh
application security School although no
we don't know if production stuff is
maybe like web free security letter you
know you and I want to talk about web3 I
mean I think we should I think we should
have a new like track in the next few
years
you're saying all these things are cool
it's like is there anything not cool
can we do like a hands up on we're sure
and blockchain like who would like to
see a blockchain trick
a web free security track I like the
name better okay
I think you have to Define what web3 is
yeah we'll do that besides unicorn
like 700 million dollars you know for it
you know it's bigger than the Central
Bank there are a lot of security
Consulting companies making a lot of
money from with three bucks right now
yeah
awesome awesome so I'm glad we sorted
that yeah okay so so that's your jam
you're into as long as the technical
presentations like
um especially uh when you go to a
conference you like to select technical
content
if it can be a blog post you know that
should not be a presentation it's
usually like my decision tree you know
should that be a blog post and I can
just read it at home or is it really
worth attending the presentation right
for me it's one of the biggest like
decision maker but just like Chris you
know I like to watch like the slides and
the presentations like later because
it's impossible to see everything so
when you're doing your sort of mental
filtration it sounds like you've got one
of your first hurdles is can this be a
well-written blog post if yes 100 write
the blog post yeah and if not it has to
have something additional yeah one of
the things I like to think about too is
are you elevating the speaker by giving
them a stage right is this a person a
group a community you want to put on a
stage in front of other people
um basically be implicitly endorsing
them and it seems like this is a concern
that's newer before it was just purely
look at the technical yeah and now we're
having to look at more aspects right
yeah
um so I'm wondering does anybody else
have your sort of You Must Be This Tall
I I try to I try to you know address
bias right and I tried my my sort of
methodology is
you know obviously focus on the content
and I almost don't want to know who's
submitted this and you know where they
work and whether you know I've heard of
them before or anything like that and I
thought so I try to go through the
content first and then if I'm asking
myself more questions I'll go back and
say are they incredible okay let's read
through bio or you know but we shouldn't
be you know obviously stopping
opportunity for people who are new to
presenting right um so at Defcon we have
an ability to submit anonymously so if
you don't want any of that to be
considered yeah
um that gives some people some
confidence to submit that normally might
not yeah yeah but it's hard because
there are also people with amazing track
records you're consistently producing
that always produce you know and we come
here to see these people present so
right the Dan Kaminsky track
yeah when Dan would submit basically you
knew you were accepting Dan yeah I look
for practicality a lot more than I think
that I used to
um I mean what changed then well I think
you know if you go back to the early
days there was definitely a lot of uh
you know you have to get the headline
you have to get the coverage of this
really cool hack this really cool
exploit that's that's coming out at
Black Cat and there's going to be this
this big media blitz around it and while
there you know there is still some of
that you know as the profession has
turned into something that's a little
bit more disciplined and it's you know
so multi fasted
I feel like there has to be a takeaway
there has to be something more than
like this person did this really cool
hack
that's great and more than the
celebration of the feet exactly yeah how
do I Advance the state of the art back
you know when I go back home to my to my
organization right what do I do and so
you know
that's that's accomplished by some of
these talks like you know James Kettle
is always pushing the boundaries like
here's a here's another new way that
HTTP is broken
that that breaks all assumptions that
then every pen tester can go back and
use starting like probably tomorrow it
pushes the state of the art it lets you
find new things that you didn't know
about before right anything you know
that's a tool even or a new practice or
a new way of thinking about something
you can take back yeah there may be a
cool hack along with that but if there's
a good technique that you can then go
add to your Arsenal I feel like there
has to be some kind of practical
takeaway yeah
and every single every single thing that
I that I review yeah yeah I definitely
find that with the hardware track like
there definitely is like the call of the
cool like the wow you know they made
that cars windshield wipers flip back
and forth and certainly
um that that is part of the hardware
track and I kind of feel like maybe
every year there's one talk we pick just
because the target is like so awesome
that um
maybe we're less concerned about
concerned about the technical stuff but
then there's so many other cool things
yeah for example there was lots of fault
injection this year lots of CPU bugs and
while those are also very cool they just
don't have the same same large appeal
same almost spectacular and some of the
other submissions and your track is um
is it sort of like a when there used to
be sort of an iot track we there's be
like iot junk hacking we'd call it oh
another embedded system running another
ancient you know it's like it doesn't
matter what it's running it's the same
system that's you know so we'd call it
junk hacking it's the same sort of thing
happening now it's sort of like somebody
learns a technique and now 30 people
submit on that technique so it's hard to
weed out the ones that actually are
doing the unique thing yeah that's
definitely
definitely kind of apply the same
two new targets and then there's the
ones that actually have new stuff in
them yeah
so
favorite talks things that wild you
things that didn't surprise you
you know
so when I think about
um
it's not you know
the ciso summit operates under Chatham
House Rules so it's it's a very safe
space for csos to share their
insecurities and raise questions and
kind of think about existential issues
you know you you're you're csos that
perhaps you work with might appear to be
super confident and know how to solve
every problem but believe me when they
get together in the ciso summit there's
a lot of insecurity and questioning
um and we you know we ask ourselves
questions like where do we belong in an
organization and
um is you know we you know we understand
cyber security no longer just a
technical issue so one of the awesome
Concepts that we talked about this time
actually was cyber security belonging to
the ESG initiative of a company the
environmental social governance
component of a company as opposed to
cyber security as a technical
responsibility which was
um rather an out there concept to be I I
don't know I want to think halvar but it
wasn't halvar but somebody was did the
company the the
the I think it was the Specter or the
Meltdown CPU microcode patch
added something like one to two percent
extra CPU cycles and somebody calculated
the carbon load of how much more
pollution that's a very literal right
like Amazon is now putting out 69 000
more tons like a bug and an ESG impact
right and so when I hear this I think
that's probably not far out there I bet
in the future when you're reading about
the impacts you're also going to see and
99 new tons of something or other on the
Azure Cloud yeah real cost a lot of it
was about you know um sharing
responsibility and less sort of
centralized cyber security oversight so
for example there's always that
conversation about cyber security in the
boardroom and now we've got the SEC
saying that you know companies should
have cyber security expertise in the
boardroom but the interesting problem
that we've got to be cognizant of is if
we've got this sort of concentrated
cyber security expert you know one of us
we're sitting now on the board of
directors the risk with that is the rest
of the board will kind of Point
responsibility for cyber security to
that person and not share that risk
across the board and across the whole
leadership of the company which is
really how things should be so a lot of
talk about sort of centralized ownership
and management of cyber security as
opposed to everything being shared plus
they're probably really excited to see
each other after two years
also a very full room yeah yeah I just
kind of show from hands how many people
by showbands did not expect so many
people to be be here
I did not yeah I did not I mean I knew
people would be here but I was pretty
surprised like it came rowing back and
uh people are registering to conferences
later and later so it's very hard on the
organizers because it comes in the last
wave just like when you get your
submissions how many of your submissions
come in on the last couple days is that
just when you think you're done
pretty much yeah no every year it's like
wow 30 submissions I can handle that and
then like one hour before the deadline
it's like well 250. yeah 250 in the last
hour take that in how much time do you
think she's going to put to those
considerations versus the people from
two weeks earlier oh yes beer please
thank you thank you
ah it doesn't matter I'll take an IPA
thank you
so it was supposed to be you observing
us having a casual conversation
we need to have the beer to have the
conversation
okay you go for the IPA okay the thing
250 submissions at the end is that you
know you kind of get review or burnout
thank you right and the last thing you
want to do is review a submission when
you're feeling exhausted and burned out
and all the words are just blurring on
the page and it's so tempting to click
next next and it sounds like the other
one yeah so you you know you've got to
sort of go away you got to manage your
time and come back and be refreshed and
give everybody a fair chance so when
people submit and they say I got it on
the deadline when are you going to tell
me
it's like well you've got to wait weeks
now because they have to digest this
huge meal that arrives you if you submit
like two weeks before like one week
before you'll get so much more like like
better quality review okay like I try to
keep up with it I try to you know I
don't know four weeks before I start to
you know start to review you know maybe
like 10 talks a day or something like
that and I I always try to keep up with
it and then of course that last day
comes and then a fully 50 to 75 percent
of the total come in on that last day
yeah and you know some people can plow
through them uh but I do think that you
know you give a little bit of short
Thrift doing that so the ones that come
in early like I'm reading those like
well I'm putting a lot of attention on
those because it's the only thing I have
to do yeah I would say the ones that
come in earlier the ones that get
probably the most attention I mean
that's how I operate
reviewing I'm reviewing yeah I'm gonna
say there actually is an advantage to
submitting early in they don't
necessarily do the best but we do pick
some talks early so if it's a very
strong solution exactly and I noticed
that you get feedback in the early when
it's late we don't have time to get your
q a right feedback and the and the other
no-brainer is if the review board asks a
question like a follow-up question you
must respond you know eloquently and
yeah some people are going to make it
easy to review the presentations because
they don't have a good abstract you know
like it's like they put no effort in
submitting so those ones that are easy
to dismiss that's the good thing I'm
going to uh I'm gonna shift the topic a
little bit
um
Russia Ukraine
we saw it influence some of the
submissions maybe around disinformation
or misinformation or maybe some Network
and attack or apt but um I'm curious
kind of more professionally bigger
picture
are we as an industry like
used to dealing with sort of Apt levels
and every other weird Cry of cyber War
now that it's actually here
is it what we expected
did it you know it's sort of like when I
talk to people involved and I'd say do
you think Russia's used all their
techniques or are they sitting on some
for some reason the general consensus
seems to be that we've seen it all kind
of seeing one of each of everything I
would say very careful of taking that
position well they said why would you
wait why would you wait six months in
but you know you know my father was in
was in Russian counter Espionage he'd
probably kill me now for saying this on
a stage yeah but it's so long ago right
um and one thing that he will say is
these people who he has a lot of respect
for think long term and on those I'm
sure but if you looked at the attack the
first week was nothing but attack and
then a week of nothing as they tried to
figure out uh what are we going to do
next right and then another week of
little less attack and then a period of
you know and so
I'm just curious is what we've been
preaching or reading about for so long
is kind of happening in real time in
front of us
does it live up to the hype well I guess
it depends uh there is what we see and
what we don't see right yeah if like
what do we see is just like the numbers
we have seen for like the first six
months like wipers and stuff like that I
don't think those capabilities for sure
you know yeah like there's probably like
stuff that we're gonna see like later on
in a few years it's like all the stuff
that happened oh the shadow Brokers
thing happened yeah and all those
exploits got leaked like the data I got
leaked were like oh that happened like
five years ago you know so I think we're
probably gonna end up in a situation a
long tail of other things coming out
yeah because we don't see you probably
see like I don't know less than 10
percent of like but it's not like a fast
and furious where there's the magic
button and shuts down the whole city and
it's the AI That's gonna it's not like
in the movies yeah we're not getting
into the mainframes turning down the
fires what are you saying oh my god I've
been deceived Jeff Moss is telling me
hacking is not like in the movies oh my
God
let me hold my chair I need to recover
on this touche not like in the movies I
quit yeah we're on that on that same
note you know what they're maybe not
being like a single magic button but
um you know when Kim zetter's keynote
today was pretty you know talking about
some of the the different groups that
have infiltrated you know operational
technology and and that some of the uh
almost like the workflows they had
around like okay well make sure that you
uh kill all these processes before you
again the ransomware like it's almost
like a magic button right it's almost
like the switch that you flip the
research has been done to kind of do
that and so
you know I think it is proving that to
be as chaotic
uh as as we thought it would be with the
citizen Army getting involved and then
the whole like that's government
government
yeah the part I'm kind of surprised is
how uh aggressive Microsoft seems to be
in combating some of it I sort of
thought maybe some of the big mncs were
kind of sit on the sidelines a little
bit and try to provide update services
to everybody but I was pretty surprised
how some companies are just pulling out
yeah pulling out or taking a stand
um
I've got a follow-up question
defense then in this super pervasive
offense environment
does defense stand a chance and one
thing I was thinking of the companies
that are really good at taking the tools
away from adversaries
probably can do really well in this
environment because the adversary might
not want to exercise something the only
thing I only have one real touch point
is when we ran Defcon for the first time
fully online on Discord the first year
people started targeting all the
attendees with custom malware
trying to get him to click on videos or
links or whatever and it was I don't
know if there's a botnet but it was a
pretty concerted effort with a lot of
unique malware and so we scripted up a
bot that just took every attachment and
sent it to virus total
and the attack stopped in five minutes
they just don't want their stuff in
virus total right and so it seems like
defense has some techniques that can
make life more miserable
I don't know many of them but I'm
curious this would be the time for
defense to shine right that's that's I
mean I didn't know that's a cool story
that's uh
a great example I think of what Chris
Krebs said the other day which was
you know moving from I think it was from
the government perspective but moving
from these long-running investigations
to more disruptive action right in that
situation you saw something you
immediately
took an action on it that would you know
create a situation that's harmful to the
attacker and want to raise their costs
right we can't do an investigation but I
want to take your tools away right so
that's that's a that's a great way to
kind of tie that together and I think as
Defenders we do
chance
um I mean I'm largely on the defensive
side of the house now so uh it behooves
me to say that but I think
um the one I was going through my notes
from all the all the briefings just
before this and the one Trend that I I
kept seeing come up was changing our
threat models so like changing that like
the need to evolve our mental threat
models like they were too simplistic
before or too complicated or they're
actually wrote These down because uh so
Krebs said you know uh you know anybody
that's running a technology that's
becoming a core fabric of the internet
has to realize that they are now part of
the National Security apparatus right
mindset shift
um the CI CD talk
um
you know the idea that
pipelines cicd pipelines control so much
and you can you have this like nice
streamlined way to push stuff out to
production and infiltrate in a way that
you weren't able to do before it's a
different threat model than you know 10
years ago when all you had to be worried
about was being attacked directly and
you know or individually
um the the web 3 talk which and one
three was very polarizing uh
topic amongst the review board I will
tell you that I think North Korea yeah
anything you need to know and it didn't
end up with it didn't end up with a trap
but it ended up with at least one talk
and you know we'll see where that goes
but
you know we're seeing all the same types
of attacks in web 3 that we saw in
traditional application security you see
the the uh
see now I forgot what the wallet hat was
but the one was basically leaking uh
private keys and mnemonics through
through overly verbose logging like
we're seeing these things play over and
over and over again but now with what
three uh the threat model is different
because these attacks can happen
instantaneously and you know in the open
and anonymously so I think as Defenders
we have to be a little bit faster to
think about you know to modify
um how we're how we're thinking about
our threat model and adapting rather
than kind of using what we've always
been using oh yeah yeah I think like I'm
so glad we have the defense track here
because I do think there's this problem
where you know you shared a really
clever idea for defense but not all the
ideas are super clever and a lot of
things that are required in being like
purely defensive are things like code
review they're things like knowing what
all your assets are
just thinking for the hardware track we
had quite a few talks on fault injection
and then there's just one talk on
techniques for preventing that and I
think that does kind of reflect on
security people's interests and I think
it's important that we understand the
value of defensive Solutions because it
is fun to break stuff but
um well there's this concept you know in
offense which is use it or lose it so
you know you've got the tool you know
Microsoft's going to release a patch you
have to now decide use it or lose it and
so I was kept expecting like with that
Tempo accelerated we'd see a lot of use
it because there's all this fomo of
losing it
but
I I I
haven't really actually seen that play
out so I'm now I'm questioning those
assumptions yeah but the thing is like I
think that is
ignoring the broader issue which is if
you had 10 fewer bugs or 20 fewer fewer
bugs attackers wouldn't even find
themselves in that situation right right
maybe not
um that would obviously wouldn't get rid
of all of your bugs but it would
make it harder for attackers make it
more expensive and you know defense
isn't perfect and I think it's always
going to be a struggle with attackers
but I don't think we should ignore the
fact that there are things we can do to
make it less likely that they have toys
to play with in the first place
yeah or even like uh the the quality of
patches I was just talking with one of
the speaker before he was saying what
they have seen actually is the quality
of patches is decreasing and he sees a
lot of like Placebo like patches where
they just fix like the specific like use
case you are giving but not the actual
Bird right and that's if strain equals
EA exactly yeah or like CVS you know
being like merged like they would send
like multiple bugs and they would just
get only like few CVS and the impact on
on teams exactly yeah
pages that do nothing yeah exactly so I
mean like products what's driving that
I know like maybe the quality of like
software Engineers like uh even if you
look now I was talking with another
speaker we're just saying that a lot of
the uh like offensive presentations
they're not coming from the same profile
of people you would see like 10 years
ago a lot of them come from like Google
for instance like defense like oriented
like company uh like the whole profile
of like offensive talks also like change
like the actual people doing like
offense we don't see them yeah because
we're not allowed to drop out anymore
[Music]
this is there less I mean I'm always
curious like when it gets harder to
develop the zero day it becomes more
valuable so you're more likely to
monetize it that's supposedly right I
mean there was the the trend in the
early days of black cat were like well
I'm famous enough now my career's
developed enough
I don't have to release that stuff
anymore now I can sell it but because
some vendors are not paying like
researchers on time and they're waiting
for like one or two years I know I don't
want to drop any names but
so right like there's a name that came
up like few times you know like this
because oh interesting but that's true
because there's a source of Revenue now
for for security research isn't it well
it wasn't an incentive to you know
present those results elsewhere right
yeah
that was never there before right
the numbers just keep going up
you know do you guys ever pay attention
to the value of when uh zoronium would
post I just get astounded every time I
see those that's what I was thinking
like the one or one or two million
dollars for like a iOS I think or Chrome
yeah yeah like this is actually for the
um projects you're over you guys
probably pay attention a lot to it I'm
sorry Target sometimes that in other
price lists because it is a really good
indicator of how much attackers value
bugs I always get nervous when I see
software like we're not taking these
anymore we have too many of them I was
like no but I run that software yeah
yeah that's going to be a problem but do
you but the the value going up of a
vulnerability
must reflect the increased level of
effort that has had to go into
discovering that it must yeah right does
it well that's I mean it's that hard
right now right look at the uh you can't
just put like apostrophe equals
semicolon yeah but if you look at like
the bridges in web free like some of the
bounties are like 10 million dollars
it's more than the airport for like iOS
bugs and stuff which is great because
that's real real money's moving yeah
it'd be like if the Swift Network said
we'll give you a tenth of a percent of
what you save us that's a billion
dollars or something yeah yeah
yeah it is hard to figure out for sure
what a price means it is a combination
of how much it's valued and how hard it
is to attack I'm always curious how much
of it is it tells you what attackers
want
like these are the targets not
necessarily what people are producing
yeah and of course it's it's a balance
um
yeah up until web 3 it made a lot of
sense
was wanted
you know maybe like maybe their
countries wanted and the level of effort
but but yeah like what Matt just said
you know the interesting thing with web3
is that there is not a regulatory
requirement for these developers to
obtain
attestations of security but they're
doing it anyway they know it's coming
right these companies are going out
there and paying a lot of money and
waiting a long time for an independent
third party review of their code if
they're doing things right right there's
a number that are not but there are many
that are there's no regulatory body
requiring them to do this they're doing
it so that they are adopted as a
platform incredible because it's like
when trail of grits announces that we
did a year and a half review of some
technologies that was not cheap right
yeah I don't know so that industry
whatever you want to call it web through
the web 3 Community have succeeded in
establishing a best practice that never
happened before it took a regulatory
pressure or some requirements some
compliance issue to require that
penetration test report right people
weren't doing it because
it was best practice they were doing it
because they had to
I've got one more topic
and then we'll go to some questions and
this is around complexity
in all the reviews and we always say
that the systems are getting more and
more complex and complex systems are
hard to secure and they fail in
unpredictable ways when you're reviewing
these talks how much of the underlying
bug or the newness or the the the
they're there that made you want to
select the talk do you think
is it is any of it related to complexity
like the libraries are so complicated
the code passes so there's so many
third-party dependencies like a lot of
these would not be issues but for this
complexity or is
yes there's more complexity but it's
kind of not relevant
anything are you talking about the
complexity of what the researcher did or
the complexity of the system they looked
at it could be either it's I'm always
curious that
if complexity is always increasing does
that just mean it increases for infinity
and we're here when we're 200 years old
and these systems look simple or is
there sort of like a natural level at
some point there's a maximum complexity
level we're just not there yet that
makes it so hard for researchers to
understand it or because they're so
complex they can only look at this teeny
little leaf and they'll never understand
the big picture
and if that's the case that means we're
as a community losing the big picture
and I don't know if that's true
I don't see the complexity I mean it's
hard to imagine reaching a peak uh so
that means forever yeah well who here
show of hands thinks that we're on the
path of ever increasing complexity with
no end in sight
no no
so think to yourself because I don't
know we don't know the answer what does
that mean
I don't think it means anything good
besides employment for life I've had
problems for our children yeah
I'm an optimist here I think unnecessary
complexity in systems makes them less
secure and over time people are going to
learn this and hopefully reduce the
complexity to what's necessary
programming and trust or yeah well
there's so many things well programming
in managed languages is one of them
reducing attack surface and making sure
that every feature is necessary is
another yeah there are course
corrections I mean you know entire frame
you know frame ritual languages that
make it harder to to make common
mistakes that type of thing but you know
meanwhile well these new languages are
being developed for Frameworks being
developed you know you also have like
entirely new ecosystems popping up and
so like the pace of those things are at
odds with one another right I think the
complexity is just this when you ask the
question it made me think of uh
there's there's this uh I guess it's
basically a survey uh called the index
of cyber security that Dan gear started
um probably 15 years ago and has since
handed off but it started off with a
handful of individuals in the industry
just you know answering questions about
kind of how they felt the threat levels
were and very pointed questions around
their their uh kind of a temperature of
the room yeah how do you how do you feel
about the how are things going and then
it would come up with like a number and
anyway over time that num there's if you
look at a chart that never that's never
come down it's just increasing and
increasing increasing I think you could
probably look over 15 years and just the
perceived level of of of of of threat
and risk is always going up and I think
this is one of those things as well yeah
hmm
yeah well I think you can I think you
can't ignore is the big increase in the
number of people using Technologies over
the years and just the sheer number of
Technologies now you've got uh Wi-Fi in
your fridge that sort of thing right
not mine
well you are missing out and also like
there's a lot of people who like to
reinvent the wheel a lot you know
because there is some research that was
not necessarily like visible or
something we see people are like
Reinventing the wheel a lot you know
that is a really good point it's
something I think as a board you
probably all face too which is somebody
submit something they make a claim that
it's new or novel yeah and it's very
hard as a review board member to verify
that claim because you can't just go to
academic references so unless you've
been in the scene forever and you say no
no FX published something 15 years ago
exactly yeah how do you know so I think
as an industry we don't do a very good
job of archiving stuff for the years
yeah or having a referenceable yeah
yeah I didn't even go farther if it was
15 years ago kind of doesn't matter or
is this topic still exactly so bring it
back nonetheless you know right it's not
it can be like even more complex stuff
like
uh like programming languages you
mentioned rest you know some friends who
are talking about carbon versus rust you
know like uh so rust is known to have
memory safety but like the way the
phrase it for carbon is like it's on an
incremental path to memory safety it's
like what does that even mean you know
it means it's never going to happen you
know so what would you try to do in your
language to replace like C plus plus to
like I think that's not as good as Russ
you know it does not makes more sense
and we see a lot of like side projects
like this yeah and uh yeah I think it's
also a problem and I also have a
personal opinion on the fact that
insecurities is probably like
proportionally like the ratio of like
software Engineers is product lower than
in the past and you have more people who
are used to like push buttons and use
regex no I don't have the data on this
it's my personal belief but I think it's
also playing in the oh everything sounds
like so complex and everything just
because there's no we don't have the
right people to like summarize it
are the people being pulled away into
Cloud Big Data something else
lack of Interest no like overwhelmed
also it's difficult I guess not to get
into security party because there's so
many things so the question is always
like where do you start so it's easy to
be misled on focusing on the wrong
topics uh
what's your opinion on that we are still
talking about
the level of technical content that we
need to be addressing to be a cyber
security expert we're still talking
about the fact that cyber security is
not just a technical issue and we need
to address the skills gaps and um the
the skills shortage and you know we
should be looking at people from all
backgrounds not just highly technical
experts but at the same time at the ciso
summit we had a whole presentation about
how the schools are putting out
badly skilled cyber security people who
don't have enough technical knowledge
unfortunately to be helpful I have um
this is a couple year old story but
supports your claim I was in uh in
Washington DC or out right outside and I
was uh supporting this conference and in
the conference where
a lot of universities and there's one
one guy from University in public said
this out loud at this panel so kudos for
him for you know courage
he said we are University XYZ we want to
be a leader in cyber security and we
want to be in the top ten we know we
can't get to the top five that's you
know but we want to be in the top ten
within three years
what advice do you have
for me I said that's great
um
you probably want to get buy off that
you can teach offensive information
security to the students because if you
don't understand how offense works you
can't really teach defense
okay maybe not the top ten
yeah
and he just
see him run through the politics that he
would have to go through with his
Provost and his board of directors to
explain that he's teaching students
offense and he was like nope wow and so
that's like a problem in a microcosm
yeah is it almost seems like the bar
like that would definitely put you in
the top top five or ten to have a good
offensive but like what we heard at the
CSO Summit which I guess we're not
supposed to say who is presenting but uh
it was simpler than that it was that the
cyber security programs that the
undergraduate level cyber security
programs are not even sending out
students with the fundamentals of like
you know networking right like if you
don't understand like the basics of like
tcpip and just like networking and how
that stuff works but you have an
understanding of like you know maybe
what's happening in the policy realm of
cyber or you know all those things that
they're trying to put into the
curriculum you can't get very far you
have it's not all technical but you have
to have a certain technical Foundation
you have to be able to write some code
it probably doesn't have to be great
code but like increasingly actually it
probably does you know as there's this
crossover between Security Professionals
and and you know uh software the bar is
pretty low to be a great communicator to
you know teach security awareness
training right which is it no but you
need to probably understand the priority
when you're teaching it like this is why
this is important or this is what so I
guess that's the question we should ask
ourselves like how deep do these people
need to go to be effective in a role
like that
so we're out of time and so I'm going to
give it a one round to everybody for
closing thoughts any any points you want
to make anything you want to leave
something going to be even bigger next
year
I hope I mean generally we have a lot of
people come from China in Asia and a lot
of those people didn't travel because
they couldn't so I don't see how it
would get smaller amazing yeah
okay so let's start I'll start with
Chris any final thoughts you want to
leave
the holdouts the hardcore people that
have waited it out here
uh you know we're still seeing a lot of
the same problems we're seeing it
manifest in different ways I think as it
applies to new technologies but we're
seeing a lot of the same problems and so
I think that whole theme of we have to
be uh quicker at adapting the lessons
that we already know we already know
about vlogging we already know about
like basic secure coding issues we know
you know we know what things to do
in a large part and they're just not
getting done and so uh good job security
but uh
you know
it's kind of more of the same it's a
little bit discouraging uh on the sort
of optimistic mentalism yeah I mean we
are seeing things getting better In
Pockets I mean we're you know sitting
where I sit in application security we
are seeing you know habits get better
around software security and integrating
security into the you know devsec Ops
and things like that but like too slowly
right way too slowly so we've got to get
better
yeah I agree I feel like Chris has said
a lot of what I wanted to say already
but but is Hardware slower or easier or
harder
yeah well I mean there's there's kind of
complex challenges in Hardware in that
um it is harder to fix things
um it's like more complex than software
but what I will say is also every year
doing the hardware track I am so
impressed by all the talks we get I
think it's one of the most competitive
tracks and yeah I am so amazed by the
research we see every year so well I
feel like there's a lot of problems I'm
also really inspired so I think everyone
should keep at it and
I do feel like one day we are going to
solve these problems or at least make a
lot of Headway
um
um I would just probably revisit the
application the ideas around the
application of our security research
Community to Innovation that's impacting
everyone so the great example of us
doing that is standing up the AI track
which is a couple of years ago a bad
example of us not doing that is not
looking at things like blockchain which
is changing the world and has a ton of
security issues and
um I think that we we get so in the
weeds sometimes with Bud classes and you
know really deep security researchers is
great but we should still try to map
that to what
you know that sort of high level
technology trends that impact everyone
in our communities and try to connect
those dots a bit more be a bit more
open-minded about how this actually
impacts people around us
um yeah and I agree on the fact that uh
like Chris said you know like it feels
like some of the things the problems are
always the same so is it because like uh
things are moving slowly or because you
are missing like new trends you know
because like as a security as like the
security industry were just like so
focused on the same problem that we are
missing right actual problems on like
looking the motives of the attackers you
know like why they do something and then
maybe it's going to help us to
understand okay like oh you know instead
of like looking from the out or like
finding the why
um I'm really proud that we got through
this without using the word fake news or
Ai No I said AI you did drink
and blockchain
thank you
all right well that concludes our
session everybody thank you for
attending um the videos will all be
edited and put online eventually for
free share with your friends we'd love
your feedback we love getting your
comments so we'll see you on the
twitters and if you're around later this
week we'll see you at Defcon thank you
[Music]