[Music]
it's my pleasure to welcome Christian
Russell to the stage
all right hey everyone uh Welcome to our
presentation uh today we'll talk about a
couple of uh Android full chains we
discovered in the wild in 2021 by
monitoring surveillance vendors
This Is Us on your left hand side you
have shingyu and Richard they work in
the Android malware research team where
they work on protecting Android against
malware and exploits
and on your right hand side you have me
Christian I work in Google's threat
analysis group I'll talk a bit uh more
about what we do in a couple of slides
so uh the main part of this presentation
is a deep dive into an exploit uh we
found as part of a food chain uh and
xingyu will guide us through this
um but before that I'll give you some
background on what tagged us and some
examples of these full chains
and after that uh Richard will go
through some post exploitation
techniques uh an exploit we found in the
Play Store and a bit about defending
Android before we wrap up the conclusion
all right so Google's threat analysis
group or tag for sure
um our goal is to protect Google and our
users and one way that we're doing this
is that we're routinely hunting for zero
days exploited in the wild and as you
can see on your right hand side
um back in 2019 we reported seven zero
days found in the wild uh five in 2020
10 in 2021 so it was a pretty good year
for us and so far in 2022 we reported
three zero days that we found in the
wild
and to discover these series
um what we're doing is that or one thing
we're doing is that we're tracking more
than 30 different commercial
surveillance vendor so any company that
provides
um exploits or implants or other
offensive services to its customers
um yeah and as I mentioned there's like
we're tracking more than 30. so like we
often see just a handful of companies
mentioned in the media but that's just
the tip of the iceberg and this is a
very thriving industry with a lot of
different companies involved
and one interesting thing that we've
seen is that some of these groups are
actually sharing or selling exploits
between each other so there was one case
uh we had a chrome intense logic floor
uh back in I think it was 2021 that we
saw several groups using the same
exploit so there's also some form of
cooperation going on here
all right and next up I'll talk about
two Android full chains that we
discovered in 2021 so these are two full
chains from two different surveillance
vendors
and the first one
um this was discovered by us in October
2021 uh and it was served to an
up-to-date Android device at the time uh
and they were exploiting two
vulnerabilities uh one of them was a
zero day in Chrome to get execution in
Chrome's rendering process which is
heavily sandboxed and from there they
need to escape the samox and they were
exploiting an e-pol reference counting
vulnerability in the Linux kernel
and what's interesting about this
vulnerability is that it was actually
quickly fixed in the Upstream kernel so
they introduced the patch like or the
bug with one patch and then it was fixed
like I think it was a week later so
pretty quickly but unfortunately in
Android only the first patch was picked
up so it left Android vulnerable for
about a year I think
and unfortunately it's not the first
time this has happened this was also the
case for another runability known as bad
binder which has been yeah documented a
lot publicly
and this was also quickly fixed in the
Upstream kernel but took a while to
reach Android
yep
um so one thing that was interesting
with this
um full chain uh in the sandbox Escape
Park so when they were exploiting this
EPO reference counting vulnerability
they had a pretty interesting
exploitation technique that I just
wanted to mention because yeah I thought
it was cool and I don't think I've ever
seen this documented before so yeah
so this vulnerability uh gives an
attacker the ability to free a file
structure in the Linux kernel uh while
you still have a reference to it from
userspace as a file descriptor so you
have a pretty classic use after free
scenario
um and the goal of this exploitation
technique which is just a part of the
exploit it's not like the full exploit
but the way that the surveillance vendor
chose to exploit the vulnerability
uh is to get Riot access to codes and
what they're doing here is that they're
getting right access to lib C and these
changes when they're writing to lib c
will be mirrored into every process on
the system so effectively this gives you
by exploiting this you get code
execution every process that uses slip C
which is everything
and the steps uh the first step is you
map lib C which is your target using a
map and then you create some file
descriptor that you can trigger this
vulnerability on
and
um
yeah so I've uh in the original code I
mean there was a huge bug trigger but I
replaced this with f put which is the
kernel API for freeing file structures
so just to kind of distill it into one
slide so it's easier to see but yeah so
the next step is like you triggered a
bug so now you have a file descriptor
that points to a freed file in the
kernel
and you quickly replace it by creating
an MFD which will occupy the last read
file structure
and then you map this as readable and
writable
and now uh we want to free this yet
again so
since we replaced this previous file
structure by creating another file both
of these file descriptors in user space
actually points to the same file
structure in the kernel so by closing
this twice we can free the file
structure again
and the reason why I have to do it twice
is because the Linux kernel has two
references to this file one by creating
the MFD and one by doing the M map
so if we and yet again we replace it
so now this
um memfd shared memory mapping it has a
reference to the previous file which you
know should be like a shared mem file
but now it's actually lib C again
and this is like the juicy part of the
exploit technique what they're doing is
looping through every page in libsy so
you don't have this Loop looping through
every single page and you touch the
start of a page this makes sure that the
kernel will load the pages into memory
from this
um but the interesting part is when you
do this for the readable and writable
mapping the Linux kernel like the page
full Handler will look up the file
that's associated with this memory
mapping
which now is actually lib C and since we
just folded in all the pages the kernel
is happy and we get lib C pages into our
readable and writable memory mapping
which we can then overwrite and this
will be reflected in every process
and this particular surveillance vendor
used this to inject a shell code into
certain system calls that would then
load an implant if it was running in the
correct process
yeah
that was the first full chain so the
second one this is directly related to
the exploit that xinyu and Richard will
talk about
um and this surveillance vendor was
using quite a it was a bit different
strategy
so instead of using zero days against
Chrome they were actually targeting a
chrome based browser that was lagging
behind Chrome in patches
so they could use
um end days against these browsers as it
was a zero day basically
and depending on the version of the
browser they have three different bugs
that they would bundle uh with their
exploit
and for the samples Escape part to
escape from chrome uh in some cases they
were using the bad binder vulnerability
that I mentioned earlier
but in other cases they were actually
using a zero day and you'll hear more
about this bug very soon
but first let me take you through the
kind of timeline how does it look like
for a user that's targeted by this
so the first thing that happens is the
user receives a one-time link
and they click it
and when they click it they're
redirected to an exploit server uh and
the job of this exploit server is to
fingerprint the device and serve the
correct exploit depending on browser
versions OS version and so on
and in both of these cases for the uh
for the surveillance vendors they were
targeting Chrome so they have some sort
of chrome exploit that gets code
execution in Chrome's rendering process
and from there at least at the time of
uh when we discovered this vulnerability
I'm not sure if it's the same anymore
but they were abusing Chrome's
webassembly code mappings because they
used to be readable writable executable
so they put some Shell Code and elf
loader yeah and they're explaining there
and by jumping to this elf loader they
load a local privilege escalation
exploits
and with that I'll hand it over to
shinyu
there we go
thank you Christian
so uh we're gonna do a div dive to the
zero day we captured and it's also fixed
in the last November it's a CV 2021 0920
so it's the most probably the most
complicated Android uh kernels exploit
last year and it could also be one of
the most convoluted exploit in across
the newest kind of History
in terms of this uh broadcast analysis
and exploitation techniques so basically
we capture two major versions of
exploits so the expiration version a
targeted at recent early devices and
expert B Target our recent devices so
everything starting at a very simple
kind of features that users can send
fight this graders to other process by
something called SCM let's call it right
datagram by send message Cisco so let's
say I am a socket fight in square a and
I send a cell to a 5D square B so what
happens in kernel is that first of all
kernel Atticus structure called SK
underscore buff or socket buffer or AKA
as SKB at attend the circuit buffer to
the receiver queue and as you can see
there's one field in the socket buffer
point to another newly allocated
structure called Sam underscore list and
it contains an Aries of file Founders
that point to the file in the flight so
from our receiver point of view it
received the message so the socket
platform is removed from the receiver
queue and get free and kernel will
install another file disclosure C in
terms of the 5A so as you can see the 5A
now has two reference count okay so
however let's consider the following
scenario like I am despite this group a
I send a cell to B and B Center cell 2A
and then what happens in the user space
is that uses space cross A and B so
there's no way for the kernel to
destruct file A and B because they still
have a reference count but there's no
way for the user Space Program to
calculus again because five Distributors
are already removed from kind of
descriptive table so that's why we need
a guard reflector in the Linux kernel so
for example every time you you call
close this car it may trigger W
collection system and the way to
identify potential garbage is to
implement something called in Flight
count so what does inflightcom means is
is pretty simple is that you know if
there's a file in the flight then we
just increment the reference in Flight
comes so as you can see the Ace in front
count is one because a is in the fly so
similarly it based in flight card is
sort of one so as you can see the
replica here equals to the infrared
count so it could be a good sign of
potential garbage but it is not always
the case if we consider this cycle like
a center b b send itself to alpha alpha
centers out to 3 and b Center a
so if you're the Space Program close A
and B what happens here is that the Run
Ace reference count equals to the inside
count and B's infinite account equals to
the reference count so A and B are
considered as potential garbage but they
are not actually garbage because we can
guide 5D square B from 5 Discord Alpha
and we can get 5 display a from the 5D
is great to be so for our coverage
collector point of view is that first of
all A and B are considered as potential
garbage so A and B are put into Global
list called GC underscore candidates
and then what kind of does is to scan
the inflight for the GC candidate so
let's say the criminal scans a first so
it will check a receiver queue
okay so a is the reciprocal Q is B and
because B is also in the GC candidates
what kind of what does is to decrement
these inflate columns so this infrared
count is decremented from two to one and
similarly Ace infinite count is also
document to zero however as a result
because this infrared account is still
above zero so B is not considered as a
garbage what kind of will do is to
recursely restore info account so this
info account will be restored to two and
Ace infant color will be restored from 0
to 1 and no one is considered as garbage
so however if you consider the the
formation on breakout cycle A and B are
considered as potential coverage so they
are put into the GC candidates and
scanning flag process will lead to the
foreign result that A and B's inflatcom
are both zero so all of them are
considered as garbage so the final step
for the kernel is to improve this
garbage is by remove and free the socket
buffer and then digital 5 in and P
so we also have two ways to cause
receive message so if we call receive
messages call without massive Peak flag
first of all it will synchronize with GC
which means that kernel will install a
new fight distribution artwork before
did she say finish so what happens in
kernel is that the receiver will remove
and free the socket buffers and install
another file distributor however if we
call receive message with massive Peak
flag it doesn't synchronize with GC it
means that we can have one third cause
received message with message Peak flag
while there's another thread doing the
GC in the meantime and also from
receiver point of view it will not
remove the socket buffer so and and
kernel will still install another file
description so you can see and the a
reference column can get elevated
okay so now we really want to introduce
the vulnerability scenario so like I
said the issue here is that the recently
message with massive big flag doesn't
synchronize with GC so there will be one
file and the reference can't get
elevated
however you know this kind of
vulnerability is difficult to trigger
because you know most of the time you
heard about is like hey the file
reference can't get decremented by
accident so how to do how to get a
user-free by elevator file files
reference count however it's very
complicated and unfortunately we are not
going to go through details here but we
will illustrate call Ideal
um so you know the color here that I
received message zip code doesn't
synchronize with uh with massive pink
product and simplified with GC so if we
at least we are very very uh complex and
consistent GC State and various subtle
risk conditions here uh when it leads to
a result in a user-free in the socket
buffer so uh you know we have to create
three main threads one thread does GC
and two or two tasks cause risky message
with some good results massive Peak flag
and through a very comfortable coaches
are one of the receiver will receive a
user-friendly socket buffer object so
the patch here is actually pretty simple
you know it's just called spin long it's
being all in two lines to make sure like
uh the best it picks the top will
install a fighter skirt before GC have
completes
and interestingly the current bug was
found in 2016 and you can see you can
check this email address because there's
a public Linux kind of email address
unfortunately the patch was not accepted
so that means any Bad actors see the
ones kind of email thread may come up
with an exploit against the Linux and
Android users okay so now let's take a
look at how of the Explorer a does so A
is for the old devices so first of all
you know there will be a lot of thread
in living and the way to win the risk
condition with higher chance is to
generate as much coverage as possible
and it's also a good sign for detection
and in reality there will be really a
lot to us including each other sometimes
for history some threads for fixing the
kernel structure for for backgrounds and
there will be also a lot a lot of
threads to impact on schedulers and
through very very cool choices there
will be very small chance that you will
have a useful object and also get
history so that's why the X-ray tries
250 times for getting a free soccer park
object and also spray on the circuit
buffer object is not it's not easy
because circuit buffer object is
allocated from our separate cache
so that means the conventional ships to
the technique doesn't work but there is
something called cross-catching pad is
that you know if we can free all the
circuit buffer object in The Sims lab
page and freeze so the page may have the
chance to be returned to the page
allocator that might be used by other
cache that could be impacted by the
normal confessional history technique
but the chance is very small and now
assume we can spray the SKB and we can
control that SKB data what happens here
in kernel inter if we call the receive
message Cisco kernel will copy address
from SKB data back to user space so now
the question here is that I have no
information disclosure what address I
should read so for the actual sample a
it's very interesting because it reads
our physical address and it is the page
size data calculated md5 hash value
comparing with a hash table with 512
values so you can calculate the kind of
base of the that so why does it actually
reads our fixed and address so we
believe it's because OEM X invent is on
things for current based realization
before mainstream kernel and based on
the exponent it only randomized nine
base at 4K alignment so an attacker is
due to excess of that it can address
locally so by having a semi arbitrary
they actually is able to iterate in the
tasks and find the exact type structures
from its one within chart process and
get the address of the address damage so
if you run your Android device which can
use conversion lower than 4.14
overwriting the address limit to like
minus two where that and user users
based program is able to write object
kind of address
so to get the arbitrary right perimeter
they actually has some very rare things
called kernel stagger for primitive and
so basic idea here is that you know if
user Space Program initialize something
called Unix address and pass it to the
kernel what kind of what does is to cast
mem copy to copy the the name of around
the user's address and as you can see
the address here is from the SKB because
we have control of SKB so presumably if
we have the control of the SKB SK then
we can craft a stack Overflow so if we
have stock flow we can corrupt a lot of
Stack variable from the above or three
voltages underscore recent message so
this is a bigger diagram and this is the
affected area of the stack Overflow if
we can control the SKB SK so the way to
do so or bypass privilege access level
is that the experts use in map Cisco and
create a USB memory with mapshare
property and because map sure property
is not affected by the copyright
mechanism so the first time reading
memory will trigger the page fault so as
a result the current way allocator Page
and the expert is able to use its semi
option real printer to find to dump the
entire Corner stack and find the
pointers or page pointers and use page
to Verge macro to get a corresponding
kernel address
in other words
the expert is able to you know get
corresponding kernel address but the
pressure the user-based memory and
kernel space memory maps to the same
Facebook pages and then you can craft
all the fake kind of data structures
from the user space memory and it Factor
trigger the stack Overflow so once you
do so and and Trigger stack flow here is
what actually looks like so first of all
there's one very critical stack variable
called massive header get corrupted so
every time when a receiver calls receive
message the kernel will be tricked to
use the corrupted method header and then
we kind of believe that hey we are using
the pipe data structure so you will look
at the fake pipe data structure so the
the right destination address here is it
pointed to the touch structure and the
source address now the point is SKB data
and it just points to it points to your
keyword which you feel with -2 so as a
result if the receiver called receive
message uh the fake pipe data structure
will be utilized so the address limit
will be over breathing against matters
too so using space program can call
option unit right primitive to do uh to
get a room privilege okay so uh let's
talk about expert sample B so actual
sample B Target out a recent version so
there will be no issues in implementing
aslr okay so you know anytime what we
have a user 360 buffer the SKB data will
be free to and if like in the if I stand
a fighting spirituality I learn the task
the kernel will allocated structure
called essay on FB list which contains
an area of five pointer that point to
the final flight okay so when the
escaping part so when SKB gets user-free
we can somehow to history to history on
the SQL data to the newly allocated LCM
activities so the strategy here is that
the activate sample spans about 85
Distributors for opening five a device
new and then from the receiver side it
will receive like 80 kernel file adjust
so you know there will be several file
structures occupying an entire slide
page
okay so if we close these five
descriptors and do the history by
sending socket datagram that means we
can control the entire stack page
and then we can craft the all kinds of
fake pipe data structure here to this is
the control stack page so the next
question here is that how to link up
with our normal file to this fake pack
data structure so this is what the
online Premiership came to rescue so
well victim tells receive users free
socket socket buffer it may invoke
something called SV on link and by
springing on the SKB and override the
next and privilege to some uh malicious
address then what happened in unlink is
that the number file especially the
private data get hijacked it to the
controls that page address or to be more
specific is the pipe in node info so the
pipe in node info designate kernel that
hey we have two following pipe buffers
for arena right primitive and the next
issue here is that Pi buffer offs is not
initialized so we can now use this fake
pipe structure now however initialize
the pipe off is a type buffer off is
very easy just write one byte to the pi
so the color will initialize the up
first
and by reading the socket used to occupy
the slab page we can link the entire
slab page including the pi buffer a lot
so we can effectively by pass the ASL
and we may also do the something called
type migration to bypass privileged
access never so to sum up we by
manipulating the type buffer page and
type buffer offset we can achieve a
kernel object in the right primitive and
this is one more method to bypass the
hardware level of mitigation user access
override and we call it as Pi primitive
and we see in the Y expert use this
tricks into the alternative
so since you have the option green right
perimeter you can get code execution you
can recover a kind of simple table
address so for more information please
stay turned on our project table guest
blog now please welcome Richard for
talking about post exploitation
techniques thank you
okay thank you
so post exploitation
um the attackers at this point have got
a kernel read write so you might think
the next step is the normal status SE
Linux to permissive and overwrite the
process credentials so you become uid 0.
however in this case the target devices
concerned have a hypervisor providing an
additional set layer of protection
the memory containing SE Linux enforcing
is read-only the process credential
structures are monitored so you can't
edit them and unprivileged user mode
processes aren't allowed to call useful
functions such as rkp override creds or
power off command so the attackers need
to find other ways to change SE Linux
and set their user ID
so for SE Linux the exploit code finds
some important static variables by
analyzing instructions in SE Linux
related kernel functions
they find an adrp instruction which if
you know arm assembler it's referencing
some data find the instruction you know
the address of the data the exploit code
can then extract the SE Linux policy
make some modifications to it refresh
reload the database and effectively SC
Linux has been made permissive
so what about uid 0 this is a little bit
more complicated the real-time kernel
protection mechanism trusts its own
executable system bin SMD exe is
executed as a privileged process so this
gives you an initial point of entry for
getting the back door running
a second executable simple perf is used
to get the the full back door running
so how this works inject a bit of Shell
Code into SMD exe
this does then use rkp override creds
because it is a trusted privilege
process so that sets itself to root uid
0.
the full back door has been put into
simple perf so SMD exe then runs simple
perf at which point we have the entire
back door running as uid 0 and SE Linux
is effectively in permissive mode
right what do the attackers do with this
um to begin with it's pretty much what
you might expect they upload a lot of
information off the device focusing on
social media databases messages that
kind of thing the list here isn't
comprehensive we didn't have space on
the slide to fit all the path names on
but you can see Social Media stuff at
the top Android accounts databases at
the bottom and there's a spelling
mistake highlighted in red which we'll
come back to later
after copying various data off the
device the attackers then go through and
disable a lot of
system security settings again they
change more settings than are shown here
but we didn't have space on the slide so
the device is now at increased risk of
other malware because security settings
automatic updates Etc have been disabled
uh
a number of third-party anti-virus
applications are also uninstalled again
potentially placing the user at greater
risk of random other malware
and finally the back door can clean
itself up if it's commanded to do so
now Christian earlier mentioned cve
2019-2215 so I'd like to go back to look
at a particular instance of that
as a reminder of the timeline in late
September 2019 Maddie Stone from Project
zero identified the vulnerability and
tag confirmed evidence of exploitation
in the wild
October 2019 Android patched the
vulnerability we wrote some detection
for exploitation and
sent that out to see what we could find
so what did we find well we found an
exploit four CV
2019-2215 uh slightly more interestingly
it contained references to a couple of
Android applications within it one of
which is shown here pictivio viewer kit
this was on play at the time we found it
and interestingly it had been uploaded
to play in February 2019 some seven
months before we knew about the
existence of CV
2019-2215 as you can see on the right
hand side of this slide that's quite a
comprehensive list of permissions this
image viewer has you probably don't need
all of those in order to render images
on your device the second application
wasn't on play that was an off-market
application masquerading as an app from
Google using the Google Drive icon
pictivio viewer kit didn't have very
many installs we saw less than 30
lifetime installs by the time we spotted
it
there are a number of similarities
between the payloads in 2019 and the
payloads in 2021. the elf files exported
a function which was essentially a
self-loader call that function that
patches up the L file for where In
memory it is at that time processes all
of the relocations and resolves all of
the Imports what's shown on the slide is
something else that we saw sometimes the
elf header was overwritten by a fairly
simple shim which calls the self-loading
function this is the 64-bit shim there
was another very similar one for 32-bit
so you can treat the L file like a blob
of Shell Code just drop it off in memory
jump into the beginning of that block of
memory and itself loads
so everything is fixed up no extra
hassle as in 2021 in 2019 the payloads
were injected into various privileged
processes
the list of similarities goes on uh
security settings disabled files to copy
applications to uninstall Etc and we see
here the same spelling mistake in the
2019 payloads as in 2021
that config file hasn't actually been in
that location for a little while so
maybe the attackers just didn't clean up
their standard list of files to copy
right uh what are we doing about this
well
native payloads anything written that
compiles into arm or arm 64. you've got
to have executable memory to run that in
so if you can see some
unexpected executable memory turning up
in your process it might be interesting
to have a look in that memory to see
what the contents are the information
shown here is from one of our internal
analysis systems running Chrome where
we've given Chrome the cve 2020
16040 exploit again that Christian
mentioned earlier
if you look here we can see
an interesting length blob of memory is
being made read write execute and then
slightly below we can see a system call
is returning into this potentially
suspicious block of read write execute
memory so there's definitely some code
in there and happily our analysis system
captured this blob of memory and saved
it out for us
so here's the beginning of that
potentially suspicious blob of memory
and the first thing that might catch
your eye is there's an elf header at a
rather unusual offset normally you'd
expect to see the elf header at the
beginning of the page or as I mentioned
earlier
uh depending on what you're looking at
potentially in this case overwritten by
the shim jumping into the self-loading
code
the data before the L file here is
another shim this one's potentially
slightly more interesting it copies some
data from one location to another
location and then it jumps into the
self-loading export from the L file
so yeah this
tldr this is the exploit payload that
shinyu has just explained in great
detail
uh so this takes us full circle tag
found the Chrome remote code execution
being used in the wild it contained an
interesting payload which turned out to
be a zero day the payloads in 2021 have
some very strong similarities to the
older payloads and in both cases the
exploits concerned are relating to
patching mismatches you could call them
between Android and Linux where perhaps
a patch wasn't applied in one whereas it
was applied in the other or something
was missed out
so CV
2021-0920 was a very complicated
vulnerability and it was quite
complicated to exploit the developers
came up with some rather interesting
behavioral Primitives in order to make
everything work
researching and implementing all of that
must have taken them some time so
they're obviously fairly well resourced
to be able to do it because it might not
have succeeded
the faster the security industry can
find and patch things like that the
better we can protect our users and the
more time and money it costs the
surveillance industry to maintain their
capability against things
so we need to reduce the time it takes
us to detect things to patch things and
to get the updates out there in order to
keep protecting people the faster
response we can do this the better
hopefully things like vulnerability
reward programs are going to help with
this because it encourages people to
submit things to us and they'll get some
reward
so with that I think that's the end
thank you very much for watching
everybody
[Music]
thank you