[Music]
foreign
now it's my pleasure to Welcome to the
stage
Stephen duchenne
I'm sorry
and Simon have it yes
thank you very much
[Applause]
in 1961 a 28 year old New York bartender
is coming home from work quite early in
the morning it's quite dark
if you see someone on the way as she
goes home she doesn't recognize him she
doesn't realize that he follows her home
and as she Parks her car and walks a
very short distance from the car park to
the front of her very well-lit building
he follows her and sadly he stabs her
twice
unsurprisingly she screams out
now the fascinating thing is what
happens inside the building
there was a spectrum of behavior from
the residents in that place
some people hear her cry but dismiss it
entirely as something that isn't really
relevant one man leans out of a window
and shouts let that girl alone
it doesn't do anything more than that
that's where it stops
some people do call the police but when
they do they describe the murder
unfolding in front of them as a domestic
argument or a scuffle
others still asked other people for
advice trying to defer their
responsibility
now whilst the 38 Witnesses who take no
action is a gross oversimplification of
what happened
no one directly intervened in that most
obvious of threats
and no one was able to communicate the
situation effectively enough to prompt
an urgent police response
now anyone who's had any time in a psych
course uh or anyone who's kind of
interested in True Crime might have come
across this story of Kitty Genovese
and whilst there are some facts in
question it's become a parable in
Psychology about people consciously
engaging with a situation that
definitely should prompt behavior and
yet for some reason didn't
it's prompted Decades of psychological
research into the the blockest of people
interceding in an emergency or when
witnessing or even personally
experiencing social injustice
and now honestly speaking
I'm not entirely convinced that whilst I
like to think of myself as the kind of
person who might want to intercede if I
saw someone with a knife there is no way
on Earth I'm getting involved and that's
really dangerous isn't it
but
we're lucky because we're interested in
a similar phenomenon but in a very
different context
foreign
engagement I typically don't want to get
caught yeah that's typically bad for me
if I can get in
get the goods and get out that's great
but as I walk around people see me they
can't help but see me I'm you know six
foot three guy I kind of stand out I'm
outside of their Norm
what we see as we walk around is people
looking up they know you're there
something's wrong
and then they go back to typing
now I can subdue almost any of that with
the recti contact and the best I can
manage for a charming smile
we call this this perception of a threat
with a choice of inaction the fail to
challenge vulnerability we want to know
why this happens and what we can do
about it
too many clicks
I'm side habit the head of cyber
awareness behaves and culture for the UK
Ministry of Defense I'm responsible for
setting the Strategic Direction and
approaches for influencing secure
Behavior across the organization my
career has had two major themes firstly
as a forensic psychologist my academic
research specifically looks into
malicious active Behavior why the bad
guy does what they do and then what we
can do about it how can we put
mitigations in place through unusual and
interesting strategies like gamification
the second theme of my career is as a
professional social engineer and I've
LED teams that have conducted
socio-technical investigations Audits
and assessments at countless high
security sites globally I now act with
one foot in both camps detecting and
then seeking to remediate behavioral
vulnerability
consultant with Atkins in the UK
I've worked with multiple public and
private sector clients to help change
cultures and behaviors within those
organizations and currently I'm a
behavioral scientist it's part of the
Cyber awareness behaviors and culture
team would say like I like to put my
social engineering skills to good use as
well looking to apply them to see how we
can help change behaviors within those
organizations
so cyber awareness behaviors in culture
in the UK Ministry of defense is an
internal capability operating in
partnership with my colleagues here at
Atkins
our mission is simple
we want to demonstrably reduce cyber
security Risk by developing new and
reinforcing existing positive behaviors
through targeted and measurable
intervention
it's really important to know the
audience size we're dealing with we have
240 000 people in the organization that
run the gamut of every demographic and
trade group but it's wider than that
we're also tasked with impacting service
families veterans Cadet forces and even
the defense industry base all in all I
am responsible for Shifting the
behaviors of over 3 million people it it
can be an unenviable task
we do this through through four key
pillars of effort at the very center of
everything that we do is data we can't
do anything unless we know the human
terrain and know whether or not we're
having an impact
we can we conduct high level frequently
sampled socio-behavioral questionnaires
to gain a large macro picture and we
also conduct in-depth analyzes of
specific data sources which detail
individual risky behaviors
on top of this we have the Discord
shaping content team
all ideas have words attached to them
and all words exist to communicate ideas
language use is an essential window into
the value the meaning and the position
of underlying mental models that prompt
secure Behavior unless we consider the
way that language and the vast lexicon
of cyber phrasing is used we're going to
find it very hard to shift behavior on
top of that
next we have the training team
unsurprisingly no one could be able to
perform a task unless they know how to
perform that task now I think training
is incredibly valuable but I do think we
overestimate how much it's required in
this specific landscape
and last but not least we have the
behavioral interventions team they're
responsible with finding detecting and
looking at specifically changing
behavior in specific groups now I'm not
going to talk too much about that I'm
going to leave that to Steve a little
bit later on
we've done a huge amount of work over
the last couple of years
and it's been visible and it's been very
effective
we've got some examples like the fact
that we have knowingly impacted the
likelihood of reporting a suspicious
event we've developed and broadcast a
game show that thousands of people took
part in
we changed the landscape of unauthorized
USB device usage
and we built and toured a physical
escape room and I'll talk about that in
a bit
now I could talk to all of the work that
we do for days and I'm not going to do
that because I've run out of time but if
there is anything you want to catch up
on do grab me after this
so that's the what we've done but let's
talk about why it works
the prevailing approach to dealing with
a socio-behavioral issue is based on a
really simple premise
if our staff know cyber security they
will behave in a secure way
that's the the kind of underlying
argument behind the two big words that
float around on on this subject
awareness and education
but if knowledge was all that was
required to shape Behavior then no one
would smoke
we cannot expect staff to hold the same
level of interest in security as us and
it's fundamentally true that degree of
interest in a task is a major factor in
the prioritization applied to that task
even so it's been my observation that
within the security profession we often
unconsciously do just this
it's that audit moment when you spot a
password on a Post-It note and you think
oh I can't believe someone would do that
it's blindingly obvious that we
shouldn't do that right well what's
Happening Here is we're transferring our
own value system onto somebody else and
quite obviously that person has a very
different decision-making process than
we do
so what do what we need to do is to
consider the sociobehavioral landscape
from a different perspective
as is reinforced throughout numerous
themes of psychological research we need
to consider the motivation underpinning
the action
now that's great on paper but how do we
do that so I'm going to pitch three
things that I think we need to consider
in order to get to a place where we're
centering the song motivation
first off we need to streamline the
problem
two things that we really need people to
do
and that's to see something and identify
it and try and intervene if they can and
if they can't they need to communicate
that issue to someone who's more
equipped than they are we need people to
challenge and Report now it's really
important to note that these are
behaviors not points of knowledge and
there are points of knowledge behind
them but what we want is the behavior
next
there are two systems of motivation and
what we really want is for people to do
things of their own volition to be
intrinsically motivated
right now we typically base our idea of
security against the expectation that
people should follow rules and in doing
so we'll achieve a minimum standard
but this externalizes security decisions
into a state of compliance
to better draw our intrinsic motivation
we need to empower our people to make
informed risk-based decisions
this kind of thinking already floats
around our industry to be honest we
don't see anything as 100 secure why
should we see people that way
now
speaking of intrinsic motivation how do
we do intrinsic motivation better well
luckily there's some Theory out there to
help us
according to Ryan inductory
self-determination Theory there are
three elements to intrinsic motivation
we need to ask ourselves are we working
to meet these factors do people feel
like they have a degree of autonomy or
even better how do we Champion autonomy
are we facilitating competence remember
that's not the same as bullying people
into building knowledge about something
that doesn't interest them it's about
giving them the opportunity to feel like
they're getting better at something that
matters and overcoming challenges which
are pitched at the right level to them
lastly
how do we connect with those around us
do people feel a heavy burden of
individual responsibility or are they
free to pass the bucket to the IT team
it's these factors that make
gamification such an incredibly powerful
tool
so I think there is one fantastic
example of gamification let me tell you
a little bit of background
Niantic Labs started in 2010 with a
mission to create a new kind of gameplay
in which the real world becomes the game
board
their foundational principles were to
explore new places to get exercise to
have social interaction with others or
in in a better phrasing autonomy of
exploration competence in health and
relatedness with other players
in 2016 they released one of the most
successful apps ever
anyone know
Pokemon go fantastic a year later
users had collectively recorded 15.8
billion kilometers of walking
if anyone's doing the math that's
roughly the distance from Earth to the
edge of the solar system
for me the story of Pokemon go is one of
the best examples of how powerful
gamification can be because through all
of their incredible success they met
their core mission of getting people to
go up and do some exercise
but the user did not download it for
that purpose they were just playing a
game
and the core of the game is really
simple
it's about fun it's about enjoying
something plays a freeing act and it's
safe
now good gamification keeps that in mind
it keeps a true essence of a game
whilst on the surface it's the action of
distilling down a game mechanic and
applying it somewhere else
drawing only on the mechanic itself and
this is a spirit of what gamification
can offer so to get it right we need to
consider a few elements
firstly we have to walk a knife edge of
difficulty
now the knife edge has two sides of
course on one side we have railroading
your freedom to mess up is obviously
like taken away from you
when we apply this to the gamification
problem in learning well it's an issue
isn't it it can be hard to avoid because
we want people to hit the learning
objectives
uh what happens if they're really good
and they bypass everything then we've
got a bit of a problem
but the other side of the difficulty
knife
is that there sorry the other side of
the
knife edge is the difficulty wall
now the difficulty well when you play a
game a good game has a difficulty curve
that allows you to grow competence as
you get better at the game and you face
bigger challenges as you play but some
games have a curve it's so sharp it's
like a wall
now that blocks all but the most
committed of players for pure
entertainment that really can work and
it does grow a cult following but that's
really not what we're after with
gamification
the next thing you need to consider is
the game world
getting world is incredibly important as
a concept the aim is to communicate a
new layer of reality in which all
players can inhabit in-game roles
sometimes as themselves but in which the
game World the environment or the
adversary can't hurt you
now this concept of a game world can
sometimes be confused with the Fidelity
of a synthetic environment uh especially
agent in the age of VR but in terms of
gamification the definition is much
wider it can be rich detailed experience
like Halo or it can be just as detailed
without the need for any visual
representations like Dungeons and
Dragons
it can be incredibly simple like
dominoes now in all of those examples
players are constantly aware that their
actions and their decisions are
operating in the game world alone
poorly designed gamification fails to
take this into account
and simply expects participants to
respond to the game mechanic without
buying the world it lives in
and don't don't worry if this takes a
while to get right uh Monopoly is famous
for dragging all of those social
frictioners out into the real world and
ruining the good family get together
now lastly for games there is a really
important factor it's almost a defining
factor of a game
you've got to win okay
winning is vital and the easiest way to
build a positive sentiment that you've
got to remember the knife edge and these
two are intention here we want our
players to win definitely but we want
them to feel like it wasn't guaranteed
it's kind of manipulative but that's how
games work
this means pitting players against one
another can be fundamentally problematic
so who do I suggest the player should
run against
a major theme in my academic research
centers on the idea that we can build
more secure behaviors among Defenders by
understanding inhabiting the role of and
by having a personalized lived
experience of a villain importantly
wrapped in a bubble of psychological
safety
in order to prompt a mitigation Behavior
we need two forces in balance a
meaningful basis for what bad could be
importantly enacted by an external actor
who can't just threaten them from inside
the company
and a commensurate set of tools that
manage that specific problem
excess knowledge begs the question why
should I bother and what it does is
results in work to amounts
alternatively if we throw too much
threat understanding or present the
threat in the wrong way then it prompts
fear and paralysis
when we look at the typical approach to
managing behaviors we spend a
disproportionate amount of time and
effort asking people to perform
behaviors without generating a real
psychological platform for the threat
sometimes we talk about how often we get
breached or how much money we lose
but when we ask someone to carry out the
behavior do we explain clearly what the
competing threat the problem set control
actually is and this is what the aim of
the threat Avatar is we use a consistent
relevant narrative expression of a
villain which can offer both a model of
real threat but we control it we curate
it in a fashion that it feels safe to
interact with
for me the perfect stereotype of the
threat Avatar is Team Rocket
they have a theme song that tells you
they're going to start doing bad stuff
yeah it's uh widely coyote or literally
any adult in Scooby-Doo
as an audience we know that every time
they're introduced they're up to no good
we don't need a deep comprehensive
understanding of their motives although
that can be built over time we just know
that they're going to try and ruin the
hero's day
we also know without a doubt
absolutely unervingly they're going to
fail
we can explore all their wild schemes
everything they're doing right there
along with them but know that there was
never any real harm to the hero
so what happens when we take steps to
transport our staff members into the
role of the protagonist in their own
story when we cast them as the hero
we can express our antagonists in two
different ways either as an enduring
story that we can draw from time and
time again or as a transient experience
in the ministry of Defense we use both
and subtly imply connections between
them
they're a living story we have the
ministry oh you love this the ministry
of defiance get it
fantastic marketing
right
your feelings are active history and
they are continually trying to attack
defense in cyber Awareness Month 2021 we
told several stories about Defiance and
they were all interconnected we had a
physical escape room which toured around
the country and it was based on new
model military accommodation
players were locked in a bedroom when a
young verbose and playfully belligerent
Defiance hacker took over their iot
devices in their room players escaped
the room by securing those vulnerable
devices through simple puzzles
we also had and developed a magazine
which we called revolt
uh it's very good and if you want to see
it do come and grab me afterwards but
it's from the perspective of the bad
guys I'm telling you how they do what
they do
this is written by the way by a
character we call the editor he's on the
front and he broke into one of our
broadcasts so we put out videos he took
over there and spilled all of defiance's
Secrets
this this is all obvious fiction none of
this is real and it's presented in such
a way that's why it's such a kit image
of a hacker because we want something
that you immediately know isn't real
as I said there is an alternative
modality of my theory and that's based
on the idea of establishing a game world
as quickly as possible and this will
become relevant soon
but before that I'm going to let Steve
explain how a targeted intervention
resulted in the application of these
theories
thank you
so just how do we know then that
developing these novel and innovative
ideas and inviting people into our game
world is going to have the effect that
we want it to
we work to three key principles in
everything that we do as part of a wider
process
we always make sure we are addressing
one target audience that we get to know
intimately and we are working to one
specific behavior
we make sure that all of this is
grounded in proof so that we can
evidence what impact we are having on
both of those things
this means that when a request comes to
us to say look at a particular thing we
make sure that we take all the politics
or the emotion or the opinion out of
that request and make sure that we are
focusing on the specific action it's not
a case if I need you to look at this
because it's making me look bad to my
seniors it's a case if we know that
people are doing this it's happening
this many times and we can evidence
exactly what it is we make sure that we
understand the specific actions and
behaviors that people are doing
but understanding this alone isn't
enough we need to understand why people
are doing these things and so we take
all of that data from the modeling and
make sure that and apply it to different
behavioral models
things like the ones that sign mentioned
earlier or the combi model of behavior
change by Susan Michie and colleagues
this helps us to understand why people
are doing the things they're doing
but we can't neglect the fact that
people do not operate in isolation
they're part of a system and that system
also informs behaviors so we look into
the wider context to understand how
organizational factors things that
leadership are doing for example might
also be influencing behaviors
this means that when we develop our
interventions when we start to apply
gamification we know that we're going to
be pushing on the right levers we know
that we're going to be able to have the
effect that we want and Target the right
behavior and again we're able to prove
it
we make sure that we refine and trial
all of our interventions before we
actually deploy them to our target
audience to again understand what impact
we're going to have and then eventually
we get to deploy and of course we make
sure that we review and monitor and make
sure that we are having the right impact
now as I mentioned we're going to talk
about challenge behaviors now this stems
from a piece of work that started back
in 2020 and effectively we were asked to
look at reducing the prevalence of
people taking Peds or portable
electronic devices into areas of our
organization where they're not supposed
to be information protection zones
now from our work from that first half
of that process we effectively come to
understand that the problem was that
whilst everyone knew that this was
happening no one was willing to stand up
to it and say that you can't do that you
can't bring your phone in here or can
you please leave your smart watch
outside in the lockers that's what
they're for
and this is a really important problem
and we know that this problem exists in
lots of different groups in lots of
different organizations and industries
around the world
again as I mentioned challenge is one of
two most important behaviors that
non-technical staff can do along with
reporting
to make sure that the organization
remains safe
yet we don't really get the opportunity
to practice that behavior
and when we do it's a real life
situation that comes with real social
pressures right
who wants to go to their colleague and
tell them that the thing that they're
doing is risky for their organization
who wants to feel like that stick in the
mud or the barrier to progression even
if you're doing the right thing and
trying to keep your organization safe
imagine a firewall that was afraid to
query a request because it felt
self-conscious or was scared about being
judged
it wouldn't be much use as a form of
protection would it and the human
network is exactly the same
we have to empower our people to feel
confident and able to challenge because
that's what keeps an organization safe
so to help Define it a little bit
further and make sure that we're pushing
people towards the right behavior that
we actually want them to exhibit cyan
and I have developed a model for
challenge this is based on two key
principles the onward social impact of
the of the action and the actual quality
of the intervention
effectively do you upset anyone in the
process and does it actually remove the
risk
so
the first part of this model the
unconstructive partial challenge it may
be overly aggressive a little bit robust
perhaps more so than we would like and
on its own it doesn't actually remove
the risk it doesn't intervene on that
behavior
up to the constructive partial slightly
more polite a little bit more more of a
friendly style a challenge but again
still not removing the risk something is
still there that is a problem
due to the unconstructive complete
again back to that maybe slightly overly
abrasive style of challenge but on this
occasion it actually removes the risk it
stops that risky behavior from happening
right up to the Holy Grail of challenge
for us the constructive complete it's
robust but it's polite and it removes
the risk it intervenes on that
particular behavior and stops it from
occurring
so we understand that we need to reduce
the number of Ip of PEDs being taken
into ipz and in order to do that we need
to increase the peer challenge of risky
behaviors
now before we demonstrate to you just
how we actually do that there's just one
more uh model that we want to try and
explain
so in the environment around us there
are thousands of pieces of information
that we always take in to help
understand that environment
we have to start to make a sense of this
we have to put meaning to it we take all
of those different bits of information
all of those stimuli and put our own
perceptions around them to understand
what is happening in the environment
this then starts to affect our
cognitions what we actually think about
the situation what do I need to do as a
result of this thing that I've just
perceived which again in turns it starts
to affect our Behavior the things we
actually do
now the world we operate in influences
this process and vice versa to a certain
extent
and that's a really important thing to
remember
because if we want to start thinking
about how we can impact challenge
behaviors we need to get people up to
the point of understanding that they
actually need to do something about it
we need to give them all of those little
bits of information all of those
different stimuli help them to put their
own perceptions around it and realize
that it is risky so that they start to
think and realize that they need to do
something about it and then act upon
them
so
I was going to show you a little
demonstration of how we actually do that
now for the purpose of this
demonstration I am just another person
within this organization I don't
necessarily know so
just a disclaimer
and effectively what we're doing in this
demonstration in the role play the whole
purpose of the exercise is we're helping
individuals to isolate their cognitions
and in doing so helping them to develop
a script towards challenging
so
picture the scene
it's a Thursday morning and I've just
got into work
I've got an absolute ton of emails to
deal with that have come in overnight
and I've got loads of meetings that I
need to prepare for today my attention
is a finite resource
and right now all of it is on the task
at hand
could do is I could take advantage of
this couldn't I if I was on a test or an
assessment I would just fly right past
him he's not gonna pay me any attention
he's busy typing
okay that's fair enough but that's not
my aim what I want to do is draw his
attention so to do that I'm going to ask
him a question
a suspicious question
sorry mate excuse me
um I'm so sorry I'm having a just a
nightmare of a day my laptops died my
phone's died uh and I'm like I've got
like two minutes to a meeting could I
just um borrow your laptop for just a
second to email my boss
okay now this is a little bit weird I
don't think anyone's ever come up to me
in the office before and asked me if
they can use my laptop while I'm set on
it right now I'm just trying to make
sense of this situation and understand
what is happening I'm trying to build
all of those stimuli into a picture
I'm starting to perceive it as being a
little bit risky but right now I'm just
trying to understand the request I'm
taking the thing that he's just asked me
to do in comparing it to the Litany of
social norms rules and expectations that
we all adhere to in daily life to
understand if it's acceptable or not
meanwhile I've established a game World
very quickly uh normal bad guys don't
typically tell you they're a bad guy
so
uh what I'm going to do is uh use this
game world I'm gonna get his interest
and then I'm gonna get him to to
challenge me to get him to do something
with that these cues by the way are
designed to gather his attention but it
might not happen instantly it might take
a little while for him to Cotton On
that's okay remember this is happening
very very quickly and I've also asked
him to do something he definitely
shouldn't do he has never met me before
there is no way he could know me which
means he definitely shouldn't be giving
me unfettered access to his laptop
hi hi I'm sorry what was it that you
wanted
so right now again I'm still trying to
make sense of the situation I'm still
trying to put all of those different
stimuli together
but I know that it's not quite right I
know that I'm probably going to have to
do something about it it's starting to
affect my cognition but I'm still not
quite there yet maybe it's okay
right now maybe I can get someone else
to deal with the problem make it someone
else's issue actually I think you need
to go and speak to it yeah okay not bad
right it's a partial challenge he won't
let me touch his laptop but right now I
could continue to exploit this person
they haven't stopped me just yet I could
push further or I could take advantage
of this permissibility to get gone and
Escape
we're trying to get the challenge so
what do I do I'm going to push him a
little bit further
oh
yeah yeah of course of course I forgot I
forgot I tell you what I've got
something better
um is there any chance you could just
take this
it's a USB stick uh any chance you can
take that just just print off there's
only one file on there and if you do
that I won't be late please
okay now again this is starting to get
really weird
I really don't think I can do this I
don't think I can take this and plug it
in but at the same time I really hate
saying no to people and actually it just
doesn't come that naturally to me
I really don't think I can do it though
I'm gonna have to Cobble together some
kind of Challenge from scratch
uh I'm really sorry but we actually
can't plug those in I think that's
against policy um
sorry who are you I'm sorry I broke down
the corridor with them
Jeff Jeff who
Smith
I I've worked here for quite a long time
I know there is no Jeff Smith and this
guy has just approached me asking me to
do really risky things and he's given me
this odd USB stick
and actually it says hack on the side of
it
and what is that t-shirt all about why
does it say I'm lying to you
I don't I think something's up I think
this might be an exercise well no Mr
cyber threat I will not plug that in oh
he's got me see that that's a complete
challenge there's nothing I could do
beyond that point to change the angle
this person has put all of the cues
together the the silly USB stick my my
wonderful t-shirt and has leapt into the
game world with me they know what we're
talking about now so now they're right
there next to me all those tensions that
they experienced earlier on that
discomfort they felt that's immediately
resolved they feel great now they feel
quite good I want to capitalize on that
as they feel quite good they've now got
a framework for conducting challenge in
the future obviously I mean self-evident
that it's not going to look like this
because they've done it once because
they've gone through that psychological
process and they have engaged in a
challenge they now know that it's going
to work out okay that it's not strange
it is a little bit strange I'll be
honest uh when
um they come to this in the future
they're building all that positive
sentiment and what else have they done
they've beat a bad guy they have won
against an immediate threat Avatar
that's quite powerful but I'm not going
to end it there it would be kind of
suspicious if I went good job
I'm going to give him a good quality
debrief
congratulations yes absolutely that is
an exercise I'm here with a cyber
confident team and this is my ID you can
verify if you like
uh we're here doing this exercise
because we want to reinforce how
important constructive challenges and
you did great you did a really good job
so thank you so much for that it's a
really important thing you need to know
that this isn't a test it's not an
assessment we never do that uh I just
want to give you the opportunity to
practice and you did great so well done
uh and one last thing
um I'm going to leave you with
this uh little card here it's green
stands out on your desk if you put it
there then my team know and we won't
come and get you again for a little
while anyway
uh and next time you're not gonna be
wearing a t-shirts so watch out for that
uh what it does is lets you and others
around you know how important challenge
is so thank you so much for taking part
in the exercise
yeah no thank you that was really weird
but there was no way I could say yes to
you there was just too many too many
things and I'll get the ID thing next
time as well yeah exactly it's weirder
on stage
so a bit of an odd a different exercise
but for me that was really useful I had
to take all of those different things
those different bits of information that
might have suggested risk and build that
picture up for myself I had to
understand that something wasn't quite
right and then I had to challenge him
I've now got a script that next time I
can use if I need to that helps me feel
confident and I know that mod expects me
to challenge this is something that we
have to do now
so that simple exercise repeated
multiple times is how we're starting to
change behaviors and we are
so far we've done this exercise 22 times
and engaged 850 people directly which
means we've engaged between two and
three thousand people indirectly as well
we've done this on multiple sites in the
UK including the only site where they
don't have to issue a warning before
firing which adds a certain element of
spice to the exercise for everyone
but when we followed up on this we can
see that it's starting to work
77 of people report the exercise as
being engaging and useful while 62 of
people reported a positive sentiment
towards us towards challenge after the
exercise the remaining 38 reported a
neutral which meant that no one reported
any negative sentiment towards
challenging afterwards we're starting to
change people's perceptions of that
behavior
but this is also starting to affect
their cognitions
91 of people told us that they would now
feel confident in raising a challenge if
they felt that they needed to
but it's not just the stats and the
numbers and as important as they are
it's the stories that people tell about
challenging and the things that they do
as a result
we've had security advisors come back
and tell us that that people on their
site are starting to challenge more and
they're doing it in the right ways and
importantly in our environment they're
also doing that up the chain of command
the no Mr cyber threat cheesy line in
the role play well that was something
that was actually shouted at us in one
of the engagements
in the middle of a really really busy
office someone stood up and shouted that
exact phrase at us
now whilst that makes us go a little bit
red and we look a little bit silly
actually it's an incredible outcome
it's opened up that game World from
being a one-to-one relationship to a one
to many everyone else on that floor
plate has now had an experience of the
floor Walker and has joined in on the
exercise with us it's helping us to
spread the effect to a much wider group
in a much quicker in a quick and
effective way
we've been heckled out of seconds floor
story windows and we've had people turn
the challenge back on us as well go on
try and get me again I bet you won't be
able to do it next time
all of these things showed that the
exercise is starting to work we can
literally see it in people's reactions
as they do that lining up of stimuli and
realize that they have to do something
about it
and obviously importantly everywhere
that we've been has asked us to return
and do it again so we must be doing
something right
so he mentioned that we always want
people to have a positive experience of
challenging
so just how do we do that well first we
have to accept that there are risks in
this kind of exercise
not Everyone likes to be engaged
directly and they may we may have
colleagues who are not necessarily
neurotypical and so engaging them
directly may actually impact people's
feelings of psychological safety or
well-being
likewise if people feel as though they
fail some kind of exercise without even
having got up from their desk well again
those feelings may just be adversely
impacted
because of the kinds of sites that we're
going to and the information that are
held on them there is a genuine risk of
us actually causing some kind of
incident or being strong-armed off a
site
but understanding and accepting these
risks means that we're able to do
something about them
we constantly update the language that
we use in the exercises to make sure
that we don't hit any soft spots for a
particular site and upset anyone
inadvertently
we've changed the t-shirts to make them
even brighter and jazzier and stand out
even more with stronger slogans so it's
so obvious that we are not supposed to
be there and we've built up our kit over
time
the USB stick that PSY handed me is just
a 3D printed bit of plastic with either
hack or virus written on the side of it
and we always use a dummy phone as well
when we go on site so that we don't
break our own rules regarding Peds
but there are things that are
fundamentally built into the fabric of
the exercise as well that help to keep
it safe we always have two observers on
every exercise that can see the
engagement and they're in constant
Communications through a covert radio
kit so they can see and hear and talk to
the floor Walker the whole time so if
someone does have a particularly strong
response we're able to step in and
intervene if we need to
we always make sure that the right
people know that we are supposed to be
there we have the permission from the
right people and they know exactly what
is going to happen we keep that
permission on as a printed version of it
so that again if someone does respond
robustly we can show them that we're
actually supposed to be there
in fact the final thing just as I did in
the exercise we always do a debrief we
don't just let the person flounder and
think what on Earth was that that's just
happened we explain the principles of
why we've done it and what we were
trying to achieve we let them know that
they did a great job even if it takes a
little bit of nudging to get them there
so that they feel confident in being
able to do it
all of these things help us to keep
control of the exercise and make sure
that we're doing it in a safe way
and so that is how we are starting to
tackle the fail to challenge
vulnerability now I appreciate there was
an awful lot of nuance to information in
that but we just want to leave you with
three key takeaways for today
so the first one
gamification doesn't have to be hard
it doesn't have to take a long time to
do and it doesn't have to cost the Earth
either in our example the game world was
set up in a matter of seconds and it
cost as much as it did to print some 3D
USB sticks and make some T-shirts
and it also draws on the same skills
that a lot of us already have
effectively we're socially engineering a
response for someone but rather than
doing it for mischievous purposes we're
doing it for a positive outcome
training doesn't have to be 30 minutes
once a year micro doses like this the
fact that we're doing 30 seconds is
going to have vastly more impact and
it's more memorable step outside of what
it is and think about what training and
learning could be definitely position
motivation right at the center of it
we obviously want you to take the
principles from today and go away and
try and apply them to your work
cyan I genuinely believe that by
applying Behavioral Science or
psychology to the things that we do we
can help organizations to become more
cyber resilient
but we can't break people in the process
there's no point in making things worse
we have to keep people safe
so if we do this make sure that we have
the right controls in place make sure
that we have the things there to ensure
that exercises run safely and we don't
inadvertently cause more harm than good
so the final thing to say is thank you
very much for taking the time to come
down and listen today we really really
appreciate it and we hope that you found
it as valuable and as interesting as Cy
and I have so take the things from today
go out practice and play
[Applause]
[Music]