[Music]
before we get into a little bit about
ourselves we'd like to First note that
what we talk about here today is uh not
affiliated with all of our Affiliated
organizations and all the content today
is just from me and Tara
all right
so a little introduction about me I
graduated from Johns Hopkins University
in Baltimore
in 2020 right into the pandemic with a
bachelors in East Asian studies
economics and international studies in a
minor in history
um when I graduated I thought I really
thought I was going to go into foreign
policy and I spent a year brought in
China so China was my focus
um in the pandemic I started my Master's
in public policy at the Harvard Kennedy
School
and I got I had some requirements to
take care of my first year and I took a
class with someone you might know Bruce
Dyer
foreign
his talents are not as well in Virtual
for the virtual space so I went back and
T8 for him the following year and had
the joy of being with him in person he
brought toys to teach everyone about the
dangers of bluetooth enabled devices I
would love to tell that story later
and that summer I needed an internship
and I happened to apply for the Belfort
Center research assistantship which is
where I met Rob kanaki who is uh heading
the project and the lovely Tara
um I am passionate about Dunkin Donuts
but I'm not here to say it's good coffee
no one says that Dunkin Donuts is a
lifestyle and I will die on this hill
uh in my free time I love knitting and I
love to travel very cool I would like
before I introduce myself to tell you
all that this is not just Victoria's
first black hat talk it's not just her
first cyber security talk it's her first
talk ever
so you can't go anywhere but down from
here honestly this is amazing so
congratulations to Victoria for one hell
of a debut already hello my name is Tara
wheeler it's a pleasure to be here with
you all this afternoon
um I am CEO of Red Queen Dynamics say
compliance orchestration and security
education firm
um I'm a Fulbright scholar for the US
and UK in cyber security and that is of
course at Harvard Belfort Center where I
met Victoria and began working on the
aviation Lessons Learned project with
Rob kanaki and Adam showstack so I had a
great chance to get to uh to know
Victoria work on this project and I
guess the reason I'm here and the reason
I love all of this especially risk
management is I'm both a poker player
and a pilot so this really hits home for
me this this question this concept of
how we manage risk in in organizations
and I love knowing this I'm a giant risk
nerd I guess for some reason or another
so um what does really bring us kind of
all together here here today well the
question really is why are cyber
incidents like plane crashes what I'd
love to do is tell you a little bit
about the history of this project and
turn it over to Victoria to explain more
about what we're doing today
so for the last 30 or 40 years we've
been using the analogy of the NTSB as a
great way to describe how an
investigation should yield a shared
history of an incident a shared
Narrative of it right one of the
challenges that we face in cyber
security is that we don't share history
we don't produce sort of an
industry-wide description of what
happened during an incident and use that
for future Lessons Learned and for
future prevention so
when Rob and Adam came together to uh to
create this project they interviewed and
then we interviewed over a hundred
different experts in the area of how to
take Aviation lessons and the process of
doing an investigation at the NTSB and
began asking what that would look like
in cyber security in November of last
year we released the learning from cyber
incidents report which is over 100 Pages
we definitely encourage you to not read
it this second but certainly soon
uh and learn a little bit more about
what people think about how we can build
a shared narrative in cyber security
that takes those lessons from an
industry that does it really really well
when there's a plane crash we all pretty
much understand why pretty quickly and
then the next year some new regulations
come out that all Pilots have to deal
with well
over the course of doing this project we
realized it wasn't just that we were
constantly facing Perpetual threats and
attacks that people hadn't really
figured out how to repeat and improve
processes for prevention for we started
to realize that
well
in cyber security this challenge of
trying to keep information secret of
trying to keep it close uh meant that we
were perpetually fighting this uphill
battle to get information disseminated
to the industry into the community about
how something happened and what we could
do in future that wasn't just limited to
some contractor failed to update the
struts box and that's how Equifax
happened right or somebody didn't push
the SMB updates and that's how wannacry
happened and so we wanted to ask
ourselves why is cyber investigation and
the production of those reports not like
plane crashes
well we don't maintain that shared
history but also I think it's really
important to look at how the aviation
industry investigates and understands
incidents and what they do to prevent
things in future now one of the reasons
I like Victoria is
she has read
every single document on the Max on the
737 Max crashes and every single
investigative report that was produced
by the NTSB and the FAA
so report nerd would you like to tell us
a little bit more about why and how the
F the NTSB creates these kinds of
reports and what we could learn from
them sure I'll take mercy on you all and
not drag you through the black hole I
went into researching this but I did
really enjoy myself
um so happy to chat more if anyone is
also interested in these kinds of things
um but so a really great way to look at
the difference that we have right now
for the streamlined approach that the
NTSB takes to Aviation incidents and the
kind of haphazard approach we still
haven't developed for cyber security is
to look at the Boeing 737 Max and how
the NTSB handled that so in 2018 The
Lion Air flight first crashed into the
uh Java sea after departing from Jakarta
the recordings of the data tell us that
over the course of the short flight the
angle of attack sensors on the left and
the right side of the plane were
reporting different measurements and
that forced the nose of the plane it
triggered the MCAT system which forced
the nose of the plane to go down and
force the plane into a dive the pilots
repeatedly counteracted the MCAT system
to take control of the plane and bring
the nose back up but we're after doing
it successfully multiple times failed
and the plane crashed the same thing
happened in the Ethiopia flight where
after takeoff the nodes of the plane dip
too far down after the miscommunic
miscalculation of the angle of attack
from the left and right sensors the
pallets tried to counteract it multiple
times and finally failed and the plane
crashed the FAA grounded the flight and
the Indonesian and Ethiopian
uh Transportation agencies connect their
own reports because it was done in these
incidents happen internationally and the
NTSU was in a supporting role but the
ntsb's final investigative report is
really important here because it went
into not only the details of the
incidents themselves but Boeing's
failure to account for how the MCAS
system would interact with other alerts
going on in the cockpit and have those
alerts would distract pilots and keep
them from responding as building had
expected them to and fall to the FAA for
failing to note The Faults and Boeing's
initial assumptions in those in those
safety procedures
trying and failing to do the exact same
thing again and again during the middle
of an incident it's starting to sound
very familiar but there's a difference
here between how we handled those
incidents in cyber security and how they
began to handle it at the uh at NTSB and
FAA so
we've been handling cyber incidents well
by generating a whole lot of reports
basically one of the challenges we have
is that we've gone from having
government governmental reports to
having Private Industry having think
tanks generate this kind of information
as well Sentinel one
um the it's it's a laundry list of the
folks that are here at this conference
right these are people providing good
information to the industry but there's
a lack of coordination over all
agreement all the time about what caused
and creates these kinds of incidents so
then we start getting additional
committees involved with it how select
uh or Senate select intelligence
committee house oversight and reform
science space and Technology
I'm not sure how we fix this except
by coming together and recognizing that
there's a way to conduct an
investigation and we don't mean incident
response this isn't the moment where
we're yanking cables out of the wall and
everybody's trying to get a network back
up right this is about after everyone's
taken a breath we've gotten three four
hours of sleep and had a chance to ask
the question what happened and how do we
prevent this again in future this is
about investigating what happened and
generating an understanding of why and
how this kind of work needs to happen so
what Victoria and Adam and I did over
the course of the last six months is
create a Playbook that lets city and
state and National governments uh
conduct an incident investigations
um uh create an in-state investigations
board and then conduct their own
investigations now you might be asking
the question don't we already have one
of those don't we have a csrb and the
answer is that at the same time that
this report was getting generated the
csrb at DHS was being created those the
kinds of recommendations we made it
looks an awful lot like the csrb was
designed to serve a different function
at DHS so we've retooled a little bit
here to say instead there's a way for
city state county tribal governments to
run incident investigations that will
start to create a massive information in
the industry and how we need to start
creating these kinds of boards
is
three phases of Investigation just like
the NTSB does and who is this for I want
you to imagine to Envision
that
a deputy city manager gets called into a
mayor's office and told we just had a
ransomware incident at the hospital
we've got the patients back we've got
the network back up again but you have a
month to tell me what happened
go conduct an investigation give me some
kind of understanding about how we
prevent this again in future
that person in government is very
unlikely to have ever had experience
standing up a major cyber investigation
this is the Playbook that shows them how
to do it so Victoria is going to tell
you a little bit more about what this
looks like if only because she is the
person who has read every NTSB report
over the last 20 years and would like to
tell you how to take some of those
Lessons Learned and get them implemented
into this Playbook so three phases of
Investigation The Playbook itself is
modeled after the ntsb's aviation
investigations manual and I read it so
you all don't have to
the opening of the investigation is when
the incidents happened and that's when
the board convenes they decide on an
initial an investigator in charge who's
going to lead the technical team of the
investigation and kind of serve as a
guidepost throughout the entire
investigation and they set the goals for
the investigation and potentially invite
other parties
um other companies to contribute
technical team members and act as
parties to the investigation then we
move into the technical investigation we
separated the technical investigation
from the review portion to create two
separate teams so the technical
investigation is taxed by is taught
staffed by the technical team who are
professionals who do this every single
day who are some of the kinds of people
who would respond to an initial incident
and do the whole initial incident
response and they are going to analyze
reports that are coming out of the
mitigation process and hopefully get
their hands on Hardware also
then those team members are now done and
the phase moves into the Board review
that's when the board members convene
and they look at the report generated by
the technical team and they make
decisions on okay what are the facts
that we all agree upon on this incident
and what recommendations are we as a
board going to come up with and propose
to the community so that in the future
events like this can be mitigated or at
least the harm reduced by following
these kinds of recommendations so who
are these board members we broke this
down into four kinds of people that you
would want on a board the first being
individuals these are cyber Security
Experts who are well respected in the
field and they have credibility
separate from their Affiliated
organizations
a good way to think about it is if
you're sitting in here you're subject to
being drafted for this in future sorry
sorry
corporations that's because industry has
immense power in the cyber security
industry however we want to note that
corporations who have a vested interest
in the outcome of an investigation for
example a corporation with softwares was
used uh in the course of an attack those
kinds of Corporations should not be
served on the board and you should
recuse themselves if they're already on
the board of a review board sorry and
we'll note too that there's a moment for
parties who are interested in the
investigation to submit information
later just if you are the corporation or
the industry that is or the the body
that has contributed at least some of
the technology that's being investigated
there's a question of interest in that
situation it's best to maintain it as as
a disinterested aboard as possible
all right next we have government
agencies regulars how also play a big
role in the cyber security community so
they have a seat at the table
um and they have important perspective
to add but they shouldn't be the entire
board they're just one piece of it
and lastly academic organizations these
kinds of organizations have credibility
and will help the report after the fact
become widespread
so they'd be really useful
who is a technical team like I said
these are professionals who
have the skill set to do the hardcore
analogy analogy analysis of the incident
they come up with a findings report that
is then read by the board members who
may not have a technical background and
yet analogies are probably going to be
one of the more powerful things they
wield in the process of creating that
report as I think we all know at this
point so what we want to note here too
is that that as we were writing this we
realized something pretty fundamental I
think the analogy I gave you earlier of
the Deputy city manager being asked to
produce a report is pretty you know
exemplary of the situation most people
find themselves in we I think as a as an
industry as a community know at this
point that people aren't going to do
about cyber security until they
have to there's going to be a
precipitating incident that causes a
local or state government to set up a
major cyber incident investigations
board right at least the first one
someone is going to have something
dropped in their lap and they're not
going to know what to do about it so the
reason we have crisis mode in this
Playbook and you'll see it in the
Harvard Belfor report will be set out
and it'll be in high highlighted text
and in the markdown you'll see a little
bit later on it's highlighted as well
which you can all get a chance to
eyeball edit and critique
my markdown could use some improvement
so crisis mode is small insets that
tells you if you are someone who's never
done this before with the absolute key
takeaways are for instance when we talk
about who's going to get put on a board
and what the the qualities and the
traits of a person who would get put on
an investigations board are I give a
quick shortcut in crisis mode and the
quick shortcut is if you don't know who
to put on a board make sure there are
four people
you're probably the government person
already right for an individual go look
at your local isaka chapters ISC
chapters or b-sides because you're
probably going to have one within 100
miles of you for academic organizations
go to your local reasonably reputable
college or university and ask the chair
of the computer science department to
either help or recommend someone inside
the university this gives you that quick
shortcut to find someone who can help
you right for most people who've never
done this it seems
it seems a little bit
um
facile to just tell people you need to
pick a couple people that aren't in
government but the truth is many people
who do this kind of Investigation inside
a government it's never occurred to them
to ask anyone outside the body that
they're working in
it wouldn't occur to them to go to
anyone other than the I.T Department of
the city that they're doing this
investigation in it's incredibly
important to make the recommendation to
reach to outside expertise not only to
connect with industry and provide that
credibility via Academia but also make
sure that industry can help with both
resources and the kind of expertise
that's usually found inside some of the
most respected corporations in
technology and information security so
that's what crisis mode is and you'll
see quick actions like do this here's
your 10 actions to take here's the 10
questions to answer you need to ask five
why's go backwards in time why why to
avoid the single points of failure and
the uh the the the root cause analysis
mode of thinking people get into right
that's what crisis mode is and that's
part of the Playbook so
what does this look like in action
all right
so take your example a big box retail
store has recently been the victim of a
point of sale attack we're not going to
name names you can visualize for
yourself what that big box retail store
would be my husband's here and I'm just
remembering about this Home Improvement
project we have to do at home right now
okay continue
so the district manager is freaking out
that there has been an attack he
contacts a bunch of people the police
finally someone routes him to the
governor the governor turns the person
next to them and says okay who should
handle this Chief nerd Chief Information
officer that's your job figure it out
Chief Information officer crisis mode
they have the Playbook and they start
turning to the Chrysler sections of the
Playbook we've drafted so the step one
is they start to form a board they find
the cyber security professional who will
serve as the individual they find
someone from industry who can serve on
the board and they find someone from an
academic organization
next so the board is together they go
and find the technical team
after going to the it the all of the
people on the board at this time go
through their networks and they find
respected technical professionals who
can serve on the technical team
and then we start the actual
investigation in the review process the
technical team does their analysis and
they come up with the findings report
the findings report is it handed over to
the board for their review
after a short time so the board members
have had a time to review the findings
report they convene and they come up
with recommendations and they vote on
the findings to include in their final
report there's one thing to note right
here it's incredibly important to find
people for this technical team who can
speak not nerd the the not nerd
translation process that translation
Matrix is amazingly important we almost
misspoke a little earlier and use the
word analogy a great deal but somebody
on the technical team who can explain to
State and local officials why and how
something happened Beyond everybody's
screens went red at the hospital or
someone didn't patch a box because it's
very easy in that moment for someone who
doesn't understand a lot of the process
to uh to say something and we'll see
this reaction in government's a lot like
well just mandate that they patch faster
buddy if we could mandate that everybody
patched faster nobody would be here
right now we'd all be drinking right so
the problem we have is that people don't
necessarily understand how to translate
in a way that will cause the correct
action we've seen people who don't
understand Aviation will uh declare that
what needs to happen is immediately the
737 Max need to have the MCAS system
ripped out well the the level of process
failure and process adaptation that that
causes as opposed to truly understanding
how and a flawed MCAS system worked for
737 Max is
it's facile again it's it's simplistic
and we need people who don't think
simplistically but can explain simply to
people what's going on and how they can
work on this this process if if your
answer to why it happened is pointing a
finger instead of the two magic words
that tell you that you're talking to an
expert it depends
then you've got a situation where the
technical findings are going to get
buried under whatever politics are
happening in that moment this is why
this is so important to maintain a
disinterested capable technical team and
a board to provide a coherent response
to what's happening and what has
happened so the recommendations and
findings need to be written in plain
clear English or whatever language is
local at that point to make sure people
understand what happened why and most
importantly how they can prevent it and
that all needs to go into
the final report and this final report
should be readable for the public
because we want it to be as public and
widely accessible as possible we
recommend hosting it or the dream
scenario is at a toasted on a public
library website like the Boston Public
Library would host it so that everyone
can access it it's not hidden on some
company's website and desperately
desperately desperately hope no link Rod
happens and it's a stable document we do
we love libraries for this for a lot of
different reasons first of all libraries
serve a whole lot more functions than
simply checking out books as I think
those of us who have seen the services
being provided at libraries in our
communities over the last couple of
years can can recall at this point but
also there's a neutrality to libraries
that that is really important in this
moment
um the the kind of final report we're
looking for has to focus in on the idea
that there are multiple reasons why
there are process failures and multiple
places that you can fix that process
failure for the future imagine for
instance that instead of having us all
recognize that solarwinds had a failure
and again after more than a year and a
half we don't have a coherent
governmental report about what happened
where why and how imagine that every
report every kind of of cause and
Analysis of a cyber security incident
all boiled down to and in turn set the
production server's password to
solarwinds123 right the thing we're
trying to to avoid is that that is a
single answer and the thing we're trying
to cause is for people to ask five why's
behind that the first why is
who let the intern have access to the
production server
the second question is
what rules and compensating controls
weren't in place that had that
outcome right the why before that is
what were the budgetary processes the
the compliance processes and the lack of
expertise or training that let those
compensating controls or technical
processes get put into place without
someone catching it is there a lack of
diverse thought among the people who
were looking at these processes because
if we boil every single incident down to
well the intern did it or the contractor
didn't hatch the struts box or any other
form of single point of failure of root
cause analysis we lose all the richness
of what actually happened I think
everyone here knows that every one of
these incidents is complex is
interesting is fascinating for those of
us who who love looking into this stuff
and understanding it I am
I I love this field and as a student
pilot I get to see every single year
with updated regulations
um in the far aims this is the Federal
Aviation regulations in the airman's
instruction manuals I get to see why and
how regulations every single year get
ticked up a little bit better and then I
become personally responsible for
knowing those every single year
we've been talking about how this kind
of work is
it seems grinding but there's such a joy
in it when you see people finally
understanding what's happened and I
recall that six months after wannacry
happened the ncsc in the UK put out a
really great report on wannacry what
happened how it happened budgetary and
process failures Geographic locations
the names of the technologies that were
used what was and wasn't updated the
lack of skills and the lack of
upskilling that caused it in specific
locations it's a beautiful document if
you ever get a chance to read it it is
absolutely the kind of thing that we
want to see come out of this process
that's the kind of final report we want
to see happen
so
so what does this mean for organizations
responding to cyber incidents in the
future
what we hope happens is that
organizations State local governments
take this Playbook and set up their own
mciib across the country so it'd be
multiple boards investigating incidents
that happen near them or importance to
them and we developed this shared
Lessons Learned narrative not just on
like the big cyber security events but
on the small ones and then we take those
and we draw the lessons and we build on
them and they spread throughout the
community and we mitigate the Damage
Done from these events we prevent them
from happening in the future hopefully
we've seen it's not just important to
have those those incident investigation
boards set up early although with crisis
mode we understand at least the first
one almost everywhere is going to be in
crisis mode it's going to be it's going
to be a precipitating incident instead
of a thoughtfully planned out process
but what we also really hope is going to
happen is
we hope that when we go back and
research what caused What in in a
historic incident in some of the more
famous breaches that have occurred over
time like for instance the OMB breach
right
um uh the the thing we're hoping is that
when you go back and look for what
happened and how you can prevent that
particular kind of incident and future
that there is a shared understanding of
what happened right now it would be very
difficult to get everybody in this room
to agree on some of the most basic facts
of the most famous cyber attacks that
exist in the world and and that's the
challenge that I think we're looking to
address I've bumped up against this
personally when trying to find out what
happened when and where and some of the
most major incidents in the world not
Petra Wanna Cry stuxnet I've bumped into
people who
think it's okay to just have an opinion
about what happened instead of going
back and looking at it and then you go
back and find that there's no
information left anymore that the
information that was hosted is gone that
it got pulled behind a paywall a pretty
famous one was the the broadcom Takeover
of symantec's white papers it happened
really quickly and it was put back up
again but everyone was relying on a lot
of those white papers from the awesome
people that Symantec who'd done a lot of
that white paper a lot of that serious
research and it was just thought of as
marketing materials the problem we're
looking at is right now so much of our
shared history in this industry is
marketing materials that can go away at
any time that's why libraries are
awesome and that's why we want to see
this kind of information available
around the world and certainly at least
in the United States
all right so what we would love to do
now is we would love to present not only
the Belfor Center's write-up of this
it's very pretty I am not a visual
person but I hear that the visual layout
on this is really great go for it uh
take a look on not only um our site so
you can also see it in a couple of the
tweets we've shared today
um and it's it's right there on
Harvard's website but we would also
love to share that for the next two
years I Victoria and Adam showstack will
be benevolently dictating over a GitHub
project that exists out there for anyone
to use this right here is the markdown
version of that Playbook
please submit pull requests Victoria
will wield an iron Hammer we're
considering having one forged it's going
to be great and we'll find out what we
can learn from the community about what
doesn't doesn't work in setting up a
board in a Playbook like this do you
have any thoughts on that too
please do it that's my thought I spent
so long writing this I hope it lives on
it's pretty awesome so yeah
um none of this is ever going to be
perfect right like we're never going to
be able to to make this all the way
perfect there's always going to be
something going on right
um the problem we see now is that there
are still organizations as of last year
26 of the organizations that were
vulnerable to wannacry in 2017
still are and I'm exhausted by that and
I think a lot of people in this room
probably are as well so we're never
going to make this all the way perfect
and I think for those of us who are
currently in organizations anecdotally
in the Fortune 500 companies or publicly
listed companies I've been part of
without naming names
I would say anecdotally on average there
are four separate
reasonably important like medium level
or above uh incident investigations
occurring like ongoing incident response
it happens all the time so you're not
alone a lot of this stuff is perpetually
happening and yet once we clean up the
mess it's like we throw the trash out
and forget that it ever happened we keep
making the same messes again and again
and I want people to be able to learn
from that this isn't going to get any
better too we're now seeing even more
sophisticated attacks
um forgive me because I'm going to say
AI enabled credential stuffing which has
a technical meaning I swear I'm not
using it in a way that's going to be
marketing but when I talk about uh this
right here I use it in its technical
term we're using the statistical
um analysis of publicly available data
to more effectively target phishing
attacks it's automated spear phishing at
scale and that's really frightening to
me this is the kind of stuff we have to
learn lessons about in advance otherwise
I mean we're going to end up with the
same kinds of situations we found
ourselves in before if you do what you
did you get what you got right
so anybody can be ready for a major
cyber incident investigation everybody
should be ready for it and your
community is going to need this sooner
or later I think in the last two hours
I've gotten three different emails just
out of the middle of nowhere of people
who need help with incident response a
ransomware investigation like your
LinkedIn inboxes are all filling up with
the same thing too right there needs to
be more people who know how to go and
and serve themselves from this body of
knowledge that we can create and if it
exists in public on Library websites we
don't have to worry about it
disappearing behind paywalls this is why
we care this much about it because it's
not going to get less complicated but at
least we can start to predict what the
future is going to look like so
um thank you so very much it's been
incredibly wonderful to be here before
you
got something to say
thank you so much
uh to kick off my
cats I was Secure
one
um I'm so excited to be here and so
excited to see all of your requests pull
requests on that GitHub document
can we get one last Applause for
Victoria first talk ever
[Applause]
[Music]