[Music]
foreign
hello everybody thank you so much for
showing up uh to our first ever black
hat talk
um thanks to everybody that you know has
sort of supported the whole effort uh my
name is Juan Andre rosade which is why
Jags is fine
um my friend Tom Hagel here yeah Tom
Hagel uh senior and threat researcher
with Sentinel one and we are part of the
Sentinel Labs team over at Sentinel one
which you may have become very
acquainted with at the airport on the
way here
so today we're going to talk about uh
certain aspects of the invasion of
Ukraine Russian war on Ukraine and try
to discuss it in terms of some of like
the Cyber war
pontificating that has been discussed
but first and foremost like I just want
to take a moment like I know uh Victor
joro is here earlier
we want to be light-hearted we want to
kind of talk about this in an
entertaining way but it's kind of hard
to overlook the fact that like there's a
real war there's people suffering
there's this kind of horrendous thing
happening halfway across the world and
at the end of the day we're playing
games with malware but it's just sort of
important to keep this thing in context
so we definitely don't want to make
light of it
and the same breath like we'd love to
pretend that like Sentinel Labs is just
full of geniuses and we did all this by
ourselves
but that's really not true so I think I
need to give a lot of credit to our
friends at ESET the folks at cisa Cyber
command cert UA a thousand percent
mandia and semantec inquest Talos Mystic
Red Canary everybody that has been
contributing to this from the beginning
of the invasion and sort of the rollout
of these wipers uh I think it's actually
probably been the best period of
sort of selfless threat Intel
collaboration since the stuxnet phase so
I think it just a minute to sort of
appreciate the fact that everybody has
kind of come rushing uh to the aid of
this
so why cyber War like honestly this term
should make us groan but we've gotten to
a point where like we have said that
cyber is now
um the term du jour and cyber War seems
to be like a pet theory of a lot of
folks where Ukraine was gonna be like
where we were going to see this or we
weren't depending on who you were
talking to the truth is that this has
been a moving Target every week has been
new developments new wipers new malware
new operations it's incredibly hard to
keep track not just of the Cyber
operations but also like the reality on
the ground who's telling the truth who's
agronizing their claims a lot of
activist stuff DDOS stuff that really
maybe is not as significant a lot of
really significant attacks that lack a
lot of context so it's kind of hard to
tell so you can't blame folks for not
necessarily getting it right but then
there's folks that maybe don't care to
get it right so if you were watching
newspapers op-eds Etc you could
basically get every opinion you could
possibly want on whether cyber War was
happening right you got a bunch of
articles by folks that are usually
mistaken anyways uh talking about how
like cyber War didn't happen they're
written like three days after the
invasion started so they were very
present uh then you've got the sort of
like sorta crowd in the middle we're
like well you know it's kind of
happening but we missed it or like it
isn't what we expected it to be and so
on
um and then you've got sort of like the
more emphatic crowd of like it is
happening
um or it's happening and you're not
seeing it which is probably a better way
to to kind of handle it but at the end
of the day I think
we're just kind of missing some required
reading cyber war is a terrible term for
a variety of reasons most importantly
because in a very Western context we
keep expecting it to be its own domain
of warfare self-contained
self-sufficient so like someday we're
going to have a wonderful game of
Battleship and like No One's Gonna Die
we're all just going to hack each other
from far away and that's a war and
obviously that's not the reality of War
it's certainly not the reality of War
for the Russians uh this is basically
required reading for anybody that cares
about the actual like cyber attacks
offensive side of the house please
so if you're going to be taking this and
starting to talk cyber war from our
perspective there are a few things you
need to first uh take into account that
some have obviously missed you know the
first thing is taking uh looking at all
the incidents that have occurred in the
first weeks to months that continue to
ongo today within regard to Ukraine and
all the Cyber activity so we're going to
kind of dive into that a bit
um and then the essentially the
consideration for Preparation leading up
to and the action's taken uh therein
after right after the invasion so
that ultimately brings us to the
question of
what in this rises above the threshold
of what should be considered cyber War
uh you know what part of this is Warfare
rather than just the traditional
run-of-the-mill Espionage or destructive
attacks that we tend to see historically
uh over the years and then we're going
to kind of dive in at the end towards
what we kind of look at as the outlook
for the Russian threat landscape and
then
I think the the changes we might see in
from the industry uh related to this
conflict or originating from this
conflict
so the intention of this is uh quite
messy you're not intended to read it all
it's a lot uh so this is a an initial
timeline of about the first two months
or so of uh public reporting modified
with what we know today around threat
activity related to Ukraine and kind of
everything associated with the conflict
uh in the first section number one we
have the uh the the pre-positioning the
preparation leading up to the invasion
and this is stuff like we see all that
that SMS uh fishing campaign we see the
uh the general
um
uh you know uh fishing for uh Finn and
gov in Ukraine and so forth and that
leads us right up to some of the uh
final announcements right before the
invasion around like Cyclops blink
related to sand worm and then uh
unknowing to us at the time that's right
when the Hermetic wiper campaign really
began to get his foot holding
organizations ultimately leading up to
immediately right after the invasion
this is kind of the first wave of
attacks we we began to track and again a
lot of this is on public reporting and
I'm sure you know as time continues who
uh to move forward we're going to learn
a lot about new campaigns that occurred
at that time that we just don't know
about
so this is a lot of the initial wipers
uh you saw the Hermetic wafer Campaign
which we'll dive to here in a second and
a lot of the immediate fishing campaigns
to get footholds in certain
organizations with throughout Ukraine
and and number three here is kind of
right around the time we began to see
more of the the hacktivism stuff to to
kind of start to ramp up in the days
right after the invasion and obviously
the timeline here is fuzzy and there's a
lot that kind of overlaps between things
but there's you know the Conti leaks we
start to see
um opinions on from crimeware groups on
who they support and who they're against
politically and so forth so it was an
interesting shift in kind of the norm
for what we see as the threat landscape
globally at that point
and then as we continue to today this is
obviously a massive cluster of activity
and it goes on throughout throughout
today but more or less continued efforts
to can conduct Espionage get foothold in
certain organizations and then this
timeline concludes quite a while ago
with the uh the industrator 2 activity
which we'll highlight here in a second
as well
so with all of that we can also consider
the amazing work done by Ukrainian cert
team
so this is a timeline indicating
public reporting from their alerts on
their website that you know a lot of
people don't talk about it like this but
the industry as a whole relied on those
alerts to get early insight into
activity that we just didn't have
Telemetry on in many cases so the the
alerts from Ukraine's hurt Honestly made
a massive difference to the global
perception of what's happening it
allowed us as threat researchers to dive
in and identify new activity expand the
intelligence that they found do some
attribution find a lot of just
interesting links overall so Kudos major
kudos to Ukrainian certain anyone that's
been assisting them over the over the uh
the weeks and months of the invasion to
that point I would suggest that for all
the discussions that we tend to have
about information sharing and public
private Partnerships and all this kind
of stuff
um drink the there's something to be
said about sort of what cert UA has been
able to do what necessity has bred and
the fact that you act like when push
comes to shove you can actually remove
all this ridiculous red tape and enable
folks to help you so it's an example
that I hope we learn from going forward
yeah absolutely and for context this
timeline shows a couple different things
yellow we have more the scam stuff that
they've reported orange Statin tends to
lean heavily into crimeware and red is
leaning very closely into likely apt or
confirmed apt activity related to
Ukraine and they've also had multiple
cases where they report on stuff not
related to Ukraine such as activity
targeting Russian organizations which
has been fascinating
and you can see this activity actually
began the green line is when The
Invasion uh kicked off and starting on
the far left-hand side beginning of 2022
so you can see right at The Invasion
it's just been a complete flood and
shift in the way that they do reporting
so it's been quite fascinating to see
from the outside
oh sorry my theme is like completely off
here no worries give me one second guys
just so this will look a little better
slides so what you're seeing here is
kind of a summary of Spark Notes so to
say of that giant mess of a timeline of
what we see actors uh what we see
related to actor wise and malware
campaigns associated with uh with each
actor and their aliases so the top gray
boxes are what we refer to as the
primary name of the certain actor the
purple text underneath is an alias used
by either one organization or another
and then the the text underneath
obviously leads to their malware
campaigns or certain activity that
they've been associated with like this
has been particularly it's been a big
headache like look just because
the people who hate like sort of all the
naming conventions all the vendor stuff
like I totally get it it's not any
easier for us either like you end up
having to do a whole lot of uh cross
matching and trying to figure out like
what so and so calls this actually maps
onto that more importantly because it's
a shifting landscape we've had so much
early reporting that there were a lot of
unks or threat actor names or UAC number
number
um that ultimately would fold into our
known naming schemes or into groups that
we already knew about but you don't know
that in the first few hours in the first
few weeks in the first few months so
there's been a lot of going back and
just trying to kind of keep these things
straight and if you're you know paying
attention there's some that are continue
to be unattributed on cluster that to
this day we just haven't quite figured
out what bucket they're in if it's a new
team if it's someone we've dealt with
before yeah and a perfect example that
is sand worm you know the the activity
related to the Hermetic wiper Campaign
which was that that first wiper that
kicked off in the three hours or so
before the actual Invasion began that
was initially
um we had attributed to the sunflower
cdapt or a certain number of unks and
later on we began to learn more thanks
to public reporting from the industry
and overall that it's associated with
sand worm and then we can build an
overall large list of more confidently
linked attribution at that point and an
important thing to note here is you know
this is everything we're seeing all the
actors associated with the the conflict
overall one in particular is at the top
right that one is Tonto team we reported
on them just recently and this one isn't
associated with a Chinese apt attacking
Ukraine this one is actually an
organization in China attacking Russian
organizations government organizations
so overall we see this as just generally
the actors involved within the conflict
or have made interesting pieces of
activity
because of the conflict overall you
might also note the Bella Russians sort
of in the bottom right like this it's a
pretty complicated space I also urge all
of you to remember especially before you
write your next op-ed like this is the
tip of the iceberg this is the loud
things that we have gotten lucky some
organization has tripped over somebody
has been willing to share we've all been
able to corroborate to some extent or
another but this is a snapshot lacking a
great deal of granularity and I assure
you there's much more activity beneath
the surface that we aren't even aware of
yeah absolutely
so an important piece that we don't want
to skip over but we just really want to
highlight is there is a large amount of
hacktivism and the information operation
side to the entire conflict and there's
there's more than we can more than to
discuss and we have time here but on the
hacktivism side the ones that really
stick out to us are two here we have the
Belarusian cyber partisans if you're not
familiar with them they're a
long-running organization uh of It's a
small team out of Belarus that has made
significant efforts to actually
disrupting uh belarus's participation in
the in the um the conflict overall one
in particular case is when they were
able to disrupt the uh the train train
system to carry resources into Ukraine
from Belarus to support Russia so
amazing work done being done by by them
then you have the kilnet side very
pro-russian organization even this week
I believe there's been reporting on them
they're at their founder apparently
really making claims that they want to
become a hero in Russia and they want to
cause casualties in to Nato citizens so
there's a very Stark difference on the
hack system side and there's so much
more that we could even highlight here
stuff that's been unverified stuff from
groups that have come up within the last
day or two so overall it's just
generally overwhelming to keep up with
that site alone don't go getting killed
by a DDOS yeah DDOS might get you
on the information side there's so many
again pieces of disinformation or
misinformation that has kind of stemmed
from this war and been associated with
pro-russian or pro-ukrainian stances but
there's there's so many things that
stand out but ultimately I think that
when you look at these there is the the
impact that it makes either locally or
internationally such as is this piece of
information being manipulated in a way
where it's trying to Garner uh interest
from the West to support Ukraine or to
have a change in opinion about the state
of Russian Affairs so there's there's a
lot and it's coming from both sides in
many cases
But ultimately from the Russian end we
do see a lot of the traditional
disinformation approach that they are
they are known for uh in my opinion it's
kind of like the spray and pray approach
uh you know claims against
assassinations the bio labs this and
that so uh there's a lot and
I think that's kind of the longest
running effort of the the Russian side
is the continued push of trying to tune
public opinion on the conflict in in
Russia overall
all right so obviously we've been kind
of glossing over a whole lot of
different types of activity because we
wanted uh to focus as much as we could
on what you might classify as attacks or
you know offensive operations more so
than Espionage than hacktivism then
nuisances and so on
um and sort of the biggest part of that
really comes down to the prevalence of
wipers and fake ransomware which might
as well be sort of equivalent in a lot
of ways
so there's I'm great you can't read it
um so there's this notion sort of that
Western European countries a lot of
cyber commands have been sort of kicking
around this idea of having cyber ranges
and the idea is that you would train
your forces there in this sort of
virtual environment
um and and that way you would know how
you're gonna move forward
um when cyber War does come
um Russian threat actors
are about live fire exercises they don't
really care for cyber ranges nobody's
wasting their time on that and the truth
is that uh 2016 to 12 2017 sort of set
the tone uh essentially they gave us a
flavor of what they were planning to do
what they meant to rely on and for them
I mean it was already in the context of
an invasion just under a much more
limited scope so obviously not petsia
was sort of the big thing everybody
remembers not petia unfortunately named
um
but the whole point of
napatia was you you had this sort of
devastating Cyber attack because this
thing was self-spreading because it was
a fake ransomware which is essentially a
wiper because it was supply chain attack
targeting a single country but having no
limits on its spreading capabilities had
this amazing amount of spillover and
while that was perhaps a victory in
their minds or something metal worthy
um it really
in in a lot of ways has sort of seemed
to set some boundaries that have
informed some of the wiper operations of
the past however many six months or so
so as Tom mentioned February 23rd sort
of uh first day of the invasion we were
sitting in like a super boring like
sales kickoff or something and
thankfully
um our friends at ESET had tweeted out
these hashes uh and
you know we sort of jumped on it just
trying to figure out what was going on
uh and that turned into this non-stop
work shift overnight because it was the
first sighting of what we called
hermetic wiper uh what Microsoft calls
Fox blade uh
it comes in the neat little sort of
package it's a this it's actually the
default for like vs code if you don't
put an icon but it looks like a nice
little gift and
what hermetic wiper does is it
communicates with this device
this sort of driver that at first we
didn't really recognize uh it was
actually contained two copies of it are
contained
um in you know x86 x64 flavors and then
depending whether you're in XP or newer
uh not that much newer though I I
wouldn't work on like Windows 10 or
wherever like driver attestation has
actually been picked up
um and then you would what the wiper
would do is it would communicate with
this driver in order to have it do all
of the wiping uh it turns out that the
driver is this thing called es us
partition Master which I had never heard
of before this
um but if you think about it it's sort
of adopting what we might call the
shamoon school of wiping
um from like Ras gas Saudi aramco days
or the destover school of wiping from
the Sony picture entertainment days
which is just to say that they bring
their own legitimate driver in those
cases there was eldos raw disc
um in this case it's just this new kind
of driver but the whole point of it
being you have a legitimate piece of
software that's meant to bypass all of
these apples and protections and then
you use you abuse that in order to get
to do the wiping right to disk
so after that
um
there's the appearance of hermetic
wizard which was kind of interesting
right the wiper hermetic wiper doesn't
spread itself at all the way that it was
seen it was sort of spreading through
like GPO and scheduled tasks which meant
that you already had some kind of access
before afterwards
um hermetic wizard comes along which it
turns out was sort of the the a
decoupled spreader interestingly
compiled February 22nd
um well UTC so who knows how that plays
out
um I really like to point out her medic
wizard because despite what some of the
uh naming conventions like romance.dll
might suggest it's really important to
make sure like we don't draw these
unnecessary corollaries to not Petty out
like we're sort of expecting to see the
same thing these wipers that are going
to spread themselves all over the place
but we have seen not what I would call
restraint but some kind of operational
decision not to just let these things
spread like wildfire but rather to use
these accesses in more contained ways
you use GPO policies you use sort of
internal networks for your spreading and
you I guess deploy them whenever you
feel is appropriate
so after this like this was sort of the
beginning and we're like oh my God
hermetic wiper is going to be the thing
keep in mind that before this like
there's maybe half a dozen wipers used
by nation state groups like it wasn't
like something that you saw every day
but instead you know courtesy of Mystic
uh you have this sort of interesting
timeline of destructive uh malware
attacks uh I say it's interesting
because if you pay attention they've
broken it down by weeks
um you can see sort of the deployment of
a bunch of different tools I also really
love week two where there is zero
destruction incidents I feel like I
don't want to read into it I don't know
if somebody had to kind of scale it back
and figure out how they were actually
going to run something that didn't end
in three days but
you see sort of the persistence and
deployment of not hermetic not just
hermetic wiper but a variety of tools a
sort of like Fiverr mentality of like
just right wipers and wipers and wipers
and see what sticks
um around that same time you have this
um piece of go ransomware we called
party ticket based on some of these like
bizarre inflammatory strings inside of
it there's like a lot of references to
like Biden and the White House and like
all the stuff
um it's written in go so it was just a
joy to reverse and you get this nice
little screen sort of pretending that
it's a ransomware telling you to like
sort of send them uh whatever for like
getting your files back but it's
actually absolute garbage it barely
works it doesn't work as a ransomware
you can actually decrypt the files but
the truth is that they made some very
uh standard mistakes for newcomers to go
where they didn't handle the
multi-threading ride so this thing just
like could kill a CPU before it actually
gets to fully encrypt a drive
after that we get
um Isaac wiper or
what Microsoft calls the same raw I'm
not sure that I'm saying that accurately
um I like to point out sort of the
timeline of compilations you know
February 24th February 25th but the
truth is that the earliest compilation
is pointed out by ESET in a sample we
haven't seen but you know I think we can
trust them uh it's October 2021 so for
those folks that are trying to figure
out sort of a timeline of preparation
whether they wrote everything at the
last minute or there is some tooling
that suggests that some of it had
already been sitting around and then
some of it that is clearly being sort of
written on the back of a napkin very
quickly trying to like support this war
effort
um what you get with Isaac wiper is uh
sort of an it's just a different style
of wiping but essentially uh this is the
it's called Isaac wiper because
originally folks thought that this was
using like the ISAC prng it turns out
that it's just the mercy and twister
prng it really doesn't matter it's just
sort of like a random number generator
um that they're feeding directly to uh
sort of a device based on like uh
specific octals and then writing out
that random data directly uh to these
devices and thankfully at least in some
of the earlier versions they give us a
nice set of strings just letting us know
exactly what they're up to like erasing
physical drives
then we get yet another one we get
double zero which apparently Microsoft
calls fiber Lake cert UA actually brings
this to everybody's attention
um
but
it's actually this dot net
obfuscated to bits
um horrible thing and rather than claim
credit for de-obfuscating it which is a
Fool's errand on my part I'll point to
Talos having done a great write-up and
sort of figuring out yet another wiper
hard-coded physical paths and
look it's almost like droning on but the
point of this is it's not understanding
how detection is going to work not
knowing what's going to work for how
long not knowing what's going to get
caught it's basically we went to fiber
we like we sat there and wrote as many
different wipers as we could think of in
slightly different ways to just
accomplish the same goal uh towards the
later part of
um well the in I was going to say later
part of the invasion I wish that were
the case towards like week four five you
start to see desert blade uh which is
actually written in go uh it's uses it
abuses things like Microsoft's go when
IO and um this hectane uh package for
apples uh I actually really enjoy
reversing goes we wrote this thing
called alphagolang that makes it
relatively easy so I can actually show
you the entire logic of the wiper in two
screenshots it's just you know we've got
what like eight functions two packages
and it's relatively well documented on
their part but essentially they're
abusing this Microsoft package to get
directly at the physical drives uh
they're adjusting the Echoes based on
this hectane package and then they're
just dumping a bunch of like random
garbage directly into the drives
this is actually better written than
party ticket at least
so the real question becomes you know
why so many wipers right it's almost
like droning on about all these
different capabilities
um I would actually point out that
rather than saying that this is a wiper
heavy uh
thick or strategy uh I think it actually
reflects more about our bias as
observers and what we can see there's
this sort of telemetrical fog of War
that's happening with Ukraine uh by that
I mean like they're in a real war folks
are
not exactly sitting at their desk
staring at their computers and
there is actually a lack of telemetry
going to most of us that are trying to
do this work so what you're seeing is
the activity that we're meant to see the
reason wipers weren't very popular with
nation state groups before is you had to
make a decision to lose the access you
had that you could have had for two
years in order to like make a political
statement or write some dumb thing to a
drive and most threat actors wouldn't
you know go that route instead here
since it's part of some you know larger
tactic of operations and sort of
disabling it is actually worth investing
into it but it's only the the loudest
part that's sort of yelling at us that
it's there so it's inevitably this tip
of the iceberg situation as far as what
we know
so there's this big question of whether
the use is random or tactical by that
like we're kind of fighting back and
forth with folks that are trying to
figure out if like the Russians are
incredibly well organized and they're
deploying their wipers
um coordinated with like kinetic attacks
and like you know you go you wipe the
place and then the Cavalry shows up and
you know I think that's giving them a
great deal of credit
um that maybe they don't deserve but we
do have this really interesting case for
those of you I hope that you went to
eset's talk earlier today
um they're absolutely the right people
to talk about in Destroyer so we're not
going to go into guts of Industry itself
but I think it is important to talk
about this case overall because it
teaches us something about the use of
the wipers
as a slight deviation I think if there's
any sense of humor left in the gru it's
being measured in argue patch variants
argue patch is this really interesting
really kind of funny uh piece of malware
that's meant to sort of be for like
early stage deployment I say that it's
funny because the first version of argue
patch also called April acts by
Microsoft that was discovered is this
sort of backdoor trojanized uh
Ida Pro debugger binary there is no
reason to use that other than just get a
kick out of things
then the next one we ever see actually
uses like an ESET executable to load the
Shell Code so someone over there is
still having a bit of a sense of humor
about this whole thing so if you think
about it caddy wiper Isaac wiper both of
them are discovered in this sort of like
slightly decontextualized manner like
there are some attacks on specific
organizations but you know how they're
using it where they're deploying it how
they're deploying it Etc is not very
clear
caddy wiper
interestingly enough is Tiny it's nine
kilobytes it has very simple logic to it
you you know you can basically see all
the relevant functions actually it might
be all the functions
um and you know you've got your stack
strings and they're just going again
device idle control specific actules
walk into PV trying not to touch any
apis that may have been hooked by any of
the AVS and so on and then recursively
enumerating all these files adjusting
privileges writing zeros out there you
know the usual
um
this is where it gets a little more
interesting yeah so we can begin to add
some context into caddy wiper overall
and the campaigns so thanks to uh this
ESET for this timeline here uh what they
began to see and report on overall was
the deployment of uh caddy wiper and the
timeline leading up to the end Destroyer
side so you know they begin by saying
hey we're starting to see this in
Ukrainian Banks and then the government
agencies and then starting to step into
the energy provider's side and that's
what leads up to the industry or two
side ultimately acting as in a sense a a
an operational lead into in Destroyer
we're talking about a second so again
kudos to ESET on their in Destroyer 2
talk if you haven't seen it uh I hope we
can catch a video online at this point
since this morning but definitely the
right sources to talk to about industry
or two
But ultimately this leads us to the
attempt of
catty wiper acting as a step leading
into disrupting the recovery from in
Destroyer 2. so great chart from from
them here again so we have caddy wiper
uh ultimately being used to stop the
recovery of the damage caused by in
Destroyer 2. so folks that missed the
the talk earlier and you know it might
be gibberish to you in Destroyer was
used to to cause the Ukrainian blackout
in 2016
to see and Destroyer come back around it
was particularly interesting but just
equate it in your minds to trying to
shut down power substations essentially
yeah so power substations going offline
then the ability for The Operators to
recover that being uh
Irreplaceable at that point
so that leads us to the the seconds uh
the right hand side where we start to
step into the Solaris and Linux sides of
the the wipers so
this is where we start to see newer
reports on a few different things so the
first one is is orc Shred
this is
um The Shred terminology is kind of
their their way of saying wipe however
orc shred in particular isn't actually
wiping anything it's actually more used
for an SSH spreader mechanism internally
within networks so being able to
essentially Brute Force
um local IP addresses inside their
Network and try and deploy the the
proper Linux or Solaris
um wafer at that point and I promised I
wouldn't do this in a Russian accent but
you can see the art most security there
we go
so yeah there we go it kicks off talking
about that and then this is where it
does the checks for you know if this is
a Solaris host inside this network
deploy the Solaris wiper and if not
deploy the Linux side
so and this is what you're looking at is
the uh the The Brute forcing mechanism
essentially to spread laterally and this
reminds me a lot of just like the really
really terrible cryptocurrency miners we
see on like Cloud infrastructure that
just all use the same crappy script
looks just like that to me unfortunately
but brute forcing internal IPS and
trying to spread the uh the script to
them at that point
so on the Solaris side we have solo
shred uh very simple no obfuscation done
and I think this speaks a lot to the
lack of requiring to evade the detection
mechanisms on Solaris host just because
of I think products that kind of support
that end
so ultimately it's doing very basic uh
mechanisms of finding
um
system directories and then system disks
to then delete irrecoverably at that
point
you're a nice rmrf no preserve route for
everybody who's ever made that mistake
before
the Linux size a little bit different we
have awful Shred
[Music]
this one actually has a a decent amount
of obfuscation and thanks to uh wands
last minute slide preparation we were
able to de-obfuscate them and I'd rather
the obfuscate at the script manually
than make slides yeah so I'm sorry very
basic mechanisms to uh to obfuscate make
it more difficult for us to understand
it overall but once you get past that
there again is more of the uh simple yet
much more specific and wider methods of
wiping that host you know we're not just
seeing them uh deleting directories and
disks we're seeing them also Purge
memory we're seeing them uh you know
look for a lot more different
directories what else is there clean
bash history they're going for the MTD
block devices they're you know cleaning
out the swap they're just trying to make
sure like they they're incredibly
thorough on the Linux side
um you know stop Services kill demons
like everything you could think of
um they're they're being incredibly
thorough in the logic of this script
and really you know after having the
obfuscated thing like this is the main
logic like you can just see sort of how
this thing flows and it they're just uh
simple but effective simple like it's
actually this is why I've been like
tweeting about the state of like Linux
security lately it's like you can
complain as much as you want about
Windows but like this is what like a 200
line script that'll just break a Linux
system yeah uh no questions asked so
yeah so looking at all three of those
it's important to note that there's not
really from our perspective any shared
code to other stuff that's floating
around there and they're all unique in
their own ways where this is all
essentially from our perspective stuff
that was slammed together right when it
was uh ended up getting being or being
used at that point rather than any sort
of thing that's on on the tool shelf for
for months at that point or maybe a
statement about how bad Linux security
is and we just haven't caught this
before I'm just saying I have no idea
yes
um so then there's the case of acid rain
sort of near and dear to our hearts
um
so there's been a lot of discussion
about attacks on telecommunications uh
in Ukraine a lot of sort of like DDOS
and sabotage whether physical or cyber
uh and trying to intermittently take
down isps and internet uh I do think
that it was kind of half-hearted in the
beginning which isn't surprising
considering that you know if you're
invading a country with walkie-talkies
and cell phones who probably don't want
to take their Communications
infrastructure down
um and it it you have a very interesting
incident with biosa that sort of work
this is what we're going to discuss with
acid rain but then sort of Starling
comes into the picture and credit to
them from what we hear they actually
have been incredibly useful in in
Ukraine so what ends up happening is at
the very beginning of the invasion and
you know this article is from the 28th
February we start to see public reports
about
um wind turbines in Germany uh going
down and let's be be sort of careful
about the terminology right like they're
they're not exploding they're not not
functioning they were still spinning
well I don't know if we'll go that far
they they essentially they were
incommunicated which is enough for them
to not function it's about 8 500 of them
um and given the timing and sort of the
bizarreness of the choice to conduct
this Invasion at least from our
perspective it made it I think a lot of
folks started to kind of panic a little
bit right like are we starting to see
like also attacks on Western Europe and
like we have no idea sort of how far
this is going to go in reality what we
start to get is sort of ViaSat confirms
the suspected Cyber attack mostly in the
context of Ukraine
um and I
actually should probably speed up so
something interesting is ViaSat kind of
comes out with this statement and they
say you know they got network access and
it's sort of like used to execute
legitimate stuff but like no malware no
supply chain attack no nothing
um at this point I need to be fair to
biasat like they didn't we call it
device that hack which is really unfair
to them they bought a company called
utel sad that's managed by an Italian
company called Sky logic and it just so
happens that like vid you tell sad got
popped
um at the time we had this reporting
from Reuben Santa Marta who was like
dumping the uh driver the sorry the
modems that were you know pre and post
attack and of course you can't see it
there but basically the entirety
um of the contents of the modem was just
sort of wiped with this like ffff uh
like decrementing from ffff by one uh
and sort of looping over and over
something like this and it's
particularly interesting I mean there's
an obvious pattern right like FFF E3
ffff E2 and so on
um
so we had stumbled upon this binary on
VT I say stumbled because like we had
some fairly basic traps around
um after
seeing some of the early reporting and
there's a binary called ucrop which can
mean parsley but it's apparently also a
derogatory term that Russians call
ukrainians uh was uploaded from Italy to
virustotal you can see sort of the name
the date March 15th
um interestingly and this is kind of
where we had based some of our stuff
it's like an l-32
um it's binary
never seen before or never seen again
sort of submitted from just one place uh
with a sort of interesting name this is
what we started to call acid rain if you
look at it it's basically like a Brute
Force wiper for Linux systems mostly
like embedded systems so it'll walk all
these directories like I kind of want to
speed it up because I know like we're
far in but it'll walk all these
directories it'll hit all the sort of
types of devices that you might normally
see in an embedded system uh it has two
types of wiping mechanisms we'll call A
and B
um I'm going to run through this real
quick if you really care about the
details go
just look for acid rain on Google you'll
find a report but essentially same
wiping mechanism that we had seen that
would produce that ffff decrementing
pattern
credit to max van omarongan who might be
in the crowd for the reversing on the
mips side hey there you are Thanks Max
um interestingly so we put this out in
this sort of tentative way of saying
look this is a wiper came around at the
same time that would produce what we're
seeing from from ViaSat like something
doesn't jive with their statement
um and interestingly via sat the very
next day like it was you know very
forthcoming very kind he just said yeah
this is the malware that was involved in
the attack I'm sure there's a lot more
to it they have a great incident
response company I hope that someday
they provide the incident response
report but that's really up to ViaSat on
you know deciding how they're going to
handle that
um the other wiping mechanism uh what we
call B which runs if you're running as
root is interesting in that it uses the
same kind of by octals and sort of the
way that they would do the wiping
um as a plugin called dstr destroy
whatever you want to consider it that
was actually a part of VPN filter stage
3 plug-in so if anybody remembers VPN
filter publicly attributed by the FBI to
sanworm back in the day is that enough
for a conclusive link
I I don't know that I'd say that but
there's definitely smoke there like
there's something sort of worth looking
at you can check out the details in the
report after about a month after this
the US UK you actually come out and
officially sort of blame
so it's concerning in that it's more
generic and they can basically deploy it
wherever they want at this point so
waiting for the next supply chain attack
so with that what happens now where do
we see the the Russian threat landscape
go where do we see the conflicts in
Ukraine going from the the Cyber
perspective
so are we entering the ICS doomscape I
wouldn't quite say so however there's so
much unknown at this point and that
really steps us into a lot of the
I would say the the newer activity that
we're seeing related to the ICS side
that we just don't know if they're going
to be used elsewhere uh in controller in
particular is of interest to us because
there's a lot of mystery around where it
was found in kudos to UA cert and ESET I
believe uh man the end
sorry yeah yeah and uh so is this is
this a new ICS piece of malware that
we're going to begin to see more leading
up to the winner and the energy crisis
throughout Europe is this going to be
used to force certain organizations to
come back to Russia for energy if they
were able to be disrupted through this
this type of malware
and then we have it overlapping into uh
potentially links to what we see coming
out of North Korea is this uh a way that
they're going to start to fund
themselves as a state similar to what
North Koreans do through cyber crime
um more I guess interaction with the
cybercrime community to fund themselves
financially
and so I'll just kind of let it go here
but essentially then there's the
question of whether we want to start
talking about cyber attacks as part of
things that the international criminal
court should investigate I know that
it's been described as something maybe a
silly idea it is something that we
should test and consider as far as the
international criminal Criminal Court
scope there's a great article about it
it's a wonderful Folks at Berkeley
working on it uh but just something to
keep in mind about how to actually start
to put some gravitas and weight behind
the idea that cyber attacks are going
after civilians recklessly uh and is the
sort of systematic fashion so with that
we have way overstayed our welcome thank
you all so much for showing up we can do
questions back there thank you
foreign
[Music]