[Music]
and thank you for having us here it's an
honor to be at black hat
um today we're really excited to discuss
with you the techniques that we're
observing advanced persistent threats
use when they perform job-themed social
engineering
my name is
I'm a principal for intelligence Analyst
at PWC where I track apts based in the
Asia Pacific region particularly in
North Korea and I'm joined today by a
veritable expert on iran-based for
actors Allison Michael
I think Savannah just called me a
dinosaur
so I'm Allison Wyckoff I've been in the
field about 20 years my focus on the
last half of my career has been on
incident response and threat
intelligence with a specific focus on
iran-based threats and in my copious
amounts of spare time I also guest
lecture at Columbia University so with
that I'll hand it back over to Savannah
to kick us off
so just to set a little bit of context I
would like you to raise your hand if
you've changed jobs in the past 12
months
how many views okay a few now what we
know is that a further one in five
people is likely to change jobs over the
next 12 months and you might all be
familiar with the concept of the great
resignation that phenomenon where in the
wake of the pandemic so many people have
decided that they needed to change
company or maybe change career entirely
and what we see as a cyber angle to the
social context is that apts are taking
advantage of this and increasingly using
job team lures particularly North
korea-based and iran-based redactors
stand out for their operational Tempo
and their brazenness in operating this
kind of activity so what we want to do
today is take you through a few case
studies of threat actors that are doing
this and their tools techniques
procedures so that you can learn to
recognize these attempts and maybe your
blue team or your red team might pick up
a couple tips and tricks throughout this
presentation
so we're going to start talking about a
threat actor that PWC tracks internally
as black Artemis this is a product that
is known in open source as hidden Cobra
which is how the US government refers to
it and Lazarus group I should caveat
that Lazarus cook is a bit of a broad
designation there's a lot of activity
that gets attributed to Lazarus that's
not surprised this is a threat actor
that has been active since at least 2007
and has changed a lot since then but for
the purposes of this presentation I want
to discuss with you a specific campaign
by black Artemis which is known as
operation dream job more broadly this is
an Espionage motivated campaign that is
incredibly persistent in targeting the
Aerospace sector the defense industrial
based manufacturing chemical sector for
everything for military secrets to
intellectual property to confidential
information of strategic interest
so let's take a little bit of a look at
how black car thing is approaches its
initial access like social engineering
I am very sad to report that email
phishing is not that I you know I wish
it was dead we all wish it was that it's
not so black Artemis does continue to
send emails with malicious attachments
to its targets
past couple years we've observed black
Artemis also people over to social
engineering of social media particularly
LinkedIn by building recruiter personas
and directly approaching targets so what
we see right there on screen is an image
that ESET actually shared in one of the
reports in this campaign where we see
the threat actor trying to approach a
victim and if I may in a very
unprofessional manner for an alleged
recruiter being like hey you know how
are you what are you doing now my
parents aren't home do you want a new
dream job which is kind of like you know
a bit strange and the victim is like oh
you know I'm working I can't talk to
right now and the third actor is like no
do you want to work for our company
question mark question mark which is a
bit aggressive I'd be like okay maybe
something's off but no what black
Artemis also does is it will follow up
with its targets via messaging apps such
as WhatsApp to make sure that the
victims do open the malicious viewer
documents or the malicious executables
that the traductor has sent
black Artemis will also set up domains
these can be for command and control of
its malicious implants to send emails
that appear to come from a legit site or
indeed to perform web exploitation as an
initial access method so let's take a
look at that
now black Artemis has set up a domain
like this which if you look at it it
kind of looks like indeed right very
prominent job search and applications
website but if you look at the Domain
it's not indeed.com which is the
legitimate site it's indeed us.org
free good fake wood for me at a first
glance and the third actor would post
here fake job descriptions for positions
at Google or Oracle so really high
profile companies and when the victim
navigated to these links in the third
doctor sent unbeknownst to them their
browser would get exploited with a zero
day at the time which is a remote code
execution vulnerability in Google Chrome
so they would be compromised and be
delivered like a back door without
knowing now we live in an economy's
information we are constantly bombarded
with everything digital and so it's not
practical to tell people don't click
links don't open attachments like
seriously we all have to do that but
there is a little piece of user
awareness
um that leads to prevention here because
just taking one second to check out
whether that domain that you have been
sent is the legitimate one could prevent
compromise so sometimes even just a
double check matters let's take a look
at an intrusion chain instead using lure
documents which is what we're all here
for because we love them so in the first
instance black Artemis will build a fake
job specification for some fabulous job
at a high profile company and it will
send it to the victim which you know at
some point might enable macros as this
happens the victim will be presented
with a doc RTF docx document but what
happens in the meantime is that the
macros are leading us to the next stage
of the intrusion they might for example
in one case that we've observed drop a
base64 encoded payload in a folder that
the victim is not likely to look into in
this case it was C drivers and then this
reductor will make sure that
certificate.exe is dropped to that same
folder and renamed surgery listen used
to run and decode The space64 Blob and
the renaming is interesting by the way
because it means that that Defender that
is doing forensics won't necessarily
know that search YouTube was used
this leave us with a loader executable
which is then going to connect to a
further remote server and pull out the
actual payload which is going to be a
fully featured backdoor you know pull
down for their file execute commands
uploads files
and the product is going to ensure that
the loader also
establishes persistence on the bikini
machine so that even after machine
reboot this redactor has access
and this is done by in most cases that
we've observed by black Artemis through
running round
yellow32.exe pointing at the final stage
payload through a scheduled task
let's take a moment
so let's say that your email filtering
solution unfortunately got fooled this
time but this kind of phishing email
let's say that your user got compromised
but that's okay because initial access
is just that initial access there is a
whole kill chain that the product has to
go through before you're fully
compromised and you can stop that so an
example of a detection opportunity here
would be monitoring your environment for
one year l32.exe running as a scheduled
task and pointing at an unusual like
file path that should not be normal in
your environment so you can monitor for
that to have an idea that something
malicious going on let's look at the
lure documents
this is what they look like so they have
that little you know enable content
because this document is protected
now the aesthetic of these lure
documents might change but what helps us
as Defenders is the metadata so in some
of these cases we saw that a lot of
newer documents built by black Artemis
had this Mickey author metadata many of
them had markers that would convert
uuids into 32-bit or 64-bit chocolate
payloads maybe they were doing specific
Windows API aliasing some variable
definitions custom message boxes this is
all the kind of things that we can find
in macros that can help us as Defenders
hunt for more of that activity and even
detect it when it's on our Network
actually I should mention here that all
indicators of compromise for activity
related to this talk are going to be on
our public GitHub which is in the
reference to this talk when the slides
are published tomorrow so you can all go
you know look at those files and build
your own detections
so far we've talked about a North
korea-based redactor that performs
Espionage motivated operations and now I
want to talk as a different case study
about another North korea-based redactor
that instead is financially motivated
this is a product that at plbc we track
internally as black alicanto and who is
very specifically focused on
cryptocurrency you're gonna tell me you
know okay fine crypto is all the rage
recently but why is a North korea-based
reactor interested in it well I've got
you
so since at least 2017 North korea-based
reductors have been known to
consistently Target cryptocurrency
exchanges compromise them to steal money
so much so that in 2021 the usdoj
indicted three North Korean Nationals
for their role in targeting Western
Banks and cryptocurrency companies for
the purposes of Revenue generation
actually just a couple months ago North
korea-based reductors were attributed to
the compromise of this web 3.0 company
axi infinity and they made off with
625 million US dollars yes last week I
got tagged in a Twitter thread because I
probably published like a lot about
black alicanto about this Daffy company
that was said that they got compromised
using the same ttps that I was talking
about black alicanto like two weeks
earlier which are the same ttps that
we're gonna see now so this is actively
going on and it's targeting and it is in
the finance and cryptocurrency space so
watch out
open source as dangerous password
cryptocore crypto mimic so quite a few
names and as we said it's financially
motivated
in terms of the social engineering that
black alicanto might conduct
email again but this director like
system compressed archives with link
files or
other type of documents maybe a password
protected Word document and then a link
file
this is also in keeping with a shift
that we're seeing the broader threat
landscape where with Microsoft disabling
internet macros productors are having to
Pivot a bit in their initial access
techniques and using more and more link
files ISO files MSI installers and stuff
like that black alicanto also abuses
enough rewarding so in mind for word it
targets an email while impersonating an
acquaintance of theirs so that the
victim goes like Oh look this person
that I know shared me
um forwarded me this analysis of stable
coins that's really interesting let me
have a look but but actually they're
getting compromised
La calicanto also does social media
approaches pretending to be a recruiter
maybe it entices the victim into asking
more about their company
black alicanto does also do means
proofing we see here gsox hr.com which
is a Goldman Sachs proof or daiwains.com
investment is a Japanese Venture Capital
company
there is a hunting opportunity that I
think is really fun and I've really
enjoyed using to find more black alicant
infrastructure which is this thread
actor loves to register domains through
pork bun registrar and if you look at
the underlying servers that these
domains resolve to they all have very
specific combinations of Apache PHP and
openssl versions in the server headers
so you can go and build that query and
find more infrastructure all of that
information is meant to be in the iuc's
on our GitHub so again you can go and
hunt for more
in terms of an intrusion chain we've
said that this reactor will send an
email and then maybe there is like a DOT
pdf.link or a dot doc dot link so you
know the victim thinks this is this is
fine this is just a normal document when
they click on it they might just be
presented with a decoy document so
they're like oh this you know this
analysis of the crypto Market is so
fascinating but in the background the
lnk file is actually calling mshta.exe
which is connecting to a remote server
to pull down a malicious JavaScript
script that we call cabbage loader what
cover Twitter does in the first instance
is to place a link file in the victim
startup folder to ensure persistence and
then pulls down a whole series of other
JavaScript payloads
these are called a whole series of them
cabbage rot and they've been described
in great detail by entity Security in a
conference talk at virus bullet in 2020
they brought a whole report about it so
please do check it out if you're
interested in this
these are essentially profilers they
want to make sure that the actual person
that's interacting with them is not a
Sandbox it's not a researcher but it's
actually a target of interest and at
this point the threadactyl manually
deploys
further JavaScript payload cab address C
which is a fully featured backdoor you
know uploads download files execute
commands All That Jazz
and from there the product can then move
it laterally across the network
other detection opportunity are you
monitoring your environment for like
link files that cool mshk exe and then
you know pull down and execute a file
from a remote source
if that's common in your environment
that's kind of weird if it's not make
sure that you're looking for this this
is not only specific to this redactor a
lot of reductors use these ttps so it's
a good thing to keep an eye out for you
know if you'll pass me the phone the the
pawn it's a bit like something fish is
going on so you don't want that
this is what a black alicanto job
simulator document might look like so
this is an interesting one because
you can see that the product is saying
this is a position for blockchain
intelligence group
but then it says welcome when you work
for Commerce real Ag and then the
picture is Chase back so like if you
want to spoofer company at least decide
which one you don't need to give me
three all at once
and talking about the metadata that we
can use to detect this kind of activity
and this is your documents well actually
link files have these really interesting
field which is called the machine ID so
unless the third actor has scrubbed it
out you can use the machine ID metadata
to Cluster all the documents that these
reactor is building pivot to hunt for
more or detect them on your network and
all those heuristics we talked about so
like the double extension files the link
file invoking a command or calling mshta
all of that is really interesting we
have IR role on our GitHub to detect
stuff like this
I wanted to highlight these documents as
well because just a few months before
black alicanto was using this we had
seen black Artemis product or we
mentioned before using a very similar
one
so you can see that both of them have
the same structure they say welcome when
you work for Blah Blah by engineering
the future well-being of humanity you'll
do XYZ this tax is taken word for word
from the Lockheed Martin careers website
what do you know like Artemis was
proofing Lockheed Martin but then black
alicanto has taken all of that and put
it for blockchain intelligence group or
whatever so you know in all these
resignation has a North korea-based
operator move teams
it's a really interesting question it's
one that I'm working on in terms of like
attribution and in clarifying the
relationship between black alicanto and
black Artemis if you track these
reluctors and you want to have a
conversation about it I'm only years you
can catch us later and we can have a
chat and otherwise I'll get back to you
finally I could not not mention
um something that came up a few months
ago so the US Department of the treasury
released an advisory saying that North
Korean I.T workers are seeking jobs
abroad often under fake identities
um maybe through proxy companies or
proxy identities in third countries and
this is in order to you know make money
they might work as application web
developers digital coin Developers
and there's a human rights angle here
which is that these I.T workers often
are in a forced labor situation and what
the advisor also said is that their
wages get taken away to finance the
North Korean regime not only if these
North Korean I.T workers get access to a
company of Interest they might actually
hand off that access to North
korea-based apts that then might
exfiltrate you know your crown jewels or
your information of Interest
so on one hand we know that the U.N
security Council has said that all of
the funds the North Korea
workers and North korea-based apt
generate go to fund the North Korean
nuclear weapons program and on the other
you know think about it if you're a
company and you run the risk of hiring a
North Korean I.T worker
on what have you risked reaching
International sanctions and on the other
you risk a North korea-based apt than
being in your network you don't want
that so
I I guess one of my key takeaways here
is the job market right now is a really
key area for North korea-based
productors so keep your eyes peeled make
sure you're aware of who you're
interviewing
and For the Love of All That is Holy
don't open those links that you get sent
on LinkedIn do not open them
on that note I'm gonna hand off to
Allison thanks forever all right so
let's move forward and talk a little
about some of the recruiting that we're
seeing uh in the Middle East and by
recruiting I mean recruiting
um before before we get into that let's
talk a little bit though about some of
the threat actors that really love a
recruiting theme in terms of iran-based
threat actors because there's not just
one so first up we have a group that PWC
calls yellow Garuda they're probably
more commonly known as Charming kitten
and open sources this is a really active
group we're not going to be talking
about them today
um but uh some of the recruiting type
things they do is they specifically
Target journalists uh and other very
specific people of Interest with job
opportunities whether it be conferences
or specific jobs themselves
uh then we've got a group that we call
yellow light Arc they're more commonly
known as tortoise shell and open sources
and this group has set up fake
recruiting companies equipped with
personas on social media platforms
specifically uh targeting U.S veterans
so several years ago they created a fake
recruiting company that was specifically
specifically geared towards hiring
veterans
foreign
that we call Yellow marrow and this
group has been active for many many
years they're more commonly known as
apt-34 oil rig or Cobalt Gypsy in open
sources like uh yellow lighter they do
run a lot of personas or have run a lot
of personas on various social media
platforms again purporting to be
recruiters from valid and fake companies
but we're not talking about any of these
folks today we're talking about a group
that we call Yellow Dev 13. and again
for people who are in the room and do
iran-based research I do realize this is
not an exhaustive list this is just
highlights
okay so who is yellowdev13
um there has been a little bit of Open
Source reporting on them so there was a
report that came out from meta I believe
it was their q1 or maybe Q2 report that
came out in April of this year that
talked a little bit about some takedown
activity that they did for some of the
personas that this group was running
there was also some work done by
Microsoft to take down
um some brand infringement type work
that this group was doing and that was
reported under uh the nomenclature
borium this group does overlap with some
reporting under Imperial kitten for
those who subscribe
um to that flavor of threat and tell but
they've been active for a fair amount of
time in the grand scheme of things so
they've been around since about 2019 we
believe that their Espionage Focus we
haven't seen any indications that
they've been performing other types of
operations and again in terms of their
targeting it's pretty run-of-the-mill
for iran-based operators so we're seeing
uh in terms of targeted regions the US
UK Canada obviously places in the Middle
East like Israel Saudi Arabia and then
some targeting in Russia and India as
well and then the sectors that they were
targeting again with the with their
particular operations pretty
run-of-the-mill in terms of iran-based
Espionage operations energy technology
Transportation semiconductor and then we
also saw some Logistics uh and Maritime
targeting as well
but um what we're really here to talk
about with them today is a lot of the
fake stuff that they use so this group
really likes fake stuff and that is a
technical term and you can quote me on
that if you want
um so they have done a Litany of fake
things
um we are going to focus on the HR
themed aspect of that but I did want to
cover just the broader operations in
terms of all the fake stuff that they've
created so they've created a lot of
spoofed companies again geared towards
those targeted verticals and regions
that we were talking about they've also
created spoofed legitimate recruiting
companies both broad ones and very
specific ones in terms of the types of
folks that they were targeting but more
interestingly they have set up a couple
of fake recruiting companies one's
called apply talents and that was set up
first and the other is called or was
called careers finders and along the
lines of these organizations they also
have set up some personas associated
with them now in the past with some of
the groups that we mentioned that do
have done uh Persona based social
engineering we've seen those groups use
uh pictures of real people in the case
of yellow Dev 13 we've actually think
that they're using AI generated images
and we'll look at some of those later
but in terms of hunting for this
activity on your network as of earlier
this week the apply Talent site was
still active so if you are concerned
about these threat actors potentially
being
targeting your employees or being on
your network I would take a
retrospective look in my network for
these two domains that we've put on the
slides and again this will be available
after the talk
okay so you might be wondering why
yellow Dev 13 doesn't have a beautiful
mythical creature uh name as opposed to
some of the other groups that we talked
about and that's because we didn't have
a full intrusion chain uh for this
particular group so they're not a group
that we're comfortable uh bumping into
some of our existing groups or breaking
out into its own group so a little bit a
little backstory there but we do have a
fairly good idea of how they're using
apply talents in terms of their
operations
um so this like a lot of these starts on
social media we think so we're not sure
exactly how they are delivering the
links to their particular victims but it
could be a myriad of ways we know they
run social we know they run profiles on
LinkedIn and they also run them on some
other social media platforms but what we
did see was that links were delivered to
people
um that would encourage them to download
a zip file from the apply talents
website
and if the victim opens that it launches
something called online interview.exe
and we're like cool here's the malware
um and when we started doing analysis of
the malware itself it actually wasn't
malware it was just an exe and something
funny happened with this and we will
look at it momentarily but the online
interview.exe actually prompts the user
for credentials and this isn't a
credential stealing operation we
actually think that yellow Dev 13
supplies the credentials to the victim
and there's a couple reasons for that
one it evades uh detection for
sandboxing uh this particular exe and
two it keeps people like Sven and I uh
the ability to to fully understand the
full intrusion chain so we think what
happens is yellow Dev 13 authenticates
the uh the victim and then there is some
payload that's that's dropped that will
essentially take things off the targeted
Network
uh and again if you're concerned about
this check for apply talents on
um on your network but let's take a look
at online
interview.exe because it's sort of fun
uh so this is what the interface looks
like
um I didn't squeeze or pull the image at
all this is it uh I love that people
enjoyed it as much as I did I was so
pumped when I saw this
um there is hashes available on public
sandboxes if you want to take a look at
it yourself
um for me I looked at this and like
what's the first thing everyone wants to
click right I know what it is like I
want to talk to somebody live so we
obviously we looked at that nothing fun
happened unfortunately but I do want you
to know like it wasn't just like there
you could actually click on and it pops
up a chat panel we didn't we didn't get
anywhere with this
um so up next we kind of went through
the whole interview guide or Duty uh if
you enjoy the misspelling there
um and again we were trying to navigate
through to kind of figure out what the
end goal was with online interview.exe
the the feedback from uh our team as we
were looking at this is wow this is
homemade
um so here's the prompt that we got with
the credentials and this is about as far
as we got we did try to click around
some more and we got a couple error
messages uh like this one so one of the
things I failed to mention
thank you that's that was our reaction
too one of the things that I failed to
mention is apply talents and careers
finders both purported to be UK based
recruiting companies so one would assume
um that uh either there would be some QA
process with this online interview Tool
uh perhaps by uh somebody who would be
probably a native English speaker so
have not passed your technical Test
please pass it first there's a lot going
on there
we're not going to go there
but yeah we really we really enjoyed
looking at this okay so let's let's
switch gears a little bit and look at
some of the illustrious team behind
um this awesome tool
um and I pulled a quote from the careers
finders website then I'm just going to
read because again we love this this is
a direct quote we'll help you find a job
that fulfill your desires uk-based
company so we would yeah
I enjoyed it too a lot a little too much
I put it on the slides right okay
so I mentioned that the this uh yellow
Dev 13 runs a handful uh of personas
associated with their operations
um and what we have seen with this group
is most of the images
um were uh were likely AI generated in
the case of Abigail Walker uh we think
it was a real woman whose images were
being used hence being blanked out
because they changed the profile image
over time uh Abigail Walker is not a
real person though and one of the things
I absolutely love about these personas
particularly the ones on LinkedIn is if
you actually look at them they make no
sense whatsoever so Abigail Walker is a
human resources information systems
consultant according to a job title
um but if you look at her bio she's a
recruiter or a staffing expert that
doesn't make any sense uh the other
thing that we always look at when we're
looking at these profiles is how many
connections they have that gives us an
indication of how successful they might
have been with some of their social
engineering operations so in this case
Abigail 265 connection and still a
little scary all right then we've got
Brian Claire
um and I'm not going to point out the
specifics of these AI generated images
where we think that they are fake but I
will give you guys some Clues when you
start looking at these uh backgrounds
ears eyes glasses jewelry hair like some
of those are major towels with the AI
generated images
um so Brian
Brian
um
Brian's great Brian's profile is great
too this is another just profile that
makes absolutely no sense so linkedin's
a professional Network we would assume
that people are on there for
professional reasons
um
we think Brian was probably purporting
to be a recruiter even though his job
title suggests otherwise and if you want
to get in touch with Brian here's this
really sketchy Gmail account that you
can email
doesn't make any sense he had a lot of
connections though which is a little
concerning and uh his profile was active
for a fair amount of time it is no
longer
okay so let's meet the team as they
purport to be on the actual websites
themselves so this is literally a screen
grab from the apply talents website and
the careers finders website nothing's
modified here grainy image and all
um and again both of these
um apply talents was created first and
careers finder was created shortly
thereafter back in uh 2019.
so at first we've got the apply talents
Team Edward miles Scarlett Grant James
Sharp and don't worry I'm going to show
the pictures a little bit more closely
so we can enjoy what these actually look
like and then we've got
Edward miles
Scarlett Grant
and James Sharp of careers finder same
names same order completely different
people uh the other thing that was
similar on these websites is they had
the same UK based phone number
all right so let's have a little fun and
drill in specifically to some of these
images
just so everyone can get a look remember
what I told you about looking at AI
generated people
so we've got Edward miles of Applied
talents and then Edward miles of careers
finder
now apply talents was created first I
think they clearly used a different AI
generated and I would say better uh
Imaging uh software or whatever they
decided to use for their personas for
careers finder
some of these are pretty good some of
these are pretty bad uh here's Scarlett
Grant of apply talents
and careers finder remember what I told
you
backgrounds
sometimes the eyes the ears
hopefully people can see a couple funny
things with this one
all right we've got James Sharp of
Applied talents
and careers finder
I actually think James of careers finder
is pretty good you're going to see a
watermark on the image that's from us
pulling the image from a VM uh not from
the image itself
I hope everyone has fun looking at these
okay so these are the fake people of um
the two recruiting companies I have a
couple more that were associated with
yellow Dev 13 operations but uh not
necessarily the recruiting companies but
I think they're interesting examples if
you want to look at some more AI
generated humans
hopefully people notice some things that
are like yeah that doesn't pass the
sniff test
great
okay
so let's let's round things out in
keeping with the the HR theme uh and
recruitment theme of this talk
um when we think about what we talked
about today from a network Defender uh
blue team red team perspective
um you know we can really kind of again
continue this theme of HR recruitment
when we look at the ttps of the threat
actors particularly the ones we talked
about today this is really their CV
their skill set their resume like these
are all the things we can do and how
good we're at we are at it and then
we've got the targeting itself so
um
that gives us the motivations uh gives
us an idea of like what they're out to
do uh we have threat actors that are
Espionage focused and threat actors that
are financially focused that we talked
about today and then finally in the case
of these three groups that we've talked
about they literally build networks of
people to help perform their operations
which is really really interesting
but finally let's like take these
takeaways up uh just a notch
um you know threat actors are
capitalizing on the great resignation so
yellow Dev 13 is a great example yes
they were active since 2019 but what we
saw over the course of the last three
years is they updated their site
particularly apply talents to kind of
roll with the climate in terms of hiring
so right now the site has a lot of
covid-19 themed uh Pages it's also got a
whole page for how to hold page on uh
remote work so threat actors are paying
attention to what's uh what's happening
and pivoting accordingly uh 2. social
engineering still works I know we're
super tired of talking about it but
we're seeing it evolve so again like
with the personas that we're seeing use
and the way that threat actors are
approaching uh our employees they're
reaching out on on WhatsApp on LinkedIn
uh on on other mediums they're using AI
generated images to make their personas
look more legitimate we're going to
continue to see an evolution uh not just
in how they approach but how they
deliver so Microsoft did uh disable
internet macros on things going forward
that's awesome we're going to see threat
actor shift in terms of how they deliver
malware though in these fishing
exercises
and and then finally
um you know how do we defend against
this sort of stuff when we don't own our
employees social media profile so as we
saw
um you know these people are or the
threat actors are reaching out to people
on things that we just don't control and
and I kind of challenge the people in
this room to think about your
organizational security culture well are
your employees empowered or do you have
a culture where they can come to you and
say hey I think I've been fished by a
fake recruiter I mean I I personally
don't know many many employees who'd be
comfortable going and saying hey I'm
looking for another job and I think I
got socially engineered
all right so with that I think we have
about three minutes for for talks or we
can kind of move to the the speaker
Breakaway room we do have um a GitHub
page that we have published this morning
did we do it right before the talk we
did it today that has all of the
indicators that we talked about today
and again the slides will be available
uh tomorrow morning
yep the GitHub link will also be in the
reference lights when they're published
more so no prepped on that
[Music]