[Music]
foreign
to Welcome to the stage along
ski and for the QA session
uh ayal Ronan
[Applause]
can you do cryptography in the dark
is the traffic is the trusted Hardware
that we use every day really trustworthy
today we'll share the Journey of our
research including the highs and the
lows
and we'll see
what exactly Samsung failed to do
but moreover will take a look at how the
industry should change
when you start the research you never
know what you're gonna get
and sometimes you ask what are the odds
that we find something meaningful
on the one hand we have the leading
Android Vendo Samsung
with Federal Security certifications and
a lot of resources
on the other end we have one part-time
graduate student in a zoo meeting with
two amazing advisors
if University researchers could find
something meaningful then well-funded
organizations can do much more
and if Samsung's failure then other
vendors with less Securities with less
security resources could do much worse
we found two high severity CVS that
affect a massive scale of over 100
million devices and allowed to fully
recover the cryptographic keys that were
encrypted by trusted Hardware
to help you understand our research
we'll start with why you should care
what we found and what are the main
lessons
this is your phone
you use it you use it every day for a
variety of security critical tasks
you store sensitive information
you pay with the service such as Google
pay
and you use it to manage most of your
digital lives
this makes it a major major Target for
attackers
and in recent years we saw many public
attacks that completely compromise the
operating systems for example City days
blacker talk by the Google manual
security team
but we still need to protect the
cryptographic keys of applications so
that attackers will not be able to
transfer money from your bank account or
log into your PayPal or Twitter accounts
for this reason model Android devices
use the untrust Zone security extension
to provide a trusted execution execution
environment or TDE the transit separate
isolated transform operating system
there are many different trust and
operated systems and trusted
applications in fact Samsung devices use
three different operating systems qse by
Qualcomm Kennedy byte trastonic and
degrees by Samsung themselves
these vendors
keep their black box design secret
making it making it harder
to verify its security
in this research we chose Samsung as a
test case
we reverse engineered the cryptographic
design of the key master
and we're interested in the security of
other protected cryptographic keys
and the relationship with higher level
protocols with a remote trusted party
as we can see
a trazon provides a logical separation
into two worlds the normal mode
which runs Android and the secure World
which runs the trusted OS
we follow the Android platform security
model which states that the hardware
protection of key of keys should
withstand a completely compromised
normal world
but in fact for our attacks we only
require a
sufficiently strong context in the
Android user mode to communicate with
trust and drivers
finally we have the Android Keystone
designed by Google
which provides cryptographic Key
Management
applications can request key generation
and the key master processed application
in the trust Zone will generate the key
in Secure hardware and before returning
it to the normal World it will encrypt
it with a hardware derived key
the keys can be stored on disk or useful
key at the station to prove that the key
was really generated in Secure Hardware
they can also be used for cryptographic
operations such as sign or encrypt
the important point is that the
plaintext material should only be
accessible by the k-master and should
never leave the trazon
never
okay so a quick wrap up
the key master protects the key material
and it should be the only entity
with plaintiff's key access
but is this assumption guaranteed
after this brief introduction let's dive
into our security analysis and before we
begin note that most details are
simplified and for more information
please see the extended paper
how do you even begin where do you start
you can download the firmware and
extract trusted applications
bootloaders and the kernel of The
Trusted OS
you can read the little available public
documentation and use security
certifications and the open source
archive
but for most of our research
we spent a lot of time reverse
engineering with gidra for dozens of
filmers and trusted operating systems
and how do you even interact with the
key master usually applications use a
binder API to communicate with the
crystal service
which uses the key master API to
communicate with transzone drivers that
execute a SMC or secure monitor call to
switch execution to the secure monitor
the secure monitor forwards the request
to The Trusted OS for example degrees
and eventually to the key master
we published an open source tool called
keybuster
that allows to directly communicate with
the key master
without any input filtering or
validation by the key master API we used
it to reproduce our proof of concept
attacks
now as you recall the key master
protects the key material by encrypting
it and after extensive reverse
engineering we saw that Samsung chose to
use asgcm with an encryption key that is
derived from a Hardware Key the rek
using a key derivation function
this is a very fragile construction
which is not misses resistant
and this is extremely vulnerable to IV
reuse
two interesting questions are
how are the encryption Keys derived
and now is the IV chosen
we saw that the salt parameter that is
used in the key derivation is the
shuttle digest of the following values
with some variation
in the first variation
the salt is a constant string followed
by a Target control application ID and
application data
in the second variation on Galaxy S9
they also bind the boot of the state
which is constant for our discussion
and only in the last variation on Galaxy
S10 and neural devices did Samsung get
16 bytes of Randomness that changed the
derived key every time
side note a possible explanation as to
why Samsung has three different
variations is the mobile Federal
Protection profile
which requires both other state binding
for example
so we saw that the client
can control the salt which means we can
have key reuse
to our surprise
we found that the client can also set
the encryption IV
so we also have IV reuse
now
asgcm is a stream Cipher that uses
counter mode internally to encrypt the
IV and serve it with the plain text
this leads to the following Ivory use
attack
given a key blob a that we wish to
recover we can extract the IV and using
the same the same IV and salt we can
import a known key B with the Keystone
API
and we can we get an encrypted blob B
now we simply solve the ciphertext of a
with the ciphertext of B
to get the Excel of the plain text and
then we Excel with the known plain text
of B
and we fully recover the key material of
a which is pretty exciting
a trivial observation is that once we
recover the key material we can bypass
any key
any key restriction such as protected
confirmation or biometric points and we
can simply transfer this amount to that
account without the trusted UI taken
over and without user consent
but this only works on Galaxy S9 and
similar devices and not on the latest
S10 and neural devices because the salt
changes the the right key changes every
time
it was surprised we also found that the
client is allowed to set the encryption
version using a hidden API
therefore an attacker could downgrade
all new key blobs to a vulnerable
encryption version and then use the IV
reuse attack we just saw to fully
recover any key blob
can this affect higher level protocols
with a remote trusted party
take for instance the Fido web
authentication standard which is which
uses public key cryptography to
authenticate the websites instead of
passwords
web authentication uses an internal
security element
called the platform Authenticator
to generate and use authentication keys
usually this is a external security key
such as ubikey
but we already have secure Hardware in
our pockets so we can just use the
Android custom based Key Master
the the important point is that an
attacker should not be able to recover
the authentication keys and should not
be able to clone the platform
authenticator so that your Netflix or
VPN subscription
will not be used on a different device
web authentication has two main stages
when the user wants to register
the device generates a keeper using the
keymaster trusted application in the
transom and uses key attest station to
prove that the key was really generated
in secure
if the certificate is valid the server
registers the user with the public key
then
when the user wants to log in
the server sends a unique Challenge and
after getting user consent the device
signs the challenge with the private key
in the secure order
if the signature is valid the user is
signed in
using gag attacks we can
downgrade any key blob recover it with
the ivarius attack and then we can clone
the platform authenticator since we can
sign any service server challenge with
the private key
in our demo on Galaxy S10 we use GDB to
implement the downgrade attack and then
key Buster to implement the ivarius
attack
and we used the Fido
the strong key Fido server and sample
application without any modifications
after registration we recovered the
privacy and verified against the
attestation certificate and to complete
our demo we use the different
application that doesn't use trustion at
all and simply uses the recovered key
we managed to successfully authenticate
against strong Keys remote server over
the internet
overall we saw that attackers could
recover cryptographic keys and use them
to steal your money or to steal your
identity
we reported our findings to Samsung in
May last year
the disclosure for the IV Rios attack
was pretty straightforward
in August they patched Galaxy S9 and
similar devices
assigned a high severity CV and remove
the option to set the IV from the API
which is great
but life is not so simple
and in June Samsung rejected the
downgrade attack
saying that it's impossible to create
downgraded key blocks
we discovered the same attack on Galaxy
s20 and S21 and we reported the
downgrade attack is a separate issue
but then Samsung
said that they think there's no security
no practical security impact
this make made us kind of sad
and we almost gave up but in a final
attempt
we sent our people with
which made us feel great
uh they assign the ice ability CV
patched all relevant devices
and completely removed the Legacy key
blob implementation
maybe the moral of the story is to never
give up
it's important it's important to note
that most of our research involved very
time intensive reverse engineering and
two weeks after our research was
published
the labsa soccer group leaked the entire
Samsung source code
we'd like to think that if those if this
code was open source then those issues
would have been found years ago
hopefully before reaching production
devices
and if not it would still make a
research much easier and much faster to
complete
also we saw similar iberius attacks
against Real World Systems over 10 years
ago
maybe it's true that people just don't
understand IVs
finally let's see what can we learn for
this
the root cause of both issues is API
misuse the client should not be able to
set the encryption IV or the encryption
version
also the key master
is a security critical application
should have minimal attack surface and
should not include any hidden code
instead the ivys in GCM should be unique
and you can use the Mrs resistant
authenticated encryption such as AES
gcmsav or use the message resistant
cryptographic Library such as think
you should also always use the latest
encryption version if possible
the bigger issue is in the composibility
with higher level protocols
in protocols like web authentication a
remote trusted party uses key at a
station to prove that the authentication
keys will really generated insecure
album
but as we just saw for Samsung devices
the secure Hardware can be flawed and
cryptographic keys can be extracted
but the fetal silver is no way of
knowing that and no way to reach it it
can't set the policy to reject
certificates from such devices because
the attestation certificate does not
contain any information about the
encryption method
in fact as long as we have
vendor-specific black book designs in
the ecosystem it's impossible to prove
the correctness of the composition we
hope that our work will motivate the the
use of an open stubborn open standard
design by Google for the key master
subsystem
side note about a month after our
research was published Google announced
changes to their key at the station
protocol making it a
making it possible to
to not
provision certificates to known
compromise devices this could be a step
in the right direction
in conclusion
we saw the dangerous pitfalls that arise
when the cryptographic design is kept
secret
we Advocate the use of an open standard
design that would would prevent such
issues
and as we just saw we think that that
there is no security by obscurity
the cryptographic design should be
reviewed by independent researchers and
should not rely on the difficulty of
reverse engineering proprietary systems
finally the design Choice the design
choice of the fragile asgcm for
authenticated keyboard encryption
deserves discussion after too many years
of IB reuse in Real World Systems
I want I want you to live today with two
things in mind
do cryptography in the open and make
sure it's misses resistant otherwise you
just might might get catastrophic
failure
thank you for your time feel free to ask
me any questions and join ayal for also
more questions thank you
[Applause]
thank you so much for that fantastic
presentation uh we're going to jump into
the question and answers here at the
moment we don't have any questions in
our virtual chat but please feel free to
throw some in there if our audience has
any questions feel free to please stand
up and we will bring you a microphone to
ask your questions to the presenters
we see you over there we're going to get
you a mic here
foreign
thank you uh I just wanted to ask you
what was the procedure like can you talk
about in details about how you reverse
engineered to find this flow in the key
master you mentioned a little bit of
like you extract something from the
public firmware that you found but uh
can you shed more light on it
yeah again they want me to explain how
do you start the research and how do you
explore the key master
is that the quest just a high level
detail of like what kind of analysis
that required uh to find this flow it's
a lot of manual reverse engineering
and a lot of like Delta walk yeah
no easy tricks
great thank you so much do we have any
other questions from the audience
I am not seeing any so oh we do have a
gentleman over in the corner there
uh hello thanks for the great
presentation uh why why you think that
DAV uh the IV was uh
um unlocked to be said uh by the AI
maybe for debugging purposes
we don't have a clear answer but maybe
it's possible that they wanted the
deterministic tests and they wanted like
to be able to encrypt and get the same
and ciphertext so they use the same IV
but that's not the right way to go
thank you
it looks like we have one more question
here
hello excellent presentation
um question on open sourcing
cryptographic libraries functions new
ways of doing things
do you see this is more of like an
academic exercise similar to what nist
does when you have new cryptographic
proposals or types or Solutions or are
you thinking more like what we would do
for open source software in general
where it's open to the world
do you want to take that yeah
um I think that's
um you want to have both if there's a
new protocol that has been suggested
like Google is suggesting now for uh
provisioning keys for the station we
feel this stuff should be described to
the public and should be open to
comments in incorporates other people
from the security Community either from
Academia or industry doing the process
which it's like this is doing but not
necessarily
um need to be by government entity after
this is done any
cryptographic implementation I think
should be open sourced as much as
possible so everybody can look at the
code and see that the actual
implementation is also secure so we want
to have both options basically
yes so there was a bit of a echo so just
like to follow his point there there
should be like a collaboration between
Academia and Industry like in the
standard standardization of TLS and the
any cryptographer if they saw the code
they would immediately tell you that
there's an issue and the
yeah you should make cryptographic code
AS open source as possible because the
security should lie in the design and
not in the uh in it's been hidden like
the obscope the obscurity does not help
in this case
thank you
do we have any other questions from the
audience
we see over there sir and we're getting
you the microphone
like to also compliment you on your
great presentation
um at the beginning you said that this
was a fully certified design
had searched from Phipps and I think
also Europeans so what is your message
to the certification authorities about
you know how they go about certifying
designs like this based on your
experience
yeah I think the message is uh to to
involve also independent researchers or
at least to to make sure like maybe
those issues like the fragmentation of
the different variations vocals because
of the uh
it's not fips but it's the mdfpp the
Federal Protection profile and maybe
like in trying to support that they met
made some issues but it's important to
know that there were professional
security Labs that did I guess they had
source code access and they did like
very detailed security analysis and they
also published some security
certificates but it was still not enough
to find a very trivial issue so maybe
they need they need to reconsider and
think what's next yeah if I can add to
this
then we have multiple examples if you
take um open SSL code which have
versions that are fips certified you're
still finding bugs and vulnerabilities
in this code time and time again but
this is because open SSL is open source
and any researcher in any person can
download the code and never look at it
so I feel that going to have a baseline
of requirements for certification might
be a good idea but this is not enough to
make sure that software is secure and we
need a lot of eyes looking at the this
type of code and again that this is
certification this might be good but
it's not a substitute to the whole
research community and trying to look at
the solutions
okay I just have a quick question so
like it makes a lot of sense for big
projects that have impact of millions
and millions of users to have it open
sourced and research what about smaller
projects I just looked up the AES GCM
website and it doesn't say anything
about read a Wikipedia page it doesn't
say anything about IV replay attacks and
the weaknesses of IB so what resources
would you recommend for people who just
are not going to have researchers
looking at their code because our
project might be seen by a hundred
business side type people we still need
to make sure stuff is cryptographically
secure
what sort of resources would you
recommend
yeah I would recommend to use a
something like a message resistant
cryptography libraries like think by
Google or other libraries that really
help you
like even if you don't have the
necessary cryptographic background like
still make it work and yeah it's an
important point because the cryptography
engineering requires very gentle and
precise operations so yeah you should
always at least know what are you using
know the security assumptions because in
GCM the security assumptions is that the
IVs are unique and you should try to to
avoid the misuse yeah
great thank you that is time for us and
I want to thank the presenters here
um we've got some wonderful information
from this and if you there are
additional questions please feel free to
speak to alone in the hallways thank you
for coming to black hat and thank you to
our presenters
thank you
[Music]