[Music]
foreign
security expert at Ledger my daily rule
is to evaluate Hardware wallets against
fault injection and search General
attacks and today I'm going to present
unlimited results breaking firmware
encryption of esp32 V3 it's a joint work
between me and Olivier rivo and Adrienne
tier
well why I'm going to to do this
presentation today
I think most of you you know esp32 it's
a very well-known microcontroller it's a
low power SOC
it has been deployed in the market since
several years and espresso actually
announced it's selling like 100 million
devices in the market by 2018.
and what's very important for me is that
it recently it has been deployed as a
main microcontroller
in the hardware wallet called Zed the
vendor is block stream
and if you are going to open the
hardware wallet actually you are going
to find an esp32 V3 chip and also an
external flash memory however the
external flash memory is used to store
the an encrypted firmware however the
firmware encryption key is stored in the
esp32 V3
so my role actually is to evaluate this
Hardware wallet against fault injection
and search channel attacks in order to
extract this key
why esp32v3 not esp32v1 for example by
the way there is no any esp32 V2
so regarding esp32v1 it was attacked by
limited results in 2019
the main idea is that they already
attacked the secure Boot and Flash
encryption mechanisms they used power a
powerful injection
using bar glitches in order to perturb
the effuse protection bits during the
power up and after successful forces
they already obtained the ifuse keys the
firmware encryption and secure boot keys
as a reaction against this attack
expressive announced esp32v3
by 20 2020 and the main idea is to patch
a
the new version against the the attack
of limited results
so the new version esp32v3
has several features
like new secure boot they use a an RSA
based secure boot in order to avoid
storing any private keys inside the
effuse and also as announced by espresso
that the new version contains Contour
measures against fault injection attacks
by hardware and software
well the outline of my presentation
first I'm going to present the security
feature of esp32 V3
and also after that I'm going to to show
you a homemade fault injection setup
that I'm going to use it in order to
evaluate esp32 V1 I mean to reproduce
attack of limited results using
electromagnetic filter injection and
after that applying the same scenario on
esp32v3
and after that I'm going to discover a
new attack path using side Channel
attacks to break the firmware encryption
and then I'm going to to make the attack
practical on a hardware wallet I mean
the jet Hardware wallet that I already
showed previously and I'm going to
terminate by the vendor reply and the
conclusion
so regarding the esp32 security features
well esp32 has a lot of features but let
me concentrate on the security feature
of the chip itself so it has secure boot
it has flash encryption and also 128
bytes of OTP
in order to store some secrets and also
some crypto Hardware accelerators such
as es RSA
random number generators and elliptic
curve as well you can use the ESP tool
in order to activate the above features
and the ESP tool it's an open source
tool which delivered by espressive and
you can find it online on GitHub for
example
well regarding the ifuse organization
the ifus as I told you it's like 128
bytes and it's divided into four slots
for example the first slots the first
slot is used and reserved for the system
for the system purposes in order to
store the setting of the of the chip
itself I mean the the flash encryption
mode the secure boot if it's activated
or not for example and you can find
block one and block 2 in order to store
flash encryption keys and also the
secure boot keys in a row and the last
slot block 3 is used for the user
application itself
well let me say that it's impossible to
to get access by the software on block
one and block two because they are
protected using ifuse protection bits
which are restored in the boot ROM
itself
and uh the only entity which is
responsible for reading those keys
actually is is a hardware of esp32 that
already use this kind of of keys during
the power up in order to whatever to to
perform the flash decryption or to
perform as well as a secure boot
well let me talk about secure Boot and
they have two versions of secure boot
they have secure boot version one for
example so the main idea is that if you
have a firmware the firmware had it has
a good loader and the public key the
main idea is that you have a key which
is stored in Block 2 for example which
is responsible for the secure Boot and
this key is used to encrypt
the bootloader and the public key using
es-256 and after that the output is
hashed using shaft 512 in order to
generate what we call a digest and the
digestive the digest is a store outside
in the in the flash memory and during
the power up the same process is
executed
and after that the comparison is
performed in order to to take the
decision to continue or not based on the
comparison if it's correct or not
well regarding regarding the flash
encryption
as I told you it's a security feature of
esp32
the main idea is to protect the the
firmware which is stored outside in the
external flash from any axis
well as a flash encryption uses block
one for uh for encrypting and decrypting
the Flash content
and in order to encrypt The Flash
they use es decryption and in order to
decrypt The Flash they use es encryption
and the during the power up the flash
decryption for example is performed
however they use something called the
key tweak in order to change the key
every 32 bytes and this key tweak is
like an address dependent so if you know
the address you can generate the key
tweak so at the end you will find it
will be like a constant and it's only
used to change the key of research to
two bytes
the first slot which is is manipulated
from the flesh during the power up
is a bootloader data which is is stored
at address uh one key decimal hexadecim
so you can use the following commands in
order to activate and store uh the flash
encryption key through the ESP tool
theft the attack of limited results
well
as a concentrated on glitching the ifuse
protection bits during the power up you
can see here in the red the already
register support trace the power
consumption Trace during the power up
and in yellow is a voltage as a voltage
source to the to the chip itself you can
find that during the power up they start
to inject some glitches you can see here
the voltage drop and this is the correct
moment that the already glitched the
ifuse protection bits once they already
performed a successful fault after that
they can execute the memory read command
in order to dump the ifuse slots
containing the flash encryption key and
the secure boot
let me talk now about the voltage
injection setup
why we need or why we perform uh fault
faults so the main idea is to perturb
the chip during the execution of
sensitive operations for example if you
if you have a secure boot which is
running you can inject
let me say electromagnetic fault
injection or laser or pole power fault
injection in order to bypass the the
security or the or the signature
verification during the execution of
secure boot
and also if you have an es which is
running you can inject faults during the
execution of the es in order to execute
or to attack the key using a
differential filter analysis for example
well I'm going to concentrate in my
evaluation about
electromagnetic faulty injection and I'm
going to use a homemade fault injection
tool we call it silicon toaster in order
to inject the electromagnetic pulses
the main idea that you have a very high
voltage which is stored in the caps and
this voltage actually is applied to the
or into the electromagnetic
electromagnetic probe here which is like
a coil in order to generate a current
and the current is going to generate an
electromagnetic field and the
electromagnetic field is going to be in
touch with the surface of the chip
trying to generate or to perturb the
chip and trying to inject faults
the tool is able to inject faults up to
one k volts and I'm going to use it for
the evolution
well in order to obtain a very stable
setup we decided to fabricate a BCB
so the main idea is that you have an
esp32 here and on the top of the PCB
and after that there's the external
flash and we select it actually to have
some vdd pins or eyes here in order to
control the value of the vdt during the
experiment and also there is an external
oscillator here in order to control the
clock
well regarding the electromagnetic
faulty injection setup so I'm using a
silicon toaster in order to inject the
electromagnetic pulses and also I'm
using an oscillator here in order to
monitor the power consumption during the
experiment and I'm using the x y z table
here in order to move the Probe on the
surface of the chip
and also I'm using a scaffold which is a
board which is fabricated inside our
the computer
well the dictionary
for the first time I'm trying to
to prove that the ability of of of the
electromagnetic voltage injection tool
in order to inject successful faults so
I'm going to first apply
um fault injection on a glitchable
application on a very simple application
code on esp32v1 the only thing to do
that
the target actually is to is to be sure
that the the tools that I have is
effective
and to keep some parameters in order to
go for the next step so next step of
course is to reproduce the attack of
limited results
and after that I'm going to follow the
same scenario that I did on esp32v1 and
repeat it again on esp62 V3 to see if
there's a difference or not
well let's talk about the
electromagnetic fault injection on
esp62v1
you can see here on the left this is a
glitchable code
there is a loop and the main idea is to
inject a code to
the counter and on the same time I'm
going to to scan the electromagnetic
Probe on the chip surface here
well after scanning all the chip surface
using 500 voltage I mean the is a pulse
value and regarding the polarity of the
of the pulse I mean I'm injecting a
positive polarity and I'm scanning 500
trials per spot and the motor stable is
like to 200 micrometer I found here
upper on the right I found a very
interesting Zone where I obtained
successful faults that I was able to to
skip from the loop so this means that
the fault injection tool that I have is
effective and I can obtain some
successful faults using it so now the
next step is to reproduce now the attack
of limited results on esp62v1
well
the steps is that I followed it's like
the first thing is that you have you
have a firmware you encrypt you store
the firmware encrypted and the external
flash
and after that you enable uh you enables
a firmware encryption through is a
command that I show here and after that
I started to track the power consumption
of the chip during
or while the flash encryption is enabled
I found that
there is a very interesting early
activity here after the power up
that may be very interesting in order to
shoot or to inject faults during this
period why because I make I'm expecting
that the if use fault the ifuse
protection bits are manipulated during
this this time
well so the scenario that I use the I
used only one single filter injection
pulse here it's a count and after that
I'm going to initialize the policy
generator to to deliver like the pulse
switch and also the offset and to
control them and after that I'm going to
restart the chip and the during the
restart I'm going to inject some faults
and in case of a successful fault after
that I'm go I'm going to execute the
read memory command in order to dump the
effuse
surface I already obtained some
successful faults
however I obtained two different
successful faults here you can find
after the experiment log for example
here Loop Number Four you can find this
is the correct key that that I already
stored however in five I flipped the
this key by only one one bit here
why there is only one bit difference
because there is a chance that when I
injected the faulted during the power up
maybe I also corrupted the the value of
the ifus which are manipulated from from
the chip itself so this it's not a
permanent fault actually but it may
happen if you if you already inject a
fault during a certain time during its
power up
so I started to register the board
traces in case of successful faults and
here you can find this is the correct
timing and you can find here the effect
of the electromagnetic uh pulse during
the power up and on the right here you
can find the The Zone where I already
obtained the successful Force
evaluation so I already you injected
successful faults in order to dump the
ifuse reproducing the attack of limited
results
on asp32v1 I used only a single fault
single fault pulse and the success rate
was close to 0.6 percentage
and now lets me
pre-produce or take the same scenario on
esp32 V3
well let me recap the counter measures
that has been added to uh
to esp32 V3 so zero
more es for example so the store only is
public key which is not secret and safe
uses and also the new version is hard is
hardened against faulty injection
attacks and software on the hardware as
announced by expressive and also they
added another features
called uart disable in order to stop the
communication with the bootstrom to
execute this kind of read memory
commands
so the same scenario I have the
glitchable application and I started to
scan again
esp32 V3 chip using the electromagnetic
fault injection
I kept the same attack parameters and I
obtained also a successful fault I'm I
mean trying to skip from the loop of the
glitchable application so I was able to
to skip successfully from this Loop and
you can find here there is a very
interesting Zone that I already obtained
successful faults well this means that
esp62v3 is not equipped with a fault
injection counter measures like for
example glitch detectors or something
like that so the chip doesn't have any
Contour measures against fault injection
but let me now try the attack of the
effus uh on asp32 V3
I followed the same scenario I have a
key I stored it in the fuses I enabled
the firmware flash encryption and I
stored the encrypted flash in the
external memory
and I started to to track the power
consumption and I found that the power
consumption during the power up in case
of esp32 V3 is completely different from
esp32 V1
so you can see now the difference there
there is a three uh different blocks
which are added here
so this means that they don't have the
same boot ROM
they may have some verification blocks
which are added in order to fight
against fault injection attacks well
this means that I need multiple faults
in order to perform a successful attack
so I changed the attack scenario
I try to randomize
the number of faults and also I follow
the same scenario here I initialize the
policy generator and also I restarted
the chip trying to inject faults during
the power up and after that in case of a
successful fault I already I will
execute the if you read memory command
I would like to stress here on not
activating that you are disabled for the
moment okay
well unfortunately I have not obtained
any successful fault the only thing that
I obtained I obtained zeros which is the
case that the success the fault is not
successful or I obtained as a timeout
why I obtained a lot of timeout that
ship got crashed several times because
of I injected electromagnetic faulty
injection several pulses in a row so
this means that the electromagnetic
fault injection is very aggressive to
the chip if you are injecting several
pulses in a row try and the chip got
crashed several times actually so for
the moment I'm I'm like in a situation
that okay I have a new version of the
chip
it seems that esp32v3 has a different
boot drum that contains counter measures
against fault injection attacks and
multiple fault faults may be needed but
unfortunately using electromagnetic
faulty injection several pulses are very
aggressive to this achievement I
obtained a lot of time out so I have to
find another attack scenario or another
attack path
well during the the investigation of the
ifuse attack I started to look at the
documents of expressive trying to find
something different to do so I just
found that they didn't talk about side
Channel attacks there is no any counter
measure so maybe if I'm going to switch
the text scenario to side Channel
attacks and targeting The Flash
decryption maybe I'm going to gain
well so it's a motivation for me to have
a chip that which already batched
and to find another attack scenario so
what I'm I I have been thinking to do is
to Target The Flash encryption
decryption during the power up
and after that if I will do that
successfully I can control the flash
content and after that I can perform
what we call correlation power analysis
in order to attack the flesh encryption
or decryption key
but before
describing the attack in detail let me
stress on some search channel basics
for example like leakage detection
so why we need leakage detection so
assume that you have an es and the es is
running on on on on a chip
and the power consumption of the chip
for example is very low and you are not
able to identify the rounds of the es so
it's better to perform this kind of of
statistical tools like leakage detection
in order to localize exactly where is
the ES
so we use it actually to reduce the time
of the evaluation
and there are several techniques in the
literature that you can find for example
the SNR the signal to noise ratio in icv
or the t-test for example here I'm I'm
going to use SNR signal to noise ratio
that you can uh use it using the for the
following formula here where X is the
real trades real portraits and Y is a
label uh
of the value
regarding the correlation power analysis
it's a it's a very well known side
Channel attack
and the main idea is that for example if
you have an es or you have a crypto
operation and when you measure the power
consumption during the execution of this
crypto operation the power consumption
is like a key dependent so this means
that
if you have an es and you are going to
register the power consumption traces
during the execution of this es you can
build an offline model for example
trying to assume all the keys if you are
targeting one byte of the key so you are
going to have a 256 assumptions of the
key and after that the correct
assumption is going to give the maximum
correlation between the model and the
measurement itself well after the model
you can use several leakage leakage
models such as Heming weight or Hamming
distance for example and if you are
targeting the yes we prefer we always
prefer to perform the Hamming weight on
the Xbox's output of the Xbox because we
we believe that the Xbox is the most
consuming part during the execution of
the ES
so China Tech setup so what I need for
the moment I need a high-end
oscilloscope in order to capture the
power traces during the power up
and also I have an esp32 chip on the top
of scaffold board and after that I'm
going to enable The Flash encryption
mechanism
let me recap again what happens during
the flash encryption so it's used to
protect the external memory
and there is a key which is stored in
Block one which is used for encrypting
and decrypting the Flash
and this key is tweaked every 32 bytes
however the first address which is
manipulated from the external flash is
address 1K which is a bootloader which
is stored in the external flash so this
means that if I can control the the
address which is uh which is like a
bootloader it's external flash and then
I can Target the the firmware decryption
during the power up I can gain and I can
perform this kind of Channel attacks
well I started to to look at the power
consumption during during the power up
while the firmware encryption is is
activated so you can find here in red
the power consumption of the chip
and in yellow I started to spy on the
SPI clock of the external flash in order
to see where the data is manipulated
because as I told you the first slot
which is manipulated is the bootloader
which is stored at address 1K so you can
see here there are two slots flash
encryption one I mean the communication
one and also communication too and after
that there are two zones A and B so for
the moment
the first slot of the bootloader I mean
the first 32 bytes are manipulated
whether in a or in B zone so in order to
know exactly where the the 32 bytes are
manipulated I am going to perform an SNR
on the value of the bootloader itself so
I'm going to follow the scenario I have
some
some random 32 bytes for example to
generate and after that I'm going to
raise the Flash and write
is a bytes on the flash at address
one key this hexadecimal and after that
I'm going to restart the chip and then
capture a Power Trace
well I started to look at Zone a for
example and running the SNR on the on
the bootloader values
and it seems that the SNR curve is here
the 32 values of the of the of the of
the bootloader you can find here the SNR
is very noisy so this means that
um
the first 32 bytes are not manipulated
during the Zone actually
and after that I tried to to do the same
but around Zoom B for example so I find
a very
a very clear SNR here you can find a 32
Peaks that means that the values the 32
bytes of the bootloader are manipulated
here in Zoom B so this means that after
manipulating the first slot from the
bootloader so this means that the flash
decryption is performed just after
in order to
know where is the es exactly performing
you can see that I have a 32 bytes are
manipulated from uh from The Flash
are divided into 16 bytes each one and
after that there is an es which is
running two times in order to decrypt
The Flash so I started to
um
to trigger where the ciphertext of the
first slot and the second slot is the
ciphertext are manipulated where exactly
so now I can see that okay I have the
SNL on the plain text in the zoom and
also I have for example the ciphertext
the SNL on the ciphertext so in between
there will be the ES
so I targeted the SNR of the first slot
of the ciphertext I find there are some
bytes which are here so this means that
the es encryption of the first slot are
executed just before
and also I I repeated the same to Target
the snare of the of the last 16 bytes of
the bootloader which is a store that
address one key here so this means that
before the zones there is the es which
is executed so now I'm pretty sure about
the es where it's manipulated I mean the
es for example of the second part of the
bootloader so it may be manipulated here
actually so I can perform the side
channel here
well
for the moment
I don't have the ability to store
several keys and change the key every
time on the OTP because it's like on OTP
so I won't be able to to know where the
intermediate values of of the years are
manipulated but in order to be sure from
the time zone of the execution of the
years I started to reverse the results
of the CPA I know for example history
and I started to
to Target the history to run correlation
power analysis and to see the maximum
correlation of the Q3 for example where
I can find the maximum Peak so if I can
find the maximum peak of the correct key
this means that yes this zone is the es
where uh where's for example the second
bootloader slot are encrypted during
this Zoom so I found several maximum
peaks of K3 for example the correct
history here one
two and three so now I'm pretty sure
that the es is executed here but
the problems that I have now is that I
already okay I I managed to get 100K
traces but using the external flash
every time I write and erase uh there is
The Flash writing and erasing limitation
so I'm I'm just limited with 100K traces
so every time I have to uh I have to
remove the remove the Flash and solder
another another Flash and I found there
is uh there's a certain difference
between the behavior because of the
noise that that may be generated from
changing the flesh every time so we took
the decision actually in order to to
make a flash emulator I mean to to store
the 32 bytes the random 32 bytes on
shift register on a scaffold and deliver
it to the MCU during the power up so in
this case I will be able to register
unlimited traces
well when I removed the Flash and I used
the flash Emirate emulator I was able to
to find and improve actually the signal
to noise ratio of the of the power
consumption
and you can find here for example
several Power traces which are uh
which are up to to each other's and what
I used here I used a very simple
alignment to in order to align them to
to be ready for performing this kind of
correlation power analysis
and I started to track history the
correct history for example so I found
here this is a maximum correlation of
the correct key I mean Q3 you can find
it's a it's a there's a very big
difference between the correct key and
other key assumptions so this means that
I'm able to perform a correlation power
analysis here successfully well
regarding the model
uh the leakage model that I used I used
the Hamming weight for the for the first
round and for the second round I use the
Hamming distance between the two boxes
of the first round and the second round
and and actually this this kind of tweak
to find the model of the second round it
helped me to to attack some keys that I
already I was not able to attack them
using the normal Hamming weight model
like the first round otherwise you are
going to find three keys which are not
very well uh
attacked successfully so you have to do
some Brute Force attacks for example in
order to attack those keys
well so now I was able to collect more
traces I was able to for example to get
2 million traces so I got I got like 2
million traces I aligned with them and I
started to uh to to perform what we call
a key rank in order to measure the
success of the uh of the attack I mean
the key rank when you increase number of
traces the correct key should goes to
one this means this is the correct key
and I was able to attack all the keys
except key zero for example within like
400k traces however if you would like to
attack k0 and you don't like to brute
force it you have to wait for example
for uh two million traces in order to
attack it successfully
well for the moment
I have to also
activate the other security features of
esp32 V3 like secure Boot and uart
disable and for me actually this kind of
security features are not very important
because a secure boot is already
executed after the flash decryption so
the first the first operation that which
is performed is The Flash encryption and
also for the UR disabled here we don't
care about you all disabled because we
we are not communicating with the chip
uh with the boot ROM of the chip in
order to execute this kind of read
memory command because I'm using uh the
flash emulator
so after activating all the security
features I was able to attack all the
keys
all the keys of firmware encryption that
used for firmware encryptions and 32
bytes of the key as I told you there is
only key zero here which is not stable
but you have to wait for more traces up
to one one million and a half for
example to to get a very stable attack
or to Brute Force risky and this is very
easy actually
so it was a practical attack now so I
started to invest the attack results
that I obtained in order to uh to attack
the hardware wallet that I mentioned it
at the beginning which is Jed wallet
it's a block Stream So as I told you
that Z is an open source and open
Hardware wallet unfortunately it doesn't
store the pin inside the MCU itself the
pin is is verified on the server of
block stream
so the only thing that I can perform now
is the FL the
the external flash it has a public key
and a private key of the user that can
communicate with a server of block
Stream So if I am able to uh
if I'm able to attack the private key of
the user this means that I can clone the
device and inject some back doors
so what I did actually is just to remove
the esp32 from V3 from the from the red
wallet and plug it inside my setup just
solder it in on the PCB and it start to
repeat the experiment and I was able to
dump all the keys
as I told you within like 400 kit races
I have all the keys except key zero
which can be brought forced easily
so now you can find that this is the
encrypted firmware of that and I use the
keys that I already dumped by side
Channel attack in order to decrypt and I
was able to obtain the private key of
the user that which is used for the
communication with the block stream
server
so now I can clone the wallet I can
inject the back door for example to
perform transaction to substituted
addresses
what we call like even made attack
let me talk about the vendor reply and
the conclusion
I started to communicate with espressive
in October last year
and we started to to talk each other
about the counter measures and how they
can improve the product actually and in
may they published an a security
advisory about the attack and the
conclusion of the security advisory is
that this attack is applicable to all
esp32 chips in the market
including esp32 V3 and period versions
esp32 S2 C3 S3
well and unfortunately they won't be
able to patch this kind of
vulnerabilities what they have to do is
to change the Silicon
and and actually in their security
advisory they wrote that the future
products of espresso food contain this
kind of Contour measures against side
Channel attacks
so let me conclude
you can see that I already presented a
a deep Hardware evaluation for asp32 V3
using electromagnetic filter injection
and side Channel attacks so by
experimental results I proved that esp32
has a hardened boot ROM against faulty
injection attacks
and also
when I found that I am not able to
attack the trip using electromagnetic
fault injection I changed the scenario
the text scenario to side Channel
attacks and I was able to dump the
overall key which is used for the
firmware encryption
using like 400k traces
and the attack is generic and works on
all the products of espressive
and well at the end I would like just to
say that protecting against faulty
injection is not sufficient and also the
vendor should consider this kind of
attacks and to combine them with the
faulty injection so this means that if
you if you are a vendor so you have to
consider seriously combining fault
injection inside Channel attacks counter
measures together
thank you very much
foreign
[Music]