[Music]
okay so we're happy to be here today
first time ever in South America for me
so I'm very excited this target is just
a team with two people
me and my co-speaker but unfortunately
he's not coming because he's too busy so
I'm here to reap to represent the team
okay so this talks about fighting the
others in immediate system using the
latest advanced fuzzing technology named
court coverage coverage Qaeda father
okay so a bit myself I'm working in
Nanyang Technological University in
Singapore and I mostly do my research in
a low-level system stuff like opening
system virtual machine binary analysis
and so on and I happen to be the author
and maintain a few reversing projects
capstone disassembler in Econ inverter
and Keystone assembler okay so my
co-speaker guys on his he's looking
inside II wonder because in commotion
company in China he's an expert on
Hardware reversing IOT security and
blockchain research okay it's so a bit
about what we presented a force on we
take a look it in some background on
Caffrey's guided fatha and the idea is
that we want to bring this technique to
embedded system so you want to build a
bit further using this guided faceting X
and to do this we need to show many
problems one of them is that how to
emulate a firmware so we can use a
father and an insider and we need some
new dynamic energy accommodation so
we can first own cap CPUs and next we'll
show you how we build our ready father
and after that you have a pair sometimes
some have some simple demo a quick demo
okay first of all what's the what's the
first thing the ideas fishing pond
fasting is the automated testing
technique to five bucks so the idea that
we fit some craft input eight to two
programs that we want to test the
parameter on to five bucks inside and
you can see he's a loop we have a loop
here so he sends a craft input later to
the program that went to five bucks
inside and when the program run will
monitor the program to detect the
violation and okay you can easily
multiple bucks like errors like crash or
hang or memory leaking and if we focus
on export export upon box like memory
corruption or information the King we
can fire funder abilities
so the idea is a on the faster because
the program you want to fight back
inside usually has a very big very huge
code space right so the idea is that we
want to generate the good input so when
the faster run the father can fire as
much code as possible or in the in in in
the other word we want to maximize the
cocoa fees to file to have a better
chance to five bucks so a few type has a
black box passing and white box passing
as a first to type so max black prophecy
is Karen Schimpf own damn father so the
idea that we fit input into some random
input into the father and the father ran
the program and the father doesn't know
how the prom work inside just send
random input and hopefully it cross so
backbone fasting is very easy to be very
easy to program to to maintain but it's
kept done because it doesn't know
hardware inside so it doesn't know how
to delete the whole input to SSI a lot
of code inside the program
so since the next type father is kawaii
box father
so this one is unlike by Professor
y-buffers a before the reason in poofles
program each child to analyze the
program to understand it how it works
inside how is the structure so we can
say this a better input so Italy the
idea why box water is very nice it
should be if we do this we should have
face methods all right
but Italy the story but in reality it
doesn't really work because hypothesis
they use some very complicated and heavy
program analysis technique so in fact
why box mother is French law pretty slow
so it doesn't work well so we come to
the next the third time father is very
box fetish something in bitching
bitching why and black and the the other
neighbour box father is is a carries
qaeda father
so yeah this guy father is they use the
same concept but you can see that when
the father runs the program it is human
it so thanks thanks to the
instrumentation the father know what's
going on which code is already exercised
so in turn you can generate a better
input so you can see that this catheter
is much smarter than the black go faster
because it know how it was house program
works inside but it doesn't you heavy
and very complicated program and a sis
technique like white box father so you
can see that is true to be very
effective this way if it's because ready
faster is very easy to use and very easy
to setup and actually it fall out a box
and daddy father becomes chanting in
phasing technology and one type
of this catheter is American fuzzy loop
or AFL and in the last few years ffs are
a lot of box okay so the idea is that in
the last two years I've used some credit
as a place on AFL but that kinda Tata I
was only for our phone system for PC now
if we want to bring this further to run
on the imperial system which is very
different from the power phone system
like PC so to know that we have many
issue we want to bring this puzzle to
run on an embedded system
the first one is ratcheted the embrace
system they are all very restricted the
second issue that they are very close
and the last one is we do not have a lot
of support for embrace system when you
build us this catheter
okay source of health issues register
system so you can see that in every
system line router or IP camera or so on
they do not provide you the view in
exercise they do not give you access to
the to the to the English system so that
mean you cannot come into the imposition
and view your own tunes to be your own
father so it's very clear because inside
on the English system they do not
provide user compilers or any like
development tools like debugger only an
assistant so that's the first issue
you cannot easy easily put your father
or any development tools in to impress
system the second issue is a closed
system so you can see that in many
emitter system they do not provide a
source code so we do not have a source
code so what we have only is that we had
binary only the firmware is our initial
score on
so this is a big issue because all or
most of the public gyda faster you can
find in the public nowadays they rely on
the source code you need to source code
and you compile the source code using
sunlight special compiler and this this
special capillary instrument program and
the further in turn around this
instrumented program inside the father
so you see that we need to source code
to compile warm right actually to be
fair there are some techniques to to
faster binary only froze upon AFL the
support chemo mode so you can emulate
the program in in qumu mode and run
inside FL but actually this technique is
very slow and just many limitation many
programs that you cannot run in cue mode
in inside FL so the last issue is that
most faster they appear for Intel chip
only so the reason is that once here the
program has a source code right do you
want to build this program to run on the
imposition no because empiricism are
very very poor in terms of performance
so usually you have source code you can
position to run on power phone system
which is PC right which has a lot of
memory a lot of stories and has very
fast bishop cpu so you can see that most
puzzles they are before entirely but not
for every system not for chips running
on a map City for miss and PowerPC and
so on so one clear example is that if we
use some dynamic instrumentation to
build a faster we rely on some Republic
dpi like Peno dino Morea right but pin
wash upon pin come from india it support
cpu on x86 cheap only it doesn't support
as a cpu so no more no support for am am
64 MIPS or policy for pin and it's the
same thing for dynamo do
okay so we see that you have many issues
we want to bring the qaeda facile to
embrace system okay so we need to show
many issue the first one is how to view
our father to run on a PA system so it
came up with one solution is just to
emulate the from one so one thing you
can see that coming from PC we go to in
the system everything is kowtow CPUs
much slower you have much less memory we
don't have like gigabyte memory on in
the system but only typically you have
like 16 or 32 mega by and of course
storage is much much less we don't have
a terroristic better by Hadees on the
eBay system so okay you can see that the
idea is that a very obvious the ideas I
want to fight back inside this in the
system I buy the device right and we try
to somehow inject our father or any any
analysis tool inside that in the system
and actually initially we bought some
device like that on like like that MDK
but on on the screen but it turned out
even if somehow we try to you can try to
inject our father into Windows a device
it's very slow you can run the father
base very slow so what's the solution
the idea is that now we want to 5 bucks
inside this device we come up with an
association we try to create a firmware
the device and bring this firmware to a
better performance system and try to
fight back in that but we do not fight
back in the original device so the first
issues are how to get the firmware so
there are many way to get from iPhones
report
you can take out a fast memory from the
device and extract from my duty from the
flash memory and you get from where I
the other way that we can somehow I
check the firmware from some IP k some
Android a patient for some reason they
have format inside or you can snip the
traffic when the device is updated the
last solution is that many vendors they
provide the firmware on the eruption so
people can get it uploaded and operated
so yeah you can have many ways to get
from web to device we want to fiber 3
the easy way that with the firmware we
try to find a real device the support
the CPUs for saponin
you get a form of the MIPS MIPS device
with the ibless system we try to fire
hood bot of meat and we bring this from
where to run on the device right for the
am from where you can buy Raspberry Pi
device and try to run this firmware on
that raspberry P same thing for am 64
you can you can buy raspberry Petri and
render for my on that however we found
that this cap solution is not very good
so on observe is an is that autumn al
team has two people right
we actually don't remotely we are not in
the same place so we do not want to buy
the same device and back-end for between
us to work together so you came up with
another solution how about we get a
firmware but we do not run on the real
device we do we do not need to buy any
device but we try to emulate that into
into some virtual machine right
so in this case we do not need any
device alone
so there's many a fantasy if we have the
firmware you can emulate that in in some
virtual machine you can it because the
virtual machine is at its own bow shock
really should wear emulator so when you
can it as many call as you want you
could put one core to call Chico for
call into that virtual machine which we
do not have in your device you can eat a
lot of more Rams compared to the
original device so first point for for
Em's in the system you can put up two
line happy iPad memory into the virtual
machine and of course you can put a lot
more stories into the virtual machine
one more advantage is that you can scale
up so if we fire on two fibers in on in
this form where you can run many many
virtual machine of this form way at the
same time and you can do a parallel
father so there are many many effort is
so it decided to go this way
so ok when we did this we look into the
past and to see how people chose this
program so some people came up with some
way so even the firmware they can they
can put this firmware into like youmu
pushing machine right remover later and
there's some how they try to conflicts a
premium little to run this from way so
she can put it up and done everything
inside the remove virtual machine
however we found that this doesn't work
very well because we have many cap in
the system right and each english system
had different different hardware now we
want to bring this firmware into
qmo Kumu need to be able to support own
cap hardware's available in all those in
the system and I should actually cream
with other support medical device so
this cap solution doesn't work doesn't
work our own
so what did we do
so now we tested we decided that we have
from where we try to emulate that into
the in the virtual machine right but
virtual machine does a support uncap my
firmware so result and we had some ideas
usually when we've tried to fire box
inside firmware we try to attack
something that has big attack surface
all right and usually from where the
biggest attack suffice in in the form is
that some service some internet some
network service that expose to the
network for support on the in the system
that we try to attack has worse server
running inside right so the idea is that
we do not want to yourself on the
firmware but we just want to emulate
that processor quad or really try to
five bucks inside right
so is this guy force upon e1 to fight
back inside this firmware which has web
server we just child to immolate the
workshop only so the idea is that once
we got the firmware from somewhere we
extract the packet binary force upon a
TT p d-- program forms up from where we
get it out and bring and bring this
packet finally to our virtual machine
and we try to emulate sup program in our
virtual machine and we attack it as i
see that's what the whole idea behind
this so okay we check out the binary
form the firmware we bring that to
sunlight standard distribution running
on our virtual machine for support Linux
form is Linux forum Linda's forums
before we copy force upon ATT PD from
from where to our virtual machine and
try to run it so on easy way that we run
this documentary in size inside chroot
on our virtual machine right so however
we found that this one is not very it's
not a very good way because
we run the process inside the CSU we
need to deal with her medical issues
first upon we need to run debugger then
debugger need to handle like on on
capital account copy the things inside
CSU so we decided that we want to avoid
issues and you want to run everything as
natively as possible we decided that you
copy the target binary to the virtual
machine around it so first issues that
find out foul we could not run it so you
can see that on streets on the
screenshot you can see that it it cannot
fight being bashed right actually being
bad is always there but you can see here
inside that it cannot fight the bin pass
so if our that we're on fire on this bin
bus in front of that this one depends on
one shared leg file which doesn't exist
inside our virtual machine so to sow
seeds to sow this program is just copy
this one this far from the firmware to
over to our virtual machine so the first
issue is not done yet because once you
copy the original binary to our virtual
machine we miss many many dependencies
many many standard program for support
here you can see that we miss some some
standard pushes like PS or some many
many share play files so what it is that
is a copy the missing dependency from
the firmware to our system always
shopping the existing share objectify
from our virtual machine to the
dependencies that this battery is is
missing yeah so after that we try to run
okay in this guy ATT PD and the program
doesn't complain anything but it just
crashed
so we went on to investigate and we
found from SJ that is to miss some
dependency even it doesn't complain at
all so we're an ashtray on this
and if I owned a foul on the missing
dependency and we are gonna be shortly
the existing dependency to the right
place
the next issue is that environ so after
we fix on the missing dependency it
worked but after that it stopped
somewhere so the reason is that usually
the target binary he's a binary one to
attack each Iran Iran is try to fire as
a configuration for super 80 DB right
try to find some configuration for our
server from the original firmware which
we do not have on our virtual machine so
the reason is that this packet binary
usually try to fire the configuration
into the NVRAM device which is a device
to star on the confusion of the target
binary so we try to show this problem by
first only try to emulate NVRAM device
on a virtual machine to fix this problem
however it was not easy because and the
RAM divides the they are different
different English system had different
cap and vram device and every nvm device
they do not have standard and usually
they are even undocumented so we came up
with this solution and we need to fire
something else so you know that the
target binary easily they do not quickly
contact the NVRAM device but it contact
another process which is NVRAM process
and it sends information requests to
this and vram process and the nvm
process intern contacts and veeram
device to get information that this the
kept binary want so the idea that we do
not emulator and vm device but emulator
NVRAM process which is much easier
so how we did that so easily is a tacit
binary
they connect to the NVRAM process via
two main socket metal do miss bloom a
circuit so we do our own NVRAM process
by writing something new from scratch
and this program by two the two main
circuit that this packet burn really
want and listen for the request pons
tacit memory and send back and forward
the function does this tuck and Maria
want so it works pretty well
another issue that some wireless in this
system there has some issues so first up
on any we're on ATT PD from some narrow
router on our virtual machine it
complains because it tried to configure
the w w bland so I let's learn the
device but you cannot fight that because
our virtual machine has no wireless
device so how to solve this one with our
chick we rename the standard e88
Ethernet 0 2 WN 0 and it works so that
was very nice trick and it works very
well
ok finally if all those solution fell
what to do the last one is that you get
attack a binary we pass it in case
everything else fell so we pass it so
that the taxpayer can walk in the in our
virtual machine but rarely we need to do
this ok so we show the first problem we
can copy the firmware you can copies the
capillary and you can emulate that in
our pretty good pretty powerful virtual
machine so what to do next how to fuzzy
so the idea is that because god has a
depend on instrumentation right but we
do not have the program you do not I
mean you do not have so SCOTUS attack a
binary we you only have attack a binary
to facet so
need a special dynamic instrumentation
program framework to do so we can do the
instrumentation but unfortunately on
those public PPI you can found doesn't
work very well on a system it has a walk
on em absolutely for miss or per PC so
we've had to be our own dpi so we can do
proper instrumentation for our Father
so the concept behind the API is very
simple dynamic binary instrumentation is
a method of analyzing a binary at
runtime by injecting extra
instrumentation code into the program at
runtime so this extra code or
instrumentation court excluded as a part
about the original code and one thing we
need to be careful in that when the
instrument program our extra code ran
inside that program right but we try
best not to change the behaviors
approver otherwise you can purchase
program okay so here's a simple in
diagram so you can see how the deep I
was so original code here by some code
one two three four now we want to issue
men after one and after after three
right so the idea that we can inject our
instrumentation code be high so coat you
want to assume and so when we so
original we run one two three four now
absol of the accommodation we run one
and our each repetition code and two and
three and P which is another
interpretation and four so but remember
here that a and B should not change the
behavior as a program okay so the
TrueType DPI techniques the first one is
a symptom translation the idea that we
transform the code the original code
something else and it puts this
transformation code into a into a
temporary buffer and we to own the
transformation here and you ran from the
buffer but not from the from the origin
original place
so this JIT transformation works very
well it gives a very good control on the
court USQ however this cap DPI is very
heavy and very complicated to design
implement so we look at another
technique which is con hoping hoping is
a very lightweight and very simple way
to do accommodation so it's much easier
to design implement hoping mechanism for
DBA on down shop hoping is that you have
less control on court executed because
we need to know in advance where to
instrument yeah so is there some this
event is that was hooking in mechanism
but you decide to focus on hooking
mechanism so that you type hoping
techniques the first one fishing pond is
in lie hoping so the idea is that you
want to instrument this original code
you want to run something after one run
something after two right so the idea
that we dig Li put the code in life
after 1 & 3 and when you run you run
everything so the idea is that this in
lie hoping allow you to instrument
anywhere there's no limitation however
you can see that one is still at the
same place right but true we need to
move it it's not at the original place
anymore because it need to be
after I now right and the same thing
she is move forest move so all the code
behind intermittent score is move and
you see that this in lie imitation is
actually very complicated because we
need to rewrite all the code after
imitation so he says that we do not go
with this coping mechanism so you look
at another technique which is going D to
a hokey so this one you can see that we
do not really put our code behind the
price you have to each you man but we
put it in another place and the court
you want to issue man you just jump to
our our instrumentation code but we do
not like politically after the code you
want to instrument so the idea that you
see we branch to the instrumentation
code and actually in our framework we
use redefine some come back some come
back which will be executed when we
reach here and you come back will be run
as a each repetition code and this T to
a technique we need to use some
intermediate some temporary buffer to
put our our instrumented code inside so
this Kappa Phi is called Champlin
memory buffer so compared to us in lie
detection technique the detour technique
is limited because there are some places
you cannot instrument using this
technique for support if the basic block
code is too small you cannot authorize
that basic block because you can
override to the next basic block right
however this dito hoping is very easy it
will be very easy to design so we
decided to go with a detour hoping the
next for our dpi so yeah so I will
quickly introduce on the detour hoping
mechanic mechanism here so the idea that
we branch from the original injection to
our comeback right but turn out that
there are many ways to do that so first
one
you can zoom dunes Champlin so here on
the left side you have the original code
now we want to instrument here so what
you do is that you allocate our champion
buffer and we override this code with
some code first one we saw the contacts
because because of Dom can change the
contact in some CPU and then employ
anjuman session here and a runtime is
jump to our champion buffer and first of
all we restore the context after we jump
so we will come back to the original
context and we need to make a cone to
our comeback right so before that which
saves the context because cone to cone
back can change the context so we need
to save the context here and it makes
the cone to the cone back and after that
when you return we store the contact we
restore the context which can be changed
here and after that we remember that we
still need to run the original injection
right so the idea that we can copy this
injection here and exq it after that
however in fact it doesn't always work
because some injection for sure want
some real a tip injection they are very
sensitive due to the to the position in
the memory so when you copy those type
each action from here to here it doesn't
work anymore so that means sometimes we
need to relocate the injection not
always it was some time before you can
put it here oppresses we jump back to
the next next code here so we see that
instead of running the original code we
run this home block and we do our best
not to change anything in the context of
the CPU so this on the Belgium to
Champlain the second one is that we do
not jump to Chapel a blue jump to come
back so you see that this mechanism we
do not use any champion buffer so here
again you say the context over right
here right and is jammed agree to the
contact and inside the comeback we
restore the context
and we asked you to relocate instruction
and do something inside to come back and
you returned to here all right so this
technique it doesn't we do not use any
chaplain before our own
so some to Chamberlain
jump to contact but just another way to
branch which is spoon so here you have
another day you just come to Champlain
so we see here you can see here that
instead of jump you do cone we come to
the champion buffer and everything else
is the same
so he is going to branch not John same
thing you can call quickly really going
to come back and here in this case again
we do not use any champion buffer on so
yeah looking at on those existing deep I
when you idiots is this research we
found that existing the die so it works
well but they are not very suitable for
our our projects because they are very
limited on platforms so the idea is that
actually for this dpi I do not want to
limit my shell to if this system
implemented platforms but I want to have
this dpi to work on own cut platforms I
only work for Windows Mac Linux and
everything else but those existing DPI
has some limitation for japon fern green
doesn't work on Windows pin and dynamo
do they do not work on macros upon the
second issue is that the limited on our
teacher supported right pin doesn't work
on anything but Intel CPU same thing for
dino Morea
but for our research we want to have
deep eyes that work on on the English
system which is can be am 64 or miss or
PowerPC and of course you want to
support international
just issues that all those existing
DPI's they provide some very easy and
nicely framework so people just use it
to program their tunes on top knows dpi
however they high many many things
inside so we cannot customize it
possible on just DB as I dunno support
on the for hooking mechanism mechanism I
assume it I introduced before the last
issue that because it high many details
they unjustly be at a limit on the
possibility to customize and and
optimize your your tools on top of a
book on top of dpi so I came up with
something myself
I do our own framework name as copy or
and he has many features it's kept lowly
for from work so you can view your tunes
on top of this from work scope low is
cross-platform it works on on the
performs on the operating system that I
can try on and it support many CPUs it
support Intel am city for miss pop PC
and spa and so on I did there's all the
for cap accommodation I introduced
before so you can choose whatever type
interpreters when you want to do and
unlike many existing DPI you can find on
the internet you can find that those vbi
many of them only allow you to each
human at the function and cheese but not
anyway after that the scope you allow
you to each main anywhere in the program
it doesn't limit on the function and
cheese okay scope less desire to be easy
to use but support on cap optimization
and in some special cases you can design
very fast tune which can be a hundred
times faster than exist existing deeper
which is important for the Vitara yeah
yes our Harbor user
so I do some I'm shocked layer to high
while on the details on the platform on
the CPUs and older platforms and on the
spew come in the Fillmore gas attack
plugin so support old cap operating
system and all caps apiece yeah yeah a
few things we need to cap out when we
build this on firstly we're talking
about cross-platform right for course
before we need to think about how to
deal with memory so because different OS
support different captain interface to
the handle memory access
so one thing we need to do that we need
to allocate champion buffer right and
allocate Champlin buffer we have
different API on different OS to
allocate memory for sapone on on the
unique system we use monologue but on
Windows you version below next thing we
need to do is that we need to allocate
Chamblee buffer to be grid quiet
executable and different OS a different
way to to set a permission as a memory
so first open UNIX they use em protect
Windows it will show unlock so I need to
take everything like that next thing we
need to do is that we need to who I to
the memory to patch the code right to
patch or completely into the memory and
that depends on the OSS so first so we
need to unprotected memory right to that
and we protect again and you can see
that is different on different OS so
first up on on Unix Linux Mac they use
em protect function on Windows user
virtual protect for for UNPO Tech and
reported memory ok remember that we need
to say in read restart context when we
do our accommodation right and this one
is not cross platform but course
architecture because each tab spew has
different way to save memory to say
restore and restore me very restore
Esther
that we try to keep the course after
interpretation as small as possible so
for example on the Intel participate you
can use pushed 82 to say on the resistor
into the stack memory and after that we
pop idea and we have as an instruction
to to say the if flex resistance for as
a cache CPU is not that easy because
even Intel city puppy or m/c for miss a
PC just no such simple injection to say
on the distance so we we did mainly cap
optimization here to keep the course
small as possible and only save the
restore that we really need to save yeah
and it's different it depend on :
convention okay we need to we need only
in our instrumentation we need to call
the comeback right when you come back
you need to pass the occupant to the
combine and it depends the passing
altman to the comeback depend on the cpu
in depends on architecture so there are
many details we need to take depends on
things you want to support yes some some
of the details and I think I so skip now
if it I do not have much time
disclosure is the preamble that we need
to branch from the origin and place to
the comeback all all to the champion
áfourá however many CPUs they do not
allow you to branch to the indirect
occur in the memory so as all I need to
have some temporary resistor - French -
Mysti but not to branch to the memory so
we have some we need to use some squash
resistor to calculate the branch target
yeah and it again depends on the CPUs
one more things you need to do is that
when you write to the memory we override
the code in the memory
we need to fast the insertion catch so
the CPU can can be aware of the new
quarter
so again here it depend on the CPUs for
Intel we do not need to do anything to
flatter the insertion cache but for
other CPU we need to do that and again
it depend on the CPU depends on us
yeah
so how if you scope your scope is pew on
top of qu other famous of what my it
depend on capstone to extract the code
from the origin place so it knows about
a way to override to and remember that
we need to realize the code right so I
use another framework which is Keystone
here to revise a new code to the to
relocate a code so because a capstone
and Keystone they are cross-platform
across our teacher so that's why scope
you on top size is also cross-platform
and cause architecture yeah so actually
this frame was kept complicated because
we want to support many thing we want to
do own cab optimization okay so we had a
deeper so you can start to view our
Father so how to do that so our Father
we do our for the on top of our Father
which is very good father for ready
father
so two feature is that unlike I fell we
support binary only when the binary
binary only together so to do that we
use copy oh because contour deep I allow
you to each human anywhere in the
program and it's our own car CPU so you
can you can do our further running on
own caps appear we suppose selected
binary forcing which means that so
unlike many and I as a DB I like pin or
dino Morea
when you use P not anymore Pro to each
human your program it's human program
from stuff right there's no choice but
always accommodation
but because scope o is using hooking
medicated mechanism so you can choose
where to each human so he only true to
instrument somewhere that we care about
for our Father
so our own so suppose persistent mode in
a FL and besides that it support many as
a advanced techniques for to make self
as a sniper like simple execution we
compiled many static analysis technique
to to make our faster better okay so
this is that alpha is pure shockwave ice
we do not use any features from the CPU
to to build this one so it works
everywhere you don't have CPU you know
lab environment so because we do not
rely on the actual hard way I have a
features it woke on on the CPU on the
our teachers native compile on the
emitter system support binary fast and
quite stable so how about the
implementation so as I said we reuse a
professor we do not change anything in
the court FL so remember that the
program when you want to fight this one
in FL it comprises the source code and
the compiler the special table
instrument this program for you right so
now we do not have the source code how
we can still run on airfare so the idea
is that we just follow the mechanism of
the accomodation in the case you have a
source code so you scope the compiler
instrumental program and we copy
actually the same thing we ensure meant
that target binary in the same way and
we use the same mechanism so once our
program is submitted at runtime it
connect to the Fatah in the same way
exactly the same way so in the easiest
what
our Father is compatible with iPhone so
we do not change anything in the court
anything our own so what we had to do is
that we perform static analysis on the
target binary before we reboot the
father so we locate where you want to
focus fasting on fresh upon usually you
just focus on the pasture court right so
we reverse the program first and
relocated we locate the boxer and we
focus on in shoumaine only those area
and we of course we use compute to hook
into the program at runtime and as a
result of our photo is very fast run the
native speed yeah here's one example how
we build the faster for the network
network program like a TTP my where
shovel so here's how it works you run
the packet binary as a fastened together
like normal right and we only issue mint
the code handling the input from the
client so here you have client and
server right you run the server in
insider inside I fell and issue may know
the code up handle to input sending from
the client regarding the calendar we put
the color code inside the Fox of Aluva
level and in turn the client when it run
it initialized the client socket and
connect to the server and Center input
that is generated by a file to the
server and it is connect up to that and
repeat on the loop demo you are not sure
I have time for them all but it's one
screenshot so will be our Father and we
try that on many in the system you can
far and yeah we found many many bugs and
some of them are very interesting so lie
on this screenshot you can see that this
is a bug from some network router or if
our in China and this cap this part
this device is very popular in China so
the pack we found here actually impacted
I think like millions users in China so
sorry the screenshot is not very clear
but you can see that here we try to
connect to the device with tonette well
of course this device has no they're not
open to the network right and then after
that we run our exploitation and the
expression connect to the web server
running on this device and it exploit
and turn on Teutonia and after that we
could like to turn it server again on
this device and you can look in as a
route ok conclusion and if you have time
you have some demo some pretty quickly
more okay so we here do our Smurfs as a
smart idea that the for embedded system
we picked up by emulating the for my
efforts
and will be faster so it really cost
pala form cause architecture we support
binary only as fast and step on it felt
really really impactful box in the
summary of your device questions but
before that I think I have few minutes
can you run the video ok so we be
officer you can really fast on binary
but because of the limited time I cannot
have run this faster on the this demo
for you on the real attp device but here
I run the faster on some some simple
packet binary on beeps so I see here
that we try to you run our binary faster
on Linux mix right and this packet is
best to which is very simple memory just
for demo and test to run with some input
and normally do something but in some
special input we can cross pass through
so now I run this father we test to on
MIT and I try to fight it boot again
cross this one
so remember that we do not have a source
code for test true so what you can see
here is that we run the father on MIPS
virtual machine and we do not have
source code for test two
yeah so we see that after like one
minute if our one crash so let's try to
see if this cross can really cross the
target binary test true or not yeah so
we are fuzzify okay one impure now try
to run tests to ities input and see what
happen
you see segmentation fool at the end so
yeah so I put that uh Oh father of how
can really cross the binary and yeah
this aphasia poor memory but our Father
that can fast the real target like
eighty TV run exactly the same way when
it took a lot more time so I cannot show
it here okay so thank you