[Music]
hello my name is Maddie stone and this
is Kylee McRoberts thank you all for
making it back from lunch and so
hopefully it's exciting keep you awake
post lunch and we will dive into the
trends that we've seen of Android mobile
malware in the first half of 2018 and
then really deep dive into four of the
most impactful families what do they do
why are they impactful what techniques
do they use and things like that
so first up as I said my name is Maddie
stone I am a reverse engineer on Google
Play protect or the Android security
team at Google and I have about five
years of experience before that doing
hardware and firmware exploitation hi
and I'm Kylie McRoberts so I'm a program
manager on Google Play protect under
Android security team and essentially if
you think my accent sounds weird for an
American it's because I'm actually
Australian so let's not confuse that all
right so as many said we're gonna be
diving into some of the trends that
we've seen in the first half of 2017 and
then we're going to be looking at some
of the technical details of some of the
key families that we've seen impacting
those trends but before we do I'm just
going to take one or two minutes just to
quickly tell you where that data is
coming from so we're all on the same
page and it's from Google Play protects
so we'll quickly run over what it is and
what the scope is firstly we're going to
be referring a lot to potentially
harmful applications or PHA so for us
PHA is defined isn't up that could put
the user their data or their device at
risk so in many ways our definition of
PHA is is fairly in line with sort of
the traditional definitions of mobile
malware that most people use a key
difference is that for us PHA is defined
by specific categories and I'll go into
what they are later but the main
takeaway for you guys is that those
categories define the scope of the type
of PHA or malware that we'll be
discussing
the trends so as I said where do we get
that data from it comes from Google Play
protect this slice adds lots of things
but the main thing you guys need to know
is that Google Play protect essentially
scans devices which have it enabled and
what we're doing is looking for evidence
of paj so where we find PHA we show a
user a warning to let them know that
that exists on their device or in the
cases of particularly harmful PHAs we
can actually automatically block or
uninstall that up for the user now
because GPP or Google Play protect is
covering over 2 billion devices in the
ecosystem this really helps us to get
some good insights into PHA trends over
the years and it's that device base
which we're going to be using today to
pull out the trends so I mentioned for
us PHA is defined by specific categories
and those categories are listed here on
the slide so if you're interested in the
definitions of each one they are
publicly available you can google them
ironically and have a look at what we
what we define for each category but as
you can see some of them are fairly
common and be familiar to everyone like
ransomware phishing and Trojans one set
of categories that I call out that might
be less familiar are related to mobile
billing fraud so essentially those
applications that charge the user in an
intentionally misleading way basically
tricking the user into having charges
against them and we divide those that
particular category into three so you
can see them listed here is SMS fraud
toll fraud and call fraud we also have
some categories up here which
essentially can either modify or disable
the inbuilt security features in Android
and for that reason we define them at
Google as PHA now we do understand that
for some users those particular apps
perform functions that they actually
want and they actually want the
applications but nonetheless we define
it as PHA so that we can then show a
warning to users particularly non power
users who may not understand the risks
but people can click through them so
that's why you see those category
is up here the last category that I'd
just call out is hostile downloaders so
for us that's defined as an application
that basically downloads other PHA
categories so these categories are
basically the scope of the trends and
the case studies that we're going to be
looking at today so with that background
in mind let's dive into some of the
high-level trends to get us started so
this is starting very broadly the slide
shows the percentage of devices that are
seen with one or more PHA on them in the
ecosystem so we kind of defined this as
the Android healthiness of the ecosystem
and it's divided into two sections you
can see the healthiness for Google Play
specifically and then the yellow bar
will show you the healthiness across the
entire Android ecosystem so looking at
the trends for the first half of this
year compared to last year in 2017 we
saw an average 0.82% of devices had one
or more PHA in the entire ecosystem and
then in the first half of 2018 we've
seen that come down a little bit to 0.72
percent in terms of the trend for Google
Play as you can see it's pretty similar
to what we saw last year bottom line
being if you download apps exclusively
from Google Play you're basically nine
times less likely to have PHA put on
your device compared to if you download
apps from other sources still keeping it
a really high level although the overall
trend for 2018 so far is good we've seen
the ecosystem become a little bit safer
it does vary by country under the device
is in so we've just pulled out ten
different countries to give you a bit of
an idea of that variance so for example
you can see the top two the blue and the
yellow line there indicate that for
India and Indonesia you're more likely
to get PHA on your device and they're
above the global average compared to the
bottom line in orange there indicates
that in Japan
you're less likely and it's lower lower
than the global average all right so
centering in on Google Play what did we
see is the top ten PA
categories for the first half of this
year they're listed here in order of
prevalence so in other words the most
prevalent PHA category that we found on
Google place so far this year was
click-fraud and I'll go into that in a
little bit more detail in a second
following click-fraud with spyware and
then SMS fraud which was one of those
categories of mobile billing fraud that
I mentioned earlier this is a similar
slide but now we're showing the top ten
categories outside of Google Play so as
you can see it's a bit different in
terms of the dominance of different PHA
categories so this time for the first
half of the year we saw back doors as
the prevalent PHA category are followed
by hostile downloaders and then
privilege escalation all right I won't
to go into for specific trends with you
today and that we found interesting and
that hopefully you will too and the
first one of those is SMS fraud as you
can see this slide actually goes back to
2017 just to give you a bit of context
for where we were heading into the year
so essentially at the start of 2018 we
were already at a spike in SMS fraud
activity so it's really been a big focus
for Google Play protect so far this year
in particular we've seen PHA families in
this category impacting the Southeast
Asian region and that is actually going
to give you the technical details for
one of the primary families in that
regard which is Brad SMS as well as run
through Shinhwa which has some of these
SMS fraud related behaviors as well the
second trend that I wanted to go through
was hostile downloaders so what was
interesting is towards the end of last
year we'd luckily seen a nice big drop
in the prevalence of hostile downloaders
that's it and that has been maintained
throughout the first half of this year
which is great but despite the fact that
it's less prevalent is still a primary
PHA category outside of play and so for
that reason we keep you know continuing
to put resources into trying to counter
this particular PHA category in terms of
why we think that drop has happened and
how it's been maintained there's a
couple of factors that we think are
impacting it some of those include the
fact that when our disallowing any kind
of dynamic code download we've also
improved the a sop detection support in
both Android P and O and then lastly
we've also removed the ability of
hostile downloaders to install other
apps so in general if there's a PHA on a
device and it tries to install another
app we'll show the user a warning
regardless on that up to try and warn
them of the fact that we know this is
coming from a PHA you may want to be
extra careful about what this is but in
the case of a known hostile download on
we actually automatically block that
download to try and stop the spread of
this particular category so we think
those are the kind of factors which are
leading into this trend but if anyone
else is looking into this area and has
any other insights and we'd love to chat
the third trend we wanted to talk about
was click-fraud now the data for here
only goes back until December last year
and obviously looking at the slide the
trend looks pretty awful for the first
half of the year but that's actually
mainly because we only began enforcement
against click-fraud in March of this
year so hence you see that big lovely
spike going on there in originally we
didn't consider a clique fraud to be PHA
and the main reason behind that is
because of the actual limited user harm
and when I mentioned that definition at
the beginning usually our PHA categories
focus in on that user harm aspect but it
become increasingly apparent that while
click-fraud may have limited user impact
it was having a really significant
impact on advertising networks and then
by extension all the businesses and
companies that they represent right so
we're having significant harm to a
different type of group and we decided
that we couldn't keep ignoring that in
our PHA categories and when we did start
enforcement in March as you can see from
that spike click-fraud really quickly
became our top PHA category on play i
think Maddie's going to be going into
view SDK as a bit of an example of one
of the families
leading to this trend the last trend
that I want to highlight before I let
Maddie delve into some of the actual
technical details of families impacting
these trends is fish
I think fishing is a really interesting
one right it's a really high impact
threat and so just serve idli so it's
received a lot of press attention both
last year and that's continued into the
first half of this year but compared to
the amount of press attention it gets
it's actually a really small threat on
Google Play you can see that last year
obviously we had a lot of spikes but for
the you know pretty much continuously
throughout the first half of the year
it's remained low the interesting story
for us about this is why we've managed
to bring the prevalence of fishing down
there are still active fishing threats
ongoing and one example is a fishing
family that's actually trying to
penetrate Google Play that targets
Turkish banks so this is a good takeaway
for us that when we're looking at these
trends and deciding where to put
resources and where to try and you know
focus our efforts in fighting PHA that
it's important not to take our eye off
categories just because we've managed to
decrease their prevalence you know
malware authors are continuously trying
to improve and trying to evade those
detection efforts and this particular
family that's typing Turkish banks is a
good example of that we need to keep an
eye out and keep trying to catch them
before we see those trends spike up
again so with that kind of context in
mind I'll hand it over to Maddie to chat
us through some of the examples thanks
Kylie so now that we sort of understand
what's the most current data of impact
happening in the ecosystem let's talk
into some of the most current techniques
that the biggest families are using in
order to have that big impact so the
first family we're going to talk about
is called Shinhwa Shinhwa is a botnet
that is pretty complicated complex and
its whole purpose is to do different
types of ad fraud premium SMS fraud or
install fraud
so when kylie told us that for 2018 so
far the biggest PHA category in the
off-market space is backdoor that is
largely because of the Shama botnet and
so prior to March 2017 Shinhwa
really pushed and tried to infiltrate
Google Play
after a lot of different defenses that
we put in place and things like that
they moved off of google play and then
reevaluated re-strategize and decided to
try and penetrate the side loaded off
market area of android
so we began detecting chinois in
mid-2016 at that point as i said it was
Google Play and it's still ongoing but
now it's completely off of Google Play
so for all of these families we go into
I will give you a sample of the family
via the sha-256 digests and I went ahead
and put a short URL to the virustotal
link in case you're trying to follow
along so here's a first overview of what
Shinhwa is so this image came from a
blog post we did on Shinhwa back in 2017
so this was when we had just a first
couple of variants and we had worked to
push it off of Google Play it still is
overall the same though Shinhwa is four
stages the first being the apk the last
being a jar of the payloads so across
that the different variants we're gonna
go into today and how they continue to
evolve is how they get or where they do
each of these different stages and the
functionality but overall the
functionality for each of these stages
has stayed the same so we see the apk
that dynamically drops and unpacks Stage
two which is a jar stage two's purpose
is to decrypt and drop stage three which
is an elf or native code within the
Android application then stage three
unpacks the final payload and drops that
and starts it running so the very first
variant we saw in late 2016 sort of goes
along what I stated before of those four
stages so first we saw this last three
stages stages two through stages four
we're all packed in encrypted in
different files in the assets folder of
the apk so Stage one starts runs general
Java code which unpacks drops the jar
each of these
final or final three files all had
dynamically generated file names so for
example stage two was always assets / 32
either lowercase or numerical characters
so I have the regex listed of what their
common file names were for variant 1 so
variant ones first payload what they
attempted to do was add general add
fraud and install fraud what I mean by
install fraud is if you think of a
payload for this type of botnet their
whole purpose is monetization so they're
cut trying to come up with different
ways to monetize the fact that they're
on all these different devices so ad
fraud is pretty general we hear about it
a lot just different ways to defraud
advertising networks but install fraud
means hey we're going we're willing to
sell you the fact that we're installed
on all these devices and we'll install
your applications as a developer also on
these phones so that ties into sort of
that hostile download or care category
that Kylie was talking about before as
well so variant one had an interesting
but simple string obfuscation technique
so it was used in both stage one and the
stage two jar that we saw for variant
one and so what you would see is there
was one class within both stage 1 and
stage 2 that just had these what looks
like an integer array in there and but
there were no strings at all in the in
the classes and then you would see that
this integer array was used in this one
function so the next thing you would see
is how was this function called and it
was pretty simple they would call this
function with two integers the intro
first integer when you take a quick look
at that function is the index of the
value to start at in the rip array then
the next integer is the length a number
of values from the array to read so in
this case a 29 comma 8 would give us
these eight integer values 111 110 67
and then it was as simple as that is the
decimal representation of the ASCII
value for the string so this string was
simply on create
so probably one of the simplest
obfuscation methods that most of us in
this room can think of but it was
successful in that you can no longer
just scan the apk looking for strings
you had to write a tool in order to find
those strings and be able to put it in
your automated detection systems then we
moved into stage 2 in the later half of
20 our very intuitive
in the later half of 2016 for variate 2
all of the stages stayed exactly the
same they still used those three
different files that were stored in the
apks assets folder they would drop them
dynamically use the same unpacking and
decryption for each of the different
stages but we saw the payload change now
instead of just doing ad fraud and
install fraud they came up with a new
monetization mechanism so this time it
was premium SMS fraud so to take a step
back premium SMS fraud in Western Europe
and the US for those people who are here
it's not as common of a way to pay but
what it means is that if you send a text
message to this short code number like
five five five five it will charge your
mobile bill a specified amount so you're
allowed to send premium SMS messages but
you're not allowed to do it without user
consent so that's what makes it fraud
and so her role or chinois would do this
in that they would do this in behind the
scenes send all these premium SMS
messages and then have it discharged to
the users build and so they did it in a
sophisticated way because the Google
Play protect Android security team had
already been building in a lot of
different mechanisms to protect users
from premium SMS fraud such as requiring
a specific permission and also whenever
the phone detected that a app was trying
to send an SMS message to a short code
number that was likely premium it would
pop up a dialog so what Shinhwa did was
it tried to find rooted phones in on
those rooted phones it would try to
install itself so that it could run as
this
stem user or the phone user ID both of
those on Android are privileged user IDs
and so once it did that then it would
different type do different types of
bypasses to make the phone believe it
had the the SMS permission and also oh
no the user has told us that we don't
want to show the dialogues for premium
SMS messages so that was the interesting
changes for variant to that was that one
basically was eradicated in march 2017
if you look up google chinois you'll see
a blog post about it that also goes into
more details then they went dormant for
a few months
because this was after we had pushed
them off of play before that we hadn't
seen them in the off market at much it
was a constant battle to just push them
off play so then in November 2017 we see
them start to come back but they've
changed quite a bit and so this time
they are purely targeting the off market
or so side loaded ecosystem part of
Android so not even attempting to get
back on play so what we see as the
stages go and why this was not
immediately clear to us that it was
related to show moi off the bat was that
yes Stage one was an apk but this time
we didn't see the same assets files
stored in the apk as we had seen
previously those random generated
characters under assets had been pretty
clear and obvious thing that something
was out of the ordinary
instead they moved stage two instead of
dropping it as a jar they just included
that Java code in the apk but it was
highly obfuscated with lots of random
class name strings and things like that
so what that Oscar now stage 3 which is
where a lot of sort of the meat of this
variant came in was now no longer
dropped what was included as a static
elf within the apk if you haven't
analyzed many Android apps thus far
developers can choose to include
compiled C or C++ code in their
applications even though we generally
think of them usually written in Java or
hotland as applications so they included
this elf it usually lived in the path
lib slash whatever CPU at it had been
compiled for usually army ABI which is
the Android sort of keyword term for a
generic arm but we also saw it for arm
v7 and arm 64 as well as x86 and then it
had a randomly generated name which was
usually Lib and then five to eight
lowercase letters dot SL so I'm gonna
take a step back to talk about these
randomly generated characters I think
it's important that whenever you see
lots of samples of a similar family if
they're able to generate all these
random file names and random strings and
class names that's a really strong
signal that it's either being
distributed to people in the form of
source code or the malware developers
have a lots of resources and have
created an automated pipeline that
generates all these different samples
and thus obviously are not generating
all the random names by hand so the key
aspect of this elf which required quite
a bit of reverse engineering was that it
didn't look the same as the previous
else instead there was a lot of anti
analysis anti debugging and decryption
around it so that it didn't look right
when you first analyzed it and so what
this was is a anti analysis native
library and Android that I have named
wedding-cake
which was one of the most complex native
libraries or complex
anti analysis native libraries we've
seen because of the variety of different
techniques they used if you're
interested in that I did a black hat
talk this year as well as wrote a paper
for virus bulletins that was published a
few weeks ago so if you're interested in
the types of andr anti analysis
techniques being used today for android
go ahead and check that out
so once I got through all of those
layers of anti analysis that I hadn't
seen before the way that I knew it was
finally chinois was that it had the
exact same functionality hiding under
those layers of wedding-cake as the
previous stage three first unwanted so
again now we found that its whole
function
was to drop stage for the payload this
wasn't working though in any of the
dynamic analysis pipelines and why it
was tougher to figure out and required
this reverse engineering is because they
now included all of these anti analysis
and obfuscation techniques but
ultimately it drops the payload as well
which they sort of backed off from the
SMS fraud payload and moved back into
more different types of ad fraud and
install fraud so I published I built
first I from about February to June 2018
built all these detections for wedding
take wedding cake Prevention's different
things like that for this new variant
and I started putting out information
about wedding cake then I presented at
blackhat and we saw a variant for come
out after talking about it and so what
they changed here was they left stage
one into the same they generally left
stage for their payload the same but
they targeted stage 3 where wedding cake
had lived so what was interesting
leading up to what I would say the true
boundary with variant 4 was we were able
to watch all the different versions of
Shinhwa apps coming in and what I could
see first is that it seemed that the
malware developers were trying to test
if we had yarra rules in place or how
are we catching them so we could watch
in both the java code as the yarra how
their they were trying to move different
things around put constants in different
places probably trying to test for those
exact types of signatures for detection
so instead they decided to pull the elf
completely out of the apk for variant 4
so what they did now is they put they
base64 encoded the entirety of the elf
and then put those base64 encoded
strings in the apk the java code of
stage 2 then decodes each of those
strings that are a portion of the elf
and then concatenates them all together
writes them to the file to then drop the
elf so what that looks like is a little
like this the new version of chinois we
saw all of these base64
encoded strings in an array here I just
happen to pull out you know value 56 but
they often have hundreds of them and so
then they just had simple code that
concatenates them all together one of
the interesting parts here is where they
build the path to drop it it's again
randomly generated strings for the
directory and then the actual file where
they would like to drop the elf but
what's interesting is they do append a
period before the folder name of Katie
u.s. IP to make that a hidden folder if
you are looking at it so that was
Shinhwa one of the biggest botnets we've
seen in the Android ecosystem and the
big contributing factor in the off
market or side-loaded space to that
backdoor category so now let's switch to
play
what are we tackling fighting preventing
on google play and that's this SMS fraud
family as Kylie alluded to we call it
read SMS because it sends SMS so it did
originally start as SMS but then as we
were getting you know stronger and
stronger detections in place prevention
they weren't having the same surface
area or you know they weren't being able
to distribute themselves as effectively
they decided to innovate and do some
toll fraud as well so this has been
about 2016 to present and again here's a
sample and a virus total link but one of
the key aspects of bread SMS that is
fascinating and sort of similar to
Shinhwa is how resourced it is because
it is rapidly evolving with many
variants so that means you have to be
very deliberate with how you use
analysis resources how you use detection
and prevention resources because you
know that their wealth resource didn't
able to find so many variants so I'm not
going to be able to go through all of
them today but I'm going to touch on
some of the most interesting SMS fraud
techniques that their variants have used
and so when you think about it
SMS fraud is just sending a text message
sending a text message there's only
three or four Android API
that allow you to do that shouldn't that
be pretty easy to detect because they
have to do it in one of these four ways
however that's where sort of the
creativity and where us as defenders
really have to work and where malware
authors are constantly trying to evolve
is because you're trying to come up with
new ways to send the SMS and ultimately
call that API call without being
detected so one of the first way these
do that is with a simple splash screen
so their goal of their splash screen is
one to prevent the automated dynamic
analysis catching them too they try and
fake policy compliance it's super small
on their screen shot as probably
intended but they have in English at the
top terms and conditions and then some
tie underneath it so what I mean by fake
policy compliance is you're allowed to
send premium SMS messages on Android as
long as it's fully disclosed the price
and the number to the user and the user
consents so this is probably their
attempt to make us think of something in
Thai they're probably disclosing this
but the other aspect of this was is that
they dynamically update the content in
their terms and conditions based on the
c2 and where you're checking in so this
is a form of the cloaking they use that
we'll get into so sometimes it says hey
click the button if you want to continue
to the app in other times they have a
real disclosure when they think it's
probably us who are trying to review the
apps
so the key cloaking that they began to
use is only sending or performing the
fraudulent behavior of sending the SMS
message when you're on a certain mobile
carrier because based on how SMS fraud
works you when you send the SMS message
that sort of provider of the premium SMS
number has to have the relationship with
your carrier to be able to charge your
carriers bill bread SMS targets
exclusively Southeast Asia and almost
predominantly Thailand so it's
not really worth it to them to try and
to accidentally be detected if they're
running on let's say a u.s. Western
Europe or Brazilians phone because
they're not actually going to be able to
make money that way
so we'll talk a little bit about how
they do that check so they send a
command-and-control request that says
hey only perform the fraudulent as I'm
sending the fraudulent SMS message if
the phone is on one of these carriers
otherwise that button will now just
start the main activity and it won't do
any of the sending so what that actually
looks like is we'll see the example
see to command and control request URL
up here on the top left and then the
response that the app received is the
JSON on the bottom left and on the right
here is the code which we'll go through
and make larger so the very first thing
they happen is they get the users SIM
operator or their mobile carrier using
that code that is then passed to the
HTTP request that is sent to the command
and control serval server you see that
as in this example code equals three one
zero two six the app then receives back
the JSON response and parses that so
based on that they've now set than they
first get the contents that are supposed
to be set in that splash screens text so
in this case they're gonna say here are
all the pictures you need about
happiness beauty beauty etc with our
most sincere service to provide you with
the most robust resources so that's
where I mean they change those terms and
conditions based on whatever the service
tells them to say the next thing they do
is they also set what the button text is
going to say here it's that content and
now they check what were the IME eyes
what they're not actually I am the eyes
but what is the carrier send back in the
response it's here under the variable
they use IMEI
so they get all of those and if the
users carrier was in those values so for
us it was not if you look at three one
zero two six is not included in these
three carrier codes that were sent back
from the server then and only when the
value is in there do they actually send
the SMS otherwise they do this top if
statement of just starting the main
activity and not trying to send the
premium SMS so the next variant is all
of that code before for variant one was
included in the application so we could
still see the HTML spend all of the code
to portray the splash screen now they
moved into a webview the reason behind
that is now the only code you have to
have in the application is what the
application wants to do to interact with
the webview page and so they can
dynamically generate allocate everything
within the webview otherwise so for
example we have this HTTP request URL
that goes to the command-and-control
server you see an operated code the name
of the app and some device ID which we
dead beefed out then you receive this
response so the very first thing you see
is the on click and it says we're gonna
run sub you see that the sub is if
JavaScript down here at the bottom but
first let's talk through what each of
these variables are because they've
hidden the premium SMS code arguments in
the HTML these are you know set as
variables but not actually displayed to
the user it's just saying short code
equals this phone number and key word is
this content the next thing we see is
some references to Android API is to
send a text message if you've ever used
Java and heard of reflection that's
another way to call Java or Android API
s without having to call the function
instead you send the strings that then
tell the virtual machine hey you're
going to find this method and run it so
that's all the arguments they need here
to do that for send text message so
therefore now we saw at the top that
this HTML said when the button is
pressed run this script we can see what
the scripts values were the first lines
of code were all to load those variables
we just talked about and now here we see
that they're actually calling a function
to send that SMS message by having these
hidden values encoded in the HTML and so
finally what that looks like there's all
the variables for you they're going to
call the Android API method send text
message with the arguments of this phone
number in that contents of the text
message which would ultimately charge
the user so that wasn't enough we then
saw them QWOP rotate to a new variant
quickly again and this time trying to
come up with a new way to call send text
message without being detected so we've
seen it where they do it straight and
they Android API calls we've seen it
through calling from JavaScript in a web
view and now they move to that native
code so what we saw in the java code of
the APK is they declared this native
method saying hey this is actually going
to run and c or c++ and compiled code
they left it still named quite well for
us so that was helpful so we have this
native send method which takes two
strings that's declared and then we see
that it's called in the APK as this
bottom line here I know it's a little
small but hopefully you can still read
and get the gist of it this is a
screenshot of the Ida of the live native
library that was included in the apk
what we see is they then call send text
message in the way that the J and I our
Java native interface how you interact
between Java
native code they call send text message
with the two arguments of the shortcode
and the contents so that was a whirlwind
deep dive into three of the variants of
one of the most impactful families on
Google Play and one of the large
contributors to the SMS fraud pH a
category that we're seeing in in the
first half of 2018 so now that we've
talked about off-market side-loaded apps
Google Play now we're going to get into
something a little different the
preinstalled problem not the first one
to come up here and say that's the thing
so Casa loon is one of those that has
been pre-installed on before so it is a
hostile downloader so that category that
Kylie was talking about earlier it is
not really off market side loaded or or
so it is considered off market or side
loaded because it's not Google Play but
its distribution method mechanism is
pre-installed so it was detected in
November 2017 and basically sort of fell
off in March 2018 largely because of an
analysis in collaboration we did with
Avast in a vast published a nice blog
post about that if you're interested in
reading more specifically about this
family so overview Casa loon it's two
stages first stage is pre-installed on
generally low end or non certified
Android devices so that stage one can
come in two different types of variants
one is just a pre-installed application
on the system partition just general
bloat where that you can see on some of
the lower end or non-certified devices
variant two is there is a package or
application that is critical to the
android platform it's in a OSP the
Android Open Source project and it's
called system UI doing as the name
suggests a lot of the UI for this system
of Android and so what they did there is
they actually modified system UI to be
this stage one dropper for some of this
hostile downloading
and networks so well they both have the
same exact functionality just the way it
was packaged and distributed is slightly
different then stage two which is
dropped by stage one ultimately displays
ads and installs other applications and
that's how it gets the PHA category of
hostal downloader so as we said it's
pre-installed for Stage one that means
it's on the system partition or in this
modified system UI which is also on the
system partition both of these stage
ones register a Wi-Fi state change
receiver meaning that anytime you either
connect or disconnect from Wi-Fi an
action is sent to these applications
that allows them to execute most of the
key behavior that we're going to talk
about is in two classes that they have
named Wi-Fi broad or keyguard broad
these have nothing to do with the
normally included Wi-Fi our key guard
applications they chose to name them
that could probably not raise a lot of
suspicion so the key here though is that
was interesting is the behavior that's
in here and ultimately leads to the
fraudulent behavior of dropping stage
two only occurs if you are not in China
it does this check of code right here to
get your locale and make sure you're
connected and but if you are have a
locale of China they do not execute and
they go dormant on the phone so once
they've done that check they've decided
you're connected to the Internet and you
are not in China they run this code
that's called check update check update
then connects to a subdomain or the
domain of Casa lucam and downloads a XML
file this XML file gives all of the
configuration settings necessary for
stage two in the payload to operate so
the version number changes for the XML
file over different versions as well as
the subdomain of Casa loon so this is
what the response to the call to get
that version dot XML file looks like so
some of the key aspects
here is one the version this is saying
hey this is the version of the config
file so the app will actually only
update the values that it knows as its
configuration settings if if this is a
later version than a version it seemed
previously this is now the URL where
they download the stage-two application
from so they download it since they're
running a system they were able to call
p.m. install - our command to do the
install of stage 2 apk package is
usually the name of that stage 2 apk as
well these startup values were
interesting so what these startup values
are is they are going to set a
preference within the stage 1
application it says every time the phone
boots up you're gonna start these
services these services are usually
living in the stage 2 application so
it's the way that that stage 1 system
pre-installed application is able to
ensure the longevity and the lifeline of
the stage 2 application that gets
installed
lastly they do a couple of different
types of whitelisting so if they they
have the ability to send board device
and model values back in this reject
variable value and if the phone's values
matches the ones of rejects they also
will not run the final interesting check
they do is they send an HTTP request to
these CD ends that are at get IP ya get
IP dot PHP this returns an IP as well as
a timestamp what it looks like is that
this is a second localization check
because it's a CDN that means you know
the server is gonna be based in
different parts of the world and respond
to you based on where you're trying to
connect from and so they use that to
check hey is this a place we still want
to run from so now that we've gone
through stage one we passed all
chess yay us we download stage two so
stage two almost always had these
different package names trying to
pretend to be Google products saying a
music service a play service sometimes
adding some integers in there and every
once in a while spelling google wrong
and this was much more obfuscated than
stage one generally stage 1 was not
obfuscated at all all of the strings
were included in one class and then they
had just about all of their
functionality in a single service called
back service so what they do is this is
the service that ultimately the stage
one was trying to start up with those
start up values and once it's started it
uses a screen observer object from
Android API s to start and stop the
service based on when the screen is on
this is used to show ads and sort of a
see we're only showing ads when the
screen is on and thus you should pay us
more for their monetization ad fraud
lastly it does drop a jar that's the ad
library yeah so the final family we're
gonna go into is one of these new
examples of click fraud as Kylie
mentioned we only started enforcing
detecting preventing on click fraud in
March 2019 so this was one of the first
families and one of the families that
sort of pushed that decision to start
enforcing and so we're gonna talk about
how they do that so we detected it
before we started enforcing on it
back in February 2018 it's only on side
loaded we haven't found this one on
Google Play so the way it works is you
have an APK an APK then drops the jar as
it's running and this jar contains the
class comm w sdk hence the name we gave
it dots star usually something that's
pro guarded so single letter the jar is
usually named nine digits jar so the way
that it does click fraud
is it creates an invisible webview that
show ads so the user can't see them
can't be annoyed can't report them can't
delete the app but then it uses
JavaScript to inject clicks on it so
that makes it look like to the ad
networks but you know a human is
interacting with your the ads you're
showing in thus they should pay the
person that has that advertising ID so
the way this works is that in the
webview client the invisible one where
they're showing all of the ads in the on
page finished function which is as it
describes an Android API for webview
that runs whenever the page is finished
loading it downloads javascript that
javascript is then run so it usually was
downloaded from this link what that
JavaScript that's downloaded looks like
was this really hidden name click j/s ad
so it comes through the webview or that
web page looking for any items that are
in the web page that have the element
named ad area it then tries to calculate
with a little random wiggle room to
hopefully not trigger different types of
click fraud detection mechanisms where
it wants to click once it does that it
then calls this foreign SDK dot ads
click function foreign SDK is the Nate
what they gave the name of the
JavaScript interface when they were
creating this webview so if you haven't
interacted with web views that often you
might be looking around for a class name
or an SDK but it's actually this other
class come view SDK 80a that they happen
to name for an SDK so then you can take
a look there and ultimately what that
function does is it checks the proposed
X Y click values that that function sent
in against the screen size and the
density it then checks the other
configuration settings such as how
quickly am i clicking I don't how many
times have I clicked and that's ways
that they try to hide themselves from
advertising networks
trying to detect fraud as well and
ultimately it uses the API call dispatch
attachement to do the click so with that
I hope it was interesting we went
through all of the malware trends or PHA
trends for the first half of 2018 and
then tried to really do a deep dive into
the most modern or current techniques
that malware authors are using to become
impactful to become prevalent and how
they evolve and sort of vary their
techniques as well so a couple of key
takeaways well I guess two more broad
ones is I've now discovered that even if
you lock that door it doesn't stay
closed by the way and my second key
takeaway for you for general life is
apparently weeks after having a cold you
can still call Ike crazy so sorry about
that but in terms of actual malware
detection one of our key takeaways we've
really kind of honed in on over the last
six months at Google is that focus
detection efforts can really have a big
impact on PHA and I think one of the
categories where we've seen that is
hostile downloaders and the work that
was done last year and by highlighting
some of the categories that we see as
being the most prominent and prevalent
in the Android ecosystem we're hoping
that we can really encourage others that
if you're seeing similar trends you know
please come to us come work with us
let's collaborate you know when we all
focus in on these categories is when we
can have the best impact the second one
is the fact that we you know always need
to suspect cloaking and obfuscation
luckily mati is a little cynical and
already does that by trade but I think
all the examples that she's shown today
really highlight that right all the
impactful malware families that we see
tend to use combinations of those
techniques to try and evade detection x'
and they're constantly changing the way
they use those techniques so we need to
keep on the lookout for that
the last lessons learned from us is
don't be complacent always consider a
missing variant when we've been looking
at these impactful families we see that
most of them are really well resourced
and that means that they actually have
the capability to evolve rapidly change
things I think bread SMS is a really
good example of that with the money
they're bringing in they can hire more
and more engineer
to change the code more quickly every
time we put in detection mechanisms they
try and work them out they try and evade
them so for us as a community I think
that means we need to constantly suspect
that there's a variant we're missing so
whenever you think that you have a
family sold that you have at the right
detection mechanism go and broaden your
search look a little bit different for
new slightly different samples and see
if there's something we're missing just
saying you know we think fighting PHA is
brilliant if you think it's brilliant to
come chat and here's some more resources
so as I said those PHA definitions are
available online and we also have last
year's Android urine review report and
in general if you see something that you
suspect is PHA here's my email please
feel free to get in touch we'd love to
hear from you and so thank you all for
oh yeah yeah so thank you all for coming
coming after lunch the two of us are the
ones up here presenting but all of this
work really has been as always a
collaboration there's many different
people behind the scenes that help us
obviously analyze calculate all these
different things so yeah thank you
Russians basalt Amazon sink we know
Chin's are apparent estar
I think it's a xi amo
you told that some hours are constantly
checking where you are right now right
why is that why do you think that they
don't they don't attack on China's soil
for example so I think one you need to
so I'm not a lawyer and I'm also
obviously making some guesses of what I
think the answer is but I think based on
where the developers are in the world
and where they may be they may not want
to target their own people there's also
the checking as in red SMS that you
don't want to it's not worth executing
the bad behavior if the person is not in
the area of the world where you can make
money I think there's also depending you
may choose if you're a malware developer
to execute bad stuff in areas where you
don't think it's as likely that if
you're found you will be prosecuted or
put in jail so I think all of these sort
of come into the cost risk or the risk
benefit decision for malware authors and
you know the world is pretty hook
dispersed in how we treat find and able
to detect our fight malware I think the
only thing I'd add to that is there are
obviously some types of PHA that
deliberately try and target specific
groups right so I think fishing is
something that comes to mind that can
often be more targeted and in that case
it doesn't really make sense to broadly
target everybody when there's really a
select group that you're going after
can you talk about the tools you use to
do this kind of analysis so we can't
talk about the proprietary tools that
you Google use this to detect but for
most of my reverse engineering
I still use ida pro or the jeb
decompiler as well as then internal
tools we've developed so yeah if you are
a reverse er have used Ida or binary
ninja or any other disassembler I
started with object dump and then before
I could get a job to pay for a Jeb
decompiler license
I used the Jade X D compiler for Java
code or Android applications which is
also free thank you
hi congratulations for the presentation
two questions first you guys try to work
with law enforcement angels in parallel
to try to find these guys and the second
questions what are the strategies
against side-loaded PJ because you guys
can't drop it from the google play
because it's not there so how can you
mitigate those threats so I will take
the side loaded question first
so side loaded so google play protect is
built into Android operating system and
if a user consents then our goal is to
still protect those users even if
they're choosing not to download their
applications from play because they've
said we want GPP protection and so I
think that's especially important
because the accessibility to Google Play
also and helmet is dependent across the
world based on what is your
infrastructure
how much does downloading an app cost
cost you and things like that and so I
think I personally care and I work
almost exclusively on the non Google
Play problem is because there are so
many other people around the world who
they have a lot of reasons that mean
maybe disadvantaged in different ways
that make it side loading a better
option for them for downloading apps I
get the first question so I guess I'd
say more broadly you know at Google Play
protect we're obviously focused on what
we can impact right and so for us one of
the primary mechanisms we use to protect
users is to show them a warning so the
whole idea is we're not trying to be the
gatekeepers to what people can and can't
have on their device you know I
mentioned earlier at the cyber
presentation about categories we have
related to apps that can modify security
settings right and there are cases where
we think that's PHA because in general
it's risky but there are some users who
want it so when we show warnings usually
users can click through them if they
choose to so step one is that that is
our primary mechanism that we use to try
and detect and protect users obviously
is good
if we receive a legal request for
information and it complies with the
legal requirements of that country then
obviously we're under a lawful
obligation to provide it and as I said
before we're always open to
collaboration with the industry when it
comes to trying to fight PHA but our
first focus is on thinking about how we
can protect it in the ecosystem we
control and that is through warnings