[Music]
this talk is about sonic attack -
spinning hard drives and I am an
authority I am a security researcher
developer whatever from Argentina so I
come here because a very short trip a
very nice country let's start with the
talk because basically this talk is
about demonstration I have like a five
or six demonstration maybe not all will
work but that's the good thing about
them right
ok this talk is about measuring audio
with hard disk these look like a crazy
thing but it actually works quite fine
you need to set up this is I create a
set up is basically a regular hard disk
blue - just a piece of iron that
simulates a computer box also this can
be done with a heart inside a notebook
but it's not so obvious so to increase
the effect I do it remotely so I so you
can see that it's actually a regular
hard disk it's not like a magic trick so
let's let's go in
let's go on how this works but this is a
timing attack I mean if you do security
since why you can see that time and like
timing attacks can be very serious
lightly in the last year there's a lot
of time in attack for example a spectra
and meltdown there are timing attacks
the problem with the computers are they
are too fast and too precise and you can
measure anything the way that you
basically rack or algo with the hard
disk is measuring the difference of time
is basically the same side channel that
you can use measuring difference in CPU
processing or or whatever you can for
any system to be safe you cannot leave
information and religion you very I see
the tracer variation and timing between
an assistant as shown
shouldn't be any variation you can
measure Advent detect things in this
case we can detect Lu
but we can detect a lot of things for
example what this is what I was speaking
with just now I it's very easy to
actually measure out your heart is a
very sensitive device they don't stand a
lot of liberation and audio as you can
see is vibration that's why in the
server environment I say that you have
to mount hard disk in rubber amounts
because they are very sensitive to
vibrations and audio the thing that they
want say is that the person of of hard
drives actually varies a lot with the
vibrations I mean you havin a lot of
environment with a lot of vibration they
the person will go down and we can
measure that I mean this is super simple
this is C code that you can see down is
basically all the thing what you had to
do we only need to read a file our times
and measure how you will think that is
simple read will take the same time
every time and not that is not right
that's not right
this simple color to read a little file
in the hard disk will change something
we will take 100 milliseconds on the
return 1 milliseconds and this
difference is basically the vibration
that they heard this is bass feeling so
that does basically this is very easy
now the thing we can do is a little
toughest demonstration is about not a
heart lies with about anything else for
example every siskel whether you recover
you to the kernel should take the same
amount of time Terry but in reality
let's do the first demonstration here
but what we are seeing here is a simple
culture to the camel to ask from the
process number is get Pete if you can
see just just I asked the colonel okay
give me my process number so this year
we take exactly the same amount of time
we plot this time in the x-axis and the
I axis is the time and we can see a
brain interesting thing here sim well
what it is what is that that thing that
we are seeing here the blue part is it a
spectrum and the yellow part is basic
like no oscilloscope so that line should
be a straight line but it is not because
why because the colonel have a lot of
internal there are a lot of process in
this computer and they're firing
constantly and while you were seeing
here is basically kernel load that we
are not supposed to see but we can see
it anyway because because the computers
are really fast and they optimize a lot
so every time we see a little line here
is the camera waking up to do some
additional some hiding process for
example there are these maintenance or
or or Y field car so we actually can see
this from our own privilege process and
this is basically from every Cisco we
can we can call for example we can try
whatever Cisco we want sorry I'm not
very good programmers on how to kill it
the old-school way for example we can
try with a stub Cisco start Siskel is
just ask for information about a file
what whatever file we can see there is a
different pattern here but it's
basically the same and we can for
example it let's do another thing in
another process here you will move this
window it should see I will not see very
much but that is demonstration Center
station was working very well but the
thing is we actually are seeing the
internal behavior of the kernel that we
shall see and we use these two ratings
and a hard disk
it's the same thing but you the thing I
want to say is this not only for
artistic you can miss you can use a
timely attack to measure all kind of
physical external physical variables
let's continue with with the demo so
this is but we are sweet we are looking
just now we can this is this is
basically a security program in is in
the future tax people will use this and
we read things into T's we take all what
is this cows in this variation I don't
know what is that is it there shouldn't
be there
okay so let's the list - this is a
little graph about the capabilities of
the harddrive microphonic off of course
is not a high definition microphone is
actually is very bad it just listen to
the term it in frequencies because it's
basically a metal case it's not designed
to be a microphone basically it just you
can use to read low frequencies and some
high frequencies but not much in the
middle does barriers from hardest to
heard this because of resonance of day
of the metal box basically and also is
depend a lot in what they hardly see
screw you on I mean is you screw on a
big metal plate like this it basically
will measure the vibration of altimeter
place and will be much more sensitive
this is the setup that I have here let's
do a demonstration now about how this
work right okay this is we can we can
measure a movement because the heart is
actually is sensitive to movement the
movement is it's a very low frequency
vibration but there's Harless is very
very sensitive to it vibration and some
sound for example this let's do the
demonstration here I think here come the
demonstrations let's see the works
I know you work because I just tested
okay now we have a very similar graph
but we are plotting the real time of the
hard disk in the yellow line is the is
basically we do a lot of really hard
disk and every time we are measure it of
course the time we will value less let's
see how it is works okay look at it is
quite sensitive I just touched the hard
disk and it already took a measurement
already since an audio wave also I can
type is so sensitive I can take the
table
it actually can play some some music
here that is the microphone is thesis
but you can see it is super sensitive to
to audio we can we can type whatever it
may be we can clap how to do very very
very very very strong I have another
task you to this a self speaker that we
can actually see how sensitive the hair
is to frequency you I want to try to do
is to apply a frequency here to see
which one the harddisks can record this
is a sweep we're gonna do a frequency
from 20 Hertz to a very high very high
tone you have to be working
okay so this is another way that is
playing as the frequency is increasing
it speakers working
yeah printer is working maybe you can
see it I don't know it actually it is
world work because we need to have take
Cork a lot of value here and the
speakers are really really not a lot of
volume here for example is put in there
oh this is working well actually the
volume was enough I mean now the hair
this is completely stopped a completely
blocked because it is entering a
resonance the idol took the speaker look
at least are working well there were
some glitches there the thing is the
hardest if the heretics top working the
kernel with ever Tory crash I mean in no
weight class you will disconnect the
hard disk we can see that as the
frequency increase the Horlicks is no
longer sensitive to it
that's it no song but now it's sensitive
again I'm gonna stop this horrible
because it's hurting my ears so we have
here
it's basically yeah it's cry I used to
do it with a song but this is more
remote more like scientific and a little
strange we can see this is basically
graph of the frequency response I mean
with that for 20 Hertz to 20 I know I
think to 2 kilo Hertz I mean within
reach 20 kilo Hertz but if it is for the
microphone it will be a complete as
writing but it's not it's not a really a
good microphone and the one person thing
is maybe you can see that at one time
the heart is completely stopped that is
because if you find the primordial
resonant frequency of the hard disk I
mean the plate will sublimate a lot and
the hardest controller will basically
just stop communication at the crazy
thing is it will not just stop
we stopped responding to the computer I
mean he will not respond even a tea
comment you know I did commands from
Scotty come on to the Harvey's you will
stop completely responding so the camera
will go a little crazy we're gonna see
that we can actually crush a computer
there was some research that a Windows
it just blows blue screen Linux doesn't
blue screen but it just won't disconnect
the hard disk and we can see in our
demonstration here I want do a
demonstration of that here because I
need a very high song for 60 seconds
that's it that I'm out of the kernel and
it's crazy and II use undo it if you
want this continual demonstration oh
this is some crazy things because I just
realized what is this should work
remotely I mean there's nothing has
taught me to log to clothes or wealth I
use hard disk and do exactly the same
test so maybe I can listen to how the
abrasions footstep whatever that are in
a remote data center I mean that will
work well I tried I tried not Microsoft
servers and I have a video to prove it I
don't want to connect your microphone
Microsoft server now also you had to
wait on jalisa - sound - Sunday - to
step on the data in the data center okay
I have in video what I did now you can
see there is I connect to the UN Asher
Asher is the cloud computer from
Microsoft that's the IP yes whatever law
you need I don't care and I run to the
same mesh room system I just I know I'm
measuring the hard disk of the willful
machine now the vector machine actually
Svidler will use a real hard disk so in
theory we can measure out your entire
hard is in the claw environment and to
think is that at first I didn't see
anything I mean I
it was several several miners' without
anything that is industr lubrication
there's nobody in a computer so this
video is actually pride long you can see
here 15 minutes nothing 60-minute
there's some space liberation there but
maybe it's the candle juice blocking for
some from some things we go to about 4
min 4 you can see we start listen to
things the thing is this thing on the
side you can see this this red points
that is on the right side that one
actually that is like like the waveform
of the audio variation and and it's
different if the camera is waiting for
something and if the how this is
vibrating so I can see this is exactly
the same way from that I get if I heard
this is getting vibration so where we
are looking here is vibrations in the
Microsoft data center so I don't know
what it is I don't I don't think it's
music and in no it's playing music in
that center but probably some vibrations
on machines start running or something
working so the thing is this is so
powerful it actually can measure things
outside the booth from machine as long
as you have a real hardest but this
doesn't work in SSD so if you have an
SSD you're safe I try it
stupidly because of course nothing will
graze an SSD but the thing is it's
actually work you can measure vibrations
in a remote at the center is crazy but
work but the crazier things is you
actually can attack a heretical causa
Daniel sorry actually we just saw that
when we reach about 150 Hertz you can
see the hardest stop working and this is
basically physics I mean you find the
resonant frequencies of any mechanical
device you will break it and you can
bring down that a bridge with that so
the thing is you need very little power
I mean this speaker is only not even a
word any no not even half of what
the stocks that actually worked as way
you just found this restaurant frequency
of this entry figure just blow away so
we can do it with the hard disk yes we
can do it and I have another
demonstration I won't do here because I
don't want to spin out a different how
this every time I do this this
demonstration but I have in video
so this is the sound you know it's very
very loud
the Hardys here is just stop stop
responding to the kernel and if you can
see here I just I just did our I just
did a common to the kernel asking from
harvest and then we can see there is the
camera basically disconnect the hard
disk it doesn't exist anymore because
they can't the Linux kernel you can see
the errors they see that is it camera
saying that they do the harvest is not
responding anymore it's not responding
anymore and after a minute it just just
disconnected and it doesn't work anymore
I mean the only thing you can you can do
it is to reboot the Machine and it will
recognize the Hardys again but of course
you can damage to have this community i
damaged a lot I mean if with enough
volume you can you can destroy it very
easily they're very sensitive devices
I meant idea is that actually you need
very little sound to do it of course you
do have a bigger sound you can really
destroy how far this very easily let's
see a demonstration of course okay now I
use a song here so we can actually see
the beads you can hear
[Music]
that's the 1000 watt speaker I'm
increasing the volume you can see it
actually stopped working but that is
really not the Anna Spector I mean if
you put a 1000 speaker the hardest it
will basically destroy yourself but the
thing is you can't do it with a 200
milli watt speaker that is basically
that ain't a new thing that you can do
this are several select cases when
alarms going on in in data centers and
blowing up the hard disk and completely
destroy them so let's go in to speak
about similar work because this is not
actually probably hooked you actually a
poster your works I presented this
research about an Argentine in about
2016 I think one year ago a couple years
ago and they were after that they were
much better research at the warm what
ROFL I mean they measure things actually
build models and they discovered the
same thing basically you you blast a
hard disk without you would destroy it
I'm surprised here this is from the
material niversity is blue note they I
think they did inside me I'm not angry
about that of course not this is another
from Princeton it's the same thing
basically they did a very nice model and
discovered the same thing dimension
actually matched what I did I did it
much more not really scientific
environment but they've measurement
actually match pretty well the same
frequency also didn't side me it's okay
and well basically that's it we have a
lot of the problem here is basically
timing attack the cameras should not be
able to to let allow you to measure time
in such a precise way because you can do
this this is only the beginning you can
measure whatever you think I mean you
have wife you can measure position
measuring that the variations on the
wife is sinus what can you do you can
measure and measure a lot of things I
mean there are timings attack in
everything there is a way to to to fix
this yes at least to unprivileged user
you should made - solution time a
survivor this actually is starting to
work I mean browsers in JavaScript
doesn't allow and a high precision time
in anymore because they they know that
there are a lot of time aside aside
chance there but you still have problems
with computers and unprivileged process
and with closed environments because
this actually I had conceived actually
work perfectly in closed environments
and what is a fine way to destroy high
risk also well nothing that's that's
basically
you think it made possible to refer the
predetermined sequence of sounds you
could write that on that remote hard
disk and do your question if if I can
using sine modify the content of the
hard disk I don't think you can actually
because a hard this is very complex
devised when you write a byte you have a
error correction code I mean you you
have to first find a way to write into
the magnetic plate in such a precision
that you can actually convert a complete
sector with the correct the the error
correction called correct and that is
quite unlikely I mean this is basically
hitting the harvest wheat up with a
sledgehammer it's not very precise tool
I mean it's precise enough to measure
audio because audio is very slow and
actually it's not very good at that
either I mean you can see that you can
measure vibration basically like steps
you I cannot measure boys with this yet
maybe in the future I will find a way
but no it's a very raw technique it's
not so precise to write things but you
know no the date of the sided drive I
restrict this I just try it or just the
harder sorry the data inside the driver
is wiped it isn't more driver is it more
data inside the driver or they just they
drive are destroyed you know the dating
said the driver is relatively safe I
mean it's not safe because the plates
are rewriting and eventually we will
destroy that I mean I have a Samsung
hard our copper some hydride it won't
work anymore they do a strange noise
like like like lick lick lick lick it
just completely up but I don't
think it's the place it is like the head
the head is destroyed because the head
is very sensitively the head punch with
the heart is I probably the thing is
when the hardest fields detector
vibration it just
the head automatically and very fast
very quickly so the data actually safe
but the head stop bouncing around and
eventually you will just just get banned
as you destroy I don't know why what did
happen but it just don't work anymore in
a data center
how does affect the sound of defense in
a broom yeah well the fans has very very
low sound it's too low to affect by
depend with the fan but actually you can
measure that if you have a very high you
have a lot of noise in the data center
it the hardest we actually will work
slower that is something that isn't the
data I mean you can just have a
real video of the guy screaming of the
hard disk and it hard is basically a
starting to decreasing in in the in the
throughput I mean this is very sensitive
so if there are regular ceiling fan did
not nothing happen but you have a big
fan possibly will affect the performance
the speakers that that the notebooks can
damage the the or reduce the lifetime of
the heart of the hard disk well I did
some tests and it will depend of the
speaker of course but I did some tests
with a with a team pad in and I could
made to completely stop but it it did
affect this drop boot I mean if you
measure the drop of the heart is about
about 10 mega a 10 megabyte for a second
and if you put a speaker at the top it
will decrease so it really affects I
made this the speakers can actually as
affect the Hadees of this of the safe
not good but the thing is I think
passing specifically either too hard is
a rate well mount at the amount in a
rubber box you can you know open it so
probably if it not work is it's another
contraction it will must be even more
sensitive I mean in a tin pot that is
rubber mount it affects so maybe in
another know who is worst thank you
I have about a video of that in YouTube
you enter my channel have an on all go
can and I need use you can measure how
who the hell
get slow have you tested with the habit
right hybrid-drive
like those that have a little SSD inside
how it will be wet sorry hybrid and
those are her Bridget hybrid 80s with a
little SSD inside yes yeah I didn't try
I did you ask it if I tried this with a
hybrid I hardest I have a plate and I
also how high density no I did not but
the thing is basically and I release a
big Akashi this is hard this I also have
a cache in RAM I mean the thing is I did
is but you have to bypass takashi by
reading enough if you read our big file
or recons a lot of sectors one after the
other eventually take the cache memory
will will will spend I mean no matter if
you have a Akashi as a flash memory it
will completely filled up and when you
fill up you will start using the plate
and then you can read out you anyway I
mean you can bypass the cache memory
regarding the frequency is it possible
to run a do s attack running extremely
low frequency without human beings
noticing this attack that's an awesome
idea actually that's a very good idea
and it's very likely that you can but I
don't know really it's all depend of the
resonance of the hard disk but we can
see that the Hardys has several
resonance frequencies and maybe one of
them is an ultrasonic range that's a
very good question
when I actually you know slightly high I
I did a break food plot of the frequency
spectrum this the Pfister we can see
here is this one and we have a couple a
couple discs here's one of two inches
and the one out of three inches is I
sure would use more point here I'll show
you my eyes my science professor we will
kill me would be to the plot but there
really is this is not an ugly spectrum I
mean and we can see there is several
Peaks and that is because the hardest is
not they have several metal parts a very
complex device and each one resin and
are a different frequency so but one of
them is very likely in the thank you hi
I was going to ask about the spectrum
also but have you been able to
reconstruct some kind of a wave waveform
from the the from from what you reading
or something like that so you asking if
you I can reconstruct sound bite us well
I did some tries but I didn't apply here
because it sound awful it's not very
good if you can see here if I applied
them again it's very easy to do is you
can you can see but it's not very
doesn't have a lot of resolution and I
try some reconstruction I tried not to
find my password from the user
there you go so you can see it here that
it looks like it's really now your bid
is very low resolution so I have about
the sample rate if you can you can do an
analogy to a sample rate as a regular
microphone a sample of 8 kilohertz the
minimum 8 kilohertz 8 2 44 kilo Hertz
whatever this is about a hundred a
hundred hairs so it's very low sample
rate does not means that you can
reconstruct anything I mean you can't
we'd use the core algorithms you know
whatever new data science can come out
you can reconstruct stuff with only a
100 hairs but it's very low and but
maybe you can increase using another
technique keys but I still didn't do it
I try to represent the sound sound very
often so I didn't know that even even
showed you how about exfiltrate in data
by sound pulses have you try it
are you speaking about exfiltrate in
data from well from the hard disk from
other machine way because in sound
pulses you know let's say it resonates
at a hundred Hertz so you can do like
small swaps of a hundred Hertz and you
could encode it like longer swaps or
shoulder yeah yeah sure so you can do it
very easily I mean it will move very
fast but you can filter the password in
under one second show you and you need
basically our computer that can process
a sound and honest answer I mean is
basically communication theory you can
of course you can do it so what so long
as the computer has a speaker or
something you could perhaps exfiltrate
data
yeah they can't do it like a like a I
cap channel who you were talking about I
caps computer where you can examine a
gap because you know which computers has
speakers
voting machines oh yeah like how this to
talk you get together
that's a great idea you should do that
also
actually yeah I mean ultrasound like the
guy did mais okay okay all right thank
you very much