[applause]
Hello. This is a format we came up
with years and years ago, where the
badge team lead stands at the front
and talks, and the rest of the team
sit at the back and heckle. I used to
be one of those people and i regret it.
> I don't think they want
to hear what the format is
No?
> Just get on with it
[laughter]
First off, I've got to thank our sponsors -
they have done such amazing work. Espressif
have given us parts that didn't exist
when - what was it three months ago?
Three months ago, the chip on
your badge didn't exist at all
and we got the first production run of them - it's
brilliant. PCBgogo have manufactured assembled
10,000 boards for us - that is a heck of
a lot of boards and they've done it in a
ridiculously short timeframe and fixed many,
many problems which we'll go over in this talk.
> Many of them are entirely our fault
So, quite a long time ago now, we were developing
a badge for EMF 2020. It was quite cool.
We we got to the prototype stage, we had
lots of pictures, little bits of art,
stuff like that. We had it all planned.
It was great, everything was going well.
And then there was an apocalypse. Everything was
terrible, EMF was cancelled. So we decided to
take a positive spin on it. It's great, we've
got two entire years where we don't have to
do anything because we've already
designed a badge for the next EMF.
> Oh no you haven't!
And then the apocalypse continued. It
became 2021, and all the silicon in the
entire universe vanished. This is one of the
chips we were planning on using - it costs
$104 now - that would blow out our budget
quite a bit and Jonty would get sad with us,
and we don't want to make Jonty sad. So yeah,
it doesn't exist, so we kind of panicked a bit
and we had a bit of a brainstorming session.
We came up with some fantastic badge ideas.
I think one of my favourite ones - the musical
soldering iron was a good idea. It's both an
MP3 player and a soldering iron. The quadcopter was
quite good, and the thermal sensing monocle badge
just because it means we get to use round LCDs
and i'm slightly obsessed with round LCDs.
So yeah, we went through all of these and
we carry on with brainstorming. We decided
to go with the one that was between the
de-auther, particularly to troll the NOC,
and the high voltage badge, which
would probably kill everyone.
Apparently we're not allowed to do that
either - First Aid get annoyed at us.
So yeah, we designed a new badge.
We went with a microcontroller
that didn't exist yet, and
Espressif would guarantee
that we could get them before the event. Quite
close to the event, but still before the event.
> Technically
Sort of mostly before the event. It's a fast
schedule, we think we can do it. It's fine,
yeah, let's go. So, we're a few weeks ago now.
We have prototyping, everything seems to work.
It's starting to look pretty
we're doing pretty well.
> Yeah it all went perfectly
well, nothing at all went wrong
> yeah, thank you for attending
the talk yeah you've been wonderful
> those four months we had
no stress whatsoever, yeah
So here's the first disaster.
We decided to be clever.
When we started designing we wanted a crypto chip
on the thing and we found somebody who had 3,500 of
them in stock so we bought them straight away.
Then, we tried to use them and it turned out
they didn't in any way support any of the crypto
that we needed. So yeah, if anyone wants to buy
3500 A1006 crypto chips, if you email
badge@emfcamp.org we can sell you them.
Apparently they are now worth more than we paid
for them so, you know, it will help fund EMF.
So we did a redesign. We managed
to find a chip that we could buy,
and we could afford, we couldn't talk to
it over I²C which is unfortunate because
ideally if you have a chip on your board
you want to be able to actually use it.
It's a bit of a pain - we couldn't get any any
of them. We could get 3,500 of them from China,
we couldn't get one of them - apparently that's
the thing. We found a dev kit left over from 2014.
It was incredibly expensive but it had some chips
in that we thought might be kind of the right one?
They were kind of the right one, we still couldn't
actually talk to them. That was fun. So yeah
this is interesting. So, Microchip on their
crypto chips, they don't label them. As part of
their "overall security features" the part marking
for all crypto devices is "intentionally vague".
"The marking on the top of the package does not
provide any information as to the actual device
type or the manufacturer of the device." This
isn't security, this is just silly but you know.
We're not an IC manufacturer, surely it's
fine. So yeah, have i already said this bit?
> You got the last point
Ah yes, we managed to talk to it in the
end. We were trying to talk to it at five
times the speed it wanted us to talk to
and we just forgot to turn that bit on.
> This will be a theme
[laughter]
Oh, I did actually try, when we got these,
to pull some strings because I have through
work some contacts within Microchip. I
spoke to somebody quite high up in their
tech support and they they told me when
i asked them that "as part of Microchip's
overall security features the part marking for
all crypto devices is intentionally vague."
So yeah, it wasn't as useful as i was hoping.
Here's some fun. When you try to buy
three and a half thousand of something,
your vendors just vanish. This battery
vendor, every three months for the past
six years, has sent us an email saying "do
you want to buy anything? We've got loads of
batteries, come and buy some batteries, we've got
batteries, come and buy batteries." You send them
an email and they're like "batteries, what?
We don't sell batteries." Or if they just...
> If anybody finds these vendors
please email badge@emfcamp.org
So yeah, we weren't getting any response from
this battery and this was about a month ago and
it takes about a month to get batteries from China
to the UK. This was becoming an issue. We sent out
the bat signal at this point and we spoke to other
European-based conference badge teams and we stole
their supplier who is amazing. They respond
to all of our emails, they send us loads and
loads of emails, they send me random WhatsApps.
They once called me. On the phone. It was weird.
> They also doubled our battery
capacity as soon as you asked.
Yeah, so the first battery we got through
they were going to give us 70 mAh which you know
we could have done with and slowly, in
between us paying for the battery and
them actually shipping them, they managed to keep
increasing the capacity of them. I'm not sure how
but we're pretty sure they're
not lying. Like 95% sure.
So yeah, we've got the batteries. The batteries
are on the way. That was happening fantastically.
The problem was, we didn't have the...everything
else that goes on the circuit board.
We'd sent quite a lot of money to
our China sourcing expert who had,
as far as we could tell, just stopped responding
to our emails after we'd sent him all this money
which isn't what you want after sending
somebody a heck of a lot of money.
He wasn't getting our emails, we weren't
getting his, neither of us had realised
that we were both waiting for an email from
another person that had already been sent
eventually I was getting to the point of writing
emails that started "as per my last email"
And then somebody pointed out to me that I could
in fact phone them.
> Whaaaat?
And that worked straight away.
I know! apparently these things can
actually be used to make phone calls.
> I hear that we gave out
phones in a previous year
Yeah
We got in touch and it turned out that our email
sending solution wasn't. Which is not ideal.
So yeah, we started production. We had
all the bits, everything was going well
and then we stopped production because everything
broke. Wi-Fi was just completely broken. We had
tested this as part of our initial prototypes
- we tested it by having a look and seeing if
we could see any Wi-Fi networks. What apparently
none of us had ever thought to test with it was
if you could actually connect to a
Wi-Fi network. Turns out you couldn't.
When we transmit, nothing was happening
and sometimes it was just resetting, so
we started going a bit silly with this. We were
adding extra capacitors everywhere, there were
inductors. This picture down here has a little
kind of "high rise" of capacitors on it trying
to trying to figure out what the heck was actually
going on. Nothing helped, we got our RF wizards in
they started generating these strange charts -
i'm pretty sure it's the tea leaves that they're
actually doing. Even that, nothing was found
- it just wasn't wasn't working and it should
have been working. And then we figured out that
you could take the antenna off and it worked.
[laughter]
Which is sort of the opposite of what
you normally expect with an RF circuit.
So yeah, that was a bit weird. So yeah, we just
turned down the power - turn down the volume a bit
and it turns out it's not talking over itself
anymore and it now kind of works? You have to
stand fairly close to a DK as you all will
have found trying to update your badges.
Yeah, it works. Fantastic, we can restart
production again. Oh wait. No. This is a
USB-C connector. USB-C is brilliant, it's on
everything nowadays. This is a USB-C connector
with very very wobbly pins and apparently that
is incredibly difficult to actually manufacture.
So yeah, they came with bent pins. PCBgogo who
manufactured our boards, they were reworking them
as they were coming off the line, they did 150 and
then just asked us to actually try and get them
connectors that would work. So yeah we got our
component sourcer to start yelling at people, he
yelled at the right people and they said "oh yeah
we'll send you over a replacement reel, they'll
be ready at the beginning of June." Yeah that's
a bit too late. We asked if we could delay EMF
until July but apparently there's another festival
here at the time so we're not allowed to do that.
We figured out a really cool - well
PCBgogo figured out a really cool way
of getting around this. They made a stencil
that has two different layers in it, to
allow you to add more solder paste
underneath the USB-C connector
and just kind of...have enough goo there to grab
the pins? Is that right? That sounds right yeah?
> Yeah so they made a stencil that is thicker
on one end than the other so tower of solder,
tower of goo on there is taller
and it reaches the bent pins
Yes
> And doesn't short too many of them out
> Right
Well it sure, we got one out of all of the
badges we made that wasn't working after
that which is pretty amazing, considering it
was all of them that were broken beforehand.
So yeah, they then gave us two assembly lines
and, as far as i can tell, literally everybody
in their factory and made all of our PCBs.
This was about two weeks ago now so...
> It feels like two months
It does. I'm pretty sure I've got quite a
lot more grey hair than I had when I started.
So yeah it was done! The boards
had shipped! Then this happened.
> I'd like to personally apologise to
Wren for annoying them so much with "what
flight is leaving from Hong Kong airport
right now? What's going in an hour?"
> We did actually track it down to the
correct flight, so all our estimates were
exactly correct and we knew exactly what plane
our packages were on at every point in time
> We can't write software
but we can track DHL flights.
Handily, it turns out DHL are incredibly
pessimistic when it comes to getting things
through UK customs, and we actually managed
to get these a week before they were expected,
which is good because getting them
tomorrow would have been non-ideal.
Yeah they arrived! There's like boxes and all
sorts. This is the badge tent, if you've checked
into the badge tent it looks a lot messier
than this right now although i think the
team have been tidying it today while i've
been panickingly writing this presentation.
They work! Look at that! It's got a
little thing on it and everything. Woo!
So we started assembling. We got the
sweatshop going. It was quite warm
we're not still not sure about
the kind of "sweatshop" nomenclature
but it was pretty apt on Wednesday last week when
it was a lot nicer weather than this. So yeah we
we did some pretty good work between all
of the volunteers who helped out with the
sweatshop just kind of flashing things,
assembling things, testing things.
So yeah, thank you, thank you so much for
everybody who's volunteered for that. It was
brilliant. I want to give a round of applause
to all the people who helped out with that.
[applause]
And then we stopped again because it turned out
that some of the screens weren't working. Quite a
lot of the screens weren't working. I was sat down
making badges and six in a row didn't work.
So yeah, we started figuring out that like
25% of all the badges weren't working,
and we'd bought 23% more badges than we needed.
One of those numbers is bigger than the
other one and it's in the bad direction.
Our volunteers figured this one out
entirely on their own, it's brilliant,
we didn't have to think or anything. Although
we did quite a lot of thinking and panicking.
We were kind of running around going "aaaaaaah"
while everybody else was figuring this one out.
We started assembling the working batches
of screens because we were able to split
off the ones that were working and the ones
that weren't working, while we debugged the
actual problem. So Matt woke up at 1am with
an idea of how to fix this. He broke it and
started fiddling around with our initialisation
code, and he fixed it but unfortunately his
badge was broken in a different way as
well, so he didn't realise he'd fixed it.
> And then I spent a load of time the next day
saying "oh, I've already tried that, don't bother"
Yeah
> I didn't believe him
> Fair.
I'm glad you didn't believe him.
[applause]
So yeah we're up and running again. Woo! Look at
that. That is a pile of 2000 badges there I think.
That's a lot of badges. It took a lot of time,
and there's a lot more still not in that picture.
> If we could have less people come to...fewer
people come to EMF next year, that would be great,
[laughter]
> so that we don't have to
assemble quite so many badges
> And let's not do three
circuit boards next time as well
Oh we'll go for six next time
[laughter]
No?
> Can I point out I know where you live Bob?
So yeah, we were able to start giving out our
badges right after the opening talk which is
entirely unprecedented in EMF history. I
got to buy myself my own barcode scanner
because the entrance tent needed all of
the ones that we normally steal from them.
And i've always wanted to buy a barcode scanner
so now I have a barcode scanner, it's fantastic.
So almost everyone has actually picked up their
badges by now. We issued 2,000 of them on that
first day and we're now up to 2,370...that's
wrong - it was 2,380 when I looked. Shocking.
> Yeah we tried closing the badge
tent and people turned up for badges.
Ben's not been allowed to leave the badge tent.
He lives there now. So yes, we're all incredibly
exhausted. Oh. Ooh. This is the end of my bit,
I get to sit down now, so yeah, thanks everyone!
[applause]
MORAG: I haven't planned this.
> It's alright, none of us have planned this.
> Can i have a heckling microphone?
Oh no, you're not supposed to heckle me. Be nice!
What am i pressing?
> Press space
Yes, so they asked me to make it
pretty and I got a bit carried away.
So i was like "ooh it's a lovely wavy shape, we've
got the sea theme." I was already drawing the
the big tiling graphic that you might
have seen on the screens and on the
tablecloths and stuff. It's like, oh I'm really
into the groove of drawing sea creatures now
but now I have the opportunity
to make them shiny! So...
I was sketching all kinds of things on paper
and i was like "oh this is this is brilliant
I've never done this before!" And then I was
having trouble figuring out the scale and then
I got my very own prototype boards to play with
and I got the paint markers out and I was like
oh actually I think this is actually how much I
can fit on there. So that was really good fun.
I'm not sure what's going to happen when I
press this button, what have we got next?
So you can probably tell, as I say I
got a bit carried away, Kliment was
absolutely fantastic on working through with me
on iterations of "oh this is a great idea...but"
> But we can't do that, because it won't work.
Yes we need we need to squeeze too many
electrons here, we can't fit the seaweed in.
[laughter]
> I literally said that
So it was a really interesting challenge of
working with these circuit traces as a
medium because if you sort of...hang on...
So the top of the board was less challenging
because there's a lot less going on,
so it's like, oh there's some blank space there
the ground plane, I can play with that. I'm
sure I can do something nice there. Oh
no the electrons have to fit through.
But eventually we sort of iterated
through it and went "okay you can have
this much coral here and here and here, don't
put anything there, stop putting things here,
and you can have that fish but it can't be shiny."
But I really recommend it as an exercise. It's
a really fun challenge and I'm hoping
they'll have me back again next time,
and it was an absolute pleasure, and seeing them
all come together is just ridiculous. But...
> Yeah can i just say at this point like at the
point where I said like "okay none of this will
work" I honestly believed that none of it would
work and i thought we'd have to throw that art
away, and you actually managed to fit it in
every constraint I gave you so that was amazing.
It turns out, if you have some - because I had
no idea what I was doing, I had no idea what any
of these chips did - I was like I've just got
the layout and draw on top of that. It's like
"but you can't restrict me to just one colour!
I need board traces and I need shiny things."
But with with actually sitting down
and spelling out which areas to protect
we managed to figure out a way of communicating
that, which hopefully we'll we'll get around to
writing up some time so you can learn from
my headaches and and so much art thrown out.
> So what stuff on there is
cool but they won't be able
to see because there's components on top of it?
> Right, yeah, we should show all the hidden stuff
Okay
> You've got the chest right there
So Jonty went "well it's under the water,
can we have a treasure chest?" because it's
a board about secrets and things
so it's like okay - it has to have
a hidden treasure chest which is under
the screens on the front of the board.
> But please don't pry them up because
you will break the screen if you do that.
Do it really carefully
> We're running out of spares, although we do have
some so if you need a screen fixed we can do that
Yeah but are they allowed to lift up the battery?
> Yeah gently, gently
Because if you look under the
battery you'll find an octopus
with a glowing golden eye which made me very
happy. And if you need to - if you want to
solder yourself to an auxiliary
power supply you've got a nice little
seahorse and starfish to attach onto. But
where lots of hidden stuff is ... is on the
extremely busy bottom board. So there's a there's
a special request - is that the...
> Blåhaj
...the CPU it's under?
> Oh that's the memory chip
That's the memory chip. Okay so remember your
sharks - remember your Ikea sharks. I put
a little one of those circle accent things on
top of the fins so you would know who it was,
but there was also a special request that the
crypto chip obviously needed a cryptid under it
so we have Nessie there as well.
Yeah i think that's most of it.
> Yeah there's also the little red board
Yes and there's - a last minute edition was
our cool little adapter from PCBgogo like
"can you just maybe spruce this up a
bit as well because it doesn't match?"
> And you did that in what, half an hour?
Some time. It wasn't too bad. I was like, I'm
drawing octopuses anyway for everything else,
I might as well add some more. And I reused the
seahorse, that's me being lazy there. This was
a really fun and a really amazing experience and
like them taking the time to interface with me on
making this functional, and letting me have
free reign with the pretty was a really
wonderful experience so thank you all so much
for trusting me with this I had so much fun.
[applause]
I've been asked to point out something else which
is...you might not notice unless
you get your microscope out,
or your magnifying glass, is that behind the weed
- what's this area here at the end of the bus with
all the fish? So if you follow the fish behind
the weed is a Moray eel chasing a couple of fish.
Here. Is that working? yeah
> I would have missed that one
There's quite a lot on here. Have you seen
the...there's little anemones everywhere.
There's some on the front board as well around
here, and little bits of coral. So they...it's
a little bit darker than I expected on the
finished board but I hope you have fun looking
at it and I can't wait to play with mine so I
hope you all have a great time with it as well.
[applause]
So apparently i'm doing a slide as well.
So yeah, thanks for everyone who spent
some time hacking on the badge, whether it's
software or hardware it's been really brilliant
looking on Twitter and IRC and various social
media things and just walking around the camp
seeing people doing fun stuff. So there's
games on the app store now, there's
three separate pride visualisations which I
think says a lot about EMF in a very good way,
and there's people been doing stuff with
the hardware as well, we made 3,500 of those
expansion boards in red - there's still loads of
them left so if anyone has hardware hacking ideas
and they want some spares or some extras
to do things, swing by the badge tent
probably pretty soon because I don't know
how much longer we'll be open and and get
some of those. People doing some really cool
things with those and also the people messing
around with 3D printers and building cases and
joystick nubbins and all these wonderful things.
It's so great to actually see people making
use of the badge and expanding on things that
we never even thought of doing. So, yeah thank
you all so much. And I think that is the end.
[applause]
BOB: I don't know why i came back up here because I
don't have anything to say but I personally...this
is one of my first times doing the kind of team
lead role and I just want to thank the rest of
the team for all being completely amazing. It's
been a great badge project this year,
we've got it done and we've had enough
for everyone and it's just been...it's
been really nice and I now get to sleep which is
fantastic. So I just want to thank you everyone.
[applause]