okay so good morning
um so to warm your brains up I'd like
you to try and read the paragraph on
screen
thank you guys
okay so give me a wave if you've been
able to read the paragraph
excellent brilliant everybody's awake
so
this is a paragraph unjumbled
and
I like this paragraph because it shows
just how automatic our reading ability
has become so when you start off
learning how to read you're having to
sound out each letter and it's really
effort it takes a lot of effort but as
we've developed in our reading ability
it's become so automatic that even when
the words are all jumbled up that we are
still able to make sense of things
so this is the psychological party
tricks talk and one of the first things
I said in the description is that I
can't read your mind
um so I just thought I'd do a little
demonstration of this
so
can everybody pick a card don't tell the
people next to you
I just want you to memorize the card
so pick one of the cards and memorize it
please
okay has everybody got a card
yep
okay so this is me I'm Dr Emma McDonald
um on Twitter I'm ninja cats
um I'm a psychologist I'm mainly
interested in teaching and learning
teaching statistics memory and dyslexia
which is what my PhD was actually in but
as a lot of people with phds most of my
time is spent doing something completely
different to the subject to my PhD
um I'm a senior lecturer at Cardiff
Metropolitan University in Psychology
and education and I spend most of my
time teaching on a Master's in
psychology in education so it's very
much applying psychology to education in
the classroom
but I spend most of my time listening to
a rocker metal station called primordial
so any rocker metal fans in the crowd I
recommend checking out that radio
station
and I've got our two pictures of my
lovely overlords Audrey and Archie up
there who spend most their time
paying it a lot of tension invading Zoom
meetings and causing Havoc
so that's just a little bit about me
so hopefully everyone can still remember
the card they picked yep
okay so I should have made your card
disappear now
so can you put your hands up if your
card is missing
good start
has anyone know exactly how I did this
yeah
I see a hands going up
so what you'll notice is I've changed
all the cards
so these are the original set of cards
and the thing is key thing is I only
asked you to focus on remembering one of
them
then I distracted you for a while to
hopefully get you to forget all the
other cards only the one you remembered
and because they're all very similar
it's quite easy to do that
and so that's where there's completely
different set of cards appeared
somebody like wow
sorry about oh I know this one
so it's quite a nice little party trick
especially when lots of people say oh
you're a psychologist can you read my
mind
I can try
so this is another nice little
demonstration it's
a gif and if you focus on it you can
actually change the direction of the
train
so it'll go you might see it coming
towards you and then if you focus you
can make it go in a different direction
foreign
managed to change direction of the train
excellent it's really annoying after the
first time you've done it kind of
constantly flipped which is quite
irritating
so now I've got another one and just a
warning for anyone who's sensitive to
flashing images there are images
flashing here so it's an image then it's
a gray screen and then it's an image
again
so the aim of this is for you to Spot
the Difference
between the two images
so you'll see a first image it'll flash
up gray screen and then it will show a
second image and I want you to try and
Spot the Difference between the images
now when you see the difference if you
could put up your hand
so once you've Spot the Difference if
you could put up the hand so I can see
you've spotted it
so here's the first one
so hand up when you spot the difference
okay A lot of people are spotting it
some people looking very frustrated
for those of you who haven't spotted the
difference look at the red drink and
count the number of straws
okay so here's another one
again hands up when you spot the
difference
harder
okay
let's
so again look at the bottom of the
screen count the number of arches
so that was a bigger change in the
picture
but because it was down at the bottom of
the screen people find it a lot more
difficult
so here we have another one so again
hands up when you spot the difference
some people are getting really good at
this now
so the disappearing Great Wall of China
and I think this is the most tricky one
sometimes it still catches me out if I
haven't looked at this picture for a
while
so
so again it's on the edge of
the picture and this these kind of
little tricks are really good at
demonstrating how our Vision Works so
what you think you're seeing is you're
thinking you're seeing a whole picture
so you think you're looking at that
whole slide or the whole image at the
front actually what your eye is doing is
dartering it down and building up an
image in your mind
and because this is a small change in
the image often unless you're looking at
that person's screen at exactly the
right time you won't be able to see the
difference
and as I said the first one you found
quite easy many of you because it was at
the center of the image and we tend to
focus on the center of the image and
build up the picture around it so the
ones that the changes that are on the
edge after much more difficult to spot
so I've been speaking for a while I'm
going to hand over to another
psychologist Richard Wiseman now hi I'm
Richard this is Sarah and we're going to
perform the amazing color changing card
trick with this blue-backed deck of
cards now the idea is very simple I'm
just going to spread the cards in front
of Sarah and ask her to push any car
towards the camper
I'm like okay let's see I'm gonna go for
this card here okay now Sarah could have
selected any card at all from the deck
but she selected the card which is now
face down on the table what I'm going to
ask her to do is show us which card she
selected
right so the card that I chose was in
fact the three of diamonds the three of
diamonds okay excellent choice that card
goes back into the deck now I'm just
going to spread the cards face up on the
table do a little click of the fingers
and you'll see that Sarah's card here
has now got a blue back not particularly
surprising what's slightly more
surprising is all of the other cards
have got red backs and that is the
amazing color changing Archer
[Music]
[Applause]
hi I'm Richard this is Sarah and we're
going to perform the amazing color
changing card trick with this blue back
deck of cards now the idea is very
simple I'm just going to spread the cars
in front of Sarah and ask her to push
any car towards the camper
I'm like okay let's see I'm gonna go for
this card here okay now Sarah could have
selected any card at all from the deck
but she selected the card which is now
face down on the table what I'm going to
ask her to do is show us which card she
selected
right so the card that I chose was in
fact the three of diamonds the three of
diamonds okay an excellent choice that
card goes back into the deck now I'm
just going to spread the cards face up
on the table do a little click of the
fingers
and you'll see that Sarah's card here
has now got a blue back not particularly
surprising what's slightly more
surprising is all of the other cars have
got red backs and that is the amazing
color changing Archer
[Music]
it means very good he's a magician
and a psychologist
um he's got loads of really cool videos
he's also got lots of really good books
and they're designed for people that
aren't necessarily have any intention of
studying psychology mainly for fun hands
up if you spotted any of the changes the
first time you watch that video
okay interestingly wave your hand if
you've seen that video before if you
spotted it
Okay so
there's only a very small number of
people that notice any changes and again
it's that same principle we think we're
seeing the whole screen you think you're
watching the whole video but actually
you were focused on the magic trick and
that's the AIM so Focus you're you're
focusing your attention to the magic
trick and then you don't spot all the
changes in the background
and there is a lot of bigger changes in
that video there and that's the
principle a lot of magicians use so a
lot of magic magic is all based on
getting the audience to focus their
attention on a particular spot on a
particular action and then you don't
notice all the other things going on
so moving on from kind of tricks of your
vision where there's changing images one
of the things that I don't know if you
are aware about is the idea of this halo
effect so we tend to judge people more
positively if they are more attractive
so the more attractive someone we often
give them kind of more positive
characteristics so on screen here I have
two famous and controversial depending
on which end of the spectrum you're on
and leaders but they were both generally
classed as quite attractive
um and they would seem quite positively
now some of you may be wondering why
I've put them on upside down
fight turn the images correctly
foreign
so again this teaches us a lot about
facial processing we focus a lot on the
eyes and the mouth
and I say they looked quite normal
when they were upside down because the
mouth and the eyes are upside down and
that's what we focus on so it's very
easy for you to look at those images and
go yeah that's fine
um it's only when you realize how messed
up the image are it's very very freaky
so this is another one which is quite
interesting and this apparently I
haven't verified it was not come up with
by psychologists it was come up with by
schoolboys but there are psychological
principles in place here so what you see
on screen here are perfectly respectable
celebrities in swimming costumes
now if I cover up this picture it gets
Ruder
okay
foreign
and
we like to fill in gaps with our mind
and unless we were told they were
wearing swim costumes we like to fill it
in with the rudest possible option
so again perfectly respectful not so
much and remember it's your mind doing
that that's not me
so I've been talking for a while now and
I really want to get you guys to do a
bit of talking
um all together
hopefully so what I'm going to do is I'm
going to show you a screen of words
and instead of reading what the word
says I want you to say the color it is
printed in so we're going to have a
practice one on here so the big word
we're not going to say psychology we're
saying the color it's printed in so
everyone together
okay brilliant
okay everyone ready for the next screen
and if you make a mistake say it again
and we'll see how long it takes everyone
to get through the screen
so off we go so blue
okay everyone's finished about the same
time which is nice
I don't find that quite easy
okay some of you I can feel giggling
because you know what's coming next
so we're gonna do it again on my second
screen saying rule the play so it's red
[Music]
and everything
okay so I could hear everybody start off
really well and you're like yes I've got
this and normally by the second line
everyone starts going a bit Haywire
so again this is another one of those
kind of principles about how automatic
our reading has become so when you're in
well preschool you learn colors first
you're able to point at something and go
that's red that's yellow you were able
to name colors before you were able to
read
but reading takes over it becomes
automatic so you all are then having a
little mental battle in your heads going
no don't read it say the color
and again it's just a really nice
demonstration of how far we've come and
again it's always when you start to
learn something new it's always effort
it takes a lot of effort and it's quite
hard to pick up something new but this
is a nice demonstration of just how far
you've come in Reading even if you found
it very difficult to start with I'm
severely dyslexic and again I can do
this and it still tricks me up
okay so this is a nice dilemma for you
and it's quite a big room
so imagine this was an example now
and you get the final page of your exam
and you see this message
select whether you want two extra points
or marks same word
um two extra points or six extra points
added to your final art exam grave so
you get to choose whether you have two
or six extra points added to your final
exam great but there's a small catch
if more than 10 of the people exec are
taking exams like six marks then nobody
in the whole room gets any extra marks
so you're not allowed this to discuss
this with the people around you you can
have a look around the room see how many
people are here
decide whether you would select either
two or six so don't discuss it
okay hopefully everyone's made this
decision
so I'm going to ask everyone who thinks
they're going to take six marks can you
put up your hand
okay
nobody's gonna get anything
one of the things that's interesting is
do you think you would have changed your
mind if you were able to talk to the
people around you so do you think you
would have behaved differently
if it's a smaller group would you be
that made a different decision if they
were all people you knew well would you
make a different decision and this is a
really nice dilemma and it's something
that's been used a lot in economics
um for many years but one of the things
that's interesting that's been applied
to at the moment is about environmental
science and climate change
because one of the things that we have
to do to help prevent climate change is
always pick the two so make the more
difficult decision so maybe spend more
money on an electric car or make more
effort to get public transport so it's
less easy for us
but it's better for everybody overall in
a bigger picture so this is quite a nice
little example and it's been applied to
I would say the world's biggest problem
at the moment
so I'm coming towards the end of the
talk now and it is the morning but I am
a memory researcher originally so I'd
like you to memorize this list of words
so I'm going to give you a little bit of
time to memorize this list now
please don't cheat and write it down or
take a photo
okay so hopefully you've got to the end
of that list
so I've got two nice little riddles for
you now and again it shows kind of how
we think quite often
so we've got the first one about the
lily pads and the second one about the
Baton ball
again have a chat with the people next
to you
see if you can work out the answer to
the two
thank you
okay first for the lily pads can anyone
tell me the answer
[Applause]
47 excellent so it doubles in size so
the day before it was half filling the
pond what about the Baton ball
foreign
yeah
so again often we kind of take mental
shortcuts with our thinking
and again it's one of those very famous
books in psychology of fast thinking
fast and slow and we're constantly
taking mental shortcuts and people
really struggle with these problems
because the way that we kind of process
the information
we often kind of jump to one conclusion
rather than another but that was just a
distraction
the big thing was the memory test so
when I show these these words I wish
when you say yes if you saw them on the
original list and know if they were not
on the original list so start off dream
cat
yup
okay brilliant you were all wonderful
participants because
these are the answers
and I was able to implant a false memory
and because sleep was not in the
original list and I'm doing another talk
today about memory
and this is one of the principles that
we use in that talk is that we often
memorize lists based on their meaning
now if you go back to the original list
you'll notice every single one of those
words are very semantically for meaning
wise linked to memory
so the way that we memorize things we
have a network and every time you're
reading one of those words it was
triggering the word sleep
and so we would go sleep sleep sleep
sleep every time you read those words
then I did a lovely little bit of
distraction and getting you to chat to
the people around you to get some more
distraction in there and so
here when you came to this list you were
like
now suresleep must have been on that
list and thank you for all the people
that said yes but well done so there's
people with excellent memory that said
no
but again it's a nice demonstration of
how fallible our memory is so even on a
short memory test like that I was able
to implant a false memory so we're all
susceptible to them
you guys so much for taking part
at McDonald's my Twitter handles ninja
cats and that's a lovely cat pretending
to be a raven or a crow
thank you
and obviously I've been analyzing you
all since you got here so I've created a
personality profile for you so have a
read of this see if I've got it slightly
accurate
[Music]
uh
so give me a little wave if I've maybe
got about 50 accurate or higher
oh there's a few people admitting to it
so obviously I haven't been analyzing
you this is a paragraph full of Barnum
statements that generally most people
will think applies to themselves so to
see there's a load of caveats in there
so people go oh yes that's a bit like me
and this is the sort of thing that's
used a lot by fortune tellers and people
that do star signs so lots of Barnum
statements but I think it's a really
nice demonstration that
it's we're all quite similar there's a
lot of things about insecurities in
there we all have different insecurities
we all have our own mental health issues
and it's something that we should
recognize that brings us together as a
group but thank you guys very much for
your attention today
[Applause]