okay so beast lights Pittsburgh would
like to take a couple of moments and
recognize our platinum sponsors trusted
SEC SecureWorks checkpoint cyber
crucible Brown tower ethical intruder
cyber reason burrowed in' XM cyber area
one is m CrowdStrike
logarithm Optive and fire i thank you
all for your support of the conference
and helping to make this happen so the
next speaker that i will be introducing
is mr. Kevin Cody who will be presenting
on a topic called ed folks tell no tales
a little bit about Kevin Kevin Cody is a
principal application security
consultant with experience working at
several fortune 500 enterprises all
those particular experience is geared
toward hacking web and mobile
applications
he's also experienced in the entire
gamut from mainframes to embedded
systems kevin is adamant on helping
build up developers through security
which can be seen in his involvement
with an O wasp we're all speaking of
events like code mash or besides in his
spare time Kevin B can be found
attempting to repair something via
online DIY videos reading tech books
fishing or simply spending time with his
wife and children without further ado
let's welcome Kevin Cody thank so
nothing is quite as awkward as standing
2 feet from someone reading your own bio
it sounded a lot better on paper so uh
yeah thanks for all coming I know it's
three o'clock
besides talks are usually much more well
attended earlier in the morning I think
that's because it's pre lunch pre booze
pre whatever you want to do at the end
of the day on the Friday but you're all
here I hope you'll be able to take
something from this I thank you all for
for coming in and supporting both
besides Pittsburgh and myself so yeah
we're gonna talk about dead folks tell
no tales so quickly although the the
intro was was excellent
that's me last year I got the the the
black badge of honor here at besides
Pittsburgh besides Pittsburgh is my
favorite conference bar none
but yeah so he mentioned that I am
a principal application security
consultant about to start my next
chapter I'm currently unemployed for
today because I started something new on
Monday so that'll be fun
I'm a walk sport guy if you haven't had
a chance to go to the lockpick village
I created a pretty fun game with white
sand and gifts and all kinds of fun
stuff so the lockpick village is all the
way on the other side of the venue this
year with the CTF room and we're gonna
be doing one more competition where
we're gonna be giving away some prizes
so please join the the lockpick village
if you haven't done that yet and after
this talk I might even be able to give
you a hand and show you how to do that
if you haven't done a lot get and I'm an
eternal student mentee and hopefully
mentor so if you're looking for a mentor
you're interested in getting into AB 2nd
you have questions concerns come to me
I'm on slack I'm on Twitter I'm on
LinkedIn
hit me up happy to guide you in the
right direction or even more if needham
enough about me we're gonna get into
some interesting topics so just a quick
warning I am NOT a lawyer I don't even
play one on TV
I'm an app sec guy I'm a hacker that's
me
if you have any concerns questions
comments about the subject of this talk
please go consult an estate attorney
this is some serious stuff things change
quite rapidly in this space and I am not
liable nor reliable enough to tell you
how you should handle your end affairs
so please take some of this and move
forward I am yeah it's kind of like a
lawyer but half-half is good so I'm
gonna be talking about death the the
honest-to-goodness truth is I'm talking
about giving away your stuff getting
access to your stuff after your life so
if this isn't a subject you want to talk
about if you feel uncomfortable about it
if you're dealing with something
personally I totally get it there's an
awesome talk next door there's booze
there's drinks there's coffee help
yourself but I
certainly aren't here to bring up any
bad memories or anything like that and
policies that I'm gonna be talking about
may change in the future so you know if
Facebook or Google or whatever decide to
change how they handle things what's
required you know unfortunately those
things are out of my control but I can
hopefully give you a nugget to take back
and move forward so after all that why
are we here
what are we what are we doing here so
I'm gonna start this off with a story
it's a personal story but it's it's
honestly where I started thinking about
the subject so a few years ago actually
about seven years ago I was in my
mid-20s just started a new job was
literally a weekend and felt something
off something was it wasn't quite right
my wife happened to be in Germany
visiting her brother at the time she was
just me was FaceTime with my wife and
said hey something's not right I think I
think I need to go to the doctor you
know there's an issue and of course
she's halfway around the world and she's
asking me questions what are we gonna do
about this what's gonna happen here so
well one thing at a time so I go to the
doctor and sure enough I went on a
Saturday and Monday morning my doctor
calls and I've cancer I need to go have
an operation first thing Monday morning
they're actually I'm sorry Tuesday
morning because he called me on Monday
and luckily my wife was able to get home
from Germany and it was all good
operation everything was set no chemo no
radiation I'm as healthy as a horse now
but during that time I started thinking
I handle all of our finances I handle
the taxes I handle all of that stuff and
it started me thinking what would happen
if I wasn't here tomorrow
what would happen if my wife needed to
get access to my password manager or my
iPhone or what have you do are we
properly planning for these events
because it's it's it's very serious I'm
gonna go over a lot of scenarios here
that will hopefully have you thinking to
yourself what would I do in
situation how would I handle this or I
never even thought about that situation
that's really all I'm here to prime and
prepare you to do is to have those
difficult discussions and have those
conversations internally with your
friends family and what-have-you but I
am a technologist so I'm gonna break
down some of the technical terms and
hopefully do some education as well
because I see a lot of familiar faces
even faces who are calling me out for my
spelling and a lot of people are coming
here to me because you're used to the
technical content that I deliver so I'm
gonna hopefully give you a little bit of
that but honestly this is more of a soft
skills this is more of a conversational
type topic so yeah that's that's the
story so yeah we're gonna go over
authentication talk about some of the
different paradigms that are widely in
use today I'm gonna go over some
password vaulting solutions and discuss
some of the pros cons and and issues
with those I'm gonna hit on federated
authentication I'm gonna talk about why
we need to be quest I think I hit hinted
on that enough in my story but it should
be pretty obvious after we're going
through this stuff I'm gonna go over
some policies terms and conditions and
I'm gonna wrap up so authentication its
core right is something you have no or
are right those are the three pillars of
authentication so most of us are
familiar with your username and your
password right that's typical you know
in the early days of UNIX
you know and it was open system and and
people just use time sharing option and
didn't really have have usernames or
passwords and then you know we evolved
into this Multi multi user computing and
we started equipping usernames of
passwords and and private files and
whatnot so that's really the tried and
true as things continue to progress we
went to using biometrics right something
you are and I'll go into more about
different types of biometric
authentication we also have tokens or
certificates those are things that we
have they're not secrets per se but
they're objects that we hold on to so
you might be familiar with you
the keys or TLS certificates or SSH
certificates or whatnot these are the
things that you have in your possession
very similar to a key to a house and
then of course there's multiples of what
I just mentioned and that's when you
start talking about multi-factor
authentication that's using one or more
from those three groups it's something
you have and know or something you are
and have etc true multi-factor
authentication is not - from one group
so if you need a password and a pin
that's not multi-factor authentication
those are two things that you know so
next is 2-step verification so this is
very very popular right now are folks
familiar with 2-step verification where
you log into your bank and then they
text you a code and you put that code
back into your bank that's 2-step
verification it's not necessarily
multi-factor although you do have access
to something that lets you receive that
code so it's kind of hybrid you have
something but there are some problems
with that thing that you have
particularly with SMS so there's this
thing called sim swapping it's very
popular right now in in the hands of bad
guys when it comes to Bitcoin or believe
it not like Instagram accounts and
getting getting access to you know
basically things that are protected with
with SMS short codes using this
two-factor verification and as always
the weakest link in this scenario is
gonna be the carrier right I happen to
work for a carrier for four years I know
many many calls many many situations
where you try to authenticate someone
you try to get their password you try to
get you know whatever it is that you
need for them to verify themselves and
they don't have it or they forgot it or
you're trying to write you know they're
trying to rush you and you're trying to
do everything you can do to resolve the
call and the first time they call you or
help them when they're standing in front
of you
and you forgot to verify who they were
you they didn't tell you the pin or you
didn't do something in the right order
well everything that has to do is 2-step
verification hinges on the fact that you
are the sole owner or person who has
access to this device this phone this
laptop that gets my messages whatever
the case may be and it's to the point
where NIST the National Institute of
Standards and Technology in the special
publication six 863 B has even said SMS
to sub verification is deprecated the
interesting part of that is they didn't
even acknowledge SMS to factor
verification until this publication so
they introduced it and deprecated it in
the same document what does that tell
you it's just really not up to snuff
compared to the other two three factors
that that we talked about now all of
that said it's still better than nothing
show hands who's heard of credential
stuffing whoa that's a lot of hands
really awesome all right well I'm not
gonna take a long time on this though so
credential stuffing is taking leaked
creds from databases and putting them
into into forms on different databases
right so take your leaked creds from
LinkedIn from 2011 put them into your
Facebook account and see if those creds
still work
that's credential stuffing but 90% of
you have already heard of that which is
awesome it was not the case five years
ago right so what is too fat two-step
verification stops it stops credential
stuffing right your random attacker who
gets your pone passwords from some dark
web or some you know stale database on
paste bin somewhere they're gonna run
into this issue where up there's an SMS
you know going out of band 90% or 99% of
accounts aren't going to be worth that
attacker then taking that and trying to
do a sim swapping attack or trying to
social engineer your rise in accounts to
get them to switch the number into yours
or what have you
right so it's still better than nothing
I'm not telling you to go home and
disable 2-step verification to then back
up to only passwords that'd be silly
right but there's obviously better
better options out there
one of those bitter options are totp and
H OTP so who there better be less hands
this time or I might just walk upstate
who here is familiar with TOTP and H OTP
all right less hands
okay so time-based one-time passwords or
H Mac based one-time passwords right OTP
is the same across so one-time passwords
are these codes that you see with apps
like Google Authenticator or duo or
authy there's these rolling codes and
it's somewhat similar to if you've ever
used an RSA token except for you don't
have a token right that's being done on
the application and the protocol that is
with the exchange of those tokens and
how the server matches up which tokens
you should have and allows you are T OTP
and H OTP so the secrets to that
exchange whenever you get the secret to
start that that handshake that's
everything if someone can get access to
the secret key of your TOTP or H OTP
initiation it's all over where do you
think that secret is hint it's the large
image on the screen right now where's
where is that image at or where's that
secret at where the QR code oh sorry the
QR code QR codes everything I can tell
you one time I was doing an application
assessment and I saw a situation where
there was a QR code that was generated
and that QR code was generated from a
Google service and that Google service
just accepted like okay this is the
message I'm one of the QR code send it
to me in the URL okay now here's a QR
code back okay and then the client then
scan the QR code in the application
everything on the surface looked okay
but what was actually happening was the
QR the secret was sent in the URL so
it's cached in a bunch of places in your
browser
not the QR code when it got back to your
browser was cached locally in your
browser so now anyone who has access to
your computer could go out and scan that
QR code and the Google service that did
it all said right in the Terms of
Service don't use this for anything
critical or secret and it was a
deprecated Google service so it was like
four strikes you're out it was it was
terrible but what I'm trying to get at
here is the QR code is everything in
this process the transfer of the secret
is everything when it comes down to TOTP
versus h OTP I'm not gonna harp on that
today ones time based ones H Mac based
you can really tell the difference if
you open up your google app or your duo
app if it's rolling every 30 seconds
it's time based if it's static until you
submit it and then you get a new one
it's H Mac based but behind the scenes
you're really just extrapolating that
one-time password that out-of-band
verification from the SMS portion which
is inherently flawed right so TOTP h OTP
infinitely better than SMS then there's
this thing called Fido which is fast
identity online the roots of Fido were
in these protocols called UAS and u2f
UAF was a universal authentication
framework u2f was a universal second
factor there's a lot of detail in here
I'm going to show you a quick flow
diagram here coming up but what you
should know is the the protocol is
typically rooted in some type of secure
Enclave as Apple would call it your
secure Enclave or a trusted platform
module or HSM or basically this special
chip that is read-only and does trusted
trusted computations and the let me skip
ahead and I'll just show you how this
works so you have an application and
you're using Fido to use as a second
factor or a secret conformation so the
client is your app could be a web app
could be a mobile app whatever the case
may be the server is whatever
business you're doing business with and
the user of course is you so you log in
to the application using your username
and password the phyto service comes
back and says hey this is what I know
how to talk this is what I can do let's
let's give you some options make sure
you have all these different things and
if so let's start this thing so you can
see here that the requirements and the
attributes are this person has to have a
TPM a place that I can do these these
cryptographic safe operations in a safe
way I offer the ability to do
fingerprint off face authentication
voice authentication basically biometric
authentication I feed the response into
the user and the user says hey this is
what I want to do and they enroll and
when that enrollment takes place some
type of secret is generated at that
first handshake and then it's sent over
from the server from that point on
there's this challenge response type
handshake that happens every time you
use the service and because you started
off with a known state you did a
cryptographic operation and then sent
back the response the server can repeat
that process over and over again and
confirm that it's you and there's a lot
more detail that goes into this process
but what you should know is there was
basically two protocols that came out of
that there's a universal two-factor
basically a way for anyone out there to
use this as a second factor
authentication and then there was also
the universal authentication framework
which is basically using this as your
identity this was you you could log into
a machine without any type of extra auth
and out of that process web auth end was
born which now is Fido - and if you're
familiar with like Windows hello or
actually even Twitter now offers web off
and standard that is basically the
evolution of the Fido protocol and the
the underpinnings are the same things
you see here in the flow chart but there
are some additional handshake
there's additional requirements or
whatnot but this is the whole idea of
Fido and you can see where we kind of
took the idea of the the okay I get a
code from some man or I put the code in
you verify it and we kind of amp that up
we took the process of not only are you
or is the server sending you something
in which you're verifying and sending
back you're using a portion of you which
is unique to you being fingerprint or
face or voice and we're doing a
cryptographic operation on that and
proving that it is the person who
originally subscribed to this method
right so Fido is really really
interesting and cool so then I briefly
touched on this before certificates
right these are things that we have you
might be familiar with certificates from
SSH or mutual TLS certificates or pivot
charts if you're from the government
type right you had the old guv
pip smart cards but basically there
isn't much verification of who you are
other than the fact that you have
possession of this thing again it's not
much different than a key if we take
that a step further there's a key to our
front door the door is expecting this
key if you put the key in everything
lines up the door opens if we take that
same thought and extrapolate that out to
certificates and TLS if you could
imagine an entity that had all the keys
to all the houses on your street and in
your city and that that entity said
you're this person here's your key
you're this person here is your key this
your this person here's your key that's
the trust that we're putting into our
certificate authorities we're trusting
that those certificate authorities are
properly vetting who people say they are
and giving out the proper keys and and
saying that yes you are going to this
person you have that trust you're good
to go
mutual TLS is is basically with
out the certificate authority this is
where you have a TLS cert and you're
presenting that to someone who's
verifying that went on this before not
going to go into into this in huge
detail but of course there's all the
biometric things touch ID Android
fingerprint sensor iris scans face
detection voice recognition hand prints
combination of you know basically
anything that you can do I just read or
heard about a new laser that someone's
using that detects your heart cadence
and they can tell by your heart
palpitations that you are who you are I
don't know but these are things that you
can't change about yourself without some
serious like plastic surgery and Mission
Impossible or something okay who
here uses a password vault keep your
hands up keep your hands up I want you
to look to your left or look to your
right and if you see one of your friends
or family who aren't using password
vaults your homework is to help
introduce password vaulting to that
person you know you're getting homework
today you're the TA I want you to check
the homework and make sure that this is
done all right
so password managers there's two types
of password managers there's online
password managers and there's offline
password managers of course it's however
cloud comfortable you are with that
there's all kinds of security and
mechanisms and and thousands of rounds
of key derivation and all kinds of fun
stuff that goes into protecting your
identity and only you can open this and
so on and so forth but the idea behind a
password manager right is that you have
a single key that unlocks all of your
other keys so it's like when you go to
the card car dealership and they have
that box on the wall and they put a key
in and they open that box and there are
all the keys to all the other cars
that's probably like an 80s reference I
think they have a machine like a vending
machine that Divis them out now yeah
I've seen them know anyway so that's the
idea behind this you
possess the key box you possess the key
in your mind that opens the key box so
of course knowing that password
knowing that initial password is still
extremely important but inside of that
key box is a bunch of other keys you
don't necessarily even need to know and
one of the really cool benefits of a
password vault or password manager is it
can do verification for you to make sure
you're putting the password into the
correct site right so when you visit a
site if you have the browser add-in
added to you know your your phone or
your browser what-have-you
it'll actually pop up and say hey this
is Facebook this is your password for
Facebook log in if someone sends you a
fish or social engineering and they send
you face but instead of the a it's the
you know Punic code version of a with a
little dot but you can't see the little
dot because it's above the fold whatever
the case is your password manager won't
offer your Facebook password for you to
log in with right so that's a huge
benefit to password managers and vaults
and the fact is I just ended my job
yesterday with my consulting company I
knew one password for all of the
hundreds of systems and client systems
and all the stuff that I logged into I
knew one password and that was to get
into my password vault yesterday when I
turned in my computer I can honestly say
I have no access to anything and it's
not because they revoke the access which
I'm sure they did but it's because I
never knew any passwords anything right
password managers are awesome and
they're even coming to the point of they
have scraped the internet and and have
confirmed what different password
requirements are for this site and that
site in this and they can help you
create the most entropy rich password
for a certain site so creating a bunch
of unique passwords for every site
you've ever visited creating really
strong passwords that are unique based
on all the crazy-ass requirements that
all these sites have and doing all of
this and being able to verify that
you're putting the password into the
proper site how many of you can say that
you can do all of that in here
no one right we just can't do that where
does not program to be able to make hard
to guess unique passwords for everything
we touch so password managers are
absolutely crucial
now there's also this thing about
grandma's passbook that has you know
it's a yellow manila or a yellow sheet
of paper and has all of the passwords
written on that
don't knock grandma's passbook unless
someone's breaking in to get into
Grandma's house it's gonna take that and
go to her you know Medicaid and try to
you know or Social Security and try to
do stuff that's actually a lot better
I'd rather see someone create a strong
unique password or at least somewhat
unique by writing it down and putting it
somewhere that's secure then remembering
all the crazy passwords right cuz if
grandma has to remember all her
passwords you know that's gonna be
password one two three it is there's no
doubt about it in my mind that's gonna
be the password and then when she can't
get into our site she's gonna call you
and say hey Kevin I'm trying password
one two three and it's not working and
then you're gonna have to remember oh
its capital P and an exclamation point
on the end grandma its password one two
three exclamation right so don't knock
the password books every few months this
thing starts up on Twitter like oh my
gosh have you seen this book they sell
at Barnes and Nobles it's called the
password book can you believe how
ignorant they are in reality it's
probably not that bad you still have to
use your brain to come up with different
combination it's not it's not as good as
a password vault but it's not terrible
as long as you can protect that and put
it somewhere safe all right so we're 20
plus minutes in and I've hit you with a
lot of authentication protocols and
standards and mechanisms and I hope what
you've taken out of that is things are
changing quickly right things are
already keep up with attackers are doing
new things
we're combative them we're changing
things up physical keys biometric codes
they can't be remembered or verbally
transmitted to someone or passed down to
a loved one right so we have these
things where at least the pass were like
oh you know you know unfortunately
so-and-so passed but we know that he
always used smokey
877 for his passwords so at least we
know how to get into the mortgage so
that we can make this payment until the
death certificate comes and we can get
absolved from that or whatever the case
is right well do you think that works
when the deceased person's finger isn't
around anymore to open their phone or
they have a voice as their password when
they call the Social Security office
quick story the big government offices
like Social Security they're using
what's called passive biometric software
to confirm if you're out if the person
who originally called is still the same
person who's calling today so the days
of you calling and collecting your
significant others pension for life or
benefits for life and you call and you
just pretend to be them and you hope
that someone doesn't pick up that's over
they have enough data saved up an old
calls that they can create an identity
that they know is you or is enough like
you
and once you variant out of that model
they know hey something's not quite
right send someone to their house or ask
them for additional identification or
something that's called passive
biometric data it's a real thing it's
being used to combat fraud today and it
can't be faked maybe a twin brother or
sister or maybe you know if you get
really lucky you might be able to but in
the vast majority of the cases it's
rock-solid right and again the days of
remembering passwords are over I'm not
remembering passwords anymore one
password I don't use that password
anywhere other to unlock the box of keys
on the wall so what do we do like what
are we doing today to recover if we lose
our passwords so currently this is the
flow that happens if you forget your
password you choose a forgot password
option you enter the answers to your
secret question right which the secret
questions aren't usually that great when
I was was in
there was this idea of out-of-pocket
questions and what that means are if I
get your wallet how many security
questions can I answer from just having
your wallet can I google your school's
mascot can I look on Facebook and get
your first car model etc etc right you
have to have things that are out of
pocket out of so that's where the whole
favorite thing came from what's your
favorite restaurant what's your favorite
book these are things that you can't
really until you go to Facebook quiz and
you pull out the quiz that's right but I
digress out of pocket are the secret
questions and hopefully everyone's using
so you enter that you get a link in the
email you create a new password and
you're in it's pretty frictionless this
is actually not a bad state you can swap
the two things you could get the link in
the email and then answer your secret
questions it's probably a little bit
better but overall that's really how
things are done today this is this is
the standard so some things that are
better than the standard right
out-of-band SMS so although again SMS
isn't the best if you can text someone
the number that you have and have them
verify it's better than everything else
I just said right SSH key verification
this is pretty cool does anyone ever
lost your password have done the forgot
password for github one person I am with
you I lost access to my github for six
months that's a different story
anyway SSH key verification so github
actually reached out to me like hey all
else failed you can't you can't give me
the key you can't give me the password
you give me the recovery codes we can't
verify your DNA whatever the case is
send us a challenge with SSH your public
and you know we'll do a handshake and if
you have the private key there's pretty
good chance that you're you right so
that's kind of neat that's that's it
that's a different thing
some do snail mail right this has been
happening for a while right you just
like wait for a password reset code to
come in the mail and hope that someone
doesn't steal it out of the mail right
I'm not saying it's great but it's not
Wurst and I don't know there's others
can grab a coffee or a monster after
this and we can chat about other
mechanisms that you think I should
should be including in this right but
regardless forgot password' mechanisms
are pretty straightforward but what
happens when we can't go through that
process there's a locked code there's a
locked phone we don't have access to
this well we have some deceased recovery
processes as well so Gmail actually has
this thing called the nickname the
Deadman switch which comes from trains
okay I was gonna say military from from
you know holding in the the detonator
and when they would die they would
release it and okay regardless the idea
is that you have to actively respond to
something and if you don't actively
respond to something something else
happens in Gmail has this this this
method where if you don't actively
confirm that you're alive and you have
access you can basically bequeath your
access to somebody else Facebook has a
couple interesting things as well they
have these legacy contacts will they'll
reach they'll allow certain contacts to
do a limited set of actions on your
behalf including the ability to set up
memorials on your account and tributes
which is something a little bit newer
right but you know I don't know about
you but Facebook and Gmail are pretty
significant parts of my digital life
right now and the fact that these at
least these two have gotten to the point
where they're trying to plan ahead of
this process which is pretty you know
it's it's it's not a fun process to go
through I think we've all been had at
least grandparent aunt uncle friends
someone who's passed away you're trying
to pick the pieces back up and put
things together and trying to find all
of these odds and ends out on top of
dealing with this kind of stuff it's
it's it's really difficult
password managers have also of course
thought of this process and they've of
course named it all emergency which
isn't confusing at all
LastPass as emergency access - lien has
emergency and one password has emergency
kit and they all do things a little bit
different my favorites LastPass
emergency access and basically you go in
it's actually pretty similar to - Lane
you go in and you designate basically
successors and you say I trust this
person I know and whatnot and LastPass
actually has this this neat thing where
one single person can't take over
everything you actually have to have you
can set it so multiple people are
basically entering the whole two keys to
the missile sort of thing multiple
people have to get together which could
be an issue if those people aren't
talking or something happens there's a
rift of something but you know basically
these password managers have come up
with ways of allowing you to designate
emergency contacts one thing to note
this is kind of the nuclear option if
something happens and the emergency
access is invoked you lose access to
your password vault you key the owner
are hopefully not around anymore
hopefully not I don't whatever the case
is you're not around anymore your
LastPass access is gone because people
have invoked the nuclear option one
password doesn't quite have the cards in
place yet they have this thing called
emergency kit which is a piece of paper
that has a recovery code printed on it
and you're supposed to put that
somewhere safe yeah and then key pass
doesn't have anything it's just like an
offline password vault hopefully you
know someone who can recover that and
get in and all that fun stuff so outside
of the the leading edge of the providers
think about everything else we do right
telecom email banks financials utilities
postal shipping all of those are pretty
much the same as they were two decades
ago before the advent of the internet
you have to get a certificate of death
most of them we
we'll change the ownership like as far
as telecoms and in banks and financials
obviously that a lot of this comes with
with estate planning but we've changed
the way we interact with these companies
where we're interacting with them
digitally so if you have to wait for a
certificate of death or you have to go
and prove that you are the successor to
an estate just know you can't access
these things in the same way that the
person who was managing these were
before meaning they don't have any
successor attributes or emergency access
plans or ways around to help
short-circuit that so if you don't know
the password you can get access to their
password vault you don't have their
fingerprints you're not getting into
these things at least digitally until
you can provide a certificate of death
and even then it usually has to be
transferred into your name credit checks
have to be done you have to wait for
billing cycles and and and all that
stuff so again just try to prep you
maybe some things to think about when
you go home might be some some
conversations you want to have and and
plan for these things so now what
Kevin's given us a bunch of problems a
bunch of what-ifs some have answers some
domme he talked to us for 20 minutes
about how authentication systems work
well I do want to give you some
solutions so there's a couple high tech
solutions there's a couple low tech
solutions and maybe a couple novel ones
thrown in there so high tech options if
you're really savvy maybe you can come
up with a distributed recovery system
where portions of your vault are backed
up to AWS and this one's to Azure and
you give you know pieces you the sky's
the limit you can come up with some
really creative things the cool thing
about technology is there's ways that
you can distribute things like you never
had before right we never had the option
to do that before there's also this idea
of passwords sharding right shard means
to break up so you like give pieces of
your password or a key to certain people
and hope they don't all come together
it's like the I'm not a Marvel guy but
like the Infinity stones you hope
all come to the same place I think
that's is that good all right that's
good all right and you could use like
multi layer encryption schemes same kind
of idea right you encrypt something and
then you put an envelope around that
with a different key I don't know what
that cracking is envelope around that
with a different key and envelope around
that with an encrypting a different key
right you can just keep adding more and
more abstraction layers around it to
where hopefully you can shoestring
something together those are high-tech
options some low-tech options like lock
boxes right just go to the bank I showed
you that that QR code earlier and the QR
code is your secret for your totp e and
h OTP accounts well you know what I do
honest to goodness Tori I hope no one
robs me when I go home I print those
damn things off when I get in a QR code
I print that QR code out and I put it in
my safe you know what that allows me to
do when I get my new phone I just go to
all those QR codes I just scan each of
the QR codes and I add them right back
in I don't have to reset anything I
don't have to hope that I remember this
remember that I can just back them all
up and if something happens I can tell
my wife hey if you need the codes the
codes are in the safe just scan your
phone and now you have access to my
second factor you can do the same thing
with Fido keys you bikies but a lot of
sites don't have the ability to add
multiple keys yet it's increasing but
just know if you don't keep that key in
a safe place
a lot of sites don't have multiple key
adoption safe deposit boxes of course
just truck people you trust with
whatever the heck you trust them with
passwords or you know whatnot
you could use some like technology that
isn't easy to actually obtain anymore
like I don't know you know put your will
or put your not your will put something
sensitive on this medium and include
that medium in the box with it and if
someone finds it they're like I don't
even know how this thing works and you
give instructions in your estate
planning on how they get this thing that
sounds really convoluted I'm not gonna
recommend that but it's something it's a
low-tech option or high-tech I'm not
sure or just bury the damn thing in the
ground somewhere and leave where your
passwords are um all of that said there
is the fact that all of the technology
that we've talked about has progressed
fundamentally just in the last decade
right so you're doing all this estate
planning and you're planning your
password sharding you're doing all this
stuff whose just say that that mechanism
is even going to be there tomorrow or
the next day or the next week right or
that you didn't get a new phone and you
had it throw out your old H OTP code and
do a new you know so unfortunately the
glass blow point here it's just gonna
get more complicated these are ideas
that you should have on the top of your
mind I don't have a silver bullet that's
gonna solve all of your problems but I
can't tell you how things work from a
technical perspective if you come to me
Kevin I don't get this I have this code
and I have this key I can break down the
nuts and bolts on how that work and if
then you can take that and replicate a
way that you can pass that along to
friends or family or come up with an
idea what you would do in a break the
glass situation albeit and I'm happy to
offer my time to do that right but you
got to start thinking about this stuff
because if you're not here tomorrow your
significant others not here tomorrow and
you got to get into your bank account
you got to do this this stuff is really
really you know imperative and you know
an ounce of prevention really is worth a
pound of cure if you've ever had to deal
with these cleanup situations where
you're trying to put the pieces back
together and there's just sitting on on
hold and dealing with with social
services and getting certificates and
proving you are who you are it's really
really complicated so if you can cut
even a portion of this off at the pass
it's certainly well worth your time and
our digital lives are just increasingly
increasingly more dependent on these
things so talk with your friends or
family talk to a lawyer not a lawyer
layer
talk to a lawyer and start your plans
for bequeathing I mean if you run your
digital lives the way I know I run my
digital life it's extremely important to
at least broach that subject get some of
your basis is covered and know what
you're gonna do next
one final plug before Q&A my buddy and
co-worker John Callahan he's gonna be
talking about crypto miners versus
machine learning in the next track next
door if you don't know what machine
learning is you think it's some blackbox
magic some vendors trying to shut sell
you something please go to his talk he's
gonna be talking about crypto miners
because it's sexy and people are you
know in Basel by what is a crypto minor
but in reality he's gonna break out what
machine learning is into words and and
statements and nuance that I personally
have never seen anyone do it's math it's
basic math and he does a really good job
of explaining it and he does it in a
really cool way where he can find these
crypto miners that are going up against
these AWS instances and he pulls that
data out of the flow log traffic so it's
really cool anyway we'd open up for
questions if you don't want to ask me
here hit me up I'm at keV Cody on
Twitter
I'm Kevin Cody on LinkedIn I'm Kevin
Cody on every other social platform
I'm not keV Cody underscore on Instagram
that's a rapper he wants keV Cody and I
get a lot of his I actually I get
contracts for it anyway question
I am NOT a lawyer no so the question is
what's the legality of trying to use
forensic software to recover data from
the deceased I would say that legality
really depends on your your right to
interact with the deceased assets right
so if you are the mailman you're
probably not allowed to do that right
now are they gonna come after you no but
they're a state might so I that was a
really roundabout as a politician's
answer but I hope that answered your
question
any other questions yes sir so I gave
you two four instances the the gmail one
and the Facebook one I'm sorry his
question was what about other services
there are there are some they most
services will at least come out and tell
you if you have a deceased family member
and you believe you have the rights to
interact with the appropriate
documentation we will deactivate their
account that's pretty much the extent of
it there are very few service providers
that you let you do other things as far
as like getting access to their accounts
and honestly if some if a service
provider is gonna reset your data or
give someone post humorous no human
access post there you go post mortem
access to your data it's a little
concerning and most of the big guys
won't they'll just they'll give a
modified ability to do some actions
others will just delete the account I
did look up whatsapp just cuz I was
interested whatsapp tells you if you
have a deceased friend or family member
open their phone select the Settings
button and click the delete account
button I swear that's what their
instructions are now that's an IM or SMS
type app so it's a little different than
like a social media but that's their
instructions if you have a deceased
member that's
so the question is getting getting
access to their digital logs and records
from from the estate so so a lot of
companies will give you the especially
with like the the different legislation
will allow you to request your digital
records chat logs and all that different
stuff that's a good question I don't
think they would release that outside of
first party I think you can delete the
account and you can remove most with it
with the death certificate I don't think
like the it's not freedom of information
but the ability to get your data back as
a gdpr whatever it is that doesn't apply
to estates I don't believe I haven't
seen anything resembling that any other
questions thanks for coming listen to me
about death I'm sorry but we got to talk
about it right
[Applause]