all righty thanks everybody for coming
to our 11 o'clock talk
so besides Pittsburgh just wants to take
a moment to recognize our premier
sponsor Terrace which and then our
diamond sponsors security risk advisors
and defy security thank you so much to
all those organizations for helping to
make besides Pittsburgh happen this year
so I'm pleased to introduce our next
speaker will doorman who will be
presenting on a topic called death by
thumbdrive file system buzzing with cert
BFF so a little bit about will wills
been a software vulnerability analyst
with the cert Coordination Center since
2004 as focus areas include web browser
technologies ActiveX mobile applications
and fuzzing Will's discovered thousands
of vulnerabilities using a variety of
tools and techniques so without further
ado please welcome well thank you and
get guys hear me okay all right good so
the legal stuff required by our company
a little bit of background information
about how I ended up getting here if
anybody has ever heard of a filing
system called FreeNAS it's actually
pretty slick you know I got a server in
our server server room it's got 40 hard
drives on it if you ever want an
operating system to intelligently use a
large amount of hard drives FreeNAS is
great ZFS is great basically FreeNAS
gets you that so a little background
we've got a
freenas server does anybody here ever
heard of a program called Rufus yeah so
right it's pretty popular and I think
it's quite useful back in the day when
you wanted to install an operating
system on your system you know you burn
it to an optical disk and you would put
it in your optical media drive and you
know go from there the problem is modern
computers don't have optical disks so
what Rufus is really slick at is you can
just have an iso file that you
downloaded and you can burn it to a
thumb drive so assuming you have a
computer you can boot from a thunder
thumb drive or USB Drive
it'll allow you to do that so at some
point of time I needed to do like a
clean install of FreeNAS so I had my
free knives ISO and I have my virtual
machine that has Rufus in it
paranoid folks such as myself always do
everything within a virtual machine
because we don't trust anything so I'm
basically you know writing the ISO to
the to the USB drive wait that's not
right
and my initial thought was well I I
guess maybe there's a hardware problem
with my thumb drive so I go back and I
you know rewrite the thing and I now
have a thumb drive which will crash
Windows 7 every time reproducible and
this is not me trying to do anything
clever I'm not trying to like mangle
anything I'm not trying to be like super
like hey I'm gonna trick windows into
crashing no I have FreeNAS I want it to
boot off of a thumb drive and we end up
with this so I'm gonna I'm gonna give
you give you guys a little little secret
a secret to my success if you consider
me successful vulnerability discovery is
often considered to be like this magic
sort of skillset that like only like
crazy people that can do assembly in
their head and everything like that
now there's three steps how to discover
vulnerabilities step one use systems
think we got everybody covered here step
number two notice anomalies so when I
had my Windows System blue screen I
thought huh that's not right it
shouldn't do that
I just wrote bits to a USB disk and then
the final step is just investigate this
and I will tell you I think that's the
one thing that sets aside people that
are vulnerability researchers or
security researchers from people that
are using the systems as tools is that
when something odd happens I have this
part of my brain that makes me wonder
why did this happen
this is basically it and I'll say you
know like I'll get into a little bit of
some of the fuzzing work that I've been
doing but a lot of the cases a lot of
the vulnerabilities that we've been able
to discover is really just looking at
systems and investigating things that
don't behave as you expect them to be so
just a little bit of background about
the certain BFF
it is a mutational fuzzer and the
concept of a mutational fuzzer is
basically you start out with a known
good or known bad but basically you
start out with a file let's say we have
a word document and it goes into our
mutation fuzzer and it shakes it up a
little bit and you've got something that
looks pretty close to a word document
and then you get that right that's your
end goal of fuzzing is you're looking
for program crashes does anybody here
have a BFF now yeah
sorry it is not best friends forever
it's the basic fuzzing framework and it
was about ten years or so ago there were
some tools that were out there like the
the peach fuzz engrain work and you
needed to have a lot of information
about like the type of file that your
fuzzing and the structure of it and you
would have to write something that tells
you how to Mike how am I going to fuzz
this my goal was to write something
that's easy to use it's maybe like 10
years ago or so at this point eight and
started out as like a very simple like
perl wrapper around a utility called zuf
which just kind of mangoes things runs a
program and looks for signals it's since
actually gotten a lot better
bigger works on multiple platforms but
the general idea of how it works is
basically you start out with what we
call a seed file in most cases it's a
like a known good file so if I'm fuzzing
a PDF reader
I want a pile of PDF documents and what
the fuzzer will do is it will mangle it
in that you know sometimes we call it
like bit flipping and stuff like that
but it really is very it's naive but
it's basically you take a bite take take
some subset of bytes in a file flip them
to some other random byte values and
just see what happens
you launch the target application and
you look for crashes and out of anytime
something crashes it's got some tools
that come with it that kind of give you
an idea of exploitability
and you can get a little bit more
information about what the crash is all
about and you repeat it that's it it's
it is it is not rocket science in any
way but it is really vulnerable 'ti
discovery through brute force one of the
you know talking about servers in our
server room like one of the things that
we have are like systems that are set
aside that just have a lot of CPU cores
and I will set up a fuzzing campaign on
as many VMs as I have cores and RAM
available and then you just come back
later you know I might come back if a
target is really fruitful I might see
something that comes up like within
minutes I've seen stuff where it's like
within the first 10 or so iterations of
a fuzzing campaign and I've seen
exploitable vulnerabilities and now
that's a sign of like a really poorly
written target app in some cases it it's
a lot more robust so you can kind of get
a sort of a smell as to the the quality
of the software that you're working just
based on how robust it is to file
fuzzing and the idea with BFF is you
know like I described before it's it's
really just taking byte values and
changing them to other values but it's
actually it's got some feedback loops
where it will look for techniques that
cause crashes and it'll kind of steer
itself in ways to like know how much do
I mangle a file before I get something
that's interesting so without getting
too far into the technical stuff and
hopefully this isn't gonna be too much
of an eye test but this is an example
output of our tool running on Linux it's
fuzzing a library called Oracle outside
in Oracle outside-in is a great target
because it's the Swiss Army knife of
something that decodes just about
anything it has five hundred over five
hundred different decoders in it it can
basically give you like a thumbnail
rendering of like a document a PDF a
text file whatever you want it's used in
a lot of products it's used in forensic
software it's used by a little product
called Microsoft Exchange it's it's it's
it's kind of an important sort of tool
but there's actually a tool that comes
with BFF called drill results so if I
just run this tool slash drill results
script it'll give me a screen like this
and it'll rank the crashes and if I ever
see something that's like ranked as like
a ten or a five that's like this is
really cool so I look here I can see
I've got a crash that has an
exploitability rank of ten and I can
look right it right below it and I can
see I've got a return access violation
accessing some 64 bit pattern but it
also tells me that bike pattern exists
in the file that I find interesting
we're feeling lucky what if I go in my
hex editor and I like look for that bite
pattern and I change it to something
like abcdefgh
week and this is just a gue e debugger
that comes with with our BFF virtual
machine here but I can see we've
actually got a return to a b c d e f g h
and i can see that value in the stack so
it's like here's a great example of a
home run fuzzing output I've just
started a fuzzing campaign
I've waited enough time and then I come
back and then basically this stuff
trickles up to the top so that's the the
basic gist of fuzzing
so we've released b FF years ago and and
i'd like to think that you know at the
time that we released it there wasn't
really a good easy-to-use fuzzer that
you could just point at something and
not have to know like what's the
structure of a PDF or anything like that
and so we ended up releasing the source
code for b FF onto github and due to the
magic of open source software we got a
pull request which is cool because it's
like here's a little toy project of mine
that like I wrote years ago
not only are people using it but some
guys saw it and said you know what I
would like it if you added two features
one I would like for the ability to copy
a file to a fixed location in - I would
like to also this came in the same pull
request I would like to be able to run a
program for each iteration so a little
bit of information about like why is it
important to copy - why would anybody
have the need to copy it to a fixed
location certain targets that you fuzz
it might only open a file from a fixed
location right and so this is an example
from a fuzzing campaign of like where
the temporary file you know for every
iteration it does it mangles the the
file a bit it puts it in a directory and
then it cleans it up when it's done now
if I'm ever working with something that
opens a file from a fixed location
that's not going to help
so with this pull request here there's a
new configuration option called cup copy
fuzz - and I can basically say ok for
every iteration that the fuzzer does I
will copy it to this specific location
so if I modify my BFF mo file I can now
save so for every iteration I will have
a copy of my mangled file in a fixed
location so that's that's kind of neat
that'll get me I've fussed some targets
that that did actually open files from a
fixed location and this will help solve
that problem the other part this post
process first option is it's a new
feature that allows you for every time
after you've mangled a file you can run
an arbitrary program so in this
particular case it's just user local bin
post process but the output of that is
every time a file gets mangled BFF will
run whatever I tell it to run it could
be a binary it could be a shell script
it could be a bass grip depending on
what platform on I'm on so the magic of
these two options is when you put them
together
so with those options together I can run
a shell script to do whatever I want
with that file that I just mutated so
I'm basically relying on BFF to take
care of the file manipulation and and
basically you know it's relatively
straightforward but it's the whatever
you want part that is interesting and
that's what got us to this particular
state of doing file system fuzzy I
fought for a bit here I was like you
know so if I go back to me trying to
create a Rufus bootable thumb drive I
thought well okay here's the standard
FreeNAS 11.2 iso it crashes Windows
seven part of your brain that like
wonders is well what if what if I
intentionally tried to get Windows to
crash can I do that
and so that's where I got into fuzzing
file systems with BFF
normally with BFF you're just gonna fuzz
a particular target application say
Microsoft Word or something like that
what I started to think about is now
with these two enhancements with this
pull request I can do whatever I want I
can I can create a script called test
disk so for example if I'm on like the
Linux platform and you don't have to
really like look at the specific details
here but this is like a copy of what I
was doing on the Linux platform here and
one of the things that I noticed is like
sometimes I'm working with virtual
machines here sometimes when you boot a
machine a Linux machine I noticed that
like it's root disk sometimes it's SDA
sometimes it was s DB depending on how
the planets are in alignment and stuff
like that so in my test this script here
I just do a simple verification of like
which one is my root disk so I know
which one is my USB disk and here's
where the actual like filesystem fuzzing
comes into play so I've basically I have
a disk image that I'm starting with you
know you can just use DD to create a
disk image it could be various file
systems what I'm doing is I'm now taking
this mangled
I'll system binary and I'm dding it to
my virtual disk and then block size 10
Meg's just to make it like not super
slow when you DD bits to a virtual disk
Linux doesn't know necessarily if
anything has changed about that this so
if I'm fuzzing a filesystem and I
flipped with some bits in the partition
table it's now going to present itself
differently to the computer so in my
shell script here I just run a command
called part probe which basically says
hey Linux go read the partition table of
this particular disk and then I'll mount
it and then I'll run the find command
which basically is just you know in some
cases just mounting a filesystem might
cause something to be bad but what I
want to do here is incrementally do
things that trigger a little bit more of
what is an operating system doing with
the filesystem
so the first thing I do is I mount it
the next thing I do is run the find
command and all that's doing is that's
walking like the filesystem table so
it's kind of saying you know what files
are on the system and then the last
thing I do is I try creating a tarball
of it so not only is it you know you've
got three different stages here you've
got the mounting of a filesystem you've
got the walking of the filesystem tree
and then you also have the reading of
the bits that are supposedly in these
files on the file system so by doing all
of these together and then finally at
the end I can unmount it just you know
so you have a whole sequence of here
I've got a malformed filesystem and I've
got one script that is doing like the
things that would happen like if you
like plug a thumb drive in your computer
so basically you run BFF and eventually
you might end up with something like
that in a lot of Linux systems you want
to actually see that because like it
kind of hides that stuff visually from
you at the point that your kernel panics
you're not necessarily in a video mode
where it's going to like give you this
information so I had to do a little
tweaking to just get you to see it but
you know eventually you got a fuzz or
you eventually you've got like a kernel
panic there windows I do something very
similar any virtual machine I have
that's windows like I like to be able to
do stuff from the command prompt and
like I want my new utility so cygwin it
is what it is but like if you really
need like you knew like utilities on a
Windows system it's been how I achieve
that but we basically do the same thing
we're doing DD on Windows I'm running a
command called disk part now think about
the disk part command is it doesn't
accept command-line parameters that tell
you what you want it to do so if you
were to look at that file called rescan
text it just has the word rescan in it
so think it's odd that you can give it a
file parameter but you can't just tell
it what you want it to do I open
Explorer
I run the find command I kill Explorer I
think at this particular time I wasn't
necessarily doing the tarring and
everything like that but it's a similar
sort of thing where it's like you have a
mangled file system and now you open it
with Windows Explorer and then
eventually you get that so cool how
about Mac OS some of us use Mac's we do
a similar thing where I'm checking for
the root disk max it's really just a
different syntax for different operating
systems but here I've got something
called disk II till I do some unmount I
DD force I think I have a maybe a typo
in there that should be a mount mount or
something like that but basically you do
a sequence of commands you have a
mangled filesystem and then eventually
you get your prize the end here is like
you know let's be able to potentially
crash all these different operating
systems
now what do we do if we want you know so
like when your computer crashes what do
you do
reboot it and you move on with your day
as if nothing happened and you know hope
that it doesn't happen again
curious folks might wonder well what did
I do to get there so I can either don't
ever do that again or perhaps maybe I
want to look at the crash to figure out
is there anything I can do interesting
with this so let's start with our friend
Linux I you know like I had a little bit
of trouble I'm not really great with
computers I'm gonna admit that and I'll
say that Linux Linux confuses me
sometime
so I basically have a Linux system and
like the Linux operating system crashed
and I was like well how do I attach a
debugger to like the curtain the kernel
right like if the kernel crashes that's
the core of your operating system how do
I go and analyze that and I found an
interesting quote here it's a little bit
wordy here but this is basically I
happen to believe that not having a
kernel debugger forces people to think
about their problem on a different level
than with the debugger I think that
without a debugger you don't get into
that mindset where you know how it
behaves and then you fix it from there
so if you don't have a debugger you you
get to understand things on a different
level but just you know that's cool
that's a really interesting way to think
about stuff it's kind of a justification
for like why don't we have a kernel
debugger and then he writes you know
because I'm a bastard and proud of it
who would write such a thing oh my gosh
yeah so cool
and this was in a thread where somebody
is saying you know oh yeah you know I
really want a curve the bugger and it's
like I'm not a coder I can't write
anything in C you know I have to Google
how to do a hello world however I'm
interested in investigating a crash
mm-hmm maybe that didn't fit into
lionesses idea of well the bugger is a
crutch that nobody should ever use and
you know people get really late
see when they have these crutches
there's a link for it if you guys want
to anyway I think these slides will be
available at some point well it turns
out you can you can do crash debugging
if you have like a serial port II it's
slow and unreliable in like I I didn't
have a lot of fun with it right but what
you can do is sorry that print is so
small but basically you set properties
for you set your baud rate for your
serial port you know there we go we're
gonna really transfer data very quickly
and then eventually I get this crash and
I can see a back trace here what's kind
of interesting in this particular case
here is I've got the instruction pointer
somewhere where it shouldn't be hmm
these are these are like the sniff test
of like something something's probably
pretty cool here if your instruction
pointers ever somewhere where it
shouldn't be you know the program will
crash or if it's the Linux kernel the
whole Linux operating system will crash
this is the sniff test that like lets
you know that you're on the right track
to something interesting
it shouldn't it should never happen well
after a little bit of digging you know
so like I was doing the serial port
stuff and it's a pain like I hate it you
have to have two virtual machines and
then the two machines can talk to each
other over the serial port it's virtual
serial port but it's still it's not very
fun I ended up finding a package called
Linux crash dump the serious stuff is
too much work and so if you just use
your favorite search engine you can
search for something called Linux crash
dump and the way that this works is kind
of magic right well I use the term magic
but it's kind of cool the point that
something happens in your kernel where
the kernel crashes the operating system
cannot do anything else safely so that
blue screen that you see on windows or
that panic screen that you see on linux
like that's actually done in
self-defense because it knows if i were
to continue going if i do anything else
at this point in time I might trash your
data
and it's basically I'm gonna stop right
here and I'm not gonna allow it to
continue the cool thing about the Linux
crash dump package is it is an
additional kernel that is loaded into
your memory so assuming you have enough
memory what this will do is at the point
that your kernel crashes it jettisons
the old original kernel and it launches
the new kernel it's already in memory so
it doesn't have to read discs it doesn't
have to do anything that requires
drivers or anything so basically at the
point that your kernel crashes it now
starts a new kernel and now that new
kernel can do pretty much whatever it
wants I was working on Ubuntu 1804 one
of the problems I notice is that it just
doesn't work by default and it's got me
wondering it's like don't people look at
kernel crashes am I really like in some
area that like is untouched before well
it turns out like you can go ahead and
edit your grub file and like by default
so I'm installing the clinics crash dump
package that comes with the abun to
package manager just doesn't work you
have to manually go ahead and say ok I
want to set aside more memory for this
separate kernel and then it'll work so
got that the other cool thing about the
Linux crash dump package is you can
modify this file and you can tell it to
like put its files on like an NFS server
and so basically I just edit this this
file and I just basically say ok well
I'm gonna put the panic file on this NFS
server but I also want the file system
that caused that panic so I can
associate it right so I just modify this
file and I do a DD and now I have a disk
image so here's like a little silly
animation of like what happens when
you're doing the fuzzing on the left
side I've got some number of virtual
machines that's only limited by the
computer resources I have and it's
placing files in an NFS share but what
I've got is a script that's periodically
looking for duplicates so this is kind
of cool because I can start my fuzzing I
can come back later and I have a pile of
what is
to be unique rashes I just come back
later it's great if you can do that if
you can set it up in a way that things
are automated and you can come back
that's pretty cool on Windows I actually
used the utility which is also very cool
called virtual Cady it works both with
VirtualBox and VMware and basically when
you modify your Windows system to load
this driver as helper driver it will go
ahead and it will spawn windbag and I
can now for a running Windows system
I've got a debugger attached to it so
the moment that something bad happens I
will see it and I can run bang
exploitable I can do whatever I want in
this virtual machine there's yeah and
the virtual machine is doing the fuzzing
and I can see well it's kind of an eye
test here but I can see it's complaining
about exFAT it says invalid boot sector
checksum check sums are the enemies of
fuzzing because flip a bit and your
checksum is no longer valid so I might
not have really actually exercised exFAT
too much but why stop at one you know
like the system I was running it on had
like a number core so just do one for
each one of them and then and eventually
I can now in my debugger I can load this
Microsoft bugger tool that tells me
about exploitability
and I can see I've now got a crash here
and it says it's exploitable it's a
right access violation in kernel memory
the kernel can do whatever it wants if I
have ever got a right access violation
in kernel memory its potential that that
might be something that could be
leveraged to do something interesting
let's go to our friend Mac OS well it
turns out Mac OS has some guidance on
how to set it up for kernel debugging
which is relatively straightforward you
basically install the Mac OS kernel
debug kit that gives you a debug version
of the Mac OS kernel and it also has
like some symbol files and some other
things like that and you basically you
can do this thing to update the NVRAM
and essentially in your virtual machine
everything here is through virtual
machines you know you can't I really
wouldn't want to fuzz things on an
actual live system but you boot the
virtual machine and it basically says
hey I want to use this kernel debugger
the neat thing about the
kernel debugging in Mac OS is I can
connect to it with like TCP so I just
give it an IP address and like I can now
interactively so when it crashes
encountered on the Mac OS I can run our
friend ll DB our debugger I tell it KDP
remote and then give it an IP address so
at this point in time it now connects to
that particular system and I can do a
back trace and I could see information
about my crash I could see right here
that I've got panic trap to debugger so
I've actually encountered a kernel panic
in like the traditional sense in that
like I've see a call to this panic trap
to debugger
I could see the source code that caused
the panic I could see NTFS collate in
NTFS version 94 line 102 then at the
very end like it actually doesn't tell
me where that code lives because when
you install the Mac OS debugging kit you
don't actually get the symbols for all
of the drivers because it would be an
enormous download so they give you the
prime ones but I'll tell you that frame
lives in the NTFS kernel module but you
can kind of tell because of the the
frame above it where it says it's in you
know it basically is giving you the
panic string that's not the actual code
there but it's just telling you hey I've
got a panic Wow
I was thinking for a little bit wait
panic why would there be a panic this is
the code this is NTFS version 95 94 and
I can see a line here where if this data
length is less than the size of the file
name attribute I call the function
called panic this is not a surprise to
anybody at Apple Bay nobody has thought
well okay I did something wrong and I
now have a crash they had basically said
in the code that we have running in
kernel and I'm doing a check and if this
check fails I'm gonna panic the whole
sister
in the NTFS code now the reason that
somebody would panic I'd mentioned
before is you panic so that you don't
cause further corruption in a system
yeah you can see the panic here when
something happens in the kernel space
you don't want to trash your files it
could be an access violation in the
kernel it could be an explicit call to
the panic but the thing that I was
thinking is this is an NTFS code your
Mac OS will never be running off of NTFS
so why is it that if it ever encounters
a corrupt NTFS filesystem it causes a
panic so I kind of shrugged about that I
was like well maybe just maybe don't
panic
I mean it's like I told Apple that I
think they're there they're going to be
fixing it I don't know if they're
removing the panic from it or just
fixing the bug I call it a bug because
like you know you're using a computer
system the operating system should never
crash this isn't the Windows 95 days
where you look at it funny and the whole
thing blue screens because it's all in
the same same memory space and
everything so I started to think about
attack vectors there's a YouTube video
if if you probably use their search
engine to find the death by thumb drive
you'll find this and I basically go
through and I demonstrate plugging it
into an a Window System a Linux system a
Mac system it's all the exact same thumb
drive which if anybody is feeling lucky
if they think they have a computer
system that's not gonna autumn out file
systems I will happily lend this to you
for a couple seconds while I watch to
see what happens but this is the very
thumb drive that happened here but
basically your three major operating
systems and I think I threw in a free
BSD just for the hell of it and they all
crash almost all of them were in NTFS I
think with Linux it ended up being like
Reiser FS and JFS one of the things that
you'll know that like with like a nun
bun to system you get a lot of stuff by
default if I look at the file systems
that a bunch of supports modify
it's got archaic stuff right then riser
fest it's not under development you know
the guy murdered his wife or something
you know
don't don't don't do that but it's still
there like when you get your bunty
system it has that code there and it's
in kernel and waiting for whatever now I
started to wonder okay well so if you
have physical access to a computer you
kind of win already right like we wrote
a vulnerability note on it like years
ago that basically said if you have
physical access to a system that might
violate some sort of protections that
you have in place but I wanted to dig a
little bit deeper what can you do
without having physical access because
you know if I'm touching your computer
and I can cause it to crash all right
that's cool but I could also just knock
it off the counter and like yeah you're
just causing vandalism so I started
thinking about max well then it turns
out all my disk images were dot DD files
and like max don't do anything with dot
DD files but if I rename that to dot dmg
it just handles it in the same way as
like it were a disk image so that's kind
of cool so if I'm the attacker I'll
rename my disk image to dmg one of the
things I noticed is that Safari I think
chrome even does this I hate that they
do this you have to turn this off please
if you're using a web browser that auto
download stuff turn that feature off
Apple decided at some point they're like
you know what I'm going to open safe
files after downloading this is a sorry
that this checkbox in there is a little
bit different because at some point in
time safari did actually open dmg files
automatically so if you're downloading a
disk image it would mount that for you
automatically and stuff happens luckily
they've changed that behavior but they
still download the file in the first
place so all the user needs to do is I'm
visiting the website all of a sudden I
have a dmg in my downloads and what
happens if I double click on it anybody
anybody want to guess yeah so we just
crashed the whole operating system as
the result of double-clicking a file
that just ended up on my system it
shouldn't happen it makes me feel
uncomfortable about how computers work
how about Linux Linux is a little bit
different I'm surprised that I'm going
to say this but like Linux is actually a
little bit safer with how it handles
disk images in that I would need to
after I download my disk image I would
still have to say open with other
application and then I manually choose
disk image mounter I couldn't find a
file extension that just actually
mounted it as a filesystem
but as soon as I click that and I hit
select alright all my work is gone if I
hope I saved my Word document than it
was on let's go to the windows and of
things it turns out there's a capability
in RDP it is optional but there is
something called remote FX which allows
you to do USB device pass-through the
cool thing about that is like I might
have like a two-factor authentication
singing jig and I don't have to worry
about like that's my RDP client
understanding that and is it going to do
what it needs to do it's basically just
saying hey I'm going to convey what's in
my USB port and I'm gonna allow it to
connect to that remote system the thing
about this that's not really great is
yeah it's optional and it's only for
authenticated users so you're limiting
your attacks to like it has to be an
authenticated user and it has to be on a
system where they've decided I want the
ability to do usb pastor but you know I
tried it you know set up a virtual
machine did the USB pass-through and
boom Windows 7 crashes stop in the NTFS
but I started to dig a little bit deeper
and it turns out if you have a disk
image on Windows you can take that disk
image and you can turn that into a VHD
file and that's basically like a disk
image format that is used with hyper-v
which is like the default hypervisor
that comes with Windows 10 and Windows 8
and later and stuff like that the cool
thing about this is like this tool it
turns out a VHD is really just the same
the DD disk image with like a little bit
of metadata at the end appended onto it
so really this VHD tool doesn't do
anything super clever just like puts the
stuff at the end that Windows is looking
for so let's imagine on Windows we've
downloaded this VHD file it's either
emailed to us and we double-click it
anybody see a theme here what happens
after you double-click it it crashes
your computer it doesn't prompt you it
doesn't say hey would you like to open
this file that you just downloaded from
the internet you know so Inc I wish it
didn't do that so I had a question here
so like the the VHD stuff and VHDX is
like a modern version of VHD i was
wondering are there security products
that scan with inside of VHD or VHDX
files when do you have like an email
server it's gonna scan zip files it
might scan even more obscure like
archive formats search you know does
anybody here know if you have is it does
anybody know of a product that scans VHD
or VHDX files let's say theoretically
there is one that exists what does that
mean to us well whatever's doing the
scanning if it's parsing VHDX files it's
probably parsing the file system within
that file maybe that scanner is going to
crash well let's say what what if they
don't scan VHD files which i think most
of them do not you have to be aware that
like here's a file format that you have
zero visibility into when you're
somebody emails you a zip file you've
got all these tools that keep you safe
you know they spent lots of money on it
VHD is is kind of interesting here now
there's another thing that i mentioned
earlier about when you download a file
from the internet Windows tags that file
with something called the mark of the
web and this is basically a piece of
metadata that says hey this came from
somewhere dangerous email internet web
browser or something like that so here's
Microsoft Word
if I open up this Word document it says
hey I've opened this in protected view
it runs with flank low privileges like
lower than even like a restricted user
so basically it keeps me safe but how
does it know that how does it know that
they came from the Internet
well it turns out if you open up a
command prompt here I can do their /r
and it'll tell me like this metadata you
know this is an NTFS metadata sort of
thing and I can actually see here here's
his own identifier and if you want to
this is kind of neat you can actually
just run notepad and you can open that
file and it tells you exactly like
here's where this file came from zone ID
3 means it came from the internet
somewhere sketchy starting with Windows
10 they actually put like the URL from
which the file was downloaded so like
it's kind of cool from like a forensics
perspective and like if you have a bad
file on your system you can tell where
it came from
so any download that you have and this
is through email or anything like that
well email have to figure out what like
how it indicates that but if I download
something with a web browser it tells me
okay this came from attacker dot
example.com so that's that's kind of
neat now let's say I have this document
that I downloaded from the internet and
I get this button here and it says you
know enable content this is just the
proof of concept that I have and all
right and runs Cal right very simple
sort of stuff mark of the web protects
you from that just by giving like one
additional click that no user in the
right mind would ever possibly click
because they understand the consequences
of clicking it right that's how it works
I think well let's think about mark of
the web and VHD so the mark of the web
is actually applied to these VHDX files
I showed in the prior slide it's there
so the mark of the web is there so it's
applied the problem is is that Windows
doesn't treat a downloaded VHDX or VHD
or VHDX file any differently than it
otherwise would be
and I get the impression that security
devices don't really scan VHD files or
VHDX files what can we conclude from
that PhDs and VHD X's are pretty
interesting from an attacker if I want
to deploy if I want to deliver my
malware to any organization I'm gonna
put it in a VHD now you have to be
running Windows 10 to be able to just
double click on it Windows 7 can like
you can manually bound it but it's like
no end-users ever gonna fall for
anything in a VHD or a VHDX file but if
you're on a Windows 10 platform that's
an excellent vehicle for bad stuff to
come in so finally just to kind of wrap
things up and I'll open it if anybody
has any questions or if anybody wants to
try out my thumb drive I will happily
learn it to you I promise that it will I
have not done anything to cause this
thumb drive to do anything permanent to
your computer like running malicious
code assuming you trust me so just a
little bit back to fussing with BFF in
like the standard way that you're
running BFF where I'm running a target
application it has a capability that I
like to think of it as atomic iterations
which is not like some awful prog rock
band name or something it's actually
what that means is every time I launch
my target application it either crashes
or it doesn't crashes and then it goes
away and then I start right over again
so every single iteration of a fuzzing
campaign exists in isolation BFF itself
will automatically deduplicate crashes
so if I'm fuzzing a target application
BFF will determine which ones are dupes
which which ones I've seen before
it will also do exploit ability
determination it does something called
crash minimization which is kind of neat
because like let's say I'm fuzzing a
Word document and I get something that
causes a crash if I happen to manipulate
a hundred bytes of that file it could be
that like there's only one byte that
caused the crash
so BFF will automatically determine
what's the minimum amount of file
manipulation that will cause that same
sort of crash string minimization is a
thing that helps exploit developers in
that let's say I start out with a word
document and it crashes if I do a string
minimization of that what that'll end up
doing is it'll replace as many bytes as
possible in that file with the
Metasploit string so basically it'll say
any bytes that don't affect the
program's ability to open the file and
then also crash in the exact same way
I'm just gonna replace it with like the
Metasploit string so as I'm looking at
that file I can say okay these are the
byte values I can change to whatever I
want
this stuff is all pretty cool and like
BFF has done this for years like it's a
free download it works on Windows Mac OS
in Linux so if you have any interest in
fuzzing I would recommend go try it out
it's found like I've used it to find a
lot of vulnerabilities more than I could
possibly count and it's found
vulnerabilities and things that matter
like back in the day like when we
developed this buzzer because like
software was like oh I will say that
when we developed it software is lower
quality than it is right now because
people have like your folks like
Microsoft have built in checks into the
compiler they do things automatically
they ensure that people don't do silly
things but we've been able to find
exploitable vulnerabilities in like
Adobe Reader adobe flash shockwave any
you know Microsoft Office we've been
pretty productive with it now
the problem is is you don't get those
benefits when you're doing anything
os-level when I have an operating system
that's running and I tell it to do
something and something goes weird in
Colonel land and it keeps doing that
over and over again that operating
system continues to run for the lifetime
of that fuzzing campaign so I might be
doing a fuzzing campaign and eventually
the operating system crashes and I'm
like okay cool it's that last thing that
it did that caused the crash mmm not
really because you have a operating
system that has been running for that
entire lifespan and it could be that one
of the iterations that I did flipped a
bit in kernel space and it didn't do
anything bad but then like later on when
it did like some heap cleanup or some
other stuff like that it caused it to
crash so you have cumulative effects you
have to do manual crash deduplication
which I kind of described a little bit
like in the case of Linux where it's
putting stuff on an NFS server I can
look at those back traces and see which
ones are duplicate the exploitability
determination yeah it's kind of like me
as a human being a Linux Linux Wow yeah
I think in all of the cases in order to
determine exploitability I kind of had
to sit down at the crashes and and they
are the unique crashes so it wasn't like
a ton of work but it was manual and then
the whole crash minimization and string
minimization stuff you can't do because
you're running BFF on an operating
system and if the operating system
crashes from underneath BFF like it's
not running anymore there is no more BFF
so on to the recommendations here's what
I tell you things that I think you
should do but I know are not really
practical it's what we do at cert for
the sole reason that later on what's
something bad happens I can go back and
say all right I told you so you didn't
listen to me and just think I did I just
want you to if anything just think about
this for a little bit and get this get
the right mindset here if unless you're
absolutely certain your operating system
doesn't Auto amount file systems don't
plug in an unknown device in your
computer ah it's great advice
it keeps you safe now everybody is
always in a situation where like you
need the let's say
in training and they pass around the
thumb drive that has like your stuff on
it kind of have to do it turns out Mac
OS a bun to Windows they all auto mount
drives so if you're using a popular
operating system it's it's Auto mounting
stuff when I was creating this this
crashing thumb drive I had to use like a
special Linux distro or Linux windowing
environment that doesn't automatically -
doesn't ottomans don't plug unknown
devices into your computer and the
reason is I've only looked at file
systems contained within USB
mass-storage
USB does a little bit potentially more
than that the other recommendation that
I have is if you're running an email if
you're running an enterprise and you see
a VHD or a VHDX file get emailed to you
block it
there is no reason ever for any of those
files to get emailed to you usually
they're very large because it's the
entire disk of like a server or an
operating system that would be an easy
thing to block and if you have like a
proxy or something like that maybe
somebody if they're working with hyper-v
and they have a specific reason to
download it maybe they'll need that the
other thing that I mentioned earlier is
that Remote effects stuff if you have
that turned on
I'm not saying to turn it off I'm saying
reassess your organization's need to
have remote effects you might need it
but just understand that by turning it
on you might increase your attack
surface and then finally just just to
kind of wrap things up I don't know if
you've ever been at a security
conference where you get a USB powered
thing anybody know what this does I
could probably even cut the cable of
that and I could see there's only a red
one and a black one it's power only
right
there's been some research where people
have been able to embed inside of the
USB connector like a microcontroller so
imagine you as a normal human being
you've received this at a security
conference or some other conference or
maybe found it in a parking lot and
you're like oh cool free lava lamp that
looks like get into your computer plug
it into your friend skip here or France
computer it's very difficult to know
without like necessarily like a scanning
electron microscope and the D kapor and
other sort of stuff you don't really
know what might happen when you plug
stuff in here's my contact info I think
we're about right on time so we at cert
we have a blog we occasionally talk
about some interesting things I've got a
Twitter account where I often talk about
not interesting things and sometimes
interesting stuff so da da does anybody
have any questions comments short
debates
ah yes so that was actually it's a very
good question in the question is it I
just did to generally summarize it is it
possible to do something oh sorry I
might have misinterpreted your question
so one thing would be you know like can
you put it on like an Android device or
maybe you plug your Android phone into
something yeah you can absolutely do
that you can you can have your Android
device do anything the other thing that
I looked at that I thought maybe you
asked was is there a file system that
Android operating system contains that I
could crash Android and it turns out
Android only has like two or three file
systems they don't have riser FS they
don't have JFS in there because nobody
wants it and like just as I've looked at
different Linux distributions this is a
difference that I noticed between for
example Red Hat Enterprise Linux it
comes with XFS and ext4 and that's it if
you want something else you know a few a
booth two on the other hand it's like
hey we got everything here's something
that was made like a long time ago but
it's turned on by default so any other
questions anything yes
all right you could go back to the
supply chain aspect of things and feel
like well here's the thing here's the
thing that I bought from Apple but like
who manufactured it for them and how do
I know it's like you know does it have
that seal of authenticity I'm very you
know I'm inherently paranoid based on
where I work but also with the things
that I've seen I'm I'm like I really you
know I do kind of follow that advice of
you know and I was thinking earlier here
I'm doing this presentation I'm like
what if they give me like one of those
clickers right I give you the the
clicker or I can like walk away from my
computer and I well that's a thumb drive
that's it sorry it's a USB device that
you've plugged into your computer so it
would be quite ironic if I had accepted
a clicker to do this presentation so
mechanically typing my keyboard thus the
life of anyone interested in security
you make the trade-offs I don't have a
good answer for that I don't know like
you know how do you know what to trust I
don't trust anything is that is that it
does that help you sleep at night I
don't know anybody else all right thank
you
oh wait I got one quickie if you want to
see something quick if my screen comes
up here as I was putting you know as I
was putting together my powerpoint
presentation here I encountered an odd
behavior and here's my like I don't
understand how computers work at all
right I know no clue so I've got this
title slide here right and like I just
found out that it's like a widescreen
format sort of thing so it's like I got
a like change it to a widescreen and
alike so I copy my slides over but this
this font was too big so I went to make
it smaller what let me let me replant it
again look at what text I selected and
when I select the smaller font size look
at what text gets smaller this is why I
have a job software is terrible software
terrible top terrible software is what
ensures that I get paid not for this
this is the thing that just annoys me
when I'm trying to put together a
presentation to give it a conference but
anyway software is awful don't use it
okay thank you thank you alrighty and
blacktrack will resume at 12:30 p.m. in
this room with lightning talks
have a good lunch