okay we're gonna go ahead and get
started so the next speaker is Dustin
Updike you'll be presenting on ghosts in
the machine orchestrating a realistic
cyber security exercise battlefield it's
a little bit about Dustin Dustin uptick
is a cyber security researcher at the
Carnegie Mellon University's assert
having previously served with multiple
industries an array of Technology roles
dustin transition into security
supporting cyber workforce development
for multiple government and commercial
contracts his current interests are in
game theory machine learning and a
without further ado let's welcome Dustin
[Applause]
hi is this thing on okay sorry I'm a
stroller so I'm not gonna stand there at
the podium
thanks to besides for having me thanks
to all of you for coming out on Dustin
and originally this talk was going to be
about developing a software system that
would replicate human behavior on a
computer the good guys the bad guys
everything in between in a way that we
could use it for training and exercise
those people learning different things
about the security industry but I
realized what who my team is what we do
and how we think are sort of critical to
understanding why we developed this
software and how we did it so you get
both of those stories because I don't
think one makes sense without the other
and that's what we're going to go
through today so of course everything I
say today is not necessarily the
opinions of my employer of the
University so my job is to be interested
in workforce development particularly in
the realm of cyber and security that
landscape we'll walk through today how
it's going to change how we anticipate
it's a change in the next couple of
years and what that might look like and
what the implications are for that
change now the TLDR of this talk is that
everything that we do in terms of
training should be rooted in some sort
of realistic scenario right so to borrow
a phrase from the military we want to
train as we fight
and so the the exercises and the
training that we put together and I'll
walk you through today the number one
pillar that we try to always stay on
course for is to deliver something that
people would see in their daily
operations and for them to do the sorts
of things that they do in their day job
right and the thinking there is if
you've done it enough times in training
you'll know exactly what to do when that
situation arises in real life correct if
you don't do that then we find that's a
great place to pick up lots of bad
habits right if you're gaming
your training you're probably not
getting the most out of it
so in terms of realism this is where we
have to start does anybody recognize
this yeah so this is the planet amine
er7
it's from episode 23 of the first season
of Star Trek the original one and so the
crew the enterprise goes there and finds
that the planet has been locked in war
for 500 years except there's no
destruction there's no chaos there's not
really any sign of armed conflict at all
so it turns out that the entire war has
been fought in a computer simulation for
500 years the the caveat is that if
you're killed in the simulation you must
submit yourself to a disintegrator and
sort of kill yourself in real life right
so that's a pretty realistic simulation
right that's not what we aspire to do
right we're not trying to build Skynet
or something like this but I think it's
a very interesting question how far
should we go in terms of building
training that mimics what you're going
to do in your day job it's probably
short of this right but it's probably
not the basic stuff that you can read
out of a textbook either so yeah that's
a Meany r7 and I got some cool suits so
as part of our simulation we wrote a
package that's that's a that's a little
bit down the stack so assume we're doing
some sort of network training we have a
network and there's lots of tools to do
that right on ESXi or some other
hypervisor we have an internet and it's
probably in a box right it probably
isn't the actual
Internet that's outside and again
there's tools for that so now we need
activity on that wire right we need
users quote unquote I don't like to use
users not not for anything but because
user sim isn't is not a new thing right
there's lots of tools out there that
does that but it's a range of things and
we want to be a little bit more precise
in what that is so there there's there
specialized hardware that puts packets
on a wire there they're highly realistic
packets but they don't track back to any
particular machine at the other end of
the spectrum and the sei is actually
done some work in this area we can
automate Windows or Linux or something
like that to do certain things so that
it looks like a user is on that box
right
we took that model and we we went with
it
we added a bunch of things that we
hadn't seen in the market before and
again this is not a this is not a sales
talk right but we we added a couple of
features we added the network effect so
that we could command and coordinate
large number of VMs to do certain types
of user behavior either as an enclave as
a group of machines or as a single
machine so at the end of the day we're
able to model all different types of
human behavior on a box and if it was
done really really well you wouldn't
know whether it was me or a computer
simulation of me sitting at the other
end of the cable so does everybody have
in mind that person back home on their
network that's super annoying that
clicks on everything that launches like
everything you're not supposed to do
right we could we could actually model
those people with ghosts because you
probably have those people that you have
to deal with in your organization now
you can model them and make fun of them
and even give them names right because
they have a user name on your network so
they can have some fun with that as well
so this is sort of the last group that I
need to poke a stick at and say you know
you should be scared there's lots of
scary things in the world the point I
want to make is that the scary things
are rapidly increasing right the number
of attacks the sophistication of those
attacks the things that we are seeing
today are largely unseen in the past and
the the thing that a lot of people
forget is that training needs to keep
pace with that
right if we're seeing more sophisticated
attacks that include larger sets of data
that includes machine learning systems
we need to figure out how to build that
my team needs to figure out how to build
that in training and make it affordable
and not super resource intensive and not
custom for every single client that
comes down the path right so that keep
that in the back of your mind we do all
different sorts of training events I'll
call them training it for our purposes
we'll be sort of a one-on-one thing I
need to learn Python I need to learn the
bash shell
I'll eat I need to learn basic
networking cloud architecture those are
the things you normally go off and do on
your own in whichever medium suits you
best right you can you can get a book
you can do the audio book you can heck
you can go to youtube and probably learn
it in an afternoon right from some 13
year old incur blackest tan we also do
exercises which i think is super
interesting because I don't know that
they exist very often in the commercial
non military world so an exercise is I
guess the best analogy for it is if we
were an elite soccer team and we had a
game this weekend I think someone is
playing right now right what's the score
if we wanted to know how we were going
to do the best predictor of how we were
going to do is to play a scrimmage game
against a team that is most like the
team were actually going to play right
use the same equipment the same rules
and go out there and try to win and that
would give us some baseline of what
we're good at at what we need to improve
upon etc that's an exercise that can't
be done in a drill right in a drill you
can stop and tie your shoe in a
scrimmage game and you don't want to
lose you have to be prepared for those
sorts of things so the military does
exercises all the time right that proves
that units are our combat ready
cyber teams do that just the same and I
don't see that in the in the consumer
world too often but it's really
interesting because the dichotomy there
is everybody has a job to do but they
also have to operate as some sort of
team right and guess what a lot of us
operate as a team so how do you train
and improve
and even baseline where you're at in
your organization if teams don't train
together and then simulations are of
course they're just automating the whole
thing looking at the result data set to
make some assumptions or some
predictions about how it might be in the
future now for all of these we we do a
certain set of of things starting with
the network right we build highly
realistic or as realistic as possible
networks that match what people are
using in their production environments
it might be the whole thing it might be
a subset of what we want to train upon
but we use the same tools and products
that they would use in production you
know cost not being a factor sometimes
that sort of changes the dynamic a
little bit but but for most part we're
using the actual tool tools that they're
using in production then on top of that
we layer different types of scenarios so
it might be to try new some new hunt
technique that DCO is is is interested
in it might be to validate that their
internal processes and communications
are up to snuff maybe there are a couple
of years old and they want to take a
look at that maybe it's to assert that
soldiers are meeting their mettle which
is that third line that's an interesting
term it's a military term it's a mission
essential task list it's typically not
tied to knowing the tool or knowing a
process it's basically can you get this
thing done under a high / high duress
right and I always think that that's
kind of interesting because that's not
how we hire or how we fill out our
resumes right we put I have 10 years of
Python experience I know how to use
plunk and that's what we get hired for
right the military says no we don't
really care so much how you do it
there's there's outcomes that we want to
see and you need to be able to do it
quickly obviously we have to work with
the stakeholders on that side to figure
out how we can validate those
assessments and time it and all that
sort of thing some of the more fun
things that we get to do is to actually
roleplay the different characters that
are in the exercise that might be some
headquarters that is telling you what to
do it might be some Intel Group either
inside or outside of your organization
providing you some direction it might be
a super grumpy contractor from lock
that's pissed off that his machine you
turned his machine off somehow so we get
really into character and we have a lot
of fun with those the funnest of all of
them is when we get to play Red Team
right in military terms that's up for
sometimes we get to do that sometimes
another group does that when the other
group does that that's just another set
of requirements for us they are
typically not the ones being evaluated
in an exercise so they're part of
assessing providing the tools for
assessment of the actual blue team we
work a lot with blue team's and then a
point that I would like to make is that
the exercise can be facilitated meaning
we're they're either virtually or face
to face or it couldn't be completely on
demand where you sort of go into the
system you pick this scenario and then
everything is controlled by the computer
and of course that is directly linked to
building ghosts and we'll get to that in
a second so when we do the red teaming
my my team always sort of scoffs at
these are these on-demand exercise
there's nothing you can do on a computer
that's as good as we are we're making
all sorts of gut decisions we're reading
all these different data points that
would be all that's impossible to
replicate with with any kind of
programming right that just can't be
done I'm a software developer so that is
a really juicy statement to launch in
front of me I get excited about what I
love when people say that's impossible
right because I want to get started on
that like tomorrow how can I was there a
charged string for that but over and
over people have made this statement and
it's kind of interesting because at the
same time I was reading ready player one
I haven't seen the movie and most people
say that I shouldn't bother but the book
is interesting because you you jack into
the Oasis just like you go into these
different scenarios and you you you take
on some task right and at the other end
of the task is some thinking adversary
that you have to sort of battle it out
with right I will admit that most on
well not most all on-demand exercises
for anyone of a certain skill set they
start to get they
feel very gaming right and you start to
take those shortcuts that we don't like
because it's you know it's not realistic
it's not using the right tools it's for
vm's and we're calling that an
enterprise network whatever the reason
might be so so that you know that's a
place for us to improve right there's a
lot of opportunity to make those better
and if I could make an exercise that my
team would be challenged by like that
would be something that would help not
only more experienced cyber experts to
improve and practice new things but that
would allow our military to use it etc
etc etc so that's not a new idea right a
thinking adversaries been around for for
a long time does anybody remember this
movie I'm not dating I'm dating myself
but you know again this is not a new
idea there's lots of reasons that it
hasn't been done right the sheer
complexity of being a network
administrator the the amount of data
that you would have to have on that
exercise being able to make good
decisions based on that data that's
coming in etc etc etc so yeah so that's
the challenge that was sort of the thing
that got us thinking about automating
our users and the good guys and the bad
guys and everything in between and
that's sort of the context for it now we
we do these exercises right and and I
want to veer off for a second and talk
about that team thing right to me
cybersecurity is a team exercise there
aren't very many people out there that
are lone guns doing something without
any other organization that they're
interacting with and that's an
interesting dichotomy because there's
certain skills that you and I have to
have right if we go back to the soccer
analogy we've got to be in peak physical
condition right to be able to run for 10
miles in a soccer game we need to be
able to not only know our position but
all the other positions around us on the
team right where is everybody going to
be when we have the ball where's
everybody going to be when we don't have
the ball so we can get it back in and be
back on the attack
but then and so we we all do that right
we all train we all learn new things we
all
or buying books and listening to
podcasts and all that sort of thing but
again back to that that team thing
there's not a lot of opportunities for
teams to train together and sort of
focus on the dynamics of the team and
less on what what each individual
component is doing so if you think about
it like how do you how can you say that
your DCO is a great DCO and is effective
in its job if you've never trained them
if you have no baseline for it as an
aside I suspect that the commercial
world does not do that because they
might be very disappointed with the
results and therefore somehow are liable
for it I don't know right but but it's
but it's an interesting thing that we
don't see very often outside of our DoD
partners now this is a say it's it's
really it's actually not that hard right
there are five areas that we typically
concentrate on for even the most
unsophisticated exercise that gives
teams opportunities to baseline and say
hey we're doing very good at this hey
our SOP is is entirely adequate even
though it's five years old so as long as
we are clear about what roles people are
playing and they're the same and the
exercise as they are in real life
the tactics and the adversaries that
we're dealing with are realistic to what
our job is so if we do an exercise where
we're defending webservers and I don't
actually have that in in my in my daily
operations back at company X that's not
really helpful right communication is an
interesting one because it's an easy way
to practice like hey we've identified
something how fast can we turn around
and do something about this and mitigate
some threat or some vulnerability that's
just been announced and that environment
is also an interesting one if a team
sits together we train them together if
they don't sit together we don't let
them sit together right so that they get
used to how things are actually on the
company floor on the technology side we
again we install all the tools that they
would expect to see and they use every
day I assume at some point they're an
expert on that tool so let's put it into
training so that they can they can show
that off a bit so if we're using Cisco
routers we put them in in game
as well I will admit that licensing is a
huge pain in the neck right right in the
middle the exercise it like never fails
that the Cisco licensing goes down and
everything slows to a crawl and and
everybody sort of slaps their forehead
but replacing it with some other router
severely handicapped so those teams and
we try to avoid it likewise for the red
team we try to make it so that they're
able to do all of the things that they
want to do in that than that scenario
sometimes that means before the exercise
starts we have to have a conversation
with blue team's about letting
PowerShell execute or letting off on
some GP oh right but that's an
understood game ISM and they're sort of
okay with that the worst possible thing
is when the cyber ghost comes in at some
predetermined time put some payload on a
machine that nobody can explain how it
got there or why it's there and then all
of a sudden hell breaks loose and teams
are like wow I was really realistic
that's great where did that come from
right so we we really avoid that and and
work hard to make it a more realistic
hey this is how this got inside the wall
and you can find that in the logs you
can see that in the network traffic etc
etc of course for a red team they have a
host of different personas that they're
going to use in that scenario might be a
hostile nation state I saw someone with
with the t-shirt with these three
characters on such a cool t-shirt but
right all these all these different
personas have different motivations
different strategies about how they're
going to attack and death of course
that's different opportunities for teams
to learn about what that's going to look
like in the real world how to identify
it how to mitigate it and for our
software's purposes we would want to be
able to recreate all of these different
personas in our exercise right so let's
get down to the to the software the
software is called ghosts it's open
source it's out on github right now I do
all the development out there all the
bugs are are plain to see
all the feature requests are as well we
have used it for the last two years
operationally that's our our test ground
some of these bigger exercises are using
multiples of thousands of characters in
game and we're able to support that with
a with a pretty simple stack but it's
out there check it out if you're
interested in building your own sort of
training environment we have a lot of
tools to help you do that quickly and
easily for for any kind of exercise or
training typically we have interactions
between humans that's us right and then
these characters that are represented in
game as NPCs to borrow a term from from
D&D right that's any that's any
character in the game that's controlled
by the computer and again if ghost is
gonna do it really well you won't be
able to tell which is which right they
need to be behaviorally accurate that
means Todd and logistics needs to be
doing logistic e types of things
browsing certain websites filling out
certain types of documents sending
emails to certain types of people versus
someone over in marketing or
communications or etc etc so that's
really an infinite array of
configurations that you'd that you'd
want to have right you want to have that
real enterprise-e level configuration
mess that we try to avoid but in in no
short order is sort of necessary and of
course they need to be fully autonomous
in a in a long-running exercises some of
ours are are over nine months we're not
gonna go in and tinker with them right
we might reconfigure them or whatever
but but we don't have to restart them or
do anything like that so if we were able
to do that if we were able to replicate
the the people that we're there to
protect bless you and the people that
are coming in from the outside scanning
our networks looking for vulnerabilities
right that would be kind of like real
life and that would give our
participants higher training value and
of course we correlate that with hey if
you're doing exactly what you're doing
in operations in your training you're
gonna know how to react that should be
successive that should that should
result in better chance of success in
the real world than not so the
technology behind ghosts is a simple
client-server architecture the server
we've been working over and over again
to make it as simple as possible to
stand up right now it's three doctor
containers so docker compose up and
you're ready to roll and the clients are
approaching that that level of ease as
well their zip file they don't require
any special permissions or any kind of
install scripts put it in a folder run
it as that user and it should be good to
go there's a little bit of configuration
to get the - to talk of course but other
than that you should be good initially
they will get their instructions from
the command server including who am i
representing right I'm Tony from from
marketing and here is my list of
timeline events that I'm gonna do
throughout a day I'm gonna browse these
websites I'm gonna fill out these
documents every so often I'll respond to
email etc and I did and of course we can
update that throughout the exercise for
the entire exercise for groups of
machines or one machine at a time in
addition to that the agents are starting
to learn about where they're sitting on
the network as well so we call it the
coffee counter effect if we took any one
of us and put us in a new company on
Monday right we start to figure some
things out we even with the least
permissions we'd be able to figure some
things out like what's my upstream
Network look like what file shares are
available what printers are out here
what other machines are around me in
addition we probably go get a drink at
some point coffee water whatever right
and we be like hey Chris where do you
work what are you doing today right and
we start to figure out who sits around
us and what they do right so all of that
information the agents use the agents
clients use to reason about what to do
next so you gave me these sort of
guardrails of things to do throughout
the day but I'm going to pick what is is
is next for me on my list unless we
specifically program it to do one two
three right which is which is not kind
of real-world that we're looking for
typical install for us is to put the
control server out of game across the
hypervisor we have a technology called V
tunnel you install on ESXi and it
tunnels all of the traffic from the
clients so that players can't see it
that's actually important because really
good players will see that traffic and
they'll start to take a look right
they'll use any edge they can to win
and I don't blame them right but we use
this v tunnel to hide it so they don't
see it at all so there's nothing on the
clients that you can look at that would
tell you oh this is this is a this is
something good and this is something bad
right so let's watch over here that
doesn't exist and we hide all the
traffic back and forth that gives us the
opportunity to do a lot of different
things so blue team can set up however
they want they can set up their
firewalls there they can divide up their
networks however they want they want to
do that ghost doesn't care about any of
that it just stands up and starts
running as long as it has permissions to
run as the user it's good to go same
thing for the red team they can organize
by they could stand up boxes that do
different parts of the kill chain right
I have these bunch of boxes over here
doing recon and when they find something
they're gonna send that over to the next
phase which is going to look to exploit
some vulnerability that's been found
right and then of course we can do stuff
in the middle so that the red team can
either attack directly they can MIT can
cover my Sun box in the middle and and
do a jump or we can do insider threat
right the sei has done a ton of work in
s in insider threat and we can represent
the the malicious plant that would
that's like a foreign nation spy is
putting responder and all sort of nasty
stuff on the network or we can have you
know that person that we were talking
about before that clicks on everything
and just keeps clicking and just keeps
getting themselves further down the hole
we can do any one of those things so I'm
going to do a demo and I apologize
distributed systems are sort of hard to
demo but we'll go through it so you get
a flavor of what it looks like so this
is the Windows client right it fires up
as the user once it installs it's going
to it installs itself and then it goes
off and hides and starts to get to work
on the configuration that we've given it
so you can see it's firing up different
office documents it's going to pull up
Word Word Excel PowerPoint and going to
start sending and responding to emails
now there's no browser so the
configuration let's change that it's all
JSON text files you can go in and and do
it here you can do it on the server and
send it down
the browser is actually running in
headless mode because for larger
thousand VM enclaves that's pretty
resource intensive so we run it headless
so I changed that file I save it go says
oh I got new instructions to do and it's
gonna restart and start to perform those
new actions and there's the browser so
you can for all these configurations
that can be random right you can you can
browse HTTP HTTPS sites at random
you can browse them go to this site go
to this page download this payload unzip
it do something nasty but here we just
have a normal machine that's going to go
throughout the day create different
kinds of documents browse different web
sites and you know that creates a lot of
of realistic noise on the network that's
just people doing their day jobs if I
wanted to fire off something that's a
one time I'm thoughtful I'm over here
doing all these different timeline of
events I can do that a couple different
ways there's a drop box where I just
paste in a script and it's gonna execute
that script move it to the outbox as
completed here you see it's just running
PowerShell and unzipping some file I can
do that as many times as I want so now
you have a machine that's doing its
normal things of the day and then
someone stops by and says hey can you
take a look at the zip file you can do
those sorts of scenarios as well and
again you can do it here on the box but
you probably do it up at the command
server send that to an API and ghosts
will deliver it to the machines that you
indicate could be all of the machines
could be some of the machines or it
could be one machine all that
information gets logged up at the
command server I have this really
cranked up so you can see a new Enclave
is coming online is checking in saying
hey I'm here and reporting all of its
activity so the top line is your macro
numbers and that middle graph is well I
ran 15 PowerPoint documents today I did
35 emails I clicked on a bunch of things
and I ran these ten PowerShell commands
so all of that gets logged if it's a
command where there's an expected
payload you get that payload as well and
then you can do something with it so you
can LS on a folder until something
happens
now if I show you one machine and the
command server that's really not that
exciting right what's exciting is when
you have a bajillion machines out there
doing all these random things that kind
of looks like a corporate network right
actually the best ghost installation I
can't tell you what they're doing right
just like I can't tell you what Joe
Schmoe is doing on a corporate network
on Tuesday morning at 10:15
that's pretty real so back to the back
to the admin dashboard for a sec again
the top line is the macro numbers this
is a nine month exercise that we did
where a team would exercise then they
would go into a sandbox period to sort
of respond to how they did adjust some
of their configurations put new things
in then we'd exercise again
then we sandbox we did that four times
but you can see at the top we get a an
overall picture of agents reporting in
this is the timeline of events that I've
done they also report in their health
statistics so you can configure hey
these clients need to be able to get out
to these internet sites they need these
permissions they need whatever and then
when they can't do one of those things
they'll report back as an alert right so
sometimes we see teams block whole 24's
or something like that
which is a sort of a game violation and
and this is a way that we get alerted
and then they poll as well just to say
hey I'm here is there anything new for
me to do the second line is just meant
to show that we can tune the activity
pretty precisely in terms of let's turn
up the amount of stuff that our users
are doing or let's turn it down at
different points throughout the exercise
and then the bottom line is just a slice
of in this particular time period we had
111 machines browsing Firefox for them
working on Excel documents clicking on
things running commands etc so you have
access to all that data row by row this
is just a rollup it's nice to have at at
the you know if you're facilitating an
exercise that here's what's going on and
everything is sort of happening as you
expect so as far as working on this
software like I said it's about
years old we've worked through that I
don't know why we picked a three-phase
approach maybe it sounded good or we saw
it on some blog post but in the third
year where we're sort of down there at
phase three we can deploy really large
networks we can have them do all sorts
of random things on a machine that you
and I would do and we can get all that
information back that leaves us with
this huge data set of everything that
basically happens in that exercise and
so what we're looking at this summer is
can we start to automate some of those
things that my team said we couldn't
automate so can we have machines that
are doing scans and then find something
that we can actually do something with
and trip that off to another machine
that's going to try to take advantage of
it right that's where we're at this
summer we have a couple people working
on it I can't tell you that that's
something we're gonna turn around next
year and come back here and say well we
have all these automated tools now to
attack other nations with like no it's
it's going to be a long process but if
we can start to make some progress with
that maybe in a few years we'll have
something that's worth talking about
because it would be totally awesome to
have a simulation where experienced
players could go in and have have an
experience where they say hey that that
was actually pretty challenging like
that thing was who's not cheating right
we don't want to create something that
knows everything about everything but
hey this was pretty realistic and it was
pretty challenging it taught me some
places I need to improve and so that's
sort of the lead-in to where we think
some things are going right training and
exercise should always be rooted in that
that next level thing right that's why
we're working on this so that we can
have teams be able to train on things
that are happening right now in the
world or are about to happen or expect
it to happen right so the best exercise
is for us or when we see something in
the news and we're able to get it in
there that week and teams are like wow
now I know what that's going to look
like in the real world I can identify it
and hopefully I can mitigate it before
you know we even have to deal with it
but that's what training and exercise is
about right it's not about training on
things that are five years old and
learning to deal with things that five
year old way right that's fighting a new
battle with old tools and
I think we know how that turns out so
that's part of our problem part of our
problem is the sophistication of the
networks that everyone is managing and
securing is sort of outpacing our
ability to keep pace with it right or
keep up with it
that could be cost that could be
resources training is always sort of the
last thing that people want to pay for
right so we have to look at new ways to
recreate these hyper realistic scenarios
without breaking the bank and without
having to use a hundred people to do
every single one of them custom right
and so some of the things that we're
looking at is using machine learning
using shared resources to recreate that
now imagine if I know everything with
ghosts I essentially know everything in
an exercise that my NPCs are doing I
know the results of everything they're
doing so I sort of know that whole one
side of the exercise now maybe I can
provide my players feedback and work
like a custom experience for them based
on how they're moving through that
exercise it's like a it's like a
choose-your-own-adventure if we were
able to do that maybe we could we could
use that to bring higher fidelity to the
types of scenarios that we see right
maybe there's a way that we can reuse
some of the vulnerabilities and some of
the malware that we're using in
different ways without having to write
it from scratch maybe if we could add
everything that the actual human players
were using to that are doing to that
data set then we'd really have something
right now I know basically everything
that's going on inside my exercise maybe
I can really give you feedback about
well this thing happened and you missed
it and now you know things are really
going wrong inside your network that
real-time that real-time feedback would
be sort of key to that jacking into the
Oasis and taking on this thinking
adversary in a way that actually helps
you get better as an operator and then
the last step of that is if we were
doing exercises that we're doing that
then why couldn't we just add a layer of
machine learning
on top of the exercise to tell you which
exercise you would get the most from
right how do you pick which scenario to
train on going back to the Vietnam slide
right you shouldn't train on things you
already know and things that you're
already good at
maybe you should train on this thing
here because we've detected some
weakness in the force right that's scary
right for this room that should be super
scary because what if we hooked what if
we hooked production systems to our
training environments like what if the
training was so good and so realistic
and so oasis like that we just took the
results of training to improve our
production systems what if we took our
production systems to build better
training modules because it would be
then based on the things that are
actually running in production now
that's crazy right that's a whole new
vector we are opening ourselves up to
attack how do you separate training data
from real data well what if the training
data was actually valuable in some way
that influenced what we do in production
these are not my words these are what
they're talking about inside the sei
there are lots of agencies already
thinking about how can we do our
training almost as a simulation to
influence what we do in real production
environments and therefore how can we
use production data to create better
training for our for our employees so
the takeaways I hope that you might get
from that is there's lots of different
ways to train as individuals how do you
get better as a team
right how do you learn new things versus
get better at things both individually
and like I said as a team and these last
couple of slides right how do you build
a training environment that's very very
realistic and then how do you maximize
that training to improve your daily
operations right hopefully I hope you
get something that might help you to
improve your current organization today
we got tons of tools out there on the on
the table that might help you build that
simulated environment and that's all I
have I'm Dustin I am a researcher up at
cert but I snuck in here I don't have a
security background it's like I'm a
total
Fausta right I'm a software developer
but I have been in security for the last
two years and I'm studying philosophy at
CMU which is all about game theory
making decisions and complex systems
it's pretty cool program so that's my
story I'm sticking to it
any questions thank you
[Applause]