so thank you for having me quite happy
to be here on stage that's my fourth
time at 44 Khan and I thought that for
once I should be I should come I should
submit something and the on the stage to
present so here I am with aunty for bugs
catching dragons so my name is Nico I'm
French I work for Microsoft Security
Response Center in Cheltenham and part
of the variability a mediation team
I'm very sorry to look like a zombie I
just have a baby with dirty fingers and
I'm learning to be a daddy so hard way
so sorry I tried to my best upgrade on
dear
don't be an issue so I'm going to talk
about exploits burn books for affecting
outlook and exchange so I thought we've
outlook first so first part of this
presentation will be focused on outlook
I expect it to last around for 35
minutes and then I spend on over 10
minutes on an exchange so for those of
you who have no idea of exploits in
emails I hope you learn something this
presentation for those of you who
already have practiced practiced of it I
hope you still learn something and for
those of you who had already exploited
there's these applications well you and
I should talk after that talk because I
don't know you so I expect I assume that
you guys are not very familiar with
Outlook exploits so I just show you
something like shoulder yeah just a
shorty move so try to think about it
what according to you what's the worst
case for Outlook it's an exploit
affecting out what would be the worst
case you would think I believe like
something that's a preview pane you sin
and you got an email and then you get it
on the preview pen and then something
happen and cat pups well look at this
one you don't even need a preview pane
to be honest you just receive an email
and
your client get ons that's one of the
worst issues ever seen in my career this
one is quite bad so I'm not going to
talk about it but instead I will show
over issues so no let's pretend that
this never happened
let's pretend that you haven't seen that
try to think about there's these
exploits affecting a make ions when I
think about it I believe that the first
thing that come to my mind are those
warmth that we saw in the early 2000
like typically I love you you would get
an email with vbscript attachment you
double click it and then that sorry
there are so many people in the room and
that it would just spread on spread
again if there was one over I think in
1997 name of dive heiress was CAC and
this one was spreading with JavaScript
signature she would send an email with a
JavaScript signature and then it would
just run JavaScript code and then Auto
spread and that was quite a nice exploit
as well
but nothing more something more recently
so we had - a good friend of mine he
voted us an exploit that he named bad
win mail in 2015 so basically he managed
to find a way to build an email
containing flash object and and we've
known a flash vulnerability managed to
get our C on this there's also that that
person Ryan Hansen so you know it's a
it's one day at the MS or C or and where
I'm checking with you and suddenly I see
a free mails from somebody that I don't
know free image reporting bugs in my
stuff outlook and I'm reading they're
aware of the quick notes right if only
half of this is true then then it's
really bad it turns out that this guy
was great and everything he said was
true so this day we got three amazing
varieties and then
there is a lot class of issues varies
those where we see the exploit and we
just don't know that I took is affected
I'm thinking for example about the
exploits that we saw in the while
targeting world about two three years
ago Soviet actors where we're attacking
people using world with with some funds
so sending a document with a malicious
fund the thing is that nobody never
realized that this also apply to Outlook
so that that leads us to the attack
surface look it's quite big to be honest
I think first about image so anything
that is present in in an email it can be
like it's a formatting like HTML can
really sounds fun somebody in animal can
be pictures can be links attachments of
course don't want to double click them
can be calendars can be all sort of
things
there are also protocols obviously SMTP
pop3 the Exchange ActiveSync one there
used to be an NTP
but I think this one is gone also all
the issues that relate to spoofing like
fraud with certificates like anything
that has to do with the identities etc
etcetera and obviously while order
remainings like we are doing with an
office application
so think about macros think for example
about a scenario where you'd get an
email and that he made would execute
macro why I've never seen that and I
hope that this does not exist but just
have this in mind also I think about
sans post their rulers attack so this
was assuming that they had the control
of box of yeah of a mailbox and they
were trying to leverage that to get
correction on on the client so obviously
I just have 45 minutes here so I'm not
going to talk about everything I just
talked about the rich text format some
early objects some attachments
and of course a TNF and my key
properties before I dive in whitey stock
so I told you I'm I'm working for
Microsoft so you might be thinking this
guy he says he's from Microsoft and he's
going to teach us how to hack outlook
right well yes but that's not the point
the point is that there are all these
exploits out there and we don't know
them occasionally we only receive good
reports of run our riches but that's
very that's very occasionally two days
ago there was Patch Tuesday one bug was
was fixed I believe this was a this one
was interesting but there are all
viewers so from time to time I'm bumping
into someone and you say Oh Nico yeah
last Patch Tuesday you killed three of
my bugs
that's that's bad because there's work
with huh sorry for you man
how do I kill the earth so why are
people are not reporting to us is it
because it's too difficult
well yeah possibly I mean you don't have
scripting in giant you know
Dez made client it's not like you're
attacking your browser it's not like
you've got that's memory corruption that
you are going to be able to leverage
easily to get to get your exploits it's
more difficult than that
why else perhaps because there's no
symbols for fees sorry this I cannot
help you but still there are some good
offers around where for example of
friends at tipping point
they are offering and there's nice
bounties of exchange on Outlook 200k for
Outlook 250 for external 0 diem also is
buy is giving the same amount 250 for
exchange or outlook so there is a very
very very some place for some room for
reserves how can we help or find us
let's just talk about war on research
and things that we've seen so that's why
I will be presenting things I've seen
myself and things that people have been
reporting us and obviously quick
disclaimer everything that has been that
his
and here as obviously being fixed info
so we're sure we'll start avoid that
slides from jefes plantation contact
two-year today two years ago so when you
when you start looking for outlook
features you quickly figure that very
something called t nif emails and when
you google that I think that the first
link that you see is a page from
Microsoft describing as a gif format and
among other things that are set on this
page there is this it's just a container
for Outlook special features and this is
exactly what we are after
who after these features that give you a
remote code execution so what Jenny a
female suggests I just just a container
basically so you've got your client and
you select you can choose the format of
your email if your HTML plain text or
rich text format you choose reach that
format you send it and then on the other
side you get this email for example you
check on the server and there is the
thing meme hitters and then some content
you see application and stn yes and you
wonder what it is something encoded by
64dd cut that and then there's these two
levers just like a file with some
binaries so obviously what is this so as
we've most of my stuff formats
this one is publicly documented it's
quite easy to follow so just a roof is
just a sequence of objects and
attributes that that are that are in in
a file basically so for this research I
built our no.100 template so I've been
asked if this thing was
so it's not public but I've got a deal
for you you send me a good bug and I
published it and an intern you'd get
also a nice blog post right so there is
often a confusion between a TAF and RTF
so when you send that email in a rich
text format you might have the thing
that you're just sending an RTF document
it's partly true you're sending that RTF
document but it's actually embedded in
that gif container so yeah you're saying
this RTF along with many other
properties this RTF document is embedded
in that clear RTF compress properties
various anchor dings first one is as one
by default the compressed one so a
custom lzma anchoring and the other one
is something that you normally don't see
because I don't believe that with VRI
it's possible to send those emails so
melih just a plain text email sorry
usually occasionally we get cases where
or finder
I've been fuzzing of finders I've been
the fuzzing as an MSG file format and
and most of the time it's this is just
because they say first the so compressed
part and my stringer some random memory
corruption well most of time this is
going to fail because the parser is
quite pedantic so if you want to first
this part just use for example view out
looking interrupts library it will help
you just select your RTF file and send
it on the wire so it's much easier and
it will just give you much much false
positive than just facing as herb is a
bits waiver
like a shotgun activity things that we
see it still works because we are still
fixing those cases I think there was one
fixed about a months ago but most of
time it won't give you any results so
now let's talk about some examples of
issues that we've seen a thinking out
so when I'm talking about RTF I'm also
talking about world because outlook uses
the world core library to parse those
RTF emails
so anything that effect word that word
parser that world
RTF parser might also affect Outlook
that's why occasionally when there is an
issue of it in the RTF file format you
will see that Bolton that we published
are critical and not important it's
because most of the time this code can
also be reached from Outlook and the
preview pane so now think about the RTF
specifications there might be things
that that shouldn't be found in in
Outlook but should still be finding in
world and that leads me to the template
keyword I didn't find that one right now
in Leda so what do you figure out so it
was 2000 2017 I think he found a way he
figure out that it was possible to send
an email in RTF that has these this
template a keyword in it and then you
would point that home plate somewhere
for example over on the web like with
HTTP on our remote chair and then in
that template you would embed a flash
object and so he figured out that even
if hi face but we might had been fixed
there was still a path one possible way
to get codecs efficient with flash and
and he was true because if you look at
the code you can see that we fixed the
way that outlook was supposed to
instantiate objects but we didn't
realize that was also possible to get
the same behavior using templates and so
that was amazing but there's not only
the problem with these objects think
about the templates yours you can just
put whatever you want here
like for example a link on the web share
and then
you guys like it getting the anti lmf
for example and then that's an easier
and that's an easy win there's also the
fact that in that case you just extend
the attack surface suddenly you are able
to be able to have Outlook load every
binary formats that world supports XML
HTML legacy binary formats everything so
just all of a sudden everything that
affects world also affects outage so
which means that that's very bad
I never issues affecting this template
this one have I found it myself
so say that you've got a document that
that is linked to a template and these
templates point to another template with
the same name but for some reason this
template is an accessible for example
it's sit on a remote chair and then you
don't have you don't have access to to
go to that chair so that we just trigger
a nice use after free in Outlook can you
all world can you exploit that it's
probably complicated but what as you can
guess there are lots of issues affecting
the template keyword and so what do we
think happened there yeah for once we
just remove the feature it's not
something that we often see usually
teams try to fix the issue but there are
cases where we just remove the feature
because yeah it doesn't need to be there
I come back no to the outlook interrupt
library so if you like c-sharp it's
probably the easiest way to build an
email so look at look at this this piece
of code very something here called the
message class property so basically
everything here is properly documented
so just go on on Microsoft website and
your finals documentation there so look
at this message place it said IPM
contact so what is that exactly if you
send a DC mail and if you receive it on
the off lock side you will get this
instead of having your email with your
text you will see the contact form
well it's possible with Outlook and with
a gif format to send basically whatever
forms that outlook support on a wire so
they are like contact forms calendars
tasks well many of them and what's
interesting is that each of this form
each of these forms as its own
properties and its own code for example
this one on the top right corner there
is a picture and you're going to say
yeah but what's what's the benefit of
this because if you send an email you
can already include pictures that's
right the thing is here outlook is not
using as a standard path to parse that
picture instead it's using the GDI GDI
plus stack instead of just VLC stack
which means that if you've got a
vulnerability or an exploit affecting
the GDI stack in Windows then you might
also be able to use it here in that
email
there are over like things specific to
as well as those properties but be aware
that when you do that there might be
hidden features that you might be able
to to to exploit so as I said they're
old as old as me such class all these
message classes and more can be found on
that websites there they are even some
that are not documented but you guys are
reversers you know how to find them just
look for strings in a binary let's talk
about issues now affecting there's
classes so receive that one I think it
was summer 2016 in ballot so eighteen
Sterman he reported an email using the
IP and remote class and this was
triggering just a null pointer and
pivoting so for bugs like this we are
not going to issue a CVD because they
don't they don't qualify for our so this
is just a motorized issue but city-state
interesting cause at least it shows some
hidden behavior things that shouldn't
happen and see it made it
to this foundation today - Frank's agian
I'm going to spend more time no showing
talking about the ITIN document classes
so this one again was submitted to us by
Ryan Ryan Hansen so imagine an email
where you have two attachments
- or documents attached so one is a
normal RTF file and the other one is
that IBM document things when you open
the first one the first attachment
you'll see world pop up but war will pop
up in in protective mode in predictive
view so this is fine however in the
other one a protected view won't be
started and you will you will have world
just popping in medium integrity so
which means that some box is not gone so
I'm very sore so that over case opening
sending mail sending emails and having
office document running without user
interaction so I'm going to just quickly
if you want to try that that's a balk
I'm going to show you a demo of these
two cases combined so send that say that
you've sent an email instead of just
having some text
you've got word that shows that in the
preview pane that's fine so this one is
running in that container so pretty view
is correctly open he's quickly starting
on the side no what do you think happen
if you double click that email then
something else is going to happen word
will show up but this time using a
sukham automation and if you look at it
you will see that practice view is now
gone you guys are reversers so you're a
big curse of how this works so I've got
another demo for you this is all about
calm stuff and if you look at the code
you'll see that word was launched in the
first demo with automation because at
some point there is a class ID says that
yet that's a whirl document with what
happens if you send another class ID
that typically the equation
enter society so remember about two
years ago we had des exploit involving
the equation editor it was just possible
to trigger that in Outlook not zero
click just one click away so be aware
that when their exploits like this that
effect words sometimes it's also
possible to have them work on Outlook
all right
I'm now going to move slowly to all the
objects but first let me talk about the
other file format that outlook support
so I've just been talking about the
email format basically dot Idi Amin
there's another one that autumn supports
a message file format several ways to
generate the slice for example
copy/paste from the client to the
desktop or you can also use the
interrupt library to just generate that
this one is is good in a way that it
will give you everything that has been
generated in that code if you do the
copy paste from outlook client to
desktop sometimes you're losing some
information so bear that in mind so when
you do that and when you try to open
this this message format you'll see that
this is actually an Ori storage that you
have so just not a random binary file
Noorie storage consisting of streams and
stop storage notice for examples of
property versions 1.0 top stream I come
back to it in a in a second might be
properties might be properties are
essentially described by three three
different properties so first one is the
PID so here for example 1 1 a1 F it's
also described by its type here 1 F for
a Unicode string and its value so here
I'd handle text so the two types follows
of windows Barn types so it's very easy
to read them free for an integer 5 for
float etc etc etc so what the
relationship between V my file format
and the research performance
look at the properties is the first
trainer superb diversion stream and
you'll see for example this this
property so everything in that stream is
encoded on 16 bytes so for example for
this property which is an integer you
see the value at offset plus sites who
are here just a sequence of zeros for it
for this one which is a string and each
size is set to 12 so obviously there's
not enough room for 4 for it to be
contained in that stream so outlook will
just create another stream for you so if
you want to first this 5 format just be
aware of des des specificities because
otherwise you will just like hit the
parsers and and we it will just render
nothing so you will just lose your time
let's come now to view the objects so
from Haifa is research we know that it's
unfortunately possible to embed some
objects in an email for example des
objects if you follow the windows
variant types they can be a ver and they
can end a ver with 0 9 or 0 D so in
Outlook they all end with 0 so here
you've got this property which I forgot
something
37 Oh 100 D which means that you've got
an substrate an object and some subs
subs over sub storages or over streams
in it and this is interesting in this
research because when you are dealing
with all the objects you are dealing
with all the functions that are in 32 so
I appreciate that you don't have the
symbols for office but you do have those
for Windows and if you're curious you
can just put your breakpoints on the
usual suspects essentially here read
message class or you open storage or
even or loader and
if you do that you realize quickly that
we are I think three plus IDs that are
under the differently in Outlook first
ones are for samhita files I think one
is for a bitmap pictures and the last
one is for the only standard ink now you
see where I'm going back I think two
years ago we saw all these exploits
involving communica most of them were
just embedded in world documents or
Excel documents I don't believe that
anybody noticed that it was also
possible to trigger the same attacks in
Outlook unfortunately so the attacks
that I'm now going to show you our
coming from these disco monitors so just
if you look a bit at the code you'll see
that from early load once you've
modified the or v01 holy stream you are
able to hit this code all the ring
moniker stream which in Vienna
I just called Ali load from China if you
look at the documentation this is just
about reading an object from a stream
and instantiate it on the I persist
stream interface how would we explain
that wilt oh man I think was the first
one to report that behavior to us so two
years three years ago maybe he noticed
that if we use Outlook 97 or maybe out
loop 2000 it was possible to send an
email with a link to an object and in
that link you would specify a path on
remote share for example and he noticed
that if you do that when the victim
would open that email in his ultra
client then we were shocked you could
see some traffic going to that to that
web share and and then the IP address
along with for example Vientiane - would
be leaked and so she was worried buddies
and that was that was a legitimate
worried and then he figured out that if
you even have missing be variabilities
it was also possible to trigger it just
with it so
I'm talking about SMB client varieties
so his attack here was just usin you
sent an email and then this immolate is
going to just blue screen your your your
box that's annoying it's not on our C
but still it's annoying there is more
that you can do if the fine manager if
you have ever reversed it varies that
that that function that is called at
some point every store shall link so
what is that thing doing you know about
windows shortcuts it's actually possible
to embed dead to embed them in there's
five monitors and he'd say that we've
got a variety affecting windows
shortcuts and that still happen one was
predicted two days ago it's definitely
possible to trigger it in Outlook so is
it possible to load a remote library
with it like we saw with subnet I don't
know I haven't tried it but I'm assuming
that potentially it is just to say that
there are always things hidden here and
there that might be able to to to figure
on out I'm not going to talk about
another moniker V of drive one so I did
that research about three years ago yes
summer 2016 and at that time I didn't
know about viewer monikers like the new
moniker the human occurs like everything
that has been exploiting the 2017-2018 I
didn't know about that
but I'm glad I throw that one so what's
that one this one is just about on
marshalling objects that have been
marshaled with a trusted marshal how do
you exploit that how do you you know
that you can send an email and this
email we just unmarshal
a calm object but see how do you get cut
addiction from this so first step you're
going to call CO and motion interface
with something that has been that is
trusted so there is a list of trusted
markers not so many of them I think 15
so it's quite easy to loop to
and proton tray find some bugs so the
first component that I noticed was this
one affecting the vid control library
and this one was interesting because
when you look at the code so this is a
code that is triggered when you open a
stream and so you see there is a loop
that take a counter and then it's going
to take like calm objects from the
stream instantiate them and then
initialize them on VI persist rain in it
interface and that init interface is
important it's different that the normal
I persist REM in it that sorry is
different that normal I persist REM
interface if you've done some browser
research you know for example does that
flash starts with this interface so at
that point I know I had that I had an
email and I was able to trigger flash so
I could get a remote colleagues action
with flash and then so this was summer
2016 so I had been at my stuff for about
nine months and somebody told me Nick oh
so now you're at Microsoft you need to
leave flash alone and forget about it
varies enough for you to do at Microsoft
all right fair enough
so I had to find something else so there
are not that many that many controls
starting with VI persist a minute so I
just tried them all and I noticed that
for this one the XML feed moniker if you
were giving it some HTML it would just
load it unload the scripts that that
were in that were container so that's it
at that moment I had an email that was
able to instantiate some vbscript it was
not enough because I was still locked
inside VB I couldn't like for example
instantiate the file system object and
all right to files so I still have to
find something else I just used a vb0
because you know we are some
but more interestingly what was fixed
with this attack so first everything
that had to do with that that with that
vid control so this was a trusted
marshal and it was very very important
crucial that everything that was on
marshal with that library was Reseda
there were at least three series on this
do some research maybe you can find ours
hopefully not the examine filmmaker and
video giraffe I'm glad that I did that
research because then we added them to
the come activation filter in office so
now it's not possible to load s come
objects anymore
it might still be possible to load the
breath in video because I think there is
a one weird use case but that's that's
another story for of your applications
this is now done do not load all the
objects in the bank you don't put the
preview pane here I'm just talking about
the panes in Outlook in general because
when you get an email and you reply to
or you forward it then that's another
thing that is going to show up and so at
some point I had a case where it was
possible to get correction just by
eating reply to to that email so you
wouldn't get correction that the
wouldn't trigger when you were reading
teammate but if you reply to then yes
you would be on right it fixed another
vbscript bug yeah but more importantly
now it's not possible to lose vbscript
anymore at least on the recent branches
and then something something quite cool
and if we restrict objects loaded by the
diagnostic service and if you followed
that plantation so far you should be
like what is he talking about think
about that that attack is not only
affecting outlook it's affecting or
orals succumb objects in general or all
the objects that are marshaled
in Windows Windows is just about objects
sent from what application to another
and if you can
abuse there's a Marshall distrust reamer
sure then you can do crazy things with
this think about variant and safer eyes
safer eyes for example just an RA
continuing different type of variance
when you when you do when you're
creating your application and you're
using a cipher you don't specify the
type on the on the safer you can do some
check later but when you use a safe
right it can it's a generic RA it can
contain whatever so know so think about
a case where you would for example load
safe for I containing strings so you
would have your strings marshaled in
that safe array and then on the other
side so code would just see that very
some string in Safari and then unmarshal
everything so now think about what would
happen if you instead of giving strings
you'd give objects exactly the same
death subject would be answer as for you
and so so if you think about it and if
you can find an application that works
on RPC and that allows that supports
there's sa Fahr eyes you you've you've
you've already won for example think
about this one it's a diagnostic service
I didn't know about that service at
first I think I learned from it at Point
1016 that South Korean guy look he heart
he managed to exploit I think to us I at
that point or was it I don't remember he
managed to exploit it just by having his
own library loaded by a system service
and when you look at it right how am I
supposed to know that these things exist
it wasn't that figure I mean there were
some restrictions it wasn't possible
just to load the library they you needed
to bypass some checks but still that's
that's what he emerged and he managed to
do and usually it's not possible to do
anything with that service but I'm not
looking at
at things that I can do if that service
I was just looking for functions
exported by this service and there was
one to get drafted updates that was
exactly what I was looking for because
here this function takes in parameter
safer right and I think this was a safe
array of string yeah if you look if you
look at at the prototype you see contour
ideas be strings so here the God is just
waiting for strings but what happen if
you send objects instead one so could we
just unlock them for you and and once
you're in that function and it's
checking if you've already actually
provided some string
it's ready to light your objects have
already been marshaled I've got a demo
for you trying that so you just receive
an email and and then magic will happen
in your program you click it and then
stuff happens in the background and you
get on and then you system payload
there's a tax work and not just only
here for the purpose of that demo
they are quite for labor and I'm
definitely looking for them this is what
I call a dragon by the way so that's it
for outlook are now going to talk about
exchange so what I found difficult these
days when I start a new project
basically when I want to attack product
is how do I do that what what was
previously done how can I get some IDs
from what was previously done can I get
some inspiration
because usually I just don't know the
target and so for exchange
when I looked at it I just I just looked
at what had been done before and
unfortunately via was not much there was
that exploits that we saw from the
shadow brokers we exploit called
Englishman dentist what was it about
this was about sending an email to
exchange 2003 on Windows Server 2003 and
then when you would view that email in
Outlook Web Apps it would reach a point
where you could you quit them download
what you could force a cut on the server
to download a picture included in in Mac
format and then there was a stack
overflow issue with the library parsing
it and then you would get a codec
solution there but this is exchange 2003
on Windows 2003 how can I get this
attack to work on exchange 2019 for
example another issue that was
interesting so this was submitted to us
by by CDI so it's not as it's not really
about emails but it's more about you
already have a control of on on a box
and you leave a voicemail and you you
play with the map you properties and
then you will get a deserialization and
it will just unmarshal
some code for you and then you get our
see on the server that's not exactly
what I'm what I'm looking after but when
you look at what has been done before in
the past for exchange this is this is
what you'll see
so definitely not much so also think
about the scenarios what are we looking
for how are we attacking that are we I
will note unstated
or do we already have some creds on the
system what sort of attack are we trying
to do are we trying XSS is inoue are we
trying memory corruptions think also
that no these days exchange is
essentially a dotnet application is it
rare dot and application look at the
components they are fairies that 1x RPC
32 I'll come back to it in a second
but some Taurus is unsure for this
research and the VIP this one is just
about opening your box your inbox and
looking at all the emails all the
objects that are in that himmel's and
the amount of things that you can do if
that this tool is just huge you can one
thing that that I really like that you
could you were able to drop literally
everything
drop it in a gif format and then that
would give you some ugly properties that
outlook was unable to generate for
example and I found some bugs just by
replaying this might be properties in
emails and this was this was this was
really cool if you do some research like
this bear that in mind because there are
things here that are aware of it except
easy no so as I said exchange is mostly
just dotnet a huge dotnet application
but there are still a couple of binary
binaries here and there that that are
coding in C or C++ X RPC is one of them
when I looked at it initially I well
I've got the source code so I first
looked at the source code and then I
started either also just to have an idea
of what was going on and I noticed some
functions that were directly working on
the map the properties taken from an
email is where some bug left here let's
see so we got for example this easy
parse and three ID function you see that
there's if you look at it in Ida you see
that there's a huge function which
dispatches to over function depending on
the multi properties and usually you've
got some code that ensured that the
magic property you've submitted is of a
valid type so for example here either a
string or a Unicode string but there
were two cases where these checks were
not done this one for example so here we
would just this function we're supposed
to take a bite all right but you could
instead submit anything like for example
a float so what would happen here is
just another difference in the delivery
process can you exploit that probably
not because of the way variants are
I'm Kareem on 64-bit it was probably
just those at work but at worst but I'd
love to be proven wrong here so if
you've got some times and want to do
some research
have a look at it it's interesting if it
was that over case he made filler from
from eighth year so when I looked at
this function I didn't see the check at
first checked for four sue properties
which is the type of property it turns
out that check is not done above in the
current function but it's done in that
function itself so there was no
possibility for a tight confident here
but then I looked at the car and I
noticed that with either not looking at
the source code it was possible at some
point to write a bit too visa before
that was submitted to buffer that came
from that email so in particle
conditions it was possible just to go
out of the bound by one bit that sounds
cool that's typically the kind of issue
that you'd be able to exploit in a
browser so how much time yeah probably
to two minutes left so what do you think
I did something crazy right I did
nothing
it was too hard I think I spent about
two weeks there trying to figure out a
way to exploit that I couldn't find
anything essentially because of the way
the hip works in in.net
and in the Indies this application is it
possible to exploit it
adopt it but again feel free to do some
research and prove me wrong I won't know
to mention quickly something else so I
so there was a bug that was fixed about
three months ago
in exchange and some people on Twitter
asked me what it was about I told them I
will talk about that later I'm talking
about it no think about oh no because I
haven't talked about that of his web
apps so that's a that's a client that's
supposed to run it in your web server in
your browser so they are obviously
functionalities features that are not
available there but some of them
are still available and Fraser refused
and an RTF email containing objects desi
audio objects this audio object
obviously won't be rendered in your
browser but there still be things that
will be render like for example pictures
so say that you've got your Olli object
and then there is an image that is
encoded with the sorry objects and
something there on that server must be
extracting that that that picture for
you so I looked a bit at the code and so
everything is done in early 32 so it's
got the symbols so you can look at it
and it turns out that various picture
formats were accepted so usually wmf but
it was also possible to specify an EMS
picture and when I saw that a figure
this this must be valid because there
are so many things that you can do with
vmf and so this was exactly what this
Advisory was about do not load EMF
pictures on the server side so I got one
last demo for you where I'm just sending
an email and then my victim
just open it in a while and then that
will just blue screen the extreme server
you like it right
I liked it too so to conclude just a few
few things about that research I didn't
manage to get codec section an exchange
alpha although I tried I tried things I
was unsuccessful I want you to get
something authenticated I found some
verbs where that were more interesting
but you needed to be authenticated I do
not try to exploit them unfortunately
for those that I found I don't believe
they are exploitable
but what can you guys found that's what
I'm interested in it is him
some references if you want to check
that the slides are online and and thank
you or thank you for it
you
[Applause]