good deal thanks for coming out
appreciate it
this talk is actually part of the mental
health hackers village so if you haven't
had chance go up to the second floor say
hello to them effectively I want to talk
today about some strategies for having a
good career having a good life and that
we talk a lot about that right oh I'm
burned out I'm not feeling good okay
good well cute you know exercise drinks
of water you're fine but what happens if
you continue to burn out what happens if
you've got a career a little bit longer
than most how can you survive and make
sure that you're headed in the right
direction those are some of the things I
won't explore today as already mentioned
my name is wolf Gorelick I am an adviser
EC so with dual and a lot of this comes
out of some of the work I've done in the
community I've co-founded the converged
conference out in the States I ran in
the besides Detroit for many many years
this was the first year I didn't run it
it felt really weird I kept trying to
tell people what to do and realizing I
could just relax
it was great start a couple different
communities like the OWASP chapter CSA
we'd try to chapter that behind the my
set group and this is one of the things
I'm really proud of a very grainy photo
of me with some of my first folks in the
thing called CBI Academy for four years
I ran an apprenticeship program - your
apprenticeship program for junior
analyst people just getting in and
there's a lot of fun we put 67 people
through that program so I can watch 67
very different very unique people
struggle and figure out how to find
their way how to find their path and how
to get a good career going and I'm
really proud of some of the people who
came out of this - because now they're
senior level people security officers
one of them is an insurance agency very
good group and gave me a lot of exposure
to what it takes to do a good career so
I'm gonna talk today about some of the
strategies for mental health I'm gonna
talk today about how to put it together
I'm gonna end up with a proposal for a
career owner's manual right what are
some of the things you should do weekly
monthly quarterly annually on a decade
basis I think that's decade lis I'm not
sure to make sure that you've got a good
current things are going well
so first off master the basics master
the basics and where I want to start
with that is what is it we actually do
what is that we do in cybersecurity I
got into this field when the movie
hackers came out if you guys remember
that movie probably love that movie I
saw it in the theaters shortly
thereafter I had a data center I tried
to skateboard it across the dish like
the plague fun fact that is not a good
idea to do
you've got raised floors and lips that's
my excuse not the fact I'm absolutely
terrible a skateboard but do you know
that idea of like hacking the Gibson and
everything really got me excited and I
think fundamentally what we do is we
sing to computers right we sing the song
that computers understand we're
responsible for making sure these
machines work and operate and do
whatever organizations need to do and
just keep the bad guys out if we're on
the blue team if you're on the red team
you sing like I don't know death metal
the computers and they break down
interpret that as you will I'm a blue
team kind of guy of course to sing the
song to the computers we have to have
good mental health we have to be sharp
we have to know what we're doing we have
to know the commands that need to be
entered we have to know the syntax we
have to know the connectivity we have to
know the ins and outs of how to secure
them we have to know how to put data
into the cloud and everywhere else so
things don't break down we have to know
to secure s3 buckets please secure your
s3 buckets and to disable authentication
protocols and as your please secure your
authentication points on Azure those
other things right we need to know a lot
and so a lot of it focuses in on I think
these two things are we seeing to the
computer in the right key and do we have
the right amount of mental health to
pull this thing off but behind all of
the course and some of the things we
oftentimes don't think about is our
physicality are we are we physically fit
do we have the right state of body state
of health to actually go ahead and run
things in our in our world and so much
of it is focused on that mental health
so much is like wow if you just were
you know calmer if you just had the
right meds if you just did but so much
of it I think overlooks that physicality
peace are you in a good physical state
are you rested are you fed have you gone
ahead and done some exercise and trying
to fit all those things in together and
have that full context so that we can
sing with machines so does it mean to
sing to the machines right part of it is
obviously knowing what we're doing and
when we don't know what we're doing you
got that whole impostor syndrome I'll
talk more about impostor syndrome in a
little bit but having a good fundamental
grasp of what it takes to do the job and
so many great ways to do that 44 con
obviously is one way so many good
conferences some good events books
podcasts it's just a wealth of
information today out today when I was
first getting into this you know I I was
on the BBS's so if you guys remember the
BBS and they were fantastic you get on
there and everyone tell you you're
terrible and stupid you don't know what
you're doing and you'd ask one question
and they would all dogpile you but
there'd be this one person go yeah but
wait a minute here's a doc and how to do
it yes I know and the log often change a
user name and you'd be like I know all
the things and someone asks the same
question like you're an idiot
and then you ask your questions quietly
and get dog powder and you change your
eyes like seven different usernames
after a couple years it was crazy but
then it was all about trying to find the
information today what's fascinating to
me is this about trying to make sure you
get the right information it's really
fascinating about how we went almost
full circle if only I had access to all
the information I could do my job and so
you're trying Google and search and you
end up at no library doing the Dewey
Decimal System and reading left to right
and this is real old days people but now
I looked at some of my Millennials of
those coaching and it was the exact same
thing I don't know where he get the
information I'm like Google they're like
why did Google it and I got 10,000 page
results so which one do I follow like I
don't know ask somebody he's the current
who do I ask we kind of come full circle
in terms of not it used to be we had
this information dearth now we are
information wealth when we had
information dearth we'd have to talk to
people now we have information wealth so
we have to talk to people to figure out
what to do
so to sing to the machines first off we
need to have a really
community and of course they have good
mental health something we talked about
all the time here in the villages and
everything else are you in a good mental
state do you have a good mental attitude
a lot of us don't a lot of a struggle
this is a hard job it really is I mean
you look at everything we have to do are
we doing the right thing I don't know
are we appreciated I don't know do we
have budget no do we have enough people
no and so to kind of overcome that
negativity can be a very difficult
challenge especially again if you look
at online not the BBS's but now Twitter
I posted something on Twitter the other
day and and it went like so many of my
tweets and actually it was kind of funny
because I posted it on Facebook and I
posted on Twitter so on Facebook
everyone's like you know like up like
emoji there's so much that I'm Twitter
they're like well yeah but and let me
explain that to you it's like it's sort
like this it's like I made spaghetti on
Facebook people are like we love
spaghetti you're awesome
on Twitter it's like I made spaghetti
people are like well why did you do that
because I was hungry did you buy box no
do you know what the does the
environment to buy box noodles I mean I
could just have made my own those yeah
you should have maybe it's true that
kind of like everyone whatever you do is
wrong or if you made your own do this
like well really isn't a cultural
appropriation that makes spaghetti
Wolfgang you're German come on so we've
got this kind of culture that's went
from IRC to seeming to be nice and now
suddenly brought out as sort of bad
habits back to Twitter where we dog out
on people
very frustrating so we need a good
community and we need to be supportive
of those in our community on the
physical side we need to have good
attention on our on ourselves you know
the the idea of hackers and body hacking
has really come about in past couple
years and I love it I know myself if I
go to the gym and the day I in the
morning I feel better all day if I skip
it I feel terrible I've been traveling a
lot and I know some of you can travel
all the time hit the gym I can't I
forget I'm tired I'm grouchy I'm not
hitting the gym in the morning and then
it's like three weeks go by I'm like
I feel terrible I got to hit the gym on
Thursday with a good friend of mine and
my lift was down he's giving me shit
he's like well you know if you would hit
it every day I'm like I know I know just
spot me I'm sure I can lift this
actually but does not only have to be
absolutely weightlifting it could be
cardio could be any number of things I
think one thing we tend to forget is and
singing the Machine and focusing in our
brain the absolute importance it is of
realizing that we are animals right
we're we're highly functional cavemen
and we need to go out for a walk we need
to go run down a mammoth we need to do
something exciting your heart pumping
and handle all those chemicals in our
body so what do we need to do for the
basics we need to have a good balance of
everything we need to make sure on a
regular basis we're getting a balance of
our basic needs right sleep and water
food obviously good food I love my not
so good food but keep you some balance
and that exercise already mentioned sex
is a good one I'm married into a sex
therapist she's like you got to talk
more about the sex like no one wants to
hear about the sex she was yeah but you
got to talk about I'm like I'm not gonna
get in stage you talk about the sex so
if anyone sees her tell her I did but
your amount of sex is up to you guys the
important thing is is that each one of
these things is so vital and so critical
and when you skip them we really quickly
run into a hard state right we really
run into a situation where we're like
everything sucks and I hate everybody
and I'm gonna yell at someone about
spaghetti on Twitter it's it's one of
those situations where you gotta
maintain those basics so as I was
lifting and I was telling my friend
about this talk he's like you need to
have a slide that says hypocrite and
like wow you're right he's like no you
don't need to I'm like no I'm going to
because as I was putting together this
deck and thinking about these things
when I opened up PowerPoint I went okay
where's my abstract and I and I had been
traveling a bit I've been writing a bit
I had this thing about two months ago
where I was like I'm sick of all the
talks I give all the time so I know what
I'll do I'm going to submit new talks
and then they all got accepted and now I
got to write six new deck
for this month and I'm like ah can I
just recycle something so I could find
my abstract for this and I'm like here
I'm gonna be talking about mental health
and the importance of not burning out
and the importance of getting enough
sleep when I haven't got enough sleep I
took a red-eye flight I drew up to
Toronto I'm trying to put together this
deck in the hotel room at the last
minute and so I actually emailed the 44
kind of folks like hi funny irony I'm
speaking about burnout I don't remember
what I told you guys I was gonna say it
happens to the best of us right it
really does and I think the the key
thing that I tell a lot of the junior
folks that I manage is you've got to
realize that this is part of the gig
we're gonna rise we're gonna challenge
the the situation we're going to fight
off the criminals we're gonna stand on
the hill and survey the damage of the
red team that's tried to climb our Hill
hopefully we're gonna stand on the
parapets and as they put up the ladder
kick them down and go ha I patched that
server before you got there but we're
gonna do these things in the blue team
and I'm the red team of course we're
gonna break it and we're gonna find new
challenges we're gonna do all this stuff
and then two weeks later we're gonna
have not slept for a while right a month
goes by we're gonna be eating like
terrible and not exercising and we're
gonna burn out and it's so vitally
important I feel in this community in
this industry that when we burn out we
have compassion for ourselves that we
understand that it happens that we build
time in over the duration of our year of
our decade of our career to have that
burnout to have that moment where we can
just sit back and go okay I do this
myself I know what I did be reflective
and figure out what got me into the
situation email the 44 count or ghen
eyes errs in hope that they'll
graciously give me a math track up or
whatever it is in your field it's gonna
happen and we got to be sure that we're
ready for it and they were compassionate
with ourselves all right let's talk a
little bit about potholes and chipped
windows common things that go wrong so
just to recap we sing to the computers
and when we sing to the computer
that of course requires us to know
things right so what we do we drink can
we know things that's the cybersecurity
community if you don't drink I'm sorry
that's not indicate that you should
drink if this was Twitter there'd be 16
people tweeting me right now saying but
we don't drink and you need to be more
supportive people don't drink I don't
care what you drink drink water for all
I care but the point is we know things
this is what we do this is our value our
values to come in and apply creative
unique solutions one part of that is
especially if you're transitioning from
one career to another or starting your
career is to recognize you don't need to
go ahead and recreate everything right
away I love the way that painters
learned to paint I dated an artist once
she was fantastic until she drove me
nuts but it was fan fantastic watching
how she learned she would go to school
and they'd be like we're gonna learn how
to paint landscapes and they're b16
landscapes and she'd pick one and she'd
meticulously copy it and then she
meticulously you know paint a paint a
portrait and paint a bowl of fruit or
whatever may be and she Kathy and she
Kathy and she copy until she went from
copying the overall composition to
figuring out what techniques work to
create that composition to copying the
individual pieces to putting those
pieces together in a new way
to creating new pieces of art and new
compositions if you were to do that in
cybersecurity a lot of people say wait a
minute stop you're copying what someone
else did your recurring someone else's
work I think it's paramount as we
develop our skills to be able to sit
back know you know what I'm gonna not be
innovative for six months I'm going to
reproduce some people's work so I can
understand it I saw a great talk at 40
for Kahn I'm gonna build that in my lab
I love the CTF I'm gonna follow the CTF
how-to and I'm gonna recreate the steps
that they did those sort of things so
that you can begin to build those skills
and then duplicate them and get better
and better I was doing I was really into
CTFs like ten years ago now probably
five ten years ago and I built this
framework called the torii well if the
torii was was a bunch of ways of doing
simple things like all the different CTF
trucks right pulling things out of a
pcap doing basic decryption Caesars
shift and all that sort of stuff and
what I would do is I would take a
challenge every week and I try for XM on
time to figure it out once I couldn't
figure it out these challenges are in
CTF time by the way if you want to do
this I take the challenge do it for a
week if I couldn't figure out I pull
down the lesson learned and I'd
reproduce what they did and then I build
a script and build my own tool for it so
that when I got to the CTF side a whole
toolbox where I could just go oh that
reminds me with this that Ramones do
that no I think I saw that on this other
CTF and go ahead and do it it was a lot
of fun I learned a ton doing that and I
think that type of approach can be very
very valuable especially when you're
starting out or especially when you're
switching jobs it's this concept of
practice practice makes excellence right
welcome Gladwell popularized it as the
10,000 hour rule you need 10,000 hours
to be great at anything I really hope
that's not the case because I think the
average tenure of seaso is like 18
months right now so no one's ever gonna
be great at being a seesaw
and we all jump around jobs every couple
of few years and the industry's changing
I don't know there's 10,000 hours but I
do think it is a matter of having
consistent discipline to practice and go
ahead and build those skills and then
also knowing how to forget things I got
kind of sad the other day because it was
like the top 20 like dead and dying IT
skills and I always pull this up cuz I
gotta read them I'm terrible
so I pulled up I'm like yet made money
off that yet made money off that yep
used to love doing that yep yep yep yep
um they're all dead
because the minute we know something
it's dead right our skills keep
advancing our industry keeps advancing
and that's one of the things that makes
it fun so one anything we learn is gonna
have a finite lifespan we just need to
deal with that and to anything we learn
is gonna be bound by our memory there's
this idea of a six-week half-life of
memory whatever I tell you today six
weeks half of it you might remember
really fascinating when you think about
it in terms of your work your job your
skillset if I'm doing it something every
single day I'm gonna remember it no
problem I take six weeks off I'm
forget half of it if I take a quarter
off or a year off I'm gonna be so rusty
it's not even funny
and that's really exciting for me as an
IT guy because I'm like I know Active
Directory and someone's like here fix
this problem I like that's not Server
what's this PowerShell and however of
course a career that can get really hard
right it's like we're constantly
reinventing ourselves every six weeks so
what are some of the things we face some
of the things that ships that may occur
in our windshield obviously all the
normal stuff being disorganized will hit
us having trouble prioritizing will hit
us not having good time management will
hit us I mentioned I was putting this
back together just a couple weeks ago
and I was so finishing it up last night
and my wife's like you always put things
off and I don't rush me woman I'm
waiting to the last minute on purpose
that's what I'm the best right when
you're the best
well torso is that but there's two parts
to that one obviously please don't wait
the last one I hate when I husband that
did all these drugs down the other part
of it is so what I think often times we
beat ourselves up because we're like oh
I read this article where super hacker X
is up every morning at 4 a.m. and hits
the gym and then reads 2 books and then
writes his blog article and then
recompiles a colonel and sends a patch
in and then hits the office at 9:00 I'm
like holy hell it's ten o'clock I'm just
getting out of bed
what what is going on again I think we
need to be compassionate with ourselves
ultimately a good career owner's manual
is very personal for you because you
need to know when you're strong and when
you're weak I used to do a survey every
day and it was just interesting me I
would ask myself like 6 different
performance questions I was trying to
spot some trends in data and after a
while I realized it's like I have two
really awesome weeks I'm like yeah top
of the world I can do anything I will
volunteer for anything I would even sign
up for ten new talks in one month and
then two months for two weeks so I'm
like I'm doing it I'm doing I'm doing it
in two weeks or I'm dead like my
performance just boom dead cuz I had
needed that time right and once I
realized that I started building my
schedule a lot more intelligently
so I'd have like more quiet weeks on my
down weeks knowing that on basis and
pulse productivity pulse of yourself to
really help you handle those sort of
things a lot of it will come back down
to like ADHD right people I call I've
got ADHD I had a guy one of my Academy
people early days early it is in the
kateri because my second team and he
comes in he's all nervous is that can I
talk to him I can't close the door
closes the door my office sits down is
that guy I don't know how to tell you
this I'm like what would what is it how
can I help you
it's like well I went to the doctor I'm
thinking the guy is like cancer or
something right though he's acting like
this is it he's done he's gonna tell me
he's got like resigned and we got to
figure out healthcare in this United
States people so health care is a big
deal this is bad and funny he's like the
doctor tells me I have ADHD and as a
manager that was my moment to be
compassionate as me I started laughing
I'm good he's like what do you mean good
I'm like you got a doctor's note to be
on my team bro you're in the right spot
because we all have hdhd or we all have
some problem with this right if we could
handle normal work and normal jobs we
wouldn't have gotten into computer
security where everything's crazy that's
why we're here but it's knowing where
our highs and lows are that allows us to
build the shock absorbers into our
career into our schedule that allows us
to succeed next thing I want to talk
about real quick is imposter syndrome
this is my favorite graph for imposter
syndrome I'd always give this to Mike
Adam II people like here's what you
think they know because you went to a
conference and they're brilliant and
here's what it really looks like because
they know a little of this and you know
that and they're faking a whole bunch of
other stuff and everything works
imposter syndrome is something that we
also all face right everyone gets
impostor syndrome it's just a nature of
of our career no matter how good I've
gotten no matter how high in the ranks
I've been I've always looked across to
my pyramid man here
good how are they holding it together
that guy's got a budget and everything I
got a spreadsheet he's over there go man
I got my budget but how come he's got a
business case because I know PowerPoint
this is one of those things right no
matter how high you get and I say
everyone's do does imposter syndrome but
don't get imposter syndrome if you don't
have imposter syndrome that's the other
side of it but I don't have good enough
imposter syndrome maybe I'm not in the
right field it's just the nature of our
of our industry and I think it's it's
good it is a indicator to me that when
you don't have imposter syndrome that
maybe you're in the wrong room so one of
those things like you don't want to be
the smartest person in the room right
you want to get to the room where other
smart people are if you feel like you
really belong maybe it's time to start
looking for a new gig and also too
sometimes you are the imposter
that's the other thing right and posture
syndrome is a syndrome when you think
you're the impostor I was speaking at a
conference and I landed and they picked
us up from the airport and here's like
the guy who invented a power show here's
like the guy who invented Ruby there's
the guy up front who does a magazine for
PHP and does it one of the major user
groups of Catholics is for it to people
on the on the side of me are arguing
about what it's like is it hard to do
your second O'Reilly book or your third
O'Reilly book and I'm like I don't I
didn't invent anything I'm not writing a
book right now but what am I doing here
and so we're at the speaker party I'm
hanging out with the guy who was doing
the track is a wasup track and I'm
hanging out with the chart guy was doing
the track and my story was about this
time that a bunch of hackers built the
CTF platform and one of my guys was a
secure web coder another guy was a pen
tester we hadn't followed SDL seals
great it was brilliant and went live and
we're hacked within 24 hours and how we
learn lessons from that and how you can
apply it to death
so that was my whole story the whole
story is just like this cute funny thing
that happened on the way to Chicago you
know it's not like I'm carrying cancer
and oh I just invented Ruby so I asked
the guy many bottles of wine into the
evening I'm like why am i year why am I
here and he had a little bit of a French
accent and I'm not gonna not gonna try
but there's something well you know wolf
I don't know you and no one knows you
okay this is a good start it goes but
you did something will throw wasp and
you have lots of followers on Twitter
like ah okay so I really am an imposter
it's great I felt such a relief at that
moment I'm like good son syndrome when
you do feel like that it was really
awesome to me because I don't like okay
there's someone I started to be there
someone is where to be there's someone I
swear to be worth the gap between where
I'm at were there and how am I going to
close that gap it's a much better
conversation to have than me going
should I belong in this room I don't
know if I belong in this room do it will
they find out if I don't blow in like no
I don't belong hi they chose me because
of my Twitter follower account which
really isn't an impressive this is like
the worst vanity metric ever but I'm
gonna talk really relieving when you
actually have imposters not had just
assumed so some lessons here one is
embraced the stress short term stress is
really good for growth right it's the
long term we need to worry about I'll
get back to that but I think
fundamentally we need to get comfortable
being uncomfortable in in this industry
in this career as we're mentoring people
I would oftentimes bring folks in my
favorite story is of a waitress before
she joined us here as a waitress and so
she 'its degree she joined my team and
within two years she left to lead
compliance for one of the top five
credit unions in my home state in the
United States and what was phenomenal
about her is she was always
uncomfortable like you know the Hulk and
the Avengers were like my secret is I'm
always angry you know that moment that
was her she's like no I focused anxiety
I'm like what are you talking about
she's like I'm always anxious you're
always asking me to do this crazy stuff
I always think we can't do it right up
into the day we do it and then the
customer is happy and then I take a
breath and damn it wolf you asked me to
do it again like you know that's true
okay it's good all right focus that
anxiety keep going and she use that to
really propel her career forward I think
it's so important we get comfortable
being uncomfortable while back there is
a earth-2 program you guys probably
heard that a biome they've tried to
build a biome to simulate what it'd be
like to go to Mars they planted a whole
bunch of trees and they find these trees
in this biome and the trees kept falling
over like
how wide our tree ski falling over
there's no reason for these trees to
fall over they're native to this area
everything should work fine why did they
keep falling over they dug into it and
what happened was dug into it like
literally they looked at the root
structure and because there was not
enough wind and stress in the tree it
was not developing deep enough root
system and therefore absence distress it
couldn't stand up on its own and I think
that's a great metaphor for a lot of
what we go through short term stress is
awesome focuses us gives us adrenaline
gives us excitement makes this career
all worthwhile
and allows us to build deeper roots so
fundamentally fundamentally right we
need to concern ourselves I think as
elite athletes we need to consider
ourselves as mental athletes folks who
sing the computers folks who push
ourselves train regularly handle stress
like an athlete and and are
compassionate with ourselves when we're
down and getting our butts whipped and
compassionate with those in the
community and do so in a way that
continues to push forward the art and
science that is cybersecurity all right
let's talk a little bit about some
traffic problems things you might run
into again we seem to the computers how
do we seem to the computers no longer
alone we seem to the computers and teams
right and teams have a lot of different
things they've culture they have rhythm
they've cadance they have shared values
have personalities they have egos I
recently joined a group and the CEO
reached out to me he's like thank you so
much for joining our group we got a lot
of big personalities here a lot of big
egos I'm glad there's room for yours
I'm like you don't know how big my ego
is bro no it's true though even in our
industry we can kind of have quite a big
ego so part of being in cybersecurity is
to ask yourself you know is the team
positioning us in the right way Steve
Jobs once had this awesome comparison
for their early Macintosh's and he
called it - you know the bicycle because
his point was
you plotted out the speed of all mammals
humans were really really low compared
to everything else she does ostriches
everything and but he put a man on a
bicycle you give him a mechanical
advantage something he's off like a
rocket and so his idea was the computer
should be like a bicycle for man's
intellect I like that analogy I like
that analogy but today almost everything
we do because of the growing
specialization cybersecurity is a team
sport so not only do we need the
mechanics and the advantage of
tool-making we also need that team
working that team to support us that
sense a friendship that sense a
connection right
that feeling of fam there is this really
cool thing mentally this in-group bias
it's a it's a cognitive trick whatever
your in-group is you love them if you
think about some great teams you've been
on I'm like I would die for you bro I
was at a data center and we lost a
generator and that should've been a bad
problem but the transfer switch didn't
work and that might not have been a bad
problem but the UPS was wired
incorrectly and those three things when
we blew out UPS's threw out like every
through cabinet and for the next six
weeks it was living hell because I was
very highly redundant which was great
but that meant like a firewall seemed
fine but then it would fail and a
failover did another one and we're like
okay we hope that one's good
we get the other one in place and then
flipped back were no notices
I just twelve node email cluster we lost
seven of the nodes it was a brutal six
weeks and towards the end of it as we're
rebuilding it I had in my office a cot
and I was taking a nap in the cot and I
got off off the cot because of right
around the time it said alarm because
some files are moving the files should
have been completed by then and I got up
cuz alarm went off I got a cup of coffee
and looked around I had one guy sleeping
on a beanbag at another guy on his
computer just like this I don't know if
he's alive or dead and I'm like I would
I would go to the mat for these people
right now right I felt so close these
people I'm like these are these are my
brothers in arms
and that is a great feeling when you're
in a team and you face down the mammoth
and you triumph it is just a phenomenal
feeling and I hope we all have that
feeling sometimes when you're facing
down the mammoth and someone trips you
because maybe the mammals will step on
you and not them that's such a good
feeling when you're gonna team where
they're not supporting you not such a
good time well you've got a leader whose
values don't match yours not good at all
so fundamentally we got to look at four
different valves I believe we got to
make sure that our culture fix fits the
company culture we oftentimes become the
average of the people we spend time with
so are we happy with the people in this
organization if we become more like them
are we gonna be feel good about
ourselves or we're gonna feel like we
need a shower you know what I mean our
value is reflected in theirs this is one
I always always ask myself right before
I leave a company are my values
reflected and do I feel good looking at
myself in the mirror every morning
because of what I'm doing at this
company or do I feel like I'm
compromising myself my friendships my
integrity are the tasks good do we like
the songs we get to sing and this is a
diversity good I mentioned earlier my
brother-in-arms because they're all like
middle-aged white guys and we loved it
but as I built more teams and had more
exposure I'm like man that was not a
very diverse team and I love a good set
of diversity because it brings different
points of view different perspectives
and when I was building my Academy teams
I was always had an eye for that because
the conversations were much better much
richer I'm a very firm believer that
high performance teams are diverse teams
so these four things we need to make
sure all the time those inputs line up
with our direction who we want to be and
where we want to go and what's
interesting is lots of companies have
lots of different values and I honestly
don't even know that it matters one
culture over another one set of values
over another with with exceptions you
know if it's like oh come work for our
company and and our values are we're
gonna sell your blood no that's not a
good value but with some exceptions I
think what honestly matters is
that they become a tool for self
selection finding your group where you
really feel like you belong we can grow
where you can become the person you want
to be soft skills are hard right
everything is a soft skill fundamentally
we need to really work on building up
teamwork collaboration skills it's an
area that I focus in a ton on when I was
mentoring people it's an area that a lot
of us growing up didn't have to worry
about because that was the one-man show
when I was at a hospital running i.t
nights he's good for a hospital I was
pretty much it right I didn't my team
work was going hey wolf do you want
coffee I would love coffee and then I go
get coffee
you know it's great communication was
phenomenal we are really all on the same
page with me myself and I but you could
do that back in the day right as long as
you know how to network and write some
code and stand up some computers you
could do the whole show those days are
long long gone so part of it is building
up good teamwork and good collaboration
skills another thing is making sure we
are stronger together
we're not stronger together you got a
gtfo all right get the eff out however
you want to say it but the point is this
is a diagnostic tool do I feel in this
tribe that I belong here do I feel in
this tribe that I'm becoming a better
person do I feel this tribe maybe a
little bit of impostor syndrome it's
gonna push me forward and make me
stronger do I feel like I'm running with
a pack that's gonna help me become more
competitive if not we need to select a
different team all right let's talk a
little bit about Road feel right driving
value delivering some skills there's
always a risk of feeling disconnected if
you plugged in and you're feeling good
you're gonna get recognition right you
have sense of respect if since the
status around the work you do you're
proud of the work you do I think we've
all have had times in our careers we
then perform it what we thought was peak
value and our boss is like why did you
do that task it doesn't matter or
they're like oh yeah we really support
James over here because she is awesome
you know John well okay keep keep
patching servers like but I splashed
everything and we avoided what took down
Equifax and they're like yeah okay
that's that's lovely I'm glad he patched
a server I reported to a CFO one day and
I remember watching his office I was all
problem like because I just heard about
risk management and I'm like all right
as the security officer this is great
we're gonna take a risk-based approach
I'm gonna start doing risk management
and he looked at me
it's like wolf we trade in Wall Street
again entire floor phd's above you doing
risk management across stocks worldwide
what are you talking about like mental
note don't talk about risk management I
am talking about Security's like yeah
good just keep things running is
everything up okay good
this has been a great meeting we need to
make sure that we're actually plugged in
right we need to make sure too that
we're able to stand out from the crowd
and the fundamental question is is how
will you stand out and part of that is
finding the tasks that only you do well
I think if you look at people who are
top of their field they're doing
something that only they can do and
contribute value that only they have it
is very difficult to get to this point
but it's a matter of regularly asking
yourself am i doing something in this
team adding value that can be replaced
with any of my other teammates or am i
contributing unique value am i doing
something that only I can do because of
I'm wired for it because I love it
because I got the skills in it because I
got the background right because I know
my productivity pulsed it fits the way I
work or am I just like 70 other people
and trying to gauge that and make that
distinction is is a ongoing effort
there's a lot of tasks that need to be
done this is a C so mind map and was it
from Dow security and I used to use this
when I was doing CSO coaching I'm like
all right here you go here's what you
need to do it's all simple just do that
stuff and the guy you have no idea I
have no way to do all that stuff I
you can't do all that you don't have
time no I've got like 60 hours no week
maximum
alright let's step back and let's figure
out a different way to do this and one
of the things we talk about is how do we
take the tasks in this a to figure out
what tasks that as I'm talking about
Caesar what tasks the seaso is really
good at and they love so let's start
with the tasks you love I'm a big fan of
outsourcing boring if you don't love it
don't do it
delegate it figure someone else to
partner with those be what tasks on this
actually line up with what the team's
mission is and what the corporation's
mission is at my own position we used to
talk about this in terms of rocks you
guys are probably heard this analogy
right you put the sand in first and then
you put the rocks in then you can't fill
up the whole jar rocks being your big
priority so you put the rocks in first
and then you can fit more stuff in you
can get more tasks done it's great
sounds motivational it's exciting this
is the way that my old team used to do
it by Coralie rocks you may have
quarterly goals you may have quarterly
okay ours it doesn't matter in your
corporation there's someone who can say
here's the top five things my company is
doing right now you get awesome and then
go back and go okay based on those top
five things
what are these line up and how do these
things tell that story that we're
supporting those top five things or
three things or two things or whatever
maybe tying those threads between
overall matters to the corporation to
what we're doing and tagging those
threads to what we're really good at to
what we're doing allows you to create a
job description that's really distinct
and supports your unique advantages all
right so what ultimately we want to
build a team and build yourself so that
you're doing their tasks to support the
company goals support the team goals and
position you to have a better career in
the long term and to put it in a
different way we need to align your
values with your verbs right what does I
do what do I care about and how do those
things come together and how is that
positioned me to be different and unique
in the organization in the community and
to give back you one more sip of water
and get parched so we're gonna talk
about worn tires rebalance every 10,000
kilometers of course ISM a nod to tires
or if you don't rebalance your tires you
end up wearing
you end up wearing them out you know
causing problems for all you drive so
what are some of those things that would
build up over time and cause problems
one is I talked about embrace distress
but what about embrace to stop short
term stress is awesome this is exciting
we've got a deadline we got a big
production coming we got a big software
release coming we've got a compliance
out of coming I know a lot of you were
like a complaints I'm not that exciting
listen to me sorry I give anyone like
trigger warnings I should have given it
right before I said compliance but but
we got something coming we're going to
do it we're gonna do the thing we're
gonna get the team together we're gonna
make it happen it's exciting short term
stress is great long term stress is
killer long term stress is I think I
think and I'd posit why in cybersecurity
were not often strategic right we're
very much here's the thing we're fixing
here's this thing we're fixing right now
because this is what we can do right now
short term stress awesome long term
stress depletes us it focuses us to the
point of being unable to be creative it
focuses us to the point of on being
unable to learn short-term or long-term
stress is one of the things that often
times will someone over the long
duration of your career because you're
no longer able to absorb information
going back to that half-life of memory
six weeks
that means six weeks of I have stress I
haven't absorbed anything I'm already
starting to loose and fall further
behind people or more rested more able
learn and more able to ingest I told you
about the trees in the dome another
experiment was done the sixties all
really interesting psychological studies
were done in the 60s I'm sure that I say
that and my wife would tell me she's
she's a therapist he'll go
yeah because they didn't have like any
ethical rules back then I'm not sure but
they like gave college kids LSD and that
was a study and that was cool so yeah
then we go back and forth on this but
one of the says those done in the 60s
was done with cute little animals cute
little fuzzy animals they put them in a
warm space they put him gave him enough
water him enough food bedding lovely
little cute low animal and then they
stressed it out with strobing lights
that's all they did everything was fine
this animal should be
so okay this was stressed out with
sterling lights which would prevent it
from sleeping and leave it in a stress
State and they were actually able to
sicken weaken and in some cases kill
animals from just prolonged stress from
a light so what happens if we're in a
sock getting ticket after ticket after
ticket after ticket after ticket and
seeing on the big boards so-and-so
hacked so-and-so all saw hacked you're
not keeping up and seen the news feeds
from other pundits going well security
people clearly have their head in the
sand right that's our strobe light it's
terrible it's a long term stress can get
us we do not only embrace the stress
short term we need to embrace the stop
longer term all right it's okay to
become depleted over the course of the
day but if that is like your quarter
we're in a really bad spot but we didn't
know a how to put our phone in airplane
mode so that we don't run on the battery
and be what it is that ultimately
recharges us what is it that will charge
up ourselves our careers energize us and
get us back in the game
and see we need to know the warning
lights the things that are actually
causing us to during our batteries
here's some warning lights and some some
things that you should do physiological
effects
I gained a ton of weight before I burned
out I'm a little bit heavy at the moment
now don't think I mean I know I am you
can pick on me it's okay
but I came like I can't it's like 40
pounds in six months because I was in
this stress job and I was building this
sock no striving myself into the ground
right physiological effects like that
having to go the doctors all the time
stress related injuries those are things
we need to balance our lives or gtfo
non-competitive compensation they're not
paying us enough when you get a raise or
GTFO if you stay if as an industry if a
bunch of us continue to keep
non-competitive compensation our
employers of course are going to
continue to not pay us competitively
lack of training if the position you're
in doesn't provide training
opportunities downtown for training
budget for training those sort of things
you need to make either make your own
time by setting your schedule and
Oh seeing that with your leader and your
team or gtfo lack of a career path if
your career path does yeah I hope you
stay that's not a career path and that
may be because there isn't a career path
in your organization that's a
conversation with your leader or it may
be because your career path is
ultimately going to take you to another
organization so in which case you need
to level up and then GTFO poor teamwork
I mention this earlier if your team is
not supporting you if you don't gel with
your team if your team's not driving you
if you don't feel like your team is a
little bit better than you can you get
some training there's plenty of books
out there to work better with others I
think soft skills is an area where we
can all improve on and if you still do
that and you're still in problems gtfo
poor leadership maybe it's a matter of
motional intelligence maybe it's a
matter of dealing with your boss better
every time I have not liked my leader I
have left very quickly because they
define your tasks they define where
you're going I mean if you're not
getting along with you later
you either make it work or gtfo
similarly if there's no appreciation of
recognition for what you're doing if you
can't tie your tasks to what you're good
at and what only you can uniquely do and
tie those tasks to what the company is
rocks quarterly goals ok ours are and
what you're achieving then you're not
going to get that appreciation
recognition
either reset your expectations about
what your job is or gtfo misaligned
values I had a client and he came to me
and is like what are we doing this for
this isn't working
and I guess not working we need to pull
the plug say I have this other company
that can do the work I trust them
they're already in here I'm like yeah I
don't want to hurt your career I've
known you for 10 years you need to you
know work with this other company
alright glad we talked I went back to my
leadership and look look
values are we do what's right for the
customers right for the customers walk
away from the deal no no we can't do
that we do lose money
but we're entering this relationship we
can't deliver we don't have the people
we don't have the skills but we got to
make it work because we can't lose the
money okay all right good gtfo
all right fundamentally these are your
warning lights and I think it's very
important we look for these warning
lights regularly it's very easy as our
battery is dying to overlook them it's
very easy to take the teenager approach
to your car and say okay yeah I got a
warning late I'll just tape over it it's
cool I keep driving I didn't really do
my brakes I was doing consulting work I
didn't have much money and I literally
had tape over one of my warning lights
and my brakes went out in rush hour and
I had to drive home with the emergency
brake
short term stress is great I never again
ignored a warning light Wow is that
scary so you need to make sure you're
looking at those in taking care of it I
don't - need to protect yourself right
your greatest kurasov is you and only
you can know what works well for you how
you work and where you need to go and
you need to make sure you're taking care
of that over the longer term we're gonna
give you a couple tools for that and
then give you the career owner's guide
and we'll call it a day
so some tools one two three relax
recharge and relearn on the relaxed side
it's all about distressing taking care
of the basics I'm doing what is good for
you in a toolbox
I would oftentimes sit down with my
academy team and say alright how do you
relax what is working for you I learned
the term retail therapy from one of one
of the ladies who worked for me I'm like
I've never felt relaxed spending money
but that's if that works for you that's
awesome
I like massages I'm a big fan of massage
I get a massage every month every couple
weeks when things are very tight
meditation works obviously therapy works
if you're in therapy
I hear it's wonderful my wife's a
therapist she's very Pro therapy if that
works for you do that
taking down days I'm gonna come back to
this idea of down days in a minute and
then taking time away right making sure
you actually take that PTO in America
we're terrible at this I don't know
maybe you guys are much better at more
enlightened you can tell me after this
talk
but we oftentimes like God I didn't take
PTO for two years I am awesome okay how
are you doing I'm fine I'm fine
what's your risk appetite bourbon okay
so good um in hiking there's this
council called zero days and in hackers
there's this concept of zero there so
oftentimes I would say something like we
had this conversation on the cut I'd
take a zero day and I go okay
and then they remind the right guy right
so I need to write an exploit maybe if I
give it to Apple I get a million dollars
and that would definitely help my mental
health
hiking there's this idea that if you're
going to do a long-distance for example
the Appalachian Trail is about six-month
total hike have been hiking it in
section since I was 18 and you if you're
gonna go the long distance you need to
have a down day so you can recharge the
zero day is no miles on the trail zero
day is you know I went far enough enough
food in my pack and the water in my pack
I'm going to sit rest recharge and do it
again we need I believe to apply that to
InfoSec so that when we reach that peak
were like a day off would be really good
will help me recharge get my head back
in the aims and I can learn and handle
those problems we need to take those
zero days then on the charge side what
what energizes you hacker conferences I
love going to these things to come back
I got a million what ideas I can build
it on my lab will be great six weeks
later I'm a rack but it happens action
movies work for me too I love the
Mission Impossible movies they are
brainless but I put them on the plane
and I land that plane and I had the mi6
you know music and my earphones is a
walking off the planet I go yeah let's
do this like wolf it's a spreadsheet I'm
like yes but I'm gonna you know you go
on those things and then as we have this
this cadence also know how you can
relearn right was it take to get your
head in the game to do those sort of
things I did several years ago burn out
really hard
I built a sock I built a red team I
built a man service provider that was
doing monitoring and vulnerability
management and I built it all in a very
short period of time and about you
a half I was just ran myself into the
ground and actually took about three
months off it was great great anyone can
take three months off I get that but it
was so awesome because I wake up I'd hit
the gym I go swimming a ticket nap naps
are awesome Pro naps don't mean to brag
but I've great staying power for naps
I'm always up for a nap I go for a long
time but not in then I will go on hey
what's up my friends right so I I added
all these things in and then I would
study a little bit in the evening go to
bed and do it again and man after those
three months I was ready to take on the
world because I brought all these
elements together and recharge myself so
was this look as a owner's manual one
thing I keep talking about GTF alright
it beats coping because it frees you up
to do something that you can really
excel at something really fits you I'm
not suggesting we always quit but I am
suggesting that as an industry we need
to make sure that we draw a clear line
of what we will do and what we won't do
and hold that line both for our own
sanity our own growth as well as for
everyone else in this room because the
minute and organization is like I could
take care advantage of these people then
we all get brought down writes our gets
brought down all the flexibility we have
gets brought down but don't quit over
short-term issues right short-term is
good short-term is awesome it's not fun
it hurts it's scary but it builds
character it helps you grow it's the
longer-term that you need to work for so
it's balancing those two window I need
to do you know check my engine or window
I just need to add some oil and knowing
where to draw those lines and I think
fundamentally only you can draw the
lines for yourself what do you do or
longer-term so weakly the basics already
talked abouts eat well prepare for the
week ahead do the things do all the
things make sure there's time you're
scheduled to de-stress and make sure
this time your schedule somewhere in
there that pumps you up and energizes
you and then do a weekly review certain
ex Crump's or like agile do this friends
do cycles if you look at my calendar
it's like two days of meeting with
people because that energizes me two
days of doing deep work where I'm just
focusing and I'm doing the things and
then one day we're on like command I'm
toast I'm I'm
catching up an email expense reports are
a thing on a monthly basis you're doing
all those things but review the stress
keep track of it was a short-term
stressor or have I been now stressed for
two months what's going on
check your warning lights check for
those things and make sure you're noting
them when they happen and then schedule
your zero days what is what day and your
month or a couple days are you doing a
downtime where you're giving yourself a
breather to catch up on tasks the hiker
version of course not the hacker version
quarterly check your health make sure
you're still in good shape everything's
going well review your accomplishment
plan here's what I'm doing keep a break
journey Journal rather here's all
awesome things I've accomplished so that
you can review them with folks as needed
review your learning remember anything
that you learned this quarter if you're
not still plying you're gonna forget in
a few weeks so review your learning you
figure out what you're going to do and
ask yourself as your is your work being
recognized and are your values being
supported subvert of do you feel good
still are you excited or those are
things keeping up annually job reviews
we all have them but how often do we
review our employers I think it's so
vital we sit down with ourselves
definitely with a peer preferably with
the leader ideally and say okay how am I
feeling about this job where am I going
where's this taking me let me review the
company in the position if I had to
apply for this again would I fly for
right now does it support your long-term
career path where's the teamwork taking
you where does management leave you and
decade Lea I don't know routinely every
few years ask yourself where are you now
right when I was 25 years ago my career
goals were a lot different than they are
today and every few years I'm just
conscious stepping back knowing where
where should I go next where is the
market going where my passions going
what do I used to be really excited
about what do I not care about anymore I
could care less about writing code and I
think 20-year old me would not believe
that
so with that the point is make sure you
got the right tools new toolbox make
sure you're doing regular maintenance on
yourself and your career
I hope these I've given you some ideas
on how to go about doing those sort of
things fundamentally this is a fantastic
industry to be in it's a fantastic
community to be a part of I'm always
excited to do it
and yet I watched so many of us struggle
and burn out and deal with impostor
syndrome and deal with all these issues
so I hope I've given you some ideas and
on the handle them if not hit me up
afterwards or go see the 44 con mental
health hackers village up top thank you
very much
[Applause]
[Music]