okay I can't actually see any of you but
you'll believe me that I'm very happy to
be here again my name is guy I'll do it
proper introduction in a moment I just
want to say something about this deck
somewhat personal I usually when I give
talks I do a lot of technical talks like
exploitation artificial intelligence and
stuff like that and those are very
technical very math oriented talks
because this is my background however I
wanted to do this talk because of a
couple of conversations that I've had in
the past I don't know probably a year or
so about research teams and the place of
research teams in larger organizations
and I haven't touched anything ok so the
scope of this talk would be more of like
how does managing the research team
looks like in a bigger organization big
might be a relative word and if you are
a manager of such a team or you're
looking or thinking about how to manage
such a team I hope that some of those
Nuggets would be very helpful to you but
also if you're a security researcher and
one of those teams I think that this
talk can help you understand the way
that the management thinks about
research teams and where you can find
yourself the most variable the best
pivot for your own InfoSec security and
for your own information security career
so first of all hi I'm guy guy behind
Arkham again not expecting I want to
actually know how to spell it I talk a
lot I like it so I travel and I speak in
many different conferences I just came
back from Vegas where I gave two
technical talks one on Linux hardening
the other about how to accelerate
exploitation using machine learning and
today I'm going to talk more about
managing security research teams I've
been a security researcher for many many
years and have transitioned into
management roles about 10 years ago I've
been in medium sized organizations like
4500 people manages security teams but
also for
very large corporations the latest of in
Cisco and Intel so both are 70 K plus
people in the org so my perspective and
this has been from both sides of the
table but also from the way that you
scale up a very small research team and
also when you transition to a role where
there's the research team already exists
and how to actually drive the most from
that situation I'm very biased this is
my own experience I'm very happy to
share my own experience but it might be
different in other places
not everything translates well even here
in the UK versus Israel where I'm from
but also from the United States to other
places but try to listen to everything
they say with a grain of salt ask
questions and I'd be happy to share
whatever information do they have
security research teams there are so
many definitions so you might be a pen
tester you might be a model researcher
you might be a vulnerability or
exploiter you might be a threat hunter
all of those come into the same kind of
grouping called security research teams
some of them are more product focused
some of them are more service or
infrastructure focused some of them are
looking at how to break anything some of
them are looking how to break specific
things but in the end most of them have
very similar cultures very similar
methodologies to the way that they work
I'm not trying to differentiate or
disrespect any of those teams my
background is more in the lower part of
this list here has been a red teamer
I've mainly done a low-level
exploitation former level stuff as I
said I've worked at Intel but I've also
worked a lot with the teams that are on
the other side even on the blue side and
that brings me to something that's often
missing in many of the conversation and
really shapes the way that other people
in the org even other people in IT who
are partners look at research team and
that is that we often forget
that the blue team has to win finding
exploit is a lot of fun building the
exploit is cool you get a lot of creds
you get a CVE you get to speak at
conferences you really haven't moved the
needle for the organization by doing
that the only way that you move the
needle to organization is if you went
over and helped the blue team to defend
against this exploit against this kind
of attack and if you're unable to
mitigate this kind of attack you haven't
brought any real value to the
conversation
finding the issue is one thing fixing it
is something greatly different one of
the things that I was very adamant with
all of my teams over the years was that
finding the issue is only one thing but
then you have to work with the
developers you have to work with the
architects to make sure that they
understand the root cause and help them
fix the issue and then test that they
actually fix the issue it's not
necessarily the same thing and sometimes
this gets lost the gets lost in a
conversation with our mad dash to run
after the next kind of vulnerability the
next kind of a new piece of PR coming
out exploiting isn't everything moving
the needle is so one of the I want to
share an example here one of the themes
that I was leading was very product
focus and here we got into kind of a I
would say like a dad spot like a
problematic spot because to me to bring
value you want to be able to influence
the development of the product whatever
the product is in a timely manner to
actually actuate some effect and if
you're not doing that then you're have
it really made a change so on the one
hand you have to wait until the product
is ready for you to do some sort of
attack on it because if it's still being
written of it's not even alphabet up
ready you have nothing to work with
on the other hand if you're waiting
until you have something to work with
and you go to the development teams or
the architecture team seller look I
found like this list of issues so if
it's too late I'm already shipping this
version next week so finding that sweet
spot of working with those teams getting
them the information that they need in
order to influence their decisions to
change the way that they are building
the product is a very delicate balance
and you have to find a
to work together with those teams so
they will tell you when is the best time
to step in and work on their product and
it's a balancing act because you have
other jobs to do as well but if you're
not going to hit that timing right you
will not be able to move the needle you
will not make an effect different teams
have different focus and you have to
take that in mind when you're talking to
those teams if you're talking with a
blue team IT team that really wants to
protect the organization against threat
it's a completely different conversation
with them working with red team's that
are trying to find each and any and a
method available to any outside attacker
in order to access the assets or affect
the way that the product is working
those are different mindset different
philosophies and that means that when
you're building your approach when
you're trying to get them on your on
your team and influence the way that
they are working you have to take
different approaches and I will discuss
some of them later being a manager I'm
going to skim over this slides because I
think they're somewhat generic but I
have been on teams where they actually
didn't know this a manager most the core
of the responsibility of the manager is
to define the mission is to say to the
team what are we going to do what are we
working on is just not handing out tasks
but actually time the vision together
that everybody is working and pulling
together in the right direction it's not
so easy for research teams when
everybody's working on the product and
you have I don't know a JIRA or
something similar to that or an agile
process and everybody's working on their
user stories it's very visible that if
you are working on something that's
toward the product or not if you're
working on a research team and you have
to team members working on something and
another working on a PLC and the third
one is researching a new piece of
technology just came out how do you pull
everyone together in working on the same
thing it's not an easy problem to solve
also as a manager you have to make sure
that what your people are working on
actually aligns with the business need
and this is something that I've talked
to so many teams that actually forgot
this part
and that is doing research is nice
during research for the name of research
probably won't fly for long in most
organization
I love project zero I really do I have
friends working project zero and they
have the mandate and the budget from
management to do what they do but they
don't go around unchecked looking at
anything and everything whatever they
fancy they have a work plan they have
focus areas they decide ahead of time
where are they going to look at and what
kind of projects are going to approach
they're not running around randomly
attacking stuff and this is like the
gold standard on the other hand I've
talked to research team where yeah I'm
researching this stuff on automotive and
another team member is doing something
on a V onyx and another team member is
just doing some on malware the company
does not matter of those domains I agree
that you can learn from anything but you
actually have to align what your team is
doing to something that serves the
business because if you don't you're
going to have a very difficult budget
conversation at the end of the year your
team is everything you are as good as
your team some managers think that
because they are the managers or they're
on the management side they get like
special bonus points for being managers
if anything you get deducted boosts and
bonus points for being a manager you
have to think about how to push your
team forward how to make their results
visible to management to other people to
make it clear that their work has value
this is one of the rows of you as a
manager sometimes overlooked getting
people on your team working together
especially in the sin of security
researchers is difficult this is like a
rugged bunch of individuals everyone's
an anarchist nobody believes anyone and
everyone is paranoid and then they want
a job and they need to work together
towards a common goal
not so easy handling this kind of enough
translates to English herding cats so
it's just kind of like trying to get all
of those cats in the single-file walking
in the same direction
it's doable but it's not that easy on
the other hand if you're not going to do
that you won't have a team so you have
to be prepared and to think about your
strategy ahead of time of how are you
going to do that when I got the
responsibility for my first team that
was lying
I don't know 11 years ago something like
that my manager at the time told me we
have a bunch of somewhat eccentric
people how are you going to handle them
which was very clear that he was not
handling them and I told him well I
don't know I'll work with them and I'll
find out what eccentric eccentric teens
they have and see what I can work with
and Maura what I have to work without
and when I got to know the team I knew I
learned how to let go of some stuff but
really bring down on other stuff and
that really helped because let's be
honest most security researchers have
their pet peeves
I had a researcher that vehemently even
violently refused to work on anything
other than vim why there are other tools
other know this was religiously enforced
mayhem he would only work inside VI
maybe then on good days okay we can work
with that I'm not forcing anyone what
kind of tooling he needs to use but if
he wants to work on the team he needs to
work with the same tools as a team write
your own plugin to make it work inside
them I don't care so you can make those
balances you can make this work if you
get prepared ahead of time but if you
don't if you're trying to work with them
and say I'm the boss this is what I've
said this has to happen you will not
have a team for very long another thing
that's very difficult for managers a
specific specifically what I've seen in
security research managers is that at
least in my experience 99% of them came
from a security researcher background
that means that they have technical
proficiency and they have at least an
aura of source of some sort of technical
capability and then they got thrust into
management maybe they were the best on
their team maybe they were the most
available to it maybe they had a flair
for managing
people somewhere in the back of their
mind they're still with security
researchers I am still a security
researcher not an active one not even a
good one anymore but I'm still think of
myself as a security researcher but I'm
also a manager and when you go into
management you have to accept that you
are no longer the hands-on type of
contributor you have other important
things to do
and you can't do the research yourself
that's why you have a team and that's
why you have to show the team that you
are trusting them that you are leaving
them but you're not trying to take their
place you can't be the only one to speak
at blackhat other people need to speak
as well this also effects training
decisions
I could probably at the time do the
training for my team and teach everybody
on my team almost every aspect of the
job if I would have done that that would
have been a very bad decision not
because I can do it but because it
shouldn't mean me to do that your best
bet is to find people on your team and
empower them give them that
responsibility oversee it make sure that
they grow from that experience and that
they take on new responsibilities and
take that responsibilities off of your
backs power and politics is always an
issue in almost while I haven't been in
an organization where it wasn't a major
driver for decisions but understanding
the politics behind them and in to some
degree shielding your team from those
politics is the responsibility of the
manager good managers are able to dance
between two different poles the first
one would be I want to make sure that my
team is completely isolated from
corporate on the other hand I
want my team to be open and transparent
about everything that's happening even
if it's going to stress them out and
give them the wrong idea of what's gonna
happen as a manager you have
perspectives that they don't have and
they are looking to you to share that
perspective sometimes you can sometimes
you don't but you have to be as open and
respect as you can
you will often find that even in our
well it's very common in large
corporates but also in smaller
corporates that there are other teams
working on similar things even on
exactly the same things that you're
working on so ignoring the blatant
misuse of resources here this is
something that I at least found to be
pretty common at the time when I was
working for Cisco I tried to do like in
an enumeration how many different teams
are working in the IOT space at the time
which was like seven years ago seven
eight years ago IOT was relatively new
it was not like something today very
orderly everybody was doing something
and then were like between five to seven
different security research teams
focusing on IOT why would this happen
why should it happen and the answer to
that is mainly politics because one of
the high level managers the group
managers or something like that said
look IOT is a new and sexy field we
should have someone looking into it and
then you have like five of those
managers and each of them has its own
group looking into it and you can see it
again and again it happened with
blockchain it happened with machine
learning it happened with IOT and need
to happen with any kind of new buzzwords
coming around and new teams will spring
up like fresh mushrooms up the drain
this causes strife this causes ego
issues this causes a lot of mistrust
between teams that all they all feel
that are competing for the same things
both of the team member ends as a
manager you have to be aware that this
happens and you have to think about how
to make sure that your core
responsibilities as a research team are
kept intact and not to be dragged away
after the newest buzzword that six
months to one year later dies out and
the team with it so you have to invest
your power strategically and realize
that some things are transient and not
everything needs to be sought-after so
vehemently ego is a big problem in
management in people in humans in
general whenever ego comes into the room
someone comes out suffering
you can't leave eagle out of the room
even though many people say that you can
or you should if you will keep your ego
out of the room somebody else will bring
his ego in the room you have to be
prepared for it there are other research
teams other than other research managers
out there and some of them will put
their ego first think about what are you
going to do in that position how are you
going to react thinking about this
before it happens and having a planned
response ready will really better your
position in the organization and in
general lead for a better team both
internally and externally skip this one
okay so how would you do that I had I am
preparing for this slide I had
conversation something like 12 different
research teams across the board as many
of you know Israel is a hub for security
technology I have friends in many many
many different security companies most
of them are in the same Watson hood so I
kind of asked around and said okay this
is the main issues that I see what do
you feel about that how how would you
tackle this and we had a lot of a lot of
lively discussions around how do we
actually manage security research teams
and I think that the number one issue
that came up is the most important for
many different reasons is that if you're
not clear or you don't have very clear
guidance about what you're actually
researching what the research question
is and who does what and why and when to
stop the research that leads to a very
bad research team experience on the
other hand if you have a manager that
clearly defines what you're what you're
going after what you're looking for and
timebox is it don't invest more than two
weeks around that let's have another
discussion then or whenever you reach to
that point that's done I don't need a
POC just make sure that you can show
that this happened get that address you
got that address fine stop there if you
have a very clear definition of what
you're going to do when you're going to
achieve it how it looks like when you
achieve it and when you are going to
stop
research team is the whole benefits
because they can affect their will their
resources their time their effort in a
very coordinated and a very focused way
but for every team that doesn't have
this thank you for every team that
doesn't have this you get a disarray you
get people getting confused to get
people investigating something
completely relevant for a very long
period of time I've heard examples like
someone on my team spent a month working
on a POC for something that's completely
stupid and irrelevant like I can exploit
this refrigerator now through that foods
ble stack and I can make it pop out free
ice cubes instead of two ice cubes
that's a very nice POC very bit
difficult to bring the refrigerator on
stage but at least I can make a video
but have you really done anything useful
if the manager for that team the team
leader for that team would have said
make sure you have code execution stop
there I'm happy with code execution and
device he wouldn't spend so much time
building it and any relevant POC I'm not
dissing POC I'll talk about them later
they have value but you have to like
focus on what's the right value for POCs
building the right research question
helps the people who are working on that
research question focus but also to get
focused help from others so when they
have a very clear definition of what
they're working on and why and they get
stuck they can go to another team member
another team entirely and ask for help
because they know what they're looking
for and they know what's irrelevant but
if you give them something general like
hack this refrigerator you get a lot of
kind of different results if you give
them something specific like I want to
make sure that nobody can access the
Twitter credentials stored on this
refrigerator that gives a lot more focus
to what they're trying to do being a
manager does not
discourage you from being a technical
person you have to be a technical person
to manage security researchers who's
that has been my experience for every
research team that I heard of that they
got a non-technical manager either the
managers left or the team dispersed it
doesn't work well but on the other hand
being a technical person does not mean
that you have to do everything hands-on
which I just talked about earlier your
job is to understand what's wrong and
how to fix it when you're working with
your team and you see that they spend a
disorder net amount of time finding
tickets in JIRA well nobody likes JIRA
but you can write some scripts to
automate it if you see that most of
their issues come from working with a
different team member some cross team
collaboration something like that and
they're spending lots of times in
meetings stuff like that step in
separate them find it video a better
solution to make that work you need to
be the voice for your team to make sure
that nobody is having a painful
experience doing what they need to do if
they do they'll either walk around it
that's what we do we'll walk around find
workarounds around those issues or we're
probably ignore them completely and
something will explode in our faces
later so you have to be really on point
understand what the team does and how to
help them do that team do their job
better research teams don't work in a
vacuum well they often don't work in a
vacuum and if you want to make the most
from your team and to make sure that
your team really influences the company
as a whole show the other stakeholders
your peers your colleagues what the
security research team can do for them
not just as their leaf a fig leaf to
protect their organization but something
that can actually help them in what
they're doing and I'll give some
examples of that later on how to show
ri4 research teams as a manager you also
have have to make some tough calls
this is your purview it's your turf
you even be responsible for active
research it's a question that comes up
in almost any conversation that they
have in end with any research manager
shoot the research managers be even be
responsible for active participation
should they be hands-on and this is
something that you should decide and the
team should know ahead of time
nobody likes a manager that comes in and
pops it up giving the keyboard I'll show
you how it's done
even if you know how it's done even if
you've done that 300 times before it's
better to give people the opportunity to
learn and to do that on their own and
learn and grow over time
then you stepping in and doing it for
them another thing is is that you need
to think about the future part of your
role as a manager what would happen in a
year from now when person X leaves the
company do you have someone else to step
in and fill in his shoes maybe she will
leave for a better proposition do you
know someone that can step in and take
over her responsibilities and if the
answer is no this is a very senior
person he knows everything we trust him
completely you're in a bad position you
need to think about how to get out of
that bad position maybe find other team
members that can take some of those
responsibilities so you'll have a backup
and maybe you need to think about what
would happen if you leave the
organization everybody has a replacement
but have you made the ground to have a
replacement from your team or what do
you have someone dropped from outside
for your team think about these kinds of
issues ahead of time and build your
pipeline make sure that you have people
ready at different stages Jr's turning
into seniors seniors transition to
leadership roles not necessarily
management when transition to other
kinds of fare rolls make sure that there
is a let's say an employment horizon for
people on your team they're not just
coming to be a security researcher for
two years or three years and then that's
it you have to make sure that they have
a career progression it's not a bad word
to have a career we just want to have a
car career in InfoSec we need to think
about our careers in that kind of lens
sometimes people are not the right fit
for your team I've had that happened
multiple times it takes time to identify
that the issue the core issue the root
cause is that you have the wrong people
on your team it might be a single person
might be two persons and it might be the
right thing to do is to transition them
to a different team and hire new people
instead it might be a culture issue it
might be the way that they work with
other people so mill gave an example
just an hour ago about bad apples well
nobody wants to work with a bad apple
and if you can build a better culture by
getting the right apples getting the
fresh apples in your barrel then you
should focus on that this will big bring
better results for your entire team than
just condoning actions and behaviors
from bad apples sometimes you have to
and I'll talk to that in the end some of
the research managers that I know try to
like walk away from hiring so hiring is
somebody else's problem let me know when
you need the technical part of it being
done I'll ask the technical question
someone else handle everything else it's
wrong I believe it's wrong I think that
as a manager you have to be involved in
the hiring process along the entire the
entire stack you have to be part of the
sourcing you have to be part of the
interview you have to be part of the
decision and you have to be part of the
transition that the employee does when
he gets into the organization a small
piece of statistic that I heard from
Google from Harvard Business Review
now we're just okay unless so they did
this study and the single most effective
factor to try to determine if someone is
going to be good or successful after
three months I found it very surprising
was that the manager the hiring manager
would meet them on their first day so to
me it was like a blown out statistics
what do you mean said some managers
don't need the employees on the first
day when they get hired and apparently
it was like in the 30 percent of the
cases the hiring manager was very busy
he had meetings he was off-site was
somewhere else and so he delegated it to
someone else and when that manager is
delegating responsibility those people
that were hired onto the team felt like
nobody cares about us we're just another
cog in the machine we're just another
screw when the manager was there to
greet them to walk them around to show
them where they're going to say it to
show them the keyboard the toilets the
kitchen they felt like okay we're on
between onboarding to a team into a
family we're going to be in the right
place and this sounds like a very small
thing to do meet your employees on
you're free on their first day on the
job apparently it's not that obvious
getting a team that's all seniors is
very bad I don't know if you've ever had
that experience trying to manage a team
of six to eight seniors it's a lot of
fun a lot of very technical discussions
for about 20% of the time and the other
80% of the times is being talked about
other stuff other than technical which
is find are all very good people but now
you have no pipeline you have no way to
grow the team senior people are by
nature very independent they know what
they're doing they're very proficient
and very professional in what they do
but there are some rows or some stuff
that they won't do for some stuff
they're overkill to do on the other hand
when you have a team of all juniors and
I had the misfortune doing this once
an experience that I don't care to
repeat you have a team that everybody is
very enthusiastic and nobody knows what
they're supposed to do which also it's a
good thing I'm not disrespecting any of
them but it's a good thing but you need
someone to be there on-site on keyboard
to help them to show them the ropes if
you're the manager you're not that
person so when I build new teams from
scratch or when I receive new teams I
always push to either get the the
directs the hiring requirements to open
new headcount for junior people when I
had a lot of seniors or if I had a lot
of junior people to say okay stop with
the hiring the junior people this
doesn't help me take two or three of
those head counts pull them together and
get me seen here because you can't run a
show with eight junior people and you
definitely can't run a show with eight
senior people you have to think about
your team for the long term you have to
think about your team in a broad sense
and not just in making sure that all the
day-to-day operations are being done
building an incentive plan for junior
people or for senior people for any
security researcher is usually dependent
on what the researcher care about I this
photo was not selected randomly I have a
huge incentive to talk right here London
is my favorite city but this is also
happens quite often because you have
tools you have opportunities when you're
talking with security researchers
there's not not just the salary the
server is not the only thing that counts
so a couple of things that really help
when you're talking with security
researchers is showing them that there
are other venues or other methods to
drinking's one but hopefully not the
only thing other things that they can do
in your team that actually they might
not be able to do in other teams so
publishing work is a difficult point
I'll give my own perspective in that I
worked for Intel someone might have
heard of that company for the past two
and a half years I left like three
months ago
and it took me over a year to get the
approval process and marketing people PR
people legal people HR people everybody
aligned properly so I would have
permission to go and talk and it wasn't
because anybody was thinking oh you
shouldn't talk about that subject it's
very risky
we're very paranoid it's more like we
haven't encountered anyone who actually
wanted to speak how would we go about
this we have no process so yeah that's
another way but that won't last for long
hitting them really clears out the
senses but doesn't affect change for a
longer period of time so if you can get
it done and I'd be happy to bring to
help you some tips on how to do that but
it also really helped with getting
people on my team because once the
people other people heard that my team
is out there presenting talking and
going to conferences so I want to be
part of that team this is the stuff that
I care about I want to do that this is a
very marginal cost to you as a manager
allowing or sending your people to speak
at conferences it's a very cheap
incentive to include in the package site
research is also very important allowing
your people to grow and enhance their
skills is a benefit to use an employer
doing this doing so on the side research
it's actually beneficial for the
business is good for you as well Google
has their or at least had a 20% to roll
most of the companies can't afford one
day week with somebody walks on
something that they care about but find
a side side project that everybody and
the team can care about and work on it
especially if you have some downtime
sending people to conferences is the way
that we as security professionals really
learn and improve our abilities some of
that actually comes from listening to
talks probably a very small percentage
of that most of that comes from
attending the office and talking to
other people and getting new views and
hearing about new tool sets a new
frameworks this is actually what happens
at conferences and it's a very difficult
sell when you go to corporate and say I
really have to go to that conference and
talk to people
they don't get it but you can't go to
them and said I really have to go to
that conference and do that workshop and
do that training and go to other
sponsors and the vendors and see what
they're doing and to better enrich my
own intelligent feeds on on how stuff is
done they can relate to that so change
your messaging the same thing still
happens if other people know that your
team is part of the community
contributing to the community they would
love coming working for your team even
if a different team is offering more
money and that's also very strongly
correlated to retaining those people ok
I'll try to hustle a bit another thing
that really comes about pretty often in
conversation about rescue research teams
is how do you show the organization the
return on investment I have an encounter
where I encountered one so I almost
never encountered a security research
team that was tied to a P&L Center to a
profit and loss center most security
research teams are part of a some sort
of research division where they get a
budget but they don't have revenue so in
the corporate world that means that
there are a cost center they cost money
to operate they are not getting any
money from operating that piece of the
business so whenever you have budget
conversation headcount conversations
anything with someone else in the
management chain in the in the overall
corporate world there say ok but you're
just costing me money show me what's
your value understanding how they think
about value and thinking about some of
these ideas will help you be better
positioned for those conversations and
you have to be ready for those
conversations because they will happen
the first thing is that whatever you're
working on should be aligned with what
the business is working on aniline is
not something like flimsy like we are
working in IOT so I'll work in IOT as
well you have to show that what you're
working if it's successful if you fund
whatever you're looking for or if you
show that you're not able to find what
you're looking for has actual business
value and you get that from talking to
the business people who actually care
about their product
you go to them and say oh you have a web
facing product and I can show you that
if you use this library then the hacker
can come in and take all of our
customer's data that's pretty bad
he understands the value for something
pretty bad going to happen doing
research like I want to do research or
new types of xxs XSS vulnerabilities
nobody cares but if you can show that
these new types of exercise or abilities
are applicable to the website that
they're working on or that the
application that they're deploying you
have immediate are I sometimes on I
really can quantify this numbers all
just like 60% of the times security
research teams go on a rabbit hole and
have no idea how they're going to come
out the other end they might find
something or they might not what often
happens is you go one rabbit rabbit hole
you come out from a different path of
the finding something else completely
and that's fine for a research team is
part of the way that they do business
but you as a manager need to be prepared
for that and have a plans to set in
motion once you have those results to
show those results and get buy-in from
people above you sideways you below you
when you have those results to show that
you haven't conducted that research in
vain however I met many research teams
that didn't have that plan ready
so they invested a lot of time they
found something interesting and now they
don't know what to do with it so now
they start shopping around see maybe
someone can use this maybe someone can
do a tool from it
maybe we can improve a piece of our
product that might use this then they
found that nobody does make sure that
you have a plan to set in motion once
you have something and if you don't have
a plan for that
think very strongly of why don't you
have a plan for that and that comes to
the point of do you really need proof of
concepts everybody loves PLC's everybody
loves building them this is the closest
that most security researchers come to
actually building products in most cases
that I've seen the POC was unneeded was
even completely unnecessary because if
you can take the same concept sit with
the development showing what can be done
you can probably solve that problem
right there right now building a POC you
best two weeks of your life building it
and then you have to demo it around to
people to try to understand why it's
relevant what they're built and it
doesn't even overlap a lot this build
instead of just showing them in their
code a POC is sometimes are very useful
especially if you need to build a dam or
something for management but if you
don't have a very strong reason to do so
skip the POC go straight to the source
and fix those issues don't go about any
kinds of tangents or weird research
paths
nobody cares about not because you can't
or you shouldn't but because you will
lose the trust of your business partners
of your colleagues very very fast do
this from time to time there's a good
compelling reason to do so but most of
the time you should be going after stuff
that's relevant for the business for
some reason people forget this don't
just go for bugs everybody can find bugs
buzzing your folks find bugs take those
bugs and find something that really
matters that that has a root cause that
might change a lot of things that might
make security better overall for the
product security research resources are
very expensive don't waste them on
finding just menial bugs focus them on
finding important impactful things for
the business you should also plan for
down times because sometimes you won't
have a new project in the pipeline so be
prepared have side projects ready
maybe something working something lower
priority maybe something that the entire
team can benefit from like new skills or
new technologies you can also think
about doing bug bounties responsible
disclosure start of things with the
caveat that you have to involve legal
because as an employee you might get
into a hairy situation working on other
people's products stuff like that still
doable you can still spend some time
doing that when you don't have something
more pressing to do one of the most
effective things that I've used in order
to show the ROI for my teams
alternative costs if we found that issue
what would have been the cost to fix it
what would have been the cost from men
hours what would the cost from marketing
perspective the damage to the brand what
would be the cost from other waste of
resources that might happen aggregate
that number now calculate how much the
headcount cost for your team for that
period of time and weigh them against
their one another and often you can show
that if you spend a week or two or three
of your team's resources it's much much
cheaper than have someone else in the
wild doing the same thing you should
invest in automation as much as you can
even for security research teams getting
good practices down getting good
automation down will free up their time
to focus on the important stuff try to
get as much of the code the black work
or the the dirty work out of their hands
and into the hands of automation because
we can and we really shouldn't do this
my hand by now over time after the first
time you'll do this calculation the
second time the third time the first
time you will have a new RI path to show
and that is you're saving the
organization money over time and that is
the first issue we found save the
organization 1 million dollars
the second issue failed $500,000 the
third issue save 1 million dollars or
whatever it is and then you can put it
in a very nice graph you do it in Excel
if buddy loves excelling management you
do the graph and you show over time
we've saved such-and-such money for the
org it was 10 million dollars from the
inception of the team but 3 million
dollars the last year alone ma
management loved those numbers you will
get support from management much faster
when you talk their language other than
saying we found an RCE and if somebody
else found that our C that would have
been horrible they have no idea what it
is even after you explain it when you
give you T
goals or even more than that when you
declare your goals upward in the
management chain be very careful about
what you want to measure because what
you're going to measure what you're
going to optimize for matters and when
you are deciding of those metrics for
your team which are going to be measured
against you might make mistakes a common
one that I found is that people give
their metric as how many bugs is that my
team found over a period of time or a
number of bugs their lines of code we
looked at or other kinds of metrics like
that I really really don't like those
metrics and the reason for it is because
you can take a two-week period and find
10 bugs you can make it take another 2
week period and find a single bug and
you can take a four month period and
find no bugs and all of them would have
equivalent value from a business
perspective and if you only measure
yourself on the number of bugs what
would happen is that one of your
teammates will write a JIRA script to
file new bugs automatically from the
fastener thermic that you use and then
you have 1,000 new bugs and the metrics
are through the roof and you flooded the
system out and nobody cares anymore
think very closely about what are your
goals what are your metrics sometimes
you will have to build a PLC to show to
upper management to show upper
management what you're working on and
how much value it has sometimes it's
something completely stupid
for example we build a demo that shows
that you can upload an image into an
image classification machine learning
system and then you change all of the
images to begin to have labels called
hacked hacked hacked stupid it was
really from a POC perspective was like a
better script equivalent of a POC from
management perspective was this first
time that they actually understood what
it means to hack machine learning so
PLC's have value if you create them for
a very specific purpose if you just
create them to talk to other developers
about what's wrong with their code over
their security impact that you found
you're doing it wrong
you're going to have to tune your ROI
again and again and again because every
org is different and rules keeps
changing but you have as the manager you
have to be on top of that because that's
the way that the organization measures
you and as a research team you're kind
of like an outlier of organization
you're the developer team you're not a
QA team you're not finance you're not HR
you're not something that they're used
to and they know how to manage in in
measure and budget you're something that
just cost a lot of money and if you're
doing your job properly nothing happens
that's very difficult for finance people
for HR people to measure because impact
is not a parent think about it all the
time how are you going to visualize how
can you float upward the value of your
team when you're in down time excellent
time to review everything again maybe
you can do something differently
collaborate with your team they might
have better ideas of how to do that in
the end you get what you measure and
that means that if you measure for the
wrong things you will get the wrong
results it's not easy to measure for the
right things and the goals post keeps
changing but be on top of it and pay
close attention just as a short note on
conferences we're all here right now at
conferences so I'm speaking to the choir
here everybody here believes that
conferences are important but whenever
you have a conversation trying to
explain to someone else while going to
conferences is important maybe some of
these ideas will help so the first thing
is that if you're a security researcher
going to conferences is part of being a
security researcher you need to have the
budget set aside for it and you have to
have the goals ready and measured
against if you're not going to do that
it means that you will have troubles
hiring talent because you're not doing
that and other places are this is an
argument that the HR really likes
because it helps them measure themselves
against the rest of the industry
learning investing in learning for
security researcher is not just easy
like getting a udemy class for the new
nodejs framework or something you don't
get security
that way you have to talk to other
people you have to learn from other
people also you need your people to be
out there and representing your brand
your team your company so you will have
an easier time to hire other people I
have a letter that I wrote and I don't
have any problem open sourcing it
sending it to my own corporate ladder
showing them why I got an ROI from
attending and sponsoring conferences I
was trying to hire security researchers
for about eight months
zero hires I couldn't find anyone I
started sponsoring those conferences
giving talks at conferences getting
myself out there and talking about what
we do I got five hires in six months for
me these are very strong numbers now not
very different from the other numbers in
our industry so the RI is very apparent
okay so what do you get by attending
those conferences a lot of on of a lot
of trainings are only offered on-site
workshops free everybody loves free
workshops also on-site you have to be
there to do them
CTF a great opportunity to learn usually
on-site sometimes their remote mostly
they're not you can go to the talks not
a very strong argument because most of
them get to be available online sometime
after the fact however going to the
underground talks which is any talk
that's not recorded it's probably worth
your time and effort to attend that talk
so for example I gave a talk about
machine learning in numerous places but
I gave one talk about machine learning
in the peaceful sky talks in DEFCON and
in that talk I kind of ripped to shreds
many of the machine learning algorithms
in the security and we seen how there
are for any for loss of a better word
lying about their statistics yeah
anybody in the business no that's not
true I just showed the numbers why
they're not true so a lot of stuff that
you can go and see in underground talks
you will not be able to see anywhere
else but the most valuable thing is
talking to other people the amount of
ideas research opportunities that I
found in conferences for my team for my
comm
for every position that I've held was
extraordinarily valuable compared to the
cost of attending that conference so
much so that I left Intel maybe three
months ago four months ago I attended
the hacker summer camp this Vegas a
month ago on my own expense because it's
worthwhile and I don't have a stronger
argument in that I'll skip this one also
a good thing to share with your team
this is an important one so it's going
to convince is just a fancy bonus which
is a nice picture of Vegas by the way
from the Bellagio I don't think so but
if you don't have a clear criteria on
who gets to go to the conference's in
your team you can find yourself very
very fast in a place of doing favoritism
nepotism stuff like that which brings
out bad apples in your team and you
don't want to be there have clear
criteria make sure that people that go
share their knowledge and make sure that
you get something out of the process it
might be a hiring pipeline it might be a
blog social awareness something don't
just send people to conferences and
that's it it's a waste of your money
it's a waste of their effort make
something out of it try to plan ahead
what are you going to do what are you
going to spend your budget on get a
budget for it sponsorship opportunities
giving a conference $1,000 to make sure
that they have their logo your company's
logo is a huge value to get in front of
the people you care to be in front of I
haven't mentioned that but I am one of
the organizers of besides Tel Aviv it's
a relatively large secure conference in
Israel about 1200 people and getting an
opportunity to just have your logo in
front of 1200 security professionals
it's probably worth more than thousand
dollars and this directly affects your
hiring pipeline in order to get the most
value out of this have a pipeline where
they have a process ready how you're
going to do that who do you need to talk
to who do you need a legal
who do you need a social who holds the
keys to the Twitter account make sure
that you have all of that information in
and that brings me to Talent the
situation we have today I don't know how
strongly you feel it here but I can tell
you definitely how strongly you feel it
in Israel it's a seller's market most
people can name their price and more
than that the half-life time of that the
security research is looking for a new
position is around two weeks and usually
that means that most of them already
have a new signed contract in hand by
the time that they let you know that
they're leaving the work place that
means that you don't only have to work
fast you have to be out there with
fillers out there to understand when
something goes wrong but also who you're
going to hire once someone leaves if you
start right now trying to hire a new
person it might takes you months to fill
that void if two persons leave your team
that's a huge void to fill now so
sourcing where can you find that talent
going to conferences going to community
events sponsoring events getting on the
right groups mailing lists IRC channel
slack channels lots of different
opportunities be out there talk to the
people who are living ask them why are
they living there are red flags you
should be aware of if they are something
messed up my slides okay don't leave
sourcing for HR do this yourself work
with HR another note which is very
important is that what happens in a lot
of cases is that you take your best
security researcher and you make him a
team leader most cases this is the wrong
decision is the wrong decision because
being a manager or a team leader is a
different skill set and being a very
talented security researcher that's true
for most teams but even more so for
security research teams because security
researchers if I'll take the like the
the metaphor for what a security
research is is some introvert working in
a basement with the hoodie over his head
that's obviously not true but for most
cases I think that we can say that we
are rugged individuals we don't work
well
with teams we work best alone when we
are doing deep dives into technical
stuff it's not really the framework that
you would want for a manager
think about how you separate the two
when people leave you you should focus
your attention about fixing the problems
that cause people to leave in some cases
you won't be able to for example and a
different workplace is offering a lot
more money than what we are offering for
example one of our sites in Israel where
I was at the Intel got a new employer
called Amazon which you might have heard
of and they paid between forty to sixty
percent above market for talent I can't
argue with any person who comes to me
and saying this new places offer means
sixty percent more on my salary I'm not
trying to argue I can't I don't have the
tools to do that but for other cases
maybe you can do something someone tells
you look I'm just I want a more
interesting position I'll be doing the
same thing for two three years find them
a new thing to do a new stuff to work on
a different team to transition into
their in asset to our organization
they're already know the organization
help them stay
help them make the best of themselves
and if somebody says that I'm leaving
because I can't stand that manager
that's a red flag research again Harvard
Business Review has shown that in over
seventy percent of the cases when people
leave their workplace they don't go
because they don't pay enough money they
don't go because the benefits of change
they go because they don't want to work
for that manager anymore
manager are the number one reason why
people leave their workplace think of
your own personal histories in how many
of those places you worked at did you
really like your manager but you decided
to leave anyway
maybe if you're offered a lot more money
probably not if you offered the same
amount of money you won't leave your
current workplace for an added I don't
know pop-tarts or something are some
bonus meals or something retaining
talent is very difficult
think about what interests them most and
get them what interests that most I
always had some toys lying around when I
say toys I mean raspberry pies some
pieces
good we can play with some lab that we
can work her a hassle around with
something we can do books learning most
of the people I worked with would give a
lot to get like I really wanted this
malware research volume number six
that's a benefit that I can give it's
like a hundred dollars it's like nothing
but the ratio between the amount of
money did cost versus the payout in
retention is huge but the single most
effective thing that you can do is to
get everybody on your team to understand
how their specific individual tasks that
they're working on are pushing whose
value for the business as a whole
everybody wants to feel like what
they're doing is important what they're
doing has value and what they're doing
is actually moving the needle they don't
want to work in a vacuum they don't want
to be disconnected from the business and
I think more often than not you'll find
that most people have a very keen sense
of what really matters for the business
to wrap this up I want to talk a bit
about what's it like to manage prima
donnas so the first thing is I know the
old meta type the eccentric very highly
sought after talent that really knows
what it wants but he will not budge a
moment to get anything else so if you
can manage that person immense value he
can like he can build everything on his
own in a midnight on the other hand the
cost of managing that person might be
too high it might hurt the entire team
when you have such a talent in your
midst so getting that balance is very
difficult on the other hand if you see
such raw talent in one of your juniors
this is something that I would hop on
with my Bo both of my hands because
someone jr. versus a senior is much
easier to educate it much easier to help
to get him out of his prima donna
position into something that's more team
collaborative position but more than
that when someone is a junior and has so
much talent you have time to work with
him to still get value from what he does
and help him to be a better person a
better teammate
get help your team are your best allies
the community is a great ally use them
ask them ask around don't keep those
struggles to yourself you can learn a
lot from other people you yourself can
improve a lot by listening to other
people and with that I want to thank you
and open them the mic for questions
other any questions yes so they very
much depends of what you're trying to
measure in regards to PR but one thing
that I can tell you that we've done
something like sentiment analysis before
and after we gave the talks to see how
people reacted differently to the brand
also we talked to the marketing people
and told them that you're doing your own
surveys look at those Peaks and see if
we got a different perspective maybe got
a different set of data I'm not sure
that's the right thing to measure as a
metric for the success of your team but
it might be worthwhile to measure when
you're working with their team how your
work influence is what they do other
questions okay thank you very much I'm
sorry someone in the back I'm sorry one
moment someone with a mic because I
can't hear you
I say there's still a question but thank
you for phenomenal talk it's probably
one of the best talks I've seen on the
leadership of security research over the
last ten years so thank you thank you
very much