so this is basic offensive applications
of MA files in W my scripting I am Sam
ruthenberg this is Devon board and arrow
and Connor Gephardt we're all students
at Towson University represent the
Seattle room and we're all Devon and I
are seniors Connors sophomore we're all
Comp Sci major studying cyber security
and kind of did this project a little
side thing be more familiar with like
some newer applications of Windows and
try to test out some new offensive
applications of a really powerful tool
called WMI which we have to like kind of
introduce you guys to and see if you
guys can come up with your own mouth
files to hack your friends so but first
like what is the windows management
instrumentation or WMI you all have it
in your windows computers at home it's
how a lot of the Windows operating
system is going to be working in the
background and the most common
applications of something like this and
most of you probably seen is when your
battery gets kind of low like 15% you
see a little pop-up show up that's kind
of like what WMI is doing it's
monitoring the window system in the
background and it's gonna check things
like hardware so like what process like
how its CPU usage what's my battery
percentage software so like what
processes are running how I should
handle those processes running how I
should handle like hardware changes in
the state so it's really just windows
monitoring itself and being able to
respond to certain events happening on
the computer and then select what is the
WMI database it's real it's really
intuitive and great as you can see the
little photo that is the W my database
really great to view you can really
understand what's going on there right
like right now you can't it's five files
you can't open with anything like
pre-installed on Windows like you need
outside software not installed to just
view anything going on so as a normal
user or even as they advanced user it's
very hard to understand and know what W
my objects are saved in your operating
system so but like what is in that
database
there are namespaces and sub namespaces
so we use a lot of the
in the root so it's a root namespace and
then underneath that we're in the CMV -
sub namespace and then inside of that
there are classes so we have like event
filters and consumers these are gonna be
like kind of like your function calls
and a normal program so you're gonna be
able to use these functions in a
namespace to like create new events that
you can use to personalize your computer
or in our case do some malicious
activity alright so obviously it's not
the most intuitive of programs that
Windows has ever created so to interact
with it there's a couple different ways
one of them is through the wmic command
from the command line you can specify
stuff like in this example we have our
namespaces root slash subscription we're
looking for things event filters where
their names are start filter process and
we're trying to delete that namespace so
this would remove an object from the
database you could add you can list all
the ones that are in a certain namespace
you can really do whatever you want with
these commands but they're kind of
clunky so a better way to do it would be
with a ma file or a managed object
format file so it's a file specifically
made to interact with the WMI database
you just it's basically a text file a
form of the WIC command but a little
better it's more programming oriented so
it's easier to use I'd say you can also
insert different scripts in it such
written in languages like C C sharp Java
Python etc so you store these files for
everyone in the system use the command
math comp to compile them but like
there's a big distinction here that like
math files don't run like normal
programs they just kind of like they add
stuff to the database whenever it's run
and then the database handles anything
that happens when those objects are
needed so like these files just kind of
exist but they don't need to run
anything they're not a process that's
running after they're compiled so in
these files you have events or consumers
which Devens about to tell you about
right now so you have events and events
you know you kind of heard them for it's
gonna be anything that happens on the
system pretty much so you have tons of
events it could be things like
user runs a process or the user logs in
or a file gets accessed or the user Bob
fails to log in because he gets his
password wrong your battery hits 15%
like we said so there's a lot of events
and these event filters we're going to
keep track of that and kind of log when
it happens and when it does happen we
have things called consumers that will
tell it what to do right here we have an
example of an event filter that we used
this is just a pretty basic one it's
gonna check the process start trace for
any process named or that contains proc
X so it's just internals process
Explorer what we're using here yeah and
here's the the consumer so the consumer
is going to be how the system responds
to that event so when the event happens
it's going to say all right do this so
this is one that we use this is just
saying when proc Expos run kill it
we used a command line template there's
active script template there's log
templates there's a lot of different
templates for various usages but we used
a command line shell so that is what we
used the the part that ties it all
together is going to be a filter to
consumer binding and this is just to tie
the event to the consumer so that it
knows when this event occurs do this you
can have multiple consumers for one
event so when one of them occurs you
could do many many different consumers
but on so some more fun stuff we have a
demo to show you kind of how you can use
these these tools for you know useful
things but also malicious things as well
so let's get into it I'm gonna put this
here
all right so we talked about how wmic is
the command-line tool to use the
database and kind of view it and edit it
but it's not very intuitive you know you
have to know a lot of command line and
you have to be it's kind of a little
clunky so they have a GUI based
application called dummy my Explorer and
it's used to administer the database as
you can see you have your namespaces
that we talked about and then you have
your sub namespaces and then you have
your classes that we talked about
instances and then the content of that
instance it's still not very user
friendly you have to know what you're
looking for if you want to use this it's
kamek registry you don't want to want to
pick around in here you might break some
stuff also it's not installed by default
on Windows so again if you don't have
this it's a knockin very useful for you
so one of the uses we talked about would
be logging that be the the biggest use
people would use it for so a user opens
a file you want to log that you want to
see when someone's opening a file so one
of the examples we had which I'm going
to show you really fast this is a pretty
basic math file it's kind of long but
it's low clunky so this is basically
saying actually I'm gonna go down here
to the event filter this is the event
filter almost exact same as when we had
in the slides except this one is using
PowerShell so when PowerShell is run
it's going to log that and then the
consumer is saying up here again it's a
little long but the consumer is saying
when PowerShell is run do this so this
is making a file called log process and
it's going to write to that file saying
PowerShell was started at this time it
has this process ID and this is the
parent process ID and then it also has
the exact same thing when it stops so
you know when a user is starting the
process ending the process so you want
to know maybe your employee is using
PowerShell they shouldn't be using it
you want to know when they're used
when they stopped what they did we
didn't track it by username but you
could do that so just show how that's
working I'm gonna go ahead and compile
that all right so that's been compiled
when I go ahead and open up PowerShell
so you're gonna see it's running now a
little log process text file was created
and that's gonna say when the process
was started with the ID and the parent
ID now if I go ahead and I close it I'm
gonna also have to close this cuz
notepad that's gonna say when it was
stopped and parent PID is zero because
the process is dead there is no parent
but this is kind of just how you would
use it a non malicious sense to log and
see what's going on in the system but we
also have some more malicious ways you
can use it and talk about that so how
many of you guys have been in the
scenario you're hacking your friend and
use privilege escalation and you get
system and then you're like you know
what this guy keeps killing my system
shell and I don't like that I don't want
to keep killing my shells it happens to
me to everyone but don't worry there's a
way to solve it it's it's a problem that
plagues a nation so so I so this was
just called pee test and this is a very
simple math file as well so it's just
two parts because you want the shell to
start when the user logs on because you
know when your friends log on you always
want to have system on all the time so
whenever they're going to log on it will
then the event the event filter is gonna
check the process stop there it's gonna
check the instant creation event of a
1:32 logon session so when that instance
it happens it will then trigger the
consumer that's gonna then call your
shell program that you just hid
somewhere in the file system and because
it's windows are never gonna find that
in the file system you just bury that
thing deep because it's WMI even if you
hide it somewhere running a system W
mine will always be so
so any process that W mines gonna call
will have system level privileges which
we can show so if we just moth and spell
it right that will then store it as well
and because these moth files aren't a
process you know they're part of the
operating system itself when the
computer restarts or is in turn on for a
week the process will always be running
because it's not really a process it's
more part of the operating system at
this point so you know they're not gonna
see a process that's calling back that
it's gonna like start the shell up when
it's logged all and it's not going to be
showing up and they're like programs are
in start file because it's not a process
it's more of the operating system itself
that's doing these things so now when I
log off my little friendly shell program
is they be called and then on the
command control module on the callee
system you're gonna now have a shell
it's calling out to you and you can just
restart your Handler and you'll be able
to get right in
you do it I know they have to be able to
login first that's key
so now after I logged in you'll see a
friendly little program called free RAM
running I'll give you a hint it's not
actually free Ram running right there
and now as you see if I try to kill this
process tree I can't I don't have access
that's higher privilege than I am right
now
because it's just running a system
because WM I called that process so then
on a Kali system all I have to do is I'm
gonna restart my handler it's then gonna
connect to that I know have an all right
now have a show so in sessions there you
go I am the authority system I can now
go into this on a traverse on reverse
CCP and meterpreter I can do whatever I
want I run this system at this point so
it's just a new way that you can really
set persistence on a system and
inventive way that a user might not be
looking for because it's not gonna be a
normal process in process start and even
more fun if they just you know be admin
in case your user gets smart and they
realize that free RAM might not actually
be free RAM somehow we don't know how
and they kill the process it just comes
right back so this kind of persistence
will just always be there there's gonna
be two on and as a normal user unless
you go in them off and you like remove
that file or you find the file that's
giving that persistence you're not gonna
be able to remove this office system so
it's a new way you get persistence and
all your friends when they log in you
can be system and just do whatever you
want and Conner will show you our true
goal
okay so yeah like you can hack your
friends and get persistence whatever but
like I really just want to like make
that make that make fun of them you know
be like hah hacked you leet skills so
when we were first assigned but not
assigned to like when we first started
this a professor Estes he was like hey
you guys should figure out a way so that
whenever process Explorer is run it
immediately quits and then it puts up a
picture of the marshmallow man from
Ghostbusters and it says there is no
process Explorer only Zuul and we were
like yo that sounds awesome I would love
to do that to my friends but it turns
out it's very very difficult to be overt
using the WMI database because as Sam
said it all runs the system so we'd
start the process with the the picture
popping up and it would be like in the
background because it's running a system
the user would never see it so we were
like this is kind of dumb like I mean
sure it works but you can't see it it's
not cool
so we came up with a better solution
which I will demonstrate currently and
it's a surprise so two moments for me to
compile this file
so we have this wonderful fun death dot
mah file so now I'm gonna just try and
run process Explorer cuz I want to see
what processes are running oh no it
immediately died nothing ever works the
first time I guess so it turns out that
the HDMI cord is accepting the volume
but there is no speaker attached to this
projector so we can demonstrate the the
meme by unplugging the HDMI and you
won't be able to see it but you've seen
it kills passes explore and then after
it
[Music]
[Laughter]
thing because it says system the users
like please make this noise stop it's
running two instances help I'm gonna
shut it down it just keeps going and
going until the product like until the
computer is completely shut off the
users like oh no help and this again
will still be there if they try and run
process Explorer when they turn it back
on tough luck you get more Rick Astley
never gonna give you up we had a great
time doing this project it was a lot of
fun a lot of hard coding you know many
issues as you can see hey but it was
really a great learning experience and
I'm really happy that we did it and now
you all know how to mean you're friends
with never gonna give you up all the
time thank you very much
any questions yeah yes