Jek
okay we're good so this talk is not
email fit it's not fail item it's called
failed time or failing towards success
and in a lot of the talks like this
you're gonna see this probably a little
bit different than the normal talk
certainly different than what and video
fail let's try again we've got to have a
failure during a fail talk that's kind
of the way it works I wasn't planning on
putting any kind of quotes up here about
failure and success because everyone
does that see in a Tech Talk we're gonna
get beyond the motivational quotes we're
just gonna dig into the things that
really matter and ultimately comes down
to why this talk what why not
most contacts talk about successes all
the great things they did they exploited
this this thing over here pop calculator
most cons talk about the successes and
celebrate the successes this is not that
talk failures happen all the time as
stakes are made and sometimes that we go
ahead and do something that doesn't make
sense because we're told to and we fail
because institutionally we have to we
follow directions that don't make sense
we do what we're asked to do like put a
picture that's on this USB Drive on my
cake right so Shawn why how did you just
what are you doing here well the idea of
talk on failure started with my talk at
Walmart spark on conference about a year
ago and during the usual post hoc Q&A I
got asked about Active Directory stuff
which is great I love talking about it
and someone said have you ever failed in
any of this like are you kidding me all
the time all the time but that's that
just gave me that idea of people only
see your successes they see you as this
person that does great things in this
area and a lot of times people don't
want to talk about the things that
didn't go right
the problems they had the things that
went wrong how they got to that point
and this idea was Reese parked so to
speak when I was talking about the
concept of failure at Derby con with
Waxwing was manning the Trimark booth so
here we are this is not a real agenda so
chalk this up as a failure of
expectation you expected the something
that outlines this journey yes there'll
be a personal anecdote I'll talk about
some technical failures of mine how to
be better failures part of success and
yes we will have to close out with some
motivational quotes I will put the
slides up on ad security org I know that
doesn't make sense but that's what I
have and I forgot to do that so I'll
save that for later so about me my name
is Shawn Metcalf and founder Trimark
security company we have a booth out
there come say hi a Microsoft Certified
Master in Active Directory
what about 100 in the world most of them
worked for Microsoft though I've spoken
in a number of conferences I'm very
happy to say that first time I ever
spoke on stage at a conference was abbé
sieyès charm the first 'besides charm so
I'm very happy to be back here on stage
talking you I felt failure which doesn't
make sense in that context but I'm a
security researcher consultant and I own
and operate 80 security org which who's
heard of that ok cool for those who
haven't heard of it please check it out
it's pretty great you don't have to
listen to me Jessica mentioned it
earlier so all right so this is where
normally the talk would pivot and talk
about here's what we did we pivot we
based on this we did this we did that
again this is a different type of talk
so we're gonna start by highlighting my
failures in my about slide I dropped out
of college male graduating I despite the
fact that I successfully attended a
community college for two years and I
went to a four-year university I was a
Microsoft MVP for a single year and not
renewed I have had talks rejected at
shmoocon Chaka Khan a black hat and I
restarted 80 security out org after a
failed attempt at blogging a long time
ago so I guess the real question is why
are you here
I mean this is a talk about failure
hopefully not everyone's here to see me
fail on stage that would be kind of
awkward but if it happens it happens so
I'll just say it was part of the talk so
we'll go with that but ultimately the
wise Master Yoda says the greatest
teacher know your ass and it's true
so one of my favorite hobbies is
photography and I started photography in
high school as many people did with
something to look like this that you
something called like this called film
and the crazy thing about film is you
just couldn't take pictures all day long
go click click click click click click
etc you had 24 to 36 exposures depending
on that film canister and so you have to
be very careful and deliberate of the
pictures you took and you have to ensure
that you had the right exposure setting
the right shutter speed and make sure
everything was perfect for that picture
otherwise it wouldn't turn out right so
I learned about photography my font for
my father was very into photos I love
taking pictures and so when my mother
was pregnant with me he of course took
his camera into pictures and so we take
a deliberate picture of this deliberate
picture of when I was born in the
hospital and later on with my mother
holding me and then once I was brought
home and eventually my mom goes hey Jim
I'd love to see those photos and he says
absolutely and she's like yeah and they
better be good because you said no to
the wedding of the photographer at the
hospital that came in to take a picture
of me and Shawn so yeah I want to see
these will be really good and so he said
great I'll get them for you and here
they are there are no baby photos of me
when my mom was pregnant with me when I
was born and a little time thereafter
why well back then when you had the film
you had to load the camera my father
forgot to load the camera
so quite an epic fail they didn't make
up got through that I'm still here but I
learned a lot from that I learned from
his mistakes with cameras and
photography now I use digital I back up
my photos everywhere I have to memory
cards in the camera it writes to both of
those cards I take it out I copy it to
my computer it cloud backups it goes
over here I've got photos all over the
place because I don't want to be in a
situation where those photos are gone so
let's talk a little bit about my journey
some other failures and major risks that
I took I got an F in European history
because I didn't understand that the
tests were entirely based on what the
instructor wrote on the whiteboard or
the blackboard I didn't realize I had to
write down everything that he wrote up
there and that nothing that was covered
by the test was actually in the book I
failed to understand what was actually
being tested and why and then the next
test came around I was like alright I'll
take some notes but I didn't write down
everything that was on the board and I
failed the test again I failed to
understand what the point of it is which
again right now I kind of fail to
understand the point of it but I
realized that I learned how to take
better notes because I was not doing
what I was supposed to I was not hitting
the level hitting the mark that I should
have been I interviewed with the emcee
twice and I was not hired honestly I
would not have hired me back then I had
the first interview I failed the
interview I said hey can you give me
another chance I can really do this I
could work for you guys like EMC this
would be cool right they gave me a phone
interview like no sorry you're not good
enough and I wasn't and I learned from
that I learned it from the questions
they asked what they were looking for
and it wasn't a good fit I wasted a lot
of time on useless stuff such as arguing
on audio-visual forums building my own
IMDB inventory of DVDs using Microsoft
Access yes I'm an extreme nerd I've
taken measured risks I left a company of
a hundred thousand employees to join one
with less than ten and then to see that
company grow to two
and fifty and eventually gets old I paid
over $10,000 to go after an elite
certification the MCM started my own
company
and then with that company I developed a
service offering that is very much like
what Microsoft does except we take it
from a different perspective that's a
risk people ask all the time well how
are you different than Microsoft come by
our booth I'll tell you so Albert
Einstein is one of the greatest minds in
history and he said that failure is
success in progress for him failure was
a very perfect component in how to get
to success he recognized that you're
gonna make mistakes you're gonna learn
from these mistakes Albert had plenty of
mistakes he couldn't speak fluently
until he's nine he was expelled from
school because he was rebellious and
didn't like what was going on he was
denied admittance to a Technical
Institute and he split the atom trying
to make beer okay the last ones I got
from a documentary called young Einstein
so I think it's accurate moving on so KT
matharis great person you should follow
her if you're not she pointed out that
quantum magazine had this article on
Einstein being on the verge of finishing
a theory that would replace Newtonian
gravity
I mean epic right except he made a
critical last-second error that had him
doubting himself one of the greatest
minds in history was doubting himself
he's like this isn't working I can't do
this but ultimately you want to keep
going you can do great things you're
gonna make mistakes along the way you
haven't noticed it's not your typical
con talk I love this chart I've seen it
on the Internet in multiple places we go
from being a beginner I know nothing
phase to what's referred as the hazard
phase I'm an expert in this area
eventually we move to the section or the
level at which we are an expert because
other people tell us we are but
realistically if you ask us we'll say
yeah I know a bunch of stuff about this
but I really know nothing because
there's so much that I could know about
so again in these kind of talks if I was
up on the Ted stage I would probably put
up some definitions so let's do that
that looks good
it's a failure talk we should probably
define that right a lack of success the
omission of expected to require action
now this is a fun joke you know I could
throw up success also but one thing
found out I've discovered when I was
going through this and making these
jokes is that the original definition of
success was specified as achieving or
failing to achieve its aims right there
look it up so at one point success was
defined by also failing to do something
which is a really interesting thing to
recognize or understand and so I was
thinking what else don't I understand
properly or appropriately that maybe
I've been missing this guy said
inconceivable every time he was like
that's impossible there's no way you
could do that so guess what Shawn did
Shawn looked up the definition of
inconceivable it actually is not far off
than how he was using it in the movie of
course the problem is he's using it as
hyperbole he's saying it all the time
which means that a certain point once
all these inconceivable things happen
you probably should recognize that maybe
they will so there's anonymous poet that
I found wrote I still mess up but I'll
start again I keep falling down I keep
on hitting the ground I always get up
now to see what's next birds just don't
fly they fall down and get up I want to
try even though I could fail if only we
could know who this anonymous person is
because this is oh that's right Shakira
try everything and where did we find
this from Zootopia exactly thank you to
the person the second row with the kids
who has probably heard that song way
more than he ever needed to and so the
key behind this is obviously you want to
keep going you're gonna make those
mistakes I think it's a great message
for kids if you think about kids they
mess up all the time they're constantly
testing boundaries where do they do when
they learn how to walk they fall down
all the time the parents run over and
pick the
you know you have to learn these things
they're gonna learn they're gonna fall
down and get back up again which is a
great song for kids and adults and Tara
another great person to follow on
Twitter if you aren't being rejected
more than accept it you're not asking
for enough if you're winning constantly
or any rut oh this is great and I also
found a quote by JK Rowling who said
something very similar it is impossible
to live without failing at something
unless you live so cautiously that you
might as well not have lived at all in
which case you fail by default you were
a failure at not at failing and so JK of
course had his short unhappy marriage
after that she was a single mother who
no job living on welfare sank into the
depths of depression found healing and
writing and she wrote star wars actually
sorry it was Twilight sorry Jay King
just kidding JK so mental barriers this
is an interesting thing that a lot of
people don't realize they have these are
the things that are preventing you from
doing something that you might want to
do there you go I can't do that or maybe
you've had people in your life that said
no you can't do that or you need to do
this or you need to go down this path
you need to go to high school you know
you need to go to college you need to go
get a graduate degree then you go and
you do this academic thing because
that's what everyone else in your family
is done right we have mental barriers
all the time we look at something we say
there's it's not possible for me to go
there because there's an entire wall and
a gate on the top and some other gate
there and I just can't get there I can't
do it and so many people when they look
at a wall they go out see I guess I'll
just keep walking until I find a way
around it other people look at this wall
and go
I see handholds and footholds and I
think I could just climb over it and we
could just go where we want to go and so
the thing about failure is it's it's
more than just the attempting to do
something trying to do something it
happens all the time and one of the
things that I really enjoyed Jessica's
keynote this morning was talking about
questions when someone asks a question
you don't understand the question it
might not be because they're dumb it
might be that you're just missing what
they're asking and so I always go hmmm
that's a good question I wonder what
you're asking because the
the the way that I see it is that when
asking a question there are words in
that question that somebody's asking
there's my interpretation of what that
question is and then somewhere in the
middle is what's actually being asked
someone may ask you how do I do this
they don't necessarily want to know how
to do that specifically or they say I
need to implement X which to me sounds
like a solution but ultimately the thing
that I'm not gaining or gathering from
them is what is the problem they're
trying to solve I might tell them how
they can deploy that solution but if
that solution solution does nothing for
them and doesn't solve the actual
problem we have not helped at all
so as professionals we want to make sure
that when someone asks a question we
fully understand what they're asking
it's okay to ask for clarification it
doesn't make you look dumb
it's just a way to get more insight and
more understanding of what that person
is trying to communicate with you so
Walt Disney said the difference in
winning and losing his most office not
quitting which is a great quote this
from a guy who dropped out of school to
join the army and the army said no we're
not taking you before starting Disney he
had laughs a graham which went bankrupt
due to his inability to run a successful
business yeah Walt Disney amy was fired
from a Missouri newspaper for not being
creative enough really that's pretty
incredible Walt Disney I'm pretty sure
everyone here has heard of Disney
especially since we were talking about
Shakira and Zootopia there's a book that
I really like and graduates tend to be
given this as a present called oh the
places you'll go and it talks about
you'll do good things will do bad things
they'll be this they'll be that it's
kind of interesting microcosm of life
about the challenges and things you'll
go through but one of my favorite parts
of this book is about a place called the
waiting place waiting for a train to go
or a bus to come or a plane to go or the
mail to come or the rain to go or the
phone to ring or the snow to snow or
waiting around for a yes or no waiting
for their hair to grow everyone is just
waiting waiting for the fish to buy it
or waiting for the wind fly a kite or
waiting around for Friday night or
waiting perhaps for their Uncle Jake or
a pot to boil or a better break or a
string of pearls or a pair of pants or a
wig with curls or another chance
everyone is just waiting by eating and
then it goes on and says no but that
won't be you you're gonna move on for
the waiting place so many people that I
know have just been waiting what do I
mean by this I mean waiting for
something to happen waiting for
something to happen in their life
waiting for a promotion waiting for
their boss to recognize them waiting for
the opportunity work on a cool project
that they want to work on waiting for
something to happen you can make that
change you can instead of wait and go I
volunteer to work on that project that
sounds really great or tell your boss
and say you know what I know it's not
required but I'm just gonna send you a
list of things that I do every week and
here's what I've worked on and here's
what you know I did and was able to get
done volunteer that information because
it will help you to stop waiting and
actually actualize the things that you
want to do so you see the elephant you
know what I'm talking about what am I
gonna say how do you drink wine with an
elephant in a top hat right no do you
mean elephant one bite at a time which
reminds me of a book by dr. leo called
baby steps and it's about how to live
life one step at a time and dr. Leo
helped a guy named Bob get out of his
office get onto the elevator walk down
the street and get on the bus how do you
do this because he told Bob don't think
about the bus and where you're going
think about the steps that it takes to
get to the door in this office and then
from there to the elevator and then the
next step and then Bob figured it out
and he did great and they made a movie
called what about Bob it was fun but for
a lot of people what they're doing and
where they're headed
seems like this big expansive desert
just looming over them something that
they just couldn't possibly get to the
end of and it's challenging it's
something like just I can't do this it's
too far it's too much others look at
this and go alright what's on the other
side of that desert there's I'm working
toward something there's something
important that I want to get to maybe
it's a beautiful beach and I walk
through all this sand I get to that
beautiful beach and I can relax and
lounge on the on the on the sand swim in
the in the ocean and really enjoy it
and make milestones make points along
the way that says okay I'm gonna reward
myself as I go through each of these
parts when I was going through and
taking Microsoft tests to get certified
as a Microsoft mcse and cm all those
what I did was I said I will reward
myself every time I pass a test
I'll go get ice cream and then when I
finish the whole thing and get the
certification I'll do something a little
bit bigger right because then I had
something to look forward to and it
wasn't such a chore at that point
because I was thinking also about that
fun thing that I would be doing later
so Curlin Harland Sanders says one has
to remember that every failure can be a
stepping stone to something better
something greater and this from a man
who founded a number of various
businesses which all failed
he didn't begin Kentucky Fried Chicken
till he's 65 years old and his recipe
was rejected a thousand times before
accepted and before calling a Kentucky
Fried Chicken it was called big bucket o
chicken all right maybe maybe not so
let's talk about some of my failures if
you try to fail and succeed which have
you done I have done many things so I'm
going to talk about a few different case
studies of things that I failed at
technically that I've worked on that I
thought would go a different way
fixing permissions so I was working as
this organization and I was new so I was
like make this great I'm gonna do
wonderful things it's gonna be fantastic
I tell my boss you know what boss boss
need a better name so Joe boss nice
knowing you
I'm gonna fix these permissions on these
shares so I took a Saturday I went in
and I used this wonderful tool called I
cackles and I'm like I'm gonna do this
and I sat down I started typing out the
commands manually first mistake and I
ran it through all the shares and
proceeded to lock myself out of
everything this was a wonderful Saturday
much like today where the Sun was
shining the birds were singing and I'm
sitting inside the data center banging
my head against the computer because I
locked everything out I changed for mrs.
I shouldn't have
I had no backup I had no backup plan
and I did not pre write the commands
that I had typed and like a dummy I
typed CLS at some point so I had no idea
what I'd run yes so much much much much
much later that night I was able to
revert all my changes and I finally left
it something like 2 or 3 in the morning
the next day so I have the slide up
there for people looking at this later
but final result failed
so let's talking about something more
interesting or or better detecting
golden tickets so the first time I got
on the stage I talked about how to
detect golden tickets and why that was a
great thing because now defenders could
actually know if someone is using detect
golden tickets in their environment and
skip and skip duck law on Benjamin Delpy
at blackhat 2014 presented on Kerberos
golden tickets how you could use many
cats to actually create and forge a
ticket they gave you access to
everything in the network in the
environment now of course you need to
have admin rights initially but in doing
this you could basically write your
ticket to whatever you want and a few
months later certainly you came out with
a white paper saying definitively there
is no clear indication of such attack in
Windows logs I decided not to listen to
them why because I was thinking there's
got to be a way maybe they didn't look
at something maybe I could figure it out
so what I did was I started thinking
about how that might work
here's Benjamin Delpy working in his
home office on his computer banging
against Kerberos with skip on Twitter DM
or a Skype call or whatever trying to
figure this out and on the other side we
have the Microsoft developers someone
from Kerberos someone from the operating
system someone from network someone from
the event log conditioned configuration
sitting in a room white boarding out and
setting up the specs and making sure it
lines up and things get logged correctly
so my hypothesis was maybe maybe Ben
missed something so I had to figure out
what the anomalies were what was
something that didn't look right what
was something that just didn't fit
maybe they labeled something that was
different than how Microsoft labeled it
maybe there was something that just
wasn't there that should have been there
or something that should have been there
that was maybe there was something that
was just so obvious that everyone had
missed it or maybe just maybe they had
done it their way because they found
that that's the way that worked ah
cinnamon so I looked at the event logs
after running through the attack in my
lab and I looked at it and I stared at
these for quite a while and I'm like dad
there's nothing here
it all looks normal I don't see anything
that's missing anything that's obviously
different yeah I use Star Wars
characters in my in my lab so Darth
Vader would normal in this situation
maybe not in your network but when I put
them together and compare them
side-by-side I said wait a second
something is obviously different and
obviously wrong here and that's how I
figured it out and I was able to figure
this out because I started looking at
things and comparing them making a
baseline of what normal is and making it
and then looking at what was different
you can do the very same thing on your
network in fact what you should do is
baseline normal in order to best
understand what's different anomalous
and again this is for people later on
there look in the slides success I
figured it out but at first I didn't I
missed it I spent several days looking
at this and I was like well maybe sir to
use right and I went did something else
and I'm like no there's got to be
something there and I went back to it
another failure case study of mine
Microsoft MVP status when MVP means
making vacation plans so two years ago
around this time I tweeted out I'm
excited to announce that I'm now a
Microsoft MVP whoo that's great
I was excited get some cool benefits it
be part of the club right let's be vited
out to Redmond to go to their super
secret meetings just kidding there
Doronin and then about 16 months or 14
months later I got an email that started
out in reviewing your impact I'm sorry
to inform you
now anyone who reads emails knows this
is never going to be a good email so
after that I'm like wow this this is not
feeling so great okay so I went to
Twitter and I was like hey guys just so
you know I was really excited I'm not an
MVP anymore so you can take me off this
list I guess just learned I'm no longer
a Microsoft MVP last year I was the
first first-time MVP and I missed that
community but I'll still keep sharing
things because I enjoy what I do and the
response and the reaction of this was
really pretty great I started getting
responses that were just like very
heartwarming very real very touching and
people all across the community were
like hey you're doing good things don't
worry about it
don't worry about what Microsoft thinks
we think you're good we think you're
great
your mom probably thinks you're always
in our MVP MVPs titles don't matter
still an MVP titles they'll make the man
and that was really great and then
probably the icing on the cake was when
Jessica talked me into submitting to
Microsoft blue hat last year late which
was in November and I was accepted to
speak about act directory security and
so I talked to Microsoft about the
problems I see in things that should be
fixed in front of an audience mostly of
Microsoft these I proceeded to live edit
my about slide which was fun and at this
point I can laugh about it because you
know what it's not a big deal I do what
I do because I love it I enjoy it it's
challenging for me and then rally sec
said hey guess what Sean you're a rally
2nd VP so thank you rally sack for
keeping the MVP dream alive
so again final results I'm not really
sure what the final results is here but
I'm okay with it
failed research topics so I've done a
number of posts on 80 security out org
and a number of posts and presentations
about things that I've looked at and
found out well there's a number of these
that never made it to the blog because
they just didn't work the way I thought
they would
one was removing Kerberos rc4 encryption
to stop attacks there's so many rc4
attacks in Kerberos Kerberos ping
initially golden tickets and forged
tickets but now they use AES for them so
that doesn't really help but there's a
number of them and I started writing a
blog post like I normally do I started
with the information about what's behind
it I write it's a few paragraphs to
provide the foundation of the
information that's there and then I go
dig into what I'm talking about
I was so certain that this was going to
work I started writing the blog post in
fact I really went into detail about
what this was I wasted a lot of time
writing this blog post and it never got
to where I thought it would be now I'm
gonna go back and test this again with
2016 and Windows 10 but it'll probably
be the same result but that's okay
because I'll learn something from it I
know what works and what doesn't so when
a customer goes and says hey I can just
remove Archie 4 right like well I tested
that out
doesn't seem to work that way and that's
something that I've learned that's
something that's helpful
the other one I looked at was an attack
using the land turtle attack which was
this hack 5 device called land turtle
plugs into the USB Drive it has a nick
on it and Rob fuller akmu bik's came out
with this attack where he realized that
if you put this little land turtle
device or USB armory which is just a
little computer on a USB stick if you
plug it in basically it's boots that
Nick and by using DHCP and responder you
start getting credentials for the person
ntlm credentials for the person that's
logged in and locked on that system and
I'm like well I can block this there's
got to be a way to block this right I'm
gonna do this and I started writing all
this great stuff about how it works and
how I'm gonna block it and all this
other things I did figure out how to
block it but nobody here has read that
blog post why because it's not effective
there's a device ID for a land turtle
there's a device ID for a USB Armory
device because when you plug in the USB
device it goes on this device ID here's
why that doesn't work USB is
packet-based
and the device is telling the computer
information about itself when does that
ever work right so I had a GPO that
would block that device ID and stop it
from working but all you have to do is
modify the configuration information in
that USB device so it's a different
device ID
now I'm Microsoft keyboard I'm allowed
right I did I was successful one point
though I did successfully break my
laptop by blocking all the USB devices
which I don't recommend you do and I had
to do a full restore and recovery on it
which is why I don't use my own
production laptop anymore for that kind
of testing so I failed on that but I
learned a lot from it so Michael Jordan
said I failed over and over and over
again in my life and that is why I
succeed Michael Jordan one of the
greatest basketball players ever was cut
from his high school basketball team he
tracks his own failures he knows he's
missed more than 9,000 shots he's lost
almost 300 games and that Michael Jordan
himself will tell you he has missed the
game-winning shot 26 times Wow and then
he let her steam the beat aliens in a
championship basketball game so I mean
the guy is amazing by the way if you
haven't seen the documentary Space Jam I
highly recommend it but ultimately
mental state matters Barney Stinson from
How I Met Your Mother said when I get
sad I stop being sad be awesome instead
true story right so I have this rule
where something happens I get upset by
it I give myself 24 hours I can be upset
about I can do whatever I want just be
frustrated withdraw a day later I start
figuring out and problem solving but
ultimately depression is no joke get
professional help thankfully the rock
has helped me write these slides because
he came out recently and talked about
challenges and and difficulties with
depression in his life and he said that
one of the most important things
realizing you're not alone your friends
and family reach out and the rock a 23
years old was cut from the Canada
Football League yes they have a football
league this is the rock that got cut
from the Canada football league at 23
seven dollars in his pocket he had to
move back in with his parents you got
very depressed got very sad about this
so for him failure is something that he
embraces he pushes forward with that he
recognizes it doesn't work for everybody
but it works for him and he's been very
successful in doing so and again thank
thanks the rock and underarmor they put
together a campaign about talking about
failure and using it to get better my
personal philosophy always making my
past failures inform my current actions
and the rock has been one of the most
successful people well you know of our
time you might say wrestling's fake but
not everyone gets to get these titles
this many time and Hulk Hogan certainly
has not said of anyone else that he's
the biggest superstar in the business
the guy has been on Forbes top 100 most
powerful celebrities it's been at number
25 and since then he's been in the top
so just because things aren't working
out out now doesn't mean things won't
work out later Sam Jackson great actor
right he didn't really get successful
until he was like in his 50s it takes
time sometimes it doesn't work the way
you want it to at this point in time
there might be a reason for that it
might not be your time now but it might
be later so there's a book that I love
called the charisma mint and basically
it talks about mental state being
everything you start with the mental
state if I can do this and even I will
do this when I look and try to figure
out golden ticket detection I started
with the thinking of there's got to be a
way to detect this there has to be
something that is different about the
way that this attack gets logged I was
successful on that I wasn't in other
things but I started with that and
positivity breeds positive results and
one of the things that I like to do when
I'm not feeling so hot or so great stand
up straight
roll back my shoulders take five deep
and go I can do this it helps a lot so
info sex failure story time I reached
out to some friends who gave me some
stories and I picked a couple of them
then i'ma share with you one of them
said years ago I wrote my first snort
signature probably my 10th looking for
content PowerShell that's it any port
any protocol etc for all our network
devices in the world nearly brought down
our back-end for processing these hits
about half a million hits in 15 minutes
and they set up new QA processes for him
but it opened his eyes to a completely
different way for looking at host-based
detectors indicators over the wire and
he went on to write nearly a hundred and
fifty snort signatures over the next
several months based entirely on that
who is this person
Daniel Bohannon who has been the person
the name in PowerShell obfuscation he
has learned from his mistakes and he
pushes forward because of them some
would say despite them so I talked to
some pen testers and they said I are
porous poison the 24 I was in which
happened to be where all the IT staff
worked i dost them all they couldn't
work for three hours I locked an entire
domain out what I didn't fully
understand how lockout observation
window operated affected 2500 users use
hash dump on a DC from interpreter blue
screen the DC which was the PDC emulator
caused a little bit of problems now so
these are a few different people I'm not
gonna name them but in conclusion you
can't completely fail at something if
you never stop trying right and there's
a movie I watched recently which had a
quote in it which didn't really seem to
fit the movie that I was watching well
that was pretty good
and the quote was if you want to make
the world a better place take a look at
yourself and make a change who Michael
Jackson said that quote and actually it
was Batman ultimately we have the power
and the ability to change who we are and
what we're doing or where we are in this
point in time we can leverage our
failure to push forward with what we're
doing it's ok to fail Silicon Valley has
a saying called fail fast venture
capitalists usually will not fund
a new company in Silicon Valley unless
the founders have already failed at a
couple of other companies first why is
that why wouldn't they do that why would
they hire the person or why would they
put millions of dollars into a company
that has failed the guy behind it has
failed why would we do that because
they've learned from it they said okay
well we're going to go into this
business that didn't work we're gonna
pivot we're gonna do this and how we're
gonna do cybersecurity so give me all
your money
so Katie masseurs again said never
believe anyone who doesn't believe in
you reject the reality and substitute
your own give everything you have to
whatever you set your mind to you can
climb the unclimbed wall when you look
back you'll reflect on how well you
accepted the opportunities in front of
you and acted upon them I love this
because so often we go to a friend and
we say hey I'm gonna go do this and
they're like that's a really dumb idea
then we go okay I guess it's done right
why why do we do that why when we're so
excited about something do we tell
someone else about it and we accept them
saying no that's stupid why would you
ever do that right
I'm gonna start a company where we're
not actually gonna have any cars we're
not gonna hire anybody but we're gonna
have people drive around cars and pick
them up and deliver them places right oh
that's a dumb idea we already have that
it's called taxis I'm gonna start a
company where I'm gonna rent out other
people's places I've never met them in
my life to other strangers who I've
never known but I'm gonna connect them
and I'm gonna call it Airbnb people are
like that's dumb why would you ever want
to do that that can't be something
that's going to be a good idea but they
persisted they kept moving despite the
negative feedback they said this is a
great idea I know it is I'm gonna try it
and if I fail I will have learned
something so Robert Schuller has a few
quotes that I'm going to share with you
and these are some of my favorites and
these are things that I really
internalized what goals would you be
setting for yourself if you knew you
could not fail it's a very interesting
effect on your psychology I'm I love
psychology I read a lot of things about
how psychology works the psychology of
selling psychology of people ultimately
we don't do something because we have
fear we have fear of failure right what
would happen if we couldn't fail in that
endeavor how would we handle things
differently how would we move forward
what would be our choices so if you
couldn't fail at it what would you be
doing differently now
or if you could fail in a way that where
you were completely safe where failure
doesn't mean anything there's no
negative results of that failure
you'd be much more inclined to do that
right so what I try to do is look at it
and go okay what's the worst possible
thing that could happen and then I walk
back from that and inevitably I get back
to something that's not so bad
building on that what dreams would you
have on the drawing board if you had
unlimited financial resources I worked
with a realtor to look at houses and he
took me to several houses one day and he
goes okay Sean if somebody gave you one
of these houses which one would you take
cuz he was asking me about questions
about I was like I don't know I don't
know I like this one I like that when I
was being very wishy-washy said but if I
gave you this house which one you take I
said none of them cuz none of them
really fit none of them are really what
I would want would I would I would want
to get it's not me and what he did is he
took the financial component out of it
and now I could make decisions without
that being something that was in my mind
something that was holding me down from
actually looking at the things that
really matter ultimately financial stuff
does matter but to a different extent I
worked with a guy who had this saying
where he said okay but for five dollars
more if you could have this on your
network would that be something you
would want to do five dollars right
changes the whole dynamic because
someone will go well I can't do that
that's too expensive what Jessica talked
about this morning in the keynote which
I really love and which I preached all
the time is you have a lot of tools in
your utility kill in your utility bill
right you can use these you can use all
of these for utilities in order to lock
things down and make them better to
protect the environment without having
to spend a lot of money sure there's
gonna be some things you're gonna spend
money on but a lot of things that are
the most impactful are things like the
Windows Firewall that are free it just
takes your time to figure out and
there's resources on the Internet to
help with that
what plans would you be making if you 30
years to carry them out again taking
time out of this consideration out of
this conversation I'm too old I can't do
that all this stuff's already been
figured out I'm coming out of college I
just got my degree everyone has already
done all the cool stuff absolutely not
one word for you
if you're graduating college or high
school and you're concerned about all
the cool stuff has already been done
cloud nobody knows what it is everybody
wants to use it become a cloud expert
and own the next ten years of your life
so I love these three because they each
take one major factor out of it fear of
failure financial concerns time those
are the three factors that often weigh
down on how we decide things how we
think about things but my favorite quote
and the one that I pretty much live by
these days is a year from now you'll be
a year older what are you gonna do Ramiz
said he said this and I use this because
I'm like absolutely as you get older
time goes faster when you're five it
seems like it's gonna be forever until I
finished my dinner and I get my cookie
right when you're 12 it's like it's
forever until I'm gonna get to go to the
mall and buy that thing I want to buy
time speeds up in another year there's
gonna be another b-sides charm what is
it that you want to achieve don't let
the fear of failure hold you back thank
you very much that's been my time thank
you for yours
[Applause]