[Applause]
we're the enemy or really Victor has
some type of physical embankment usually
sighs we have resources are better right
it's no longer just a physical attribute
if your nature or your company or your
there is more resources you're gonna win
the worst attrition right knowledge
right physics you have analog dictated
that's why the little space race
reference about soccer my ornament is
that innovation
oh wait we're picturing this active
everyone because because we have a
required curriculum a portrait of all
kiss haptic and my curriculum for system
sharing and this is the capstone
students that they undergo this case
it's not paid your long wonder what so
when it gets kind of apply this ball
statement that does reading it to us how
to use artificial plugins to not really
work terrorist organizations five
Schuster's what just came up with as
part of this
rapid work but she's a party didn't like
as a potential for distraction using a
y22 powers laptop they didn't help I'll
have expertise may be back home students
themselves chief Connor bottom extremist
organizations they wire on the best ways
like not just technical everybody both
muttering screams of terror so in that
background I guess that's like there's
like much of these systems Twitter it
out these and Balkan walls
later on the South we would hear about a
map it to some white people try to get
some metrics to figure out what's the
best way of many projects use and very
quickly some value Democrats for those
inventors best respect right oh come on
technological one in the middle some -
what I learn from this right that's good
and a good thing as the instructor at
West Point
you know chemists ga3 all professors I
had to call out who sent us it's the
great research scientist at home except
I was able bring these projects in run
around estimate impact with a team like
TVs difference and extension between
human and machine what the advantages
are for each swatch a very low level
approaches
[Music]
if you don't want the curl in more
bigger warning bigger
[Applause]
okay it was all big till today I thought
when we do have sonogram challenge that
again part of this network Healy
supplements your cell phone
[Music]
[Applause]
first thing they reversed
[Music]
I also hate our bull just this
superiority with cyber Werner I'm wrong
sir point of you go with legendary
bionics that's a good sign
this is awesome
pulse with Doctor Who shooters on will
surprise that scene as many as four
words because for me the best
you don't care this how much like
putting this bubbles baseball my Star
Wars promise block that right as Darth
Vader comes more more mechanized now
that we've heard all these stories
ranking Google just to Google search for
all these it's amazing right all these
that's why you drinking a lot Martha
Cheney is a great piece I Sparkle on
planting east excellence and truly pop
this even just to stop this from
adversaries who are adjusting their
purple of a daily basis to performer
other under face reality spending than
fiction
right burgers Facebook's artificial
language the other side but again if I
get something whether you forget this
something is something researchers did
not intend and it's not just from us
there's China China's attempt at there
almost watch your black piece of
government and as he's next what those
are as opposed to things that are
contrary to the economists but here's an
interesting point I actually know this
China won because I give another talk on
innovation hub of innovation and speed
with which the weight is high the
Chinese are learning just like Facebook
just like Microsoft just like try this
morning we can get more and more reports
of a lie
I've seen Stanford in China time
researchers just came up with a language
program that's actually much better
things researchers so that's a concern
when I see you them a family that's
actually a good song experimental
problem epoxide wristers another way
learning warm-up me the orbital is me
doing and then pull thread Caston twice
here and we have more audience actually
to my colleagues are key members of this
group
[Applause]
yeah or private my sleep depends people
I sort of do what this plan I can warm
cybers to be more body that's pretty
good and I told my cadets my shoulder my
cup sticks general pretty good read my
capsule or so I guess that could be my
socially very way of just telling them I
think I made it to college was its
Anthony and the great news is I pick up
this talk really as an introduction talk
about quantitative methods use on to a
better party place what marketer needs
now visit this very short climb not be
revisit this much of what my concern
actually have my thickness myself by the
worst case
[Applause]
Nicholas better find this case car beeps
lights team all the folks in are the
harp and given honking - is a great job
after 140 right well here's I'll shut
this down
[Applause]
so I got C's me Alicia Keys past Mike
all right
[Applause]
you know like so many changing hands
everyone assumed I'd swap are you happy
so it might be this
we were talking what what he was up
there he was talking that was not a
check the pansies are all set the left
[Music]
you can turn so like all things and like
all things on our campus we study when
troubleshooting so my apologies it looks
like this money is mustard all right
I'll do my test awesome
[Music]