[Music]
[Applause]
good morning and welcome to Panama City
Panama for ICANN 62 our Policy Forum we
are very excited to be here in the Latin
American Caribbean region for this
meeting and we thank our local hosts for
the warm welcome they have given us it
is important to note that I can meetings
I am we that I can we promote a safe and
harassment free environment for all
during the sessions the ICANN ombudsman
wants to remind us to follow the ICANN
acceptable standards of behavior and the
community anti-harassment policy our
opening session this morning is a very
special one we will hear remarks from
Keith gracyk a community representative
Sherine Shalaby ICANN chair
Joran marbie president and CEO and our
honored guest today this is the fifth
multi-stakeholder ethos award which was
started in London at ICANN 50 it is an
invaluable effort led by the community
and a selection panel comprised of
representatives from the various
supporting organizations and advisory
committees appointed by their leadership
to identify fellow community members
each year who follow and embrace the
values represented in this award the
criteria talks about one a demonstrated
ability to work across the community
lines with an aim of consensus building
and collaboration to the person should
be a facilitator of dialogue and a fair
and collegial manner engaging people
from various backgrounds cultures and
interests and finally the third criteria
demonstrated contributions of time spent
supporting the multi-stakeholder model
through the voluntary service in various
working groups and other activities
[Music]
[Applause]