all right so welcome welcome to having a
picket illiterate or malware stagers and
Enterprise Services this is a very
windows heavy Oh a little bit about
myself I'm with the Department of
Defense been within roughly eighteen
years started off as a system
administrator moved into sock defense if
you will about six years ago let an
incident response team through a number
of high visibility incident and then
moved over to vulnerability assessment
Red Team if you will and now I'm going
to the director of an operation center
where we do both vulnerability
assessment Red Team and incident
response
I'm a adjunct sub security professor and
a local college down in the gusted
Georgia that's why I come to you all
from
I developed a number of red and blue
team tools I like PowerShell you'll see
that throughout this and I'm out
throwing the interwebz in a couple of
places alright so here's the agenda well
really highlight really the history of
such talking about some malware talking
about the kill chain or a methodology
will go through utilizing said
methodology or tactic to to hide stagers
and enterprise services and then I'll
end this with a demo in which I'll
highlight or really walk through each
one of those all right so first we got
to kind of start off with definition so
this whole malware thing all right what
is it
well you see a lot of text up there but
really the meaning potatoes of it is is
that malware is gonna be an actual piece
of code developed by somebody to
actually inflict something on a person's
machine whether they want to actually
take it down whether they want to take
over it but nonetheless it's gonna be
code at heart it's kind of interesting
when we think about malware
now there's different variations of it
but before we even get into that let's
let's talk about where it all started
well roughly back in 1971 there was a
guy by the name of Ben Thomas who
actually developed the creeper malware
and literally what it did is right
through the screen I'm a creeper
catching me if you can and it propagated
by hand it was very manual in nature
we're talking floppy disks right can't
even find a floppy disk these days
I say that like some organization still
have um but that's that was the first
piece of what we know to be malware and
it relied on human interaction that's
kind of interesting because now today we
don't see human interaction being a
necessity as much right and today we see
things that are much more sophisticated
right much more streamlined may be
broken up to different phases if you
will and they're constantly evolving
it's a constant cat-and-mouse game from
a defense perspective you're
consistently trying to highlight what
adversaries are doing trying to put
things in place in which you can
articulate and really highlight the
activities that they're doing and as a
red team where vulnerability assessment
person you're just sitting there trying
to find some loophole buzz that software
and find something that allows you to
gain some code execution and even better
a shell a root shell is really what
we're after right but it also has some
financial gain with it because we have
criminals doing it for the purpose of
financial gain
we have government's doing it right
trying to get after the political game
and in all honesty it's almost like a
silent war happening that we don't see
on the streets or really see as much in
the news and let's it's some wine owned
company of source so when we look at the
common types of malware all right we see
what's before us and generally speaking
I think worms and viruses are kind of
the thing we previously always thought
about when we mentioned malware but now
we see a lot of rant so we're definitely
financial game right where somebody's
trying to get code execution on the
system they want to encrypt the drive
they want to hold the system for ransom
we see root kits that's always been a
thing all right there's user mode most
common there's actual kernel level very
sophisticated right at that point it
makes it a little bit more difficult to
trust the system to really even identify
it and then you have like a hypervisor
version of it so we can get in the inner
workings of actual working with virtual
machines Trojans kind of go without
saying key logs are definitely much more
prevalent especially when you think
about people trying to do things for
financial gains or gain in execution or
access to a machine then we have great
we're right adware spyware the bloatware
that comes on brand-new computers if you
will those are rare we're gonna be
around but all the malware has to have
some very have to have some method to
hide all right
unless you're like Rick James and you
don't really care typically you're gonna
want to hide your malware and some
typical aspects to do that is you're
gonna use some type of packer maybe A to
B X or something else where you want to
add your malware in with some legitimate
program maybe you want to use a new
krypter in which if somebody was trying
to re a to reverse engineer then that
payload and aspects of that data may be
encrypted may be much more difficult for
them to actually understand polymorphic
much more sophisticated consistently
changing its data set and itself as it
traverses right think of how signatures
are ever gonna find that heuristics um
good luck right so polymorphic is
definitely much more sophisticated then
we have stagers they've definitely on
the rise and this allows us to really
survey a machine or do something to a
machine before the real malware come
right so we can all think about some
sport maybe it's boxing
there's the main ticket and then there's
these other people who are boxing before
the main ticket we can almost think of
those other folks as the stages right
there prepping the battlefield if you
will getting everybody height or the
real deal and the real deal is gonna be
the malware I wish the stages come give
so a little bit more about these stages
we know the mesh droppers downloaders
but nonetheless they're they should be
tiny
all right you typically would not want
to use a full mega to payload as a
stager but generally speaking if we're
going to exploit on if that is the
method in which we're going to use to
get on the system we may have a little
minute limited amount of space that we
can actually use for our payload and
this is where stage are actually coming
good with us and once we get access to
that machine our stages should allow us
to actually interact with that machine
ie our stage will
that machine contact us so we can then
either task it for something else
or send an actual real payload that's
gonna actually sit residue on the system
now the big thing about this is it
allows us to break down our toolset
malware development is really expensive
either money-wise
or man our wise but nonetheless I'm not
gonna free willy nilly just throw my
payload all over the place and see what
sticks I want to get on a system survey
it understand if it's even a good
candidate for me to do something with it
and then at that point then lay it down
right maybe my surveying is what type of
antivirus they have on there what's the
state of the system is this a system
owned by somebody like my mother who
doesn't know much of what's going on in
the system or is this some aspiring
young computer science or some type of
admin a person who's really into the
machine now looking at the delivery
mechanism we have something like this we
have the system being exploited in our
stage or being part of it and then we
have the system reaching back out to our
c2 server generally speaking when that
system reaches back out is probably
gonna be on some type of well-known port
in which general client machines would
talk on right so I probably wouldn't
have my stage ever hosted at you know
quad floors or something like that in
that case would blend in a lot more with
normal traffic but when it reaches back
out and we're talking that military
there then I may have something else for
it to grab and it could be virus worm
something else right it could be just
other instructions but nonetheless it's
like that main ticket or that
heavyweight fight right my system is
gonna I'm sorry that systems gonna then
reach out grab whatever that next stage
is once we have that we're gonna set up
some type of encrypted c2 channel where
periodically every or whatever the case
we would then have the ability to
interact with each other
generally I wouldn't have that c2 server
actually initiate communication with
that implant or whatever my follow-on
payload is I'd have this guy on some
period of time
random period of time like I don't want
the periodicity to be so clear-cut where
you could be like hey every three hours
on the dot this thing is actually
reaching out with some periodicity in
which this guy may come out check my c2
server see if I got anything else for it
and then execute the mother who common
task goes without saying I want to
survey it what is this data the machine
I may have some other payloads that I
want to lay down but I want to ensure
that that system is has the requisite
software installed or maybe this thing
doesn't hold any true wealth for me to
be able to do something follow-on within
the organization this also allows me to
validate whether it's running in a
virtual machine or not right maybe this
is some honeypot of stores or if I
understand that organization and most of
their stuff is virtualized then I could
really deem that is normal if you will
the other thing about issues in a stager
is that additional payload we reach out
to grab we could actually inject that
into memory reflectively inject that DLL
and at that point our DLL wouldn't touch
disk the work being a little bit more
stealthier in that aspect
when we look at just a generalized
methodology of sorts we can refer to the
cyber kill chain cyber kill chain has
been around since roughly 2011 developed
by Lockheed Martin and there are a
number of methodologies that all kind of
articulate the same thing but ultimately
just highlight really how somebody would
look to do something so the interesting
thing about this is this is gonna be
linear in nature every step is almost
required for the next so if I had my
young child here you know my little five
year old and I was chasing him it would
be me trying to catch up to him instead
I'm gonna try to pass him get in front
of him so I can then block him or
entertain them or whatever it is my goal
is so the goal here are really idea here
from a defense perspective if you can
identify the methodology in which an
attack or an adversary would take you
can then get ahead of them so that way
you're not sitting there trying to
follow but you're more or less getting
around and then blocking stopping
identifying a mitigating aspects of
which they would need to achieve the
further go along
we're really gonna focus on here though
is not the exploitation perspective
we're gonna focus more on the
installment piece where we're actually
going to lay something down and then
we're going to utilize that to
communicate back with Darcy to serve all
right a common tactic to do this I wish
I had disclaimer here because this is
not the only way it is one of a few ways
to actually get off through it it's
almost like eating a rhesus right
there's no long way to really do that
unless you dip it in milk that just
that's not right oh so a way to do this
is we'll take whatever our data is we'll
convert it to bytes
well base64 and then we'll store it
somewhere so the premise of this talk is
utilized in Enterprise Services this is
specifically Microsoft we're gonna
utilize the very things that Microsoft
calls features and we're gonna store
some code there this code today is gonna
be benign it's just gonna print a string
back to the screen to let you know all
those well but this approach is very
post exploitation all right
this isn't telling you how to get on the
Box you're already on there now you're
looking at the next stage and this kind
of fits the category of paulus if you
know the interesting thing about this is
what we're going to lay down is our
stager is going to be an IP address or
it could be a URL and then we're gonna
lay down a URI off after that actually
specifying the file that we want
it's a download so what do we lose if
that gets burned well I lose an IP
address if I'm using an IP if I'm using
a domain I lost the domain I can go buy
another one for a dollar ninety-nine
cent and then whatever I specify is the
file that I'm downloading I could lose
that name right that doesn't really help
a defender because today the file that
I'm gonna host is call it stage or dot
ps1 but if you ask somebody what's in
that file nobody would know unless they
went out there and downloaded the sample
of it so what are you really losing
right I'm lessening the surface in which
I is an offensive person could become
burnt or show my hand as to what I'm
doing
all right so we'll start with Active
Directory Active Directory from an
enterprise perspective that's gonna be
the authentication authorization
mechanism for user accounts throughout a
network same thing with computers Active
Directory is a structure in which is
typically a raid of objects and the most
common objects are the users computers
and actual groups now the database
itself is stored in system 32 and TDS
that so if we were trying to take over
an organization maybe dump some hashes
it's not about us getting the same high
because that's gonna be local and
enterprise we would want that
that's another top the big thing about
this is when we look at Active Directory
users and computers we see the top
screenshot there cool we see things like
Oh use organizational units and then we
have sub oh use there as well and in
each under each one of those
organization units we may have other
objects in this case we have some users
we have some groups we also see some sub
organizational units as well interesting
thing about this is people aren't
typically quick to create users they're
not always typically quick to delete
users or if I move from one section to
the next they may give me or change my
rights it may not go back and take those
so we see things like privilege creep
and a number of other things come up but
from a GUI perspective that's how an
admin may look to actually access Active
Directory we can utilize something like
PowerShell and access Active Directory
as well and we see the same names there
that we see as part of that oh you there
if we were to click on an actual object
we're presented with a number of
properties about that object roughly
there's about 50 of them if we go tab
the tab we'll see these properties and
generally speaking each one of those
properties has the ability to store some
amount of data whether it's one
character 512 right it just really
varies from field to field now there's
also a number of fields that are not
shown by default generally speaking in
each one of those tabs if you're
familiar with acting director
you can go along the toolbar and
actually enable advanced features and
you'll get things like attribute editor
now an attribute editor will be able to
see the fields that are not typically
shown by default and I'll highlight that
is I do the demo so when we looked at
this user we're looking at the same
stuff within powershell so this is good
because if we can get our code in there
our stager domain users by default have
the ability to read objects in Active
Directory so that's cool now I can
almost beast using this as a file share
if you will and I can go from box to box
and have that user read that actual
account and grab that code
so now we we kind of moved to the
registry registry goes without saying it
is amazing from a defense perspective
it's awesome for forensics and artifacts
from an offense perspective
it is like a kid in a candy store
they're just too much right so if you've
ever been an admin I can tell you about
every key in the registry I'd be
interested right because there's just
way too much in there for any one person
to be able to know every particular key
so if that's the case that makes a good
place for us to get our code in and the
fact that we can get our code in allows
us to really skate under the radar a
little bit more now when we look at the
registry we have the hives that sit on
disk and then we have the hives that are
loaded into or what they assemble into
in memory upon the system booting up or
this or somebody actually logging in so
and the users profile there's an into
user that that is specific to the
individual user when he or she logs on
it becomes their HBCU and then we have a
system 32 we have stuff like hklm I'm
sorry a software system those along with
a number of other ones become what we
know is hklm now we also see the linkage
between those items so we have our hives
on this on the left and then we have
what they become and memory on the right
the good thing about this or not really
the good thing is if we were trying to
affect the security hi when the system
boots up it gets loaded into memory and
it's locked
all right so that's really really good
in the sense that we know it's gonna get
used it's gonna be loaded in so we can
get code in there it's a high
availability method for us to actually
use if we were just looking at the
registry we're used to seeing reg
editor right and for us to store code
there I like to go several layers deep I
like to look for just random places I
don't even care what the key is really
used for all right because the more
deeper is less likely somebody's gonna
be looking at it so in this case we're
not very deep but we're in the users
hive were within software and then
sysinternals
and then I see a key for the EULA so
they've used strings before and they
accepted that EULA and then
I can look at the same data by utilizing
PowerShell and I see the EULA
highlighted there the short here is
we're showing that you can utilize the
GUI but you can also utilize the command
line this is gonna be key once we get
into the demo piece because largely
everything I'm gonna do is then command
line and then we'll go back to what it
looks like in the GUI because that's
what most admins are gonna be utilizing
so have event logs so this is gonna be
detailed records of things happening on
the system generally speaking we have
audit entries that if enabled were right
to event logs if somebody was gonna wipe
an event log it would generate an event
11:02 so that gives some reassurance to
an admin that if they can write stuff to
the event log they have a good record
the interesting thing about this is
there's a huge amount of event logs like
huge right we see where those event logs
are stored at on this there are some
tactics to wipe event logs in a good way
actually I can't think of any good
reason why anybody would want to do it
but if we were doing it from an
adversary perspective there's a couple
of tactics that we can do it without
admin being able to see it they do
overwrite themselves so an admin likely
would have something write to the event
log and then ship it off to like Elks
Blanc or whatever their centralized log
aggregation server is but when we talk
about there's a huge amount just looking
after a server 2016 virtual machine I
had deep bought nothing special i had a
roughly 380 unique Long's not talking
about log entries we're talking about
unique logs
now generally admins know about security
system application may be some small
other ones but I don't know how many
people can name more than 15 20 logs
that are actually in the system so the
fact that we have several hundred gives
me some pleasure and utilizing this now
reading an event log we would use Event
Viewer the GUI aspect and we would see
an actual message and we see some other
data about it we can utilize power show
as you see below to essentially read
that log as well now if that's not
enough for you you have the ability to
write custom logs so from a defense
perspective maybe I have my dev shop who
developed this in-house tool and they
didn't build in any inherent logging so
now I can utilize something like
PowerShell write my own custom logging
to get it in the event logs from an
offense perspective I see a place in
which we create our own event log that
could we already got 385 what does it
matter we have 300
86 right we'll just add one more on to
it and now we can write our code there
and go back and retrieve it at another
time reading it is such like this so
I've made a new event log or actually I
made a source within the application
event log and then I wrote just an app
has started and then when I go look at
that an event viewer
I see the actual message that I depicted
and then I also am able to read that
very same thing utilizing some power
ship
we have group policy so group policy is
gonna be that that infrastructure that
utilizes implement specific
configurations across an enterprise all
right I remember my time as a as a
helpdesk person right they told me I had
the most important job in the
organization that was right before they
gave me the most work in the
organization right it was like hey we
need to update these machines and we
didn't have centralized management so I
was walking around with my disk now I'm
dating myself I had city booked but all
kinds of software and I realized that
was no way to treat a human being right
and you know we have things like goo
policy where we can set it once and
didn't have those settings proliferate
across an organization so it's a
wonderful thing and then again we find
areas that we can take advantage of it
from within Microsoft group policy
itself there's an enterprise management
perspective through policy management
and then we have the local machine has a
local group policy editor as well so
we're gonna look at doing it from a
enterprise perspective that's gonna give
us the most bang for the buck but either
one of them will suffice and the way
we're gonna do that is we'll look at the
group policy management from a server
perspective I have a default domain
policy which every domain would have
that I don't care if it's enforced
length or not but we have this think all
comments and over there I've never seen
an admin actually used it ever so for
this uh for the sake of this screenshot
here I just put in that this is the
default policy link to the domain or
whatever the right I'm gonna put text
there now but we're gonna utilize that
area to store our code awesome now
before I lay any code down I'm gonna
understand the infrastructure to really
highlight would this tactic work like
I'm not gonna go to every machine and
try to use MSO eight zero six seven
right because that's not gonna work
everywhere but I would want to
understand targeting which I'm
interacting with now our next one is
alternate data stream and some of you
may be like man really yeah hey it still
works all right just like that at six
seven one I just talked about
so alternate data streams resident
within NTFS filesystem
I'm generally speaking that's what our
systems are going to be
or Windows perspective um we have the
ability to really add in the stream of
data if you will and if we looked at the
size of the file our data stream size
does not affect our actual size of our
files so that's good now this was really
developed to have any capability match
with Macintosh systems but it's still
something that's available so every file
has a dollar sign data stream and then
we have specific files depending on how
your system is a raid but we could also
have zone identifiers have you ever been
downloading the file try to run it and a
pop-up said hey be careful this came
from the internet you shouldn't trust
stuff blah blah blah well that was a
zone identify 80s that was attached to
your file Sam that zone 3 or 4 whichever
one it is that tags it saying it came
from the Internet that's what
highlighting or really stopping you and
prompting you it's that zone identifier
80s that's being tad
so an example of this is really good so
I have a file that I created and right
now it has zero bytes I created an
alternate data stream that I'm gonna
call my stream and I'm gonna put my
son's favorite write dr. Seuss in there
and right now the length of that is
$35.99 but still the original file the
donor if you will is still that zero
bytes so if I'm gonna use this I would
look to want to do it on a bow that I
know that's gonna be there right
and one for example not the only one is
the host file right the host file if I'm
going to try to sinkhole a domain or
maybe redirect something locally then I
could utilize this host file and put in
an IP in an actual domain but regardless
of what's in the actual file itself I'm
just gonna be a straphanger with my
alternate data stream and really this
thing it's gonna be a donor form
we have environment variables they're
gonna be dynamic in nature so we were
using the environment variable username
I'm sorry user profile it would really
highlight the profile path for the user
that you're logged in it for example if
I'm logged in as a user called wolf and
I said hey change directory to
environment variable user profile it was
dynamically set to that environment
variable that might use a profile that's
the path of see users wolf blah blah
blah alright so it can be dynamically
set and this is good now we also have
the ability to have user environment
variables and system ones we're going to
look to get in the system one so that
way it doesn't matter per se which
person there's a lot of information
that's being utilized here to really set
what's going on in our operating system
and the same could be said about
whatever programs we have installed
there the same way we have our
environment path we can add other things
in
so in this case we have our user
environment variables up top I have the
system ones that are down in the bottom
these user ones are in my NT user diet
that for whatever user it is that I'm
logged in as and then these system ones
are part of hklm
from a GUI perspective a more from
ingoing perspective I have where I can
go into properties of computer and then
I can see up top my user environment
variables and down below my system ones
so we're gonna add one into our system
one we'll come back and check this
screen and we'll look at what an admin
would actually see and how he or she
could actually highlight that we have
something going on and we have a WMI and
sim alright so from this perspective WMI
was Microsoft's implementation of W bean
so w bins like how we're going to share
information across a subset of machines
within the last couple of years
Microsoft has gone away from that and
went to sim which is common information
module or model both of them somewhat do
the same thing WMI is gonna use decomp
sim is gonna use a thing called WS man
but ultimately the namespaces and
classes that were accustomed to from W
and Mark are still available so we're
gonna take advantage of that in the
sense of we have these classes
namespaces that have a particular set of
information about them so these classes
has properties and methods and
properties are nothing more than
attributes methods are nothing more than
actions and then if we want to interact
with them from a GUI perspective on our
system W beam has an actual executable
assistant 32 that we can connect to our
machine and access all our namespaces
and classes and we'll highlight that too
in our demo as far as how an admin can
see that but when we talk about the
sheer amount of them is gonna vary from
system to system just like when I add a
particular piece of software on my
system it may add a new registry key the
same is
or WMI and sim as far as classes so on
the machine that I ran a demo on I had
roughly 10,000 right refer back to my
comment about the registry if I can find
an admin that can tell me about more
than 10 classes I would be I wouldn't be
shocked I would want to actually talk a
little bit more right but 10,000 that's
a lot just on my system so if I have
10,000 112 what difference is it gonna
make if I add one more to it alright and
that's what we'll do this is gonna help
us with storing our code having it in
the place in which an admin largely it's
not going to see it so that makes it
great for us when we want to come back
and actually grab
okay so now we're going to demo
and
and think this port through is I didn't
mirror it so
you
okay
all right cool so I have another machine
that is running a web server and this
web server is really dirty it's really
dirty in that so you heard of a Python
on simple HTTP server all right so we
did the same thing in PowerShell we're
talking 19 lines probably get it down
more than that all right so it's really
quick and dirty it's HTTP I can add a
certificate on to it if I needed to but
nonetheless I can utilize something like
invoke web request and I can access that
server so I'm just ensuring that I have
access to it I see I have a status code
of 200 cool so I'm gonna take what is
really my stager and it's that bit of
code that bit of code where I'm going to
reach out download whatever is being
held there and I'm gonna store it in the
context of memory so that whole string
itself is going to be my stager if this
gets caught I lose an IP address I lose
that I was reaching for something called
stage or ps1 but honestly I couldn't
call it it 1 2 3 or ABC Mickey Mouse or
whatever right or not United States or
whatever right cool so I'm gonna go
through and I'm gonna take that string
I'm gonna convert it to bytes and then
I'm going to convert it to base64 and
then I had that base64 code so now
there's my off you stated string in
which I'm gonna lay down in a number of
places as you see I have it is encoded
text so as I go through these examples
I'll be storing encoded text the
variable and all these random different
places and it will call upon it so I'm
gonna utilize this person Nick shank and
I'm gonna look at a couple of properties
associated with their account right now
we see employee ID employee number
division those are the three I called
upon and they have nothing their
division can hold 256 characters I want
to say employee numbers like 512
employee IDs like 16 and there are many
more that you can find but those three
aren't available by default so what I'm
going to do is
go into Active Directory and I'll go
into Schenk's computer I'm sorry shanks
account and I'll come into attribute
editor when I come into attribute editor
you
I noticed that division has nothing
there so that is the one place that an
admin would see it in attribute editor
now I would have had to essentially do
an advanced view and I don't know admins
that just scroll down attribute editor
like oh let me see what's going on in
here
so if that is the case where an admin is
gonna do that then I'm gonna get a
little bit more stealthier but first I'm
gonna store this base64 code there we'll
look at what it looks like cool so it's
there from a command line perspective
from a GUI perspective
we now see our base64 code and depending
on the target I might be like cool it's
there let's go or we may want to get a
little bit more stealth there with that
so we're going to push that down a
little bit and what I mean by push that
down is I'm gonna Pat it with spaces
right I'm gonna push it off the screen
so that way it forces an admin to
actually interact with it
to know what's there now I said division
takes 256 characters right employee
number takes 512 so if I'm already gonna
Pat it with 250 blank spaces then I'm
gonna now put it in employee number
now when I go back in here and I look at
employee number we'll see what that
looks like
so employee number shows blank but
notice everything else around it that's
not set right it actually says not sit
if an admin gets to this point it was
like huh why does that one not said and
why does it doesn't have anything else
next to it and they want to double click
it
oh you got right so let's go a step
further with this we're gonna actually
add in not set so we're gonna add in not
set we're then gonna push it down 250
white spaces and then we'll add in our
text so I'm gonna now overwrite employee
number with that so we'll go back in
here and we'll look at that so now when
I look at employee number nothing to see
here right now look if an atom is gonna
go double click every one of these
look bro you gotta write like you have
no real job right but now when I go in
here to actually interact with it I see
my code I see my whitespace and I see
not set I've pushed it off the screen
making it more difficult for me to find
now when it's time for me to actually
execute this what I'm gonna do is call
upon that property I'm gonna trim not
set and I'm gonna get rid of the white
space there and I'm gonna actually feed
that base64 the PowerShell and what I
have this stage or that ps1 is nothing
more than that green text saying stage
and test right call it a proof dot text
on the desktop if you will the old STP
Amazon all right whoo so that's a way
for me to do it now if I was if I get a
new guy on my team right everybody's got
a cut they teach somehow so by hey man
welcome to the team hey check this out
we're working on Active Directory I need
you to go through every property known
to man kind of research and find us a
property that we can throw data into
right good luck right we all have to
like start somewhere so that's a way for
us to do it now from a registry
perspective I'm gonna utilize this key
called console and console itself it's
like super random I just scroll down in
and found it somewhere
that's how random is now I can't find
all right cool
so there it is so we see nothing's under
console other than something that says
default that's awesome so I'm going to
create a new item there and I'm gonna
call that value updater 32 and then I'm
gonna store my code there
well why are you calling the updater 32
because let's be real here if you add 32
and 64 people will make themselves feel
like it's legit yeah looks legit it's
got 32 on it all right so we come back
in here we look at this and you're like
that's ugly now we'll go back before cuz
I'm like bro this thing is like six
layers deep ain't no way I'm ain't gonna
find that yes they will okay fine we'll
do something similar like what we did
before we're gonna push that thing down
in this case I'm gonna do updater 64 I'm
gonna Pat it with 250 white spaces and
we're right there as well so when we
come look at this we now have that so if
an admin is at a point where they're
looking at registry keys and they see
the key with no value and they want to
click on it really I guess they're
indication there these three dots here
but if they get to a point where they
see this and they want to click on it
then cool I guess they'll stop there but
if they're really nosy they could scroll
over and see my code now if I want to
make this blend in a little bit more you
see how we have this key default and it
says value not set that seems really
legit so I'm gonna do that alright so in
this case I'm gonna do app cache 32 I'm
gonna add in value not set add in my 250
white spaces and I'll add in my code so
now when we have this
we have value not set we have some three
dots out to the side so that triggers
them so be it but when they click on it
we have value not set all the white
space and then we have our code so if I
get this in such a place where a rest is
short no admin is looking forward
depending on the defenses I feel like I
can get around it when it's time for me
to call upon it I'll trim that white
space and everything else associated
with it and I'll be able to execute it
now from a event log perspective I'm
gonna create an event log a brand new
one it's not gonna be system security
anything like that
I'm gonna create one called Windows
Update so that is really legit and I'm
gonna utilize a source call updater 64
so now that I created this event log I'm
gonna write data to it and the data I'm
gonna write to it is gonna be an event
ID of 10 and you guessed it it's gonna
be my base64 code so when I come in here
and I look at this we'll be able to
actually see it
you
okay
you ever had a talk with the demo gods
and it was like yo bro I got you you're
gonna be good
all right there's my updater 64 or my
windows updater when I look at that I
got basic before sitting right there
right so I'm like cool
there's 386 logs now what if they see
this and I'm also doing this in my own
log because if I did it in the
application and everything else we've
already said it's gonna roll it's gonna
overwrite so I don't want to lay down
something today try to come back and
utilize it tomorrow and then like the
network had so much activity that my log
or my entry is now rolled so we'll add
some white space in there all right cuz
white space saves everything when we
come back in here now and look at our
next entry we see nothing there we
scroll down we'll see our code so now
what I want to do is I want to
essentially when I look at like an
application log or something there's
some text there and I'm good I typically
don't interact with it we're trying to
scroll down if I see text whitespace I
assess that that's the end of it so what
we're gonna do is try to get past a
human nature in that same respect and
I'm gonna say an update was detected
we'll add in 50 white spaces in our code
all right surely if this is the Windows
Update err event log surely something
like an update was detected is legit
so now we come here we see an update was
detected if they scroll down they'll see
my code but at that point I feel pretty
good
I'll sleep good that night I may worry
the next day if I'm waiting on the
beacon and we're like three minutes past
that time I might go smoke a cigarette
now any smoke all right so cool from an
event log perspective and the same thing
when it's time for me to actually run it
I'm going to call upon that entry I'll
trim all the white space and everything
else that I have on there and I will let
it rip now from a event log perspective
we have the comment field there's not a
way from the GUI that we can edit to
comment though it would force somebody
if they're gonna use it to utilize the
command line so for us to get after this
we're going to read in or call upon the
default domain policy I'm going to
change the description with you guessed
it my text and now when I come look at
this I'm like whoa that can't be good
right because even if an admin is just
quickly browsing through getting ready
to interact with it something like that
may stand out so you can kind of see
what we're gonna do here we're gonna
suppress everything
now before I was able to use backtick in
for new line but for some reason
backtick end did not work here so I
found myself almost like I was trying to
overflow a buffer where I was writing in
like no characters like Oh Craig I can
still see it let me do another okay now
I can't see it that's the magic number
cool so I added in roughly 40 or so
blank spaces and then we'll be able to
actually write it there so we'll execute
that
you
cool now we'll come back in here and
we'll look at it
and we see it's now off the screen
awesome if we want to actually call upon
it or just read it we'll see something
like that well we have all this blank
space and our code if an admins reading
a group policy objects utilizing command
line like this our mileage will vary but
when it's time for us to execute you
guessed it we can trim everything and be
good to go from a host file perspective
I'm gonna just call in or read in that
string and then I'm going to add content
to that file a value of my base64 code
and I'm gonna add it to a stream called
zones right why zones because it felt
good on my soul um when you look at this
right just looking at what uh ATS is are
there we'll see something like this and
if somebody's looking that data dollar
sign data is gonna be the default one
and I just added in zones because it
felt good it looked good smell good all
that good stuff so now I'm going to read
in that data and then I'm going to pass
that to PowerShell so I can actually
have it
execute all right all right all right so
we got two more the second to last one
here is going to be dealing with
environment variables so when I utilize
PowerShell to affect part environment
variables I'm going to create one but it
doesn't persist past my current session
and I'm also gonna create a system one
but it needs to restart this the system
needs to restart before it kicks in so
this first one is creating a temporary
one and then that cept second one
creates my permanent one but it again
won't kick in into the system restarts
what I'm gonna do is come back over here
and really look at where that's at so I
have a number of things that are there
and we see the one that we created there
was already a w6 six four three two so I
created a w6 for cuz it felt good but
again it stands out if somebody's
looking at this so we're gonna Pat it
with some white space
awesome come back in here look at it
and now we have this ugly blank one so
instead of us doing value not set here
I'm gonna use a donor if you will I'm
just gonna copy what six four three two
has its entry also save it here and
steadily have my white space and push
down my actual code
so I'll read in what six four three two
has and then I'll execute nearly the
same thing starting that entry off with
the code that six four three two has and
when we look at that
we see our w66 with the same thing as
six four three two and if we were to
open it up and interact with it we have
our code we have some white space and
then we have C Program Files common
files ultimately I want an admin if
they're gonna investigate this I want
them to feel like there's nothing to see
here just keep moving right I also want
to be a snitch and be like hey man don't
look at this event code um go look at
I'm sorry this registry key don't look
at that one over there that's who you're
really looking for when it's time for me
to run it trim my whitespace and be good
to go from aw on my sim perspective
again roughly 10,000 on my machine I'm
going to create one called
win 30 to defend 64 cuz largely locked a
decent amount of the classes begin with
win32 so I want this to blend in I'm
going to create a property called path
and I'm gonna store my code there and
then when I go back to read it I'll be
able to see my code now this class is
now one of 10,000 plus entries on this
system when it's time for me to execute
it
I just called upon now I don't feel like
I need to further off you scape that if
somebody wanted to actually look at
these classes a little bit deeper and
they knew which one they were looking at
they could actually use this program
inherent to Windows and from here they
could specify recursively all roughly
10,000 or so or they can do the
immediate ones in that namespace and
from that perspective they can then
scroll down to something that they're
looking for maybe get to a point where
they see when defend 64 notice we don't
see our code there and if they had a WoW
hair they could then interact with it
come down and they would see the
property in which we've created lots of
work that's good
you
all right so as you see there's a number
of ways for us to do this now
you may be wondering well people really
using this hey look from the objective
perspective oh don't trust what I'm
saying let's look at what the data say
right says so we have a number of
organizations the nation-state
hacktivists whatever you want to call
them that are utilizing stagers in some
form of fashion alright and this is just
a small list when you think about it it
only makes sense like why go all in when
you can kind of taste the water a little
bit to make sure it's what you want
before you put your hard-earned equity
on that actual system
now we do have some pros and we have
some cons so the pros very lightweight
could be low equity absolutely because
again if I lose that what do I lose and
domain maybe an IP address maybe you
know just a name of what I call the foul
and that doesn't even mean anything it's
modular so I have this stager that
literally goes and has one job and then
depending on what it brings back to me
for information I could have a module
that then surveys I have a module that's
a key logger I have a module does this
that's this right so it's very modular
in nature where I don't have to bring
everything at one time and literally my
c2 server could be hosted anywhere the
same with my stager it's like if there
is a place for me to store it in Windows
and there is a million places they call
it features um it's a place in which I
can go back and grab it now with that
there's some work that has to be done to
even get to this thing we're talking
post exploitation so if you can't even
get in the door you won't even get to
the point of using it and some defenders
are better than others we can all agree
with that so as we begin to use this
really it's visible then next stage of
our retrieval it's going to create a
connection so if there's real decent
logging and somebody is actually looking
it could highlight if the organization
has a good EDR we could be seen as well
right this is where you understand the
environment and then you pick which tool
is applicable or to tasks at hand we
could have ourselves we could find
ourselves rather in a place in which our
c2 server is blocked if we're using a
domain or really even an IP if we're
using a domain if the organization finds
it they could sinkhole the domain and
really new to our communication so
there's a lot riding on issues in a
stager and at perspective some detection
mitigation strategies
well proactive threat hunting like come
to work and actively go look at stuff on
your network assume breach well it's
quiet that's because they're good I'm
telling you if you go look you'll find
stuff all right reputation based web
analysis what does the
rest of the community think about this
domain or this file or whatever case
what is the rest of what is my
organization think about it in the sense
of is this file
resident somewhere else am i my system
mitigations least privileged
segmentation isolation application
whitelisting it hurts what man if you do
it it's worthwhile right somebody still
can do some nefarious stuff but at the
end of the day we're making it harder
for them it goes without saying patch
patch patch all right so cool now I'm on
the down stream right making my descent
down and I gotta get these shameless
plugs out right it is what it is I
apologize right so you see me use a lot
of power Schiller you guess it I like
power shield so I run a site called
under the wired I tech myself into other
people and been around for roughly 20
since 2015 we've had over 90,000 people
play from 78 countries when I google how
many countries there are I get somewhere
between 192 and 196 either way I'm
pretty happy with those stats it's free
and it's persistent it's going after the
core aspects of the language so if
you're looking to utilize the language a
little bit more because you maybe
thought what I was using it for was
pretty cool then here's a way to kind of
get after it
now if you feel like you know the
language I also run a site called posh
hunter so Posh hunter is very often sand
defensive-minded I'm gonna put you in a
scenario in which are either a defender
or your vulnerability penetration tester
and you're going to answer questions
utilize in an operating system or a
Windows instance that we're providing
all right so if you have questions I'll
step off to the side and answer them if
there is anything that you want to take
a picture of this is it when I get back
home to Augusta tonight I'm gonna put
these slides up there if you want to
interact with me on Twitter or anything
there's that and there's my code so
again I'm gonna step off to the side so
if there's any questions I'll take them
in thank you
[Applause]