we welcome to the stage Anitra data
Majumdar and honorable
[Music]
almost there almost there so this is the
last talk and after that it's all open
for fun and games
so today myself and a noob of both of us
from the LinkedIn house security team
would be talking about building
securement a machine learning pipelines
the challenges and the security patterns
that we have been following okay so we
would like to acknowledge the
contributions from the various internal
teams in LinkedIn and also of course the
house security team the larger team that
we are a part of for spearheading some
of the initiatives and programs for
securing the machine learning pipelines
at LinkedIn so the talk outline we will
be covering the major use cases of
machine learning at LinkedIn and
basically the business use cases the
various phases involved in machine
learning pipelines and some of the
nuances of the distributed
infrastructure that backs those phases
we will then be going into some of the
security risks and security solution
patterns and eventually we also touch
upon some of the scalability aspects
that we have issues that we have
observed while applying the security
controls to secure these pipelines okay
so the major machine learning use cases
at LinkedIn so we use machine learning
to help members build network on the
LinkedIn platform machine learning is
used to predict relevant jobs to the
various members on our platform machine
learning is used heavily to predict and
recommend feed content things like
articles
to our members on the platform and of
course last not but not the least we use
machine learning to detect abuse like a
count takeover fake accounts harassment
and spamming on our platform so what are
some of the high level phases involved
in machine learning we have the
experimentation phase where the most of
the time is spent by data scientists and
performing feature engineering and
problem formulation we have the model
training and evaluation phase where the
data that is prepped in the
experimentation phase is fed in and the
model that has been authored undergoes
training and then the best model is code
and selected in the model deployment
phase the models that have been the best
model that is selected in the previous
phase is actually deployed into the
infrastructure production infrastructure
usually for the purpose of model serving
and inference which is the last phase so
currently there is an initiative at
LinkedIn called productive machine
learning or tro ml where all these
various phases are tied together through
integrated workflows and tooling and
libraries and the main goal behind this
initiative is to boost the productivity
of the data scientists at the company
because currently various teams within
the data science organization use
different methods for each of the phases
so the main goal of this initiative is
to bring all those processes and tooling
and pipeline components under a single
pane of glass and of course the major
security concern is is our member data
protecting our member data on our
platform from data exfiltration and
unauthorized data access
so how does the ml flow logical
architecture look like so we have
offline components in our infrastructure
that primarily performs the
experimentation and training phases and
by offline components I mean these are
jobs that are batched or scheduled in
nature we have components that bridge
the offline and the online world and
these are mostly in the form of event
bus like in the case of LinkedIn it is
Kafka and also there there is a model
artifact store which is used to store
and retrieve models and of course the
online components which are basically
applications and they communicate with
one another over rest interfaces and as
a part of this online components we have
the model deployment phase and the model
serving phase that run so what are some
of the security risks and challenges in
each of these phases that I just
described in the experimentation phase
the major challenges unauthorized data
access and the data leakage so as I was
mentioning like in the experimentation
phase various data scientists in the
organization have a need to do feature
engineering so during the course of such
an action this like unauthorized data
access is a risk that we have seen and
also during that process there might be
a leakage of sensitive data into the
less secure areas of our infrastructure
in the model training phase the
important concern is generation of
intermediate datasets through automatic
flows which could be sensitive in nature
and which might not have any associated
audit trail and may be flowing into the
areas of the infrastructure that is less
secure in the model
women face the main concerns our
unintended model actions like model
publication to production or test
environments and in some of the cases
the models themselves might be
personalized and might be leaking some
containing some member data in that case
we don't want the models to leak member
PII into less secure areas of the
environment and finally in the inference
phase the major concerns our security
misconfigurations
which could lead to a potential denial
of service attack due to resource
exhaustion and also using serve ulnar
about software components there are
lesser known theoretical attacks
possible as well like member inference
attacks where an attacker is able to
guess the datasets used for training the
model so what are some of the controls
and the pattern security controls and
patterns we have adopted for the
experimentation phase the major controls
are access control and by access control
I mean both rule-based
and role based access control in the
rule based access control is usually
based on the attribute of the target
that is being accessed and the role
based access control is on the attribute
of the source that is trying to access
the target and the rule based access
control is usually done in some sort of
a uniform access layer and where the
rules can be enforced in an integrated
manner for the encryption control we use
both encryption of data at rest as well
as encryption of data in transit for
encryption in data at rest we have seen
cases where we absolutely need to
decrypt the data during the process of
model training so in that case
what we try to do is reduce the data in
the encrypted state or in the decrepit
state as much as possible so that the
exposure of the sensitive decrypted data
is reduced and the other control that we
have been using is in the as a part of
the rule based access control is also
like enforce rules so that privacy
doesn't privacy of the datasets doesn't
get leaked and what I mean by that when
multiple non PII fields are combined it
shouldn't be leaking some PII field and
this is usually done in that data access
layer that I just mentioned through some
rule-based throw through the enforcement
of some rules and the last one is the
feature sensitivity annotation where we
do have an architectural component in
our environment called the AI metadata
hub where various features used for
during the training phase are annotated
for sensitivity and it is contacted by
various applications and tooling in the
pipeline during each of the phases
during the model training phase we have
the encryption as I mentioned in the as
in the case of an experimentation phase
and and most of the training flows are
more automated compared to the
experimentation phase and they were the
thing to look out for in this phase is
the leaking of PII during these
intermediate flows especially in the
case of a complex multistage model and
we have also developed some in-house
machine learning based classifiers to go
and detect for PII x' in areas of the
infrastructure that it's not supposed to
be in
and also do some monitoring or alerting
based on that detection in the model
deployment phase we used controls like
dual verification which is live very
similar to the to a code review process
like me the code cannot be checked in
without a reviewers shipit so similarly
in the case of a model a model cannot be
deployed to prod unless it has been
reviewed and okayed by a second person
and usually these model deployment
systems are accessed through a new eye
and we enforce multi-factor
authentication on that the other control
that we have started looking into is the
model randomization control and this is
applicable more to personalized models
which could leak member PII data let's
say in the test environment and of
course during the model deployment phase
in the testing infrastructure we must
ensure that synthetic data is used
instead of actual member PII for the
model inference phase the major concern
is security miss configuration and the
way we proactively address this is
through the running of security
benchmarks that can detect low-hanging
security miss configuration issues and
then making sure it's configured
according to the best practices in the
benchmark and also the other controllers
we typically want to segregate workloads
in production based on the sensitivity
level of the data that the model is
handling and the model health assurance
which is a part of the pro ml initiative
helps us look into the model health or
observe the model health over the course
of time
to look for performance degradation like
accuracy degradation issues over a
course of time which could suggest
potential denial of service attacks that
the model would be could be under now
going into some of the key challenges
that we have been facing in our
environment so basically had using
heterogeneous controls in our offline
and online environment like
heterogeneous authentication controls in
this case so our offline environment
which is where all the offline training
jobs run are mostly backed by things
like the Hadoop HDFS Hadoop MapReduce
job spark etc so the main method of
authentication in this offline
environment is through the use of
Kerberos delegation tokens and block
access tokens using which all the
compute jobs is able to distribute the
workload and access data from the
storage in the online infrastructure all
our services communicate with one
another over HTTP based connection which
uses mutual TLS so now when a online
service needs to contact an offline job
of to get data or for whatever purpose
as a part of a flow that spans both the
online and offline world there is a
translation problem so the way that we
are have solved this problem is through
the introduction of this service called
the translator service which goes and
consults an identity management system
to get the entitlements of the
Authenticator that it gets from the
service online service and in this case
it is an x.509 certificate and then it
decides whether to grant access to that
principle or not and generates the token
and that token is used to complete rest
of the flow to go and contact the
offline jobs and the offline data and
through this means a full user
attribution or a full service
attribution is established that spans
across both the online and offline
environment another challenge that we
have faced in our on-prem environment is
due to the tight coupling of the compute
and the data tiers like usually all
these machine learning phases are
heavily distributed environments so it
is this such a tight coupling can
actually introduce some challenges when
we are trying to apply security controls
for authentication and authorization and
what I mean by tight coupling is let's
say there is a compute cluster that
needs to go and contact a cluster that
stores data during the flow of a
training job so the compute cluster
relies on some host level identity to
identify the storage cluster and then
and then goes and completes the
transaction so this introduces the tight
coupling the way we would be solving
this problem is through moving to the
cloud Azure through an internal project
called blue shift so as a part of that
project all these storage services are
already available as azure services as
well as the compute services are also
encapsulated as Azure services so the
main job over here would be to come come
up with an access layer in which all the
controls for authentication and
authorization can be introduced in a
scalable manner and then the access that
can consult the identity layer to go and
check for entitlements of the various
principles
moving over to deep learning pipelines
so we we have use cases and LinkedIn
like each of those ml use cases that I
was mentioning in the beginning
currently there is a trend and that this
is primarily to improve the model
accuracy for each of those use cases
that data scientists are using deep
learning and this is because on the
LinkedIn platform there is a lot of text
data like member activity member
economic graph member profiles so all
these data attacks data are taken and
then vectorized through a technique
called embeddings and fed into deep
learning network like convolutional
neural network and such an operation is
computationally intensive both in terms
of hardware and software so in order to
scale those curve to that computational
demands there is a common pattern where
we are seeing that there is a use of a
lot of open-source containerized
software to boost the innovation and
scale of use and with that having said
the context of using containerized
pipelines i will hand over rest of the
talk to my co-presenter an above thank
you so how does a machine learning
container pipeline looks like it just
looks like any other application
container pipeline the only fancy thing
here is for deep learning we are using
GPU cluster instead of a CPU cluster so
what are the phases so in build phase a
container images build for a specific
machine learning workflow for building a
container image the base image as well
as system dependencies and any
application artifact is it's packaged
together
and which builds our container image
once you have a container image you will
push it to a image repository from there
a container deployment deployer such an
Orchestrator will deploy the container
on the container runtime environment
once the container is running container
management tool will will manage the
container for the availability as well
as scale as well as continuous
monitoring as well as continuous
monitoring as well as from anyone
ability scanning so on a high level
let's go through offline workflow here a
data scientist authors training service
model training service on its laptop
then pushes it to a code repository then
builds a container image using Jenkins
or any internal image tool pushes that
container image builds our container
image using the like base image as well
as any system dependencies and the code
heap that data scientist has pushed to
the code repository and push that
container image to the image repository
then to spin up a kubernetes cluster
training cluster the data scientist can
use a cool CTL job and will trigger a
API call to API server which will turn
bring up the tensor flow training
cluster which will fetch the image from
the image repository will train the
model and based on the data fetch from
the SD FS cluster and once the model is
generated it will be pushed to the model
artifact store in case of online
workflow now the model has been trained
now it's ready to be promoted to the
production environment they will be a
kafka event generated the model
deployment component of the pro ml
workflow will consume that kafka event
that the model deploy executor will
fetch the model from the model deploy
artifact store and will stage the model
on the kubernetes cluster which will
pull the service image from the image
repository
so what are the security challenges
which we see in container environment we
enable data scientists to use images as
well as system dependencies which they
can download from external environment
but they may pose a threat
they include vulnerabilities and they
can lower down the security posture of
our environment the other challenge is
related to the insecure access
insufficient authentication as well as
authorization an example would be a cube
API server allowing anonymous access as
well as Orchestrator allowing access not
based on role just wide open access the
other risk is inter container network
traffic by default any traffic within
between the hosts between the containers
within our hosts is not restricted that
means any container on that host can can
see the packets all the packets at the
container level these are more related
to the runtime vulnerabilities any new
components and in your vulnerabilities
found on any of the containers which are
running at the moment and the last one
is insecure configuration of container
runtime this is more specific to how we
are configuring the container runtime
like a container de or a darker which is
running on the talker which is running
the containers an example would be
allowing direct as such within the
container these allowing containers to
run as a privileged root user host
allowing containers to to mount
sensitive directories so these are some
of the risks we see
so what are the control patterns at the
image level start from basics make sure
you certify the base images any system
dependencies as well as application
artifacts by certified I mean perform
benchmark checks against the base images
perform vulnerability scanning if you
are downloading perform vulnerability
scanning against any external libraries
which you are downloading from external
sources any application artifacts should
go through a security review download
the Excel external libraries as well as
images from trusted sources trusted
sources here being your trusted vendors
as well as partners at the registry
level makes sure to encrypt all the
communications to Eric to registry make
sure to enable authentication based on a
certificate or token-based
authentication use a scrub or a bus to
scrub and still images or any vulnerable
images by still images I mean any images
which are which hasn't been used for a
long time and may contain some
vulnerable components at the
orchestrator level segregate the cluster
based on the workflow sensivity makes
sure to create virtual networks for
different sensitivity workflows enable
audit log in on all the user generated
events as well as request log it
remotely compare the configuration of an
Orchestrator with the benchmark check
like these are the like start from
basics you do the basics correctly then
you can build on top of that use the
least privileged access model by least
privileged access model is provision the
access for the users based on their
roles and
and don't just widely allow access to
all like all the containers or in on a
host or all the services in an
Orchestrator at the container side
certified runtime configuration make
sure you apply resource isolation ensure
SSD is not running on the container and
show the container is not running as a
privileged user apply user and the last
one is user attribution all the actions
on an container should be attributed to
a specific user so let's revisit the
same diagram with some controls here now
now you can see that any images which
are being built goes through a benchmark
image benchmark check as well as
security and legal vulnerability
scanning and it's being logged all the
communication is over TLS as well as
certificate authentication all the
secrets are if you are using at CD for
managing some other secrets should be
those should be encrypted otherwise use
a key management system to store any
secrets for application between
kubernetes cluster and as DFS its
Kerberos token-based authentication and
use a remote log or for example cousteau
in case of online services the Kafka
online workflow for machine learning the
Kafka event which was generated needs to
go through dual verification which means
it needs to be peer-reviewed validated
and user attributed all other
communications are rest over TLS as well
as certificate authentication is applied
ok
so what are the key takeaways for
building a machine-learning security
patterns segregation of infrastructure
machine learning workloads are very are
highly distributed in nature so it's
very important to apply security
controls in a scalable manner which
means we have to define some security
boundaries once we define the security
boundaries we can apply sorry we can
apply security controls on those
specific boundaries which we have
defined the high level guideline here
would be to divide or segregate the
machine learning pipeline environment
into following three phases three
environment based on storage and
computation tier based on your based on
control plane and data plane components
as well as based on on those workload
sensitivity once you have segregated
your environment or your infrastructure
based on these three tiers then you can
apply security controls only specific to
that specific tier and it's easy to
manage and scaleable a metadata system
machine learning the risk associated
with machine learning are very specific
to models for example model performance
degradation as well as a model learning
PII during training phase so it becomes
very important to understand what sort
of what's what is the purpose of a model
is what sort of access that model has
like what sort of access what sort of
features that model is accessing as well
as the data and it becomes very
important to maintain a meta data system
which will have Association of all this
information as well as sensitivity and
rotation of each and every feature used
by that model so that controls can be
designed as well as segregated based on
that information
monitoring continuous monitoring is
important make sure you whenever you're
designing your mo a pipeline security
patterns you are applying the concept of
continued continuous monitoring that
means you are scanning your environment
regularly for any vulnerabilities many
monitoring the infrastructure for any
specific performance degradation because
that's one of the major risk in machine
learning pipelines as well as collecting
as many security metrics as you can do
to design controls security
infrastructure in ml in pipeline there
are two key security infrastructure
components one is Identity and Access
Management and the other is your key
management system so make sure whenever
you are designing your security
infrastructure that should be scalable
and highly available any any any design
should incorporate the concept of
automation that's where the security
control scaling comes into picture all
the controls we have spoken about or
what ana mitra has spoken up about
should be automated with supports the
concept of scaling with that thank you
and if you want to contact us email
address is here otherwise we will be
available at the speaker cover corner we
also have a team channel which is
blackhat 2019 Li ml so contact us over
there thank you
you