I'd like to introduce our next speaker
Sridhar sridhar is a senior software
engineer in the azure security data
science team wherein he ships
high-performance scalable machine
learning solutions for other security
services everyone please welcome Sridhar
[Applause]
so there been a lot of talks about false
positives today right you know that's
that's definitely a problem that system
analyst faced and in mid-sized to large
enterprises and here are some numbers
actually you know a midsize company
spends around 21,000 hours per year you
know chasing false positives and that
costs them around like 1.3 million
dollars a year right so this is
definitely a problem and there are
multiple speakers who talked about this
today so what is the solution for that
we want to enrich our security alerts
with additional metadata right that can
help you deal with possible false
positives increasing the alert fidelity
and rid like you know help you to
mitigate or resolve your alerts as well
in a quick manner right so this talk is
going to be about enrichment just what I
quickly go through our main goals like
on why we want to do enrichment the
first thing is like we want to reduce
false positive as I told before like we
want to make sure that we provide extra
context to your others so that you can
confidently say something is a false
positive or not and then also like the
second is like we want to reduce your
mean time to resolution of your alerts
to help your investigation and also like
to focus on investigations on on others
that are important not all alerts are
the same right so and also like give you
know help help increase the expertise of
the SEC upstream and make them think
like you know think in terms of graph
right so I know I know there's been a
lot of talks about like
the famous John Lambert blog as well
like the attackers thinkin crafty for
defenders think and list so we are
nudging we are with those enrichment our
goal is to nudge you know defenders to
think you know in terms of graph so
today we we do like in my team we do two
types of enrichment one is the peers the
peers are you know networks of users
within your organization right and the
blast radius for now I'm just going to
say it's a graphic it's a graph
representation of like all your assets
and entities and the relationships
between them in the cloud but we'll go
in more detail about that okay first
appears so who I appears in your
organization like typically the people
you collaborate with and they're mostly
the people who may share access to
resources with right so we have defined
peers like this
to find your network of users within
your company the next thing is like does
since we are an agile security like you
know there's a sure has information
about your peers one of the things is
that you can use as the active directory
hierarchy information that is available
in agile but not a we found that we
actually did some investigation we found
that not a lot of companies set this up
in Azure in fact like only 40% of
companies have at least you know to any
person of users in their hierarchy and
also like guest users I don't know like
if you know about business to business
users btp users from other tenants they
are not usually part of an organization
so they get left out so we decided that
is not the right approach to take so at
least it won't solve all the scenarios
that we want to solve for the next is
groups I mean this support for groups in
almost every major directory offering
and I sure also has a hazard and a lot
of organization use groups
for you know for mailing list or
security groups for admin axes and all
these kind of things so groups are very
common so we wanted to take that
approach to find people who he appears
are now how do you find peers from your
group so like you know people with whom
you share common groups are most likely
to be appears right and also like we
take transitive membership into account
as your supports as your Active
Directory supposed nested groups so we
have to take transitive membership in
also into accounts and we ignore large
groups like if you belong to a large
group we the assumption is you're not
going to work closely with everyone in
that group like so the inverse is like
you know smaller the group more likely
you're like to collaborate with them so
these are assumptions like on how we can
find peers from from group membership
details right so what do we use we use
an algorithm called term frequency
inverse document frequency it is a text
processing algorithm so let's say that
you have millions of documents and you
want to search for the phrase the Lord
of the Rings right so terms like the and
off are like you know terms that occur
very frequently so documents with those
terms are actually prioritized less less
in your search results
whereas terms like rings and Lord you
know those terms are occur less
frequently and they are weighted more
and documents with those terms are
prioritized more in your search results
right this this is like really simple
text searching algorithm and we have the
a version of that is what we use for
calculating your the PS so we provide
normalized we get normalized weights for
groups smaller the group higher the
weight that's how we deal with it and
the output of this algorithm is like you
know a ranked set of peers
for for a user so just to give a little
bit go a little bit deep into it here
you can see a Venn diagram of of group
membership details really simple one so
who are the peers of the green user
right so like I'm hoping it's obvious
here but the closest peers are the
couple of blue users that are there
because they share all the three groups
with them okay who's gonna be the next
closest set of peers the red users they
share a couple of groups the orange
users as well the yellow users as well
but the way we rank peers is that like
we provide weight to smaller groups so
the next set of rank of peers would be
like the red red users because the
chroman groups are smaller right and
similarly like the next and the rank
would be the orange user because the
common groups are like smaller then the
yellow users so this is how we're going
to be ranked appears so how good is this
algorithm like I don't know like many
people at Microsoft can recognize these
names so this is the executive
leadership at Microsoft so this network
was created completely from group
membership nothing else right so as you
can see such as the CEO I picked up the
top five PS was sat here and then their
peers and formed created this network so
as you can see like Satya is a as a CEO
and he has like a me hood is a CFO Brad
Smith is the chief of legal affairs so
and Scott goos the head of cloud in
Microsoft so like so we were able to
find out like we were able to like say
that hey this algorithm works pretty
well with with the data at Microsoft
we're also trying to get feedback from
our customers regarding this but yeah
this this is completely based off like
the tf-idf algorithm okay now we have
calculated appears now what are the use
cases and security like
what do we do how can we use them let's
take that there's a user called John Doe
and this user and the purple nodes here
are users like there's a user called
John Doe or the purple nodes are users
and it's the Spear network like let's
say there's an other trigger due to some
anomaly activity from John right so as a
security analyst what do you do with
this one thing that we can help out with
is like if it is in line with the peer
activity if the peers have done the
similar same kind of activity then you
can suppress that as a false positive
it's that accesses you know usual for a
spear Network so there's probably
nothing maybe this is a low fidelity
alert and then you can suppress this
right if not if if if the axis is not in
line with peer activity then there is
something suspicious happening right so
in that case you can you can say that
this alert may alert needs further
investigation as well right so this is
like one of the use cases for peers I
mean they're a bunch of other and like
when you think about it like there was a
teammate who joined our team recently
and then see like as we do we do this
calculation every day for peer for peers
and then see Sharon Lee shows up like 1
XI 1 XI is on-boarded 2 with the new
hair document and everything and then
she shows up she shows up as my peer
like and we found out that she she one
of her peers we're members from the
older team from the from her older teams
and we were and we were able to make
sure that she was removed from our older
groups appropriately as well like there
are a lot of use cases for this but this
is like one example and like for
reducing false positive like there was
one of the points like one of the goals
for enrichment and next we're gonna move
on to blast radius so I think people are
talking like some of the speakers where
we were kind of like talking about
similar things but here we go
so what is blast radius so it is we are
defining it as privileges of an entity
in your cloud environment it must
include hidden and transitive privileges
as well I think an entity here could be
anything like a user or a group or even
a virtual machine in your cloud right
and and blast radius should be able to
answer the question what is the full
impact if an entity in your organization
is compromised right that is also is
important I mean that's the main one of
the main goals here and it helps to
think of last radius in you know in
directed graph you know the nodes can be
entities in your cloud the edges could
be relationships and there can be
multiple edges between nodes and the
edges can carry all kind of information
like what is the access level between
the or the type of access between the
entities when did they start when did
they end so that it can maintain history
also right so so yeah so directed graph
is like a really good way to represent
blast radius so let's go a little bit
into it yeah this this is like you know
every cloud environment is complicated
like these are like a sample of services
that are offered in Azure right and they
all interact it interact with each other
in like complicated ways or not or I
would say not very obvious ways it's
easy to miss configure something or lose
track of something right and that's
where we want to help out like with our
security expertise as well so
I'm just gonna give you an example here
this is a sample blast radius of a user
right so the purple node is a user the
green nodes are subscriptions a really
simple explanation I don't know like how
many people are familiar with Azure but
a really simple explanation is just a
collection of as you're agile resources
like VMs or storage accounts via Web
Services right so any permission you
have on a substrate in US on a
subscription it's actually propagates to
those resources as well the brown nodes
are groups groups are kind of you know
it's easy to configure all the team
members in a group and provide them
access to a subscription that's like a
standard way of doing things and yeah
I'll talk a little bit about service
principle but before that yeah let's
like you know this was the blast radius
about for the e for the user even like
I'm hoping it's obvious like you know
this person Jane Doe is a member of this
so this person Jane Doe is a member of
this group code hexa team and as a
result of that she gets permissions to a
bunch of these as your subscriptions so
I mean like the goal is to capture these
you know relationships in a graph manner
and a graph like a visualization so
let's say that the user you received an
alert for this user right and you want
to like I'm gonna talk about like you
can seed an alert and you want to you
know that this alert is positive right
and you want to like ReWalk some access
for this person right I'm talking about
your mitigation steps here right like so
let's say that you want to remove access
to this particular subscription so what
do you do it's this graph helps you to
find all the edges that go from that
user to that subscription and you can
make sure that you cut off all the edges
that need from that user to that
subscription so in this case you have to
cut off the access to this group this
group as well because there is like you
know a reader access
coming from this this group seems has
read of access on the subscription and
also one more one more group because
this group also has a read of access to
the subscription right so this is like
one example on how we can help you with
your mitigation the next example would
be service principle like those
principles are really useful in agile so
ok let me explain what service principle
is first they are just another identity
natural-like it also kind of like a user
right
we have credentials for a service
principle in fact you can have more than
one potential for a service principle
and you can it's primarily used for
automation for you can assign like you
know your service principles specific
privileges and you use it for automation
right you don't need to you don't want
to use user accounts for that you want
to you don't want to maintain passwords
for that click create accounts user
accounts and maintain passwords you know
those principles are really good way of
doing those automation or securing your
automation as well you know in principle
a service principle should never be
authenticated by it should be
authenticated by a user should not be
using the service principle you know it
should be completely automated right if
a service principle is getting up is
getting the auth token from your token
server it should be done it should be
from a script that is running inside
your automation you should in principle
yeah a user should not be using a
service principle of course that's
that's not the case and service
principles are also an interesting
attack vector for
for hackers right so remember that it's
just another identity in Azure so what
this means is when when a service
principal performs an activity in Azure
your Azure audit logs will have the will
have the identity as that Service
principal right it won't have the
identity of the user behind that service
principle right so they can easily mask
themselves if they get if they gain
access to a service principle as well so
so so having said that about service
principle it's it's important it's a pig
I've seen a lot of people like it's it's
an interesting you know entry point into
your into your cloud infrastructure I've
seen a lot of times where it has been
misconfigured or over provision with
credentials and all these things so in
this case let's say that you want to
revoke access to this particular
subscription right so of course fall for
that user you will have to remove access
to that group as well but you will have
to make sure that you remove access to
the service principle as well it's today
this is not very obvious and agile good
yeah and the other other aspects is like
you can you can we can pivot around a
subscription here here it shows the
blast radius of a user right so you can
pivot this graph around the subscription
and then you can see how many attack
points are there like what is the attack
surface of that subscription like how
many users can potentially I mean have
access to your subscription today right
so you can you can I mean that that
would be that would be useful for
compliance purposes for example I can
make sure that only a team should have
access to your subscriptions right so we
and you want to make sure that you cover
all kinds of entry points into your
subscription right so that's one of the
use case for this in the end like you
know we this graph our goal is to
provide this information in this graph
like that so that you can do your you
get one zero you're somewhat positive
about your
investigating your alert you can take
necessary mitigation of remediation
steps right so that is the main goal
here so just a small plug here both this
data is something that we do analytics
is something that we do today if you are
a natural customer if you use as your
sentinel it is available today just as a
private preview picture you can contact
me or actually it runs the PM for this
feature there you can contact me around
the way it works this as your sentinel
is built on top of like log analytics
log analytics is a columnar database
available in Azure so we push all this
data into log analytics and then you use
something what is called as a cousteau
query language to extract the data in
fact this visualization that I provided
in the previous slide is actually I the
way it is done is like we will retrieve
the data from the Crystal query in a
Jupiter notebook and then we display the
result of that query in a graph like
manner using some JavaScript libraries
so that Jupiter notebook is actually
available in a public github repo but I
forgot to include the link here but I'll
make sure I'll include the link before
this this slide these slides are
uploaded to github as well so yeah yeah
so if you're interested in this yak you
can talk to rama or me meanwhile like
I'm at the end of the talk I know it's
been pretty quick but if you have any
questions yeah
does anyone have any questions
all right please join me in thanking
Street our
[Applause]