alrighty hello everyone
this is hack the planet and space two a
very quick
introduction to satellite hacking so i
am rachel velasco
and thank you so much for supporting
visa charlotte this year
so let's get started a little bit more
about me every time i play among us
i have one of the imposters without fail
and
the theme of this year's b-sides is what
i learned in quarantine
and unfortunately i was one of the many
people
whose mental health was greatly affected
by the pandemic
so my depression anxiety i've been
struggling with those for several years
now and
it definitely works in my impostor
syndrome within
infosec and i couldn't find any joy
with my work or with what i was learning
in school
and i felt that i was constantly
defending myself
and having to explain why i belonged in
infosec
and eventually it got to the point where
i thought it would be so much better if
i just got ejected but anyway
my uh treatment plan was revised and
one of the first things that i got
excited about in a long time that felt
like a long time was
i'm satellite hacking and i'm excuse me
i am back to work now in school and i've
taken up some leadership roles in some
tech organizations
and i'm definitely not an expert but i
am very excited to share
what i learned about hacking space with
all of y'all
so let's go over the agenda
i'll be discussing exactly what
satellites are
how you can go about attacking them and
more resources for learning more on your
own
and getting some practice in
so satellites but first
i have some news in march
of this year this article came out how
space is becoming
a lot more dangerous and the
army space and missile defense commander
he said that they have a lot
of new tools like interceptors which is
anti-missile weapons hypersonic missiles
and directed energy weapons
and he said it was pretty darn awesome
yes that is super awesome however
they are applying this technology to
satellites and just a couple of months
ago as of this recording
um russia conducted an anti-satellite
weapons test
but this anti-satellite weapon is on a
satellite
so these satellites are becoming more
and more dangerous
so why would you want to hack a
satellite
what even is a satellite well
in this context an artificial satellite
is any object that was intentionally
placed
into orbit and they have a lot of
different purposes
depending on what orbit they're on
but for the most part there's
communications
navigation for science like weather
monitoring and whatnot
and for recon there are a lot of spy
satellites up there right now
so the orbits by altitude
i'm only going to be talking about three
but there are quite a lot of them
and this first one is called the
low earth orbit and satellites here
they they're generally for uh
communications but you'll also find the
international space station
the hubble telescope and the us iridium
communication satellite system
and this requires the lowest amount of
energy to
deploy and keep in orbit next
we have the medium earth orbit
and there's a subclassification called
semi-synchronous and what that means
is it's consistent the satellites on
this orbit
pass the same two spots on the equator
every single day
and in medium earth orbit you'll tend to
find a lot of the navigational
satellites
like gps and glonass which is
i believe global navigation satellite
system
and finally the last one is not high
earth orbit even though it is
considered an orbit but it is a
geosynchronous orbit
so geosynchronous means that
um at the same time every day you will
find the satellite at the same point in
the sky
excuse me and there's a special kind of
geosynchronous satellite called
geostationary
and geostationary means that
it doesn't matter what time of day you
look up in the sky that satellite will
always be in the same spot
and of the geostationary satellites
a lot of them will be commercial
communications
or broadcasting and since it's so high
up
they'll have a constant view of a large
surface area from up there
there's also the geostationary
operational environmental satellites or
the goes
so a lot of these
they they tend to function
uh like scientifically they have uh
weather monitoring you can see all the
hurricanes wildfires from up there
and they can also detect distress
signals from
ships and planes so they're also very
helpful with
search and rescue and a little bit past
the geostationary orbit is the graveyard
orbit
and this is where satellites go to die
and all these defunct satellites
that no longer serve their purpose or
have broken and can't be fixed for some
reason they end up becoming space debris
and china tried solving this problem
with an
anti-satellite missile and it did
hit the satellite that they were
intending to hit
but it just split into a bajillion more
pieces and spread it out everywhere
so yes and
there's also the problem of collisions
there's the space debris and the still
functional satellites
not too long ago there was a defunct
russian satellite that collided with a
functioning u.s iridium satellite
and they ended up um
colliding yes and their
debris went back to earth and so there's
a lot of like radioactive material
that they dumped and i think it landed
in the u.s
um so that's a giant problem with
these uh defunct satellites colliding
and there's also the issue of light
pollution
all of these satellites in orbit are
blocking the view
of other celestial bodies so scientists
have been complaining about this
now how do you go about attacking
satellites
there's this wonderful paper by the u.s
air force nasik
called competing in space and
there are a couple uh threats that they
list to space systems
so i'll be talking about the user and
ground segment
in one part and then the link segment
and the space segment
and if you noticed there are a lot
of familiar terms because
satellites are basically computers so
what they call the signals that a
satellite receives is the uplink
the down link is the signals that the
satellite sends down back to earth to
ground stations and to phones and
whatever other
endpoints there are so what exactly
is a ground station it's just a fancy
radio station
that communicates exclusively with a
satellite
and honestly it's just a fancy computer
and
antenna combination so this would be the
cheapest way
to take over the satellite since you
could just hack into it like you
normally would a
usual computer but unfortunately
since it is a usual computer there are
logs
so there will be a trace of when you
have like
tried to interfere with this ground
station
and there was this instance back i
believe it was 2008
there was the terra earth observation
system satellite
and nasa found that the responsible
party
achieved all steps required to command
the satellite
but did not issue commands so whoever
hacked into this satellite
they had control over it but they didn't
issue
any commands to like change its
inclination
or anything but this happened 10 years
ago
so satellite hacking is not a new thing
next we have the link segment so
satellites have
a communication payload module which
have
a transmitter receiver on it or a
transponder they usually have
a bandpass filter so this makes sure
it it only allows frequencies within a
certain range
and they will also have a low noise
amplifier
because these signals tend to travel
very long distances from the ground
stations
so it will amplify those signals and
make sure they are
heard and like with typical wireless
attacks
um satellite link segment attacks are
um susceptible to spoofing
replay attacks and eavesdropping there
was a wonderful talk
earlier um this year at defcon by james
paver
called whispers among the stars about
them
eavesdropping on satellite
communications and it was very cool but
also very scary
and finally we have
jamming so there have been many
instances
of countries jamming each other's
satellites
and what jamming what makes jamming
different from normal interference
is that jamming is intentional so
there have been times where the us
has they have found
iran jamming their gps satellites
there's been issues with russia
and china and all the usual people
now this space segment
can you physically hack a satellite
that's in space
yes you can slap a hardware implant on
there but that requires a lot of money
so this is normally uh reserved for
nation state actors
and bored billionaires but
this is purely theoretical there's not a
lot that we know about it
and it probably has happened but it's
very highly classified so to recap
the threats to satellites there is the
grounding user component
the link segment and the space segment
so here are some more resources for
learning more on your own
there is this cool open source project
called sat nags
and it's a network of many ground
stations
are just made by average people
and they have a crowdsource satellite
info
database and there's actually one fairly
close to here
i believe it's in weddington and that's
station 642 and you can see
all the satellites that it's been
tracking it's very very cool
and the aerospace village this year had
nyansa
and this was a giant collaboration with
the us
air force and red balloon security and
they had a build your own ground station
kit for only a dollar
so as you can imagine they sold out very
very quickly
but they do have all the parts listed on
their website
for building your own ground station
with them
and there's a lot of helpful info on
their website still
and finally we have a lot of
simulation software from nasa there is
42 which is simulating
altitude and trajectory dynamics there
is a lot of math
involved with hacking satellites which i
definitely will not go into
but um 42 is very helpful
with determining the math
you need for hacking a satellite since
you have to be able to see them to hack
it
and there is also uh nas cubed
the nasa operational simulator for small
satellites
and there is also this very cool project
called the cubesat sim project
and a cubesat is a very very tiny
simulator it's or sorry
a very tiny satellite and it only weighs
a couple pounds
so there are quite a lot of them um up
in orbit right now
and i actually got to build my own as
well and it is sitting in my closet
unfortunately
but yes it's fairly cheap all the parts
together
are less than a hundred dollars to build
your own so i highly recommend
uh building your own cubesat sim
so some more organizations to learn from
highly recommend
the aerospace village they have all of
their talks and workshops
from this year's defcon on their youtube
channel
there's also the defense digital service
they they were the ones who ran the
hackasat competition at defcon this year
and finally the library space foundation
they are a
big organization they have many open
source projects like the satnags
they also have the upsat
cubesat and pocket cube satellites that
you can build on your own
so there's a lot of cool documentation
on their website and i highly
suggest checking them out
so thank you very much i am rachel
velasco
and please let me know if you have any
questions i will definitely do my best
to answer them
but again i am not an expert but yes
hack the planet in space