hi
my name is ali hansen thanks so much for
having me
and thanks for tuning in today so my
talk is called
i started an llc from my bed and so can
you
um it's kind of a funny story so i'll
just give you some background but
before we dive in i just want to let you
know the very typical
um covering my behind
so i'm not a lawyer i'm not an
accountant i'm not
an insurance or a financial person or hr
um so none of this presentation or if we
talk afterwards please don't take it as
legal or professional advice and
i just also want to caveat that this
presentation and my process
you know it's not a perfect thing i
learned a lot of lessons along the way
and also you know i'm extremely blessed
in a lot of different ways and we're all
different
and so your journey through this should
you decide to try
uh will probably be different and that's
good and that's okay
um and then just very you know last
thing feel free to dm me anytime
hey ellie hansen on twitter so with all
of the
formalities out of the way let's get
started
so um first things first
i started an llc for my bed it might
sound kind of like
um an interesting title and
it's actually true so let's see
i can't believe it's still 2020. somehow
it is
and in the beginning of the year
um i was kind of so
burnt out from my work and
i was really um you know i was always a
high achiever and i found myself a
really low point
um just in general in my life and
you know i was burnt out mentally
physically emotionally
which is really um really a difficult
thing and i had never really reached
that level of burnout before and i hope
you know i hope that
none of you listening um get to that
point because it's it's truly
devastating
and um you know i was just drained
and disintegrated really to my core
and um so you know it was like there was
nights i went to sleep
and i really was so exhausted that i was
not
100 confident that i would even wake up
from that sleep
it was a really scary time in my life
and i would wake up in the morning
you know luckily and i would just be so
angry and so frustrated like as soon as
i opened my eyes and i knew that
something had to change and that that
was just not a healthy way
to be living my life um and so
basically um you know the the title of
this talk
i started an llc from my bed and so can
you
it's it's actually true right so i
stayed um
for about two weeks straight i kind of
just stayed in bed
and then uh slept and recovered and then
slowly but surely
i started to think about my next moves
and i started to think about
um you know what steps i needed to take
to get there
and sometimes it was just really sending
like one
email a day or researching one topic
a day and i would consider that a
success for that day
and so i took it very slow and steady
and i guess that's
you know one of the reasons in addition
to
um so you'll see there's like a little
cell phone icon
on the screen and i did most of this for
like
basically seven or six or seven weeks
all of this planning and
creation i literally did it on my cell
phone
and uh my cell phone was actually
cracked so
pretty much the worst type of uh
situations you can think of for like
trying to start a company
um so that's why i say you know if i can
do it i think you guys can too
so um a little bit of background
on how that all came to be so i guess
the first thing
uh that you would want to think about is
what do you want to do
right it's kind of obvious but you need
to think about
um you know what what business or what
you want to do or what service or
product
right and you probably you know you
might have an inclination of that
already
like depending upon your background and
your experience and what you want to do
um for me i already kind of knew what i
wanted to do
and that was to provide us consulting
service
and so i kind of already knew what i was
gonna do it wasn't like
i had to you know create a tool or
um you know make an actual physical
invention or anything like that right so
for me that was kind of easy
um and i'd be you know very happy to
talk with you guys about
sort of the creation of your idea and
what you want to do
if that's something that you need help
with
so for me i already kind of knew and i
had done a lot of
informal research sort of in formulating
what i was gonna do
you know with whom to whom everything um
and again you know we could talk about
that ad nauseam in terms of like
you know sort of market research and
things like that if you needed to
but for me i kind of knew i had a good
idea of what i was going to do was
pretty needed
so um so after you kind of figure out
what you want to do
there's a few things for me that i had
to
really consider and go through so
the first thing um is money
the second thing is timing
and the third thing was like contracts
and legal considerations
and your situation might be very
different and again this is just
you know my story and my journey um so
these are the three main things that
you know before i really got started i
decided i need to
figure out these three areas so
the first thing how am i gonna get money
to
you know just give myself a little
cushion to live on
and to pay whatever these expenses are
that are gonna come up because i didn't
even know
and you know there was really nothing
online
you know on any of those entrepreneur
websites or business websites like
nothing was actually really helpful and
that's why i'm hoping this is going to
help you all
and um in a way that maybe you can't
find online
just the real answers or a real
checklist or real considerations
so um that's my hope here so anyway so i
was like thinking okay how am i gonna
get money
and i decided personally that i was
going to withdraw
some money from i have a few 401k
accounts so i was gonna
look at the one and i kind of took a
survey of all the accounts that i had
you know previous jobs and i was looking
at um the performance of each different
account
because some were performing a lot
better maybe i didn't want to touch
those let those grow
more um and obviously different amounts
in each one
different penalty rules just kind of
different things like that like also
maybe
certain accounts were charged a certain
annual fee
others were not right so there's you
know kind of some
research that you can look into all of
your different accounts for your
401k if that's what you decide to do and
luckily enough i was able to do that
um and so basically just you know so you
know
um there is a 10 federal fee so that
goes to the federal government
for withdrawing pretty much any amount
um if you're under the age of like 59
and a half
which i am so i knew i had to pay a 10
fee on that amount that i was going to
withdraw
in addition you will have to likely pay
whatever your particular state fee is
um so you have the federal level fee and
also a state level fee
and usually that's less um but you'll
have to check with your exact state
and then um you will also have to be
paying
um basically like your taxes
on that income that you withdraw from
your 401k account
so whatever your tax bracket happens to
be
you kind of attack that on so there's a
lot there's a lot of fees that add up
um if you go with this route and you
know it wasn't necessarily
maybe the best route or you know the
least fee
amount um you know method obviously
but it's what worked for me it's what i
had and um so here's a quick example you
know just really high level right so
let's say you have
a 401k account with a hundred thousand
dollars in it
which by the way i think would be pretty
good um and then if you had that 10
federal fee i live in virginia and
um so that state fee is 5.75
so um 57.50 and then
let's just presume like you know a
general tax bracket
is not really what i am right now but
let's just say that was you know 25 000.
so
all of those fees are going to subtract
out of what you have in your
401k account and then you'll be left
with um in this example 59250
as your deposit that'll like go into
your actual bank account
and that's the money that you really
have to use
and to live off of um so that's it's
kind of like a few things you gotta keep
in mind
because if you uh if you think that
you're going to be able to
have all a hundred thousand to spend you
know that's not necessarily
true um so just be careful of that and
i guess one other thing i learned in the
withdrawal process
is that um because your
401k accounts are likely based on like
the real
market you know like stock market and
everything
um the amount that you are calculating
with
one day for like your 100 000
um that could maybe the next day be like
99 000 and some change just because of
those variances
in the market so that kind of threw me
for a loop because i wasn't
i didn't know about that so just a heads
up those could change a little bit
um there's also if you're looking at the
401k
option this is something i did not know
about and i kind of wish i had
um so i'm sharing it with you there's
also something called a 401k
loan and they're selectively available
so you'll have to check with your
exact account plan um but the great
thing is
that unlike the full withdrawal where
you're taking that money back in your
pocket
the loan is is a loan so it's actually
not
taxed it's not categorized as income
going into your wallet since it's a loan
which is kind of like a temporary thing
and um there could be interest on
the loan like kind of in normal loans
there's usually some type of interest
sometimes there is sometimes there's not
you'll have to check
and then um you know obviously if you
take the money as a loan from your
account but you don't
put it back you know in time or based on
whatever calendar terms that you have
um you will likely be facing some type
of fee
i i see that the 10 is a is a common
number so
you know you do have to be careful but
that was an option that um i wish i had
known about i might have done that
um and then obviously you know if you
have savings or you have
other you know sources of money that's
wonderful
but this is just what i what i did so
i'll share that with you
and obviously these are kind of
strange times and as such um
so covered has also affected
the rules and guidance behind
401k withdrawals and so
there are sort of a continuation
of guidance slash um modified
rules um that are kind of in the works
um
i just checked with some folks recently
and there's still no
final guidance out as of right now this
recording
um on this sort of like forgiveness if
you will
for um taking out a 401k withdrawal
um so basically that would as far as i
can tell would
sort of um forgive that 10 federal
fee and then who knows maybe there's
maybe the states will also do something
so we're not really sure but
there is something kind of in the works
there so something to think about
and um so i'm gonna pause just really
quickly because i know that's a lot of
information on the 401ks
um and then so the next sort of like
part of money
is not only money going in but money
going out
and i think a lot of people are really
curious about you know
how much would it cost to do your own
thing or
you know maybe even in the beginning or
total
right and so that was something that i
couldn't find
on the internet at all it was really
frustrating and i just
really hoped that i had enough money to
live off of and to pay whatever
i'm gonna need to pay so i'm gonna share
with you all
um my you know my information on what it
cost me
hopefully that can give you guys some
type of ballpark um
for the same types of things so let's
look at money going out because you're
going to want to think about this before
you
um really you know before you really
press any buttons and press
enter and take out money and and you
know quit your job if you're doing that
so
so kind of do some pre-planning here
what is what what are the finances that
you need
to live off of for your own personal
uh reasons like your housing or your
utilities and bills um savings
if you have any sort of like monthly
subscriptions that are um
auto paid right i donate to charity
quite frequently so that's something i
like to
also include and obviously your own
taxes and then also on the business side
of things
so um and we'll get more into this whole
column for the business
so um hang on for that but just sort of
like an overview
you'll see that there are filing and
formation fees
um services that you might need hardware
software
general supplies um labor like your own
kind of your own work
um again charity if that's something
that you want to do with your
organization
and of course taxes so yes um more on
the business stuff
later or actually really soon um but
just kind of an overview so
let's look at your money situation how
are you going to get money
how is it how are you going to spend
money and then the next
sort of like big thing that you should
probably think about
is your timing so for me
as i said um i was employed and then i
actually
um you know painfully uh resigned from
that position to focus on my own health
and
and bouncing back so um for me i kind of
had to really think about
the timing very carefully um
and you're going to want to plan out
like when is the best time to
leave if there is a best time i finished
a huge
project for my organization um
and wrapped that completely up before
you know i pulled the trigger so to
speak
and i just felt like that was the right
thing to do for me
and um you also might want to consider
like do you have a goal
of when you want to begin your actual
work for
clients um as well as chiming for
finances right like if uh depending upon
your money situation you might really
need to start sooner than later
or something like that so um
you're going to want to also just kind
of think related to timing about your
your goals as it pertains to time so
like
when do you when would you like to make
your announcement
at least to your network or you know who
it could be your friends or your family
or
it could be to the public right when are
you going to want to announce
when do you want to have your first
client solidified and you know the
contract sign
and then also again financially uh when
do you need
to have money coming in because that
will also play a role in the timing
um let's also touch
on the third aspect that you're going to
want to think about
potentially if you're also in a similar
situation which is the leaving aspect
um and so as i mentioned you know for me
i
had quit a job and then i had some time
to heal
and then i was going to start on this
journey to make my own company
um so um let's
let's dive into this more so like
contracts really
for me and for a lot of other folks out
there who have employment contracts
and this is nothing like specifically to
what i had but just in general this is
kind of stuff that you could see
so you might see you know contractual
terms
in your employment agreement about
payments
pay benefits um non-competition
non-disclosure
ownership of discoveries and uh maybe
even governing law which basically just
says
where which state does your contract
kind of like uh which state does your
contract follow the laws of
if you were looking at it in a legal way
it would be pertaining to how let's say
texas
looks at those laws opposed to a
different contract
that was kind of like written
for governing law in like alabama would
be
different legal laws as it pertains to
the contract so you might see those
things too
um and i guess you know the one thing
i would really recommend is that you do
uh
consider getting an attorney to help
look through your contract and your
agreement
and um especially just so you can
understand
any things that are binding that you
have to consider
like a lot of the non-competition
non-disclosure
that kind of stuff that will be you know
anywhere from six to 24 months
um that you're binded to that and so
that is a very serious thing that you
should you know
um abide by obviously you're
contractually
supposed to and um you're going to just
want to understand
also like potentially for your business
what um what can you do what can you not
do
um and just kind of like get clarity on
any gray areas that might exist
so in a lot of cases maybe there's no
really you know there's no reason for
concern you're doing something totally
different
or you're providing a different service
right so but i think it's a good thing
to
um to gain clarity on and i would highly
recommend that anyone do that for me it
was a great investment
for me to seek my own legal counsel and
so
for example like if my contract were
written governing law in nevada i would
have
sought out an employment lawyer who
had was able to practice in that state
of nevada
right so you're going to want to match
whatever your contract says
um so that's probably you know
you know very important step that i
would recommend
in addition to the money situation the
timing situation and then your
sort of like legal situation right so i
told you we would go back
into the business expenses and so that's
what i'm gonna do for you right now
and then um sort of at the end you'll be
able to see
you know feel free to take a screenshot
or whatever um
what what we're dealing with here so um
first thing
filing and formation costs
so um just so you know a lot of people
get a little bit worried about like oh
what should i call my business
and actually um you can change the name
of your business
at any time it's like a ten dollar fee
to do that it's really not a big deal so
don't freak out too much about that and
like get caught up on that
really um there's a simple little form
you can you can file it's like i think
it's ten dollars
um so don't worry you can just call it
you know ally's
cool business and change it later like
it's it's really fine
um don't let that stop you and um
there's a lot of confusion and a lot of
um
i would say conflicting opinions
especially on the internet
of you know how should you file where sh
what state should you file
and um what several professionals have
told me
um is that it's actually you know not
really worth it
for a small business that is likely
going to remain
a small medium business to file in one
of those friendly states like everyone
always says delaware
or um nevada or there's a couple other
ones that are like popular
so really the whole scenario behind that
is
um you know it's only really helpful if
your company eventually
is like going to go public or have stock
you know or be an actual corporation um
those protections
may at times help those types of
companies but for myself i knew i wasn't
going to do that just a little
just below me maybe some employees
eventually or something like that so
everyone said no no just just file um
you know
somewhere that's convenient to you like
where you live so
just something to also consider um
there's
there's legal zoom you know services
like that can that can help you through
the filing formation process for your
business
um the one thing that i had found out
was that um
especially sorry legalzoom but um i had
heard that you know
some of the services that they bundled
in were not
actually necessary for what you need to
do and then
actually kind of negatively sometimes
you have to
undo paperwork that was unnecessary
in the beginning and undo that um and
that can be
you know costly time and money so i was
kind of a little bit wary about that
once i found that out
um so i i decided to go with a
friend that i knew um and an accounting
firm
that provided those business formation
services
um and you know that was a lot of there
was a lot of trust there and a lot of
personal relationships there so that was
really great
um also just real quick on tax
classifications because this is
something that's really important to
you know the tax part of your business
um
there's the sole proprietorship and
that's really so like your taxes
um with the business are basically
considered like just whatever your
personal
tax situation is there's like not really
a distinguishing
um factor there so that's what a sole
proprietorship is
in terms of the tax classifications um
the s corp um is basically like
you'll see this word pass through um
which basically means that if you have
your
business um taxes over here and then you
have your personal taxes
over here in an s corp tax
classification your business taxes
pass through your personal
tax like bracket or situation so
they're separate but when it comes down
to it the
business tax situation just goes through
to whatever your personal situation
happens to be at that time
um there's also you know kind of
on a larger scale there's the c corp and
um you know partnership
tax classifications which you know i i
wasn't involved with
um but that's basically like a c corp
would be your text on your business
stuff
plus you're also you know taxed on your
personal stuff
so instead of the pass-through where
you're kind of like benefiting because
you're only being taxed on like one
situation
because it passes through you would be
taxed on both so
um and then again for the sole
proprietorship um there's really not
even two it's just one
so hopefully that makes sense feel free
to you know chat in any questions on
that
um let's see and then just so you know
so an llc
limited liability corporation um it's
actually
not a tax classification in and of
itself
it's a type of business and so if you
decide to you know make an llc like i
did
you will also have to choose what type
of
tax classification you would like
because it's not inherently
uh one already so you'll kind of you
know do both things
um so that was interesting i didn't know
that so i had chosen the s corp the
pass-through
um to complement my llc business status
um also so this is kind of like some
really good checklist stuff for you
and then hopefully when you are able to
um
you know receive a copy of this
presentation or you can dm me or chat me
i do have embedded links to these
actual forms and resources in here again
they might have changed or been updated
but
you'll be able to get a good sense for
what's involved
so um for me i wanted to
you know protect my privacy and
my personal information so i decided to
get a virtual
business address so that i wouldn't have
to put my home address
on any of these forms that some of them
are public some of them aren't
um and so that's something to consider
especially if you're in you know
security um and then in order to do that
you'll have to sort of like
um allow that business to
be able to take in your mail so there's
a little form from the usps that you'll
have to do
and i think it's free to file but you do
have to like give them authorization
um there's also something in the filings
like process where you can hire
something called a registered agent
and that person or some entity will
register all of your paperwork and stuff
on your behalf
with their personal or you know their
professional information
so that uh you know you wouldn't have to
file
these official paperworks with your home
address and your
cell phone and things like that so those
are two um
nice services that are totally optional
but i decided to spring for those
just to protect my own information um
you'll have to get your
employer identification number which is
you know pretty simple process
but there's a form for that you'll have
to file your articles of organization
which again um is kind of you know
specific to
an llc situation you'll have to
um file if you're gonna sort of
go about business with a different name
than
what um you're going to put in the
paperwork so that's like doing business
as
dba you'll have to do that little form
and i think that's the one that's 10
and then you'll also have to let the
government know
what type of tax classification you
actually want to
to be you know seen as so there's a
little form they have to fill out for
that so for me is escort perform
um and then i live is bad upset but i
live in arlington
virginia and so um arlington county
or arlington city um also has like a
little process that you have to go
through
to just sort of get your license uh your
certificate of
occupancy etc so um that was pretty easy
to do i don't think it cost me anything
just
just a little bit of time um and again
the blue ones are all um totally
optional
but ones that you know may be
recommended for your situation
um and these are the costs right so this
is should be hopefully really helpful
um for me you know you can see 60 to 100
um monthly fee for having that virtual
business
address so i can use their address for
everything
their services and registered agent that
was a one-time
yeah that was a one-time fee um and you
can see
some of the filing paper fees um that go
along with that
okay and then oh
this presentation is actually worth at
least 450
because that's what i paid some
professionals to help me through this
process so
you're welcome okay and we talked
already about the expenses sort of money
going out
and just want to quickly go touch on
services
so for services you might need those
attorneys that i talked about
sometimes i'll be depending upon where
you are and their experience level you
know 150
to 250 plus an hour um
kind of pricey um so you just want to
kind of you know budget for that
um if you have accountants and payroll
folks which i would highly recommend you
get
because i'm not a tax professional i
don't want to mess that stuff up
they range from like 50 for sort of the
admin help
to upwards of 200 if you're getting like
the top person out there
firm um for filing assistance
again i told you that i had used that
accounting firm because they offered
that as
as a service and um i think that was
actually
um the 450 that i just told you about
um you'll also want to consider your
business insurance so don't forget this
um there's largely three types of just
like
you know baseline insurance when you get
into more specified
types of work and services and products
you'll have additional different like
you know specific types but in general
you'll have your general insurance your
data breach insurance which we should
all be semi familiar with
what that is and also your professional
insurance
and so um annually that can range
depending upon you know your your
providers i actually
i went through my sort of auto insurance
provider and they
were able to hook me up with a really
good um
insurance provider that they work with
um to get all this business insurance at
a really good rate so that was also a
good tip to maybe kind of
ping who you are to use and see if you
can get a good deal on that
um if you have any questions about the
insurance stuff happy to chat about it
there's some distinctions between those
um obviously if there's any technical or
security services um luckily i'm able to
tap some friends that i have
to help me um and you know obviously
some software that you might need too
to run your business um i had an issue
with
of course my dns getting that set up for
my
mail client and everything so um yeah so
you'll probably need to have some type
of resource for
help with certain things like that if
you don't already know it all yourself
um and then other services you know your
bank and your credit card services for
your business right
business bank business credit card um if
you have if you're going to want to have
any hr
services i actually used to work for an
association
that you'll see this peo is linked and
that's a professional employer
organization
and they kind of do like outsource hr so
they're companies and they handle all
your stuff
and you can look into that if you have
any questions let me know because i used
to work for them
um and then you know marketing or
administrative expenses right just kind
of those ancillary things
um oh also just be careful
there are um sometimes minimum dollar
amounts that you need to have in your
bank account
um so you don't well so you avoid any
you know recurring business fees like
just to have the accounts kind of silly
but it happens um
my bank minimum was like 500 which is
kind of significant
so or else i was going to incur a 20
fee every month so something to keep in
mind i didn't know that
um okay really quick on hardware
obviously you know you're gonna want to
have some type of
computer system um i ended up chatting
with dell
um on sort of the chat feature and had a
really great experience with some of the
folks over there
who helped me get a custom quote on my
laptop
um and obviously there's a newer model
available but that was something i
didn't know
you could do and it actually saved me
quite a bit of money
also took quite a bit of time not sure
if it's because it was custom or because
of the
you know the crazy times operationally
logistically
but um keep that in mind too it could
take some time to get your laptop
software you should be familiar
obviously you're going to need some type
of you know domain host
um a website maybe your
sort of email slash you know just data
organization system right office 365 or
google suite right there's other options
and you can kind of
decide what you want to do there um if
you're going to do some accounting
software
you know something like quickbooks if
you need professional
software like your a professional
linkedin
account that's something to consider if
you want to get the upgraded version
of anything that's freemium like um like
a web meeting service or something like
that
or you know if you need a creative
software um so lots of stuff to consider
and especially depending
upon what you actually end up doing um
so this is kind of what
it costs for me which was not too bad
but um something to consider for our
finances
and um just really quick you know on
labor so
basically eventually you'll get into all
of this
um you know paying yourself a salary and
if you have other employees
um your own benefits and health care um
if you want to do a 401k program you
know your training budget if you want to
have that
conference attendance headshots i was
able to get that for free because there
was a program
um sort of within the the coveted times
that was really helpful they did free
headshots
um so you can kind of look for things
that pop up for that
you know business cards equipment
supplies licenses like there's a whole
bunch of stuff
um that can come up that you know you
can
you can be aware of so we're nearing the
end here
and we're going to do a quick running
calling um
total if hopefully you know my math
checks out here but total
it took me about four thousand seven
hundred eighty four dollars to
start up and that was over the course of
i think about
eight weeks because i took it very slow
as i told you
um and yeah it's over eight weeks
and um so right now fast forward i
actually have two companies um the one
that i started
and then i joined another small business
um
and i'm a partner for that i have
clients right now
i have lots of good things going on um
and i am one happy girl so
uh i know that was a lot of information
you know please
feel free to chat me or dm me anytime
i'd love to help you i'm
already helping some friends in the
industry um explore
their own options and that makes me
really happy because
the one thing i knew before i even
started
any of these steps that i talked about
the one thing i knew i said look
if i can figure this out and get it all
squared away
you know i'm going to take really good
notes on my process and everything and
i'm going to share this with everybody
because i want everybody else to be able
to
have an opportunity to you know work for
themselves
or do their own thing or um you know
just follow their own dream and so
i knew from the get-go that i would be
sharing this with you all
and i look forward to sharing even more
as i find out
more steps of the journey here um so
i've been in operation for
you know september so i've been in
operation for maybe a solid three or
four months
um at this point in time and i know i'm
gonna learn a lot more stuff
um as the calendar year progresses and i
you know incurred different types of
experiences
i've already learned a few other things
um since
i made the bulk of this presentation so
maybe i have to keep updated on that and
again if you have
any questions please feel free to chat
now or
message me later more than happy to help
out with anything that i can
and i just really appreciate you all
having me and thank you
to besides charlotte and all the
wonderful folks running this and
i really hope that you all um you know
show your appreciation for the immense
effort that goes into this
and i hope you take care i hope you um
are able to have a good rest of the year
and thank you again