this hi i'm my name's stephen kirby and
i'm a security engineer
with bright spring health services in
louisville kentucky and i'd like to
thank you for
uh stopping by my talk on training the
itu
it security staff i'm glad that
i'm glad that you've decided to attend
besides charlotte
and i'm grateful that they invited me so
hopefully we can make this an
informative
and potentially entertaining session
a little bit about me uh i'm a former
graduate student in history i'm
eminently qualified to
work in it i was a graduate student in
history
in my younger days i was a reference
librarian for about 10 years
i've been exposed to i.t for almost 30
years now
beginning back in the late 1980s when we
set up a small
local area network using
artistsoflantastic which nobody
remembers these days uh we moved on to
nobel netwear a little bit later and i
did netware for a couple of years
and then discovered unix and i've been
doing
unix systems administration off and on
now for about 26 years
going back to some dusty old versions
like deck ultrix or
sdi irix that haven't been supported
haven't been used hopefully in quite a
while
i started with linux very early on about
in fact my first version of linux was
running igrasil
the kernel was 0.99 patch level 5.
so linux and i go back a ways as i
mentioned i
currently work as a security engineer
and importantly for this talk i hold
multiple security certifications and
that's important because as you know
anybody who's certified
obviously knows what they're talking
about right
i should offer a disclaimer uh that the
views and opinions expressed during this
session are entirely my own my employer
is unaware of
the contents of what i'm going to
discuss in fact most people i work with
don't even know that i'm presenting
so this is should not be construed as
official
positions of any previous or current
employer
unless you've been living under a rock
or in a cave for the last five years you
know that
it's pop it's popular in the security
press
to say that skills are in short supply
particularly cyber security skills
uh we have a quote from 2019 that the
skills shortage
is getting worse uh it could cost us
millions of dollars
there's a war a virtual war raging for
cyber security talent
there are thousands of information
security jobs that are going unfilled
there may be as many as three and a half
million unfilled security jobs
by 2021 that's next year
uh i personally have my doubts that
the situation is quite that bleak i
think that there probably
are some issues with structural
imbalances
but and this this was really real this
is really geared for
a physical conference and i hope to be
hopeful i'll be able to find out next
year
if maybe i've just missed something but
if the skill shortage is really as bad
as people make it sound
wouldn't a security conference like
b-sides
look more more like this look more like
a fraternity rush party
none of the conferences i've been to in
the past have looked like this i mean
maybe the kegger
was someplace and i just missed it i was
on the wrong track
and i look forward to going back to
another conference next year
and actually being able to test this
hypothesis for myself
but for the time being i would have to
speculate that maybe there's something
else at play
that maybe we're not we're not suffering
from a skill shortage
so much as we are a credential shortage
i think the skills are there
the talent is available but it's simply
not qualified
because the way that we hire security uh
personnel
i mean most security positions are not
entry level
they assume two to three years of
somewhat of
some experience uh managing servers or
networking gear or desktops or whatever
so that you have some idea
what the assets are that you're trying
to protect
one of the reasons that we may have that
shortage
is because security training is so
damnably expensive
uh for example if you wanted to get
training from comptia
for their security plus certification
which is a very popular
and very widely recognized uh
entry-level certification
comptia wants about 2 500 to train
one individual to study to prepare for
that certification
and that's a lot of money uh
particularly in
large corporations where the trading
training budget has historically been
viewed with some suspicion
i've heard it said that security budgets
are the last to grow and the first to go
when time when budgetary times get tough
when there's a
need to cut budget or trim costs
training is often one of the first
first casualties one of the reasons for
that is that the link between training
and corporate strategic goals are not
always clear or
at least not made clear uh to the
budgetary authorities
and finally a lot of places including
most places i've worked
training is viewed as an employee's
responsibility
we hired you because you were good and
we expect you to do your best to stay
that way
and it may not necessarily be the
company's uh
position that they need to be actively
involved in that
i understand that's not universally true
and if you
find an employer who is willing to
invest in you
that is definitely a feather in their
cap as far as i'm concerned
on the other hand as many people have
said i've seen it most
often attributed to napoleon if you want
a thing done well you may have to do it
yourself
and that's really what i'm here to talk
about today
ways that you can provide security
credentials that will
impress an employer qualify you to move
from maybe a systems administrator or
network administrator role
into security and maybe make a career
change or
a career path change
to the security field
there are a number of ways that we can
do that uh
one of the most common historically has
been
higher education institutions in full
disclosure i spent
25 years in higher education i'm a big
believer in it
but it's particularly as we have seen it
during the pandemic
it's not without some issues for example
it's expensive uh we'll talk about that
a little bit in a moment
and right now people are objecting to
have to spend
having to spend full cost for
classes that are being offered remotely
uh greek programs can take a while
uh sometimes
full-time a four-year degree well it
takes four years
there's no way to streamline that and if
you're taking
classes part-time uh that could drag you
out even longer that
it's not that local community colleges
and universities
aren't able to to provide training
but it's expensive and it's slow
for example i live in louisville
kentucky and across the river
is purdue university the state one of
the state universities in indiana
it's a very fine institution with a
great reputation
in information technology and i.t
security generally uh
gene spafford who would probably qualify
as the
founding father of i.t security at least
in the united states
has been affiliated with purdue since
the early 1990s so
it's a very well respected program
but it's not cheap if you notice their
program requires 180 credits for a
four-year degree
that we're at 371 dollars per credit
hour
if you extrapolate that
180 times 371 works out to
66 780 for a
four-year degree the future value of
that degree
assuming in the 30-year a 30-year career
and an eight percent interest works out
to about almost seven hundred thousand
dollars
works out really to about twenty two
thousand four hundred dollars a year
which means that
if you go that route and get that degree
the first twenty two thousand four
hundred dollars you earn
every year for the next thirty years
goes to paying off basically
the future value of that education
you're gonna have to amortize it that
way
so that means that if you're making
fifty thousand dollars a year for your
first
first job and that which seems a little
on the high side to me
that you're only really clearing about
uh 26 000 because you're having to
offset the income that
that you lost that you could have could
have earned or could have
you could have acquired simply by
investing that money
uh in some sort of security over time
that's expensive uh it has its
advantages
i don't recommend people avoid higher ed
but if you're looking to make a career
change or if you're looking to
transition
into something else it's an expensive
and very slow way to go
there are some alternatives
even within higher education we have
what are called
a mooc or moocs massive open online
courses
these are generally offered by large
universities some of them with
some of them world-class universities
that you would have a difficult time
getting regular
admission to but you can take classes
with them you can audit the classes very
often for no
no charge at all or you can take you can
get a certification
from them that doesn't carry college
credit for
a reasonably nominal fee there are a
couple of them i'd like to talk about
the first one is edx which was started
i guess probably 10 or 12 years ago now
by mit and a couple of other
institutions in the northeast
if you notice down at the bottom those
are not inconsequential
institutions that are involved with edx
most people will recognize those names i
don't want to spend a whole lot of time
on it because it appears that
edx has recently changed its business
model and their
certifications have gotten considerably
more expensive than they were
when i first started putting this
presentation together
they are available though if you want to
audit just for just to gain knowledge
that's
not a an unwise course a course of
action
so i will mention it but i'm going to
focus a little bit more on
one of the alternatives and that is an
outfit called coursera
coursera is also also provides training
from
prestigious universities i'm very fond
of the university of illinois
one of the ones mentioned there at the
bottom because that's my beloved alma
mater
uh but duke university in north carolina
is there
the university of michigan uh ibm
obviously these these are prestigious
institutions or
large corporations with a good
reputation in the industry
and all of them offer courses of some
sort through coursera
not all of them necessarily are offering
uh information technology classes
or security classes but they are they
are
available for uh study
as i've mentioned most most moocs offer
the ability to audit courses for free of
course sarah does
that fee payment is required for
formal certificates or former formal
credentials through coursera
but it's very reasonable starting about
39 a month and you pay for as long
as it takes you to complete the course
so
it can be if you can cram a little bit
more in
it might you might be able to save some
money that way they do offer financial
aid if you're looking at an ambitious
program
some of their programs can take up to a
year
possibly even longer i don't know for
sure
most of the ones i've looked at have
been in the uh
three to three to six month range and
those will be the ones that i'm going to
focus on
but if it turns out that the cost is an
obstacle uh you might be able to
negotiate something with coursera where
they will be able to
provide some assistance with tuition
one of the courses that i would call
special attention to if you're just
starting out
is this one from new york university's
college of engineering
uh it's it's offered by a gentleman
named eddie moroso
amoroso used to be i believe he was a cs
the
ciso or cso at a t for a while
uh and he has a fascinating background
he's been around for a while
and the stories that he tells in class
some of the anecdotes are rich just
because of the historical value
so if you're looking for a place to
start i would recommend this very highly
i have i've actually audited this course
myself
because i was curious what it was about
and i have to say i enjoyed that process
tremendously
another one that is very fairly recent i
just discovered the next two
in the last couple of months and i've
talked to a couple of our
younger people at work that are have
started taking
at least the first course the
certificate program from ibm
on cyber security analyst and they've
been very impressed with what they've
seen so far
this is an entry-level certificate that
off
i think it takes about three months to
complete
uh and would be an injury would be a
good entry-level credential to be able
to show to somebody
that it demonstrates that you can
complete some that you can complete a
task
you've got a you've got to validate your
interest in knowledge
insecurity and as i say might be a good
place to start
if that's what you want to do if you've
decided that's what you want to do
if you want to get a little bit more
serious about it ibm also offers what is
called a specialization and that's more
extensive
uh training and security matters
i think it i think this one runs six or
eight months something like that
so it's a little bit more involved but
uh
it's an extension of the certificate
program
it both of those might be worth taking a
look at and as
you notice on the screen uh you can do a
seven day full access
trial to see if this is something that
you might be interested in
to kind of get a feel for what these
courses might be like
and what what they're going to cover
i've got one more that doesn't really
fit the mooc
uh model but i didn't have any place
else to put it
so i'm going to talk about security blue
team this is a british outfit that has
just recently started i think in the
last year or two
they are now providing training for what
they as they say
defensive cyber specialists the the name
pretty much explains it
uh they currently offer courses
uh i think the cost was about
20 20 british pounds which i believe is
about 30 dollars per course the last
time i looked
i didn't i haven't verified it lately
but it would be worth looking at and at
the end of each course
uh level one level two level three
the theory is that you'll be able to
take a certification exam that validates
that you've you've learned the material
uh level one is available now
levels two and three will be forthcoming
probably in the next year or so
but again if you're looking to
uh cut your chops and show that you have
some
uh background that might be of interest
in possible
use to an employer this would be another
place that you might want to start
the big question that we want to talk
about though is are you certifiable i've
had people tell me that i
am for years but i think they meant in a
different context
here we're talking about cert being
certifiable
in the context of information being of
information security
uh certifications have a lot of
advantages over more
formal uh forms of education
the big ones are there faster cheaper
and more directly focused on job skills
because
a lot of these are designed to provide
to document that you possess skills that
employers are looking for
and that's how these credentials are
able to earn their reputation
one potential model or road map for
deciding what certifications
you're interested in would be the
department of defense's
8570 section 8570 program
if you're going to work for the dod in
any capacity whether it's a civilian
or as a service person you're going to
need to be aware of this because
these are certifications that it are
required to advance
and to even qualify for entry level
positions
it's not something that necessarily
is looked at quite the same way in
private industry
but it's a useful guide because it gives
you somebody
somebody some influential employers idea
of what certifications are worth i
mention it here
it's kind of a reference we'll come back
to the idea of a road map a little bit
later
towards the end of the session but if
you're looking for
places to start and what certifications
you might want to
aim for in the future this is one
possible way of finding that out
uh other there are other ways i mean
i've seen very often
uh people cite the number of times that
a particular
certification is mentioned in job ads
that's a little bit hit or miss because
you don't know whether
that certification was listed as a
requirement or
as desired or as an example of something
that's required
or desired so this provides you
something a little bit more tangible
than just the idea that it got mentioned
in somebody's advertisement
the first thing i want to talk about
would be vendor certifications
and there are a couple of vendors that i
think merit particularly
mention microsoft does offer a nice
introduction
retroductory level certification in
security
and then the other vendor has been cisco
historically cisco has been
a major player in security
certifications
but it looks to me like some of the
changes they've announced in their
certification programs
lately indicate that they're kind of
stepping back from that a little bit
microsoft offers their technology
associate certification
and as i say this is entry level it's
aimed at
recent high school or college graduates
or maybe someone who's working on a help
desk
somewhere and looking to advance to a
different position
it's it would it would be almost an
ideal first certification
and there are several advantages to it
it's not a terribly expensive
uh certification uh there are a number
of ways that you can prepare for it
we'll talk about some of those
and it does provide documentation that
you're familiar with some of the core
security concepts
as well as that you can see a program
through to completion
there are other microsoft mta microsoft
mta
certifications besides security some of
those might be worth investigating as
well
for example they offer one on windows
servers
administration they offer an
introductory networking certification
all those might be useful to look at but
i wanted to call special attention to
the security mta
because right now that's i as far as i
know the only security
certification that microsoft offers
i mentioned cisco and not too long ago
they introduced the
certified cyber cyber ops credential
and it is still available it is one of
the it is
the main security credential now that
cisco offers
uh it is an introductory level
certification but probably on a little
bit higher level
than microsoft's mta uh
if particularly if you're coming from a
networking background
and you want to explore what might be
available in security and possibly
make a transition this would definitely
would be something that you would want
to investigate
of
the used to be a cc there was a ccna
or cisco network associate i believe it
is
insecurity and apparently that doesn't
exist anymore
uh there's now one ccna to rule them all
and it is a general credential so i'm
not sure how long
organizations are going to recognize the
old ccna i would assume that those are
going to be grandfathered in and will be
good for life
but i have i guess that will probably
vary from institution to institution
but i did want to mention that it looks
like cisco has stepped back a little bit
from the prominent role that they used
to play security certification
probably because network security is
network certification is really their
core business
and there's a lot of other competition
that makes the security route
difficult and expensive for them to
maintain
we need to talk to about some
certification bodies
some of the most important ones would
include comptia
the computer technology industry
association
they offer several security
certifications including one
we've mentioned already security plus
that is probably the best known
entry-level security certification on
the market
and it's certainly well-regarded one
they offer several others
a scissor plus which is the cyber
security analyst i believe
it is a blue team certificate
if you are looking to become
knowledgeable to demonstrate knowledge
and background
in blue team activities in
incident response or cyber self-defense
that might be a security certification
that you would want to pursue
it's an intermediate level certification
as is pentest plus which is its
counterpart
uh as the name suggests pentest plus is
a red team
certification for people who like to
break into systems
but with a white hat for they're doing
they're using their power for good as
you should
uh it is a relatively recent
certification i think it came out in
2018 if i remember correctly uh
and it's got a developing file one but
it i don't think it quite has
the uh recognition that some of the
other
uh comptia certifications do as of yet
the last one to re to mention is the
cast plus
uh i hold this one it is
that is geared towards senior level
security people with
10 years of experience who don't want to
go into management who want to remain
technical and that's how it uh seeks to
differentiate itself
from other certifications that we'll
talk about here in a minute
uh i read on dice.com back during the
spring that
this is one of the emerging
certifications for
2020 so if you fit that category where
you're looking for
a senior level certification but you
don't necessarily want to
pursue a path that will prepare you for
management
cast plus might be one that you would
want to consider
one of the neat things that comptia has
started doing in recent years is the
concept
of stackable certifications and what
that means is that if you earn
two or more certifications you get
an extra certification as a bonus for
example
uh if you get the security plus
and comptia's cloud plus certification
you automatically
qualify for the secure cloud
professional certification
without having to take any other
additional exams
and as you progress you can actually
it almost gets to be like a video game
because they they do multiply so quickly
uh if you i think ultimately you can get
i i have a number of them
it and it makes for an impressive
impressive looking collection i guess if
you just value having stuff to hang on
the wall
but these are all valuable
certifications that i think would be of
interest to employers at least they have
been to folks that i've talked to
and i thought i'd mention them because
that is another another path to
demonstrate your knowledge
the next one that i want to talk about
is isc squared or the international
information system security
certification
consortium say that three times real
fast
there's a reason why it's almost
universally known as isc
squared ise square offers
two very well known certifications uh
the lower ranking one would be the
system security certified practitioner
and if i were going to recommend a
an initial certification for someone
with maybe two to three years of
experience on a help desk or
as a junior administrator of some sort
this would be the one uh sscp
is a natural transition to the cissp
that we'll talk about in a moment
uh it is it does have isc square's
reputation behind it
so it has it does have some influence uh
it's also considerably cheaper believe
it or not than
some of the other uh alternatives i i
think most
places i've seen a voucher for example
security plus
running somewhere around three hundred
dollars the event the voucher directly
from ise squared for
sscp is 249 dollars
and again i can tell you from experience
that
studying for sscp will get you
a large percentage of the way towards
cissp which is the next
certification we want to talk about the
cissp is probably the gold standard
for security certifications in the
marketplace in 2020 and
has been for quite a while uh if you are
looking to become
cso at a company or if you are looking
to become
some form of technol of security
management
cissp is going to be an almost a
requirement
and if you're looking for even some
senior level technical positions like a
an architect position a lot of employers
are going to look more favorably on the
cissp than any other credential
the downside to the cissp is that it's
expensive
uh i will i don't recall exactly what
the latest
uh certification costs but i think it's
about eight hundred dollars
so it's not an inexpensive examination
to sit for
but the return on the investment can be
quite high
uh and as i say it is the gold standard
for security certifications
so it's definitely one you need to be
aware of if you weren't already
another not necessarily gold
standard but definitely on
approaching the ise squared level would
be isaka
uh which had the good sense to change
its name from the information systems
audit and control association to just
isaca because
nobody nobody used their real name
either
and they offer several interesting
credentials one that i was surprised to
find out i just
discovered the first one a few months
ago and that's the
csx cyber security fundamentals
certification
again it's an entry-level cert uh
and it is also quite reasonably priced
as well
it does not have an expiration date uh
with
security plus and sscp you would have to
recertify i think after three years i
know in the case
it's three years in the case of security
plus and i believe sscp is the same
the cyber security fundamentals uh
certification from isaca
does not require that so once you've
earned it
it's yours it's yours to keep forever
probably their two best known
certifications are
excuse me the cism
cssm the certified information security
manager
which as the name suggests would be very
appropriate for someone
looking for a management credential
and then the certified information
systems auditor
those last two are definitely senior
level credentials so they would be
something that
you would aspire to after five to ten
years experience
in the security field as you are ready
to make a transition
from a hands-on techie to
managing hands-on techies and the
auditor
obviously is geared towards people who
are going to be uh
auditing involved in auditing and
compliance
uh both of the both of these are widely
recognized and widely respected
credentials
and anything from my saca is going to
have
name recognition with employers
the last certification body i want to
talk about is mile
two uh this one has been
this body has been somewhat
controversial
on certification discussion forums uh
because there's some question as to how
widely recognized their certs are
full disclosure i have three from them
in fact mile two is basically what i
have done during the
to keep myself entertained during the
coronavirus pandemic
mile t specializes in alternative
certifications
a lot of their certifications are
loosely based
on something else the advantage that
they have is
they don't have some of the overhead for
example work experience requirements
that are required to even sit for
something like the cissp
or the cism or
cisa you pass the
if you can pass the test you qualify for
the certification
and that's the end of the story and
these are not
these are not simple certifications uh
for example
i've mentioned that they're some of
their certs are generally
based on other more widely known certs
uh the cisso comp that compares to the
cissp
in fact mile two's version was developed
by the same gentleman kevin henry who
developed the training materials for
ise squares cissp
so he's very knowledgeable about about
the material
and from what i can tell they cover a
lot of the same questions
they just it just doesn't have the
necessarily the same recognition
but if you've got some other
certifications to hang your hat on
that may not be such a big deal uh
other certifications for mile 2 that
might be worth mentioning would be
the cissm which maps to the cism from
asaka there is a cissa
that compares to the cici for my
saca and the c-i-a-h-e which is an
incident handler
certification that compares to the
jack or sans institution gcih which
is simply not going to be in my my
budget anytime soon
uh either to prepare for
or to sit for i mean sans exams
certifications are very widely regarded
very highly regarded very
widely respected but they are
prohibitively expensive unless you can
find
at least for most people i know unless
you can find someone else
who's willing to to pay the examination
fee
so in to summarize so far
here here's one possible set of uh
career paths that you might might follow
as you look to advance your credentials
in cyber security you might want to
begin with something like
the microsoft mta or cisco cyberops
security plus sscp
or the cyber security fundamentals
certification from isaka uh those would
require anywhere from
zero to probably three years of
experience
uh before you can before you can really
get the most out of them uh
you if you have a little bit more
experience as you as your career
progresses
you can look at other certifications
like the sisa plus that i mentioned
or pentest plus the sscp does a little
bit of double duty here because
it uh covers some of the ground that
comptia has split off from what what the
security plus used to be
and they've used that to populate their
intermediate
certs the sscp from ise squared covers
some of that same
ground uh in a single certification
and then if you're if you're feeling
ambitious
the cisso from mile 2
might be a way to get your feet wet and
find out where you stand
without spending the full price to sit
for the cissp
and maybe have it qualify as an
associate which
we you would have to do if you didn't
have requisite uh
work experience and other background and
finally
if you're once you reach the seven to
ten year mark
you might look at something like casp
plus or the cissp
or one of the isaccar credentials is a
way to
put a an exclamation point on your
career progress
we need to talk some about online
training providers and where you can go
to prepare
for these certifications because as i
mentioned early on
uh getting trained for most of these
search directly from the vendor is going
to be very very costly
and if you're doing it yourself if
you're having to fund your own
uh security
certification preparation you're
probably going to want to do so at the
lowest possible cost that will enable
you to prepare
to pass the certification exam
one of the most popular ways to do this
or one of the most popular vendors
of certification preparation and other
training is plural site i recommend them
very highly
i generally i have had my own
subscription
uh from time to time i don't have it i'm
it's not currently active
because i'm doing some other things but
i recommend them very highly
they provide for example their
certification course for
sscp and cissp training
is developed by kevin henry who
developed the training that
you would actually pay ise square to
take
but you can you can get his uh course
directly from
pluralsight for a relatively low fee i
think it's about 30
a month right now or at least it was a
few months ago when i was still
i had an active subscription
and as i mentioned in addition to
certification training pluralsight
offers
uh courses on multiple topics that might
be of interest to security staff
for example software solutions like
splunk or ibm's q radar
both event log or sim solutions
uh vulnerable scanning with
vulnerability scanning
with uh tenable nessus or if they
their course is aimed at open vas but
openvas as such doesn't exist anymore it
is now the
green bone security assistant
gsa i believe uh and it's more of a
demo for the commercial product
unfortunately but you can still
at least master some of the fundamentals
of vulnerability scanning
by using that product in conjunction
with the
training on vulnerability scanning that
is available through pluralsight
and if you're looking for training on
security frameworks and that's a popular
topic these days
you want to learn the iso 27000 series
or
nist or pci dss there are individual
courses on that that are available
through
pluralsight very similar to pluralsight
is
linkedin learning which would used to be
known as lynda.com and they've been
around for quite a while too
they were recently well a year or two
ago i think purchased
uh by microsoft and merged into linkedin
if you have a premium subscription to uh
linkedin which again i think is about
thirty dollars a month
you have access to one to uh linkedin
learning
again it's very similar uh in scoping
and intent to plural site you will find
training on a wide range of subjects
including a lot of courses that can be
useful
for certification preparation
i want to mention make special mention
of udemy in some ways udemy is my
favorite
of the certification providers they
provide
they're they contrast a little bit with
uh
linkedin learning and with pluralsight
with those courses you pay a monthly
subscription and you get access to
their whole range of training whatever
you
whatever you want to study that at that
minute if they've got a course
you can take it you to me it's a little
bit different you
purchase access to a course and then
that course is yours for life
uh whereas with pluralsight
and with linkedin learning you may you
will find generally
one course per topic if you're looking
for example for
security plus training they will have
one set of courses
uh from usually from one uh trainer
that deals with the subject matter udemy
is a little bit different you can have
mult canon will find multiple training
providers for most of the major
certifications
so you have have a wide range of choices
some of these choices are very very
some of these alternatives are very very
good
some of them are not so you need to pay
attention to
things like the reviews available one of
the nice things about udemy is they do
offer
a trial so if you don't like the course
after 30 days you can get your money
back
uh the other thing that is noteworthy
about them is that very frequently
they offer reduced prices for training
courses
i don't recall ever having paid full
price for a udemy course
if you wait maybe a month almo it seems
like
inevitably the course is going to be
available for
9.99 or 11.99 or something like that
as opposed to in some cases the list
price which could be over a hundred
dollars
per course but the advantage that udemy
has is that
you do have a range of providers if you
don't see one
if you don't like a particular course
you may be able to find
one that you do like from someone else
for example for
uh the microsoft mta cert security
certification
here we have multiple courses that could
be used to prepare for that examination
uh i would call attention to a couple of
things here
that are a little bit more important
that they might be for
providers like pluralsight and linkedin
you need to check the expiration date
or the up last day update on each of
these courses because
sometimes you'll find courses here that
go back
number of years in fact if you want to
look for i believe that
there are still certification prep
courses for
the previous version of security plus uh
that are still available through you to
me and if you're not careful you can
wind up
buying something that really won't do
you much good to prepare for the current
version of the examination
so you might want to check and make sure
that the course is currently being devel
updated and it's also useful to notice
the
student ratings that might give you some
benchmark
of how other people have looked at the
course they do provide reviews
the opportunity for people to provide
reviews the way that amazon does for
products for example
and so you get some idea of what people
did and did not like
about a particular course and again as i
mentioned
uh they do offer a 30-day money-back
uh guarantee if you buy the course and
decide that you don't like it
i've actually taken advantage of it
several times and they're very prompt
about refunding and that's one of the
reasons that
i am so fond of you to me as a training
provider
another interesting uh provider is pac
publishing
and this is one that a lot of people
haven't heard of
you can prov generally with udemy you
can
purchase access to a course but if you
want to download that
say and store it on your laptop
most often with udemy you can do you can
do that for mobile devices but as far
as i know they don't have an application
uh that will allow you to download it to
a laptop or to a desktop pc
pack allows you to purchase that and
similar to udemy uh that matter of fact
they offer a lot of the court
a lot of the same courses that are
available through you to me if you
want to if you're looking for a
particular one and want to hang on to it
for a while
you could possibly buy that udemy course
through pack publishing
but you're able to provide down actually
download it
as mp4 files and you can actually have a
package
of full training for generally for often
not a lot of money
i if you wait again you can probably
find something on the ten dollar per
course range
and they do have uh black friday and
a lot of sales or at least they have the
last couple of years
late in the year where i one point i
think i got
10 for 40 or something like that
uh now the downside is that
in packs case you may
they may break up a single course into
three or four different components and
ask for you to pay for each section
separately
so the cost can mound up but
if you if you time it right if you catch
it catch them on one of their sales
the price can still be quite reasonable
and if you
don't want to necessarily uh
be attached to the internet all the time
though that's not quite the problem that
it used to be
pact is one way to go you can purchase
the offer also offer
pdfs of what would normally be printed
books that can be used
for certification training or
preparation
so that is something else to be aware of
they offer
they also offer a monthly subscription
it was
9.99 i haven't checked it
recently i mean in the last couple of
weeks to know whether or not it's still
that price or not but
it is an alternative that you might want
to investigate if you're looking for
preparation for a particular security
certification
i will recommend several uh
providers that are available through
pact as well as udemy
uh one is jason dion i've used his
preparation
for his materials to prepare for several
certifications
mike myers is both a trainer himself and
owner
of an outfit called total seminars
and i found their products to be
universally quite good
and one that i have discovered
relatively recently is thor peterson
uh i'm actually using one of his courses
right now to prepare for
uh my next certification and
i think he does a very good job as well
so if you want if you're looking for
someplace to start
those names might give you
someone to look for the downside about
peterson is that he really only targets
upper level
uh certifications cissp cism
cisa as far as i know he doesn't offer
any
lower level certification prep courses
one more that i would like to mention is
cyber and once upon a time siberia would
have been a favorite
uh they used to be and used to means
maybe a year ago be famous for offering
free training
and they would charge you for
certification to completion
the way that a mooc might they've
recently changed their business model
because
they've merged with some other training
providers and they're now providing
a wider range of training some of it
obviously commercial but they've also
increased their price to about 49
dollars a month per subscription
or 400 a year you can you may be able to
find it during specials for a lower
price
but it's no longer universally free for
anything that they offer
and a lot of their good certification
prep courses now
uh required payment of a fee i don't
recommend them as highly as i used to
but
they're still a lot cheaper than uh
most of the formal training from
certification providers
so it's worth at least knowing about a
couple of people that i'll mention is
would include kelly handerhand i used
her
uh training class to prepare for the
cissp
or in my case cisso uh
last spring and it was quite good i
caught i got
i was able to take it right before it
got moved behind
i guess you'd call it a pay wall and i
recommend it very highly it was the best
cissp prep course i took and as i
mentioned that also includes kevin henry
who
developed the training for ise squared
and hand her hands courses are usually
i've never i've never taken one that i
didn't like and i've taken several
and another gentleman i'd like to
recommend i mentioned ed amaroso before
uh he is now and is a professor at
nyu new york university but he also has
a couple of courses available
available through cybury that i would
expect would be very very
worthwhile uh i think one of them is a
for preparation to become a ciso or siso
and the man is definitely qualified to
address that topic
last but not least this is something
that the uh
staff on our help desk turned me on to i
don't know about a year ago when i was
starting to put together this
presentation and that's professor messer
uh the advantage that that professor
messer's courses have is that they're
free
not only does he offer for example
security plus training he also offers
i believe a plus and network plus
training if you're interested in
something like that
but he also offers uh
free study sessions online study
sessions where people can meet and
exchange ideas and discuss
uh topics that they've gone over in
that week's lecture uh the courses are
available for free he makes his money
by selling access to training notes and
study questions and things of that
nature
and his material is surprisingly good
given the fact that
he's not charging for it i mean you
can't it's hard to be
free for free for price and if you're on
a tight budget
uh looking for a place to prepare for
one of these lower level certifications
definitely check this guy out uh there's
a link to his website in the slides
uh you can you could probably navigate
from there to
find some of the other certs but i
actually recommend him quite highly
and have recommended him to other people
that
in our in our team that are looking to
get certified
to wrap up and summarize what we've
covered
uh i hope i made the point that security
credibility is a combination of
experience and credentials
if you just have the credentials but
don't have the experience
that's not going to be as valuable as if
you've got both
if you've been a security if you've been
an assistant administrator
or a network administrator for a couple
of years
you've got some if you've got some
technical skills under your belt
that's going to make the credentials a
whole lot more valuable than just having
just being a paper tiger
and having a certification to hang on
the wall
credentials both the degrees and
certifications they complement
experience but they do not replace it
so just you shouldn't think of a
certification training course
if something is going to teach you
skills it's going to help you emphasize
skills that you've already developed
because that's what employers are really
going to be looking for
i maintain that systems and networking
experiences is
essential for security work because
those are both
parts of the part a large part the
assets that we as security professionals
are protecting
and obviously things like patching
hardening and configuration skills
can be reinforced and enhanced with
security certifications
because the skills you've acquired along
the way
could be can be documented uh
and you can you can be shown you know
how to apply them
uh to security work
last but not least even after your
career is launched you're going to need
to learn
continuing education and continuing
education credits most certifications
with a few exceptions that i've
mentioned require them
for example for comptia cert you're
going to have to earn
so many so many uh continuing education
hours
per year for three years in order to
renew your certification
you're also going to have to pay a fee i
think it's 50
per year the number of uh ceu credits
varies from certification to
certification
and i hope you know that learning never
stops uh
the fee the reason that continuing
education requirements exist is
well partly to make sure that there's a
continuing income stream for the
certification providers i'm
too much specific not to believe that
but it's also
to help keep people engaged in learning
and
new developments in the field so i
hopefully
this this brief chat can serve as an
introduction
or for a reminder for some of you some
excellent low-cost means of learning
and i believe we've got hopefully we've
got a little bit of time left and we'll
be available for questions
thank you