hi I'm rich Trumka pacnet for years they
don't know me basically here to talk
about subsea cable systems in Asia and
the impact their availability and repair
schedules have on backbone design and
planning so first I just want to do a
brief review of subsea operations and
repair also some common outage factors
and the second half of the presentation
I just want to go through the design
factors that operating in region that's
heavily dependent on submarine cables
and what those factors are and your
consideration for designing backbones so
first of all who is packed meant just
very briefly we're basically a pan-asian
subsea cable provider and Internet
service provider and we wholly owned and
operated submarine cables in Asia the AC
system cdc system and EAC pacific easy
pacific basically represents two
independent fiber pair on the 55 repair
unity system so just as a quick review
high-level subsea cable components
typically have your subsea cable itself
which is typically unarmored deep sea
cable lightweight cable and deep-sea
applications and then you'll have
additional armoring protection as you
come into shallower waters you have
branching units which provide stubs or
Spurs to other markets without having a
deploy a completely separate cable you
have repeaters that are responsible for
all amplification and equalization needs
of the optical signal and then as the
cable system comes in the beach landing
typically the cable is buried for added
protection usually anywhere between one
and a half to about three meters deep
that comes into a beach manhole access
point which ties into a terrestrial
extension to bring you into the cable
landing station basically a cable
landing station is a hardon facility
that has all the optical equipment and
the power feed equipment necessary power
the repeaters so this is just a snapshot
of a sample repeater this one happens be
a teiko repeater basically is a
self-contained advice that houses all
the internal hardware necessary for
amplification and equalization of the
optical signal and this is basically
what makes subsea operations
and subsea cable systems operate over 10
kilometer ten thousand kilometer spans
this is just snapshot a typical repair
equipment deployment equipment we have a
cable ship it's a specialized ship that
houses spare cable I typically has
multiple cable tanks cooled you can have
thousands of kilometers to cable in
these tanks and then additional burial
equipment such as plows and rvs for
shallow water burials this is just a
snapshot of a typical subsea cable
construction it does vary by vendor type
typically start with a unit fiber
structure basically this is just a
polymer tube that houses the optical
cable or optical pairs and protects them
surrounding that you typically have a
high strength steel wire support either
adds support and strength and stiffness
to the cable as well as providing a
pressure vessel surrounding night you
typically have a seam welded copper
sheath this pretty much provides a power
main power conduit for the PFE which
powers are repeaters and then
surrounding that you have a polyethylene
jacket which backs is an insulator to
protect the main power conduit from the
natural ground potential of the Satan
that's baseline lightweight cable
construction which is typically used in
deep-sea applications as you come into
shallower waters for additional
protection and adverse seed bed
conditions rocky conditions you have
additional armoring and protection these
are just some common fault types you
have a shunt fault which basically is
when the power conduits exposed to the
ground potential to see fiber pairs
remain intact and the PFE has to
reconfigure rebalance to maintain
service but the segment can remain in
service until you can get a ship out to
do the repair you have a cable cut which
is actually complete cable cut of it the
segment obviously the segment at that
point is taken down repeaters as highly
available as they are reliable and have
redundant components in it to protect
against laser diode failures there may
be instances where you have a
catastrophic outage or event that
actually does damage the repeater and so
then you have to bring a repeater up to
either service it or repair it or
replace it this is just the diagram
logic diagram of power feeding in normal
condition so you have power feed
equipment both ends of the cable like
cable stations one with a positive
negative voltage differential that
supplies a constant current and constant
voltage drop across each repeater and in
the center of the system you have a
Virtual Earth in a cable cut our cable
fault the power Connor becomes exposed
to the sea water and creates a grounding
point the PFE has to reconnect to
maintain a constant current on both ends
and maintain a constant voltage drop
across each repeater for two main
reasons one is to protect the repeaters
from damage from having to high voltage
levels of power levels and the second is
in a case of a shunt bowl you can
actually maintain service on the
surviving fiber pair that's unaffected
so in a shunt fall scenario to be able
to isolate and localize a repair to get
a ship out site to the site to do the
repair you have to take a voltage
measurement so at each end to the cable
station there'll be a voltage
measurement that you can take from the
PFE to determine roughly where the shunt
fault occurs to bring the ship out to
the repair in the case of a full fiber
cut you can actually perform additional
optical measurement so you typically do
an OTDR measurement which actually text
basically the backscatter of light on
the actual fiber break that test signal
sent back to the test kit which is very
sensitive equipment and can determine
within approximately 30 meters where
that fiber fault occurred and this is
again over spans that can be several
thousands of kilometers this is a
snapshot of the test kit sample test
signal so as you can see to the left
there is a sawtooth diagram that
basically shows a test signal
amplification as it crosses each
repeater it's a approximately space to
every 70 kilometers or so and as you can
tell from the green line in the center
that's actually where the test signal
degrades from the actual fiber cut so at
that point you have to send a repair
ship out to the repair if it's not a
complete and clean fiber cut typically
you'll have to do what's called a
cutting drive you actually cut the cable
the cable ship will then head down
dream from where the cable cut occurred
typically twice the distance as the
depth in which you're doing the cable
repair that's to be able to provide a
counterbalance and additional
counterweight to be able to pull the
cable up to the surface it'll use a
grapnel to hook the cable bring it up to
the surface buoy it off head over to the
other section of cable that needs to be
repelled up which is the second holding
drive it'll splice in spare cable
typically protected with a joint box and
at that point lay additional spare cable
over to the first buoy site perform the
final splice and that point gently lay
the cable to the ocean floor you can't
just release the cable because if you do
it has a significant danger of
entanglement and further damage to the
cable and you have to go back out and
repair it again so this is just a
snapshot of that sequence on the
timelines that are associated with each
repair as you can see at a minimum it
takes approximately ten days give or
take a day to do a subsea operational
repair but that's a best-case scenario
there are additional delay factors that
you have to take into account and that
can cynic significantly affect the
repair time frames for segments that
your trunks may be on so the permit
application process depending on the
territorial waters that you're in to do
the repair could take anywhere from a
couple days a couple weeks or even
longer some environmental factors that
come into play typically whether
additional after aftershocks from
seismic activity cable repair ship
availability proximity so where is the
cable ship docked how far away is it
from the actual fault how long is it
gonna take for it to head to that fault
location and then shallow water retrieve
on Barry o additional equipment time and
incorporated with actually burying the
cable protected in shallow waters so for
outage factors you know there's two
types there's natural disasters and
typically external aggression so you
know in summary you know seismic
activity tends to be the one that gets
the most press seismic activity undersea
earthquake typically triggers a
turbidity current that turbidity current
can actually very high roads very high
speed depending on the slope of the
canyon as well as a density of the
material which basically takes
everything out in its path including
undersea cables some useful tools that
are typically available on the web is
that from the US Geological Survey is
they track seismic activity throughout
the globe and what's interesting is you
can actually drill down into specific
regions and identify seismic actively
areas clusters heat maps based upon
particular areas that tend to have a lot
of seismic activity and understanding
what cables cross those points and what
routes maybe have potential damage to
them or have a higher probability of
failure you can drill down at the
details on the individual earthquake
itself and so I highly recommend you go
to the site I've root around for
yourself and take a look at the
information that's there aside from
undersea earthquakes typhoons as was
evident from typhoon work out in august
two thousand nine basically a torrential
downpour and resulting storm storm surge
caused a significant amount of debris to
walsh offshore and triggered a turbidity
current in the calpain canyon this
turbidity current actually the
interesting thing about this committee
because it actually occurred to separate
flows so the first flow was triggered
during the peak flood I took out two
cable systems initially and then three
days later a second flow was triggered
and most likely from the build-up of
sediment material along the canyon walls
and this resulted in additional cable
events a total of eight cable systems
were recorded to be affected some cable
systems had multiple faults and the
interesting thing about this is that
just because a typhoon rolls in through
the region and you're monitoring your
network and understanding that there
might be a potential risk of an outage
on trunk passing through that area
you're not necessarily out of the water
no pun intended for after the typhoon
passes there actually may be a lag time
in terms of susceptibility to outages
that may follow from build up a sediment
material on the canyon walls
so the vast majority of badges are
actually not environmental most our
external aggression typically shipping
and fishing vessels anchor drops and
drags bottom trawling bass fishing while
a net will snag a cable and break it and
to some lesser extent believe it or not
dynamite and explosives bass fishing
there are portions of South Asia where
this is unfortunately commonly practiced
it's kind of cheating / fishing but it
does do to him which the cables and also
piracy there have been recorded
instances of segments or portions of
segments stolen for the materials that
are in the cable and most of the
individuals seemly cable they're not
going after the fiber they're going
after the copper it has a higher
intrinsic value for them for resale on
the market so you know again in terms of
restoration prayer constraints a lot of
things you need to keep in mind aside
from weather is that there may be other
events that are not the norm and those
events may be unique environmental
factors which was evident from the Japan
Fukushima plant there were areas of
radiation exposure that made it very
very difficult for cable repair ships
and operations to go in and actually do
repairs and had to wait for that to
subside before their repair ship to get
on site so a lot of things that you can
take into account on you know when
looking at your your backbone design and
diversity is understanding well what
type of outages will affect the repair
time frames you know are there is it a
shunt fault repair does it actually
require additional cutting drives
there's additional abilities associated
with that we're repeaters damaged from
from the supplier you know do they have
to go out and actually replace the
service of repeaters there's additional
time associate with that as well as the
types of conditions in the location
default in shallow water a lot of times
it's diver assisted repairs and fast
currents and dangerous diver conditions
can delay repair time frame so that may
add a few days or even weeks to the
repair time frame so a lot of subsea
cable investors operators there is a
significant amount of research done in
terms of planning risk projection during
the route analysis phase of the
desktop study of the design they do look
at cable faults proximity probability
seismically active regions what type of
fishing and shipping activity may cause
actual further outages but obviously you
can't protect the entire safe there are
certain routes that you have to use just
because of geography one of the
interesting things is that a lot of
government entities have taken a look at
the value that submarine cables are to
their local economy if cable systems are
taken out it adds an effect on their
bottom line and so they've taken steps
to actually create protection zones
where ships are prohibited from fishing
and shipping vessels are prohibited from
dropping anchor now creating a
protection zone is completely separate
from actually doing enforcement so
obviously even if you create a
protection zone and you don't enforce it
the issue is that they're those
particular areas are still susceptible
defaults so from a cable some submarine
operator summary cable operator some of
the things that are added disposals we
typically can deploy Guard boats Guard
boats you know given just the vastness
of the ocean and tens of thousands of
kilometers of subsea cable there
typically not effective for long-term
protection you can't deploy guard boat
to cover every area that you have
submarine cable where this is
particularly useful is where you have a
major event portion of the cable system
is taken out and so to protect your
restoration capacity you will
strategically deploy Garbo's to areas to
ensure that no additional faults occur
until you complete the repair so again
for for some of these components that go
into and impact your decisions on
designing backbones there's a lot of
things you need to look at typically
geographical there are limitations on
subsea brats you can't lay a cable
everywhere there are there tend to be
preferences in terms of laying cable in
very deep and shortened paths just to
again be more efficient in terms of
deployments minimize the amount of cable
that you're actually deploying to to
meet the need of connecting certain
markets Luzon Strait is a perfect
example this unfortunately it by it goes
over a major release
a major seismic active region and a lot
of cables are grouped there as we all
were aware from the 2006 Boxing Day
earthquake they're also regulatory
constraints you may look at alternative
routes for designing diversity into your
network may be taking through China or
some other markets but you also need to
take into account licensing restrictions
ownership rights termination rights and
so there are a lot of options for routes
coming in and out of of every possible
market you can also do some historical
Mouse of analysis and planning you can
look at you know particular markets that
are have a high degree of shipping
activity Singapore is notorious for this
you have a large port backlog a lot of
ships coming into the area they can't
get any access to the port they're
waiting their turn they'll drop anchor
so in that area the vast majority of
cable faults and outages are typically
anchor drops from shipping activity and
again you can look at other routes in
terms of crossing certain shallow seas
where there's a lot of fishing activity
so you know from a submarine cable
operator we've been looking at ways to
make it more efficient in terms of
bringing international capacity into a
particular market and some of the things
that we looked at is collapsing the
cable station and pop essentially moving
the capacity set it from the cable
landing station then terminates a
backhaul shifting it into the Metro
directly and one of the ways to do that
is look at shifting the SLT to the city
center basically in that scenario the
cable annexation remains just as a power
feed station you may have a dry repeater
there to extend it another 70 kilometers
but some of the limitations are based on
distance so typically coastal cities
like Singapore and Hong Kong are
appropriate for this model but other
countries in which there's long
distances between the cable landing
points and the city centres such as Jay
Korea and Japan this tends to create
issues in terms of whether or not this
is actually technically feasible so then
the other approaches to go in the
opposite direction and in this instance
you basically build data center in the
cable landing station and a classic
issue is well cable landing stations are
typically closed environments so
maintain carrier neutrality how do you
have access to diverse systems and
routes it is a problem but one of the
interesting facts is that given the
limitations on viable landing points if
you look at international cable systems
most cable landing points are clustered
and so maybe not in the same physical
building but within a few kilometers you
have access to diverse systems and so
it's just organizing an approach to be
able to gain access and interconnect to
those systems to give the diversity that
you need and again you may it's not a
one-size-fits-all opportunity you may
look at a hybrid approach where you keep
your compute centers and your data
centers in the metro environment but you
put a small network node in the cable
landing station and in that case you can
be more efficient in routing topology
class example is us to Japan so I you
don't today a lot of capacity coming
from us to Japan terminates into Tokyo
before heading on to other markets and
so one of the efficiencies look at is
put a small network node on the coastal
edge in the cable annexation and you
only route traffic into Tokyo for
traffic that has to drop him to Tokyo
the traffic going on to other markets
like Hong Kong and Singapore can route
directly off of the ocean front so from
a trunking standpoint we've seen the
migration of fault-tolerance go from
traditional optical protection where
yeah optical protection was provided by
the service provider the issues with
this is lack control on backup routes
and the latency impact that you may have
on a backup path as well as ring
interconnects so interconnects between
systems tend to create a common point of
interconnecting the single point of
failure so the shift has been into
building your network doing multiple
linear services this way you have
control over the routes that you're
taking as well as the latency
performance of each route that you're
designing the issue becomes what if you
get into a catastrophic scenario where
multiple systems are taken out again
Taiwan was a lesson learned in the sense
that even though you may have designed
multiple linear paths over multiple
cable systems going through the same
pinch point may take out multiple trunks
and then now you're fighting and in a
scenario where you're you're choosing
between manual versus on
restoration as well as prioritization on
being restored with the supplier so that
one of the options is that a lot of
suppliers are looking at building
optical meshes it's been done in the US
it's now taking taking a strong foothold
in Asia this is basically setting up an
intelligent switching platform using a
sauna GM pls and in essence it gives you
a lot of control in terms of the routes
that are available to you so you can
create a primary secondary tertiary
routes you can pick and choose the paths
that you want for those backup pads and
you can design in a way in which the
latency performance is within a delta
that's acceptable to you again this may
not be a one-size-fits-all approach you
may want to look at strategic markets
where this makes sense Hong Kong
Singapore for example there are many
systems in which latency performance
between those markets across separate
cable systems is within a few
milliseconds difference and so you may
look to actually build your trunks using
a provider supplied optical mesh for
protection for one or two of your trunks
but then for routes where the latency
differential is significant you want
more control you can adhere to the
linear approach say for example back to
the US where you may choose a AG or TGN
or PC one or any number of cable systems
that are available to you and so this is
basically just an overview of you know
some of the factors when designing
backbones in a region that's so heavily
reliant on submarine systems and some of
the factors that you have to consider so
there's any questions comments alright
any questions for rich
hi I'm luili Equinix thanks this is a
very interesting I wanted to ask if you
guys have looked at is a cop would it be
cost-effective to have a couple of
lookout points on the shore to see to
look at areas where there might be ships
dropping anchors high probability of
ships dropping anchors waiting to come
into port to see if you can detect ships
that are not moving any faster than the
current um it's a good point it's I
think it's the amount of resources that
are involved in doing that again
depending on how many cable landing
stations you have tracking that activity
can be very difficult additionally you
know again ships tend to take available
space where they can when they're
waiting for a particular port backlog
and so in that instance the locations in
which they actually drop the anchor
change and they bury and so what may be
a particular scenario and high high
incident location one day may not be the
same the next but it could all be
automated because you already know where
your pants are and you can use your gps
and triangulation to figure out where
the ships are so that could be a
potential solution didn't you want to
take back gonna bet okay anybody else
have it over mini yes net I also find
this all absolutely fascinating even
though I really don't have anything
personal to do with it at all as far as
the ground return is do you rely on the
sea water the ground that naturally
exists around the cable purely or do you
have exposure of the outer protective
metallic protective layer of the cable
to the sea water as well it's typically
the power conduit come in contact with
sea water it just creates a natural
earth ground and a grounding point and
we use that as a reference point for the
voltage measurement
okay any others going once going twice
all right rich thanks very much thank
you