good morning welcome to nanog 52 in
beautiful Denver it's great to see all
you got everyone out here it's we've
been off to a great start we had great
tutorials yesterday we had a great
social last night let's hear it for
alcatel-lucent coresight I mean it was
really great I thought the food was
great the venue was great i really had a
good time I have a few announcements
that I want to make and then we'll get
going here first off um thank you google
for the great sponsoring of the
newcomers breakfast I don't know how
many people were there but there was a
great turnout it was a nice event so
thank you google so for the breakfast
out out here in the south lobby i'm just
going to read all these because i can't
i wanted to write them down but then I
there were more characters than I've
written down in a long time so I just
thought I'd read it so alcatel-lucent
Arbor cns Cisco fortinet friendfinder
networks infinera network hardware
resellers NTT America OSI hardware PCCW
global subspace communications and Tory
point and virtela so thank you very much
for that it's it's really great the
sponsorship we're getting this time so
and everybody here is get is able to
take advantage of that so thank you
again okay so now the boring updates
take Phillip the nog lab survey if you
have been in the nog lab or you'd like
to there's a there's a giveaway after
the break so today fill out the nanog
surveys because we have giveaways
tomorrow and wednesday associated with
those so fill those out um take the
survey so we like to say there's one
agenda issue on that that we're making a
slight change in the Tuesday afternoon
and the 12 to one time period there's
two talks in there sort of related to
the rpki are related to rpki and we're
going to reverse the order of them
so Sharon will go r and you'll go first
I think and Cheryl the second so just in
case your timing anything around that so
with that I want to welcome you all to
952 and I want to hand it over to Steve
to say a little bit about what's going
on with the board good morning thanks
for joining us on behalf of the board I
wanted to extend our welcome to you as
well thanks for coming I want to say a
little bit about nanog as an
organization as of the this meeting
we're now a completely self-sufficient
standalone nonprofit organization we are
nanog one of the things that you can do
if you'd like to join us become part of
the government's vote in the elections
is to become a member and if you'd like
to do that please see there's a
membership table up there in the lobby
near the registration desk and they'd be
happy to explain what being members all
about and even help you sign up if you'd
like so that I've got that other way my
other duty up here is to extend a
welcome to our host James tin Dolph I'm
alcatel-lucent so thank you for coming
and everyone please give it alcatel this
in the round of applause for having us
here
and on behalf of on behalf of the board
I'd like to present you with this token
of our appreciation thank you very much
why haven't you got anything yet and
I've already gotten awards like it's
going to be a good day so welcome
everybody to nanog 52 this is our first
first sponsor as a company as
alcatel-lucent it's my first personal
time here in several years I had been to
several previous nanos in the past and
when I was packing my suitcase yesterday
I had to go through the debate okay
what's the dress code going to be the
last time I was here it was pretty much
shorts and sandals and so I said I know
is enough account upscale or not and
when I showed up to the reception last
night in a jacket and saw that I was the
only one I went okay I'm glad I brought
the jeans today anyway because I'd a
little quite out of place so it's good
the fees that see that some things never
change so we have been involved with
nanog for for quite a few years but this
is our first time to sponsor the event
and we've been to some of the beers of
gears but this is something that we're
quite committed to as an organization
from alcatel-lucent and something that
will be continuing to do as we go
forward these nano events are important
and for a lot of reasons and not least
of which is we're no longer just looking
at some of the technology problems we
have an awful lot of business problems
to address now to which can arguably be
a little more difficult to solve in the
technical problems right now so I think
this is important that we get together
as a community as well as the various
organizations that support the the
internet and figure out how we're going
to scale all this stuff and actually
come out with our shirts in dect so I
think it's a very good venue again
thanks to all the sponsors for for
supporting the event and congratulations
to the new organization and understand
this is the first time we're meeting
under the different organizational
structure so thanks everybody that made
that happen and of course many many
folks work very long and hard hours to
pull all this together not just from a
show perspective it from all the other
nickel in the gear that has to go up
thanks to centurylink for getting our
connectivity in here I understand we
have a special fiber poll just for this
kind of event thanks to the sheraton for
for all the logistics support their core
site with the the co-sponsor and merit
and special thanks to merit for all the
years of service that they put in to
make this kind of thing go so I don't
think we can give them enough enough
appreciation and gratitude for that
invents of interest while we already had
the social last night so it's a bit
redundant if anybody is expecting to go
back there tonight it probably won't be
quite as lively as it was last night but
we do have the Bering gear tonight from
six to eight o'clock encourage everybody
to go and participate and look at some
of the some of the particular pieces of
equipment and the networking things that
we've got going on there the nog lab
with all of the various demos that we've
got going and you use a bit of a picture
of what we've got going a lot of ipv6
this one would expect get some WDM
technology we've got some routing
technology to get some access technology
and I don't know that it's quite time to
to pronounce the death of ipv4 but i
think the footsteps are coming quickly
so ipv6 is certainly front and center
and a lot of the implementations that we
certainly look at now and I think it'll
be an interesting time over the next few
years
technical difficulties
also nobody sees lives and I think
okay there we go now we get a network
diagram so I've been talking to myself
basically up here for the last few
minutes anyway the rest of it was all
words you can read them not a big deal
the network stuff is the network stuff
is the fun stuff as you can see we've
got a fairly extensive v6 network set up
with a lot of the v6 peripherals in
order to to really demonstrate some of
the end end v6 performance network
itself we've got the the nog lab that's
hooked up and wired through some of the
various other parts of the the hotel to
provide connectivity going back through
the nanog router and then finally up
through CenturyLink so again thanks to
essentially for providing this
connectivity the obligatory network
diagram yep we got switches and routers
sitting around aggregating things up I
don't think there's a whole lot of
rocket science here but proof of merits
hard work got to have the obligatory
pictures of the the actual wiring
closets and all the all the real the
real work that goes on into putting
something like this on to get all this
connectivity up and get all the labs
connected in wiring closet memories and
certainly we all have seen a bunch of
punch down blocks in the past so again
thanks very much for attending the show
I'm really looking forward to to seeing
how how this is developed over the last
few years and welcome
thanks again for the great social and
for hosting okay um Maurice are you
around okay well Maurice is going to
come up and say a few words and about
one of our colleagues and then after
that well let's do this first hi there
I'm on the race team I am going to say a
few words about them but a dear friend
and so the way that we lost suddenly I
where Joe would passed away on friday
yeah sorry last week and when as we're
such a small and tight-knit community
quite a diverse community that Joe
really enjoyed being in part off I put a
few words will be appropriate you know I
really love the fact that everyone that
knew Joe went when describing water and
that finds us some difficulty because
frankly his he was a very unique guy and
there are there are phrases that come up
frequently mostly around has great smile
and his infectious sort of presence and
that laffy had that shows a like
thinking about it now this is hard to
speak but yeah but also they were
referred to talk about him just being a
deeply caring guy very passionate about
what he does and and a sweet gentle bear
yeah that and I all's I also say that he
was a great hugger yeah and of course
he's a kind of unique lovable audible a
left-field thinker and yeah and someone
who has a depth of knowledge in this
particular technical field that that was
astonishing to anyone who had the
pleasure of working with him depth of
his knowledge across an expertise across
optical mpls routing switching software
and favorite hobby of bug hunting
I was just breathtaking for her to
experience it's not a personal note I I
was Joe was one of the very few people
that was a was a really inspiring mental
his ability to understand large-scale
complex systems and then explain them in
a few swipes were painted at a
whiteboard what was the just on
unmatched and truly somebody that will
be missed but yep I just wanted to say a
few words and say Joe you know we love
you we miss you and and as a community
where we're shocked by it by your loss
and there's a there's a there's a gap
here now but okay
you