I'm Miriam kuna from the ripe NCC and
the measurements and monitoring
she was changing the well
the sixth day we mentioned a few times
yesterday I'm during the panel so I
thought it might be interesting to just
give you an impression or give you an
idea of what we actually measured and
give you some pointers on where you can
find more information and we did one
thing a few days or like a week before
the world v6 day mostly targeted to end
users where they could check if they
will have problems on the day and we
call that ipv6 I chart and I'll show you
an example we actually fetch some images
from servers enough for various
organizations that wanted to be listed
and and you could see if that works if
they view well let me just show you the
example in it's easier to explain that
would show up on the screen or
everything was okay and you had no
problems with them you know witching
content on unworldly six day for people
that switched on b6 and then there were
a few other options that one could see
in case there were any problems for
instance this one you know I would have
been problematic and then you know we
had some descriptions or a little hints
another under the image what you could
do to fix that before the day and then
there were some other kind of you know
mix brokenness like where the energies I
couldn't have done anything but you know
should probably contact the provider and
yeah that was there was it there was the
one thing it's still running people can
still go to that site and see if they
have any problems reaching other sites
on v6 and we will we'll keep that
running I think for a while another
thing we've done with them just before
World v6 day and then during these 24
hours and we measured or we checked if
like who said on their career records
and a few here you can see that looks
better than on my screen here basically
the the green in the middle that's kind
of the data it's on 8 of June and you go
to the to that side you see little time
slider underneath
can you can look back in time and you
can see here quite nicely of people
switched on v6 and icon um midnight UTC
and then most people switch it off again
and but you can also see that some
organizations kept running after 8th of
June so I'm dead still on the website vm
stopped collecting that data but you can
still see what happened during the day
and we could see it just as a snapshot
here we could see some we are
interesting things happening just before
for instance some people kind of switch
it on and off and on and often reluctant
kind of testing before they actually
switched it on @midnight and yeah we
could see some other interesting things
like the google site XM of augmented 2.0
whitelisted and others weren't and so we
didn't see anything there yes that's
pretty much that's what we've done is
just an explanation of that chart I just
showed you and how we how we measured
that and then also we're going to do
some more analysis of the data that we
collected and we will put that on web
labs and the all the measurements are on
that website there at the bottom that I
showed you before and just at the end
just one other thing also on that side
and that's it looks like this I just
thought it was a pretty picture I wanted
to show you and for those of you know
DNS mon dns monitoring system at the
ripe NCC is providing that works very
similar here just did it doesn't connect
to DNS servers but took HTTP servers and
so all our vantage points like all the
measurement boxes we have out there they
were looking after could reach those
tt-this HTTP servers and depending on on
that each sub T cells add a little color
color code and you can see on the on the
side how how the changes over time so
let's say actually all i wanted to show
you just to give you an impression of
what we've been measuring on the day
basically Corday's and and the HTTP and
then we also provided this eye chart
for users to check if they will be
archived on you if they don't see any
problems on the day and then that's it
any questions website again okay thank
you thank you all right
here
okay next up is Manish hi I'm manish
from the research group at Merrit what
I'll be talking about today is network
reputation and in particular what we're
doing to build towards a network
reputation in particular where we're
starting from and what our early results
are once again this is really early work
hence the lightning talk so feedback is
very very welcome let's start with the
introduction and motivation these are
the really hard problems how do you
create incentives for people to run
clean networks how do you measure the
relative security posture of a given
network how do you balance the need to
communicate with another network with
the risk because inherently there's a
risk more more interestingly how do you
estimate the likelihood of a future
attack or future malicious activity from
a network given historical data or
current data can you assign a risk
metric to a BGP path hard hard questions
but what would help what would help is
if you had some historical and current
notion of the behavior of a network from
a security perspective some some notion
of reputation so that's that's what
we're trying to get at that's the goal
what are the properties well we know one
of the things that you should not do is
rely on a single source of data because
then you're your reputation results will
be biased towards a single type of
activity so you have to have diverse
data sources bgp dns email anything else
malware analysis everything you should
be able to get a lot of this information
passively by just watching traffic
watching routing but you should not all
you should also have a way of including
public participation in a lot of cases
there's information out there which is
heavily dependent on vantage point you
want to have as many vantage points
contributing to your sources of
reputation as possible both global and
local data sources is is very important
shouldn't it should hopefully not be the
responsibility of a single entity to
generate this reputation it should be
crowd sourced taking as much input from
the community and be as distributed as
possible it should have mechanisms for
example for local parties to wait or
are to emphasize or D emphasize
particular reputation that you may be
providing them and you should be able to
merge global policy and then apply it on
a local perspective so here's the
architecture it's very simple what
you're seeing is basically for four key
elements of it one is the third party
data reports which are from external
systems to are the participation reports
from individual people or networks who
participate in this reputation
generation system the third is some sort
of a central collation agency which
collects all this information could be
single entity it could be a distributor
group event of people but the core
responsibility of this of this global
reputation system is essentially to
leverage some theory from mechanism
design and game theory to do the right
setup to set the right incentives for
people to participate to set the right
weights of how do you value information
from different people differently and
then of course the central authority
should also have some way of
disseminating this reputation once it's
been generated let me quickly go over
what the key components are the external
participation reports are essentially
third party data sources in our context
these basically mean things like spam
reports the our BLS malware IPS that
have been identified from malware
they're generally published by a third
party and you have lots of hosts and
essentially what these reports are
indicators of host reputation and what
we do from these is try to seed the
network reputation from the reputation
of these hosts the second component is
the participation reports this is really
hard you have to have the right
incentives for people to contribute
honest reports and disincentives for
people to lie and this is where we're
hoping we're going to leverage some
background from mechanism design and
game theory to set the right incentives
in the system so that it is not easy to
gain here's an example of finally what
it'll look like the prefixes will all
every single prefix in the bgp table
will have a reputation score from 1 to
100 and basically what you will be able
to do with it is
set security policy so what are some
examples of security policies if you had
this reputation what could you do with
it well for example for bgp you could
compute paths for each s path you could
compute a relative reputation score for
it reliability or risk metric if you
want to call it that and then you could
set bgp policy saying i don't want my
packets to go through a bad neighborhood
or I want them to prefer this other path
based on my analysis of how well these
networks are run in in das path spam
scoring this is already done to a large
extent maybe you could tweak it a little
by using network level information as
well inbound firewalls could be much
more than just a single accept or drop
rule you could have gray scale so you
could say maybe send this so maybe drop
everything that's in the top worst 5% in
the next ten percent maybe I will send
them to a dpi box and in pain will close
attention to that traffic where's
everything that's in the best ten
percent I'm going to just pass it
through to my to my regular servers
applications could make use a reputation
as well for example your you're a bank
you could say well I'm going to block
the worst five percent the next twenty
percent I'm going to send to a site
which requires two factor authentication
and the the rest don't need it because I
trust those networks so there's so if
you have this information it enables a
whole range of activities which are much
harder to do right now so so let's talk
about how weird bootstrapping the system
right now we're starting with lots of
third-party data so BRB l xbl spam cop
they're all the spam data types then the
command and control data coming from
comer e and shadow servers we're
building our own data set for document
scanners activities coming from
different networks brute force SSH temps
we're collecting that data as well and
of course drone be else they all all
these lists have different magnitudes in
terms of how many IPS are on those and
what we do is we take those and try to
bucket them into prefixes and try to
derive reputation scores based on those
not sure if the lines are very visible
on this graph but essentially what we're
trying to
is that all these are BLS when you
assign when you take all these
individual IP addresses you just put
them in your bucket than my prefixes you
can get some notion of how many IPS in
each prefix are on our BLS and then you
can sort of derive a relative dirty or
clean this off for network this is a
very very preliminary notion of what a
reputation of the network is but it's a
start so let's take a look at some of
the the mail at some of the RB l's and
geographically distributed country-wise
bucketing what do we see if we try to
just bucket by countries for example
here's the xbl I'm just going to show
the top 10s here you'll notice top 10
India Brazil Russia spam cop pretty much
the same set of factors prbl st. what's
different with the this is the comer e
servers different map what we're seeing
all of a sudden is United States Germany
Canada of Japan shadows over United
States Germany France what's the
difference what what our conjecture here
really is is that the types of lists are
different the country and the shadow
servers are essentially reporting
command and control infrastructure and
it what it looks like from at least the
content for examining the contents of
these lists is that the command and
control infrastructures are being based
in the developed nations and IPS that
our countries essentially the BRIC
countries which are the Brazil India
China Russia are serving as the spam or
the sender hosts the ones that are the
compromised machines the ones that are
sending out there being used to send a
lot of email The Dark Knight scanners
list is sort of a mixed bag it seems to
have IP addresses that are spread out
fairly evenly there's some overlaps and
the data types as well because we have
to know what but what the overlaps
between the different rbl czar comer en
shadow server seem to have significant
overlaps the xbl and the end the spam
cops seem to have significant overlaps
so we have to sort of take this into
account when we wait reputation for
networks here's an example of the BRIC
countries for example in in half and
they show up in
in these different lists and now what I
wanted to quickly get to was an example
where we're building a reputation score
if we take just three data sources and
we wait them all evenly this is the
percentage of and we build them
basically on the percentage of the total
IP addresses in a prefix that are on
these lists you can come up with some
scoring or reputation index and here I'm
just presenting three data sources the
top ten lists and roughly resolving them
to where their locations are so it's
hard to say whether this is definitive
proof of reputation or not but it's sort
of trying to build that and once you
have prefix level of reputation which
you can then do is you can build a
notion of a s level reputation by
aggregating across all prefixes and and
here's the swing shot from our prototype
system well off the top 25 worst
reputation asses so conclusion the goal
of the network repetitions really is to
create some some sort of a predictive
indicator of how well a network is run
and then allow for security policies
that take that into account the relative
likelihood of a future malicious
activity from a network if you have this
information you can use it for for
making sound policy decisions that
affect the future not just reactive
policy decisions this is still work in
progress so comments are welcome Michael
Sinatra yes net I said some of this
yesterday I'll just say it again first
thank you for presenting this this is a
useful window into the data you've
collected the research you've done in
the methods you're using I think that
especially to the extent that you use
reputation to derive policies you will
get into endless discussions about the
quality of data the models that you're
using and the inferences that you're
making so you have to be very very
careful of course to the extent that you
make that more and more transparent
you're going to get into more and more
discussions to the to the extent you
make it more and more opaque people will
trust it less so it's just a difficult
tightrope to walk and also just be a
little bit careful about how you use
game theory since it's not really
it's a modeling method okay and most
game theorists will not call themselves
game theorists they call themselves
formal modelers as someone who used to
do that work and so the important thing
is that the theory behind it is good
okay thank you so it's a good point that
and I do want to clarify on the game
theory part we were warned against going
game theory because this is not a game
inherently what we want to do is a
derivative of game theory which is
mechanism design and what we're hoping
is that that will give us a theoretical
background for incentive setting and how
the incentive should be weighted in the
system to get honest feedback in but the
important thing is the theory part and
not the method you're using to derive it
you need to have a good theory starting
out chrispy softlayer technologies um I
was curious are you getting your
prefixes from like the BGP global tables
or you breaking them down to the 24 so
if your rating on what you're learning
out of the tables is it possible that
with just a few hits you would end up
you know degrading an entire 15 or 14
and causing adverse traffic flows to
those networks you know being in the
hosting industry we have a lot of
customers that will come just pop up and
do bad things and they would get rid of
them and then they reform themselves and
next time they come to us we don't even
recognize that it's the same customer
and again we get hit we take them out
but in your kind of method it looks like
a lot of our prefixes which is always be
in kind of a negative rating right so
the the way we wait the prefect prefixes
of the reputation of a network is really
how as a whole the total possible hosts
in it how many of them were seen doing
malicious activity of one form or
another this can also be weighted in
different ways if you're doing SSH force
break-ins well maybe you want to wait
that data more rather than spams because
we know that's not very reliable so yes
there are different ways of waiting it
our initial system does do purely a
density of how full your network was in
terms of badness people have chris's nos
last question and you can he'll be
available the speaker be available
afterwards you can talk to them
sorry Chris I missed the beginning did
you say how I can get access to this
data or house with good access data and
the format in which the data comes we
have not publicly released the website
but I can share that with you and we can
talk about it offline but but but
eventually once we have a reasonable
system built we do met intend to just
distributed over XML or or you know
download it okay yeah so it seems like
this again we have the scheduler
yesterday but the sort of making the
data available in a fashion that
enterprise folks could make use of it I
don't necessarily think that the is it a
/ 15 that got you know thrown away is a
problem for the enterprise people as
much as it is for for isp people okay
all right so thank you and next up and I
say you can grab them off the deciding
always next up is Anton
alright good afternoon so what I've been
working on lately was prompted by a
friend BTW and subsequent to meeting
paul barford some time ago we've taken a
taken upon ourselves to look at more
measurements more available data that we
can chew through and think about and so
today we're talking about some work that
we're doing an ongoing work that's
that's already begun to look at roughly
what's what's really happening in
mobility in terms of usable and
available performance and specifically
how does that compare to cellular
performance and we decided to start with
one of the best or not best but I
shouldn't qualify it like that i should
say one of the most prolific data
sources we can find which is
speedtest.net who's from the with speed
test roughly copy all of you so you know
you mean you saw roughly know how it
works its or tries to help you
understand what's going on on your
connection and the thought we were
starting with in this work was what is
the real difference between someone who
is rooted on a Wi-Fi type connection or
someone who's using purely mobile
cellular connections so we started to
process this data in a short what this
stuff really amounts to is a combination
of some javascript and flash
applications that seek to do basic
upstream downstream assessments as well
as some amount of time people who
operate servers people who providers
rather who operate the speedtest.net
servers which are publicly listed in a
database are provided the table you see
at the bottom it may not be easy to see
but the general idea is that a server
operator understands who's hitting it
through the eyes of this data source and
through some sort of an EDI or web
interface you are given the results of
tests that were executed against your
server it can also request them request
of speedtest.net your own interested
data you can ask for particular metros
or cities and after some
agreements were signed you can have far
more data than your server itself
provides you see here that we just get
general things like platform the IP the
client came in from the who is quote
unquote ISP information date time stamps
up downstream bit rates wait and see and
most importantly for our work here the
location in in space will have to
damange itude from the mobile device
having been reported by the application
and most importantly connection type
cellular or Wi-Fi the two shown here of
course are not on Wi-Fi so that's that's
kind of a top level but really we
started a scratch below the surface a
bit and found out that speedtest.net in
fact is powered by cats like much of the
internet in the application you will see
this and we think it perhaps is the
whimsy that carries the app on the air
general methodology is that measurements
are done against the server from the
client through the process you see here
first a couple round-trip texts attempts
are made over a socket that essentially
passes basic headers and nothing more
that's repeated is a number of times and
then gets I used to estimate and then
finally execute the bulk of the
downstream tests and the same thing is
repeated for post methods in the
upstream direction the top 10% of all
the one second measurements made at the
clients socket reader right processes
are discarded as well as the lower
thirty percent this is to denoise you
know if you will bursty behavior
schedule schedule schedule where we led
the behavior that could mislead the
client with regards to exactly how much
data was in fact received or sent over
the network layer and then that final
result is average and reported to the
server so an example server running in
Madison Wisconsin which is a small
region rate tends to attract clients
from areas you know as far east as
perhaps milwaukee in chicago and as far
west as Dubuque Iowa and parts into
northern northeastern Iowa and Eastern
Minnesota and the resulting traffic you
see here is not huge but for such a
small market surprisingly peaky
diurnal of course weighted towards the
afternoon and at no time do we see any
single tasks doing more than a few
hundred megabits so surprising result we
thought we'd see people with very high
speed connections pegging it for regular
periods but that doesn't seem to happen
why is it so interesting I think it's
the Gibson affect the gooeys that the
company provides are compelling not to
discredit any other research
crowd-sourced tools but these are really
sexy and it seems to be that more of
them Iran than any other testing
structure I'm aware of literally
billions per year so a lot of data and
we want to make use of it so we're
attempting to start on that through a
paper that's going to hopefully appear
at conex so I don't need to jinx it so
look for that perhaps so it's star
looking at some actual numbers looking
at the prior five weeks between februari
pointy second and the 31st of March we
sampled data from our server of course
people on desktop computers regular
browsers laptops and so forth outnumber
Mobile's almost four to one and
accordingly people are typically almost
two to one using Wi-Fi versus cellular
we thought the ratios would be different
so this is kind of orienting us into a
new area we didn't know that these
numbers would be so so largely weighted
towards more traditional connections we
had assumed mobility and cellular
mobility specifically was was the new
thing so let's filter it a little bit of
all the servers are other valla traffic
that hit the Madison server only half of
it was within one County with in Dane
County the rest of it was everywhere
else considered a very Geographic long
tail if you will interestingly
considering how many rows had anyone
sell upstream downstream where latency
tests failed we find that barely 19 is
provided which i guess is surprising to
me in that I thought mobile data was
even worse of the seven thousand or so
tests that we received total about two
thousand were from cellular so the other
ones that had been failing we're from a
mixture of Wi-Fi and cell there seems to
be no real bias
so currently Wi-Fi is faster the data
we're looking at here again from
februari to end of March doesn't
conclude much LTE deployment or our 4G
deployment because the region we're in
is not one of the ones on the top 15 or
so sites that verizon or sprint or
anybody else has enabled yet we expect
to see this trend shift as that happens
so comparing Wi-Fi and cellular of
course the intuition hold and it's true
that Wi-Fi outpaces sailor we thought
the upstream would be more profoundly
different but in fact it's barely three
times so simple stats round-trip time
tells a different story Wi-Fi is doing
fairly well but worse than we expected
cellular is not as good as we had
assumed our user experiences on a video
and on you peep it HSPA overlays on UMTS
can't you say this today suggests that
real Robin sometimes a much lower than
application is measuring but for some
reason when all the data is considered
with no special filtering other than
failure tests being removed sailors is
clearly lagging breaking it down into
groups of eight hours we see a general
trend towards lower overall bandwidth
and we see a trend towards higher
overall latency which is perhaps assumed
this is roughly the view of the entire
county with the data looking in just the
city you see some interesting clusters
several these clusters where you see
several dots orange for sale green for
Wi-Fi tend to correspond to the same
user and GPS jittering gives us a false
sense of population interesting stuff
more I think personally more interesting
things tender emergency start to look at
ticular cellular carriers as a subset of
all of the cellular tests executed
looking at a simply a histogram where
the bottom most horizontal axis is
megabits per second and the vertical
axis represents how many tests were
logged at a particular or a given bit
rate we see that 18t in particular has
bimodal distributions strongly bimodal
distribution sup stream and the
downstream is a normal distribution
upstream is generally the more
challenged radio link and a mobile
network so we find that the biggest
divergence and various Network
performances are seen there again the
horizontal axis is in megabits and
vertical is in test count 18 teased by
mobile sprint is generally a linear
regression towards unlikely ER and
progressively unlike leader services and
in the case of verizon almost everyone
gets half or a third of the upstream
available any one time it looks like to
us if we didn't know better t-mobile is
simply unloaded in this market after
some further analysis it looks like GPS
should have a new definition the
application itself is not terribly
reliable in that it does not sample
multiple times it does not denoise does
not average it grabs the first available
bit of information from the hosts api
and is reported but you know what power
is ingrained so that's good and
interesting on android devices we find
that between application execution
periods it might report the same
coordinates enormous times leading us to
believe that several AP is perhaps could
deserve some additional attention
specifically in terms of data quality
with mobility position quick test
confirms it of course over a few weeks
running my iphone at the apartment
roughly where the yellow pin is located
we see a huge distribution beyond just
the normal error reported by the GPS
itself so this leads us to believe that
the data collection potential whether
the analysis potential is a lot lower
than we once thought given the relative
noise of any kind of positional
coordinates and further work is going to
be looking at larger aggregates such as
US Census Bureau zones or zip codes more
likely Census Bureau given that's a
roughly even population distribution per
area so that is that I hope you have the
carrier you wanted to have and we don't
have time for questions and I want to
thank guntown very much and
you