good morning everyone I'm Joe who from
Huawei here I will talk about what you
some that a kind of IP on layer 2 VPN
service it's can be used for DCI data
centre interconnect here I list some
major requirement for DCI the first aid
will and scalability for them how to
scale the whipping instance beyond 4 key
limits the second is Mac table
scalability most layer 3 VPN solutions
are using the Mackin and mapping map and
in caps game so the core or the corridor
of the pillars for running table in
outside through the number of the peak
opioids so there are no problem for the
cold waters but if we just extend the
layer 2 domain across multiple data
centers the C switches expecially the
community C switches will need to learn
more MAC addresses not only the local
matches but also remote MAC addresses so
it will become big challenges the sturdy
is broadcast sternum reduction for them
home how to reduce the air peeper cost
impact on the network performance and
the host performance and how to WoW the
owner unicast flooding the story the
motor homing and a lot balancing so I
had to increase the high ability Gemma
city and
to optimize the bandwidth utilization
expense later
perpend backbone bandwidth utilization
what you submit a very simple idea by
using the proven less routine and the
ERP proxy technology it can provide them
all their IP only allowed to APN service
compared to the existing layer 2 VPN
solution the virtual subnet had the
following benefits the first is
suppressing the Ono unicast and ARP
broadcast flooding since we as can
restrict the reach of the flooding
domain within a single site the second
is reducing the Mac table dress of C
switches the third is achieving
multi-homing
and a lot of penance by using the way RP
this example into a subnet unicast on HP
rotor it's local C holds the RP entries
will be learned automatically and hosts
votes for their local C hosts will be
automatically generated according to the
their ERP entries and then these host
routes will be distributed across the
backbone with the existing layer
sweeping similarly if hosts they want to
share a packet host B it's real first
then RP requests for P p1 and ARP proxy
Wednesday in this packet will return its
one MAC address to host a the host a
will send packets for host being with
making a retesting MAC address of oh
please Mac dress
peih-gee receiving this package will
turn out it towards the next hope PE
router P 2 then P 2 will forward it
packets towards the destination host we
can see here the forwarding behavior on
the periodic in no exchange compared to
the current letters will be p.m. forward
in presence the difference is we use
host route based forwarding this example
into subnet unicast here a gateway is
connected to P 2 now host they want to
sense a host P which is located in a
different subnet they will sell packet 2
P 1 but just a MAC address with PE p is
mac to us that way was how here sorry P
P 2 is connect to the C gateway router
so it will be configured with the four
routes then this before Road will be
distributed to other peer orders now
jose san a packet for host b p1 upon
receiving the packets will tunnel spec a
to p2 according to the default yacht p2
then set its package according to the
configure stem stake route to the
getaway
here if to see rudders for example are
connected to two period Earth's
respectively for getaway redundancy
purpose only the peer outer which
connect to the where P master will
belong to advertise at the for route we
can't cheat let's go weary with a very
simple way for them poor let's hope that
for route is sent to set at the virtual
router IP and that the Warroad will not
be deemed as wearable until there the
host load for the next hope dress that's
the next hope of elevated check check
trick loco si host are automatically it
is covered by peer orders so ERP
learning Mac name to keep those who
learn learned up your entries from
coming out
peer others should send a unicast ARP
request to those no see host
to ensure the periodical learn all it
slow cozy hosts in a short time
especially after we boating off due to
some reason the be router should perform
at least once hope a host scanning for
them hold the pier otters cost an ERP
ICMP echo request to IP block address
every sea host receiving that request
will respond with it ARP reply
continuing its IP to Mac mapping in this
way
the IP to mapping Mac mappings can be
learned by peer others by doing ARP
proxy on P routers are people custom
contained within a single site for
example if our IP u quest for a local
sea house received the periodic just
discarded for I the IPU quest for a
remote C host the peer others should
return its own MAC address for our ARP
request for uh no see see host that is
there no matching Oswalt fell for that
destination host the P surely discard
this packet in see more humming scenario
we are P enabled amount P rollers which
are connect to Murray home site and only
the ARP master allowed to act as happy
proxy in this way a key atamora homing
for the incoming traffic can be achieved
since all Pierre ours attend to a given
Modi home site can orbit eyes the host
vote folder for their local C host
when I see house for example we M moves
from one whipping side to another
the pirata attend to the new whippy
incite what heís a host vote for that CE
host when was receiving great ears ARP
message from their C host and this
pirata attend to the previous whip in
sight upon receiving the ball host wrote
announcement will send a request for
that CE host to check whether that the
house is still connected to it if not
the pirata will discuss the
corresponding ARP entry and withdrawn
the hosts blood for that CE host which
had been retired before otherwise
it's what just seemed odd home in case
for customer multicast and broadcast
Rafiq my pin technology including the
equation mag name can be used without
any change here's a customer bok ba-cock
traffic will be processed at a special
customer market traffic this is a brief
cooperation between we pious and
virtuous Annette has DSi solution VPS
cannot reduce on a unicast flooding
across multiple data centers but which
subnet can achieve that goal with yes do
nothing about Erica's production the we
s can reduce the RP flooding by using
the proxy technology since the flooded
the layer 2 domain is just extended
across multiple sites in the VPS
solution
the sea switches need to learn not only
the mattress or local sea host but out
the mattress for remote see host in the
West solution since which only need to
learn local MAC addresses we peers
cannot support active at Murray homey
but we as can in case of see they over
the triggered Mack will join in the we
peer solution will cause owner unicast
flooding in short period well in the
what your subnet solution Chevy float
will not happen
thank you comments questions