>> Yeah, alright. Thanks
everbody for coming, it is super
exciting to be here. It's been a
few years since I had a talk
here at DEF CON and it's great
to be back. I'm Michael Ossmann
of Great Scott Gadgets and I
make hardware for hackers. I
spend my time completely devoted
to building open source hardware
primarily for the information
security community and for other
innovative people. So this is
the NSA play set RF
retroreflectors. Hopefully some
of you have noticed this is not
the only NSA play set talk on
the schedule. Some of my cohorts
are in the front row here, they
have talks coming up soon. The
concept of the NSA play set is
now that the catalog has leaked
and it leaked last winter, we in
the open security community
suddenly have a glimpse of what
the NSA uses or at least in some
cases, their hardware and
software as attack tools and the
implants, hopefully some of you
have seen, the concept of the
NSA play set is now that we know
those things, let's build them
ourselves. Let's create similar
capabilities using open source
hardware and open source
software, anything off the
shelf, anything that is readily
available, very accessible, try
to make this stuff easy to use
and try to raise awareness about
the security implications that
‑‑ of these technologies
existing at all. I gave a talk
with Dean Pierce, who's in the
front row here at tour camp, the
URL is up there, you might be
able to read it, the color is a
little off, but most of my
slides are black and white
anyway, so who cares. If you're
interested in a little bit of a
background in the NSA play set
and a broad overview of what is
in the ANT catalog and how we
think these things can be made
in the open community, that's
the best place to start, that's
the introduction talk to the
series. And this weekend here at
DEF CON, a number of us are
doing talks on specific parts of
the NSA play set. Today I'm
talking about RF
retroreflectors. And last night,
by the way, how many of you were
at the EFF Summit? The Summit
last night? Yeah? Really? That's
it? At the Summit, I know a lot
of you were there and a bunch of
us from the NSA play set donated
a whole bunch of hardware. We
made this cool play set bucket,
it has hack RF's [indiscernible]
in it,it has IME's, PCI express
attack tools, thunderbolt attack
tools, it has a hard drive full
of rainbow tables for GSM on and
on and on, a huge kit. And it
went for $2,250 in the auction
last night. So thanks to
everyone who contributed.  	>>
[Applause].  	>> And who bid on
it. Is the winner of the auction
here? No? Well, I'd like to
shake your hand at some point.
That was pretty amazing that we
were able to pull together and
do that. So my talk today is on
RF retroreflectors, similar to
those that are in the ANT
catalog, and an RF
retroreflector, and I never
heard the term RF retroreflector
before the amp catalog leaked,
so I have kind of adopted it,
but it's a little implant that
modulates an incoming radio
signal and reflects it back to
the radar device illuminating
it. So the attacker is on the
left, it fires a radio wave at
the target. The target has a
little implant that reflects the
radio wave back to the radar
unit being used by the attacker.
The process of irradiating a
target is often called
illumination, think of it as
shining a light on the target,
except the light happens to be
radio wavelengths instead of
visible wavelengths. Otherwise
it's the same thing. You are
shining a radar beam at a
target, illuminating it and
seeing what gets reflected back.
And then the implant is some
very small device that is
designed to modulate the
reflection. And this can be done
at extremely low power, which is
one of the reasons that this
approach is useful. It can be
done with no battery, for
example. It can be completely
powered just by the radio wave
itself. So it's a super simple
kind of implant design that is
very low power and uses a very
small number of components. So
it can be tiny and it can be
without any local battery
source. So that's the kind of
thing I'm talking about today. I
kind of wanted to set the record
straight a little bit. One of my
earlier talks got some press and
some people were writing that I
was reverse engineering tools in
the NSA AMP catalog and I don't
think that's actually correct. I
don't have any devices from the
NSA. I don't have any inside
knowledge of devices used by the
NSA. All I have is the
information that's this the
public leaked amp catalog that
anyone can find leaked on the
Internet. So I'm not really, I
don't really feel that I'm
reverse engineering the NSA's
tools. I'm forward engineering
tools that have similar
capabilities to those that the
NSA uses. And hopefully this
will help us in the open
community create a set of tools
that we can use to research this
kind of capability and find out
how it works and how well it
works and what the implications
are and whether or not these
things can be made much ‑‑ in
the future, much more
sophisticated than we know of
now. So in this talk I will
cover leaked classified
information from the amp
catalog. I don't think I've put
any screenshots in here from the
amp catalog, but I'm going to
talk about things that I
observed from the amp catalog.
So if you don't want to hear
about leaked, classified
information, you can leave now.
Anyone for a game of spot the
Fed? I am going to show you in
this talk a few hardware designs
for my own retroreflectors and
I'm going to tell you how to
build your own retroreflector
right here at DEF CON, if you
want. I'm also going to do a
live demonstration. And really
kind of the reason I'm doing all
of this is to lure you here so
that you can listen to me rant
about the state of emissions
security. Emission security is
the field of security where we
study emissions from devices and
a fair bit is known in the
public research community, the
hacker community, about passive
attacks. But not very much has
been known historically about
active attacks. And today I'm
talking specifically about
active attacks, where an
attacker actually transmits
something towards the target.
The passive attacks that we know
about, you may have heard the
code name tempest. And sometimes
people apply the word tempest to
all emission security, but
really it's a code name that
relates specifically to
unintentional emissions. Now
there are all kinds of different
unintentional emissions, there
are RF emissions, there are
conducted electrical emissions,
thermal emissions, audio, all
kinds of things. There are all
these different little side
channels where somebody might be
able to pick up some kind of
unintentional emission and from
that information figure out
something about the state of the
target and in some cases figure
out extreme information about
the state of the target, like
reproducing what's on a video
screen or capturing key strokes
and so forth. So there's a fair
amount of research in the area
of passive emissions security
attacks. And if you want to get
started reading about these
things, probably the best place
to start would be the writings
of Marcus Coone. I do think
there is quite a bit of
opportunity in the field of
passive emissions security for
future research. There are lots
of things that unexplored at
this time. However, we at least
have a little bit of information
and a little bit of public
research and you can find
papers. That's not true so much
for active attacks: Active
attacks, the main thing that
we've known about for years is
that everybody always talks
about being the prime example of
active emissions security is the
thing, the great seal bug. This
was a bug that was discovered
inside a wooden carving of the
great seal of the United States
in the U.S. embassy in Moscow
and information about this bug
was released publicly in 1960.
It was supposedly discovered in
the early 50s and may have been
implanted as early as 1945. So
this is ‑‑ this is technology
from the mid to early 40s. And
it's an incredibly simple
device. It consists of a
microphone and an antenna, and
that's it. It doesn't have any
active components whatsoever. It
simply is a condenser mic, which
is a capacitor that changes its
capacitance based on the air
pressure. And that is connected
to an antenna in such a way that
the air pressure, the changes in
the air pressure modulates the
impedance connected and that
modulates a reflection that
comes back to a radar unit that
is illuminating this device. In
some ways it's very difficult to
detect because it's not active
most of the time. If you looked
around to try to see, like
before a big meeting, if you
went around looking for any bugs
that were transmitting, you
would pick up nothing from this
thing, but once the meeting
starts, then your attacker
starts illuminating the device
with the radar, then suddenly it
is active. And it uses no power,
no local power supply
whatsoever. And it's a pretty
incredible invention for the
time. The next thing I think
everybody has heard about now
since we have had these RF
retroreflectors in the amp
catalog, what happened between
the thing and the amp catalog,
we have 53 years of rumor and
speculation. And I wish I was
exaggerating. But really if you
look for hard evidence, if you
look for example designs, if you
look for somebody who did an
actual experiment to show how an
active emissions security attack
works, you'll find almost
nothing between 1960 and 2013.
It is such an unbelievable gap.
We are decades behind the
intelligence agencies in our
basic understanding in threats
against our own systems. Now
some people will argue with me,
some people will say otherwise,
they will say, oh, I know all
about these active attacks and
they will rattle off code words
and mention declassified
documents and, you know, I say
to them, BOCGGOFO. Because,
yeah, we've had a lot of hints,
we've had a lot of hints from
declassified documents over the
years. We have had a lot of
speculation, but show me the one
place where someone has done a
research paper, show me the one
place somebody has given a
conference talk, released a
hardware design, done an
experiment, published the
results. And I personally have
not found any. I would love if
somebody ran up here and proved
me wrong. That would be amazing.
I've been looking, but I have
not found it. Now one thing I
found, a brief mention in the
paper Soft Tempest by Marcus
Coone and Ross Anderson, they do
mention an attack where a
keyboard cable, a computer
keyboard cable was irradiated
and key presses were detected by
the return from that cable. Now
this I would put in the category
of rumor and speculation because
it is one brief mention in paper
about other things. And it comes
from a declassified German
document. As far as I know, no
one has actually tested this in
a public experiment. And one of
the interesting things here is
that this is apparently
irradiating or illuminating an
unmodified keyboard and cable.
Unmodified, no implant was
intentionally installed in the
target. The equipment, out of
the box, was vulnerable to this
attack, which is quite
interesting to me. And there
were some hints in the amp
catalog that suggests similar
attacks are possible on other
things. For example, there's a
VGA video implant that is
retroreflector for picking up
the video signal. And on the
page describing that implant, it
says that it provides an
enhanced return, which suggests
to me that they get some kind of
return sometimes from VGA cables
without enhancing it. That's
very interesting, I think. Post
ant catalog, just this year,
there have been some public, on
YouTube, some experiments that
this one person, GGPPR has
posted, so I recommend you check
those out. As far as I know, he
and I are the only playing with
this stuff and talking about it
publicly. So today I'm releasing
open source hardware design for
actual implants and I'm teaching
you how you can build them
yourself and how simple they
are. And I'm going to do a live
demonstration on stage, which
hopefully will work. And I
mentioned just a second ago that
there may be capabilities, maybe
possibilities of making this
kind of retroreflector attack
work without actually implanting
a target. And so I would
consider that a case where we
have an unintentional
retroreflector, which is my
bottom row there. There's also a
case where we have an
intentional retroreflector,
where we have some kind of
implant we install in the
target. And then there are other
cases in these columns. What I'm
doing today is I'm intentionally
illuminating, firing a radio
wave at the target. But there
are also other cases where a
target could be unintentionally
illuminated. For example,
everybody is walking around
carrying mobile phones that put
out far more radio energy than
my test system up here. So if
people ‑‑ so if you're walking
near a device that is vulnerable
to this or is implanted so that
it's vulnerable to
retroreflection, then you may be
unintentionally illuminating it
and causing it to create a
reflection that an attacker can
pick up. And these types of
attacks, you know, we've seen
hints of, we've heard rumors
about, but I don't know of any
research into any of these
categories really, I don't know
of any publicly demonstrated
experiment‑like ‑‑ expect for
what I'm doing today, just in
that one category. So this is a
wide open research area. There's
a lot of opportunity. And what
I'm doing today is scratching
the surface of that one square
in the grid. A quick note about
the term retroreflector. In the
ant catalog it's spelled with a
hyphen, but I don't know why
because you look around at other
literature, you'll find that
it's actually a fairly common
technical term without the
hyphen. So I have adopted it
without the hyphen, because that
seems to be the common usage
every why other than the NSA.
But I am adopting the term
retroreflector, which is a
little bit of a stretch maybe.
The word retroreflector means
reflecting something back to
it's source ‑‑ for example, when
you are driving down the highway
at night and you're headlights
hit the roadsign the roadsigns
have a retroreflecting coating
on them so most of your light
from your headlight comes back
to you and the road signs look
very bright. But somebody
standing off to the side of the
road who is not back near the
source of light, doesn't see the
road sign illuminating so
brightly because of that
retroreflective surface that
somehow reflects that light back
towards the source that it came
from. And this technology, if
you want to see a really cool
application of that, optical
retroreflection, the cast AR
project is doing wonderful
augmented reality sort of system
that takes advantage of that
type of optical retroreflection.
So a radio retroreflector, in my
opinion, would reflect most of
the energy back towards the
source. And that doesn't
actually appear to be what the
devices in the ant catalog are
doing. They appear to be using
very small, not very directional
antenna. And so they're
reflecting, yes, but they are
kind of scattering energy in a
lot of directions and not
particularly back towards to the
source. Now with bigger, more
sophisticate antennasin the
implant they could be more
retroflective. So, just be aware
that that term is used a little
bit loosely here but I've
adopted the term RF
retroreflector just because
that's what they are called in
the ant catolog. If you want to
find out more about how this
method works, then back scatter
is probably more the search term
you would want to use instead of
retroreflector. There's a lot of
public research on RF back
scatter communication. Can
anybody tell me the year of the
first paper on RF back scatter
communication? Anybody know did?
Nobody? I'll give you a free
retroreflector.  	>> [Off mic].
>> I didn't hear it. Sorry,
guys.  	>> [Off mic].  	>> 1948.
1948 there was a paper called
Communication by Means of
Reflective Power. And realize
this was after the thing was
deployed. So the very first
public research paper on this
means of RF retroreflection or
RF back scatter communication
didn't happen until well after
the thing was deployed. So that
thing was a pretty cool
invention for its time. Now
there was research into optical
back scatter prior to this but
this is the first paper I can
find on RF back scatter. There's
a lot more research over the
years since 1948. And in
particular, over the last couple
of decades, if you look for any
UHF RFID technology, UHF is a
range of frequencies that is
used by the RFID tags that get
longer distance, longer range.
The really close range, the
stuff that you have to have very
close proximity for is down in
the low‑frequency, LF or HF. UHF
RFID tags are a little more
similar to the type of things
I'm using and the NSA seems to
be using. In fact, most of the
NSA implant seem to be working
in the UHF band. So if you look
at designs for the UHFRIDF tags,
they are very similar to the
type of design you would want to
use for building a
retroreflector. Now I have to
have a retroreflector, but I
also have to have radar system.
I have to have a means of firing
a radar beam or illuminating a
target and picking up the return
from that target. There's plenty
of off the she have radar gear,
a lot of it is pretty expensive
but you can find things like a
police radar. I got an old
police radar off eBay for, I
don't remember, 50 bucks or
something like that, not that
much. However, police radars are
typically up above 20 gigahertz,
which in the order of magnitude,
higher frequency than the NSA
seems to be using based on the
ant catalog so maybe that's not
the best approach. One of my
favorite devices is the Hot
Wheels radar gun. You can find
these on eBay for 25 bucks and
they operate at 10 gigahertz,
which is at least closer to the
frequency range that I'm
interested in. And they're just
fun to play with. The device is
made up of kind of three
separate parts. There's some ‑‑
there's a battery compartment,
the wave guide antenna, the big
tube, and on the right hand side
of that the circuit board. And
then a separate circuit board on
the back with the
microcontroller and the LCD. The
microcontroller board is the
part that typically fails. So if
you get a broken one, it doesn't
matter because all you really
need is that radio board that
has that little black cable
coming out of the back of it on
the right. And that little black
cable has 3 wires in it and all
you have to do is apply power to
it and you get a base band
signal on the third wire. You
can plug it into an oscilloscope
or you can plug that into a hack
RF or into a sound card even and
measure the return that it's
getting. So it's a pretty cool
device for experimentation. And,
you know, it's really easy to
add that base band output. I
recommend checking out that
website if you want to find one
of those and learn how to take
it apart, which is a little
annoying. There's also, I've
noticed, quite a few devices
that you can find that are very
similar to the Hot Wheels radar
gun, but in a smaller package,
they don't have the whole big
wave guide antenna, they don't
have the plastic and trigger and
everything. They are designed as
modules for people to use in
their own little electronics
project. If you search eBay for
Arduino radar, you will find a
few of these things shipping
from Hong Kong and they are only
a few dollars so that is an
interesting option. They are at
the ten and half gigahertz band,
which higher than the devices in
the ant catalog. The coffee can
radar is pretty cool, from Greg
Sharvot, and various other
friends that have posted
information about that design,
or that family of designs. There
was a talk here at DEF CON a few
years ago on the subject. It's
cool expect it's typically used
with capture ‑‑ base band
capture using sound card, which
is a low bandwidth and isn't
sufficient for some of the
targets, the higher bandwidth
targets that I'm dealing with.
So it has potential. Also it has
some circuitry to do FMCW radar,
which is more complicated than
the simple CW radar that is all
you need for this type of
application. So what I'm doing
primarily is using hack RFI One
which is my own design SDR
platform. By the way, if any of
you backed hack RF on quick
starter, I'm happy to announce
they have all shipped.  	>>
[Applause].  	>> Yeah, whoa!
Although some of the shipment
notifications have been delayed,
but the units are actually
shipped. So I'm using hacker RF
primarily which is a software
defined radio peripheral that
connects to a host computer.
It's open source hardware so
anyone build this, anyone can
get them and extend the design
and I think that's important
when doing anything sciency. The
official operating frequency
range is from 10 megahertz to 6
gigahertz. If you want to know a
thing about the unofficial
operating frequency range, come
to my talk at the wireless
village tomorrow. The base
bandwidth is 20 megahertz, which
is 3 orders of magnitude higher
speed than a sound card. I was
talking about how the sound card
input really isn't fast enough
for some of the targets that I'm
interested in, but 20 megahertz
is quite a bit of bandwidth. Not
as much as the ant catalog radar
devices, but it's enough to be
able to do some really
interesting experiments and it's
a half duplex transmit receiver
which means I can transmit or
receive but I can't do both at
the same time which is why I
have two units up here, one to
transmit and one to receive. So
my super sophisticated cardboard
test apparatus holds two hack
RFs and two directional
antennas. These PCB antennas.
I've actually split this up here
so I can have these antennas
pointing different directions
instead of being parallel. I can
make a triangle out of them and
we'll see how that goes. And I'm
using a frequency of 2482
megahertz, 2.482 gigahertz. It's
right at the top end of the 2.4
ISM band used by Wi‑Fi and
Bluetooth, however, just above
the frequency used by Wi-Fi and
Bluetooth in the U.S. So there's
a little bit of room at the top
of the band that isn't getting
used by a whole lot. And the
NSA, according to the ant
catalog is using frequencies in
the range of 1 to 4 gigahertz,
so this is kind of right in the
middle there. And it just so
happens that range happens to be
in the kind of center area of
the hack RF where I get the best
hack RF performance around 2.5,
2.4 gigahertz, that band is
where I get the best performance
and it's also easy to find off
the shelf filters and amplifiers
if you want to experiment with
amplifying these things for
example. Although you have to be
careful about that, I'm using
unamplified hack RF for my demo
here today. This is a pretty
good operating frequency and
tThis is what I've done most of
my testing at for these variety
of reasons. The first
retroreflector that I built is
called conga flock. I don't know
if you guys can see it very
well, but up there across the
top, those numbers are
centimeters. And between those
two orange pieces of wire,
there's a little tiny piece of
circuit board. I know what you
guys are wondering, how int he
world did this thing get to be
so huge? It's giant. It's giant
for a number of reasons. The
first retroreflector I made, I
very first one, was just a bare
transistor that I soldiered some
wires to. And then I decided
well, it's good to have a PCB, a
substrate, that kind of holds
everything together and gives it
mechanical stability. And then I
wanted to have a few extra
components so that I could
experiment with some things,
I'll talk about in just a
second, and then even after
doing that, it turned out that
the circuit board was less than
half the minimum size
requirement from Osh Park, my
favorite PCB maker, so I had to
double the size. But at least
that gave me some room to put
some silk screen text on it and
give it a little bit of a handle
so I can put it into my bench
vice and work on it a little
bit. So I'm going to go over the
hardware design here. I usually
go over electronic schematics in
details in a talk like this, but
this one is simple enough that I
think it's worth going through
in detail. The first thing you
need to know, the thing in the
middle, the funny little thing,
Q1 is a mosfet, a type of
transistor. And then all of the
various long rectangles are
resisters or they are places
where you can put a resister or
some other passive component.
However, the one on the upper
right, R1, that's do not
populate component. It's just
something I put there, it's is
footprint I put there just in
case I wanted to experiment with
putting a different impedance in
that spot. So we can ignore
that. It's not populated. And
the two at bottom are not
populated, but they have a
little bypass through them where
you have to cut the bypass if
you do want to populate. Those
two at the bottom are there in
case I want to change the
circuit in the future. So we can
ignore those, those don't really
exist in the circuit. And then
the other resister there, the
only purpose of that 10k
resister is just to protect the
gate of the mosfet and it
doesn't really affect the way
the circuit works much, other
than providing the protection.
And the mosfet itself, the one
I'm using typically have
built‑in protection, so we can
ignore that, too. And what we're
left with is an incredibly
simple circuit with an antenna
connected at the top, the target
device connected on the left,
and the mosfet in the middle. A
mosfet is just a transistor and
you can think of it as a switch,
when the gate, which is the
input signal from the target
device, when the gate is going
up and down in voltage, the
mosfet switches on and off the
antenna. That's all this thing
does. It just switches on and
off the antenna according to a
signal that comes from the
target. And that creates a
change in impedance on the
antenna that modulates a
reflective signal from that
antenna. So it's incredibly
simple. It's a one component
circuit. And I can use this as a
general purpose retroreflector
and connect it into whatever
device I want as long as that
input is swinging through a
couple of volts, at least, when
typically target devices will
have 3.3 volts or 5 volts,
that's plenty to drive this
thing. So I made a few and they
are really small. So I made
1,000. And if you want to make
one, I have this whole kit
together here that I'm going to
deliver to the hardware hacking
village that includes the
circuit boards, the mosfets,
some wire you can use for the
antenna and some wire
strippers/cutters. And this is
what you do if you want to build
your own. All you have to do is,
the first step is break off a
PCB from the panel. That's a
little more annoying, they are
not scored very well, but find a
nice sharp edge on a table and
you can break these things off.
Then you cut two antenna wires
and you want to make them about
an inch long for operation in
the 2.4 gigahertz band. There's
a nice little guide I have
Sharpied on to the bin here. And
so cut two of those and soldier
the mosfet on to the board and
solder the antenna wires on to
the board. And then you might as
well solder the other two couple
of wires on to the other two
little pin headers because
you're going to need something
in there to connect to a target.
So if you soldier a short little
piece of wire, you can put
alligator clips or whatever to
it or solder your other end to
your target. So it takes a
little bit of electronics
know‑how. And I apologize, these
things are a little harder to
solder than they could have been
and harder to break apart than
they could have been, so if you
do try this, you're going to
hate me. But hopefully you'll
have fun or at least take home a
souvenir. And then I will solder
it into something, in this case
I took a PS2 cable from a PS2
keyboard and spliced in the
conga flack to the middle and I
was able to get a return off of
it that way. So flamencoflock
was my next retroreflector. It's
taking this same design
basically and putting it into a
convenient form factor for
experimenting with PS2
keyboards. So all it does it has
two PS2 connecters, you can kind
of see one of them in the photo
there. I have one up here. It
has two PS 2 connecters and a
retroreflector in the middle. So
the actual circuit, if you look
at the two antenna wires,
there's a little black blob
right next to them, that's the
whole circuit, all the rest is
just connecter. So if I'm going
to snip PS2, I'm going to be
tapping either the clock line or
the data line. The clock line we
see in this diagram at the top
and the data line we see on the
bottom. Now ideally we would tap
both to recover the data, but
I'm only going to tap one and
I'm going to tap the data line.
And what we have here is a
diagram of what the voltage on
the line should be for the
letter Q, if somebody were
holding down the letter Q on a
keyboard. And so I'm going to
see if I can snip this using
flamingo flock. Let's see what
happens. I'm just turning on my
hack RF to transmit a couple
seconds at a time at 2484
megahertz. And I'm using my
other hack RF with this flow
graph ‑‑ not this one, this flow
graph here. And the long and
short of it is I'm going to be
picking up the signal and doing
an amplitude demodulation. So
I'm doing AM. An AM
demodulation. Let me see if this
all works. Now my ‑‑ I think I'm
getting a signal out of it. Now
if I were to adjust my target
here so everything is well lined
up, I'm firing a signal at it
with one of these antennas and I
am detecting a signal from the
other antenna. And I'm running a
little short on time here, but
hopefully this works. I'm going
to look at triggering this. This
is basically an oscilloscope
that I'm looking at, a software
oscilloscope. And see what
happens if I hit some keys. Oh,
I'm getting something changing,
but it's not looking very good.
So this is a total demo fail.
Probably because I spent all
last night trying to raise money
for the EFF and I spent all of
this morning trying to help kids
solder the land taps at the
roots asylum. Ah‑ha, I think I
actually got something. I'm
going to can change my accounts
per division here. And oh, there
we go! Let me see what's going
on. If I ‑‑ well, you're not
actually seeing what you should
be.  	>> [Applause].  	>> So
don't clap yet. It's really
close to working. This is a
little finicky because I have
highly directional antennas and
if they are not aimed very well,
then this may not work
particularly well. I'm
definitely getting something,
but I'm not sure that I'm
actually getting ‑‑ like I'm
totally not seeing the letter Q
yet. So I'm just going to show
you a screenshot from a previous
run and move along. In a
previous run I did looked like
that. And do you notice the
three downward pulses and then
the one wide pulse? This is what
it was supposed to look like and
it looks like that. It's very
recognizable. So I'm running
short on time so I'm not going
to be able to do a better job at
my demo, unfortunately. I'm
going to show you the rest of my
retroflectors. Tangoflock is a
retroreflector for USB. And I
use it to monitor USB keyboards
in particular because they are
low speed USB devices. I've
briefly tested low speed devices
and I figured out, yes, I'm
getting a signal with
characteristics that look like
low speed USB, but I have not
actually decoded bits. Although
I have decoded bits from the PS2
cable. Full speed USB, which is
kind of the next step up in
speed probably works with this
implant. I doubt that high speed
would work and you would need
much high bandwidth collection
platform than hack RF. Super
speed definately doesn't work,
you would need some kind of
incredible system for that and I
don't even connect the wires. So
Salsaflock is the next one I
have. The Def Con speakers ops
were totally awesome to get me
an extra VGA projector and I'm
totally not going to use it
because I'm running out of time
and it probably wouldn't have
gone any better than the PS2
demo. But I have this little
device and again, it's a fairly
simple circuit that gives me big
connecters, that makes it
convenient for experimentation.
This circuit is a little bigger,
it has more components in it.
The reason for that is VGA
signalling is for lower voltage.
There isn't enough voltage swing
in the VGA signal. It's too low
voltage to trigger the mosfet's
gate. So I have to do some
biosing of the mosfet to get it
up to voltage. But I have gotten
to the point with this that I
can detect a VGA signal and I'm
in particularly tapping the red
signal and I can very easily
detect the vertical synch
happening every 60 hertz or
something if I refresh and I can
definitely see patterns within
that, so there's some potential
for recovering the image on the
screen. Now how much of an image
I can get with only doing 20
megahertz sampling with the hack
RF, I have not determined yet.
It may only be useful when the
target has a low screen
resolution, which means it has a
slower pixel clock and you would
need a higher speed sampling
rate in order to target higher
screen resolutions. But this is
an image, this is just a plot.
And you see each of those AMD
modulator signal that I got from
Salsaflock, you see those tufts
there, those individual tufts at
the bottom, those happen 60
times per second and this was a
60 hertz screen refresh, so
that's why I was seeing the
vertical sync. I don't have a
whole lot of time to talk about
counter measures which is
probably a good thing, because I
don't have a whole lot to say
about counter measures. I don't
think that we know enough about
these threats yet to develop
good counter measures, but we
think we need to think about how
we validate that our equipment
works, how we evaluate that it
hasn't been modified or had
things implanted in it. We need
to know, are we being
illuminated or radiated by
things? And are our devices
prone to retroreflection without
being implanted? We don't know
any of those things, we have a
lot of research to do to be able
to do that. There is a talk in
the next hour by Leah that looks
interesting. He is kind of
taking a higher level view of
the problem and trying to figure
out how to detect this stuff. I
want to invite everybody to play
along. An invitation to hack. I
would love if people built some
of these here and started
experimenting with them. I would
love if people took my designs
from gift hub and started to
build some of their own. If I
solder some up this afternoon,
we'll have some over the at hack
five table in the vendor area.
Darrin was kind enough to give
the NSA play set crew an area
there and other folks who are
doing NSA play set talks are
also going to have some things
there. We are trying to get
tools out to people, if we can.
And of course we have the EFF
summit last night. I want to
remind people, there's a big
open field of research. Do be a
good neighbor if you experiment
with this stuff, know the laws,
try to not interfere with
people. Doing low power
experiments is really easy to
do. I have done PS2 sniffing
from one meter with unmodified
hack RFs that transmit a much
lower power than your Wi‑Fi card
in your laptop. So coming soon,
later this weekend, Mike Ryan is
giving a talk in the wireless
village tomorrow on some really
cool Bluetooth smart stuff,
these are all NSA play set
talks, Josh and Teddy are doing
a talk on I squared C implant,
which is very interesting how
you can expose and get to your I
squared C without opening up
your computer. NSA play set GSM
from Dean and Lochi on Sunday
and PCI express from Joe & Miles
on Sunday. All of these I'm
really excited about. I hope you
check them out. Thank you to
Dean for coming up with the
name, the NSA play set and for
the whole NSA playset crew.
Everyone has been great and
We're a loosely knit group, we
take anybody who comes along and
has a ridiculous name for a fun
project. Please join us, if you
think you have something that
fits in the NSA playset we'd
love to hear from you. Thanks
Jared Boone for helping me
troubleshoot some of my
retroreflectors not too long
ago. NSAplayset.org is where you
can find all information on NSA
playset. My retroreflectors are
on gethub and that URL. I
recommend waiting a few days
before you download and have
PCPs made because I do have a
couple of minor corrections I
need to make. They are pretty
minor. They are things you can
fix easily with a soldering
iron. And my url for
greatscottgadgets.com is
greatscottgadgets.com. So I'm
going to have a little Q&A
session out by the pool in 15
minutes, so, you know, after I
leave here, go look for me at
the pool. I'll be wearing this
awesome NSA play set T‑shirt
that says my ex key score goes
up to 11. If you see anybody
wearing these shirts, they are
probably people doing awesome
NSA play set or they are people
who supported the EFF last
night. Either way, they are cool
people to talk to. Thank you all
for coming. "This text is being
provided in a rough draft
format.  Communication Access
Realtime Translation (CART) is
provided in order to facilitate
communication accessibility and
may not be a totally verbatim
record of the proceedings."