>>How is everybody how holding
up? Way better, okay.
[Applause]. Okay so this is
Fatih and he's going to be
talking about Vio Wars, let's
give him a big DEF CON welcome.
>> Thank you. I appreciate it,
for lasting and saying hello. My
name is Fatih Ozavci and I will
talk about VoIP wars today. What
we need we kind of previously on
Voice over IP Wars. Because I
had another presentation last
year and we had Voice over IP
wars, return of the SIP and we
talked about session initiation
protocol attacks. I provided
Viproy; it's a kind of next
generation Voice over IP testing
tool. It is developed for only
pan testing, not for attackers.
So basically you cannot omit
your tasks but attackers may
not. I will not talk about SIP
too much today because I already
talk and if you are curious
about SIP security, you can get
the talk but I will talk about
Voice over IP solutions to your
security and some Cisco and
voice solutions products and
newer novelties. I will provide
a few new techniques; I will
provide a few new attack
services. A few new novelties
almost for you novelties and
three of them still unpashed....
And I will provide new tools and
new features also developed new
interface for you as well. >>Ah,
yeah, we are starting now. >>I
am Fatih Ozavci, Security
Consultant and I am working for
Sense of Security. I'm proud to
be part of this team and thanks
for them. Also my interests are
voice over IP mobile
applications, network
infrastructure, I am a
penetration tester so I can pan
test anything, that's why I am
pan testing voice over IP. I
missed some skills in this
presentation so the key word is
combining and merging the
skills. I....voice over IP
penetration testing tool
kit...it is actually a .....word
that means call, so this tool
will have new feature and those
features are skinny attacks,
skinny libraries, voice special
attacks, STP features,
encryption features, and vander
extensions. My agenda is talking
about host voice over IP
services and giving some basic
information. I am sure you don't
need it but let me try.
Furthermore we will talk about
network attacks, Cisco
inter...communication domain
manager attacks, Cisco
inter...manager attacks. We will
have three different lines.
First one is attacking SIP
services and we will talk about
Cisco specific SIP problems.
Furthermore we will talk about
attacking lines and we will talk
about skinny attacks. This is a
basic infrastructure for hosted
voice over IP services. Hosted
voice over IP services are multi
talent environments. So,
basically multi talent
environments, pro-wide talent
specific services. Sandbox items
and sandbox services are fully
dedicated to this talent. But
shell services, they are
available for all talents, not
specific ones. So basically they
may have IP phones, soft phones,
teleconference systems, some
other third party connections
but they will use sandbox items,
sand box objects for all voice
over IP communication. Which are
STP, RTP and SIP servers,
unified communication servers
and some CDR servers and data
base servers, of course.
Furthermore, they have shell
services. Shell services are IP
phone services, client
management, tent environment
management or PBX connections
such as land line connections
and GSN connections.
Furthermore, they have shell...
but it depends on the
infrastructure and
configuration. If we want to
attack one single talent, we
should use sandbox items. If you
want to attack all the
environments, if we want to
compromise all talents we should
attack directly to the shared
services. I will show some jail
breaking attacks here. I will
talk about Cisco and Wahl
solutions, Wahl solutions,
basically hosted a voice over IP
.......... Cisco is a partner so
basically they will provide this
hosted voice over IP environment
for many customers. We will talk
about Cisco and Wahl today but
these attacks can be cloned as
well. Also known as voice over
...... as well, so you can use
this extension as well. We will
talk about these services.
Services are basically separated
into two sections. First one is
web based services to support
and manage all talent platforms.
The second one is Voice over IP
services to provide essential
services. And we will attack
almost all of them. Our goal is
discovering the network, finding
the box, defining the errors,
learning the design and
attacking those objects. They
think host and voice over IP
environments are secure, it is
physically but they are not. We
have physical pan testing and
they showed me, even military
grade operations, they are not
secure. Their physical security
is kind of insufficient for
those services. We can use a
talent connection, local form or
comprehensiary forms; we may
have PC port connections behind
the forms. Furthermore we may
impersonate a technical guy or
another, a cable guy and we can
get an access. Also we can
.....a physical access and we
can get a connection, a kind of
access for voice re-land but we
should know voice re-land and
that is why we have CDP attacks,
DDP attacks and Arc sweeping
attacks as well. I do hope to
raise a simple model for Viproy;
it is called a discovery
protocol model. It is available
on Viproy package and you can
use it on Metasploit, actually I
used Hopper .... too many times,
too many years. But I needed a
cross path, a kind of
customization which is why I
loved this model so, if you have
a Linux you should use ...., if
you do not have a customized
engagement, you should use this
model to customize it. Also you
can use this model to far.....
And after all do you have
voice...ID. And we will have a
kind of connection but we should
keep it persistent, we should
add a kind of modified form or
wiretapping object. This is why
I think about Tapio Pi. Tapio Pi
is basic... PI in the IP form.
This is Cisco IP form, 7940. I
disassembled it and I saw that
there's another board on it and
this board is a basic board and
it provides broken actions.
Those broken actions are PC port
connections, talent connection
and a kind of ancillary
connection as well. Furthermore,
they have power source, when I
extract this board I saw that it
is connected using a wide
circuit. You can use this
circuit to connect or
disconnect. When I extracted I
saw that this internet
connection, RJ45 connection has
pins behind the card. So
basically we can use these pins.
I used a basic cable kit 5 and I
created a basic clone of the
transpart. If this phone will be
attached to the voice land we
can create and connect ... to
the same network. And yeah,
there are two spaces inside the
phone. First one is on this
board and the second one is
speaker space. I put my... to
the speaker space and you can
use the other one as well. You
may need the other one for
battery because power on the
internet may have to choose in
the same environment because it
needs, actually the IP phone
will use electricity.
Furthermore ...needs electricity
as well. But power over internet
may support only two power
supplies at the same time. And
as you know IP phone needs more
electricity. This way you need
another power source. You can
use a cell battery or you can
try your chance with a ... IP
phone. For example, if you
extract speaker you will see a
battery connection right there.
And yes, it has electricity so
you can use this electricity to
your supply. It is not completed
yet and I am still working on it
and I will provide a blog on it.
Actually we will not talk about
hardware attacks we will talk
about the modern protocol
attacks and service level
attacks. All of this environment
must be managed. This is why we
have Cisco Host Calibration
suite. This Cisco Host
Calibration suite contains Cisco
unified communication domain
manager. Also know as Wahl
Solutions. It has IP phone
services, self care, talent
user's management and their
services, furthermore talent
services management. The
difference is Talent uses will
use self care. Talent
administrators will use Talent
Services administration.
Furthermore, unified
communication manager will be
used for all voice over IP based
services. We have reported
almost 40 novelties to Cisco.
Cisco reported that some of them
they are not novelty, some of
them, yes they are novelty but
their impact is very limited.
And yes, some of them are
novelty. And Cisco published a
few advisories. I will share
those references at the end of
the presentation. But, here is
the thing, we have another
security advisory. This security
advisory contains two different
unpatched novelties and one real
novelty. Two unpatched ones are
novelties. We found them on Wahl
solutions IP phone examiner
services. It is still unpatched
and will be patched in
September, maybe the second
week. The other one is embedded,
maybe you already know that, but
the product is pretty expensive
so you cannot get this product
easily. So, I have no priority
right now. If you have this
product you can extract SSHT
easily using this exit file.
Cisco unified communication
domain measure also for
embedded. Wahl ....is a basic
client platform and this
platform contains some scripting
novelties and yeah they are
stored scripting novelties and
you can affect other users of
the same talent. But domain
manager actually management
services for talent it is a good
attack surface for us. We can
get an administrative user
easily by using features.
Furthermore if we have a user we
can elevate our privileges as
well. We have multiple privilege
escalations. Also we have some
stored scripting novelties. We
have potential and software
escalations as well and we will
talk about them. A basic user is
here, if you use device user you
will have a response and you can
create this easily. But if you
use upload features and if you
send a bogus file which contains
injections or a few bogus
contents as well you will have
this error message. This error
message contains some additional
errors, for example, soft
errors. Cisco says that it takes
this bug but it is not a novelty
because there is no injection
here . I could not test it
because all of them was a part
of a project in an engagement.
During the engagement I had only
5 days to test all this
environment. HCS, infrastructure
also unified communication
system as well. This is why I
could not try SP injections. If
you believe Cisco it is fine but
if you do not believe you can
try using insecure file out put
features. It leaks; it has CGI
tools so you can create the
qualified inclusion attacks and
execution as well. But they are
potential attacks, you can
attack. Escalation is easy, you
can modify a user if you have
basic access, you will be a kind
of location administrator of the
talent. You can modify the
environment and modify the user
and add a different role on it
and add role for example talent
administration, division
administrator or infrastructure
administrator. Furthermore if
you want to add a user you can
use user type as well. If you
use user type, you can use admin
user and you can add a new admin
from scratch. Furthermore we can
manipulate number translation to
redirect all calls or all
extensions to us. So, basically,
we have many attacks. However we
have another measure service
here and the services are
perform management feature of
Wahl solutions. Wahl solutions
provide IP phone examine
services. This service is a
shell service. It is a family, a
basic tool set, but it is a
basic shell object for all
talents. All phones, IP phones
or cell phones or teleconference
room phones, or devises, it
doesn't matter. They will use
this service. So basically we
can attack the service to get
additional access or compromise
all talents. We can use
additional attacks on it. For
example, call forwarding, speed
dialing manipulation, voice mail
access, pin changing, it is
still unpatched. Second week of
September it will be in use.
This URL is the basic attack
service; SRV is the service type
and service name. Device ID,
make and address and you can
easily get it. An action may be
called for rewriting or updating
basic speed dial. It is very
secure, binary, unrecordable
protocol. So it does not need
any authentication authorization
feature. Who can't record a XML
file, right? Basically this
service works on an XML content.
You can not record an XML file,
right. This is why I developed
two different models to exploit
this novelty. I will not share
this exploit on my software
package but I will share here.
Furthermore I will show the
service in a different way.
First problem is this product is
expensive. I have mentioned yet?
Okay. But the thing is I cannot
provide a live demo on this
product because I have no Cisco
UCDM here, that's why I
developed a fact service for it.
So basically I will use my
exploits to this fact service. I
hope it will work, I hope you do
as well. But, we will see. Okay,
we have a cheat sheet here and
basic Wahl's demos. This service
provides MAC based
identamanagement, after that it
all services such as call
forwarding or speed dial. At
this demo I will use the call
forwarding feature. I have this
service here, probably one of
them. Ahh, here. This is our
fact service. We can copy on
past our code. Basically we us a
model call forwarding, 4.1 which
is me my port and action and it
seems we have a target. If the
MAC address is valid we will
have a display name of the faint
number. Faint number is eunuch
in this environment. But this
faint number is basically
exemption. If you want to
redirect it you should update
this faint number. So basically,
we will update it. For example
set action, forward two. See, it
seems okay. Our display name is
007. Furthermore, we are talking
about Cisco environments. Right?
We are not talking about IP
phones. We are talking about
everything which means we have
jeopardy interface as well.
Jeopardy interface provides
additional connectivity for
third party items as well such
as Cisco Jabber or regular Cisco
clients. Furthermore, SDK for
all other third party clients
such as Microsoft Link. At this
point we can use forwarding just
like this as well. For example
set forward to James Bond. And
we can use name, agency name is
updated. I am showing this
because Microsoft Link and other
products may need a main address
to handle a message or call. So
this is basic call forwarding we
can update all talents and we
can redirect all phones to us
and we can redirect just like a
basic internet exchange server.
We have additional speed dials.
Those phones need a speed dial
service because they have no
speed dial on SIP protocol. That
is why they need a kind of
protocol to provide this speed
dial access. That's why we have
another model here. Viproy was
speed dial. Okay? Here we go. We
have three different speed dials
for this MAC address. MAC
address can be obtained using
scan attacks as well. So we can
get a kind of communication map
of the talent or all talents. So
we will have a communication
path. We can add or remove a
content for example, add Viproy
to third position. Set action
list and run. See, Viproy is in
the third position. We can try
to add Viproy to a specific
position, for example one. That
position is not available
because it is in use. But, we
can modify this as well. So, get
the list again, Viproy is in the
position now. This service is a
kind of dangerous service but
the thing is it has been used
for all talents, we can jail
bait all platforms here. We can
redirect everybody, every user
of all talents. Okay, if we go
back. We have additional
features. We talked about web
based attacks. But the thing is,
sorry; I should show the fact
services card and my expert card
here. My expert is, actually it
is pretty complicated. Actually
it has bypass and depth bypass
issues as well. So, basically
you should very careful. Agency
this is the exploit part. This
is my shock cord and agency,
this is ASR bypass feature,
provide their name, field number
and forward to. If you do not
use forward to, you will not
bypass sandbox and AS alarm and
dep as well. So basically
exploit is very complicated. I
will not share this exploit
because it can be pretty
dangerous. However, I can share
my fact service so you can find
how it works. Right? It is
already available on Viproy so
basically you can work on this
fake web service to understand
how it works. Okay. We should
continue. Sufficiently attacks,
we have additional voice over
web attacks here. Those are
unified communication attacks.
We have TDM, PSDM and they are
old they think SIP is next
generation and they think SIP is
ready to use for all unified
communication systems. However,
they do not agree about features
of SIP that's why they modified
SIP. Not even Cisco. Cisco,
Microsoft and all third party
vendors, because SIP has message
metals. It has invite as well.
But, the thing is they use
secure sharing, adding file
transfer or a kind of voice mail
using sample, Wildfire, etc.
Those are very complicated
things. You cannot use SIP just
like that. That's why they
modified it. But they modified
SIP, regular SIP protocol. They
have additional exemptions. We
will talk about a few ones. The
thing is Cisco has
authentication problems about
SIP. Microsoft has a few
additional features on SIP.
Yeah, we will talk about Cisco
now but we can talk about
Microsoft later. It is basically
a Linux operating system so if
you will first remove the Cisco
unified communication and if you
have a novelty you can execute
the code on a regular Linux
server. Keep the same
formations. We should discover
web services using our regular
features such as Viproy
discovery features, registry,
other tools. Furthermore, .....
are in the group tool, it is in
use and developed by Zander
Gucci, thanks to him I have used
this tool for many years. After
that I developed Viproy because
I needed additional
authentication features because
authenticating SIP services it
needs some kind of
authentication. After
authentication you may have
additional features. For example
registration, yeah you can get
that kind of access on this SIP
server. And we talked about SIP
service attacks last year, and I
actually demonstrated a few
advance attacks. But the thing
is Cisco SIP authentication is
somehow different. It needs
address, device type and
exzantion. Three of them must be
valid to authenticate you as a
form. If you want to use user
name and password it is fine, it
is supported for third party IP
phones as well. Furthermore,
Cisco suggests that security
requirement is essential for
voice over IP environment. So,
they can use digital certificate
base for authentication. Cisco
unified communication provides
additional user name and you can
use these errors. Register and
subscribe it is very easy task.
You can use Viproy; you check my
presentation last year. You can
use or change your phone number
and address or regular text and
we can use them. Furthermore I
have demonstrated additional
advanced attacks such as SIPro
advanced attack. We can use
remote SIPro, other services to
attack. It was what we
demonstrated last year.
Furthermore, we can use it to
attack other servers. For
example, they provide four or
three billion messages which is
too much. If you send a bogus
message you have errors. If you
use IP spoofing you can use
basic service attacks. Also we
can use hacking SIP trust
relationships. We can use IP
spoofing, we can get a
communication. After that, we
can add IP addresses in the
field. Find which IP address and
port is trusted. I demonstrated
this last year this, and we
initiated a base call. Also, we
can attack mobile applications
using this as well. But the
thing is.... is somehow
different in the same
environment. First of all Cisco
UCM accepts addresses as
identity and it doesn't need
further authentication for many
SIP based IP phones, and our own
skinny environment. Also, we can
find raw waste in the same
environment, it will provide for
users, antennas and all the
other environments. However,
they need citrons connections,
that's why they use additional,
some connections are looters.
That's why we can use them to
initiate calls because they have
no identification by default. We
can use custom headers, we can
add specific headers. Here is
the thing, remote party ID is
where generic header and Cisco
accepts remote party ID because
it is a kind of compatibility
issue. So, if add a basic remote
party ID in our current
connection, authenticated
connection, Cisco will accept
remote party ID as an identity.
So we call everywhere with a
fake identity. Caller ID
spoofing, yes, it bypasses the
billing features furthermore we
can access voice mail and third
party operators. Here is the
thing; we have public real world
attacks such as caller ID fraud
for all operators. If we had an
operator we could not initiate
our attack, caller ID spoofing
attack. Initiate a call through
the land line connections to
call the third party GSM
operator to access a voice mail
account without a pin. It's all
caller identity, it's an attack
and it is in use. Also we can
send call back messages, we can
send fake messages, we can use
spam, we can use this attack
against other operators and we
can use for other terms. And
this is a basic demonstration of
an attack. I already
demonstrated other SIP attacks,
you find my last presentation,
voice over IP, it is on you tube
as well. I will use a basic SIP
connection here. We will use our
invite model and we have two
different clients here. First
one and second one and they are
connected through a Cisco
server. It is a trial edition so
basically we will have a trial
access and yes it works. I have
registered forms here and I will
use invite model with proto TCP.
We have TCP on tailor support
now so we can use it.
Furthermore we will use specific
phone number and log in
features, furthermore we have
different log in metals, I
choose register. Furthermore, we
have vander extensions and it
must be used. Vander extensions
first one is Cisco device. If
you want to register yourself as
an IP phone such as 7940 or 41
you should use Cisco device with
application. If you want to use
third party device such as third
party clients you should use
Cisco unification header, after
that my user name and password.
This is not a novelty, see we
have a call. And yeah, the thing
is it is one of thirteen. Let me
explain why. If I had set the
remote party header it will have
a call from 2001 which is my
original one, right, see. But
the thing is we can set custom
IDs. For example from James Bond
or we can use a current client
for example, 1013. Also we have
additional features here, for
example sending a message. We
have no public tool to send a
message. We should manipulate or
we should prepare our tools such
as SIP and after that we can
send a message, right? But we
can manipulate message features
such as message tie or message
content that is used for
additional sharing features of
third party clients such as
Cisco jabber. So basically we
can change this content to
attack different clients using
different scale. For example
message tie, fuzz 2000, it is
possible as well. But I will use
this sample for a basic search
engine feature. Operators hack
the operator because bypassed
identification. Furthermore, it
is the basic HTML feature, HTML
message. So basically we can
send this message to the real
phone as well. If it receives
this message, if it is a smart
phone as well, this can be good.
Furthermore, we can change
message content, for example
message tie, it is still text
and plain but message content
could be fast 500, fast 5000. It
depends on you. Some of the
clients they are really
vulnerable such as Cisco Jabber
or for example XLight or you
know Microsoft Link. Yeah, we
will continue with other
attacks, because we can attack
clients. I mentioned client
attacks last year so I will pass
this slide I already provided
this slide on my presentation so
you can check them as well. And
Cisco has different clients and
we can attack all of them we can
use attacks as well. And I have
a tool for it. Reproxy is
another tool I have developed
for TCP, TNS interception.
Furthermore, it supports custom
digital search features. It has
low feature it has multiple
duplication as well. It is a
fork of proxy. So basically we
have used this tool to
manipulate other clients. It has
multiple issues; sorry about
that but I will fix it in a few
months. You can fix it as well,
it is available on Viproy. I
would appreciate a few patches.
This is a basic SIP fishing demo
and I already showed it. Basic
client attack demos, we can use
them as well. I have crashed an
IOS application last year using
only spoofing, so we can attack.
But, this is not the case. We
should talk about skinny as
well. Skinny is a generic
protocol. Cisco uses it for all
local environments. Even for
hosted voice over IP services.
It is a kind of compatibility
requirement because they will
use SIP by default. They will
use skinny for regular SIP
phones, regular Cisco IP phones.
It is a kind of protocol so
basically you should use many
packages to register yourself.
We can use basic attacks, when I
search, VoIP or SIP attacks or
skinny attacks; I sell always
one single name, Jace Nostrom.
He has a pension about VoIP but
not only VoIP as well he helped
me too much for this
presentation, thank you for him
again. Of course Viper and Spara
they have published some tools
and novelties on skinny. I am
not sure about Viper 11 as
skinny support because I saw a
communication but I am not sure
because there is no information
on their page and yeah. Also
Felix found a few novelties on
skinny protocol. But we have no
public skinny analyzer or skinny
tool. That is why I decoded this
protocol using Y Shock, just
like it. But the thing is it is
different versions, such as 17,
19, 20, so some of the packages
and samples are not available on
Y Shock consult. So basically
you cannot decode them. There is
one item of this library, right
side basic skinny passer, it has
many different options for many
different responses from server
and left side is a basic sample.
Signing the register, it is
pretty easy. Everybody develops
a basic skinny model. But the
thing is, developing a skinny
model; yes it is easy, such as
register or call. It is pretty
easy. But if you need more, you
can develop using same library
as well, because I provide a
basic library through
Metasploit. So you can basically
develop your own... on skinny. I
have a basic... but it is not
good right now. But, think about
it, register needs no
authentication, right? First
register packages. So basically,
many...but nobody...for example
button templates, or nobody ...
the remote server during a call.
So you can do it because all
packages and all comments very
easy for example prep, open,
receive channel. And you can use
a bogus device app here or a
port. So it's a kind of new
attack surface for you. But I
have a demo as well. If you
register it to a specific mega
address we can use regular
clients as well such as Cisco IP
Communicator, it supports device
name, custom device name and you
can use your device name here,
if you have a registration. Here
is the demo. I have Cisco
communicator right side. I have
Cisco UCM, I have Cisco UCM 912.
But I tested all the novelties
on 10.5.1, 10.5.2 and lower
versions so it works with them.
It has two different options
Cisco IP Communicator or regular
Cisco IP phone. You can use all
of them. In this sample, I have
two different clients; let me
check they can call each other.
They can call, good and they
called, and yeah. Now we will
use skinny attacks. This is a
basic register plug in.
Basically we will use remote
target MAC address and IP
address, that's all. IP
addresses, server IP address MAC
addresses, IP phones MAC
address. After that we can
register. Agency, I can
attribute information of this
MAC address such as line ID's.
But the thing is I am not using
MAC spoofing here. I am using
MAC address in the connection as
an identity, that's all. There
is no MAC spoofing here. So, I
can use other MAC addresses such
as this MAC address. When I use
this MAC address agency lift up
our first line. It is
disconnected now. It's a kind of
service for older versions. I
reviewed the information which
line is available for this MAC
address and I am one of them.
But the thing is we can insure
the call here. For example, I
can call anyone. This is another
model, Viproy skinny call and I
will use another MAC address and
my target is 1,013. When I use
it, it will be registered first
and the Agency it is here. I do
not fix this error. It is
necessary because if the other
client, real client, will try to
connect, re-connect, you will
have this error. Because your
PTC connection will be
terminated, that will be only
one single client. This is why I
keep this error. This says the
remote client is trying to
reconnect. We will try it again,
see it will work. So, it is
registering now and we are
getting confirmation and we are
calling, see from 1001. Okay,
register called we can
additional features such as call
forwarding, it is more useable
one. It is still trying to
register, but if you try to
redirect this phone number 1012,
1013, it will be really good for
us, right? Because, we can
redirect all phones to us, after
that we can redirect them to
anywhere. It is connected right?
When I try to register it is
disconnected again. It may try a
few times but it will have
success. Lines open for call
forwarding, 1013 numbers dialed
and see it is forwarded. This is
my skinny model and you can use
basic features such as register,
call or call forwarding or you
can turn it as a kind of
advanced pauser so you can
attack remote Cisco UCM's using
this attack. As you see I did
not talk about toll fraud too
much because we have a good
speaker here. Patrick McNeil
provided a really good, maybe
best toll fraud speech ever,
this afternoon, sorry this
morning. And it was really good
and you should get a video or
presentation and please visit
our register 436. Am I right?
Okay good. So he has a really
good toll fraud speech. And I am
talking about other attacks. So
basically, we can attack
network, we can attack Cisco
UCM, we can attack Cisco Unified
Communication Domain Manager
clients, skinny protocol, SIP,
we can attack everywhere.
Solutions, our solutions
published by Cisco and we have
additional suggestions. First of
all, IP phone examiner service
or remote party ID. This ..and
they are yeah, they are still
unpatched and you can attack
these servers using remote party
ID or IP phone examiner
services. Furthermore, you can
use other novelties and starting
from 3277 to 3283. Furthermore,
a few additional novelties and
92, sorry 97 and 32 sorry 3302
and we have yeah, many novelties
here almost twelfth series
assigned, some of them not here
because they are information
level. And yeah, basically you
should secure your design we
have attack services on
everywhere we can attack server,
we can attack protocols, we can
attack lines and we can attack
web applications as well.
Basically security deployment
and good design they may help
you to secure the network.
That's all. And yeah, I have
references that you can download
that you were here. I have a 15
minute training video, also I
have another Def Con video you
can use you tube to find it. And
we have agency attacks there.
Furthermore, I really
appreciated a Sense of Security
team they supported me too much
actually. They encouraged me
again and again here.
Furthermore Jeff Norstrom helped
me too much about this
presentation. Furthermore, some
good suggestions about my point
of view. Also, Mark, Paul Henry
and Sandra, of course. This is
my presentation, this is what I
have. Do you have any questions
related with this topic? I
cannot see by the way. Do you
have any questions? No question?
You do not give any questions
here, okay? Okay, thank you.
(Applause)