>> Alright, so like you said I'm
David Dorsey. I work at Click
Security doing R&D. I've been on
the defensive side for the last
ten years. File analysis, RE, a
little bit of IR. Recently doing
some stuff with machine
learning, if you're over at B
sides. But, we're here to talk
about ROP. So, quick level
setting, ROP is a technique used
to bypass non-executable memory,
bounce around memory, executing
small gadgets. Typically input
the return instruction, hence
the return oriented programming.
I use pin to do this. It's a
dynamic binary instrumentation
framework from Intel, it's
really nice. You don't need to
compile source code and it can
instrument dynamically generated
code. It gives you lots of
different granularity on where
you can instrument by
instruction, basic block
function, dll loads and unloads.
It can do way more than what I'm
using it for but it's a really
cool tool. So, the basic idea
here is, we're going to force
some control flow integrity.
We're starting with just coarse
grain controls. So, the idea is,
we know where your calls and
returns are supposed to go. You
know, the functions,
instructions after a call
instruction, things like that.
So we want to create a white
list of these addresses and then
we want to store the offset to
these because dll's are loaded
ALSR now. Then, if an indirect
call or a return doesn't go to
one of these addresses then we
go, hey, this is a ROP. So,
first we have to get those
offsets, we have to build our
white lists. So how do we get
those? So, the first I did is I
build a pin tool to give me
those addresses. So, when DLL is
loaded it iterates through the
exported functions, analyzes
them, finds the calls, if it's a
direct call we put the target of
that on the white list and then
the instruction afterwards. If
it's an indirect call just the
instruction afterwards because
we don't know where it goes yet.
Then, in addition to that, all
calls and returns are
instrumented on the instruction
level. This is because when you
run a program not ever function
is in one of those exported
ones. There's a whole lot more
so we need to get access to
those. Then, these offsets are
stored when the program ends,
it's dumped to a text file.
There is some post processing
that goes on afterwards to add
them to the white list and make
sure that you don't have any
duplicates. So, this is really
good in the sense that we get
real, actual used values. There
are not questions, there's no
heuristics we have to worry
about. Bad news is that it's not
the fastest thing and we only
get values that are actually
run. So, if a DLL isn't loaded
you're not getting a code for
that. And you also probably need
to run it multiple times just to
be safe. I would have to run
three or four times to make sure
every different code path is
executed. So then I decided that
wasn't a good idea. I didn't
want to do that so I turned to
pyew. It's much better at
detecting these functions. It's
much better. You can extract the
flow graphs and then you can
bulk run them. I actually had to
create a patch for pyew that I'm
making available. At some point
it will be put in the main trunk
but I have to fix it first. But
it's much better; I get a lot
more details, or a lot more
information quicker. So, now
that we have the data what do we
do with it? So, I store all of
them by per dll and I store them
by the md5 hash. This is because
dll's can have inversions and I
need to be able to account for
that. So, now that we have all
of this let's detect the ROP.
So, we have another pin tool.
When a dll is loaded pin gives
you the location of that dll
disk. So, I take that location,
open up the file, I hash it,
then take that hash and load the
white list for that. Then I
instrument all indirect calls
and returns and if you're not on
the white list you're a ROP. So,
examples: Adobe 9.3 on Windows
XP, there is the hash. This is
an old exploit obviously. So, we
run it, wave our hands, and
viola; we have a detection. So,
you can see the address where we
are coming from and where we're
going to. Then in the
parenthesis there's the offset.
So yay, we found one. That's
really good, I was really happy.
But, we only detected one and
that was disappointing. All you
need to do is detect one but,
you know, I always want more. So
let's take a look at what
happens. So, this is an
enco-type dll. The attacker
already has control of the EAX.
This is the beginning of the ROP
change. So, the call executes
and then we just here. Actually,
we don't detect this one at the
moment, there is a call before
it, so this address is actually
on the white list at the moment.
That's disappointing so that's
probably why we didn't detect
this one. We execute those three
instructions and we get to this,
so we do a stack pivot, and this
is the one we detect. Ok, great,
we detected this one now let's
see why. Let's look at the
instruction before it and there
really isn't an instruction
before it because it's not
really an instruction that is
supposed to be there. Just
returning into the middle of an
instruction and we can detect
that. So, at this point this is
where it dies, at this return
right here. And that's because
the pin is affecting my memory
layout. It's messing up the heap
spray so when the return happens
we're going to a random spot in
memory which is generally not
useful when you are trying to
execute a program or anything.
So, on a side note, I don't know
if we should run everything in
pin because hey, I prevented it
from happening. So, let's make
believe here. How would we have
done if this had actually
executed completely? So, there
are forty-five chains in this
ROP sequence, only fourteen
unique addresses. Not terribly
surprising once you have a
gadget that works. No sense
finding another to do the same
thing. Two of these were
indirect calls and we had 43
returns. Three of the fourteen
addresses were on the white list
so we had a pretty good
detection rate there. So,
overall out of all the chains we
only missed three of them. Not
too shabby there. Example two
here; Adobe 9.5, also on Windows
xp more recent vulnerability
from late last year. This one,
unfortunately, I didn't get
anything. Pin was messing up the
memory layout again, despite my
best efforts. So again,
unfortunately we have to go the
make believe. So this one
actually had a huge ROP
sequence, its 208, but it was
dominated by a NOP sled
essentially. It was returning to
itself over and over again and
once it finished that then it
went around about its business.
Fifteen unique addresses this
time, all of them returns.
Again, only three were on the
white list and of all of the
chains we detected two-hundred
and four out of two-hundred and
eight. So, we seem to, on the
address part, about the same
detection rate. So, let's do a
little math. How good would this
work if we could get it to work
in pin? So, you can see, you
know, the math works out in your
favor pretty quickly. Even at
ten there are a lot of nines in
that detection probability.
That's a good thing. So, let's
say that might be a little
optimistic, let's say. So, what
if we drop it to fifty percent?
Even at ten addresses you still
have 99.9 percent. I was happy
with that. So, let's talk about
the limitations of this.
Obviously breaking on the stack
limit. That's a pretty big
limitation unfortunately. Since
we are running this in pin it's
also kind of slow. This is not
ready for prime time. I don't
want to make you think that it
is. We don't handle jump
oriented programming, JOP; I
would need a sample to test that
out first. We only do the course
grained control flow integrity,
not the fine grained yet. So,
what's left to do? Obviously I
still have to figure out the
heat problem. There are probably
much better, smarter
implementations I can do. Maybe
do things at the basic lock
level rather than every single
instruction. I can push the
analysis to another thread. The
analysis doesn't take a long
time but microseconds add up
when you do it billions of
times. I want to add checks for
JOP in there since I think we
can do that. I'd love to
implement this on OS X and Linux
would be fine. Also, on
Wednesday at Black Hat there was
a really good talk on bypassing
all the ROP stuff called The
Beast in in Your Memory. I want
to talk about that for a little
bit here. They defeated
essentially all of the coarse
grained CFI's. They had to
sample a demo where they
defeated EMET, the latest one.
It would defeat my current
implementation. It defeated
return frequency/sequence length
heuristics, from Kbouncer and
ROPecker. So, that is the state
of the art now. So, they raised
the bar so how can we defeat
them now? That's the big
question. So we can start to
implement fine grain control. As
I stated earlier, we currently
wouldn't detect this particular
call into this location.
However, really the only
address, the only place where
you should return to this
specific, the CB38 is from that
call. So, if we're not coming
from the return in that call,
then that's very suspicious. So
we should be able to do that.
When we pull all of the
addresses with pyew we can
easily get all the return
addresses from where they go.
Since we do all of this
pre-process this shouldn't add a
lot of analysis time and I
think, you know, we should be
able to detect ‑‑ we should be
able to defeat what they
currently have at the moment.
So, it's just raising the bar
and then they're trying to raise
the bar. So, there's probably a
smarter way to do this. Maybe
you want to do this in a
debugger, Detours, Kbouncer, in
particular, I know uses the MSRs
for the last branch and that's
how they can get their
performance. Pin is pretty slow
tonight but it's nice. It's
slow, it's good for using, for
poofing out a concept but it's
not going to be a prime time
tool at this point. And so
that's about it. I have code to
your. It's not up yet. It should
be I'd like to say tonight but
let's be honest it would be more
like tomorrow morning. If you
want to contact me you can.
There's further reading. You
might be able to read this if
you're in the front but if you
want the slides later there's
some good links there about some
things there about ROP. And
that's it. Any questions?
(Applause). >> All right. I got
tons of time. So, I can go back.
I know, I talk fast, I
apologize. So, one thing to note
here, the icucnv36 that's used a
lot because it's not ALSR'd so
in the 9.X series and most of
your attacks go behind that.
They'll use this. Let's see what
else? That's about it really.
The other ones ‑‑ there was some
calls that I could detect,
indirect calls, so it wasn't
just returns.