>>My name is Joe Grand, I do
computer stuff, I do electronic
stuff, I designed a few years of
DEFCON's electronic badges.
14-18. Today is a talk that I've
been really wanting to do for a
really long time, and that's
look at different ways to get
access to inner layers of
circuit boards to help with
reverse engineering. So, we see
a lot about chip-hacking that
Chris does at a really
microscopic chip level. We see a
lot of hardware hacking,
embedded systems, component
level, connecting up through
JTAG interfaces and through UART
ports and all sorts of stuff
which is slightly higher level,
but we never really look at the
board level. And this is
something that I've really
wanted to do for a long time, so
I'm excited to give this and
lucky that I guess I convinced
enough people at DEFCON to let
me give it. So just to get
started, reverse engineers PT
boards isn't that much different
than anything else, except we
look at the circuit board. We're
undesigning a system that's
already been built. In this case
for this work, I'm sort of
assuming a black box type of
scenario. Maybe we open up a
product and access a circuit
board in the field that we want
to figure out what's going on
with it. So we take that system,
and we use destructive methods
and nondestructive methods
whatever we need, depending on
the situation so get all the
information about the board so
we can go and perform an attack
or do SGLGS something else. The
main ways soldier to access each
individual copper layer, which
is the primary thing I'm most
excited about. Once you get
those, if you get each layer of
the board, sometimes they have a
multi‑ layer board, and I'll
describe the kind of typical
board composition. You can kind
of lay those out together and
stack them in just (?) and do
imagine processing types of
things to trace out connections.
Once you do that, you can say
this part connected to this part
and maybe micro controllers
connected to international
memory to give you an idea about
what's going on. Oh, yeah, also
besides the obvious sorts of
things figuring out how the
system works, good to verify
security schemes of things. What
I really like about this is
injecting kind of new behavior
into a device. This is something
that's like, yeah, of course you
have the standard research type
of things or forensic analysis
or whatever. If you have the
board design, you have the
fingerprint of the board. If you
have that board level, you have
firmware and other things. Lots
of governments have been doing
it for quite some time, and they
must use the techniques I'm
assuming. It's interesting area
because now you take a board,
delayer it and figure out what's
going on and find a good
location to inject something
that isn't going to be detected.
Whether it's enabling some new
feature, whether it's some
surreptitious monitoring or
whatever it is, people don't
think if somebody changed the
board layout between the time I
sent the board out to fab and
the time it came back from
China. No one is thinking about
that. At chip layer maybe.
There's all sorts of kind of
gray mart areas for chips, but
circuit boards, you don't think
if someone adds functionality to
a board, but you should. So we
look at three different
sections. I've broken this out.
The first soldering, thing is
getting access to the top or
bottom layers of the circuit
board. Then we look at
delayering for multi‑ layer
boards to how to figure out and
get access to each individual
layer of the board. Then imaging
with nondestructive types of
stuff. A lot of tools we look at
here are not that impressive,
but it's just never been talked
about. So we have manual some
manual methods and chemicals.
All these different things are
cool to put in one spot. And a
lot of thing we use are design
for failure analysis, so they're
engineering tools that
legitimate designers are using
and legitimate fabricators are
using that we're using for
hacking hardware and for reverse
engineers and that's what we can
do a lot. Take advantage of
tools out there and use them to
our advantage. Just work was
done for a cyber fast track
project so our tax dollars at
work to play with circuit
boards, which is awesome. I was
going to do it anyway. I didn't
tell them that. So before we can
actually start getting access to
the layers and start doing some
of these techniques, we need to
understand how a circuit board
is put together. How many are
familiar with circuit boards and
how they're built? About half.
How many have designed a circuit
board? About the same half.
Okay. Cool. I guess that makes
sense. Okay. Half of you guys
are familiar with it and half
aren't. That's pretty good.
Circuit boards are basically a
sandwich of layers. So you have
your insulating layers and your
copper layers. Your top layer is
copper and then you have your
insulating layer. So I call it a
circuit board sandwich and made
a shirt just for the occasion. I
don't know if you can see it
from way in the board. Circuit
board sandwich. Circuit boards
are awesome. So this is  ‑ ‑ the
circuit board provides a
physical carrier, so you have
all the components that go on
the board with the physical
carrier where the component
connects on the board and they
provide the electrical pathways.
If you figure out what they are,
you can do the reverse
engineering. This picture on the
right this cross‑ section is a
16‑ layer board I happened to
pull out of my stack of circuit
boards, and it's a cross‑
section. So we're looking at
each individual layer from the
side‑ view. There's a bunch of
-- I don't know what it is. I
can't do the math in my head.
There's thin layers and two
thick layers in the middle and a
bunch of other ones. If you do a
cross‑ section not uncommon,
sometimes you can do it from the
edge of the board so you can see
and try to get an idea of
interlayer spacing. The inter
layers are thicker that means
power or ground planes or
something carrying high current
there. The picture on the left
is an awesome, awesome thing if
you can ever get it. It's the
Dutch Indonesian specNell, which
is an awesome layer cake and not
a PC board and taste much better
than PC boards. I can guarantee
this. I ordered this at a
restaurant in the Netherlands.
And I didn't know what it was.
They brought it, and I was like
oh, my God, this is awesome. I'm
putting it in my presentation.
Now you know what circuit boards
look like. There's a bunch of
other layers on a board. You
have your copper and substrate
layers, but you have other
stuff. There's a silk‑ screen
layer usually for markings on
the board, and sometimes other
colors. That's made of a
printable ink or epoxy. Usually
part designators are on there,
sometimes you see manufacturing
logos and sometimes markings by
engineers for testers, things to
take advantage of it. That's at
the super top layer. The next
layer down, the solder mask ,
coating that makes the coatings
green or white or blue or
whatever, basically the
protective layer that protects
any area of the copper that is
not intended to be exposed. If
you look at your Defcon badges,
all those copper pads, those
copper circles are intentionally
made to be exposed. You can
solder to them and tap onto them
and do things. If you look
carefully you can see a bunch of
trailers underneath the actual
solder mask, and those are not
intended to hack on. That
doesn't mean you're not allowed
to go there and do it. It means
the engineer doesn't want you to
access those and protects the
board from dust and erosion and
a bunch of other stuff. We need
to deal with that solder mask
later. The circuit board fab is
almost approaching like high
feature size chips, like you're
getting so  ‑ ‑ these tiny, fine
features so the state‑ of‑ the‑
art costs less than 1 mill,
1/1000 - thousandth of an inch.
Which is amazing density. Half a
mill, less of half a mill
diameter laser drill holes.
Circuit boards are highly
complex. They're amazing. Avia
inpad connects different layers
today. Normally in a traditional
PC board fab you have it going
through the board say it
connects layers 2 and 6 of the
board. It's still going to go
all the way through, because
it's an easier fabrication
process. When we have avia pad
or buried via, you can't find
the via sometimes. It's insane.
Via and pad is like you have a
highly integrated device where
there's a matrix of solder balls
underneath the part. If that pad
needs to connect to an inner
layer, it doesn't have to go OP
top layer somewhere else. It can
have a via straight in the pad
and going straight down into an
inter layer, and you would never
see it unless you did some of
the techniques that we're going
to do. Very, very advanced
capabilities, but normally we
look at traditional capabilities
tracer space, 8 mill mechanical
holes and buried vias and they
only connect the layers that
need connected. You can't access
it from the outside. Just
amazing what PC board fab can do
right now. This picture is an
iPhone 4, a cross‑ section of
that. Ten‑ layer board and super
thin. What is it?   .75
millimeters or something. Let me
convert that. 29.5 mills. 29.5,
so 30/1,000 of an inch thick.
Ten layers. I didn't actually
convert that in my head, and I
have notes. Some can do math
really fast, but I can't. Thank
you for joining us. You too,
fellas. Please sit down so I can
continue so you don't interrupt
me anymore. I know them. It's
okay. Yeah, so this type of
board is super complex, and I
use this iPhone board in a lot
of experiments. I wanted to use
kind of traditional standard
board. I did some two‑ layer
boards and cut some six‑ layer
boards and had complete control
over the design on each layer. I
knew the layer spacing, knew
everything about it so I could
kind of validate the success of
the various techniques. Then the
iPhone board is a real world
situation of an actual consumer
product using current state‑ of‑
the‑ art technologies. So I
grabbed a bunch of these things
on eBay that were actually Apple
iPhone knock‑off boards. They
looked grate and there were
noticeable defects and cracks in
them. I couldn't imagine someone
buying an iPhone board on bay  ‑
‑ bay and building it. It was
fun to use this for a hobbyist
board to prove the technique
works for the real deal. So I
mentioned we wanted to try to
get access to the inner layers
or all the layers of the circuit
board. If you do that, if you
can only access, say, the top
and bottom layers, that's still
better than nothing. If you get
all layers of the board, whether
it's a four‑ layer board or
whatever, you can start really
putting together the entire
design. So this thing here, I
show this again at the end of
the presentation with one of our
techniques. This is four layers
of a speech assist board I
designed that is a great
reference, because I know
exactly what it's supposed to
look like. If you also know the
components, almost all of this
stuff except maybe some of the
nondestructive methods assume
there's no components on the
board. If you go through the
process, you make a note of the
components and take them off the
board to actually start
destructively getting down to
the different layers. If you
don't know, then you can re‑
create a whole schematic. It's
like an electronic road map, and
then you totally win. All right.
So the first set of things we
look at is solder mass removal.
This is getting access to the
top and bottom layers, because
those are the only two protected
by the solder mask. Lots of
different layers. You'll see the
mechanical layer that the manual
abrasion and mechanical. We go
through these and see. It's
surprising a lot of stuff you
see the lowest tech ends up
being actually most useful,
which is great for us, because
it's also the cheapest. So what
I'll do is run through a bunch
of these techniques. On the fast
track work, a bunch of stuff
didn't work. I don't have the
times to go through all the
stuff that didn't, so I have one
slide for each section that
didn't. You don't have to fail
the way I did. I tried lots of
stuff. They're will on my
website as of today, so if you
go to grandideasstudios.com. I
have an academic paper published
next week or something, so that
will be what I'm saying here
except written down in like
really nice sentences. That took
a really like time to write.
Sandpaper, everyone has
sandpaper. It seems like an
obvious sort of solution, and it
is. It works great. So this is
something, URN, for this
particular section, and just
sanded it. It worked great. The
one thing to worry about,
though, is you have to make sure
the sandpaper is plain art to
the surface. You want to make
sure you evenly sand, because if
you don't you get wear and sand
down into the substrate and into
the copper and the substrate.
I'll show you that when we do
the delayering stuff. It's using
sandpaper. You can put boards of
the same height of the board
you're sanding to keep things
really level. The effective
lowest cost way to do it.
There's just some results of
that. Different grits. Depending
on the finish, some circuit
boards have gold surface finish
on the pad. Some have a solder
over bare copper where it's like
solder kind of leveled or blown
over the pads. So depending on
the surface finish required for
the board, you might need a
different grit sandpaper. So the
thicker the surface finish, you
may need a stronger sandpaper
first, and you move up to higher
grit to remove the solder mask.
You see on the iPhone board, 400
grit sandpaper, you can wear off
that solder mask, but you don't
wear down the copper at all.
Using a fiberglass scratch
brush, which I hadn't known
anything about before but I
guess they use them for scraping
off rust on metal that you're
working with or cleaning off
different types of parts,
they're great for removing
solder mass. It's better for
selective areas. So say you want
to access a single trace on the
board, that's what the
fiberglass brush is great for
it. You can do a whole board,
but it will take a little while.
Make sure you wear gloves
because it will flake off and
you have tons of splinters all
over your hands and finger and
everything. I posted a picture
of some of those at some point.
One person realized fiberglass
shards are really bad. I'm like,
I know. Thanks for that tip. So
that's a scratch brush.
Sandblasting, you don't normally
associate sandblasting with
circuit boards. I don't. You
sort of associate it with like
building motorcycles or
something like that. Using it
with big pieces of metal. But it
actually works pretty well to
scrape off solder mass coatings.
So I went to a place called
TechShop, which is a fitness
center for nerds or something.
You try to use the machines, but
there's a really, really cool
idea. There's places all over
the country. Different
organizations do the same thing.
I went over there and say, hey,
I'm working on a project. Can I
use your machine. I'm not a
member. I don't want to sign up
for a month to use your machine
for an hour. Can I come in and
stood around for a long time,
and they're like, okay, come in.
I gave the guy 20 bucks so he
can go on his lunch break to do
this stuff for me. It's amazing
what you get when you ask nicely
and hold money up. So this one,
we had to be really careful
because sandblasting is normally
a very PSI, high rate of speed
type of application, so the
operator tried to kind of scale
it back a little bit and be a
little gentle on the board. We
had some pretty massive
failures, but once you got the
technique right, you use the
standard type of sandblasting
machine. We were at a 60 grit
aluminous oxide 80 PSI, and
that's the standard. He had the
best success 6 to 8 inches away
shooting at an angle. This works
really well with standard types
of boards. We put an iPhone in
it, and it got destroyed to
shreds. It was way too fragile.
The standard types of boards,
even two‑layer boards with a
thick substrate seem to work
best. We got noticeable pitting
in the copper, so technically,
so there's no damage in the
copper. For our purposes it
stent matter as long as we get a
good image of the layer, we can
do post‑ processing and clean it
up. They do also make things
that are called micro abrasive
blasting capsules, which are
much smaller for fine detail on
jewelry and things, and that
probably would have been a
better solution. I didn't know
where to get one of those. This
is fun. This is my favorite
part. Making a mess. Oh, wait.
Wrong conference. I mean,
removing solder mask. So these
chemicals, there's lots of
different chemicals out there,
and if you search the Internet,
you have to use the sodium
ethanol meth late to dip it in
the thing and hold it under the
heat lamp and the bunson burner.
They say all this stuff, but I
don't think people actually ever
test the stuff except people
that plow their fingers off. I
was a little wary of stuff I
read on the Internet, and I
think I'm using chemicals
designed for this type of thing.
Luckily, there were chemicals
that exist. There's two
chemicals I looked at that were
actually used by circuit board
fabricators if they mess up the
application of solder mass,
there's a chemical to strip the
solder mass off and they can
redo the process. It sort of
makes sense. I don't think I
have to say how dangerous this
stuff is, but it was really
dangerous. I don't have a fume
hood or anything, like proper
OSHA compliance or anything.
This was in my backyard. I went
to Home Depot, and then I went
on a shopping spree, to the Home
Depot for supplies an electronic
surplus stores for plies. I got
a shopping free to buy all the
stuff. I have a chemical mat, a
mask, respirators, hot plates.
It's not a stir plate. Kind of a
magnet to stick it around or
something. This was a hot plate
I got on eBay, and then the
chemicals and rocks to hold the
thing down. This was in my
backyard, and this particular
house that I lived in was
diagonal to a hotel. With all of
the doors of the rooms facing
down into my backyard, which I'm
sure they loved it when I was in
the hot tub, but this I think
freaked them out a little bit
because people are like, I'm
having a nice vacation in San
Francisco. They look out and
say, what is this guy doing
dressed in a crazy suit? Oh,
yeah, which is  ‑ ‑ yeah. There
are actually was a black car
outside of my house for two days
when I was doing this work. I
shit you not. Who cares. If
Spartanburg sees all the stuff,
I'm doing work for the
government. I have a piece of
paper that says it. They
approved it. I'm allowed to do
it. Nothing happened with it. So
I wore the suit, and it was
funny because with these
chemicals you have to heat them
up to a certain temperature
because that helps with chemical
reactions and all this crazy
mask stuff. So I had this full
chemical suit on. Who took the
picture? It wasn't me. Yeah. So
my wife took the picture. Yeah.
You remember her when she was
pregnant and called my phone in
front of 8,000 people or
something in DEF CON a few years
ago. Yeah, she took the picture,
and half the stuff was like
heating up on the hot plate. She
got really pissed because
apparently it smells bad, but I
didn't know that because I'm
wearing a respirator. She took
the picture and said why are you
wearing the stuff and I'm not
wearing it? She got super  ‑ ‑ I
would swear if  ‑ ‑ I'm not
going to swear, because I'm a
nice person. But she was really
angry and kind of going off like
a trucker. So she ran out and
shut the door and stuff so the
smell wouldn't come in the
house. The fumes actually went
into the house. Next time if I
do this I'll do it further away
from the house or just buy her a
respirator. So yeah, this is  ‑
‑ that was fun. I was really
freaked out. I don't normally
deal with chemicals that much
when I etched circuit boards.
Someone else etched the circuit
boards, but did you dump the
chemicals down the drain? (
Inaudible response  ) >> Yeah,
chemicals, I don't know. They're
very effective, as you see, but
also just really freaky. So it
turns out both of these
chemicals I used. One is a U.S.
company, and neither of them
attack the actual substrate,
which is good for solder mask
removal but not if you trying to
delaminate the board. When you
put the circuit board into the
heated chemical, it just starts
flaking off, which is really
neat. The time depends on the
temperature and the thickness of
the solder mask and things like
that, but the result is super
awesome. Full copper exposed and
no abrasion or anything like
that. Really, really well‑ done.
Then lasers. Lasers. Who here
has a laser? Yeah. A lot of
people, right? They're not
uncommon anymore like a laser
cut other something in the
hacker space. The one I use is a
gigantic one, but it's no
different than - I don't think
it's much different than the
ones you have in hacker spaces
where you're doing laser
engraving on your iPhones or
something. So this one I went to
a company in Milpitas. I wanted
to use the laser and shoot it at
circuit boards is see what
happens. They said that's weird
but sure. I went by. Places are
willing to do interesting
things, because for them I was
talking to the operator, this is
totally fun because we have no
idea what's going to happen, and
it's way better than like  ‑ ‑
way better than what we do day
in and day out. For them it was
something fun. It happened
almost every place I went. It
was kind of fun for the
operators because they didn't
know what to expect. In this
case, who knows. I was worried
we would set the place on fire
or something. (  Inaudible
comment  ) >> All these guys are
wearing. I guess this is like a
‑ ‑ this is like a Defcon
tradition. Thank you, guys. I
love you so much for that. Thank
you. I actually told them before
the talk, nothing is going to
throw me off, not even a giant
dong. You said you weren't
coming on stage. You broke the
rule. Take your mustache down.
Okay. Where were we? Come on.
Take that out of here. Okay. So
the lasers are for cutting
material like flex circuit
boards, the cover layer is for
doing, say, like stencils or
solder stencils for circuit
board. We were just trying to
see, like, could we shine the
laser, and would it get through
solder mask. I went to use them
to see if we can get to inner
layers, which I'll explain later
on. That doesn't really work.
But in this case it did. Like we
just had a single pass of the
laser at medium power. I don't
know what that means, because he
told me there was low, medium
and high. Let's just start with
medium and see what happens. So
we did one at medium power, and
it worked. The more you do it at
medium power or if you had high
power, the more energy you're
shining at the board, eventually
you destroy the board. In our
case if the single pass is fine,
we remove the substrate and very
little damage to the copper or
to the substrate underneath. The
one on the left is from my test
board and one is from annual
iPhone board. This is
interesting, because this
connector that we've exposed is
traditionally under solder mask.
If I look at a board and see
something like that, a connector
under solder mask, I would say,
okay, that's probably like a
programming interface or some
connector used during
development or some test points
the engineer wanted during
development. They cover over
with solder mask after. We use
that as a clue for it. Let's get
access to that. It took about 30
minutes to set up the machine. I
don't know. We were waiting 30
seconds or a minute to do the
passes to expose the solder
mask. If you wanted to do a full
board for that, it will take a
while to do that. Manual methods
seem to work better than the
high tech ones. I tried to use a
knife to run the solder mask
away. There's mechanical
abrasion type of things, and
other chemicals not from the
Internet but things that I
talked to people about.
Different types of heat. Because
on the Internet someone is like,
if you use a heat gun and heat
the solder mask, it's going to
melt. The thing with solder mask
is if it's properly designed,
it's meant to withstand a lot of
heat. So it did its job. So
these are sort of some of the
failures. So the next set is
delayering. This is where things
get more interesting, because we
look at the inner layers itself.
So kind of a manual method and
we have different mechanical
stuff. This is where I started
to learn a lot about the process
as you'll see. So, again,
sandpaper is very effective,
low‑ cost method. I just took
the board, double‑ side taped it
to the work surface. As opposed
to the solder mask, which if you
use sandpaper it comes off fast
in a few minutes maybe. When you
delayer an entire layer of
substrate that could possibly be
40, 50, 60 thousandths thick, it
will take a toll. I don't care
how strong you are. It's going
to hurt. Going to get sweaty. I
know a lot of people don't like.
Instead of just using handheld
sandpaper, you could use a
sanding tool. On the left I have
a sands stone, which is a 60 or
80‑ grit stone with a better
grip on it. I have a Norton
sheet Sander tool, which you
attach it to this thing and go
back and forth. It takes a
while. Here's a little video of
it. Time lapse, of course. So
I'm taking the stone and trying
to get the top copper layer off.
We'll have the substrate, and
then I have to work on the next
layer. So first the sanding
stone, try to use that and sort
of works. We have the sheet
Sander tool and little by little
it comes off. With the solder
mask removal you have to be
careful with the edges of the
board. If you don't sand
straight back and forth you have
the wear along the edges. I show
the result. It looked like it
happened really fast. That was
20 minutes and I was drenched at
the end. Here's the result. We
had a little bit of scratching
of the inner layer and a little
bit of wear around the edge, but
we have basically the second
layer of that four‑ layer board.
So pretty cool, I think. So I
had the second layer exposed and
I was like all right we have the
three layers. I'm not that good
with mechanical things like
tools or anything like that that
has moving parts, so I had a lot
of failures with the Dremel
tools. I damaged a lot of stuff
along the way. This flap wheel,
120‑ grit flat wheel worked
well. You get through that
substrate a lot faster than
manually using a sheet sanding
tool. I don't have a video of
it, because you know what it
looks like when it works. Here's
the result. This is layer three.
I heard someone laughing.
There's something wrong with
this picture, isn't there?
There's a whole corner much
circuit board missing. I
mentioned that. I'm not very
good with this. We works this,
but it works fine. It's really
hard to control the Dremel tool.
When I did that, I was like wait
a second. I do this mechanical
abrasion, and you'll use this
machine to automate the process.
That took me nine minutes, by
the way, with the Dremel tool. I
had a CMC Miling in my office
next door to make circuit boards
because circuit boards are
awesome and you need to make
them all the time, I think. This
is a T-Tech quick circuit 5000
and it's basically just a really
accurate CMC. Did I use a
special one designed for
specifically cutting fiberglass
types of material. So there's a
setup. I have my computer
running the whole show and the
milling machine myself. Fist I
started with the known reference
board, the six‑ layer board
because I knew how much I could
increment each layer before I
would get access to the next
layer. I knew the thickness, so
I used the machine to kind of
route it manually control the
machine and adjusted the access
for the depth to come down and
kind of move the milling machine
back and forth. With this
particular board you can't see
the left image at all or the
right one, really. But the left
one has a bunch of numbers for
the different layers, so layers
1 through VI all numbered. I
went and exposed the numbers so
I could prove I can access
layers 1 through 6. That was no
problem. That was sort of, you
know, a board with very thick
inner layer spacings, so it's
sort of like cheating. I did it
with the iPhone, and I tint want
to manually control it, because
I wanted a precise outline I was
working in. So I created that
inside the tool and adjusted the
z access in 1 mill increments. I
run the rub‑ out of this
particular rectangle and adjust
it and keep running it again and
keep running it until you got  ‑
‑ this is so funny. You're
dirty. So I keep doing the
operation until I could almost
see the copper, and then I would
use a fiberglass scratch brush
to do that really fine removal
of the substrate. There's a
little video. Just doing a
little bit. I don't know how
long this will last, but it's
like taking off a super thin
layer of that substrate. I did
that for a few hours until I got
it right. It actually worked, so
I could see inner layers of that
ten‑ layer iPhone board, which
is seriously complex. If you do
that across multiple sections,
you can reverse engineer the
entire board. If you can do it
on something this complicated
with that technique, you can
pretty much do it on any board
authorized. So last one of
delayering is surface grinding,
this is another one where I do
the Dremel tool and the surface
grinders grind down surfaces to
create nice surfaces and to do
all sorts of crazy metal work.
We have this rotating wheel on
our rotary table, and the table
moves around and the wheel stays
where it is. It's just a very,
very cool thing, but gigantic.
So on the left is a typical
surface grinding machine. I went
to a place in Oakland, and this
is like a straight‑ up metal
shop. I don't think they deal
with computer people, tech
people very often. I called them
and said I want to grind down
some circuit boards. They're
like, yeah, I don't know about
that. I was begging. I heard
that surface grinding would be
awesome, and the one guy I know
in San  Francisco that had a
surface grinder didn't want to
do it. He's like, try these
guys. Try General Grinding. It
was amazing. We did it like
after hours in 8:00 p.m. in the
worth neighborhood in Oakland
where they escorted me to my car
after the work was done, which
was awesome. I can't defend
myself. At least in that
neighborhood. So what we did is
we had this metal block, and the
surface grinders have a magnetic
chuck. So you mount what you're
working with, and usually it's
metal. So it goes not this
magnetic chuck. You can work
with it. The circuit board is
nonferrous, and we put it onto a
block and it would hold it in
place. My machine had give or
take maybe half a million,  .1
mill. give or take, half a mill.
A machine like that size is way
more accurate. Here's a process
with a little dressing of the
wheel. It just comes down and
just grinds the board. It does
this whole process, and it takes
like a 45 second process or so,
and it doesn't look like it's
doing much, but it's shaving a
really thin layer of the board.
You do it over and over again as
we got down, and what you can do
is if you already know the
interlayer board thickness and
do a cross‑ section first and
look at the side with a
magnifying glass, then you can
set it in the machine and you
can automatically do it to that
point where you need it. What we
found is that the surface finish
created by doing this was so
smooth you didn't have to get to
the layer itself. You could  ‑ ‑
as long as you see it through
the substrate, it would polish
is so mush you can see the layer
through it. This is pretty cool,
and a bunch of failures and heat
and laser doesn't work in this
case for delayering because
laser energy affects materials
differently. So if you're trying
to cut through a layer of
substrate, that's going to work
differently than a lay of
copper. If you don't know how
the substrate and copper they're
laid out on the board, you have
a big mess. So for imaging here
we have x‑ray, 2D and 3D.
Everybody here probably had an
x‑ray or knows somebody that
does. What you probably don't
know where to get access to an
x‑ ray on your own. They're used
a lot for failure analysis of
circuit boards and of components
on SISH circuit boards. GUK to a
contract manufacturer and say,
hey, can I use your x‑ ray
machine? They'll say sure.
That's what I did. X‑ rays
shining through it, and then the
object is absorbing radiation
and you'll be able to to see the
results. We only see a composite
image, not individual layers in
this case. Here's what the
machine looks like. Here's a
veriphone pin pad from a pin pad
division with the active circuit
board shield on top of the
circuitry. The 2D x‑ ray isn't
that great because you don't
know which layer things are on.
We can use it to get a general
sense of what's going on. In
this case this active shield had
like four layers of basically a
maze of copper we had to figure
out how to defeat that to get
access underneath. If you have a
simple board, you can adjust the
field of view and angle of the
x‑ ray to trace it out. It gets
very hard. They're that four‑
layer board. So it's already for
certain things, but this is a
real money shot right here, x‑
ray. This blew my mind. This is
the best part of the whole
research. CAT scans where you go
in that machine and it spins
around and you get slices of
your body parts or whatever, you
can do that with circuit boards,
too. Just like there's
manufacturers that have the
normal x‑ray machine, a lot have
the 3D x‑ ray machine. You
basically take a number of 2D
images at different angles
around the object and
mathematically processing that
down into slices. Here's a VGA
solder ball with a defect in it.
Normally these companies look at
small objects or small defects,
so I went in and actually called
the company, which is
recommended by
SonicManufacturing, the
manufacturing that does it's a
2D x‑ ray, and I called the CEO
and it turns out he was in
Germany for a conference. So it
was like 5:00 p.m. my time and
3:00 a.m. his time or something
like that. As soon as I heard
the ring tone change from the
U.S. to the European, I was
like, oh, crap. He answered
phone at 3:00 in the morning. I
woke him up, which is not a good
way to start a relationship. He
was just more than willing to
help. He's like, sure, I get
back tomorrow. Let's set a date
and let's do it. I've never done
it, and let's try it. It was
totally awesome and a big
surprise for everybody there. So
we took 360 different images of
that board, that four‑layer
board, and then once we got
ought all of that data we loaded
it into a manipulation program
for 3D manipulation and moved
through each layer and we could
manually creates a bunch of
JPEGs so we could hit a key and
look through each layer. I don't
remember the actual layer or
slice thickness, but it was
totally amazing. The results
vary based on how many layers
you have, the inner layer of
thickness and what other
materials are used because some
high end boards use very complex
materials. Here's the result of
this CAT scan on our board. So
we're slowing going through each
layer. Layer one is about to
come up. Let's see. There it is.
There's layer 1, and then layer
2 comes up. There's layer 2. We
go through the middle of the
board, the middle substrate,
which is thicker than the
others. Layer 3Coms up fast.
There's 3, and there's 4. So now
nondestructively we can see
through the entire circuit board
without doing anything, which is
awesome. Here's another view of
it. So you'll notice  ‑ ‑
thanks. It wasn't my machine,
but thanks anyway. So you notice
the field of view is small, so
if you do it across a larger
board, you have to do it
multiple times. It took half an
hour to get this done so totally
awesome. We had failures doing
acoustic microscopy that didn't
work at all. In the paper
released next week and in the
presentation, I broke this down
into a characterization.
Depending on how much time and
money you have, likelihood of
success, how much you want to
risk your life, you can look at
the techniques and figure out
which is good for which of your
situations. I like the manual
methods because it's a quick and
dirty thing. The x‑ray was
totally awesome, too. Next
steps. There are some other
methods that people told me
about for delayering using the
key tones to actually strip the
inner layer adhesive, drum
Sander which is like a surface
grinder. What I want to do and
started to work on is a tool to
take all of the layer images I
have gotten through the various
techniques and start a process
to kind of automatically or
assist in reverse engineering
those back into something
meaningful. Take the layers and
do image processing and figure
out connections and possibly
turn that into schematics. Maybe
by next year I have something to
show on that. It's a great
opportunity for me because it's
a lot of software and I'm not
much of a software guy so I have
to learn Python and stuff. It's
like D‑gate, which is a tool for
pattern recognition of silicone,
and then Ron par, which is major
malfunction tool does
recognition as well. Those are
chip level. I want to do
something board level and super
cool. There's the link with all
the materials, but just go to my
website and find it. There we
go. The end. Thanks for coming.
(  Applause  )