[Applause]. Hello everyone I'm
Ryan Lackey and Marc Rogers and
the Grugq not here as you can
see. I think he had severe
traveling difficulties and
there's sketchy details so I'm
not too filled in on it but we
worked with him on this project
for the last year and awhile
have been in contact with him
so... I actually work for Cloud
Farea company that does CDN DDoS
stuff. Marc looks for Look Out.
Working on this as kind of a
side project, a fun thing. The
Grugq is an OpSec consultant and
works on a variety of cool
projects. >> I'm mostly the head
of security here so I apologize
for shouting at you. >> Laughter
>> So we're excited to be here
and show off this cool thing
we've been working on. So we're
going to go over why you want to
hide. We're using software that
will let you hide in network
traffic. We're going over
principles of operational
security which is really Grugq's
main area of study and he's the
pretty much the most interesting
person in the field taking how
larger organizations learn about
op sec and applying it to the
hacker and activist community
and other groups that don't have
a huge intelligence arm or
anything. We will go over
serious op sec fails and what
happens to people then how
technical counter measures are
used against people, existing
tools, travel routers, and how
to use these things for safety
measures of the tools and then
we're going to bring in the
exciting new technology the
travel routers. So, just to
start why would you ever want to
hide? If you're doing normal
stuff we're not talking about
helping people hide from doing
all sorts of bad stuff. You're
in your normal life. There's a
lot of reasons why you would
want to hide. A lot has become
much more clear in the last
couple years. Especially post
Snowden. But even before that it
was fairly widely understood at
least within this community.
Part is to avoid a global drag
net. You want to make sure that
if somebody is monitoring all
the communications that you're
not swept up in that. Because
the problem is, while you might
be doing nothing at all wrong
somebody next to you or somebody
you have a phone call from or in
any loosely connected way might
do something and due to how
software works and scoring that
plus another interaction plus
something else depending on
where you live could actually
get you droned. Not just on a
watch list but signature strike
or something like that. Prevents
all sorts of problems but really
it's like none of your business.
Why would you want to be
monitored? It doesn't benefit
you in any way so if you can
avoid it you should possibly do
it. 	>> There's also the fact
that you are doing something you
don't want people to watch.
Maybe it's illegal, maybe it's
just something you want to
maintain OPSEC for your project,
OPSEC for your company. People
are actively trying to steal
secrets for both national
security reasons and security
reasons and because they want to
steal your secrets. >> And the
crazy thing is people that were
in various illegal activities
knew this and people that were
in the hacker community knew
this but now there's a whole new
realm of people that really need
to worry about this kind of
thing that you would never think
of as spies or hackers.
Journalists giving any kind of
activism in an environment where
their adversaries are well
resourced these people have this
as a serious concern and it's
crazy and it's an asymmetric
problem where there's people
that have problems now and don't
have the resources. >> There's
two important takeaways we get
from this. One number OPSEC not
new. We like to talk about OPSEC
as though it is a new thing that
we've discovered. It's probably
as old as mankind. And many of
the techniques to protect are
just as old. The other one is
the tools and stuff we're
talking about there's no rocket
science here. We are talking
about using exiting tools,
existing technique. [Inaudible].
The difference is we're showing
you how you can use it in a
seamless way so you don't have
to think about it and you avoid
the number 1 problem, human
error. >> So Grugq has sort of
distilled OPSEC basic principles
which are listed here. We're not
going to go over them but he's
done this many, many times and
it's  okay. So Biggy Small
actually had a great song about
how drug dealers apply OPSEC to
selling crack and it's been
analyzed by law professors and
everyone else as pretty good
actionable advice for people
involved in any sort of activity
and it's not just crack dealers
that need these. It's people
involved in complaining about
spying systems being installed
in their loan port system in
Oakland or Human Rights abuses
or really anything. So it's a
pretty universal kind of problem
a lot of people have. But on the
other hand what happens when it
goes wrong? This is a photo from
Somalia where the U.S. Marines
were going in to intervene and
try to distribute aid and food
and stuff and get rid of war
Lord' s. They did this opposed
beach landing which they hadn't
done since Normandy in World War
II but it was a big opposed
beach landing. And unfortunately
the media knew about it in
advance so they were doing this
landing with a bunch of little
rubber boats and everything else
with a bunch of journalists
sitting there with cameras
waiting for them on the beach
putting the things live on
satellite TV that all the war
lards saw. So that could
definitely have gone a lot
worse. And... Yeah. Then we've
got other examples of basic
OPSEC failures bringing down an
organization that many people
think was sort of a libertarian
commercial market. >> When you
look at many of the big busts,
issues that have happened
recently you will see the OPSEC
failures behind them are basic.
Really, really basic. Take for
example Silk Road, the largest
most successful online could not
band, 957,000 user accounts,
9.5 million coins and the guy
behind it allegedly runs over
it. Russ Albrect (sp.) used his
personal Gmail account when
setting up an account that he
then used as the administrator,
an account with Altoid. He then
used that Altoid account to host
jobs, advertise for people to
come in and do coding for Silk
Road related projects. He also
advertised Silk Road using this
same account. He later on kind
of caught up to this and changed
his handle, changed his Gmail
handle to Frosty.com but once
you've opened the door the
information is out there. The
internet doesn't forget. And if
you start then building it all
becomes fruit of the poisonous
tree and everything you do from
that point onwards is tainted.
Next one. Sabu - Even worse.
Sabu, a skilled hacker knew what
he was doing. Except every now
and then he would forget and log
into IRC. Just once is enough in
this day and age. It used to be
you could get away with one
mistake but now in this world
where it's possible for people
to wholesale, capture and store
just in case there's something
interesting that one mistake
will hang you. Perhaps even
worse than that he also used his
home address to use stolen
credit cards to buy car parts
and had them shipped to his home
address. These kinds of OPSEC
failures are really obvious. Not
surprisingly he was busted. Mark
Karpeles, allegedly we don't
know exactly what's going on but
we do know around the time that
they had completely run out of
money there were things he used
to prove that they still had
liquidity. Those accounts are
still around and active. So
people started looking at them
and guess what? You follow the
chain and looked to them, they
still had money in them. Way
more than he allegedly had.
Unsurprisingly when people
started talking about it he
miraculously found another pile
of bit code that he didn't know
about. >> So what are the common
mistakes and vulnerabilities
here? These are just three
examples. There's a bunch more.
Insider threat is the most
difficult to resolve and also
the easiest to find in almost
any organization. People making
mistake, human error and data
leakage. People using the wrong
channels for the wrong kind of
data. Then there's more serious
technical threats. You have
people tearing down either
seizing your hardware or getting
semi rather access or going live
or cold analysis on it. You have
people doing network or RF
monitoring of your systems. You
have people tearing down remote
servers. Then you have acts of
tampering. These are pretty
sheers threats and maybe it's
not worth trying to mitigate the
most difficult thing. Start with
the easy things. Then of course
there's the financial audit
trails left by any system people
interact with. >> One of the
most important things you can't
take care of everything. You
can't think about everything.
But if you can automatically
catch the low hanging fruit and
protect a certain segment of
your stuff that you don't have
to thinking about you can then
focus the rest of your resources
on the more complex problems. >>
So network forensic pretty
widely understood. Metadata of
course being the target of
almost everything. Metadata is
so much easier to process from
the attacker side. They don't
need to bother translating it
into the native language or
normal lies the data. It's there
and automated and trusted and
reliable. So we've seen a lot of
recent attacks where metadata
really was the focus of the
attack. >> And it is very much
the low hanging fruit. As we saw
from the talk that was given.
Even data that you think is
encrypted such as some of your
personal information on the
iPhone is not because when the
device is running certain
segments of device are
unencrypted. That means it's
accessible and in fact the only
time the iPhone is secure is
when it's powered off. >> So
there's all this data you would
attack from a desktop system,
any sort of server you're
attacking. It's pretty clear.
And on cell phones which are
basically computers you have
fairly similar kinds of targets.
They have some additional threat
factors because they connect to
telephone networks and we can
tell you horror stories and the
fact they're with you at all
times and taken out of secure
spaces and taken back into
secure spaces and taken out over
and over again it's a more
interesting threat but it's not
really terribly novel. >> This
is all low hanging fruit. This
is easy stuff that can be
gotten. Almost every cell phone
with commonly available tools
without expending too much
effort. >> All this stuff used
to be hard. People haven't taken
that into account that it's
changed and become a lot easier
to go after. Used to be you had
one agency in the U.S. and one
in the Soviet Union to worry
about. Now pretty much everybody
with RF equipment can be your
threat. Anybody with a network
router in your path can be your
threat. Anybody running a
service can be a threat. Anybody
that gets access to your
equipment. So it's a much, much
wider population of people
tracking you. If you're not
attractive to the government as
a target, perhaps you are to a
different government or to an
individual or organization. It's
really the democrazation of
SIGNIT and attacks. >> One
interesting thing from the slide
is everyone is talking about
Snowden and how everyone is
moving to more encrypted. It has
had an effect on the traffic on
the internet. We've gone from in
the U.S. 2.2% was deemed to be
SSL traffic. Today it's 3.8.
That's a really big increase.
Right? >> A lot of that traffic
is unencrypted which leaves all
this data available. Even if the
data is encrypted you can get a
lot of information from pure
traffic analysis. You can see
source and destination of
target. You can see the type of
traffic in a flow and you can
actually in a lot of cases get
content information from the
size of packets because it's not
data dependent and it's pretty
terrifying. >> What you have to
realize is you don't have
control over this. Vast majority
of this traffic is backend
traffic. This is your
application talking to
application server. You don't
have a choice to say I'll only
use encryption to the dev that
built your app. >> It's pretty
bad when you pop up a commercial
operating system on a new
computer the first time and has
all this software you're not
familiar with and you don't
really know what's phoning home
when. Cell phones are even
scarier because you actually do
have pretty good information
that they're phoning home all
the time. They're always in
contact with the tower and
they're relaying an awful lot of
information you don't really see
as a user but it's there and is
a threat. And the scary thing is
while you might trust your
operator and you might trust
your phone vendor over the air a
lot of this data can be gathered
just from passive monitoring and
anybody else over the air can do
a lot of the stuff. Then we've
got examples of when you travel
to places like China. It's a
great place to visit but they
have a fairly restrictive
international firewall. The
great firewall and you don't
really know where  it's not
really one firewall. It's
different in every province and
different operators have
different policies but in
addition to being monitored
there's just a basic problem of
stuff is blocked and it's really
annoying when you go and you
want to connect to your
services. You want to basically
operate like you would at home.
You would think just a VPN would
protect you and allow you to
bypass this stuff but it's like
a whack a mole game they play
where they block things all the
time, it's a pain to deal with.
>> One last thing on the Chinese
firewall they are getting smart
on how they look out for VPN's.
Before it was identification VPN
end points, then they get
blocked. Now as we see with Tor
since 2011 they're actively
scanning suspected nodes and
they're doing things like
talking Tor to suspected nodes
and they can block it. Now that
makes it real difficult, now you
have folks who are actively
looking for your all your tools
and blocking. So whatever you
have to do has to be robust
enough to protect it. >> So
there are a bunch of tools
people use to protect
themselves. Basic principles
that make certain tools easier
to use and more privacy
protecting than others. Tools
generally are tools used by
smaller communities rather than
a wider tool are going more
likely to work in a given
scenario. Although there's an
engineering quality issue of a
tool not used by many users
generally not of high quality.
Generally I like things that
aren't realtime, things
asynchronous like email based
systems, rather than connection
oriented systems. However we
really moved to the World Wide
Web and everybody was connection
based systems. And then
encryption even if it doesn't
provide you with full protection
it provides with you a little
bit of contact protection in a
lot of cases even if it's not
implemented fully. So if you
have the choice always add
encryption. And there's a lot of
common tools that can be
reconfigured. VPN's were never
intended as an anonymity
technology, it just happened to
be useful in certain
circumstances. They do provide
some privacy and some firewall
busting just because people
don't want to block all VPNs
because it will block a lot of
business traffic. It's an
interesting thing. And then the
really interesting thing is that
cheap hardware has gotten so
cheap that you can dedicate
hardware to a certain task. It's
hard to build a secure multiuser
multiapplication operating
system. It's really much simpler
challenge to build a single
purpose device and dedicate it
to a certain thing. >> Before we
move off of VPN's one amusing
thing came up in our discovery
as we were playing around. We
discovered that you can actually
weaponize it - great firewall
works and detects a node doing
something it doesn't like it
floods it with reset packets.
And it's not really doing much
to validate the source address
so...  [Laughing]. It's also
quite nice it floods it with
reset packets for sometimes up
to 30 seconds. So it's an
amplifier. So oh I was just
playing around like I mentioned
and I watched as the great
firewall flooded him for the
next couple of hours. And he
couldn't do anything.
[Applause]. >> I think not
demoing that live on the stage
is a good idea. >> Although,I
highly advocate doing this. But
carefully. >> So yeah we've got
things  the other thing is Java
script. You have to have a
separation between your data and
code, bad things happen with
that and when the addressing
information is completed with
the messages so the OSI stack
isn't kept as separate as it
should be or where code is mixed
with data this leads to bad
stuff. As we said cheap hardware
is great. Prevents a lot of user
errors. The problem with a lot
of these secure systems is users
use them incorrectly and if you
give somebody a single device
and say that's to talk to go one
other person it's a much easier
user model then you need to
enter in code every time you use
it and authenticate them and do
all sorts of other stuff. >> A
great real life example of this
literally yesterday as part of
my goon job, I had to provide
protection for John Mc. We were
walking around with John who is
a colorful character. With his
security detail who are even
more colorful. Especially the
one who remembers faces. And he
is talking about security of his
phone. He said he always uses
burner phones, I'm very careful.
Once I used a phone for a
certain amount of time I attach
it to a (Unknown) and it goes
off all around the country and
they can follow that and they
always track me down within a
couple days and they can follow
me. I had a chance and I said by
any chance do you regularly call
the same kinds of numbers. He
said yes. That would be why. It
doesn't matter if you're
changing your phone if you keep
calling your mom. >> So one of
the issues is again if you go
buy this hardware and order,
this whole problem if you order
hardware if you're receiving it
internationally, say you're the
Grugg, it's going to be high
that, that hardware will not
come as the hardware vendor
intended it and you probably
want to start buying stuff off
the shelf that's preconfigured
or sort of a commodity thing.
It's unlikely they will back
door every hardware but the one
piece of hardware that Grugg
orders that could very likely be
back doored and cash is great.
[Indiscernible]. And the same
thing applied to accounts. So
VPN's are sort of near and dear
to my heart. I ran a VPN
provider for a year. Then we
shut it down when the
(indiscernible) happened.
They're definitely a useful
tool. There are some concerns.
They're not really designed for
anonymity so they don't give it.
You have to use them correctly
for stuff like that. Of course
there's the problem if you trust
the operator of service to one
operating in a certain way. And
two it's really, really a bad
idea to expect a third party to
break the law on your behalf for
like $3 a month. It's not going
to happen. So you will have data
turned over. The third party
doctrine in the U.S. means a
third party has little tool
protect their customer data if
it's sought by another customer.
Tor is a great tool. It can keep
you anonymous. I believe Snowden
has it's endorsed, others have
endorsed it. It has a
recognizable signature, high
profile. Lots of people looking
for it. And it's pretty
complicated and not really so
simple for users to understand.
So you have to build systems on
top of it to make it useable.
Tor browser, bundle, are great,
but you pretty much need
additional tools to make it a
useful tool. However it's gotten
myself. If you try to use it in
like China they're getting
better and better at if it's the
default Tor protocal blocking
it. D packet inspection can
block it and of course if you
have exfiltrated data network
that logs everything there might
be a human analyst and the
traffic will be obvious so
whoever sent the tour
traffic... So people realize
this is a problem and there's
transports which are great
tools. There's 7 alive. Think is
still accurate and there's a
couple much more popular than
the others. >> The benefit of
the Tor transports is they're
recognized there is no one tool
that will solve the problem.
There's no silver bullet.
Whatever solution you use needs
to be variable because if you
keep doing the same thing
eventually someone will catch on
to it. Plus you will get some
real genius and some of these
travel transports are
phenomenal. The general concept
of this is transform traffic so
it doesn't look like it and the
next level is take the traffic
and make it look like some other
form of traffic. >> I will go
through this really quickly. A
lot of the censorship tools out
there are quite crude. What they
do is use regular expressions to
look at the protocol and make
judgments as to what they think
it is. If you use those same
expressions yourself you can
play to them and make your
traffic look like whatever you
want. The screen here is
transformed traffic that has
been put through a transform
that makes I look like an SSH.
While it won't stand up to
immediate scrutiny. The point is
with this vast volume of traffic
going through the only people
who will get that special extra
special scrutiny are people that
popped the red flag. This is
about not popping up the red
flag. So if your traffic hides
amongst the general Tor traffic,
there's going to be no reason
for them to dive deep enough for
them to say this is suspicious.
>> And there's an additional
tool, where if you have a
cooperating end point on the
other end, you can actually,
like Google App Engine, I've
talked about this with Cloud
Flare. Various providers, you
can encode your traffic as
normal HTTP traffic, put it
inside HTTPS, you can make it
look like it's going to a
regular website and do cool
stuff there so... Then I guess
the ultimate thing is to make it
look like natural language.
Banana phone does this.
Obviously it won't stand up to a
human analyst looking at this
after the fact. If you aren't
routinely sending literature
back and forth to someone but
you can imagine a scenario where
there's an automated or you
built a system on top of that.
And there's of course the
classic network tools that are
primarily used for getting
around like captive portal,
authentication systems where DSL
huddle, at a hotel such as the
Rio and these are pretty cool.
>> The point of going through
these is these are the tools we
looked at for building the
travel router. The travel router
itself there really isn't that
much to it. We looked at all the
best tools out there and built
them into this as a library so
you have an OS build that's
going to sit on a device. You
can carry it anywhere. It's tiny
and all these things will be
available to you to choose. And
we're hoping to build some
intelligence on to it as well so
it makes choices for you to say
are you sure you wanted to
select that? That might not be
the best thing here. >> There's
not silver bullet so it's a
bunch of separate tools
combined, So as we were thinking
of this, we tried to figure out
because we had the practical
concern we travel a lot and go
to places and we're not the most
interesting targets. I know a
lot of people that are greater
targets and it's really
difficult I can build something
I can use myself mostly out of
existing software. But building
something I can have somebody
else use that's easy for them to
use, simple that I don't have to
then go with them all the time
is a much harder problem. We
looked at a lot of VM systems.
VMs are great, but the problem
is, if something gets subverted
the top level operating system
there's problems. Fingerprinting
stays the same then there's
really no way to know that the
system is intac. I work with TPM
and it's still not quite there.
And the other problem is this
stuff is expensive if you build
is out of pure software on
dedicated high end laptops,
virtualization with bunch of 16
giga ram Mac Book Pros, you
can't afford it. Most of the
people really that need this
stuff are also people that are
not rich. They're also not
willing to throw away a
3,000dollar laptop. So it wasn't
really the most ideal target. So
we looked at something that
would be providing much of the
same protection but be a lot
cheaper a lot easier to support.
Ideally something people already
have to use and we came up with
a secured travel router being
the sweet spot. They're pretty
awesome. They're , I have a
whole box of them. They'are
about $20-100 each. They are
about made by a bunch of
vendors, TP Link, Linksys,
DLink. All the low end network
companies make this stuff.
They're available everywhere.
But a lot of people use them
when you go to a hotel and you
have to pay per WiFi device this
lets you share a wired
connection in a hotel with a lot
of a lot of connections. There's
a lot of really cool stuff you
can do, but they weren't
explored as a security tool very
much. >> One of the problems we
have is the hardware is
variable. So some of them have
flash memory, some have no flash
memory. So the code, we, the
next version is going to have
another kitchen tool and what
you'll do is put in the version
of travel router you're working
with, how much resources it has
and it will can look it up in
the library and it will tell you
which modules you can then
select. So you can have Tor plus
these transforms and if you
don't have secure voice you can
have these other things added in
just enough to squeeze it in
without filling it up. >> We've
used a lot on that. There's a
lot of open source firmware. I
think the 54D was the grand
daddy where it came with crappy
firmware. Fortunately wireless
hardware has moved on to newer
stuff. That whole wireless
hacking community has been going
on for a while. The EFF started
working on a project to make
secure routers for home use.
Primarily focused on protecting
them from outside threats as
opposed to using them for
security tools themselves and
that's a huge improvement over
the status quo even a year ago.
The problem with these things is
they're embedded systems like a
billion different ones of them.
They're too weak and it's a
pain. It's not a huge pain like
dealing with true very minimal
resources embedded stuff but
still not the easiest thing to
use. Other people worked on this
before. There's a safe plug
which is cool. They have 4. They
don't do pluggable transports.
It's more for home use. Onion
pie which another company has is
like a learn how to do something
project. It uses a device,
raspberry pie and has external
hardware and I have been looking
at this stuff individually and
he talked to Grugq and I
realized the guy that was
working on it I talked to so it
was an obvious thing to do. >>
There is only one Grugq. >> It's
not that rare of a name. So we
worked on this. The original
portal from a couple years ago
have pluggable transports but it
was a pain to install. And it
did a lot of stuff but it wasn't
like an all in one thing. So out
of this full range of hardware
we needed to come up with an
initial piece that we needed to
support. It was awesome but the
problem is  it's an awesome
piece of hardware. We wanted to
have a prebuilt image with
multiple ports and wanted to
power off the USB because you
can use USB batteries and power
off your lap top and you can use
the Nexis7 or cell phone and you
want your mobile phone to talk
to this device which has a WiFi
connection or a 3G connection
plugged into it. So having
something that can be battery
powered is great but putting a
battery in a small cheap device
is more of a consumer
engineering challenge. So we're
not all hardware guys so we try
to make it as simple as
possible. And obviously needs to
be easy to use. But there's some
problems. A lot of the hardware
is designed to be as cheap as
possible when you make it in
like million unit quantities.
The price difference between
like 64mg chip is snacks the
quantities so they put the
minimum on a ram, absolute
tiniest flash they can do and we
wanted to have multiple radios
and Ethernet. It wasn't really a
common use. The other problem is
we're in the middle and USB2 is
still the most wide spread power
protocol we can use so we're
limited to 500 milliamps.
Quality is really, really bad.
They're using antennas and then
we wanted to make it ourselves
but making quantity like a
thousand  making quantities is
easy because you can make it
yourself. Making a hundred
thousand or a million of
something is also fairly easy
because you can justify
amortizing your debt costs but
making a thousand of them or
5,000 is still a pain point. And
we looked at the cost of making
them and you can buy the travel
routers for a hundred bucks, $20
or whatever. For us to make a
small quantity would be really
expensive and if we make the
special secret spy router, one
we have to distribute it to the
people that want it and it's
suspicious. So the guy carrying
around the super secret spy
device will get special
attention and that's the last
thing you want in any of the
states. So we were kind of  >>
Speaking of someone who gets
special attention every time he
goes to the airport I can tell
you it's a real drag. >> So we
really had no idea I've been
working on this as a hardware
thing and ended up selling. I
was looking at doing something
and I ended up selling my
company instead. So it was like
a back burner thing then I was
like oh what are we going to do.
Then we were saved by China.
There's apparently a company in
China that makes the perfect
device. It appears to be a clone
of a much more popular device
but it happens to have a huge
amount of ram and rom and
they're really cheap. It's this
box, the good life GLI net box.
You can buy them for about $215
for 10 of them. You get them in
3 days. They're awesome. It does
everything you want. It's pretty
much the perfect packing
platform for this kind of
hardware. It's got two ethernet
ports on it, USB and micro spkr
power. It's a pretty good deal,
and the RAM that we need. So we
have portal.com, we have tools
loading up there that will let
you use the old portal chain and
additional pluggable transports
on it. Building the service is
maybe a little ambitious at this
point but definitely the client
side of the hardware will work
with existing services. >>
That's it. >> We would actually
like questions at this point. It
would be great to talk to
people. >> Obviously we welcome
a ton of feedback because we
want to shape this into a tool
that's genuinely useable. This
is no good if it's hard to work
with, it doesn't quite meet all
the cases. We want this to be
the kind of thing you put in
your pocket and a journalist can
take and go to a foreign country
and use it for secure coms
without even thinking about it.
Thank you. >> Open source of
course not commercial.
[Applause]. >> If anyone has
questions we'll be happy to
answer them.