>>This is KAREN. I'm still a
little tired. So without further
adieu we'll get into the talk.
>>	Hopefully you can hear me
okay like this. How are you guys
doing? Having a good DEF CON?
Welcome to Sunday afternoon|
track one, also known as the
after party track seeing that
everybody has had a pretty wild
weekend. I guess you guys might
be hung over. But let me ask
you, how many of you are here at
DEF CON for the first time? That
is a lot of you guys. Give
yourself a hand. You made it.
You are no longer DEF CON
virgins. All right! And the
reason I bring that up is
because this is actually my
first time speaking at DEF CON.
And I am extremely excited and a
little bit nervous to be to be
honest, to be with you here. But
the reason I'm here is because I
honestly deeply and firmly
believe that hackers can have a
positive impact on the world. We
can actually save the world for
generations to come. Now, I know
that sounds like a tall order,
but I'm going to take you
through it SXISHGS hope by the
end, we'll make true BLOOEFRNs
out of you. My name is KEVIN....
For those of you who find it
difficult, you can find me
online as Karen E. Or also known
as special K in certain circles.
So let's get the show on the
road. A little bit about myself,
I've been in the security
industry for almost 15  years
now. I've worked with a bunch of
fortune 500 companies,
consulting firms, government
agencies, think tanks, academic
organizations. All across the
board. Security operation,
product management, intelligent
work, but that's not why I'm
here today. I'm also on the
advisory board of a pretty cool
crypto currency (indiscernible)
five. For those of you know
crypto no, ma'am son. Yes the
company is named after the one
in the book. Thank you. But
again, that's not why I'm here
today. Actually, this woman is
the reason I'm here today. So
that is Angelina Jolie right?
She portrayed acid burn in the
95 film hackers. I was 14 at
that time. And I can see you
doing the math trying to figure
out my age. I'm 33 now. So, I'm
going to save you the trouble.
It's Sunday. When I saw this
movie, I instantly realized that
all this stuff that I like doing
was actually called being a
hacker. And it's a thing. And
girls can do it too. And hackers
can be heros if they want to, so
that is why I'm here. Now I have
another confession to make. Like
I told you, this is my first
time speaking in DEF CON. I've
always wanted to speak here and
I've actually been submitting
talks for years and I could
never get in. So then last year,
something exceptional happened
to me. I was invited to speak at
the little place call Ted's.
Those of you who are not
familiar with the concept, it's
a pretty high profile media
conference where they also film
the talk and put them online and
then millions of people watch
them. Naturally I freaked out. I
was also certain that I might
get hacked for giving a talk
about hackers. But then
thankfully, I learned that ran
dell from (indiscernible) was
also going to be there. I so I
was relieved. I thought
everybody was going to pay
attention to his comments and
cool stuff and not notice me. I
also realized it was a once in a
lifetime opportunity to use the
(indiscernible) platform to hack
into people's minds. To get them
to change the way they see
hackers. The way they think
about us, about this community
that I've been a part of that I
believe can do positive things.
So in order to make that change
happen, I created a virus. A
mental virus. An idea that would
stick with people as they
watched the talk and hopefully
would propagate and spread on
ward. And that ideal was hackers
are a vital part of the world.
That we are actually kind of
like the immune system for the
information age. And that it
falls to us to find the
vulnerabilities and force the
world to fix them. Now I didn't
know how well this message might
come across and I am humbled and
overwhelmed and excited  ‑ ‑ I
think the virus worked. Because
almost 800,000 people watched it
shared it. And so apparently,
outside of this conference,
outside of this community, there
is a willing audience ready to
start looking at hackers
differently. Expecting us to
start being those heros. And so
it's time for me to be here and
come full circle with you guys
and tell you about how we can be
those heros and how we can make
that change happen. Now I'm not
a futurist, but I can offer one
prediction with regards to the
technology of future and cyber
space. We don't know what's
coming around the corner.
Technology's changing so fast.
But if we leave our digital
future, our civilian and
government infrastructure, if we
leave all of the technologies we
rely on solely in the hands of
governments and multinational
corporates, guess what guys,
they will mess it up. Now we can
argue about the degree and
measure of failure that is going
to happen. But based on past
experience, there is no reason
to expect things to be
different, especially with the
way certain governments are
looking at cyber space. So I
think now is the time, now is
the transformative time in
history of technology and it's
the time for hackers to start
making that kind of impact. But
in order to make that happen, we
have to make a choice. We have
to decide that we are willing to
be part of the solution and not
part of the problem. So today,
in order to make it easy for you
to make the choice, I'm going to
walk you through some of what I
think are the biggest thorniest,
hairiest problems and why I
think it does fall to hackers to
fix these and we can't leave it
in the hands of government. Now
let's start with what is perhaps
the chunkiest problem of them
all. That is the cyber problem.
I know cyber's been, they lose
it to a drinking game. And I
will happily have a drink later,
but I think there is a good
reason to talk about securing
cyber space. And not just
information space, or
information policy. And in fact
I will also buy a drink to
anyone who can tell me right now
where the word cyber, or the
prefix cyber, not the noun, not
the verb, but the prefix cyber,
where does that come from? Raise
a hand anyone? Yes?
>>	(Inaudible). >>	Yes you are
correct ma'am, in fact. Very
nice, I will buy you a drink
later. The lady mentioned it has
to do with a Greek origin. Let
me give you kind of short
history lesson about that. This
guy, professor nor bit weaner,
that's his real name. He's a
man  ‑ ‑ he was a math professor
here in the United States. And
in 1948, he developed a new
scientific discipline called
cybernetics. He came up with
after he saw in World War II
what new remote command
communication and consulting
technologies were doing. How
radio has been transforming the
(inaudible). How the new concept
of digital computers is
influencing signal intelligence.
And how new technologies out
into the world are making a
transformative change. So to
(indiscernible) all of these
different control and
communication systems in the
animal in the machine, that's
the name of his book, he used
the term cybernetics. He didn't
even know the type of
technologies they have right
now. But he did boar refrom the
ancient Greeks and rather for
their term, for the guy running
the boat, the (indiscernible)
commanding controlling, and
communicating orders. That guy
is maybe called in English a
captain, but in Greek, it is
called the (speaking another
language.) And that is the
source for cyber. And actually
my home language of Hebrew, we
still call the captain of a
boat, also the guy running the
country (speaking another
language.). it comes from the
same origin. We can make fun of
cyber and whether it's a
relative term or not, but
cybernetics technologies
controlling and commanding
stuff, this is how allow human
kind to have freaking laser
shooting robots running around
on Mars. But also tweeting
about. This is all apart of the
same problem space and I think
this asterisks describes
securing these technologies as
cyber security. In the past 25
years, these have been the
software environment, an IT
ecosystems where most
vulnerabilities were being
(inaudible). This is a top ten
organization and software
environment and have the most
vulnerability TS according to
force fire. 25  years of
vulnerability report. That's
been our history. But the future
of our (inaudible) is not going
to be about information
technology. It's going to be
about new devices, device  ‑ ‑
not PCs, not web servers.
Devices, watches, ATMs,
(indiscernible) cars, that are
running these vulnerable
software. And it's also going to
be about all of this other
stuff. Radio frequency and
global (indiscernible) systems.
And aircraft control. So this is
a lot of different technologies
coming together. The same stuff
that allows the university of
Texas hackers to hijack the
course of an $18  million yacht
by changing the signalling of
the position information that
they were getting, by sending
out positioning signal that was
stronger than the one that was
on the boat. They tricked the
actual (indiscernible) man, the
actual (speaking another
language.) Of the boat and sent
it going someplace else. It's
the same stuff having setting
people take control of
instruments. And yeah, cyber
security is also about
protecting a blue tooth enabled
toilet. So you know what guys,
there is not one single
government vendor or any entity
that's secure all of this stuff.
It's a complicated problem. But
not only that, a lot of these
vendors and governments are like
new shifts have come to life,
man. And we have got to stop and
wrap our minds around this
complicated boggle. And they are
somewhat correct, but you know
what else? Some of this is old
shit connected in a new way. And
the only reason it is coming to
light in the first place is
because hackers are exposing it
and showing those
vulnerabilities. So to quote to
late barn bee jack, sometimes it
just falls to us to demonstrate
the threat so we can spark the
solution. And I wholeheartedly
agree. I think we have to keep
looking at these new
technologies. Because there is
no better (indiscernible) than
the light of day. If the hacker
community makes the point of
researching vulnerable
technologies, whether they are
blue tooth enabled toilets,
smart homes, cars, medical
device, we will make some change
happen. And it is going to take
a bottom up approach. Not a top
down solution created by one
company or regulator or one
government. You got to research
what matters in the worlds of
josh and Nick from
(indiscernible). Just one years
ago they showed I think in this
very room, in fact,
(indiscernible) Sunday right?
Telling hackers about why we
have to start focussing our
research and efforts,
researching technologies that
matter for protecting human life
and public safety. And
yesterday, after a year of
activities, they showed the
progress they have made. With
research in medical device
security, automotive secure,
smart homes and infrastructures.
And I encourage you to check
them out and see what they're up
to. But that's not the only way
you can make a difference. There
are many different ways. And I'm
going to go into that in a
second. I think I have to make a
quick stop now. Hi guys. So umm,
I have a nice life over there.
No ice for me. Another way to
contribute and make positive
things happen, ooh wow, that's
nice. So, this is a bottle of
12‑ year‑ old (indiscernible)
whisky I believe. Thank you.
(Applause.) >>	'Cause that's how
she rolls. >>	True that, I kind
of make a point mentioning to
them I am a single malt girl and
I will not drink bourbon
Tennessee, other types of
whisky. So building securely is
a project  ‑ ‑   ‑ ‑ to offer
internet of things security for
people that are developing
(inaudible) project. So it's an
easy way if you're interested in
some things, it's an easy way to
get information project. And
before I move on to the next
one, thank you so much. >>	It's
really hard to get accepted to
give a talk at DEF CON. Let's
give a big round of applause for
our speaker. Show the love.
(Applause.) Cheers cheers.
>>	Thank you so much. >>	Thank
you. >>	(Speaking
simultaneously). >>	I'll check
in later then. >>	Okay. Thanks.
Cheers. Thank you guys. I
appreciated that I got a glass
right. >>	(Inaudible) long talk.
>>	The reason I only drink
single malt WIS key in a real
glass is because you know, it's
spent 15  years in a barrel and
then some time in a bottle, I
just can't bare to put it in a
plastic disposable cup. You know
what I mean? All right, on with
the show. So the plot thickens.
Even with the best intentions in
mind, those governments and
vendors are not going to be able
to solve the problem. But guess
what, some of them don't have
the best intentions in mind. In
fact, there are huge resources
at work actually keeping the
world vulnerable. In the past
year, we've all been perhaps
shocked to learn exactly how
much money the NSA has been
spending on buying a our
vulnerabilities. Then we learned
they even went as far as to pay
a security company to include
the deliberately weak random
number generator and make it a
default in one of their core
(indiscernible) qualities. Now a
few months ago, as the openness
vulnerability became known to
the President Clinton, it was
also alleged that the NSA has
knowledge of this and expected
it for years. Now that might not
be true, but it is safe to
assume that similar things have
been going on. And so there is a
little bit of a paradox at play
here. Because security agencies,
security agencies have been
making the world deliberately
insecure. And that's part of the
problem we have got to be
facing. What's really making my
own heart plead if you don't
mine, is STOIry stories like
this. Cover of time magazine
last month. You probably
haven't, but you've seen the
headline. It says World War 0.
The global battle to steel your
secret is turning hackers into
armed dealers. Get it guys. We
are the armed dealers. Not the
government agencies. Not the
vendors, not the companies
selling 0 data to the highest
bidder. This really does break
my heart. Because I think a
small group of people making a
profit by selling 0  days is
painting all of us in a bad
life. So what's the solution to
this? How can you avoid being
the armed dealers. I think we
can start by not keeping our
(indiscernible)s to ourself. Tip
ST scale and disrupt the 0  days
on vulnerability market. Yes
there will always be 0  days.
‑ ‑ before the bad guys do,
we're going to make their life
harder. And in fact, the reality
is, never before have there been
so many different avenues for
hackers to disclose bugs and
didn't get paid for them. We all
know about bug bounty programs
like competitions like
(indiscernible) to own. There
are literally dozens if not
hundreds of bug bounty programs
out there by specific vendors. I
think that's a fantastic thing.
It's transformation in our
industry. There's also the
internet bug bounty project
started by (indiscernible) first
and hacker one. That is a great
avenue. Hi. Casey's right there
by the way. Give her hand.
(Applause.) So things like the
internet bug bounty is this
fantastic way to have an
incentive  ‑ ‑   ‑ ‑ that are
maybe open source or not managed
by specific vendor and still get
paid. And I think that's great.
Google's announcement of project
0 also give us some room for
hope. But again, the plot
thickens, and it will need our
help. There are a lot of
companies and organizations that
do not have bug bounty programs.
That do not have disclosure
policies. And the reason they
can do that because they can
afford not to have that. They
can sweep up the bugs under the
carpet or ignore them or pay a
little  ‑ ‑ or pay a lot to
those companies selling the bugs
quietly and never fix them. So
we have to work that much
harder. We have researching
vulnerability disclosing them.
And make it so these companies
and organizations cannot afford
not to have a disclosure policy
in place. Or a bug bounty
program. Again, there is no
(indiscernible) infection than
the light of day. And it is
going to take a bottom's up
approach. When I say bottoms
up... (Applause.) So we don't
have to be polite about
disclosing vulnerabilities. We
can start polite, but if they
don't listen  ‑ ‑ database. But
I see some of the faces here in
the audience are still kind of
like this. Not convinced are
you? Why should you care right?
Just security professionals, you
want to protect your own little
piece of heaven from all the bad
stuff out there. You want to be
doing your stuff and not let all
the bad stuff touch you. Well I
want to tell you two more
reasons, two more problems why
ink each of us as a security
professional needs to care about
securing cyber space as a whole,
a big problem space of all
technologies. The first reason,
which is burden overall, we are
only as weak as our weakest
link. That's not a mistake.
We're not as strong as our
weakest link, we're as weak as
our weakest link. In the past
year, we learned you could be a
retailer have a multimillion
dollar security program in
place, you will still get
(indiscernible) because you're
lame as  ‑ ‑ out of bumps
wherever, didn't bother to put
antivirus in place. You can be
one of the world's leading
security companies and develop
the cutting edge one time pass
ward security (indiscernible)
mechanism. All it takes is one
e‑ mail, one spear fishing e‑
mail to your parent company with
one slash vulnerability embedded
in an excel file. Not X files. I
was a fan you know, so. Still
waiting for MULDer. Anyway. This
is all it takes to implicate
that multiple dollar security
company in the fact that the J
22 model out of change due china
looks a lot like the F 35 model
made by Lockheed Martin. And so,
it might be a question of time
before one of your providers,
your partners, your customers,
your employees, will mess it up.
And get you owned in the
process. So you have to care
about the security of other
organizations and people you are
in touch with. But this problem
also has another aspect to it.
And that is everybody's actually
on the front line. Guess what,
there are no fierce cyber
warrior defending the perimeter.
Because there's no perimeter. We
are all civilians in the cyber
space and using the same
infrastructure. YOUN those
people who say why should I
bother to secure my Facebook
account. If you're not part of
the solution, you are part of
the problem. These are exactly
the people and organizations and
companies that don't bother
enough and then their resources,
their digital assets, their
cloud and social media profiles
and e‑ mail systems become just
a launching bad for the next
effect on you. Now I'd like to
move on because I think if we
don't take the time to solve
this problem, then we are all
going to be part of a bot net or
our machines are going to be
part of fishing campaigns. We
all heard about these problems.
They're pervasive. So what can
we do faced with a complicated
nature of this problem? You
could always join the Amish.
That might work for some people.
But that's (indiscernible)
bones. Yeah, they now have smart
phones as well. That's a good
point. So maybe the Amish are
not that safe anymore. Perhaps
another approach then might be
to start working together. To
start collaborating and not
being shy about saying how
exactly we were breeched and
what were our problem. Reaching
out of your industry, your
sector, your community, there
are so many information sharing
programs, so many ways to share
this technical and practical
information about, how you got
own so the next guy doesn't. ‑ ‑
I'm saying you should be doing
this, collaborating and sharing
information because you're going
to be a text next. And you're
not knowing the malware is
coming at you unless you talk to
your partners and competitors at
times. But where we are going to
get I think the most bang for
the buck as it were, is by
empowering the mass  ‑ ‑ the
shiny happy people that don't
think they have anything to
hide. Nobody's looking at them,
but nobody's interested in the
device of their machine, the
credentials et cetera. These are
the people we have to start
talking to. And there are
various ways to make that
happen. One thing I like is
crystal parties. These have been
hugely popular in Europe and
Germany. And there's a wiki and
how to to throw a crypto party
in your home down. It's a
community event where you teach
basic security, privacy and
cryptography measures to regular
people. But you don't just teach
them, you actually configure the
stuff on their devices. So maybe
they can learn how to use PGP. I
know it's a bit hard. And other
ways to be supportive is policy
organization that changing
public opinion by raising
awareness but also challenging
and renegotiating the terms of
engagement with government
civilians and the technologies
in between. Now I'd like to tell
you about something pretty cool
that we actually did back home.
Which is a little bit out of the
box I think. We called it red
cyber team. And this is one of
the group of volunteers. Maybe
one of them is even here today.
(Indiscernible) you around? All
right. He's hiding. So this was
a group of volunteers. People
who are (indiscernible)s and in
their day job, they do security
assessment. They brought
themselves together, and in the
course of a few afternoons,
maybe a month or two, they
visited a local hospital outside
tell VOOEF. That didn't really
have budget or awareness or
security issues at all. After
they went in is and show it had
hospital management exactly what
they could do, that turned
things around and that got that
organization to pay attention to
security. They did follow a code
of ethics when they did what
they the did. In the end, they
only got a (indiscernible) hat
and the fit feeling that they
did something good. I'd like to
offer you a way to own some
bonus points if it were in the
effort to make the world a
better place. I know that sounds
kind of corny. Sisco estimates
that we're going to need one
million more security
professionals in the coming
year. Now, it's time we started
procreating. It's time that we,
as a industry, yeah right? It's
time that we as an industry
begin propagating and making
more supported specialists out
there. You can do this by
reaching out to someone.
Creating a mentor.   ‑ ‑   ‑ ‑
company or organization by
talking to people. Something I
do a lot is go speak with
computer science and engineering
students in high schools and
colleges. And I just tell them
what they can do in the cyber
security industry. And they seem
pretty excited. And I hope many
of them become security
professionals. Now you cannot do
anything about this. And guess
what, there will be one more,
one million more security
professionals. Because the
market is going to need them.
They're just not going to be as
qualified as you guys like them
to be. That should be an
incentive to start reaching out
now. Overall, what I'm
suggesting is that we empower
these shiny happy people to be a
bit more like us. Right? To be
armed to the fists, to be there
with us on the front line.
Because they're only going to be
as secure as we help them
become. And if we don't, they're
going to drag us down. So that's
one way, or actually I described
a couple ways you can do good
things. But to kind of wrap
things up, I'd like to ask you
who here knows what has been a
phenomena causing power outages
in the United States that's also
(indiscernible) on  ‑ ‑ in the
past 20  years. I'm sure
somebody can guess. That's
right. It is the squirrels. You
guys know your stuff. For those
who don't, in the pretty
extensive SUR way, the New York
Times did last sum E they found
out squirrels munching on power
line|s, I mean the actual
animals, eating power cables
were the cause of a lot of power
outages. This was actually
mentioned here at DEF CON by I
believe (indiscernible) a  ‑ ‑
Yes we don't see billions of
dollars persistent squirrel
preventive technologies. A
mystery. This is because the the
fuzz of cyber has taken over. We
can raise our hands and say kids
get off my lawn or try to change
this. For those of you not
familiar with the term fuzz,
fear uncertainty and doubt this
is actually originally developed
as a scare tactic by IBM sales
people in the seventies. They
wanted to prevent competitors
from selling technology to the
customers. They told them
there's no telling what's going
to happen if you buy that stuff,
but today, FUD is being used to
funnel billion of dollars into
government agencies and military
work and hacking  ‑ ‑   ‑ ‑
offensive and defensive
technology that's simply not
going to help the everyday
people. So the public is kept in
constant fear  ‑ ‑   ‑ ‑
pixlated apocalypse that's right
around the corner. Have you
heard of digital pearl harbor,
that kind of stuff. That kind of
stuff keeps it vague and scary
and in the hands of government
and militants. Where actually,
where I believe most of the
problems are, are in the
civilian cyber space. Regular
people and regular companies.
Not the mill TARZed weapon
stuff. How can we stop the
spread of FUD. You can fight FUD
with facts. You can seek the
truth out for yourself. And when
somebody use AS vague term like
millions of cyber attacks are
being stopped each day, ask them
millions of what? Millions of
packets? Millions of port scans?
Millions of infected devices
communicating with the CMC
server? Be concrete with the
terms. You know in biology, we
can hear about the ten million
microbes living in this bottle
if people don't get sick all the
time. You're going to be using
concrete terms that have
relevance to our industry, to
our field. And it's easy to go
out to those high numbers A.
Billion cyber attacks on
counting microbes. Once they
seek out that information for
ourselves, and I think that is
something this industry, you
know this community is very good
at doing because you know, raise
your hands if you're allergic
to  ‑ ‑ That is I believe a
defining characteristic of our
community. It's good, it's good
to have that. But it's also
important not just to be
allergic to bullshit to have
that knee jerk reaction, but
also speak down OT information
that's really happening. And
once you know what's up,
communicate that out bounds.
Communicate it outside of our
community. There is a gap
between us. A gap between the
hacker world and the rest of
them. And we have to be mindful
of that gap and keep preaching
out and telling people what it's
like so they're not this warted
by the fog of FUD. The problem
of FUD flows both ways. Certain
government, agency, certain
decision makers, if you pardon
my French, they eat where they
shit. That means, they're also
feeding the public with the same
FUD they're being fed. Those are
a lot of Fs. I need a drink. So
they're being fed with the same
FUD they are spreading. You know
how they say there is no patch
for human stability? That is not
accurate. Because if we expect
the decision making people and
the decision making algorithm
are not going to change, we can
still influence the
(indiscernible). We can still
make sure that the information
that the decision makers are
getting and the way that they
are keeping these issues that
will matter to everybody are
concrete, honest, not laced with
if you had and bullshit and high
PESH la. So many meetings with
congress people et cetera. You
can do the same thing in your
own communities and countries.
To wrap things up, I think the
internet needs you not to grow
cool facial hair, but rather to
save it for the future. And
there are five things that we
can all start doing right now.
And you know what's the cool
thing about it? We don't need to
ask for permission. We are
hackers, we can do whatever we
like. We don't need a key, we'll
break in right? So to summarize,
we can be researching the
technology that affect human
life and safety. We could be
researching stuff that matters.
We have to, you know, disclose
more bugs, find more
vulnerabilities and get more
information out there one way or
another. We can collaborate and
share within our industry
community but also outside of
it. And we can empower the
masses so that they don't have
to  ‑ ‑ are going to have red
mohawks. And of course, stop the
spread of FUD, which is
something everyone can do just
like  ‑ ‑ to help the spread of
microbes. Now let's reflect on
everything I've told you. I
claim TA GFTs will |fame to a
certain extent to claim cyber
space and (indiscernible) space
for the rest of us. We can argue
about how big the failure will
be, how (inaudible) the extent
of it. We can argue about what
are we going to do about it. But
one thing I don't think we can
argue about is can we afford not
to do anything right now? And so
yeah, we can use our powers to
read people's e‑ mails. That's
fine. We can also use our power
to be this guy to save the
world. Or maybe more like this
guy, if you're a cyber fan like
myself. You could call me in a
sense, naive, adorable, as some
people have been known to do.
You can say that I am a romantic
hacker that expects things that
are not reasonable. I grew up
with my little ponies, but also
with hackers and gadgets and
(indiscernible)s. And I'm
excited to see the science
technology I imagineed a
reality. I think in that
reality, hacking is magic. And
it can save the world. Thank
you. That's overwhelming. Thank
you guys. You're too fine. Guys
and girls I might add. This
year, I've seen more ladies at
DEF CON than ever. (Applause.)
Yeah, keep coming here ladies.
And so let me know what do you
choose to do. Red pill or blue
pill, part of the problem or
part of the solution? And you
can easily find me on twitter or
the interweb and you can also
send me multicolored
(indiscernible)s if you think
that I'm romantic. But I hope
you join this and become part of
the solution. Thank you guys.
(Applause.) I think we may have
a minute or a couple for
questions. All of the hand
waving and signalling. That
might have something to do with
the WIS key. I see a guy over
there. >>	So I don't think
you're naive. What areas are you
personally dressing with
(indiscernible) process of what
it is that you would want to see
or have done. Specifically
what's happening right now over
in your own country. >>	Okay. So
actually specifically with
what's happening right now in my
country. That's a good question.
I have a story to reply with
that. I can clean it up. Anyone
know what that is? IE row dome.
The missile defense system
that's been intercepting rockets
that have been fired  ‑ ‑   ‑ ‑
don't worry this is not
political. A few weeks ago brine
KREBs broke a story about how
some of the defense companies
developing iron dome has been
breeched by Chinese hackers. The
story made the rounds on BBC.
Business insider, guardian, a
bunch of others. And the
headline started to volt. And by
the time they got into Israel
media, the headlines read iron
dome needs a cyber iron dome. As
I was getting ready to come out
here to DEF CON, I within the to
see my hairdresser. Obviously an
important person in my life
right? And he was like I know
you're in the cyber security
stuff. What's going on? Are the
Chinese hackers now controlling
the rockets over our heads? And
what I do when I'm faced with
that sort of fear, uncertainty,
and doubt, I go back to the
media and the people I'm in
touch with with people in the
university and other people in
Israel, and say listen, let's
get the facts right. What
actually happened is that
several companies that have
something to do with the
development of iron dome did
experience a breech. And those
companies responded that the
breech happened three years ago
and it has some classified
documents lekked out the to
potentially Chinese hackers
associated with a specific
threat, 61389, that it wasn't
anything about iron dome,
specifically in it. And it was
not mean that some guy siting in
shanghai can now control the
rockets here in tell VOOEF. So
to answer your question sir S to
talk to the people like that. I
go to the media. I talk to the
public  ‑ ‑ and I try to get the
facts for myself so that I can
communicate them outside. Yes? A
question right here? I am not
familiar with you guys. So if
you have a question, wave
perfusely. You guys and then one
guy over the back. >>	How do we
get more women in security?
>>	That is a fantastic question.
I actually, one of the panels I
submitted, but it was rejected.
Never mind, I got over it. Not
(inaudible) all no. I think one
way is by creating accessible
role models. For me it was
Angelina Jolie. For other people
it might be different women. And
I think it's critical we get
more speakers and
(indiscernible) and talk not
just about technical stuff, but
also about our specific career
paths. I speak to girls who are
learning computer science back
in Israel all the time. I tell
them how I got start. What's the
security industry like. Is it
true that there are only boys at
DEF CON. No I tell them it's not
true. And every year I've been
coming, I've seen more women. I
tell them that. And I think it's
a good question too because we
are going to need, you know,
that 50  percent of the
potential work force. So my
response would be accessible
role models and getting more of
that out. There's another side
to that, and that's something
you guys can do. You know our
black hats, white hats, don't be
a douche hat. (Laughing) thank
you. There was a guy over there
in the back. Yell. Okay, so the
question was in academia a lot
of the (indiscernible) is
focused on the military side of
thingings. And not enough on the
civilian side and the civilian
role and security matters to
civilian societies and how can
we counterthat? So one thing
that I am a big believer in is
having always that one leg in
academia. My research fellow
with tell -inaudible-
university. And I constantly
talk about this stuff. We talk
about things like anonymous and
private individuals who are
making a difference in the
security industry. We talk about
the role of. I don't know here
in the United States, it might
be different, but in IZ really,
the tell code (indiscernible)
the civilian companies are not
doing inform. They keep saying
that. Every place I get in
university, and outside of
university. I also kind of am
using the university as almost
like back door in a way. Don't
tell them right. But I'm using
that to influence public
opinion. Because university
(indiscernible)s where the prime
minister comes down. It's a
prime minister. And I try to
make sure at those events, the
content and questions about not
just military and strategic
cyber war and stuff, but also
practical cyber war security
issues and everybody raised. All
right guys I think that's all
the time. >>	One more question
please. It's over here. Do you
think it's time for us to take
back the word hacker. It's not
cyber criminal, it's not
attacker, and when somebody says
a hacker did this and hacker did
that we need to say no that's a
criminal. That's a nation state
hacker. And something specific,
than say hacker which is lazy.
>>	Personally I have to say,
I've been proud to use the term
hacker. I've been proud to say
I'm part of the hacker
community. I never thought it
was a negative thing. I always
thought it was a badge of honor.
Honestly, I think the term
hacker implies capability. It
implied intuition and curiosity.
And then what it call comes down
to is the actual individual
choices the hacker makes.
Whether they choose to become a
cyber warier defending their
nation, whether they become a
cyber criminal, a hack VIS.
Those are career paths.
Personally, I think it's
important to use the term hacker
in every opportunity I get. My
first line| my I first sentence
is a security researcher did
that. Otherwise known as a
heark. I put them together to
make it clear that this is the
sort of thing that's being done
by hackers and it's a good
thing. Each of us has to make
their own decisions about how
they are proud or how they want
to represent themselves. But by
being good hackers in a way, I
know it sounds like care bare
stuff, but I like the care
bares. They're cool. But by
being a good hacker, we can
redeem that image and we can
say, yeah, hackers did that. And
that's really cool. Hackers
brought back internet
connectivity to Egyptian
residents in the  ‑ ‑ also
helped Syrians and they are also
exposing problems in medical
devices that are life
threatening. So thank god we
have hackers. That's what I
believe in. Thank you. Thanks a
lot guys. (Applause.) Thank you
it is incredibly rewarding and
humbling and overwhelming to be
able to advance you guy SCOMBS
girls here. So rock on. Hack the
planet. (Applause.) More
whiskey, the lady in purple, I
owe you a drink. So for anybody
that has questions, she's going
to be moving to the chill out
cafe. Feel free to follow her
over there. Enjoy. >>	Chill out
cafe, questions. Chill out cafe.
Thank you guys.