>> Hello! Thank you for making
it through to our talk at the
last day. Oh, I should probably
not run that stuff before I give
you a disclaimer. So we're going
to be talking about improvements
in attacking client devices on
Wi- Fi networks, so rogue access
point or evil AP stuff. And this
year is the ten year anniversary
of when Karma attacks was first
released. And there's a lot of
work that needs doing and that's
what this talk is about. Some of
you might recognize the logo we
put up there, after Heart Bleed,
we realized that every tool
needs a logo. You can't just
write code anymore, you have to
have a logo. So, Facebook writes
hack on everything and they sort
of sent this out in an email
invite, so I hacked their logo
to make a logo for our thing, I
thought that was appropriate.
But thanks to Facebook for not
suing us yet. Okay, so we're
going to be talking about Wi- Fi
at Def Con and we got live
demos, so it's guaranteed to do
terrible things at some point.
We'd like to not do terrible
things to you, so please turn
off your Wi- Fi if you don't
want to be part of any potential
terrible things. If you choose
not to turn off your Wi- Fi and
you stay in this room, we take
that as consent that you're ok
with it. That said, we're not
going to be showing people's
passwords, we've got demos of
our devices and things like
that. Standard disclaimer. Hi,
I'm Dominic, this is Ian. We
work for a small company in
South Africa called Sensepost. A
Pen Testing firm that has been
going for about 14 years. Those
are our contact details. Our
first name at sensepost.com if
you want to get a hold of us. We
like talking about this and our
happy to continue the
conversation and we're also at
Twitter at those handles.
Alright, so the ubiquitous why
Wi- Fi or justification for our
research slide. I think we all
understand that Wi- Fi is pretty
valuable. People when they start
hacking, the first skinny
project, you go buy yourself a
pineapple and turn it on and if
you at Def Con, you get owned. I
don't know if you saw that. SO
it's pretty fascinating, we were
worried that the volms and that
stuff might -- because of some
commonality exists in ours,
thankfully it doesn't, but we
suspect we spotted it every now
and again, just massive amounts
of shell code stuff flying
through the sky and so who ever
that is, nicely done. But I
think -- so Wi- Fi gives you
pretty cool stuff. We know that
these things are ubiquitous,
they're sitting in our pockets,
we've all got them on us and
they are all connected to cloud
services with tons of valuable
information, be it your
corporate information or your
personal information. So we want
to hack the Wi- Fis. They're
everywhere and they give us
useful stuff. And the promise of
hacking Wi-Fi is that you get
creds from the sky. Manna from
Heaven. There's vulnerabilities
that have existed at every layer
and we can own Wi- Fi devices on
almost every layer of the ozone
model. And we should have creds
falling from the sky. So you can
spoof devices into connecting to
your network with rogue AP
attacks. If there's a secure
network that you can try and
crack those creds. WPA handshake
cracking or EAP cracking then
you get corporate creds. Once
you are on the network you can
man in the middle them and get
passwords like Doug Song
released this stuff in 2000,
Robert Graham released his
hamster and ferret stuff in
2007, we had Fire Cheet in 2010
there are lots of tools released
to give you passwords once
people have connected. And then
we've got stuff to try to mess
with protection so we can get
around SSL using SSL strip and
Moxie's tools. So technically at
every layer we've got these
vulnerabilities. Why can't we
walk around with passwords
filling up the database
somewhere? The reality these
days is kind of far from that,
there's no Manna falling from
Heaven. You can run this stuff
and you will get maybe the odd
noob whose still checking mail
over pop without certificate
validation. You really don't get
a bunch of credentials flying
out of the sky. And to try to
get a lot of credentials, you
have to put a lot of work in. So
if you look at the Karma attacks
which we are going to look at in
a bit, those things don't work
as well as they used to, and
we'll get into that, ten year
anniversary. With things like
cracking WPA handshakes and
cracking EAP networks, those
things have not kept up- to-
date with our ability to crack
stuff and the speed of which we
can do that. And if you look at
the man in the middle stuff,
Doug Song released D-Sniff in
2000, and if you want to capture
MSN credentials, going with the
MSN messenger, those things are
great. But nobody uses MSN
messenger any more. And then
things like HSTS and certificate
pinning have come along and
messed with our ability to man
in the middle as well. So we
wanted to fix that. So we're
releasing a set of tools today,
we're calling it the Manna
toolkit. We're calling it Manna
because of the Manna from Heaven
thing and we're trying to figure
out what a decent acronym would
be. Something that made that
make sense. And we thought of
something lame, like man in the
middle and network attack
toolkit. And we thought ok,
that's possible, we'll go with
it. Somebody yesterday suggested
we call it -- many are now
active. Which we thought was a
pretty cool blame. I don't know
if you're here, so we decided
we're going to call it, many are
now active. Okay, so before we
look at Karma attacks, this is a
targeted primer about Wi- Fi.
First off we are talking Wi- Fi,
we're not talking 3G, GSN,
Bluetooth, NSC, anything like
that. 80211 ABGNAC stuff. In Wi-
Fi, you have three types of
packets. You have management
data and control packets. The
control packets are the kinds of
things that prevent RF
collisions and allow lots of
devices to talk RF at the same
time and get decent throughputs.
And data packets are the stuff
that carries the data you are
sending over the network.
Management packets are the ones
we're interested in. And in
particular there are three sets
of packets, probe requests,
probe responses and beacons. So
when your device looks for a
network, when you open up your
phone and you look at available
Wi- Fi networks or do it on your
laptop, this is what happens.
Your device sends out a broad
cross probe request and then all
of the access points nearby say,
hey, I'm this network and I'm
available. And that's a probe
response coming back. Now when
you connect to a network, this
happens. Well, something
slightly more complicated than
this, this is the simplified
version. You send a directed
probe request which is different
from a broad path probe request
in that you are looking for that
specific network and it will
respond to that directed probe
request and you get an
association. So if you have
played with the aircrack suites
and you have run fake off with
air replay, that's what this is.
And you get that association ID
to reach the end of this
process. So current Karma
attacks, the stuff released by
Dino and Shawn in 2004, and they
target this aspect of the
association. So if something
tries to associate to a network
with a directed probe, they will
respond -- But they don't target
this part of the whole thing.
And what ends up happening is if
you look at - - sorry - - I'm
jumping ahead a little. Anyway.
So if you look at problems that
happen, if you run Karma these
days, it doesn't work as well.
So if you take like a standard
Android device, this is a Nexus
running the latest one, it will
show you a list of networks that
are available, but it's not
necessarily directed probing for
those networks. So Karma won't
know to respond to that stuff.
So if you have a home network
saved there, you can click on
it, but it will say your home
network is not here, so I'm not
going to try to associate and
send that off. So we need to
fool those devices into thinking
that network is here. I'm going
to jump back a little. So in
South Africa as kids, we play a
game in the pool called
Marco/Polo. We asked some people
in the conference if they have
heard of Marco/Polo and they say
they have, not the explorer, the
game. I apologize if this is a
localized reference. But the way
the game works is, some kid
closes his eyes and he is it and
he shouts out Marco and then
everybody nearby shouts out Polo
and he has to try and catch
them. So he has to acoustically
locate them. So this works well
for Wi-Fi. So imagine that your
client device when it sends out
a broadcast probe is shouting
Marco and all of the access
points are responding, shouting
Polo with their network name. So
that's -- what Karma relies on
is the fact that we can't tell
the difference between one
person saying polo, home
network, and another person
saying polo home network. And
that's built into the pro -- the
way Wi- Fi works. It's your
corporate networks, you're going
to have hundreds of APs spread
across your campus, you need to
be able to have lots of BSS,
BSSIDs advertising the same
ESSID so that you can roam
around and connect to lots of
different things. And the places
where authentication happens is
after the association. That's
where you do your EAP stuff
where you do your WPA stuff. So
before then, it's completely
unauthenticated and you can
spoof it and nothing knows -- is
any the wiser. The other aspect
that makes Karma work is that
devices have preferred network
lists on them. So when you
connect to a network and you
choose save that network or
remember it, that gets stored as
a preferred network. And one of
the problems that devices have,
is that they probe out for these
networks even when they
shouldn't. They should just be
sending out a broad burst
request and looking for networks
nearby, but for a variety of
different reasons on different
devices, they will send directed
probe requests saying, hey, home
network, are you here? Hey, home
network, are you here? Just
shouting out Marco. So the
modern implementations of Karma
these days, so the guy on your
right is Robin Wood --
DigiNinja, he wrote the first
patches for Karma for host APD
which is the open source and
access point software and that's
the stuff that's used on the
pineapple, although they
released a new version of
pineapple stuff yesterday, so
it's slightly changed now. The
guy on the right is, I can never
pronounce his name, Thomas
d'Otreppe. I'm sorry if he is
here and I'm butchering it. He
is the guy that wrote the
aircrack suite and the airbase
MG tool implements Karma in
software mode. >> Right, hi
everyone, as Dominic said, my
name is Ian de Villiers. Believe
it or not this little note is
actually stuck up on my wall at
the office because I really
battle with host APD. It seems
that the developers follow that
old thing about not commenting
the code because if it was
difficult to write, it should be
difficult to read. I've also got
to say it's a bit disappointing,
I'm doing my first presentation
at Def Con and I'm forced to use
Windows. We presented yesterday
and Linux just didn't want to
work with the projectors and
stuff, so I thought -- I'd be
safe, but anyway. In any case,
there a big thing that Dominic
pointed out, in order to
successfully start getting
devices to associate with our
rogue access points, our access
points are going to have to
respond both to directed probe
requests as well as broadcasts.
So literally what we did is we
did quite a bit of work on the
actual hostapd code and we added
components, essentially just a
bunch of hashes and stuff --
patch tables where we restored
the list of networks that
devices had probed for on a per
device used. So if Dominic's
phone is probed for three
networks, we would store that
and then later on we'd respond
for broadcasts with that. And
this literally would mean that
devices would potentially start
noticing that networks were open
and would start connecting to
them. So to give you an idea
over here, I'm just going to
display over here -- yeah, one
thing, we are going to fire this
up now, as Dominic said right at
the beginning, the disclaimer,
if you have your Wi- Fi on,
you'll probably see networks
that you associated with
previously will start becoming
available as I go through the
talk over here. In any case, on
the screen, we have a screen
cast of an Android device, we
can see a couple of networks
connected to previously, so post
mana, et cetera, et cetera, they
all stored -- the Flamingo Rooms
is currently available over
there. And then literally, we
are going to fire up Mana and on
the left hand screen we're going
to fire it up and you will see a
bunch of output from it and that
is where it's storing a direct
probe request for specific
devices. And when we come along
over here, our previously saved
network is now obviously is now
available and it's attempting to
connect to the thing and we can
carry on and it's actually
connected. This is following the
same logic as normal in terms of
it follows the new logic we
implemented that being, that
we've stored the direct probe
request and then responded to
the broadcast, hello, we're
here. And the device is actually
going to connect. If this gets
further and we just delete that
network and we create a new one,
then you will see more how the
original Karma attacks worked.
So, we delete that, we're going
to create a network, and then
it's going to say, hello, are
you there? We're going to call
the network Manna Sensepost, we
haven't connected to it before,
and we're going to connect to it
almost immediately. It just
makes it very easy. There we go.
And so we've connected. >>
Sorry, I'm laughing at some of
the messages that some of you
are choosing to send us in your
network names. Thank you. All
right, so the implication there
is that Karma starts working
much better than it used to.
We're now responding to those
broadcast requests based on the
view of the PNL that we can
build up from your device. So if
you have Wi-Fi on now, we're not
running anything malicious other
than just sending out the Karma
stuff, it's pretty busy at the
moment. But you should see some
networks specific to your device
showing up. Now one of our
colleagues who is sitting down
in the front here, Glenn, he
presented in this track
yesterday around this time on
practical ariel hacking
surveillance and a tool kit that
he built called Snoopy. And what
Snoopy does is it looks at these
probe requests that you are
sending out and it builds up a
location history of where you've
been. So based on your network
name, if that's unique and it's
been driven into the database
can find out where you are. So
stuff like Snoopy and creepy ass
retailers using this to track
people around and other things
have led to a reduction in the
number of probes, directed
probes that these devices send
out send out. Because
technically these devices don't
need to send a directed probe
out other than when it is
actually associating to the
network. So in the case of IOS,
the number of probes it sends
out for open networks has been
dramatically reduced. And even
the number of probes it sends
out for hidden networks has been
reduced which I will come back
to in a moment. In the case of
Android devices, they've
actually pushed the patch to WPS
applicant which is the thing
that associates to networks and
to limit the number of probes
that gets sent out. That will
get built into Android at some
point in the future. So we
expect to see even fewer probes
coming down the line. So when I
was trying to figure out why IOS
devices weren't probing for
hidden networks, because that's
weird. Hidden network, it's not
broadcast on the SSID. If you
send out -- I mean on beacons --
if you send out the broadcast
probe request it won't respond
saying, hi I'm this network. You
have to know the network name
and do a directed probe for that
network and it will respond. So
what that means is if you have
any hidden networks in your PNL
on your devices, basically your
device runs around going, hey
network are you there, hey
network are you there. So how
had Apple figured out to not do
that? Like it's impossible. I
spent a bunch of time building
Faraday Cages trying to see if
they were maybe they were using
location history and then
realizing I don't know math and
can't build a Faraday Cage to
save my life and tin foil works
much better. And we eventually
figured out that what Apple does
is if there is at least one
hidden network nearby then it
will probe for its hidden
networks. But if there is no
hidden networks nearby then it
won't probe for hidden networks.
So easy win if you weren't using
stuff like Snoopy or your trying
to look for probes or you want
to make your Karma attacks work
better you must have a hidden
network nearby. >> Right, so
what we did then is we thought
about this because there were a
couple of things one could do.
One could either run a hidden
network or we also thought about
broadcasting hidden network
frames alongside the beacon and
so on and so forth, that's not
implemented yet, or
alternatively de-offing users
and having them rescan which
could potentially be
problematic, it's really easy,
but problematic from other
aspects. Eventually what we
thought was because different
devices react in different ways
and the large number of people
these days carry more than one
Wi-Fi device around with them,
which would probably have
different levels of stealthness,
if I can put it that way. What
we thought we would actually go
along and implement something
else. You remember earlier when
I was talking about Karma with
the -- device view of networks
that it actually probes for, we
decided, actually let's skip
this. If there's anybody out
there, we're going to go through
every network that we've
actually collected from any
device and we're going to
broadcast it. And it actually
makes our Karma attack
significantly better. So if I
skip back to the videos and I go
to Karma now, it's basically a
configuration setting. It's not
enabled by default because it's
really noisy. And we start
running the actual Karma engine.
What we're going to see is on
our right hand side we have our
Android application there's only
one open network, but as Karma
starts picking up more and more
networks from other devices
nearby that list is going to
grow substantially. And all of
the sudden you start seeing a
whole heard of them and
unfortunately that tablet that I
was screen casting this from is
a bit longer than my screen, but
there are a lot of them. And
they just sort of carry on
coming up and so on and so
forth. It really improves the
success of our Karma attacks. >>
So I'm running that at the
moment, if you are looking at
your Wi-Fi device, you will see
that. But the problem is, it
ends up trying to generate more
packets than this card can -- or
frames -- that this card can
send out in a reasonable
timeframe and there's lots to
view. >> It might work for a bit
and then it will probably fall
over and start working again.
It's working. >> Okay, so up
until now what we did is we
fixed Karma. Karma is ten years
old, it wasn't working so well,
it now works much better. We
field tested this and we're
prepared to stand by that. We're
releasing this tool at the end
of the talk, you can take it and
have new Karma attacks that work
much better. But then we wanted
to -- [Applause] >> In a fine
tradition of over promising and
under delivering, we thought
what else can we put in our Def
Con abstract that will make it
look cool? So we thought let's
make ridiculous claims about
secure networks and see if we
can live up to them. So Karma
attacks work only on open
networks, you need the network
to be open. Secure networks, so
that's WPA networks, or
pre-shared key networks, or
stuff like 8021X are juicy
targets. They, on the one hand
provide you credentials and on
the other hand, if you can
actually get them to connect,
you get man in the middle -- the
benefits of the man in the
middling someone. So we spent
some time working on extending
that. And Ian just gave me a
meaningful look which makes me
think that -- here we go -- the
meaningful look meant I forgot
something. So when you have a
secured network in your PNL
list, different devices behave
in different ways. Let's say an
Android device probes out for a
hidden -- not a hidden network,
a secured network. Right now
current versions of Karma and
Karma running in open mode only
our version, will send a
response, but the devices match
the network based on the
security settings and the name.
So they are not going to auto
associate to those networks.
They see it as a different
network. So what that means is
that if we want devices to
automatically connect, when they
are in people's pockets, we want
them to automatically connect to
us. We don't want them to have
to click on the network to just
connect. That's not going to
happen. And even if they do
click on the network to connect,
different devices give you funny
warnings. Like on an Apple -- on
an OSx device it will tell you,
this used to be a WPN network
and now it's open that's wired
are you sure you want to
continue. Android shows it as a
completely different network and
things like that. So we spent
some time thinking about how to
deal with that. >> So one of the
things I came up with was well,
we came up with was basically is
we decided if there's no
certificate validation on a
device, then it actually could
theoretically be quite easy to
get them to actually connect and
look at cracking things. Now the
big thing is previously people
have relied on Pre Radius
written by Joshua Wright and
Brad Antoniewicz. I hope I got
that right. But what we've done,
we've actually ported some
patches by Brad into hostapd so
we've now got our own Radius
server and so it's all
incorporated to make it a little
bit easier. Nice. So we're
rather tethered over here.
Anyway. But in any case, if we
look at WPA2, we only got to
capture the first two parts of
the authentication and pass them
off to some other cracking tool
and then what we thought we
would do is look at
automatically crack and add EAP
credentials into our hostapd
config. So the reason for that
is just as Dominic pointed out
is very much -- firstly we've
got to Radius server built into
the thing, point number one.
Point number two is you are
talking normally about slightly
more high venue credentials,
it's not someone's WPA2 personal
at home etc, etc, it's normally
going to be a corporate or
something similar. Plus you have
the benefits of actually being
able to man in the middle that
specific device, so that makes
it really, really, really juicy.
If we have a look at this, we
have a video over here again.
There's a bunch of stuff
happening. There's two windows
open over here. Just explain
quickly, the bottom left hand
one, and unfortunately, the
screen is a bit compressed so I
hope it's going to be clear
enough, is where I am going to
tail our EAP users file so we
can see when users get added.
The top list is the output from
hostapd and I'm going to stop
here a bit later as the crack
and add process actually works.
And on the right hand side, we
have an Android device with a
secure network configured. Now
if we actually skip through
this, have a look at the network
config -- The identity, the
user, password, et cetera, et
cetera. And we'll skip on ahead
a bit and now we tail the users
file. That's basically pretty
much the default one. I've got
nothing past the final entries
in that. And I just want to keep
an eye on the time here because
it's -- so literally I started
this app now and we'll see our
device is almost immediately
going to connect, about now.
Yeah, it's really already come
through, I actually missed it.
If we have a look on the top
left, we've got output from
crackapd, which sort of says
credentials cracked user Peap,
TTLS, password and we have a new
entry in our EAP users file. And
if we let this carry on, you
will see it says it's going to
connect pretty much now. There
we go obtaining IP address and
it's now connected. Now how it
all works currently is literally
from hostapd, I just write up --
create a -- when the application
starts and I write from there.
But the cracking is actually
taking place using generic
tools. In my case I'm using
Asleep with the standard Charlie
Linux BrockU word list. But the
script itself is implemented in
Python it just makes it easier
-- people want to go along and
start looking at cloud based
cracking providers or something
like that. It makes it easier to
extend that. You have to say
depending on the complexity of
the password, it might not crack
as fast as this one. This one's
user was password so it would
naturally crack virtually
immediately. But it could take,
if it's crackable it could even
take a significant amount of
time. >> So the implication
there is two-fold. The one is we
took free-Radius WPE which was
released in 2008 and has not
been really updated much since
and that's not integrated within
this toolkit. You don't have to
run a separate tool, that stuff
will all work for you. And then
the other thing we did is also
crack an add as Ian pointed out,
so you can hopefully get --
start man in the middling
people. So up to now what we did
is we focused on improving Karma
attacks. The broadcast stuff and
trying to deal with things like
loud mode, trying to deal with
secure networks. But to really
make this stuff count, like if
we just left it there and it's
kind of a technical -- it
doesn't fulfill the promise of
creds falling from the sky,
Manna from Heaven. So we
realized we need to look at the
man in the middle side. Now here
we have relied a lot more on
lots of other people's tools. We
built some of our own. But the
problem is there are so many
different tools out there and
you never really sure which of
the ones that are going to work
best for you and with the
current configuration and the
way devices work and the new
stuff that's coming out like
HSTF, and certificate pinning,
some of that stuff just doesn't
work. I mentioned it in the
beginning that it doesn't work
as well. So we spent some time
trying to put together a
configuration that would give us
really nice results when man in
the middling and give us the
credentials from the sky. So up
to now we are just getting the
EAP credentials. What else can
we get? So the first thing we
used is a tool by a guy name
Daniel Roethlisberger. Once
again I'm sorry if I'm messing
it. That's why there is a
hamburger there. So I could
remember his name. This is a
tool called SSLSplit. If you
want to man in the middle SSL
connections, I highly recommend
this tool. It's scalable, it can
do non HTTP protocols and it
wraps the output out into useful
formats. It's a really cool
tool. The Mana toolkit uses this
to do a lot of heavy lifting, we
didn't make any changes to it.
The next thing we looked was
different configurations for
different situations. Most
people when they are man in the
middling will rely on Natting or
some kind of upstream connection
that they are literally sitting
in the middle of. But it's
really useful to be able to do
this stuff in places where
people have left their Wi-Fi on,
but haven't -- but there isn't
necessarily an upstream
connection. Like if you are a
visitor in a foreign land and
you don't have a data bundle. Or
an airplane or down a mine,
something like that, lots of
people leave their Wi-Fi on in
airplanes when they're not
supposed to. So a lot of devices
will do these checks to check if
they are on line or if there is
a captive portal. Apple devices
and more recently Android
devices try and get trixie. So
Google will make a request to
something called generate 204
and expect a HTTP 204 response
back. So to make it think it's
on line, you have to try and
respond to these different
things. Apple gets particually
tricky, they make a random
request to a random URL on one
of two hundred different hosts
which chooses randomly with two
different user agents just to
check that it's not being locked
based on user agents. So we
built a bunch of stuff that
deals with all of this, Apache
Vhost it's built into the Manna
toolkit that'll help you deal
with it. And the reason it's
interesting is because of stuff
I'm going to talk about just
now, where you can push
malicious certificates to
devices to make your man in the
middle work much better. There's
an option with this stuff, in
the toolkit to have that happen
as it connects to the network.
So one of the ways we can get
creds, one of the easy ways is
to have a malicious captive
portal and we'll show you the
demo and it's a bit lame, it
says log into your Google creds,
and hopefully somebody will do
that, but all of you guys would
be far too smart for that I'm
sure. But it also gives us the
ability in the upstream mode to
start getting some credentials
from people and it gives us a
place that we can push out our
malicious certificates which
I'll show in a bit. So if you're
going to be man in the middling
stuff on these devices, it's
really useful if there's a
certificate in their root store
that you have the private key
for. But we're not Law
Enforcement or the Government of
Tunisia, so we don't get to do
that to our population. And we
have to try and convince people
to put those certificates on
there. And that's supposedly
quite difficult, right?
Actually, it's ridiculous easy.
And I think people should maybe
taken to task for how easy it
is. If you send an Android or
IOS device a .cer file. C-E-R.
It doesn't even have to have the
right mime type. Then they will
helpfully offer to add that to
their root CA store. Like over
HTTP. So if they are doing their
captive portal network request
and they receive a dot server
instead of an HTML file, they'll
be like, hey, you're sending me
a certificate. Why don't I add
that to my root CA store? You
need to type in your password
granted, so there is an element
of them warning you. But it just
feels like that should be a
harder thing to do. Like
somebody in corporate IT should
have to go and do that, or you
need to like work for it, not
you can just send it. And in
Apple's case you can even push
malicious iOS configs over there
in the exact same way. Once
again you have to type in their
four digit password. But some
users are going to fall for that
and given that it gives us a
root CA on their device it's
totally worth it. The next thing
is HSTS. HSTS stands for HTTP
strict transport security. Three
acronyms I can remember. Four,
it blows my RAM. So HSTS is
something to defeat tools like
SSLStrip. And what SSLStrip
relies on is that if you type in
something like Google.com, you
didn't type in
HTTPS://Google.com because you
are my mother. She is a very
smart lady, but she's not going
to type that stuff in. So you're
going to hit the page on HTTP at
which point you'll get a
redirect to HTTPS. So SSLStrip,
stuff -- previously, it will
just prevent that redirect and
serve things over HTTP and
rewrite links to HTTP. With
HSTS, a site can configure that
will basically send a directive
to your browser that will say,
always access me via SSL. So
even if you type in
accounts.Google.com, or
HTTP://accounts.Google.com, your
browser will still go to
accounts of Google over SSL
without ever hitting -- playing
clear text HTTP. So things like
SSLStrip don't get an
opportunity to work there and it
gets very difficult to man in
the middle. But there was this
guy, Leonardo MVE who presented
at Black Hat Asia this year, who
had this awesome idea for
getting around HSTS. And it
works really well, so we
implemented it.?And it's one of
the things we are releasing in
the Manna toolkit. But, it's his
work, all credit goes to him. We
just made some changes to make
it work slightly better. >> So,
I'm going show you some demos of
how those things fit together.
So it's the same set up as up to
now, we have the tablet on the
right and we have chrome open
and we're running in no upstream
mode. So if you try to go to a
page that we haven't faked, it's
going to take you to our captive
portal. And we're going to go to
foo.com. And it takes us to our
fancy captive portal and you'll
notice it asks you to log in and
it's got a drop down for
different services like Google
or Facebook and the hopes that
somebody is going to be a dork
and just type their details for
one of those things in. Creds
from the sky. Ok. So, we're
going to type some creds in
there and we've created a bunch
of accounts for the purpose of
these demos. Somebody types it
in and it will send it as a get
request over plain HTTP. We can
just pull that from our Apache
logs which is where we're
storing all of that. If we look
in our Apache logs, there it is
his username and his password on
the right hand side. So that's
really straightforward. But now
if we wanted to actually get his
Google creds when he went to
Google, what we can do is
implement this HSTS bypass. So
you will notice we went to
Google.com, but it's redirected
to quadw.Google.com, now
quadw.Google.com it's not a real
domain, and because it's not a
real domain there's no HSTS
policy for it saved in your
Browser. So this requires two
things. One is it requires a DNS
proxy which Leonardo wrote that
will do this exchange. So you're
trying to go www.Google.com,
actually go to four w's but to
return the proper result and the
modified version of Moxie's
SSLStrip that once again
Leonardo wrote and that will
serve the right content, strip
out HTTPL, HTTPLL. In this
instance, we're not actually
using that because this is in
upstream mode we can control the
full interaction so we can
create a VHost for quad
w.Google.com and later on we'll
show you it running in nat with
that stuff happening live. So
now we have rewritten the link
so that if you click sign in on
the right, which would normally
redirect you to
accounts.Google.com, it once
again keeps us on the
quadw.Google.com domain, and
with the live nat stuff it will
redirect you to
accounts.Google.com.x And now we
type in the same credentials,
we've edited the get request,
it's in clear text and it's
going to show up in our Apache
log just the same as the other
one. But then the last thing is
this malicious certificate side
loading. There is the username
and password showing up in the
get request. Ok so that's the
second way we can get -- the
third way we can get creds from
the sky easily. So lastly we're
now going to try the certificate
side loading. We're going to go
back to foo.com, a site that
doesn't exist with our portal.
And you will notice it's got
this helpful let us auto
configure the network for you.
Ten minutes, thanks. If you
click on that, it pushes that
cer file to you and chrome
helpfully pops up a prompt
saying, what do you want to call
this new root CA with a healthy
add for you? You can type in
anything and you click ok and
you have a root CA sitting on
your device. Like, it shouldn't
be that easy. So if the user
makes the mistake of believing
us, clicking on that and
clicking okay. And then it kind
of comes down to how good your
social engineering is I guess
then. What it does, to their
credit due, in the top left hand
corner you will see a warning
pops up which says, warning this
network might be monitored by a
third party because our root CA
is not signed. So those are
three ways in which we can
improve the state of man in the
middling after we have gotten
things connecting to our device.
>> Great, so those that were
Glenn Wilkinson's talk yesterday
about aerial surveillance, etc,
etc. You would heard a reference
to FireLamb, but in any case,
FireSheep no longer works, etc,
etc, so Glenn quite a while ago
wrote a tool called FireLamb,
which is basically a Python
script. That sort of can capture
cookie information, that parses
out cookies made by requests
made from specific machines and
literally creates new Firefox
profiles with the cookies stores
for every device that's actually
gone through or all the traffic
that's been sniffed or loaded
from a packet capture file. We
used a modified one in terms of
it, in terms of Mana because
obviously a large chunk of our
information is actually still
traversing the network
encrypted. All be it through
SSLSplit etc, etc. So obviously
FireLamb isn't going to work, so
we have quite a lot of
modifications to actually parse
-- not a lot of modifications,
but just to parse the cookie
information out of the SSLSplit
logs. And this basically gives
us -- because now, obviously, we
have spoken about credentials,
we can get that using all of
these specifics thing. But in
terms of that session IDs and
cookies, etc, etc, are also some
form of access token and they
are obviously very important. So
we've implemented FireLamb
inside the Mana toolkit as well
and let's give you a demo of
that. So, it's quite a long
demo, so I'm probably going to
skip a head a little bit with
this one, at some places. But in
any case, if we go through here,
this one has got a bad
certificate loaded, this is all
stripped, we are man in the
middling all over the place. So
first thing we're going to do is
we're going to go to
accounts.com, this is the real
Google.com. Accounts.Google.com.
We're just MITMing it at this
specific point. And we signed on
and we can see that it says
Andrew Hacker, Hacker that's the
profile page etc, etc. And
that's not enough, so we'll skip
forward and we'll sign on to
Facebook as well. A Hacker 1337.
What's nice to note over here
you will see we've actually --
Facebook also implements HSTS so
we've got the same trick
implemented and we've actuall
signing on to quadw.Facebook.com
as A Hacker, which is awesome
and then we can sign on using a
password. And I'm going to skip
ahead here a bit. I believe he
creates a post to -- >> His
mother. >> Hello mom what is you
maiden name? And then he sends a
mail etc, etc. All of this
information is being captured at
some specific point. But the big
thing over here is if I sign on
to my Charlie Linux which is
doing all of this work, in this
case I'm now going to be running
FireLamb to actually have a look
at this. I'm going to hit space
here. You see what it's gone and
done is it's created a bunch of
output directories. Now all of
those output directories -- what
they implemented -- are actually
Firefox profiles. In my case I'm
interested in output directory
number 6 and I can actually go
along and enter 6 at this point
and it's going to fire a Firefox
using that actual profile, which
means I'll have access to all
those cookies, I'll have a link
to a whole bunch of pages he's
actually recently visited. So
let's pick on
accounts.google.com, we are
using the same cookie he was
using a couple of minutes ago,
so we now actually have signed
on to it -- well signed on,
we've been impersonating him on
accounts.Google.com as Andrew
Hacker. [Applause] >> And now we
can set them and go back a bit
and we'll go on to, in this
case, it's strange, the host
name is actually
pixel.Facebook.com, and not trip
W. But if we click on that, we
get the same effect. >> Any
moment now. >> Any moment. There
we go. So we have actually
authenticated, well impersonated
him on Facebook at this point.
Now we made a couple of changes
to FireLamb once again, in the
meantime we are pulling out a
whole bunch of creds, which
obviously aren't cookies, etc,
etc. But they stored all over
the place in these SSLSplit
files. Which hasn't all been
completed by the time we
recorded this demo. So I'm just
going to skip forward a little
bit over here. The other example
is basic auth for -- and I know
that's not that one. Somewhere
over here we've got basic auth
for mail. >> Uh- oh. I think
that is time. >> But in any
case, even the clear text mail,
everything is stored in there
and that is all over there.
[Laughter] >> So I'm sure many
of you have seen this before.
These two fine gentlemen and I
use that term very loosely, have
never spoken at Def Con before.
So what does that mean they do?
>> Shots! [Applause] >> You go,
that's right, they drink! Oh,
not yet. I have to get my shot
of water. [Laughter] >> Thank
you so much for joining us and
congratulations for our first
timers. And everyone give them a
huge round of applause.
[Applause] >> Hey, feel free to
go about your business -- Hey,
they're not done yet! Feel free
to go about your business. >>
Thank you. >> Okay, so somebody
was shouting, where can we get
it? We have not posted the code
up there yet, we just need to
switch it over to the public
repositories. But they'll all be
there. So you can see there are
a ton of tools that we messed
with, and so Mana is the main
thing that ties it all together.
The others are tools that we
have written or contributed to
and made changes. And in other
tools like SSLSplit we're using
that vanilla -- there just
configurations in Mana. So the
net results of all of this stuff
is that we think, and we run it,
it works, we get creds falling
from the sky. There are still
places in which people are
protected, so this isn't
something that's necessarily
inherent. You can still run
secure, but there's lots of ways
in which people can make
mistakes. Even though we're
supposedly savvy to this, we
keep catching ourselves, we
forget to turn off our Wi-Fi, so
you see your home network show
up, next thing you see some of
your creds coming and it can be
a real pain. So if it starts
working against us, it works
even better against potential
victims. So that's us. Thank you
very much for your time and
patience. That's where you can
get the info. >> Thank you very
much. [Applause]