>>  SO, I'm going talk to you
about highjacking build
pipeline. I'm Kyle and this is
Greg. We both came from
Rackspace. 	All right. When I
talk about build pipelines I'm
talking about your source
control from GitHub, GitLab
GitBucket, wherever you are
storing their code, depending
what site you are on. Continuous
integration, are you running on
(?), Kravitz, do you just run it
on your local box? What actually
is  -- where are your tests
running as well as upstream
sources? Like NPM, by pi ruby,
GEMS, all of those. 	The reason
I care about this is I work with
a lot of open source software
where we set up builds for that
software and you know anybody
can contribute, anybody can push
patches in, so what sort of
vector is that? What can you do
with that? What can you leave?
Kind of the precursor here is
all need secrets, you might need
secrets for testing if you are
deploying to production,
database credentials, OF ced,
might be cloud credentials,
GitHub tokens, Twitter tokens,
the actual SSH keys to get onto
boxes. 	So need to manage these
secrets in some way. Not
everybody does this
appropriately. Credentials get
leaked. Like if you do a simple
search on GitHub for AKIAJ
you'll find Amazon credentials
instantly. I'm throwing 1071
results just finding for that
stream. Right? Run
infrastructure or do whatever,
keep going. 	I think this is a
problem with how people treat
Git. (Pause) Like you start up a
new project run GitApp,
everything goes in there. If you
have any secrets encoded into
the repository itself it's there
for the world to see next time
you get pushed. 	This even
happens to people who know what
they are doing. Rich Milgo gave
a talk at BlackHat on working
with the cloud, and to do
security appropriately, set up
the DEV environment
appropriately as well as lock
down your instances and how to
handle keys. When he ended up
looking at the account that got
highjacked for him, what did he
find running there? 	Right, so
they didn't actually care about
his running infrastructure at
all, they just wanted someplace
to go mine. They pulled up
really big, really, really big
instances and just started
spending his money. If you want
to read more about that, go to
bit leave/mobile, he does a good
article on what happened, what
he did forensically to figure
out what they had done, tried to
go back through cloud trail to
figure out what they had access
to and what else they tried to
get access to. It's not just in
the GitHub credentials either,
this is an Android file, APK. If
you look here in the middle,
there's there cedes so every
client that downloaded the app
has access to their Amazon.
(Laughter) So what fun can we do
with cloud credentials? I can
spin servers, take down their
servers, redistribute DNS and
load balance exercise, maybe you
have another node you want to
put into the mix. I can remount
volumes, if you are on Amazon
you have your cloud server and
it has a EVS volume on it.
Disconnect that, connect it to a
separate like you've got their
server and their EBS volumes
connected to their own. Have
your SSH and make you have
access on their box. 	For open
stack Nova you can append your
own key to the main key they use
when they spin up new servers so
that every time the authorized
key file gets dropped you get
access to the new server. 	So
how do we find these keys to
begin with? 	Like I was saying
before for Amazon, just search,
find a list of keys, there it
is. For open stack and the open
stack writers it's a little
harder because they actually
just use a hex decimal D so you
have to look at what it would
look like in the code. OS
passion word would be if they
had an environment variable or
in some config file. 	The
results are really big here but
it could have come from a
library. Same thing with
Bianchi, looking at 3,000
results. And then API key,
305,000 results. Again, that's
like could be the libraries,
too, doesn't necessarily mean
it's the actual API key. We have
to do some amount of triage. For
GitHub they only let you search
for 1,000  -- you only get 1,000
results back so you to have
break it up. 	So like one day we
took the Rackspace EPI key and
we were looking for one good
Python, we can do it with or
without language. GitHub is
their own search setup so you
can break out as many things as
you want and also look down
particular paths and languages.
We get 4 20 for Python and 8,303
for the rest. When I was
breaking these out I had to go
through pretty much all
languages and break them into
their own discrete begins.
Paragraph bins. Right. Keep
sweating. 	Couldn't we just let
people know when they fuck up?
Like those are all there, their
e-mails are attached from
GitHub. 	So we created a project
get get sec nanny. It searches
repositories for the same
security oop. He mail the
original committer and the owner
of the project, let them know
how to revoke keys and also how
to panic! 	(Laughter) The
responses were very flip. They
were like wow, thank you, how
did you find these? You're such
a savior and, this is only a
testing project. Is it your
testing credit card? (Laughter)
So far I found about 265 keys,
I'm clearly going after one
provider I want to protect.
There is certainly more out
there to find. 	One of the
biggest offenders for this were
rails developers, config
initializer secret RV, it's got
usually with cred, there are
rails itself and this one is
infamous, there's a port out
there that will never get
accepted that just adds it to
the get ignore so it doesn't
happen to people in the future.
The comment from rails was,
they're not gonna do it in there
because people shouldn't be
doing it that way. (Laughter)
You know  -- (Laughter)   --
great! So they're supposed to
use environment variables,
that's the way you are supposed
to develop and deploy an app.
Anyway... (Laughter) So you have
to be  -- we have to do it the
right way if we're doing a
security checker. This isn't my
security checker I just noticed
this last week so Danny
Greenfield here he got the
message back. You can't read
that enhanced. There we go! All
right. So they said they have
confirmed this possibility by
manual inspection and then
there's the secret. I don't
think they inspected that. 	So
that's it for secrets. But what
if you actually need secrets for
testing? It's not like you can
live in a vacuum where your code
never touches anything. You are
not gonna build any real web
infrastructure with that. One
opportune nivt  -- I'll give --
(Inaudible) -- in a second,
travesty i I great for open
source, just do a get push, hits
the web hook and then sends out
tasks to run the build and let
you know if you have success.
Lot less control than Jenkins
but super simple. This is the
definition for a Travis yammel,
you sign up language, here we
are doing Python, 2.7, we have,
before the install you have
steps as well as the
installation and then what
script will run. 	They thv neat
thing called encrypted secrets,
though. Like you put secret on
the Web out in the open, so I
was curious if I could use it.
All this does is sets up an
environment variable that can be
used later. 	So could we leak
those deC ed secrets? Like where
do they come out? How do I get
the secrets out? Say we open a
request and we'll try to echo
off their environment variable
has the secret. 	Oh, nothing!
What! So Travis, the keys used
for encryption and decryption
are tied to the repository. If
you fork a project and add it to
Travis it will have a different
pair of keys than the original.
What that is saying is if you
make a repo it gets one key,
someone forks your repo they get
a separate key. They could run
their own secret stuff they are
running off their own fork to do
testing, but then only the stuff
that is on master gets tested
with the original keys. 	Nice.
So let's say we emergency that
port request, secret message
then comes in. So drink. Right,
so you are only  -- only
variable is cloud review and the
fact you to have trust Travis.
At some point Travis is
decrypting secrets so you have
no idea. But those guys drink
good coffee and live in Berlin
so I assume they're great. Now
we'll talk about Jenkins and
I'll pass over to Greg.
(Applause) 	>> Thanks, Kyle. So
for those of y'all who are not
familiar with Jenkins or you're
not  -- Jenkins is a continuous
integration and deployment suite
used for not only functional
testing but also deployment to
production. Even if you are not
a Jenkins user this is something
you have never heard of before,
why do we care about Jenkins?
Well Jenkins is the road to
production. If there is a
general since server at the end
of that pipeline is either a
repository that multiple servers
are using, or a production
server with data worth ceiling
sealing. The normal interaction
is hipster developer pushes code
to GitHub  -- (Laughter)   --
Jenkins is notified via web hook
that there is some code ready
for testing. What we want to do
is masquerade as hipster
developer so we can push code to
production servers or
repositories and compromise
them. 	So let's say that hipster
developer makes an oops. He
either commits his cloud
credentials which have no off
token or he commits his GitHub
token directly to his code
repository. We're kind of off to
the races, right? 	So if there
is a repository at the end of
that pipeline, all we do is
propagate vulnerable code we can
scan for and then pop every
single server  -- yeah, and the
mic  -- (Laughter)   -- so you
can pop every single server that
is using that repository. Can
y'all hear this? 	>>  Yeah! 	>>
No shit! Okay. (Laughter) So
what's the other option, right?
The other option is instead of a
repository there's a server with
information we want to steal and
sell. So one thing you can do is
propagate things for
persistence, think reverse
shells, the other options is to
try to extract the secrets that
Jenkins has out of the build, so
there's two different ways to
manage environment variables in
Jenkins. Either you throw them
directly in configuration or
you're using the credentials
plug-in but at run time they all
boil down to actual environment
variables. So both plug-ins
could possibly be leaked if you
could sneak something like this
into the code. 	So the goal of
this script is to print the
environment variables and then
phone them home to a server. No
problem. 	So that's kind of cool
but that will only give you one
server. You know what's really
cool is compromising multiple
servers. So how do we do that?
We target the Jenkins install
directly. So for my testing, I
was using the Jenkins database
library or Jenkins user
management for authentication,
Jenkins is like widely
configurable so you might not
run into this unless you use
that exact authorization to
replicate this. 	I was curious
about how Jenkins decided to
manage its users and it boils
down to this file called
config.xml and here is what it
looks like. You'll see that
there is a user name, a hash'd
API token and a hash password.
So what caught my attention is
they are using JV script. So I
did more digging. A lot moreing.
All the way down to this file
called Hudson private security
realm. And wall you'll see is
how Jenkins is actually encoding
and stories passwords. There's
nothing really wrong with this
except that it's really to
duplicate. 	So using this
three-line Java code, we can
create hashes that are passable
to Jenkins. But so now we have
to figure out a way of how to
actually pass those hashes and
get them installed on Jenkins.
So what if we have something
like this in our build, the goal
of this code is to locate the
config files for all users and
attempt to replace all hashes to
a password of our choice. Let's
find out. (Pause) So over here
is my Jenkins server. To show
I'm not cheating, I need a
password, anyone. Admin? That
would be a good guess.
(Laughter) So "admin" clearly
doesn't work, right? What I do
is go over to my Java code ...
(Pause) We get back a secret
path. So then we go over to the
compromise repository. And we
throw this in our code. So if we
go back to the Jenkins instance,
we will see our project is now
building or it's queued to build
and it's building. Building...
>>  -- (Inaudible) --
(Laughter) 	>>  So part of the
reason that it's going through
this right now is in the script
there's a command to restart
because you have to refresh the
file. And boom! We can then  --
(Cheers and applause) 	>>  So
from there it's really simple,
right? All you have to do is go
change the voice script and
propagate them through. The
other thing I wrote just so  --
thankfully it worked, too, I'm
really scared of live demos, the
other thing our script did is
phoned home all the users that
Jenkins has so I wouldn't even
have to know user name, Admin.
It's right there for me to see.
Yes. Maybe. Not in this room.
They kick you out. 	But so there
is a catch to this technique and
that's this config file is only
stored on the master node of
Jenkins. So if builds are
allowed to run concurrently
that's really good news for us.
All you have to do is add a
sleep function to your malicious
code to put the nodes to sleep,
and back on (?). If you are not
allowed to run concurrent builds
you'll have to get creative. One
option is to just keep
committing and that's because we
know these people we have
compromised are developers and
they will be executing other
builds. 	The other thing you can
try is with the compromised
credentials, commit other
repositories and push other
repositories to try to trigger
other bills on Jenkins but what
if there aren't any oops, right?
What if we really want to
compromise this deployment
system because at the end there
are 100,000 servers that are
consuming the repository or
maybe you have like a vendetta
against someone and you just
really want to get into their
production boxes. 	Well, one
thing that can help you out is
that the low-hanging fruit in
this scenario is that they're
doing automatic floor request
building which basically means
they are taking all the core
requests they get and they are
building them before they decide
to push them to master or merge
them into the repository. From a
security perspective that sounds
really stupid, right. Why would
you ever run code that you have
no idea what it does. Well the
nice thing about Jenkins is if
you were to do this, it would
tell us first it was functional
and, two, how the performance
compared to previous versions of
the code. 	There is definitely
an argument to be made for doing
this. I'm glad I don't develop
because I would probably do
this. The other option, though,
is that you hit the gate. And
you get this notification from
Jenkins asking for one of the
Admins to verify the file. 	So
if you are not going to give up,
and no one likes to give up, you
essentially have two options.
(Pause) (Silence) The web hook
we originally talked about,
right, Jenkins is notified there
is code that has to be a web
hook from GitHub and it's always
or it's by default configured to
be at GitHub-web hook on the
Jenkins server. How the process
is kicked off is a simple post
request. If you can forage that
post request, you can beat the
gate and cause a trigger and
compromise the Jenkins server
and all things attached to it.
The worst-case scenario, right,
it let's say there is no
continuous integration, there is
no deployment system, it's just
a repository you want to
compromise. Sneak in your code,
hope no one sees it and it might
propagate. So real quick, I'm
going to do the quickest
overview ever on how to secure a
Jenkins server. So disable
anonymous access, date your
deploys, use random port,
disable executors on master,
change web hook from default
URL, and it's that easy.
(Applause) 	>>  So we can take
questions. If you have
questions, come up to the mic.
>>  This is kind of tall. 	I
noticed that Jenkins failed. I
have a suggestion. There is a
URL you can hit on the Jenkins
master that will make it reload
all the files without restarting
so no one would be able to tell
you just did that. 	>>  You have
to be authorized for that.
That's my question. You back
off! 	(Laughter) 	You're
absolutely right. There is a
reload URL in the Jenkins server
but there's two problems with
that. A, you have to be
authorized and, B, you have to
know where Jenkins server is.
This is like a blind injection.
I don't even have to know where
the server is because it will
phone home that information to
me. 	>>  Okay, thanks. 	>>
Anyone else? Anyone? Anyone? No.
I know you. I'm not taking your
question. (Laughter) Thank you
all so much for coming and feel
free to come up and talk to us.
(Applause)