>> So, as a speaker, it's very
difficult to come to DEF CON and
watch really terrific talks and
not develop some sense of
speaker envy, you know. So this
is a very humbling thing to do,
and even though this is my 6th
year doing this, it's nothing I
take lightly, and it's a great
honor to be with you guys doing
this, so I'd just like to thank
the goons that do speaker opps
for make a really great
experience as a speaker. Every
year at DEF CON, something new
happens and I had a new
experience this year. I want to
thank the people at black hat,
as well. I decided to come to
the Rio on Thursday to pick up
my credentials and went home, I
live here in Vegas and I very
innocently took out my materials
and I sat down my black hat
badge on my dining room table
and put my DEF CON bag next to
it and I looked at it and I go
this is really interesting and I
did a tweet, you know, the
difference between black hat and
DEF CON in one picture and I
this that was amusing, I didn't
think it was bad amusing. Well,
between re‑ tweets and favorites
and whatnot, this got reposted
like 700 times on Twitter, so my
phone was doing this for almost
the entire Con, it was like warm
‑ ‑ that was a cool experience,
a very cool experience. So my
name is Michael Schrank, I have
a book, I will be doing a book
signing, if you have questions,
we can book up, I don't tell
people I write bot nets and bots
any more, I didn't tell people I
do that any more because I'm ear
met with blank stares or looks
of horror, so now I just tell
people I do business
intelligence, and that seems to
have a better story for people.
I've been doing DEF CON since
97, DEF CON 5 was my first one
and I came out here to cover it
for a computer world magazine,
it was the first article that
I've ever had published and I
started thinking this weekend
about the effect DEF CON has had
on my life, if I hadn't come out
here for that, I would have
never been published, I would
have never got a book deal, all
of the things that came after
the book, all the foreign
travel, the speaking
opportunities, the gigs I
probably didn't deserve, if DEF
CON hadn't made me come out to
Vegas once a year for 17 years I
probably never would have moved
here, you know, so it's an
awesome thing, a very awesome
thing. So today, what I'm going
to talk about, the name of the
talk is your leaking trade
secrets, but what I'm really
talking about is organization of
privacy, and it's a little bit
different than personal privacy,
because individuals tend to leak
identity issues whereas
organizations tend to leak trade
secrets. So the message I want
you to have coming out of here
is information that you put
online, on the web, is not
always read by the intended
audience and it's not always
used the way it's intended to be
used now, there's been a lot of
awareness about personal privacy
but there's been much less
awareness about organizational
privacy and I think that's
largely because of the way the
media handles it. The media's
been roll good at informing
people about things but less
good about informing our
organizations, and I think a
lost that is the types of
stories they cover. So in the
case of leaked trade secrets,
these kinds of stories are
always treated as news stories,
they're factual, but they don't
really teach any lessons.
Whereas, you know, there are
other reasons I think for the
press covering personal privacy
issues. For example, the one
thing, it creates a lot of
customers for a lot of
advertisers so it makes good
business sense to do that kind
of thing. The other thing is it
is just really good content. One
of my favorite stories about a
personal leak, about a year ago,
that there was a head master at
a Privilege School, I believe
it's in Georgia, who was let go.
And he felt he was let go for
the wrong reason, he felt it was
age discrimination, so he filed
a suit, they settled out of
court, stipulation that he never
talked about 9 case about what
does his daughter do she gets on
Facebook, she lets her know that
the case was settled and they
were paying for her trip to
Europe. The other story like is
if you're a soldier and you're
stationed someplace where your
government says you're not, you
can probably removed the GEO
codes off your selfie before you
upload it to Instagram, I love
that one, but these are great
because they teach lessons. And
the lesson that this should be
teaching all of us is that there
is not a piece of software,
there's not a piece of hardware
that can protect against this
kind of stuff. It's an awareness
thing, and there's really no
substitute for awareness. So one
of the things I'm going to do is
we're talking about trade
secret, I've got examples of
unintentional data leaks and
this is really all about
business intelligence, because
if it wasn't somebody doing
things with these leaks, they
really wouldn't matter, right,
so we're going to look at little
bit about how online
intelligence is different than
offline intelligence. But then
finally, we're going to talk a
little bit about what can be
done to minimize the effects of
all of this kind of stuff. So
what is the trade secret? Trade
secrets are intellectual
property but they're very
different than patents and very
different than copyrights. The
biggest difference is that you
don't need to publish a trade
secret, and if you did publish
one, it would not be a trade
secret any more, so that's
obvious. Unlike patents and
copyrights, they have absolutely
no expiration date and they're
protected by something called
the UTSA, and this came about, I
believe '70s or '80s unlike
patents or copyrights, there
were no laws. All but one or two
states have signed off on this,
but it used to be an issue
because if it were a big company
and you had offices across the
country, you would subject to
the various trade secret laws in
those various states, so this
simplified things quite a bit.
In order to be a trade secret,
it must have some kind of
economic value. The interesting
thing that I think about trade
secrets is that you can use
anybody's trade secret if you
happen to discover it on your
own. So if you find it on a
piece of paper on a sidewalk,
you can use it. If you find it
in wiki leaks, you can use it.
If you discover it through
reverse engineering, you can use
it. If you discover it. So what
is the value of a trade secret?
Well, basically  ‑ ‑ oh one
other thing I think I forgot to
mention is you have to make some
effort to protect it, that's the
other thing, you can't just come
back retro actively and say
that's a strayed secret, that
doesn't work. The reason you
established trade secrets is so
you can sue people and recovery
losses and damages and attorneys
fees and that kind of stuff. But
only if somebody misappropriates
the trade secret. If you lose it
through your own stupidity, it's
our own fault. So when people
think about trade secrets they
automatically think about things
like the recipe for Coca‑ Cola
or the formula for a fragrance
like Chanel number 5. The
interesting things about
fragrances is you can't
copyright or patent a fragrance
but you can have a trade secret
over the formula, so if you go
in Walgreens and find a knock
off, they're perfectly legal
because you can't copyright or
patent a fragrance, but you can
trade secret the process or the
recipe. A lot of times, trade
secrets are used in conjunction
with patents, so you might have
some patent, but the way you
implement those patents is some
kind of a process that's
protected by trade secrets. But
today, more often, trade secrets
take the form of data, and I
just listed a few of these here,
you know, things like your list
of your employee, your list of
your suppliers, customer lists,
funding sources, expansion plan,
marketing plans, new product
planning, pricing strategy,
labor issues, how quickly things
move in and out of your
inventory, how fast thing sell,
IT infrastructure change,
security information, this is
all data and these are all
straight secrets and in your
organization, you should treat
these as secrets. And every try
is going to have a different
one. There's no  ‑ ‑ I mean,
depending on what you're doing
you're going to have different
things that you're going to call
trade secrets. For example, in
the European Union, they have
much more progressive privacy
laws than we have here in the
states, and in the EU, if
somebody is collecting personal
data, you have a right to go to
that organization and say what
is the data that you're
collecting on me? And they have
to show it to you. Well,
somebody in I believe Ireland
approached Facebook and says I
want all my data, I want to know
what you're collecting on me,
Facebook used a little exemption
in the law that said if through
the disclosure you're going to
show trade secret, you're exempt
from the law and Facebook said
hey, that's us, that's us. And
these are all the trade secrets
that Facebook wanted to protect.
And I'm not putting these up
here for you to read them, I'm
just showing you there were 22
of them, a lot of them and they
included things like, you know,
if you delete an image, we just
erase the pointer, it's still
really there. If you poke
somebody, we record that. You
know, all that kind of stuff.
And they were saying if you have
your data, you're essentially
learning about what we do with
that data, since we buy the
nature of that data, so data has
become a trade secret. So we've
got all of these potential trade
secrets now and they're all
floating around on the Internet
and this has really changed the
way business intelligence is
collected. For example, before
1995, and I use 1995, because
for me, that's kind of when the
Internet [indiscernible] a
little bit, before 1995, all the
web pages looked like
[indiscernible] web pages and
things have just matured a
little bit there, so before 95,
you had to do things like this
guy, this is Mitch Modell, the
CEO of Modell sporting goods and
he was accused of the following:
He dressed up as a disguise,
misrepresented himself at dick's
sporting goods, told the
receptionist that he was an
executive for Dick's and he was
waiting for a meetings with the
CEO and she preceded to show him
room where there was a lot of
files and he started particular
pictures and he was just helping
himself to information. What
makes this story really weird is
that the same guy was also on
undercover boss on CBS where he
basically did the same thing
except for his own employees so
he was really into this. But
this is the way intelligence was
often gathered prior to the
Internet. So before 1995, there
were limited number of sources,
you know, where are you going to
go? You can go look at the
patent files, you looked at
newspaper, maybe subscribed
clipping service, it was manual,
it made it a really expensive
process, so it's not something
that you could do over and over
again. Basically, you would take
a no shot of what was happening
at a certain time. It often
required physical contact, you
know, maybe would go to a
conference and get your
competitor drunk and talk to him
and not tell him who you were,
you know. Probably we've all
done that. So it required
physical contact and it often
required people to identify
themselves or if not identify
themselves, occasionally get
caught. So you're anonymity
would be blown. Now after '95
there's almost an unlimited
number, I would sigh there is an
unlimited number of sources
because they keep coming in and
out to automate data collection,
we can repeat it, do it day
after day, you start looking at
data collected over time, and
you start to analyze trends and
do all kinds of cool stuff. It
can be done remotely. And you
can usually  ‑ ‑ it can usually
be done anonymously, so this
looks a lot like hacking, right?
You can do it remotely, automate
it, you can do it anonymously,
so basically, business
intelligence has now become as
far as I'm concerned, the other
thing about business
intelligence collected online is
that it is immediately
actionable. And this evident in
my talk last year where I talked
about a bot net that wrote about
$20  million worth of cars over
a period of 9 months, 20
million retail, I did it totally
by self. And this data that we
have basically, the inside
information we had some inside
information on servers that
allowed the client to basically
buy things at will, and we were
able to act on that intelligence
immediately. So through the eyes
of a hacker, anything you put
online is potential business
intelligence. And that's a
really important point. Again,
every industry has its own
cases, I picked out a few that I
think we can all relate to. All
right. So imagine the plight of
an online retailer, this is what
they're thinking, I need to keep
my online store up to date and I
need to keep up with what's
happening with competitors as
far as pricing, so I need to
respond to my market basically.
So a hacker looks at that and
says hey, I can watch the store
remotely, I can do it
anonymously and I can automate
the information gathering. So if
I monitor a retail site and you
do it over time it's possible to
leak pricing strategies, you
start to figure things out, you
can Figure out inventory
strategies, you have items
coming and going, I can't is
that? Why is this no longer
offered? Sometimes they can show
supplier issues, right, if it's
something you know that they
always have but they don't have
it now and they really should
have it, they're having a
supplier issue. If they come off
and they are always having a
lower price than you, they are
buying it from somebody
different or they have a better
deal than you have. The problem
is much greater when you are a
retailer and selling specific
item, oh, so we're not talking
Sears now that has an infinite
number of T shirts we're talking
about a real estate website that
has one house on the corner of
3rd  and main, we're talking
about  ‑ ‑ SE is a huge
business, in excess of a billed
a year. Emerchants tend to sell
one item  at a time, you can
learn what is a good thing to
sell on eBay and watching what
sells and for what price. Used
bookstores tend to sell single
copies of things, car
dealerships, any kind of seller
of collectibles, and this group
includes anyone selling any kind
of uniquely identifiable goods.
So if you watch one of these
stores over time, they basically
disclose their entire service
record, right? You monitor this
long enough, you pretty much
have enough information where
you can do their accounting. And
this is something that people
don't think about. Okay. Let's
look at  ‑ ‑ I love picking on
HR because I think they're
probably the biggest source of
leaks within an organization. So
let's think about a HR manager,
put yourself in their position.
They're thinking this year it's
going to be a busy year for us,
we have a lot of stuff going on,
I need to post 250 job postings.
So that's what they're think,
that's what their task is. The
hacker on the other hand thinks,
I can watch these job postings
remotely, and they can be
anonymous while I'm doing it, I
can even look like somebody
else, I could look like an
actual job seeker if I wanted to
and I can automate the
information gathering. So what
does this do? Let's just look at
a simple job listing here, this
is natural listing, I won't tell
you the company  ‑ ‑ this is an
actual listing, I won't tell you
the company it came from, this
is a decent job listing, I will
show you one that's not sos did
but this one is fine, there
doesn't seem to be anything
wrong with it, we have a new
location here, we haven't seen
this before, and we have a new
skill, that's something they
haven't seen before. If you look
at this over time, you're
watching this remotely,
anonymous, doing the information
gather, you can start to grasp
things, you can check out when
new postings come out and new
skills are mentioned, you can
look at when new locations are
mentioned, it's like oh, yeah,
here's did they've never hired a
HR contact representative
before, I wonder what's going on
there, Portuguese? They haven't
needed that before, and an
office in Puerto Rico, what's
going on here? And if you look
at stuff and how the listings
come and go, it starts to paint
a narrative where you can start
figuring out a company's
strategic plans, okay? I've been
in a lot of HR meetings and I've
never heard anybody say are we
leaking our strategic plans by
listing these job I've never
heard anybody say that. Let's
look at another one. I love this
example. I'm going to advertise
a vacancy we have for an IT help
desk professional, that sounds
like a you nice thing to do, a
hacker comes along and says can
I read between the lines to
learn how to compromise your
network? Let's take a look. This
is a recreation of an actual ad,
and this was an actual ad from a
law firm that I used to deal
with, and I saw this published
than I got on the phone, talked
to one of my friends who was a
partner and said you need to
take this ad down now! And so
you look at it and it looks
fine, you know, it's a law firm,
and the company overview, looked
at the description, they have an
immediate opening for an IT help
professional, with remote access
tools like PC anywhere and phone
dial, this was a few years ago.
Talks about the
responsibilities, so yeah, I
mean, it looks like a nice
little opportunity for somebody.
And you're like whoa, what is
this? They are announcing they
have secret, they're a law firm.
Do they have to announce they're
a law firm? No, no. The IT
people you hire for law firms
are essentially the same IT
people you would hire for any
kind of manufacture plant or
whatever you. It's like oh, they
have secrets, we know they have
secret because their a law firm,
we know what kind of secret
these have, they do
acquisitions. So if you deal in
stocks at all, this might be
interesting information, right?
I wonder who's secrets they
have, oh, they've got their
client list. So we though
they've got secrets, we know
what kind of secrets they have,
we know who's secrets they are.
Okay. Let's look a little bit
further here. Never say you have
an immediate opening for an IT
position like this, because that
means there's nobody there now.
[ Laughter ] >> No one is
watching the store. What kind of
social engineering could happen
with nobody watching the store,
you know? Oh, they're telling us
how to break into their network,
they're using PC anywhere and
phone dial‑ in system, so you
guys remember how that works
back in the day, you just
started at the bottom of a block
of numbers and starting dialing
until you get something that
sounds like a fax machine and
then there's nobody watching the
store, get your things ready,
because we can automate attacks,
right? The other thing is that
they're liking the fact they
have problems with remote
access. Okay, so social
engineering‑ wise, I mean, yeah.
And the other thing is this was
the only IT ad they had
advertised and this guy's got
way too many responsibilities.
Helping attorneys, you know,
working remotely, responsible
for network security, software
install, license management,
policy development, problem has
to see do some training along
the way, right, this guy is
overwhelmed so what can possibly
go wrong? What kind of social
engineering things can you think
of? What I would do is call them
up and ask them, they will tell
me if this job has been filled,
oh, yeah, we filled that, great.
You wait for the great to get
settled a little bit, you pose
as one of these attorneys emote,
you're having problems dialing
in, it's 2:00  in the afternoon,
you've got a surprise hearing at
2:15, want to settle things out
of court, you need a paper from
the home office so bad, this
guy's new, he's going to do
everything possible to help you
out. You're in. So be careful
what you put in ad, especially
IT ads. All right. >> [Off mic].
>> Do you ever go fishing, take
a hook out after a fishes mouth
that's kind of the response,
it's like what? Really? Yeah.
Oh, I see. Okay. They did take
the ad down. Okay. Sometimes  ‑
‑ so basically what we talked
about so far is walking websites
and building a database over
time, changes and whatnot.
Sometimes databases are left in
plain sight, and that was what
hand here. This  ‑ ‑ if you
Foley elections at all, this was
one to watch, because it was so
bizarre, it was the senatorial
election of 2006 in the state of
Minnesota, it was an
extraordinarily close election.
It was decided by a few votes
after a long period in the court
systems. There was a lot of
shenanigans going to ban back
and forth, a lost accusations of
hacking, a lost servers going
down, a lot of things happening
but probably the strangest part
about this election was the cast
of characteristics involved we
started out from Frank, probably
known from his days in Saturday
night live where he was a writer
and a cast member for I think 10
years a long time. Norm Coleman
has a really interesting
political background, he started
off  ‑ ‑ well, his first elected
office he was elected mayor of
St.  Paul Minnesota, he changed
party affiliations and we
reelected. He ran for governor
where he was defeated by Jesse
Ventura, he was the incumbents
in this race and he became the
incumbent because his opponent
died in a plane crash before the
election. And then there was a
third‑ party candidate who did
pretty well, he got a half
million votes, Dean Barkley and
he was most well‑ known for
being the political advisor for
this guy Jesse Ventura, so it
was a very likely election, I
believe Ventura was actually the
governor during this period. Of
what happened is after the
election, after the Norm Coleman
had the most votes not enough to
keep the recount from happening,
after the recount, Al Franken
was ahead by three notes, since
month later they decided whether
or not they were going to count
all of the absentee ballots and
Al ended up winning by 312
votes. But like I said, there
were all kinds of charges of
misappropriation of trade
secrets, and in such a close
election, any little dirt you
have on your opponent or
anything is gold. Well, along
the way, somebody came up with a
database of Norm Coleman's
political correcter, their
names, what they did for a
living, Social Security numbers,
their credit card numbers, and
the first thing is we've been
hacked, somebody took our
database, no, they didn't, they
actually put it  ‑ ‑ [ Laughter
] >> [Off mic]. >> They
compressed it and put it in a
directory that was unprotected
on their website. If you want to
hear the story behind this,
Richards how a lot of stuff on
YouTube about this but basically
they just left it there and
there's a lot of this going on.
I don't know if you  ‑ ‑ there's
a tons of this, one of the
things that I do in addition to
business intelligence, I do a
lot of work with data
journalists, primarily in the UK
and the Netherlands and I love
working with an investigative
journalist because they've got a
hacker's mind, they think like
hackers. You give them a tool,
they run with it, they take all
of their background and
experience and do all kinds of
wonderful things. I have been
doing all kinds of stuff like
this. They were finding like
stockbroker's list of clients
and how much their funds were
and where they had their stuff
distributed and they were
basically just doing Google
hacking is although were doing,
just looking for files. So one
other back story to this one
that I think is kind of
interesting, so I somehow came
across this database, and it was
just an Excel spread sheet,
first thing I did was I imported
it into an actual database,
where I could do queries on it
and I was doing queries on it
for a couple of days trying to
find out interesting
combinations of data, and I had
done this before, I mean, I had
worked with a lot of European
newspapers and stuff, on doing
this kind of stuff, mostly from
freedom of information act kind
of stuff and in had enough
information I thought that
probably would have been good
for probably 3 to 5 stories so I
contacted the major news
newspaper Minnesota, told them
what I had done and the kind of
stories they could generate from
this and the response I got was
we have our own IT department,
we really don't need what you
have. All right. Cool. Okay. VNF
can be a major source of leaks,
and especially when it comes to
marketing. You know, some of you
are probably aware of this, but
I've got a couple of examples I
think that are pretty cool. So
you're a marketing person, you
go I need to register so domain
names for new products we have.
Well, the hacker comes along and
says I have been watching these
registrations remotely, I can do
it anonymously and I can
automate the process. Or if I
have $750, I can just buy this
information, a little bit
cheaper, and it's true. You can
see that Apple has registered
about 4500 domain names and for
not a lot of money, you can go
and see what they are all. Do
you think Samsung does this? I'm
sure they've got a copy of it,
you know. The thing that I found
interesting for this is this
particular screen shot I took
during an organizational privacy
talk in Dublin Ireland for the
security forum, so this snapshot
was done in March, they had
4,000  ‑ ‑ 4544 domains on
March  17th. I did this again
earlier on just like last week
and they had almost another
thousand domains they had
checked out. Do you think
there's any intelligence you can
gather from those thousand
domains? I'll bet there is. I'll
bet Samsung has that list. >>
[Off mic]. >> They could be
doing that, they could be
diversions, but there's probably
intelligence you could gather
from that, as well. The question
was, you know, maybe they're not
real domain names but yeah, I
think you can probably read
between the lines there, too. So
here's another example, this was
an example from a data
journalism class I taught
through the center for
investigative journalism in
London. Keep in mind, this is a
group of primarily journalist
from the UK, they were not
Americans, and I asked them, you
know, knowing what you know, can
you tell me when Sarah Palin
gave first real thoughts, first
documented thoughts about
running for president? So they
were all busy and again,
investigative journalists,
they're like hackers, and they
started looking at DNS records,
I didn't tell them to go to DNS
records, they just went there
and they found this listing by
Jay Griffith who after a quick
Google search you can find out
was her political advisor and he
took out the domains Palin for
president, Palin 2012, right,
that gives you a little bit of
an idea of what they were
planning, Sarah Palin 2012 a and
they were all registered on
August  24th  of 2007, that was
pretty much a year before she
was interviewed and before this
ever became  ‑ ‑ before she was
ever even a candidate for vice
president. So there were some
talk in the past. So DNS records
are like a snapshot of the past
like little time capsules.
Employees leak trade secrets all
the time, and they'll do it on a
personal level, just like that
by the number of employees that
you have, that's the kind of
problems that organizations
have. So if you're a HR
director, again, we're taking on
HR, they will say the company is
only as great as their employees
and to succeed I need to train,
hire and retain the very best
ones, I need to invest some
money in them and because of
that, trade  ‑ ‑ your list of
employees is really a trade
secret. So what does a hacker
think? Oh, I hacker thinks
linked in and Twitter is what
they think. Because you can go
on to linked in and within a
matter of minutes I could
probably tell you every  ‑ ‑ for
example every new business
development person in your
company. And if I triangulate
that information with their
endorsements, and what they're
doing on Twitter, I could tell
you who your client list is.
Okay. That's not information you
want to have out. Sometimes you
know, you can't keep people from
using media but you can keep
them from doing really stupid
things. This is a case where
this was actually pretty common,
people leaking the code names of
top secret NSA projects on their
LinkedIn profile. You know,
yeah, this is my experience, I
worked on this project. You
know, it's a lot easier to find
out things about projects if you
know what they're called, right?
And I actually, this is not just
snapshot in, this is still going
on, you can't keep  ‑ ‑ excuse
me, you can't keep people from
doing stupid things but you can
monitor and keep an eye on
things, so what I recommend
people doing is use corporate
social media accounts for any
kind of marketing kind of things
that you've got going, in fact,
social media accounts are now
actually being considered as
intellectual property, just the
account itself. There was a case
about a year ago where there was
a salesperson who was Twitter
account very effectively, their
followers were their customer
base and the name of the Twitter
account was something like
bob@ABC company, well, Bob@ABC
company jumped ship took a job
with XYZ company, what does he
do, he renames his Twitter
handle Bob@XYZ company, takes
all of his contacts with him,
his former employer sues him and
they won and they determined no,
that is not yours this belongs
to your company. So to avoid
anything like that, use official
accounts that you have control
over, if you're going to go use
social media for marketing. Now,
a lot of leaks you really can't
avoid, a lost them are done
transparency for regulatory
purpose, it's worth watching
these things, court record,
people pulling building permits,
there is a lot of information
you can glean by looking all the
things like, you know, licensing
and you know, FCC filing, that
kind of stuff, SEC filings, but
you have to make sure your
competition [indiscernible]
degree that these are problems
for yourself it's more about
learning about your competitors
and what I ask everybody to do
is think about what happens if
your website is monitored and if
all the changes end up in a
database some place, would that
change what you put on your
website? I think it probably
would. I strongly suggest,
especially if you're doing new
product stuff, you are picking
out new domains for new
products, use a proxy, don't do
what Apple appears to be doing.
Don't host your own website on
your own network. There was a
case if you're in Las  Vegas
within the last year, where I
believe it was a group
associated with anonymous got
into the Sans corporation, Sans
if you don't live here in Vegas,
they own the Venetian and in
addition to breaking into their
website, they discovered that
their website was on their
corporate record so that gave
them access to HR records which
they published and strangely
enough, it also gave them access
to the network where all the
slot machines were. [ Laughter ]
>> So there is no reason to host
your own website on your
network. In fact, I don't think
you should host your own website
anywhere, you should have an
agency do that for you. There's
no reason to do it. And the most
important thing to do, I think,
is to get everybody's buy‑ in,
the organizational privacy  ‑ ‑
that organizational privacy is
important to everybody in the
organization. You know, any one
leak basically pulls everybody
down, so you need to get
everybody's buy‑ in and again,
this is a training issue is what
it really is. You need
enforceable policy. How many
times have you seen security
policies that aren't
enforceable? You know, there's
as good as not having did
they're worn not having policies
because they give you a good
feeling. And when I say
enforceable, they should be
enforceable through tools, there
should be tools enforcing those,
you shouldn't need people to do
it, you know. You should be
doing your own business
intelligence on your own system.
Audit everything that you
publish. Anything that goes out
in your website should be
audited through some group
hopefully that group isn't
marketing, because they're empty
going to get it, okay? Because
the real important thing here is
that security and privacy are
not IT functions, they're
everybody's responsibility. IT
can't protect you from the
nonsense that you showed you
here. Don't disclose a lot of
organizational information on
every job posting. It's not even
important and in most cases it
may you don't even needed to put
the name of your company,
there's no reason to have job
listings on your own corporate
website. There isn't. I
encourage people to use cookies
to track their competitors when
they're coming to their website
and it's good to do cookies and
you start to associate cookies
of known gateways of your
competitors, so that way if you
have their cookies, if they're
using a laptop or mobile device,
if they go somewhere else or go
home and go to your website,
sometimes people will go to your
corporate website and look at
different things at home than
they might at the job. So you
can really screw with people,
too, when you do this. And I
suggested this to a number of
clients I've never had one do it
but if you're tracking your
competitors and you've got their
cookies, you can show them
whatever you want, you can show
them different prices, you can
turn it into a recruiting
website to recruit from your
competitors. I would love to see
somebody do that sometime. Okay.
To the that's my talk, thanks
for coming. If you have
questions, we've got a little
bit of time now. We've 5
minutes, otherwise, rhyme doing
a book signing at the no starch
booth. Thank you all for coming.
I appreciate it. [Applause] >>
[Off mic]. >> I don't know. >>
[Off mic]. >> We're ready for
questions here at the mic or are
we going to jump right to the
desk? >> [Off mic]. >> Sure.
Your comment about the hacking
with the  ‑ ‑ >> I'm sorry,
what? >> The casino in Las
Vegas, your comment, your
comment and presentation about
the casino being hacked. >>
There's a lot of noise. >> Come
on up. >> I understand that  ‑ ‑
you said that you published
donor lists. >> Not in every
case, only certain donors that's
my understanding. >> [Off mic].
>> Okay. Okay. >> [Off mic]. oh,
yeah. >> [Off mic]. Well, a lot
of it is  ‑ ‑ it was also a
political thing. >> Yeah. >>
[Off mic]. >> Okay. >> [Off
mic]. >> Great advice. >> Thank
you. >> [Off mic]. >> No, but
that's a great identify and this
is something that I'm going to
publish. Like I they'd, there's
a lot of awareness about this.
>> [Off mic]. >> Most of the
things don't really
[indiscernible] I mean  ‑ ‑ >>
[Off mic]. >> She was saying in
2007 about running in 2012. Oh,
I see. >> Right. [Voices
overlapping] >> Oh, thank you.
>> [Off mic]. Washington
D.C.VIP. >> Okay. >> I'm going a
book signing at noon. Is this
still on? I was asked where the
book signing was going to be. >>
I have most idea what I'm
supposed to do. Sort of. >> Is
this on? Okay. probably, no.
Sometimes I think I do thing
better drunk. I'm not typically
good at [indiscernible] I'm good
at [indiscernible]. So yeah, I'm
not good at single pin picking,
I was submitted for DEF CON was
for a lock pick game, I've been
doing a lot of that recently.
After I leave here, I'm going to
go by me some new toys in the
vendor room. We've got about 6
minutes before we talk again.
How many people here understand
the basis of how tour functions?
Mostly. Okay. I'm going to do a
real quick rehash, I'm going to
try to limit it to 10 minutes, I
have 45 minutes and in want to
get to the main dirt. >> Okay,
hi, Scout with speaker opps and
it's my pleasure to introduce
Adrian. [Applause] "This text is
being provided in a rough draft
format.  Communication Access
Realtime Translation (CART) is
provided in order to facilitate
communication accessibility and
may not be a totally verbatim
record of the proceedings."