Announcer: And so, right now
we're going to open up track
two, our 11:00 o'clock slot with
Maggie speaking about GFCI's and
girl fault interrupted.
[Applause] Maggie: I'm glad I
don't have to stand behind that.
So, hello DEF CON. If you are
here to see sparks and smoke,
you've came to the right talk.
I'm super excited to be here to
talk to you guys about something
that I tripped over, pun
intended. [Inaudible.] But
first, let me tell you a little
bit about myself. My name is
Maggie Jauregui and I have about
three years of security
experience. The first two at
Intel in Mexico doing security
validation for the graphics
driver on the software side,
specifically for DirectX 8, 10
and 11. For the past year, I've
been working in the U.S. doing
software security validation for
wireless innovation
applications. This is my fourth
DEF CON, first time speaking,
super excited. I come from the
most incredible country in the
world and if you haven't been
there, you really should. Bucket
list it at some point. The most
amazing people, food, everything
and I'm having a hard time
figuring out why I ever left. I
got an incredible education as
well. I got to participate in
math tournaments where I was
named fourth best in the country
two years in a row and first and
second best in highly script
date a couple times. When I'm
not doing techy stuff, I do more
artsy stuff. A couple of
disclaimers: Everything I do,
research, images, here is my own
and in no way, shape or form
does it represent anything on
the side of my employer's past,
present, or future. Like I said,
my experience was mostly
software so this business is
something I've been looking at
for a few months. I don't claim
myself the GFCI queen of the
world so if you have
corrections, or suggestions or
ideas, I'd be super happy to
talk to you guys about them.
There's a small part of me, or
maybe not that small part of me,
that loves that I can start my
first DEF CON talk ever with: So
I was doing my hair the other
day . . . [Audience laughing]
'cause I was going to go out on
a date and this guy thought we
would save millions
communicating through RF. So we
bought a couple walkie-talkies
and enough batteries until
kingdom come and we hadn't
really synced as to when to use
them. So I was doing my hair to
go out and I thought I heard
something in the other room,
someone speaking through the
radio. So I ran over there and I
talked through it. "Hello,
hello, is anyone there?"
Nothing. So I come back to the
bathroom and I click the call
button to make it buzz on the
other side [makes buzz noise]
and when I do that, the GFCI of
my hair dryer on the wall
vibrates viciously out of
control -- horrible sound, then
a spark and smoke. So, my jaw
dropped. I was like, "Oh my god,
you've got to see this." And,
yeah, for some reason I thought
my hair dryer was dead so I went
and got another one and tried
the same thing. And it worked as
well. But devices keep working
after you disable the GFCI. It's
only the GFCI that I get to
effect. So then we needed
supplies. Where can we get a
whole bunch of hair dryers and
stuff? So thank Goodwill for all
the materials for the
presentation. We got a couple of
GFCI sockets, an antenna, and
more decent radios. I studied
for my radio license. I got my
call name and all. [Applause]
And then I started thinking, why
would this matter or how do
these devices interact with us
on a day-to-day basis? Because
don't get me wrong, if someone
can DOS even temporarily my hair
blow drying ability in the
morning, to me that is an
extremely high severity
vulnerability but I wasn't sure
that the rest of the world would
see it that way. So where are
these things? One of the people
that we worked with suggested I
look into AFCI's as well. That
kind of put the picture
together. Because in your house,
your outlets, your electricity
is basically either protected by
GFCIs, AFCIs, sometimes both.
So, I really focused more on
GFCIs and I'll tell you guys why
in a second, but we do go over a
little bit of AFCI vulnerability
towards RF as well. Why are
these things there? They serve
two different purposes. GFCIs
intend to protect you from
electric shock. They have to do
so in a really quick manner. I
think they have between 25 and
40 milliseconds to stop because
when the body comes in contact
with from five to 30 million
amps, then that's when your
heart goes into metrical shock
and that's when ventricles
instead of contracting the way
they normally do, they just
spazz out. Whenever it senses
that the electricity -- if you
think of the circuit as water
and what comes in has to go
somewhere, so it has to return.
If not the same amount of
current that's coming in is
coming out, it detects there's a
problem. It has to be really
specific and really quick.
That's what GFCI's do. AFCI's on
the other hand are trying to
keep your house from catching
fire. It's basically like worn
out old cables, if there's a
spark anywhere, AFCI's are the
ones that are supposed to find
it. They do so by analyzing the
wave form of the alternating
current. So it has to be smooth
and it's a much more complex
little piece of equipment than a
GFCI. So, code requirement.
Every year the National
Electrical Code deliberates
where we need what. GFCI's are
needed anywhere where people can
come into contact with both
electric equipment and water.
So, your bathroom, pools, hot
tubs, kitchens, laundry areas,
anything above grade level,
unfinished basements or garages.
Whole bunch of stuff. And AFCI's
pretty much protect everything
else. They do overlap in a
couple things, I think the
kitchen and laundry area. Other
than that, the general living
areas, the family rooms, dining
rooms, living rooms, bedrooms,
sunrooms, any other room. I live
in Oregon. I need some. Okay.
This is how GFCI's work. Their
little diagram. And it's really
quite simple. It's a little
transformer and there's a
magnetic core, the toroid, and
so you -- and there's an
insulated copper wire that goes
around them and that's just a
general normal transformer.
Through it go the wires, the hot
wire on the way out and the
neutral or the hot wire on the
way in and the neutral on the
way out. According to the right
hand rule, if the currents are
going opposite directions and
they are the same magnitude,
then they should cancel each
other out. There should be no
current in that wire. If it
detects a small current in that
wire, then it's calibrated
specifically to 3 or 5
milliamps, then the solid state
circuitry will inform the shunt
trip to open the circuit and it
will save you from
electrocution. Pretty simple
electro-mechanical. So, here it
is. Right hand rule, going one
way, going the other way, they
should cancel each other out but
there's also -- if you notice in
the little toroid there's two,
the hot and the neutral, and
there's an extra one with a test
button. So if you push the test
button, it will enable that
third line, which will imbalance
it and trip it. It will cause a
trip. That's what you're
supposed to do to test if the
GFCI mechanism is actually
working. I recommend for people
to test it often. How many of
you test your GFCI's often? Very
good. I'm super impressed. Cool.
Okay. Inside there is something
called a solenoid. Oops. This
thing that says "shunt trip used
to open circuit," that's what
this solenoid is. And there's
the coil that goes around the
transformer then coils around
this little thing and inside it
is like a Silverbullet that
moves in and out and there's a
spring. So as long as the
power's connected, the spring
keeps the bullet inside. If it
notices -- if it gets the signal
that there's a little current
there that shouldn't be, then
the bullet comes out and pops
the reset button, opening the
circuit. This is the thing that
we cause trouble with with RF,
so that's why I'm going into it.
[Inaudible] Like I said, we're
analyzing wave forms and making
sure that they are smooth. It's
a lot more complicated as it
does thermal checking and it
does, I think, also some of them
do ground fault and the wave
form analyzing and something
else -- power surge. You're
dealing with much higher
voltages and it's a little more
scary. So now, some demos. I
start with the less impressive
one. Just so you know. This is
just a regular GFCI plugged into
a wall where this is close
range. So we're pointing at it,
putting it nearby with either a
radio or the antenna and this is
what happens. [Loud Buzz.] You
should be able to see some
smoke. But it might not be too
noticeable. You see some?
[Chiming sound] There you go, a
little bit of smoke. This is the
first one. This one we get a
spark. These are both closed.
The little box is closed. Then I
open it up so we can see what's
actually going on inside. This
one we can start to look
through. [Buzzing] You saw? That
blows it up. That's pretty much
it. This is the socket, also
close range. You should look at
the lead in the corner. There
you go. That's all. Do it from
the side. Do it from the back.
Now across the wall. Okay,
confession time. We were testing
these things. First thing I did
after testing the 90-degree
built into the plug GFCI was try
to find them around the house.
So I tested the bathroom ones,
the kitchen ones and then other
people's houses, friends of
course, with their consent.
[Audience laughing] Because I
consider it like lock picking.
It must be the same. You know,
If you do your own, if you buy
things to break them apart, then
it's okay but you're not
supposed to go messing around
with people. That's not why you
get a radio license, no. So, but
yes, at some point testing one
of the sockets on the wall, we
heard a distant vibration
somewhere else and we were like,
"what's that?" It was something
in the neighbor's house. So we
stopped immediately but we
realized we could do it across
the walls, too. Radio on one
side, GFCI on the other. Bad
filming. Little delay. [Buzzing]
Basically the same. Now remote.
We got it up to about three or
four yards depending on the
device. Yeah, it really depended
on the device. Some of them
needed to be really close, some
could be a little further. I did
get recommendations from people
to use a bilateral amplifier or
you can use a huger, bigger
antenna with a tripod, but you
know you got a lot of wattage
and it becomes scary and a
little more terroristy. With
this little thing, I was
affecting my neighbors. You
know, I didn't want to figure
out, I don't know, that I could
fry a chicken with it. It wasn't
really the point. There. So
doing different pulses. And
actually it would burn up. You
can kind of see the button move
there. So this is the cool one.
Try to see if you can notice the
button flying out. [buzzing]
[Laughter] [Applause] This is
when you open the GFCI. When I
got here for real, so yeah,
first thing -- [Laughter] -- I
swear everything works if you go
check, everything works. I just
had to check to see if they were
vulnerable, everything is
vulnerable here. The sockets,
the hair dryer, everything. I
just tested them. Then I wanted
to show my dad, "Look, here's
what I do." I said, "I'll film
it, what the hell." With this
one, you get the flying piece of
component like flaming out of
it, it almost caught my dad's
shirt on fire. So, for the demos
later, we have a prepared goon.
[Buzzing] Male Voice: It's
smoking. Wow. You're lucky it
didn't get me. [Laughter]
[Inaudible] [Applause] Maggie:
So, this is what a fried GFCI
looks like. The solenoid. The
encapsulation of the wire on the
solenoid melts out making it not
a solenoid anymore, so it's not
a GFCI anymore. That's why it
stops working. The device keeps
working because what we do is
that -- let me go back to the
diagram of the solenoid. Here.
We get the bullet to move,
because it's expecting -- okay.
Maybe I should go back to where
we were. Sorry about that. The
reason why I didn't try with
bigger things is because of the
wattage and because it was
scary. But we did notice people
who have done this before. There
was a Youtube video. I thought
that would be good enough
instead of me trying to jump
onto my house and install this
huge thing. [Applause] Okay,
cool. So, I didn't make this
myself so I can't vouch for its
validity but it's pretty cool.
They have an antenna on the top
of another house. They are
pointing it at the circuit
breaker, the AFCIs. Male Voice:
[Inaudible] There's an antenna
right there above the tree I
think. Black pole, radio
antenna. Maggie: It's this
antenna on the top of a house
and it's pointing to the circuit
breaker of a different house.
[Inaudible] Cool, that's good
enough. So they pointed it at
the circuit breaker of a
different house. This is what
happens. [Video -- Audio
inaudible] Really slow video.
Male Voice: You can stop packing
the wireless for just 2 minutes
please. [Laughter] Maggie: Okay,
so you see, you see? So it
bounced a whole bunch. AFCI's
are also vulnerable to RF, you
just need much lower frequencies
and bigger antennas that are
much more expensive and scarier
so I didn't do that. Male Voice:
Seems like a logical breaking
point. You guys know the drill.
A round of applause for our
first time speaker. [Applause]
Cheers. Maggie: Cheers.
[Applause] Male Voice: To DEF
CON. Maggie: To DEF CON. So I
can't guarantee there wasn't
someone back there sparking the
wires making these things
trippy. We're kind of trusting
these Youtube people but there's
also, you know, the national
association -- Male Voice: This
is really cool. Maggie: Thank
you.[Laughter] So, I did find a
letter from the National
Association of Amateur Radio,
kind of apologizing, because the
amateur radio enthusiast's
neighbors were complaining that
their AFCI circuit breakers were
being tripped. And they did work
with Levatron to make a better
breaker that would withstand
that kind of frequency. So
what's going on? Like I said, I
only did the directional
antenna, that's kind of where I
stopped. The fundamental thing
that I'm doing is extending the
electromagnetic field that comes
from the radio directionally and
that is captured by the
transformer which creates a
current that flows through that
wire. And then it makes it
believe that there's a ground
fault but it doesn't -- it
thinks -- what? Yeah. Oh yeah,
we weaponized it. Pepper laser.
When I did this my antenna
wouldn't work because there was
so much metal in the hair dryer
that it messed up my
electromagnetic field.
[Laughter] I can't say much
about my antenna.[Applause] This
is about as much as I can say
about my antenna. [Inaudible
voice in audience] But look at
it now. Okay. So now, resonance.
Wires or antennas. We are
antennas and things resonate to
a certain frequency. Like if you
grab a tuning fork and you hit
it against your leg and then put
it up against a guitar, the
string of the note that is tuned
to the same note as the fork
will vibrate. Only that one.
Things are tuned to resonate to
a certain frequency, that's how
radios work too. You modify the
metal inside, the amount of
twists and the width of it
determine what frequency it
vibrates to. Things are made to
work at a certain frequency. I
think for 120 volts it's like 60
hertz all around. So we're
talking about possibly a distant
cousin harmonic that the devices
are capturing. And I can do two
things. I can either do what I
showed you guys where, I should
do both -- I can either trip it,
meaning it was on and now it's
off, but I can click the reset
button and it will work again. I
don't ruin the GFCI mechanism.
Or, I can melt it and it will
never work again. It's just hard
wired. So, that leads me to
believe that the different
materials and the different
designs are either capturing,
like resonating exactly to a
harmonic that it is expecting or
just something annoying and not
quite enough to move the bullet
all the way through. So, yeah,
this is what it looks like on
the inside. These are the
components that this one, the
FCR, we'll talk about it a
little bit more. That's the one,
this one and probably the C4 are
the ones that shoot out. This
will be the transformer that's
capturing and this is the
solenoid that melts. I have to
go back to the other picture to
show you from before. This. So,
the bullet usually gets the
signal it's supposed to and goes
all the way through. When I'm
giving it kind of a weird
frequency that it's not used to
and it's way smaller than what
it expects, instead of 60 hertz,
it's a lot more, so it moves.
Like a little bit forward then
back, a little bit forward and
back. It's alternating. So it
does this and that's what causes
the vibrating sound [buzzing
sound] and things like this are
only supposed to work for so
long. Like when you buzz someone
into a building, the thing is
meant to just be a shunt trip,
right, you click it and then
it's opened and the person walks
in. If you stand there and you
push it, it will melt. It's not
meant to withstand long periods
of time. So, when we keep
annoying it for long enough, it
overheats and melts and it stops
working. Okay. I was just
admiring my GFCIs. The ones that
are vulnerable and the ones that
are not. The top ones are
susceptible to my attack, the
bottom ones aren't. Can anyone
guess or see anything that is
different between these two
things? [Inaudible voice in
audience.] 	Yes. The transformer
on the bottom ones is definitely
larger and has more turns.
There's also a little chip in
there, in the top ones. This is
that chip. I couldn't find
these, the actual ones that I
had physically. I found a data
sheet for one of the patents and
I'll show the patents that I
found that are vulnerable and
ones that are not. That patent
led me to a number piece and I
went to go see that but the ones
that I had in my hand were not
that number. The data sheet that
I found supposedly does protect
against... The reason why I
think its vulnerable is because
sometimes cheap Chinese
electronics will count both
positive and negative current,
so it's adding up slowly but it
measures that there's more and
more current coming through
there. If it's only measuring
the positives, like it should,
then it will never get to the
threshold that it needs. Right?
So, what I think is that this
little chip is -- we couldn't
find the data sheet for it
anywhere -- is counting both the
positive and the negative
impulses of the frequency that
I'm sending and therefore
conducting the current. If it
just looked at the positive,
then it wouldn't happen. In the
case of the FDR's, one of the
ones that jumped up in flames,
and it was very, very simple and
I've calculated when the gate
gets a little signal. It's
really low. I forget what it
was, but a tiny amount of amps,
then it will connect them. So,
if it notices a little current
there, it will activate the
shunt trip. So, it connects to
the solenoid and the little
ceramic capacitor also had a
chunk of it jumped out. And
these explode from overheating,
overcurrent or short circuit, in
this case, I'm thinking
overheating as we saw. It melts.
The GFCI power outlets -- really
the most I could get out of
them, the ones built in the
wall. The house where I live is
17 years old and the bad patents
that I found are about 15 years
old, so it makes sense. But the
newer ones that I got at the
store, I could trip them but I
couldn't melt them. And these
have a centric transformer coil
which was a different thing that
I didn't see anywhere else. The
patents, the bad and the good,
it seems like there's kind of an
equal amount of yes' and no's
but if you look at the count
that I found, there is a really
popular bad GFCI out there. 1999
patent, so it's fifteen years
old and I found in it a whole
bunch of things and
across-the-board in a lot of
different brands. I'm not naming
brands but pretty much all of
them. They are all Chinese,
pretty much. Yeah, this was my
bag coming in. I was worried
that TSA would - [Laughter]--
ruin my presentation but they
didn't. Other cases in which it
might be a bad idea, some people
don't even know that their stuff
is connected to a GFCI. I saw
people online saying, "For some
reason if I trip this button the
lamp outside will shut off."
It's like, what? So, if you get
a GFCI outlet, the top two
screws are to plug into the
wall, the hot and neutral and
the bottom two you can connect
to other plugs or appliances and
it will make them part of the
circuit so they're also GFCI
protected or vulnerable.
Relevance, why could this
matter? Well RFI could be just
accidental, that you live near a
radio station or an amateur
radio enthusiast or it could be
intentional. It's wireless and
fingerprint free. Although I did
read that devices have very
specific frequency so they could
do forensics and match the
signal, the bad signal to the
device but I didn't get into
that. And that was one of the
things that kind of annoyed me
from my talk. I found it was
either just annoying, trolling,
where someone is making their
guacamole and I'm like, "ha, now
you can't," or potentially super
serious things where it would
matter, like someone who lives
alone and is elderly and depends
on a breathing machine or
overnight hemo-dialysis or
depends on a machine somehow.
That would be bad if they could
trip the switches somehow. Male
Voice: Hospitals. Maggie: Yeah,
hospitals. I tried not to get
into that because this is my
first talk and I don't want to
anger the wrong people. There
are medical grade GFCI's but I
didn't look into them. Also
hospitals should have a whole
bunch of other things to protect
them, right? So, if someone
attacked their AFCIs for
blackouts, they're prepared for
that, they're staffed and
there's manual overrides. So
they should be good but, yes, in
public places, it could matter.
Just recently there was a GFI
news article about an eight year
old boy in Lake Carrow in Texas
who died, electrocuted, because
of a GFI malfunction and it was
hard wired. I mean, it was
burnt, it didn't work but it was
on. It burnt on. And he was in
the water for a total of 15
seconds I think before he was
pulled out. And the city said
that the city limits changed and
that's why they hadn't
originally checked for
everything to be up to code
standards. So, that's an example
of when it could matter and for
the most part, it won't matter.
It's kind of like a life
insurance. I mean -- well I
guess we're all gonna die
someday -- but you might never
need it. I don't know that my
life has been saved by my hair
dryer countless times but it's
nice to know maybe I did need it
and then it was there for me.
You know? It's one of those
things that when you need it,
you really need it. So, yes, our
solutions are testing often.
Make sure that button pops up
the reset and just reset it
again. Updating to newer
patents, the newer devices
should be better. They would all
kind of be vulnerable but to
different frequencies. The newer
ones are vulnerable to lower
frequencies like they are
supposed to, the 60 hertz. The
thing that kind of shocks me is
that we've known about this for
a long time. And it's been fixed
for a long time. So why is it
that everything I buy and
everywhere I go I can do this?
We should know better, right?
Male Voice: Could we get a
recall for some of these
products? Maggie: Yeah and I
will talking to some of these
and saying, "Hey." I'm guessing
older patents mean cheaper in
mass production. Maybe in a hair
dryers, maybe it doesn't matter
but what if, you know? Also if
you have a loved one who's home
alone or yourself who depends on
an electrical appliance being
on, just make sure you have
other options like a power
generator, batteries, or a
manual override so you have
wiggle time to react. And
another thing that we thought
was to do a little fair day cage
grounded encasing covering the
thing that should also be a
solution. Now I need my lovely
assistant so we can do some of
these things. Okay. For my first
trick --[Laughter] [Inaudible
voice in the audience.] What?
Computer Voice: Frequency
Closed. Maggie: So, the power
outlets we only found that we
could do from really close by
but then we thought wires are
antennas too and they will
conduct an electro-magnetic
field. If you do it through the
wire, like maybe thinking across
the wall, you could potentially
get to it. There we go. That's
one. [Applause] And now. These
two. Now hair dryer, live from
track 2. Alright. I opened these
up so we could see something
interesting. Male Voice: Why are
you standing back there? Buzzz.
Maggie: Get a camera. Male
Voice: Are those electronics
I've got on me? [Laughter.]
Maggie: Should we... [Inaudible
voice in audience.] If the
device is on while you're
interfering with it, it will
turn off but then you just
unplug it, re-plug it and the
device works. Should I plug this
in? Male Voice: Yeah, hold on.
[Random Noise][Inaudible]
Maggie: I have to reset it.
These have not been tampered
with, I just opened them up. I'm
trying to get a camera so you
can see it. I don't know if it
will be big enough. We have
someone ready with a cup of
water just in case. Nothing has
ever happened, although it was a
close call. Male Voice:
Something has to break. Maggie:
We sacrificed the PCB and
countless hair dryers for the
demo gods. You know how it is.
Male Voice: Plugging in the
camera does help. Male Voice: It
is plugged in. I swear. Maggie:
Nope. We can just do it here.
Male Voice: Here you go. Maggie:
Oh cool. No. Okay. Male Voice: I
think we're doing it live.
Maggie: Doing it live. Male
Voice: Hold it up to the mic,
then they can hear it. Male
Voice: Don't point it at me.
Maggie: I need another mic
that's not on my face.
[Laughter[LW1]] And you can --
this is one of the more sensible
ones. You could probably do it
from a bit. Do the laser,
there's a purple laser. Male
Voice: How many hands do you
think he has? Maggie: Sorry.
[Clicking Noise.] If we do it
from closer, maybe we'll get it
faster. Male Voice: I swear to
god this is not a hold my gear
moment.[Laughter] Male Voice:
There you go, it's smoking! Male
Voice: We have magic
smoke.[Applause] Male Voice:
Wanna do the other one?
[Inaudible] Maggie: And yeah, I
could show, maybe... [Hair dryer
noise] Still works. We could do
another one. You guys want to do
another one? [Applause] Last
one. I swear. We have like 6
more. By the way, I thought to
make it interesting whoever
tweets me the coolest or most
bizarre thing that you could
think of that would be bad that
could be done with this by like
4:00 p.m., I'll get you just off
the plane from Mexico Also Anjo
tequila and I'll give it to you
later at the Rio somewhere for
your Saturday night partying
needs. [Applause] So tweet me
maybe.[Laughter] Male Voice:
There you go. You all ready?
[Buzzing] Maggie: Better.
[Applause] Thanks to awesome
co-workers and friends who've
helped me, given me ideas. We've
got a cute little blooper.
Where'd the antenna go? Oh no!
[Laughter] Yeah. Proxy is famous
now. That's about it. If you
guys have questions or
something, I think I have a
couple seconds. Male Voice: If
you have any questions, there is
a Q & A mic right here. Come to
the mic. Male Voice: KD5QLN.
Have you tried other frequencies
besides UHF like 2 meters?
Maggie: Oops, I didn't hear
that. Male Voice: Have you tried
other frequencies besides UHF
like 2 meters? Maggie: 2 meters?
Male Voice: Like 120 megahertz?
Male Voice: Anything besides 2
meters? Male Voice: She's doing
UHF. That's 420. Maggie: No.
Male Voice: 120 megahertz I
could probably do it. Maggie: We
tried the range of the radio.
Not much more. Male Voice: Okay.
Male Voice: More questions, come
up to the mic. Male Voice: This
is sort of a shameless plug. You
have your technician's license?
Maggie: Yes. Male Voice: You
should show up tomorrow at noon
and get your general or your
extra. We're doing amateur radio
exams across the hall at the
Krypto Privacy Village. Maggie:
Awesome. Male Voice: Yeah, if
you guys want to do
this.[Applause] Male Voice: Any
more questions? Maggie: If not,
you can catch me later. I hope
to meet you guys at a party or
hallway near you. Thank you.
[Applause]