>> So we're going to get this
all going. >> Okay, thank you
very much. Today I am going to
be presenting my topic which is
'Meddle: Framework for piggy-
back fuzzing as well as it's
pretty useful for reverse
engineering, tool development as
well. This presentation is not
affiliated. First I'm going to
go over a little bit of
background, then I'm going to go
into the Meddle Framework itself
then I'm going to go into a few
examples of using the framework
for several different purposes.
One is, the first demo is
attacking the OpenSource XRDP
server and then afterwards we
are going to go into go into
dumping the devise IO control
messages and I have written a
parser to the capture into
Windows Message Analyzer as well
and if we have time we're
going to
>>[Audience] Can I
interrupt momentarily? What's
the initiation with first time
speakers? >> That thing that I
said wasn't going to happen, is
happening. (Laughter) >.Speaker
Okay, sorry about that guys. So
first about myself, I'm visiting
from Vancouver, Canada. I
currently work at Microsoft, the
presentation is not affiliated.
I originally got interested in
re-engineering from game
hacking, if anyone cares -
probably not. So first I'm going
to go over a little bit of
background. There are several
different types of Fuzzing‚..and
some of these overlap with one
another. They aren't exactly
distinct. Like for example, File
Format Fuzzing can be PDF for
Microsoft Word meanwhile
protocol Fuzzing could be things
like RDP; Application Fuzzing
could be COM objects or API
calls and some of those cases
you might be looking to say,
escape a browser sandbox or it
could be for elevation of
privilege on the local machine.
And web application Fuzzing is
kind of a different story, it
could be Joomia or web
applications or looking for SQL
injections. There's quite an
array of existing Fuzzing tools
out there right now. A couple of
these worth particular mention
is I would say is SPIKE from
Immunity is a very popular
commercial one from my
experience. Another couple worth
mentioning is SAGE from
Microsoft that is a really
fascinating one that I'm going
to go to go into a touch of
detail on. The IOCtrlFuzzer from
eSage Lab here is also really
cool. It's actually running in
the Windows driver mode and it
Fuzzes all the driver
communication coming from the
driver itself. It's going to be
related to one of our later
examples where we're doing a
similar thing from user mode.
There are quite a few different
Fuzzing algorithms, these are
only a couple of the particular
ones that I say are worth really
good mentions. First, Naive
protocol fuzzing, basically you
don't understand anything about
the file protocol itself. You
would just basically randomly
modify the data yourself and
then load that data and
application itself and hope that
it would crash. So you don't
know anything about the file and
format, you don't know anything
about the protocol. Protocol
aware fuzzing is where you
understand certain thing about
the, you might know a certain
blob of blob of data represents
a unicode string for example,
maybe a length followed by
unicode string and then you
might try some specifically
string related fuzzing attacks.
You might try a format string,
you might try, might try
increasing the length of the
string to be extremely large as
well. So that's more protocol
aware fuzzing where you have
some underlying understanding of
the protocol. There's some real
cool examples of more Advanced
algorithms, Auto Fuzz
implemented a really cool
protocol learning approach. You
can give it multiple recordings
of say client to server
communications and then it
builds a model of what it thinks
that protocol is and then it
starts fuzzing. So in that case
it might recognize that this is
a string, this is a looks to be
the command and this state leads
to that state and then it might
try some protocol specific
attacks. Feedback driven fuzzing
is a really interesting approach
when ran by quite a few people
and it's used by Sage for
example. It's where you actually
do run time tracing of the
application you are fuzzing and
then you basically do
controlling of the fuzzed input
and then you see how it affects
execution of the application you
are fuzzing and then you can
drive certain branches and
conditions to be taken and
explore deeper non accessible
code so that's a really cool
approach. Google, well the code
coverage fuzzing was proven very
effective by Google. Google had
a big fuzzier project where they
fuzzed Adobe Flash, they built a
collection of terabytes of Adobe
Flash files, then they rendered
each one of the those Adobe
Flash files in an instrumented
version of Flash Finery, and
they recorded which code was
executed with everyone of those
flash files and then they
reduced, they did a reduction
then, they reduced the set of
flash files to the minimum
amount of flash that gets
complete code coverage within
the Adobe flash library. So that
way they know what they are now
working with a set of Adobe
flash files which gets code
coverage as they can get using a
small set of files. Then they
began using the fuzzing and that
was a really affective approach.
I think they discovered over 200
vulnerabilities that were
reported to Adobe. A very
effective, very effective
approach. So I'm going to give a
quick introduction to a few of
the more basic fuzzing
algorithms. This is an example
of file format fuzzing. True
type fonts have been the target
of attack. I've seen quite a few
cases where, the dokoo
vulnerability, the dokoo
government, well the dokoo apt,
it exported vulnerability in
their true type library because
you can actually embed them say
in a Word document and it will
be installed when you render the
Word document. And it's
actually, the true type fonts
are actually rendered in the
driver, in the kernel mode so
they are rendered by 132k.sis,
so if you open that document it
gets remote code execution at
the kernel level so it's already
really screwed you. So, for a
basic approach for fuzzing true
type font, you would actually
take an existing true type font
and modify some of the data
randomly creating thousands of
variance in that true type font.
And then you would install each
of those fonts, render each font
and then you would be hoping for
the blue screen of death crashed
report. As a really simple
approach to it. But the true
type font is actually really
complicated because it's got
it's own virtual machine
language built in there, which
they actually use for
exploitive, which was rather
impressive. So, another example
of simple protocol fuzzing could
be RDP, RDP client connecting up
to an RDP server and you're just
intercepting that network
traffic that is being sent and
received and you're just
modifying some of that data in
transit hoping for either the
client or server to crash to
indicate a vulnerability. So
you'd queue up many of the RDP
clients connecting up to the
server constantly modifying the
data hoping for, hoping to
reveal a problem. But the
problem here is that the later
messages in the RDP protocol are
actually encrypted messages, so
it might not have quite the
desired affect that you'd like
unless you, unless you, unless
you do the fuzzing before the
encryption, internally within
the RDP protocol. So an example.
How you can target the encrypted
messages is you could do a
client logic where you actually
implement the fuzzing logic
before the encrypting logic. Or
you can actually take files
approach starting the protocol
as well for example. Lieu Wii
gee and Romeo (indiscernible)
had everyone really worried back
in early 2012. And when he
posted his concept for an the
Microsoft RD[P] vulnerability,
his proof of concept was
(indiscernible) the server and
pipe in this binary provided. Do
this many times and you're going
to see the RD[P] vulnerability.
There was a lot of worries
surrounding this vulnerability,
because it was hugely
exploitable. A lot of people are
(indiscernible)ing internet. And
had a reliable (indiscernible)
promote for this. But lucky for
us, it was a really hard
vulnerability. And there's still
no publicly known exploitation
really. I'm just going to skip
over it quickly, because I don't
think we have enough time for
that one. Now I'm going to go
into metal. It's open source
frame work for vulnerability
fuzzing. You're going to be
writing most of the plug ins in
iron type font. Which is
basically the same as python for
most purposes. You can include
(indiscernible) as far as I can
tell, it's mostly the same. The
frame work itself is written in
(indiscernible). But you don't
need to touch that. You want to
add functionality at the higher
level. I put a lot of work into
making it support both 32 and
64bit process, so most
everything you do is independent
64bit process. And
unfortunately, it's Windows
only. I haven't.. I've only
been running this on a 64bit
O[S] myself. So I know it only
works on 64 bit or 32 against
64bit processes. It still
needs to be tested on a 32‚bit
O[S]. But hopefully there
shouldn't be any problems there
. So the goal really is to bring
real simplistic environment in
order to write some fuzzing
attacks. And to be extendable,
reproducible of course, because
you want to know what caused the
application crash to occur. So
the original goal is to go after
piggy back fuzzing. So you
already have an RD[P] already
for example. So the idea is to
automate many of those RD[P]
clients mucking up the RD[P]
server to implement the protocol
for you. So the frame works
consists of... you only have
to worry about the iron python
stuff on the right. It has one
controller which is controlling
the attack or measurement. And
each controller can have
multiple processes. Like you
might be running 20 RD[P]
clients in parallel all
connecting to an RD[P] server.
And each process implemented
multiple target. Each target
implements a set of hooks. So
you might have one target with
win soft ten and one target for
win soft receive. And you might
have a target that handle
information to the process for
example as well coordinating
resolution. How generally how
the controller, how you set up
the controllers is it's... the
default controller have it
running right now does a
measurement baseline, first of
all. So it'll connect... it'll
create, say, an RD[P] client
connecting up to the RD[P]
server. And in that process,
it'll record say 100 messages
sent to the server and three
messages received. So that's
instrumented as the baseline,
first of all. So you might...
in that process, it creates an
RDP client, connects to the
server, it'll probably wait
about five or ten seconds and
then it'll terminate the
process. And you have the
measurement for baseline.
Currently it's not the most
intelligent way of doing it,
Once it begins carrying out the
attack, it creates, it sets up a
work or two of processes. So
it'll be running 20 RD[P]
clients in parallel. You say
those RD[P] clients is set up
being ordered to attack a
specific occurrence of specific
events. So the first process
that's cued up, its goal is to
attach the first message of the
sent data. The second process
that's cued up is to attach the
first mess OJ of the received
data. The second and third one
is.. second message of
the sent. So in this way, you're
fuzzying all the (indiscernible)
messages... the early
messages from the protocol. So
it's just making sure your
fuzzing the really deep messages
in this case. And similarly,
you're spending equal amount of
time fuzzying the event type. If
you have an event that happens a
thousand times vs. a up coL, you
want to spent an equal amount of
time, even though one occurs
much more frequently than the
other. So I'm going to go really
quickly through what target
looks like. Everything is
designed to be really quite
simple. So there isn't much code
actually here. So for the
target, all you have to do is to
implement the initialized
(indiscernible) for whenever
grade point is hit. In the
initialize, you just want to
copy the stuff that's there. And
you want to modify these
parameters in which functions
and libraries will be
considered. The hook X words and
symbols... library will
be considered for hooking. And
the symbols, if you enable the
symbols library from the store,
and hook in @ symbols that are
loaded as well. The libraries
just specify the libraries that
will be considered. You can
specify them
implicitly... soft is
being targeted. Or you could
specify it by a (indiscernible)
statement. Similarly for
functions. You specify either
the function names explicitly
considered, or you specify red
jacks which is an includes for
the functions to be considered.
So all this for initialize. And
great point hit is a bit more
complicated. For the parameters,
first you specify the
parameters, which is basically
the arguments that are coming in
at the great point location. And
enyou have to give it a calling
convention and according to the
processes it's attached to. So,
this case, it's a pascal naming
convention.... it needs
to be transformed according to
the process because it may be a
32 or a 64 process which
influences the calling
convention. And then it
transforms it into a registries
specifications as well as a
stack specification. So it's
going to make a sense in a
second. But it basically gives
you an argument structure which
has the parsed arguments. And
then you can access the
verticals naturally. So this is
what the parameters
specification looks like. This
in this case we're hooking win
soft send. This does support
complex structures is a fairly
simple structure type. So we
have, this is ordered, so make
sure to put the arguments in
order here. And here's...
here's the buffer. If you look
at the type of the buffer, that
means it's a pointer. Because
it's... the type of it is not
numb. In this case it's pointing
to a method that knows how to
parse this specific types. In
this case, it's parsed the
buffer. And that buffer is going
to be a thick sized buffer,
which is according to the
argument (indiscernible). So if
the size variable is ten, you
want it to only have .2 buffer
size of ten. So that's handed in
through the type art for the
reference to the argument. And
the fuzz, the fuzz variable you
have for each of the variable
it's what the default action is
you do with the w that
parameter. In this case, it's no
fuzz for all of them. We only
want to fuzz the contents of the
buffer. We don't want to be
fuzzing the contents of the
buffer for example, in this
case. This is what the parse
buffer looks like. If it
returns just the same format.
Can be an array of parameters.
But in this case, it just
returns... it just searches
upwards for the already resolved
argument. It needs to look up
the size, what size of this,
this buffer is and then it just
adds it as a field called
capital buffer. So, it... so
here, once you have the parse
arguments, you can just do two
string. And it's going to print
all of them. So here you can see
the buffer is stored in RDX. And
the contents of the buffer is
stored at that address. And you
can see the contents of the
buffer, it's dumped hex 13 bytes
of the buffer there. You can
reference these fields
naturally. So you can do the
argument for the buffer. That is
referring to the pointer of the
buffer at that 2 string. And now
it's printing out the pointer as
well as the contents of the
buffer. Or you could go right
ahead right to the argument
itself. You can do arguments to
the buffer and then dereference
the pointer to the buffer two
strings. So in the line above
there, you see, it does
arguments, dot size dot
two inch. So when you
reference a parameter like this
you need to convert it to a
type. So, in a case like this
this, you're converting the size
to integer, because otherwise it
doesn't know how you want to
access that underline type
example. So you can access them
naturally once you have it
parsed properly like that. The
process is much simpler, which
is great. The only thing you
have to change here is in the
initialize, just specify the
path to EXE as well as the
command line. You can attach to
an existing running process if
you include a pit instead. In
which case it'll ignore the
arguments and attach the already
running process if you include a
pid as well, and it will ignore
those 2 arguments directly
attached to a already running
process instead. On the debugger
attach, use the exact template
in the examples except all you
do is specify the targets
that'll be added. You can add
multiple targets, but here is
only adding the windsock_send to
the target in this case. So the
controller, the controller is
the brains of it. It runs the
measurements operates. As well
as the workers queue processes,
which are running the attacks.
The... here's an example of
how you do the measurement in
the process. The measurement
phase. You need to create a
break point handler which the
break point handler decides what
to do with the fuzz information.
In this case, we just want to
measure the fuzz blocks, for
example, so you just create a
break point measurement. You
create that process rdp and when
you tell the controller engine
to attach to it, the rdp process
is already running with all the
instrumentation. So just wait
five second nd copy the measure
out and stop it. Now you're
finish your baseline. So you
took your rdp client, you hook
the windsock 32 function as it
was loaded. And connected to the
server recorded all the
communication, waiting five
seconds and then terminate. The
target brake point measurement
just calls the target brake
point handler recording a
result. So now we finish the
measurement part of it for the
attack part of it. You just
implement a brake point attack
instead of brake point
measurement. The brake point
attack you tell it which event
name as well as the number, the
event number you would like to
attach. But you don't need to
change any of this normally. You
can just use the existing
template that's there for
controller. So normally, you
just want to change the target
and process implementation. So
now I'm going to jump into the
the first example of
fuzzing... the xrdp server. So
it's rdp server. I've got it
running on the VM right here. So
this is the example of the
target implementation here. So
it's actually... this one is
very... what we've been going
through in an example so far
targeting windsock 32 just a
send example. So here we're only
hooking export to the library.
So here I'm running it with a
verbose flag so it connected up
to the rdp server. So it's just
printing the buffers that are
sent to the rdp server. You can
see these later messages here.
You don't see any clear text
here because they're actually
encrypted blogs in the later
communication. But if I go up to
the earlier communication, you
can see clearly in some of the
first messages, you see some
clear ASCII. It's connected to
the server. That's my computer
name here for example. In this
case it's, I just thought I'd
show you what it looks like
printing the buffers before I
carry out the attack. Now I'm
running attack mode. And the
first thing it does is a
measurement, a process
measurement right now. So it's
recording the baseline. So it's
printed out that there were 20
messages involved with
connecting unto that rod server.
And involved with 257 blocks.
All the possible data is
decomposed into eight byte
chunks, blocks of fuzzable
block. Each one is considered a
fuzz block, call add fuzz block
with some logic. I I've got it
set up to run 25 of the rdp
clients in parallel right now.
Let many go to control options.
I'm running 25 of them parallel
right now. And they're going to
each time out at five seconds
and keep 20 of them running
continuously. It usually only
takes a matter of probably about
one minute or so in order to
crash the rdp server right now.
Right now I'm running the old
version which is vulnerable to
vulnerability disclosures. So
you can see here, they're
attacking all the different
events of it right now. Some of
the message blocks are coming up
because it's failing to connect
because it's buzzing with some
of the early messages and
causing it to lose connection.
If I give it a few seconds, I'm
hoping we're going to crash it.
And then I'll show you what the
crash dump looks like. Come on.
Last time we ran it, it only
took about 15 seconds or so.
I'm hoping this is going to
crash in a second. It seems to
be taking a little bit longer
here than last time. That's
okay. We're going to show
another example in a second
which is going to speed it up a
little bit. So back to the
example, it still isn't ideal
because you see the encrypted
messages there deeper in the
communication. Although we are
fuzzing that data, we're not
fuzzing it properly, we don't
know what type of encryption is
applied to it, maybe there's
some check, some checks assigned
to it as well as for example.
So, the problem is, now we have
to figure out, we want to hook
it before encryption as well.
So, we may not know necessarily
what the encryption protocols
involved there so, I'm just
going to be including target,
which also paints the symbols
along with the data. That is
this one right oh here. It's
explicitly specifying the
mstscax. That's the library
responsible for the rdp within
the client. And for the
functions include statement, it
included everything. So
everything internal symbol is
hooked in this case. And it's
only hooking this symbols
instead of the exports. And the
brake point hit event with
handler only prints the event
name. So then we get an internal
view of what it looks like. I
have to add that already. So now
this is printing all the
internal symbols but it's also
printing the sent data at the
same time. So we have a frame of
reference. I'm just going to
wait until it connects here.
What I'm going to look at is
what's happening right before
it's sends one of those
encrypted messages internally.
Sorry guys. So this one here is
encrypted blobs that's being
sent right here. And you see
just before it, it's calling all
these send buffer functions. I
originally went ahead and looked
and thought let's have a look at
what the parameters are for
these send buffers before
encryption. See here, the
encryption function is this RC4
which is being called shortly
before the function is called.
So these send buffer functions,
I found actually had really
complex definitions that I
wasn't able to easily reverse
it. But for the RC4 all you have
to do is print, say define four
arguments and all those pointers
to buffers and just do print and
you can clearly see what, based
on the contents of that, it's
clear to see which is which.
Which argument is which. So that
RC4 is the easiest one to hook.
So now, in this case, now this
last target is attacking just
that RC4 encrypted data. So
here's it's just attacking the
mstscax DLL. RC4, which this one
is a really simle definition,
just key size buffer. So now I'm
going to go ahead and carry that
out for the buffer. Now you can
see the data here is looking
much better now. You can see
msptc.exe there. And here you
can see my local machine time
zone as well as my local IP
address as well. So now the
data's looking much better, it's
looking not encrypted which is
great. Now I'm going to carry
out that attack. Which fuzzing
the rdp buffer, instead of
attacking the windsock messages.
So again it does the measure
operation right there. And it's
found that there were 19 calls
to RC4. And of course
150 blocks of fuzzed data. So I
was carrying out the same
process here. And if you look
closely at the screen you
might... actually, I already
passed it. All right, that one's
successful. Now connect to the
server because it's no longer
there. I'm going to pull up the
crash dump to show you what that
looks like. Although it's a
fixed vulnerability now which
could be one of a few. This one
is the xrdp bit map compare with
the CRC. It had a fixed size
array of the bit, in their bit
map cashing. And it's over
flown, it's passed the ends of
the bounds of the array. Here
you can see the self-pointer
is clearly incorrect, it's just
a four by value, bf 5f. And it
tried to dereference a variable
off it. Which caused it to
crash. This vulnerability has
fixed now, which is great.
(Applause.) That's it for the
rdp example. I'd be really
careful about using open source
software for stuff. Which might
often be connected to the
internet. In this case, the rdp
code, there were quite a lot of
pretty bad vulnerabilities in it
that can be exploited from
remote execution even before
authentication. Even before
authentication. You should be
careful about what code you have
in your computers which is
listening. Especially if it's
connected to the internet. So
this right here is one of the
other vulnerabilities where it
creates a buffer, just 8KB for
example, it doesn't even check
when it copies data into it. So
if the client says, oh, the size
of the the field is actually
bigger than that, it'll actually
over flow that then. That's
another dangerous one. So now
the second part of the
presentation, I'm going to do a
quick demonstration of hooking
device control messages. So
device IO control messages are
for low level communication firm
from user mode up to drivers.
Drivers run in the kernel mode.
They can be used for things such
as low level disk reading and
writing as an example. But it's
used for all sorts of devices
and drivers. So you might wonder
what kind of devices are
communicated with a normal
basis. This is a list of devices
that are connected to notepad.
So if you start with notepad,
you just do file save as, and
browse the file save as dialogue
that comes up, browse the
network locations. This is the
list of the devices that are
communicated with. Like for
example, I don't know what most
of these are to be honest. NSI,
point manager, lanmandatagram,
et cetera. These ones here you
see with the... these are
actually just file system
accesses directly here. But in
the add min divide NAD, in video
add min device for example..
so here's a quick example
of.. I'm not going to
actually be attacking the device
IO messages in this case. You
want to be careful if you do as
well. For example, we're a disk
write operation, you could be
corrupting stuff for your disk
as well. So this is... here,
is actually going to be hooking
ntdll hooking device profile.
Even though it says file in the
same, that's actually the...
that's actually the lower level
device IO control function.
Device IO control file. And for
when the break point hits, it's
got more of a complex type here.
But again, this isn't a good
example for complex type
structures. None of these are
really complex structures in the
case. input buffer, output
buffer - both of them are fix
length buffers. So it's rather
simple calling convention. And
when this is hit, it's actually
just logging it to a... to
basically csv file, which with
the database 64 encoded. Which
then we're going to load into a
windows message analyzer using a
parser. So this is just printing
the data again. I've got it set
upright now to often you might
want to increase the surface
it's testing by pairing it say
with an autoscript. In this
case, using an autoscript for
each process it attaches to to
bring the style as well. To
(indiscernible). Server. Here's
what some of the log looks like
in terms of who it's
communicating with. At the ver
start it initializes within the
admin device, ADVM. I'm not sure
what any of this communication
is. It's sending to the ADVM
admin device, but also recording
the output buffers as well. So
when I ran that there, it was
actually saving the data to
capture that log there. It's
basically just a csv file. And
I've written and included
window's message analyzer parser
for it. This is kind of what the
parser looks like. It's rather
really simple. It's, the only
tricky part is the base 64
coding . And I'm just going to
load up that capture file right
now. So right now, it's... the
UI's been designed for multiple
processes. So you can capture
with multiple processes. But in
this case, we only have notepad,
you could say expand this and
it's grouped by the device it's
communicating with. And each of
these, I've separated the input
and out put buffers into two
different messages currently.
And they decoded datas right
here for example. So the idea
is, with Windows... for those
of you who aren't familiar with
Windows message analyzer, I
think it was released in the
last year by Microsoft. It's a
replacement to the Microsoft
network monitor tool. The
message analyzer is made to
capture more generic messages.
So it capture and analyze
network traffic for example. But
it's more designed for all types
of Windows messages, so it could
capture, it could process log
files and event logs et cetera.
It's much more generic then just
network for all sorts of
window's messages. And if,
although I haven't expanded on
it, you can actually extend this
as capture, this parser to parse
the protocol for each of the
individual devices you are
communicating with. You can
write a parser for an admin
device you start reverse
engineering protocol for how
it's communicating. Okay, and
I've just got one last simple
account with you. So one last
example here is say you're
writing a sandbox using the
frame work. Right now it does
support things like process
forking. But to be honest I've
found a performance isn't quite
what I wanted for currently for
a sandbox. You're going to find
it's a little bit slower
unfortunately. So in this case,
I've written targets that handle
several different things. Like
it's adding handle target, which
is a resolver for a handle
identifier for names as well as
it's adding a target to find
what the clean modules are in
the application. So by default,
it's currently not a really
intelligent way of doing it.
It's assumes the first is module
loaded is malicious and any
module loaded afterwards is
considered clean. But say if
they create (indiscernible)
inject into it, that is also
considered malicious, so only
properly loaded modules is
considered clean afterwards. And
it's logging registry. And this
log on trusted as logging, the
exports of all dll's only if
they're only logging at the
function called incurred if it's
coming from untrusted code.
Because you don't want to see
every internal function that's
called. You want to see only if
it's coming from untrusted code
for example. And targets fork,
is hooking the only the great
process function. So when it
does create a process function,
it will fork and attach on to
the other process that's being
created as well. But the
performance isn't quite what I
wanted unfortunately. But I'm
working on improvement s for
that. So here we're running
notepad audi XE as a quick,
simple example. Now I'm just
going to bring up the
(indiscernible) dialogue, that
will cause some registry
changes. But as you can see,
it's not the fastest,
unfortunately. Give it a second,
sorry. It should be almost
there. I'm working on some..
I started working on a code in
order to upgrade it right now
using a native debugger engine.
And in in the future, I'd like
to upgrade that to be not...
to actually attaching it to a
debugger. I want it to be more
native based. Not debugger based
to improve the performance. So
I'm just going to close that
now. Like I said, embarrassing
slow. >>	Sorry? >>	(Inaudible -
off mic). >>	You're right. That
is coming from each of the
targets individually decides
whether they want to hook the
DLL. So each of the targets want
to hook each of the DLLs. One of
decides they want to hook 0. One
of them decides it wants to hook
three of the exports. Those are
from two different targets, why
you are seeing duplicate there.
Yup. So now that's actually
created the log that, this
events dot log here. Which is
the log file that recorded for
that notepad run. So if the
registry handler is recording
the query values, which is all
of those. So this is where
notepad itself is starting up.
It's recording all the
export.. well whenever an
export of any library is called
from untrusted code, it's
printing it out here. So you can
see what it's doing internally.
And you should only be seeing
what malicious code is calling
in. Like if kernel 32 calls NTD
function is automatically
filtered out here. Yeah right
now, it's automatically
dereferencing strings at low
level. So this right here comes
common control dialogue 32
choose font W. That's when I
clicked on change the font. So
it's been recorded here. And
you'll see shortly after, it's
going to set the values...
yeah, so now it's setting all
the registry values as I hit
okay, for example. This is
changing all the font settings.
And here, for example, it's
changing it to the Times New
Roman default font for notepad.
And then you basically quits.
One other thing is that I forgot
to mention with the
vulnerability fuzzing, each time
it's creating a process, each
process is logging into a file
what changes it's made in the
connection process. And it's
located in this log files
folder. So when you have that
rdp crash, for example, at the
end of my last example, you can
go ahead and refer to this log
files folder and see how to
reproduce the crash for example.
So it's going up sequentially.
So the last ones which
communicated with it, were these
bottom ones. So in these log
files, you have this one didn't
quite reach there. So these last
processes I think were created
but weren't able to connect to
the server, that's why we're not
seeing any fuzzing. Normally
you'd see something like this
where you'd see the brake point
handler. You see the arguments
are passed in. So you want...
if you want to reproduce this
attack, you have to create a
brake point attack sequentially
use this seed number to
reproduce the fuzzing decision.
And that tells you.. now
it's buzzing block three from
that from value of this to value
of that for example. So it uses
several different algorithms
because of the changing of
keyword value. So in this case,
it'll either flip a few random
bits or modify a random byte in
that keyword or modify a random
word or D word in that section.
So, I think that about wraps up
my presentation here. Thanks
very much for attending
everyone. (Applause.) Any
questions? I just realized I'll
take... okay yeah sure.
>>	(Inaudible). >>	Yup. Thank
you. Okay, thank you.