>> Thank you for coming out and
give a big hand, this is Chris.
>> Come on, get that going?
(Applause) 	>> Thank you. These
lights are bright. I just took a
shot. This is The $env:PATH Less
Traveled is Full of Easy
Privilege Escalation Vulns. I am
a security researcher, Chris
Campbell for the Harris
corporation. I am not do not
represent them in this talk,
this is all personal research,
standard disclaimer applies. Any
former red team people here?
None. They love me so much. I'm
one of the developers at
PowerSploit -- does anyone use
PowerSploit I'm on Twitter
normally yelling at people at
obscure sec and my blog is
obscuresec.com. This is my first
time talking here. I've wanted
to talk for many many years, I'm
excited and terrified at the
same time. So let's start with
Windows sucks! 	(Laughter)
(Cheers and applause) 	>> As
someone who has been forced to
work with it for over a decade I
can say that with great
authority. It sucks a lot.
Windows 8 is terrible. But it
does suck a lot less now because
of power shell. Right. Everybody
using power shell now? Finally
we have a full shell like the
rest of the worlds. PowerShell
is awesome and it's definitely
moving Microsoft's product,
their flagship product, forward.
And gives us a lot more power
but moving forward in the next
version of Windows in Windows 9,
we're going to have some new and
exciting things in the form of
OneGet. It is already shipping
with PowerShell version 5, a
package manager. Has anyone ever
heard of 1 get?	 	>> Woo-hoo!
>> Wow, that's more people than
I thought. How many people have
heard of chocolaty nuget? Yeah,
how about PS Get? All these
utilities have lots of purposes
and the reason I put this talk
together was to highlight these
things because every con I would
go to I'd mention it and people
had no idea. Full disclosure
chocolaty nuget was written by a
friend of mine. I do beat up on
it in this talk but he's a good
guy and he has patched all the
vulns before today. These things
will help simplify if you are an
admin or pen tester and you want
to advocate how to patch third
party applications moving
forward this will be a way using
1 get to patch Adobe, Java,
Flash, all the third-party apps
you are paying money for other
products. OneGet will allow you
to patch those on a regular
basis with easy scheduled tasks.
It also is great for researching
vulnerabilities. I'll tell you
one story about how I used it in
a few slides and another way is
to build quick CTS. I do that
quite often. Once I find a
vulnerability and I am building
a little environment for people
to play around in, this speeds
this up and gives you the
ability to randomize what is on
each box to make it look more
real. 	These are quotes from the
Oneget page. A new way to
discover and install software
packages for Windows. It's new.
Except everyone in every other
language -- every other
operating system has had it
forever. But it lets you see
mostly in stall and uninstall
with single PowerShell command.
It ships with version 5 which is
in beta right now, you can get
it and download it and it's
actually open source which is
really cool. Give Microsoft a
hand for starting to open-source
some products! (Applause) So
it's on get hub if you want to
check out source code. At the
bottom. All right. 	My favorite
package manager is Chocolaty
Nuget. This has over 4 million
downloads and over 2,000 unique
packages it's written by Rob
Reynolds, over 30 contributors,
open source as well and recently
Microsoft declared that it was a
supported open source project. I
really don't honestly -- not a
knock on Microsoft, I have no
idea what that means, if it
means money or what. But
Chocolaty is out there, if you
have never used it, it's great
but it's got a few problems.
PSGet is specific to
PowerShell. I just included it
just to be complete. PSGet is
for like PIP, it is just a bunch
of functions that have been
screened by a few people you can
grab easily and download and
use. All right. So I was doing a
long-term engagement and
discovered chocolaty knew gat
being used and they had their
own private repo server in an
enterprise. Has anyone ran into
any of these on a package
managers on a pen test ?
Anybody? Nobody. Yes. So you
probably will run into them in
the future so it's great you are
here. I saw it was being used, I
found some privilege escalation
vulnerabilities on their main
baseline and then later
discovered they kind of came
from their use of chocolaty
nuget, I reached out to Rob, and
told him hey I'll do tests, he
was like cool I didn't realize
Rob was paying for his bandwidth
so that first day I just started
downloading every single package
and just shot his bill sky-high.
All his numbers on his website.
I also blue-screened the VM
because in my infinite wisdom I
decided to do it all from one VM
so I just said you know download
start and install them all. So I
tried to install 1800 binaries
on a single Windows 8 GM and I
got the frowny face pretty
quick. 	Let's go over a couple
problems. It is 2014, is it not,
can we stop using http to
download installation files?
This is currently on the
website. This is how they
suggest that you install PS get.
What you are doing is you are
using the .NET and you are
downloading the content of the
Get.ps1 script, and you are
piping it to IEX, which is a
alias for invoked expression so
you are basically downloading a
script from a http and executing
it. It is 2014, people! Below
that, though, you have chocolaty
which had a similar problem but
he immediately fixed it as soon
as I brought it up, but the
installation itself was pulling
down a NUP KG package which is
just a zipped up PowerShell
script over http so it, itself
had the exact same problem. But
that's been fixed. 	All right.
So the next thing I decided to
do was to make this more
parallel so I created a bunch of
Windows VMs, some of them using
Azure and got a nice call from
the Azure abuse team. But I
decide today use Windows 7 and 8
because not all software
supported Windows 8 at that
time. And then I still had a few
blue screens so the first thing
I want to do because it's my
friend's repo was no one was
doing quality check on the code
or the actual binaries, packages
being submitted. 	I wanted to
see if it was being abused
already with malware. So I
scripted hashing every single
one in there, tons of tools to
do this. One is built into sys
internals so I was able to find,
I scripted hashing all new files
and found 100 that when I
submitted MD fives it didn't
know about. So then I scanned
those and 31 of them had
detections. A lot were admin
tools but there was full-blown
malware including one that was
straight you were on the
binaries that someone built a
package for and put it up there.
Most of those I believe are
removed. I think Rob and the
other developers are doing a
good job looking for that now. I
also wanted to use this
opportunity to write a new tool
to look for escalation
vulnerabilities. Aspen testers
that's something we do on the
box a lot. You are Fishing and
you have to escalate. Every way
I've been taught is run a series
of commands to check to go
through manually so power slate
was missing a module so I looked
for the common path-based file
permission base service
preloading and found a bunch and
a lot of this talk would be
about that but I had a lot of
push-back from vendors so you
can beat me up about it but I
really got tired of dealing with
them so I'm not disclosing any
of the silly vulnerabilities in
silly products and not giving
them any press at DEF CON. Most
of the applications were so
obscure that no one here really
would care. 	But the talk I
followed mostly was this one.
Has anyone seen this talk? On
Encyclopedia of Windows
privilege escalation. Couple
years old but still very valid.
Great talk. I wanted to give
that talk a shoutout. Here are
other resources, Chris Gates and
Rob fuller gave a talk a couple
times, I believe it was add is
the new black. That talk is
great. Rest is mostly about
subverting the path. I wrote a
blog post about that couple
months ago at the bottom. Those
other two are great resources
for privilege escalation. There
were already -- there was prior
work before I submitted this to
DEF CON. I actually took this
code almost completely and just
rewrote each thing in
PowerShell. So this was Windows
check from pen test monkey. Has
anyone used this? Couple people?
It's actually really cool but it
kind of defeats the purpose in
that you have to either compile
it as a binary, put it down on
disk or have Python installed on
the box. With PowerShell we
don't need that. I wrote a
privilege escalation module I
was planning on releasing here
but then this guy who is awesome
harmjOy, wrote power up. Has
anyone seen power up? Couple
people. All right. 	Well,
hopefully more people, it's
already on version 1.1, Will
added a ton of stuff and it is
way better than what I wrote.
What we are doing right now is
porting all that, adding things
and that will be the next
privilege escalation module in
power suploit but it will be 95%
of Harmjoy's work, download it,
it works great. So back to the
package managers. 	The problem
that 1 get suffers from already
and it hasn't been released yet
is the repo server has to be
trusted and right now there's so
many people already using
chocolaty repo servers they have
decided not to stand up their
own yet. Maybe they will do that
in the future. We saw that over
four million people have used
Choclaty repo's to download
stuff but Choclaty repo allows
anyone in this room to build a
package and deploy it. So right
now with 1 get, you have to
explicitly go and say yes, I
trust chocolaty repo but it's
already there, really easy to do
and there are a bunch of guides
on the Internet, just trust this
repo but bottom line is all
packet managers whether written
by Microsoft or anyone else,
they inherit all vulnerabilities
from both repo and the packages
themselves. So here is probably
can't see that at all can you.
This is what a chocolaty
package looks like, two things,
XML document with different
descriptions. And then it's a
PowerShell script to install it
and all the different switches
and flags to install it
silently. That's really all it
is. So it would be really easy
for an enterprise to stand up
their own repo server and deploy
their own for all internal
tools. So let's talk about the
path. Really easy to see what's
in your path. And this
screenshot, I have a few things,
anyone see anything problematic
that is in my path? Say it
louder. Python. Check your box
right now, see if Python is
sitting on the root of C. If it
is it probably inherited the
permission which allows the user
to write to any binary in that
folder. Now we have created not
just a DLL preloading problem
but we have created a problem
where every service that is
using the path to pull its TLLs
can actually be abused. 	There's
something else that uses the
path. PowerShell version three,
really easy way to find in
problem and deal with
highjacking and other
DLL-related issues is use
process monitor. There are lots
of guys on the Internet that
show you how. In this case
PowerShell version 3 will check
for PS console host reline.PS 1,
P MS1, PST (?), blah, blah,
blah. Anyone have a guess as to
wait does as it finds it? It
would not execute it, would it?
(Pause) So any user on this box
could just write PS console
host.cmd, and make it be net add
myself to local admin and sit
back and wait for an admin to
just open PowerShell, as soon as
the console shows up, that's
executed and you have just
escalated. 	So the vast majority
of packages, I'll show you but
so up top is what it used to be
install for chocolaty used to
look like and at the bottom is
what it currently looks like.
The problem with chocolaty and
all its packages and why they
were almost all vulnerable
including things like sys
internals, if you are using
chocolaty, you might want to
check those out because they
didn't go back to fix
permissions. They were dropping
everything with, in C chocolaty
bin which any user has the
ability to write to. So anyone
who was using chocolaty or
OneGet with chocolaty and
installed packages, all those
packages are vulnerable to
privilege escalation to the tune
of hundreds and hundreds and
hundreds of them. The fix was
actually really simple. He's
using all users profile. Can you
guys see that? Yes, you can see
it? 	Before the fix, that does
not look great on this screen
either. 	Before the fix cinst is
the command to install
something, CINST, you can go
into the actual chocolaty files
and go in and change and add
whatever commands you wanted and
then the environment I was pen
testing they were running
commands remotely to execute
this locally to update
everything. So I was able to get
domain admin by just writing a
net user add command to add
myself to domain admins and
sitting back and waiting one
day. In this case I'm just
popping. So I really have no
idea what I'm doing most of the
time. So I have lots of friends
and friends are good. So I'll
start with Rob. Rob wrote
chocolaty, and he has done a
great job fixing everything that
I find and telling me when some
of the stuff is just plain
stupid. Matt Graber, really good
friend of mine. Joe Bolakirks
from Microsoft, help me a lot,
Will who wrote Power Up, and
Will Peteroy and Lee Holmes from
PowerShell security team who
worked through removing that
feature from PowerShell version
four and all of you guys who
came to my first DEF CON talk. I
hope to have many more and
hopefully the next ones are a
full hour. But thanks, guys!
(Applause)