Introducing Thomas Holt
Associate Professor at Michigan
State University. [Applause] >>
Thank you. Thanks, everybody. I
appreciate it. Thanks for coming
during lunch. I know this is
always a hard thing to do.
Hopefully you have a beer and
some liquid food to enjoy. Today
what we're going to talk about
are Stolen Data Markets. This is
something you probably have
familiarity with already. Raise
your hand if you have heard
about mass data bridges. I would
think everybody, good. Anybody
had their card reissued this
year? I'm working on my fourth
card this year thanks in part to
the fact that I have a nine
month old who requires all kinds
of stuff so between going to
Target and going out to eat
we've lost many a card this year
so mass data breaches have
become a big problem in part of
my personal and professional
life. Today we're going to talk
about research funded through
the National Institute of
Justice. This thing at the
bottom is a direct result of our
funding agency. So as a point of
clarification this research was
funded by the U.S. Department of
Justice and everything I'm going
to talk about today is in no way
a reflection of the attitudes,
opinions or what have you of the
Department of Justice itself.
With that out of the way we'll
jump into the fun stuff. In
thinking about Data Breaches in
an academic point of view,
there's been a good deal of
research that's started to come
out. Most looked at two angles
either the IRC communications
that go on or through forum data
sets. Thinking about the IRC
data this is good but there are
substantial limits. The same is
true as far as what it seems as
though forums are becoming a
little bit more of a popular
medium for individuals to sell
data through mass breaches but
the limitations through all of
these data sets are substantial
and we have to give some
consideration to that. When we
think about who is selling data,
one of the biggest dilemmas that
emerges is the fact that
communications typically take
place in cyrillic or to a
certain extent English languages
communications. Cyrillic based
languages, are they Russian or
are they using machine
translation. If you have ever
used Google translate you know
the translations are adequate,
sometimes very poor so that's
going to have a direct impact on
what it is we're studying. Most
of them are based off of a small
sample. It could be maybe two to
four forums. Some people have
started to use single IRC sets
and a small number of
researchers have begun to use
dead forums. So groups like the
shadow crew, the grifters, the
dark market data set and
analyzing those. It's very
helpful but if we're talking
about a group was that active
five to 10 years ago what is
that going to tell us about the
processes of the market as it
exists now? So one of the
biggest issues that emerges
within this whole round of
research is the fact that very
few people have tried to assess
anything with regard to the
economics of the markets
themselves. Only two studies
have even published information
about the basic pricing for
data. So if we're talking about
a credit or debit card number
how much is it going for? That
information is largely absent
from the empirical research. The
same is true in regard to
organizational issues. Are we
talking about a complex mafioso
organized crime network or
talking about something that's
more distributed? More of a
network of colleagues rather
than something that's very, very
sophisticated. And in thinking
about the data markets
themselves there's good, good
theoretical research that talks
about the idea of these markets
being lemon markets, basically
prices vary and what you pay
directly impacts what you get.
Same with buying a bad car from
a car lot. If you buy a car for
a thousand dollars and it breaks
down as soon as you leave the
lot that's a direct expense you
incur. You might have gotten the
car cheaply, but it stopped
working on you almost
immediately. The same could be
true with data markets. If we're
looking at information from
English language forums where
people are untrustworthy and
there's lots of complaints the
fact that they're selling data
for five dollars a lot doesn't
tell us much because that data
might be inactive or old or
invalid and it's not a true
reflection of what we are
seeing. So there's an argument
that there are multiple markets
operating. There's a lower
barrier to entry for English
language forums. If we were to
Google stolen data markets we
would see no barrier to entry
and you probably can't trust
what's being sold. There's a
deeper secondary market that
exists where we expect higher
prices, greater trust, greater
insularity and as a result,
those may be a more accurate
reflection of the market in and
of itself but few people have
tried to address these questions
empirically. Instead we end up
with the question what do the
markets look like? We'll talk
about what the conditions are
like within the market, what are
the costs for goods and
services, what's the
organization of the market and
then what are the structures
like between participants, how
do they know and relate to one
another? And to do this we
collected a set of posts and
threads from 13 active forums.
We oversampled on Russian
language groups and tried to
capture a range of entities
operating world wide. We have a
number operating out of Russia,
some in Germany, one in the UK,
Netherlands and a few in the
U.S, one in the British Virgin
Islands, but communicated in
Russian. It gives us a sense of
where the sites operate. The
language is more important. If
we're talking about a site in
the British Virgin Islands where
everyone's communicating Russian
it's unlikely that it's the
residents participating. We're
talking about Russians, eastern
Europeans or people using Google
translate to talk. And we
captured a number of threads
from each of the forums and
tried to over sample on time
frame. We have data going back
to 2007 in four of our forums
and some going back to 2008. Our
data collection stops at 2011 or
2012 depending as we had to
collect all of it and had to
analyze it and translate it. We
worked with a certified Russian
translator to get the
tranlasations as they appeared
in as close as we could in
approximation to English as
possible because unfortunately I
don't speak Russian. My
colleague in the study is a
native Russian and her assistant
was great in getting the project
off the ground. The reason that
we have both English and Russian
language groups in our sample is
because we wanted to get at this
question the lemon market
argument. What does an English
language market look like
relative to a Russian one and
can we find evidence of
differences in terms of
products, resources or
organizational dynamics within
the market based on language? So
that's the rationale for this
study. In thinking strategically
about what is sold we conducted
an economic analysis breaking
out products by specific
purpose. Most of the data in our
set involved advertisements for
data sales. So we have a range
of things like dumps if you are
familiar with the term dump it
refers to a lot of personal
information associated with a
credit or debit card. Some
individuals selling CVV's the
security code on the back of the
card. A small proportion selling
Fulls and those are all of the
information associated with an
account including Social
Security number, address and
pertinent information that would
allow an individual to take over
the account. Some people selling
Ebay accounts, and other
personal accounts and personal
information whether it's E‑mail
user names and passwords and
other financial products
generally. In case you are
wondering no we did not see
medical data in here nor stocks
or other types of financial
products of that nature instead
it's mostly involving financial
institutions, banks and credit
card agencies. But we had a
number of individuals selling
data manipulation tools. This
might be cash out services,
people who can go withdraw cash
from legally acquired accounts,
some people offer drops where
you buy goods online and have
them shipped to a specific
location and left via UPS or
FedEx and those products are
pawned, fenced, or shipped on to
another person so an
intermediary for goods. And a
small number doing money
transfers. And a small number
offering personal identity
documents so if you needed a
credit report or credit history
or something else they would be
the individuals to go to. Also a
small amount of sellers we saw
offering associated services in
order to manipulate data on the
back end or acquire it on the
front end. A small number of
people sell skimmers, that's a
device that you clip on to an
ATM or gas station terminal
where you swipe the card and it
captures the data on the back of
the magnetic strip. That's a
very small proportion. 84% of
our ads involved data sales of
some type. Moving from the
economy we're going to look at
this from a organizational
perspective. We use a
sociological framework which is
admittediably a little bit
different than what you're used
to. >> In this case we tried to
understand how people operate
based on how they work together,
how they communicate and how
long they exist. This gives us a
framework for analysis, are they
like a Acusa or Mafia or flat
but tries to understand the
group based on different
divisions. How long they
operate, what kind of division
of labor is present? Do you have
someone that is a distinct
coder? Another person receives
goods so is there any kind of
specialized labor force
operating? Do they offend
together? That's the issue of
mutual participation? And then
there is the issue of mutual
association. How do they get
along? There are some types of
crime where you don't have to
know the person. For example
prostitution. You don't have to
know anybody, you go, solicit,
do your business, everybody
leaves. We want to know what
types of relationships are we
seeing in these markets for
stolen data? And finally
depending on time, we also
conducted a network analysis. So
if you are familiar with network
analyses these are ways to
statistically connect
individuals within a market.
This sociograph here represents
participants in one of our
boards. We have a small number
of individuals connected. Say
here we have one person who is a
seller with a number of people
and you can talking to that
seller and see what we can buy
and what we can get. Then we
have a number of isolates at the
bottom. These are people who no
one talks to for one reason or
another. >> This is important if
we're thinking about targeting
groups. How do you disrupt the
network if they're loosely
connected? It's different than
how you might if there's a
hierarchical structure in place.
This is an important way to
think about connectivity. How
does the market operate? What
I'll talk about now relates to
both social organization and
economics. If you are not
familiar with how these markets
operate it starts when someone
posts an ad. This is an ad for
instance, for dumps. I realize
this is small but I'll hit the
high notes for you. This person
is selling Dumps: stolen credit
card numbers from around the
world. They're offering U.S.
data. A classic or standard card
is 20 bucks, Gold or a platinum
card is 25 bucks, a business or
signature corporate card is 30
and American Express card is 20.
And then Canadian dumps.
Interestingly Canadian data is
more expensive. $50 for a
classic or standard card, $70 to
$200 depending on what type of
advanced data you want. Then
getting into European markets in
places where chip and pin
encryption is used, you can see
the prices are even higher. This
is important to note. Every ad
typically incorporates
information about pricing
structures and the quality or
quantity of data available. They
piece it out by product and
type. They also explain their
conditions for sales. Since
vendors have the ability to
advertise and direct their
traffic they can explain in very
crystal clear terms how you and
the seller are going to
interact. In this case the
person explains how you do
business. You contact them, use
the one ICQ number that you want
to use, calculate the price and
then submit your order. Send
money first and your e-mail.
How's that for a bum deal. Send
money first and then we'll send
you product. This is different
than a drug transaction or other
illicit markets in the real
world where product and payment
can be exchanged near
simultaneously or within
relative close proximity.
Instead this seller says send me
money and within 24 hours we'll
complete your order. In this
case Liberty Reserve payments
are what they prefer. Anybody
heard of Liberty Reserve
payments before? They were
recently taken out of a large
scale law enforcement use in the
U.S. This payment venue no
longer exists but online
currency payment systems like
Liberty Reserve are the
preference for individuals in
this marketplace. We didn't see
anybody using Bitocin incase you
were curious, or any other types
of crypto currencies. These
individuals seem to be tailored
more towards immediate transfers
of payments. 	There's an
interesting point here. Point 5.
We replace only pick-up or hold
call dumps within a 24 hour
period. What that means if you
bought 100 cards from this
person and 90 worked and 10 came
back as either invalid, inactive
or held as inactive cards, you
can contact the seller and say I
need these 10 cards replaced and
they'll do so. That's a degree
of customer support they're
willing to offer. Just wait. It
will get weirder. Customer
service is an important venue
within these market places to
generate people to your
business, you want people to
come back and buy from you on a
consistent basis. Offer them
something and give them a reason
to come back to you. So this
individual for instance, offers
free replacements. There are
other types of customer service
that are out there. This is a
good example. A person selling
eBay and PayPal accounts from
the US and the UK. You can see
Tthe pricing structure is low.
If you want an unverified
account with a credit card
number, it's 1WMZ or LR. That
means web money US. Z is the
designated nation or $1 Liberty
Reserve. If you want an
unverified account attached to a
bank account that's a dollar. If
you want a verified Pay Pal
account with a credit card
number, that's $3. Anybody have
a confirmed account? a couple of
you? That's pretty cheap. We
have accounts with E‑mail, just
ask. The seller's not
responsible for security
measures. We check all accounts
manually prior to giving them to
you and you will get a clean
socks5 proxy. the rationale
being if you are an individual
living in Europe trying to use a
U.S. account it's clear that the
traffic is coming from Romania
you will not be able to use the
account. They will give you a
proxy for the associated
country. If you burn the proxy
it's on you as they say here.
Seller is not responsible for
the unsuccessful usage of the
account. If you burn the proxy
you have to get another one.
They're offering a modicum of
support but nothing too fancy.
This is the type of
communication that each
individual can specify. Vendors
can control the market based on
what they feel is relevant and a
final example an individual
offering money laundering
service. They work specifically
with the Russian federation,
they will work with cash funds ,
they will transmit electronic
funds, with dirty funds and the
advantage working with them, low
commission. With regard to
customer service they're going
to take a portion of the amount
of money. Say there's a thousand
dollars being laundered they'll
take between 10 and 20 percent
as you dictate the terms and
work out the relationship. And
speed, as a rule funds are
received on the day they're
credited to the company's
account. Next day or maximum of
one day after they're credited.
So you want your money quickly
work with us. We turn things
around fast. This idea of
customer service is very, very
interesting and very unique to
these markets. Just to give you
a quick sense of how products
are priced, this is a break out
of our product pricing. Let's go
with dumps because that's a
common item sold. The lowest
price we saw was 4 cents,
highest was $8,000. Gives us an
average of $102.60. We saw CVVs
going for between 1 dollar 8,000
dollars, the average being
$26.We saw the majority of our
pricing going towards our data
products. Data manipulation
services vary and largely it was
because individuals would list
percentages rather than total
amounts. The reason being if you
are laundering money on
someone's behalf or working as a
cash out team, it will be easier
to take a proportion of those
funds than to have a set rate in
advance. It works out for
everyone to have a little bit of
difference in payment. What I
want to do is move on to a
specific idea about quality and
quantity of services. These are
the products that are sold in
our markets based on the top 10.
If we include all forums in our
sample the majority of products
sold are dumps and CVVs. But
since any individual can enter
this market and there's
potential for lemon markets
where people are going to rip
you off, we had a number of
complaints in two of our forums
so we designated them as ripping
forums. Places where if you go
there to buy data, you're going
to get ripped off. That's a
common term used within the
market itself. If you are a
ripper you are a bad guy. We
just want to deal with people
who are going to get us our
money and get us our data and
everyone makes a profit. So you
want to avoid rip off artists.
When you exclude two of the
ripping forums from our data set
the proportion of products
change dramatically. Dumps are
still number one. Cash out
services become more prevalent,
other products, could be
consumer equipment, different
accounts or other products.
Malware jumps up quite a bit
dedicated hosting services drop.
EBay and PayPal jumps up quite a
bit. So there are differences
when we think about the products
and quality of sellers within
any given market So to continue
with the idea of dumps for a
moment, given that they can come
anywhere we ran an analysis to
see the pricing differentials by
country. Given that the US was
one of the most prevalent in our
data set. We tried to see what
the average price was and how
pricing differs by country. So
we took a logged price for each
specific item to remove
variation in prices and
separated them by Asia, U.S,
Canada or different regions and
compared the two. What's
interesting to note is that U.S.
data for dumps was cheaper than
other countries. Same for the UK
and even Canada to a certain
extent. These are statistically
significant differences. That is
if you are going to buy data
from a different country, the
U.S. and UK are going to be
cheaper than other countries. If
you think about the quantity of
mass data breaches that we've
had in the last few years, that
might be part of it because the
market has been flooded by data
from these nations. Plus we have
lower standards for security and
for use of payment mechanisms.
So there are real variations
that are evident. Moving from
products let's stick with the
sales process itself. An ad goes
up. Once the ad goes up the
individual contacts the buyer
and all sales happen outside of
the forum. This is important
because it makes it hard for us
to understand how much the price
is for any given data. That's
part of why these limits are
present in a lot of the research
out there. What an advertised
price is could be radically
different from what a person
paid. Generally we know all of
the exchanges are going to take
place through E‑mail or ICQ
which is 50 percent of the
preferred mechanisms for
contact. And the various systems
we saw were electronic primarily
like Liberty Reserve or
WebMoney. We also saw a
proportion taking Western Union
or MoneyGram. Some sellers that
accepted Western Union payments
ratcheted up the price by 10 to
20 percent. The rationale
meaning they had to have an
intermediarial work with them or
in some way they had to have
someone physically show up to a
location to get cash so it made
it harder. There's another point
here, escrow payments. This was
offered but at a small
percentage and within a few of
the forums. Escrow payments were
present for those boards that
had a good degree of
organization and had a lot of
trust between the participants.
This is an example of Guarantor
service. The guarantor of a
forum has been created so that
you will not be deceived. By
conducting a transaction with a
guarantor you know you can
trust. Here's the terms. Buyer
and seller reach an agreement
working through a guarantor.
Someone who has specifically
designated by that forum as the
guarantor. The buyer contacts
the seller and using the
guarantor they get in touch with
the ICQ. One of the parties
gives money to the guarantor and
the other the goods. The party
holds the money in reserves.
Once the money is there and the
data is sent each individual
party gets what they paid for in
this case data to the buyer,
money to the seller and that
gives a way to ensure
everybody's happy. Otherwise you
don't know who you are working
with or who you can trust. As a
result grantors are there to
ensure everyone gets what they
want. And grantors also get a
little bit of takes, you can see
guarantors services are free for
up to $30 but once you go up to
$500 it's prorated 8%. So the
more you buy the less you have
to pay the guarantor. This idea
of trust is really important.
It's odd to think about illicit
markets because we don't think
about thieves having honor or
trust but within these markets
that's the way people get things
done. In fact since sales take
place out of the forum it's hard
to know how an exchange goes and
that's why individuals offer
feedback. If you buy something
from someone there's a
reasonable expectation that you
are going to go back into the
forum into that person's thread
and explain how it worked, how
it went and what you thought of
the data and services. That way
the seller can validate their
reputation and the buyers can
demonstrate how things went so
it's a way to be open and
transparent in the marketplace.
This is one example of some
feedback that was provided. This
went to a money launderer
service. They said the Thread
Started laundered $300, the
speed is comparable to the
second cosmic speed. Everything
was magnificent, I'll go back.
The next person said I did some
laundering of money from a
female partner,, everything was
quick ad excellent, and the
Thread Started takes a small
percentage which makes everybody
happy. You can imagine if you
were working in Amazon or eBay
this is the feedback you would
want to see for a reliable
vendor. It's the exact same
thing here. This leads to an
important thing to consider.
Negative feedback has the same
role in the marketplace. If you
don't think you can trust a
person read their feedback. If
it's negative you don't want to
work with that vendor. In this
case this is a good example of
negative feedback. A person asks
has your service been tested or
vouched? How do we know that we
can trust you? I can provide
potential business for you if I
can trust you. Next person says
he's a ripper. Don't believe
him. He says his drops are from
Florida. The seller says I'm no
ripper, I've never had a
complaint, this guy is just
trying to cause trouble. I've
never dealt with him before,
moderator please ban him. He's
just trying to disrupt my
transaction. The next person
said, I contacted him on another
forum, I asked him if he accepts
escrow for grantee, of course he
refused. this person won't work
with a guarantor, I don't think
we can trust him. The negative
feedback if it stacks up can get
them completely blocked from a
forum. Moderators and
individuals who are engaging in
transactions don't want to deal
with people who are just messing
around. People want their money,
products and they want a
successful outcome. This is as
much a legitimate business using
certain business practices like
customer service in order to get
people to use illegal products
to engage in identity theft and
cyber crime. So this is an
important issue. When we think
about organization we've got a
participatory experience with
regard to transactions. Buyers
and sellers interact. Buyers get
the potential to give everyone
feedback through the use of the
positive or negative reviews.
That affects the way that
sellers are perceived in the
market. This also creates an
additional layer of complexity.
Not only do we have guarantors
operating but some of our
forums, those that are
sophisticated have guarantors
forums, etc, will even provide
product reviews and testing and
that affects all the
transactions. You might think
why would a forum provide a
check or validation process for
selling? Because they want
everyone to be satisfied and
this is just an example of one
forum's checking process.
Checking your goods takes place
voluntarily or if the
administrator of the forum
requires it. Checking is done by
one specific person, takes one
to three days. After the check
the guarantor there will be no
stupid flames in the topic, like
we showed earlier where the
person is trying to argue no,
we're a legititmate vendor. The
moderator will write a review on
this and close the topic. If a
requirement to provide your
product or testing is refused
you are risking ban and your
announcement is erased. So
either you play or you don't. If
you don't and you are asked to
play then this runs the risk of
you being kicked out of the
board. No money is taken for
testing. This is interesting
because unlike guarantor
services or escrow payments the
forum's completely doing this
out of the goodness of their
heart for participants involved.
They want to make sure that
everyone is satisfied with the
outcome. You provide the
products for the test in the
same configuration in which you
sell it. You give it to us
exactly as you would give it to
the buyer. A good review is
going to go a long way because
it demonstrates that you are
trustworthy. In some cases
forums will designate an
individual as a verified seller.
A verified vendor of a specific
product. That's its type of
person you know you want to go
to because they're not going to
cheat you or rip you off This
creates an additional layer of
complexity. And when we think
about all of the encounters, not
only do we have the potential
for checking and testing but our
best forums also had a good
degree of administrative
oversight. In that case forums
would actively go in and disrupt
or remove vendors on the on the
basis of negative feedback. This
is an example of just one of the
forums rules on how vendors get
banned or blocked or how
complaints are processed. They
say if the transaction has been
carried out it has to be
confirmed. If you leave a
fictitious review you will be
banned perhaps even permanently.
You can't just come in and junk
up the thread and make
complaints. They have to be
validated. They're going to want
you to post logs proving guilt
and what they're saying is they
want the ICQ logs of your
conversation with the person.
They want to see how exactly it
went down. You can't just say
this person is a ripper or a rip
off artist. You have to
provide validation. In the last
part, users with one to ten
messages that have not been on
the forum for long will be
deleted at the discretion of the
moderator. That means if you are
a seller you can't create five
accounts and say this guy is
great, I've worked with him
before because those will be
removed. This has an important
implication. In some of the
recent publications regarding
how we might disrupt stolen data
markets some people have argued
for a civil attack procedures,
where you go in and post
anything that makes it hard for
sellers to interact and for
buyers to know who to trust. A
civil attack is only going to be
effective in those disorganized
forums. The ones heavily managed
will figure out what's going on
and block the individual, block
the account.If you're doing it
from a specific computer, the
computer itself might even be
banned. So better organized
forums may not be disrupted by a
civil attack. If it is effective
it will probably only be for a
short period of time. So we have
to think what we're going to do
about a disorganized market That
leads us to a final point about
Organization. We have
individuals working in a
collegial fashion to engage in
transactions. We have a peer
process where individuals are
being reviewed, vetted, tested,
challenged. At a macro level
where we divorce ourselves from
the individual transactions and
think about interaction we're
dealing with what we might think
of as formal organizations. As a
moderator who provides a place
for people to buy and sell data.
They also offer a good degree of
managerial structure that is to
an extent that is hierarchical.
And there are interconnections
between our forums. Some of the
better vendors would say I
advertise on the following
sites, you can see my reviews
there as a way of demonstrating
I am trustworthy and reputable
so this kind of cross form
interaction is important. And
finally duration over time. Four
of our five forums we had posts
over a five year window. If you
look at a date of an
individual's post some of them
went back to 2004. So we're
talking about a long period of
time where some of the groups
have been active. That's a very
important thing when we're
talking about market disruption.
If you have a group that's been
active for a decade they might
be harder to disrupt than one
that's been active for three
months or one that has come up
and gone away. So there's a
definitive difference in the
types of markets we see. What
I'll do now is transition away
from the Organizational issues
and I'm going to talk for a
moment about the economic impact
of the markets. We've talked
about pricing and the way in
which products are bought and
sold. So, let's take just a
second and look at the potential
money that people might make.
There's a lot of data being
sold. How much can an individual
reasonably make? In order to
come to these conclusions since
we can't necessarily know how
many transactions were
successfully completed what
we've done is added up all
positive and negative feedback
that an individual received.
That has potential for error.
There could be fictitious
reviews and false positives in
the data. There could be one
potential way to understand how
many instances the transaction
took place. As you can see with
dumps we had 190 instances of
transactions from our
non‑ripping forum and 67 in our
ripping forums so 257 dumps or
transactions that took place. We
have 63 for CVVs, the majority
of them coming from the ripping
forums, reinforcing that our
data point from earlier. On bank
accounts the majority come from
ripping forums. From eBay
and PayPal accounts we saw 6
from non-ripping forums and 3
from ripping forums. So this
gives us some degree of how many
transactions might have taken
place. Another problem that
comes up though is this excludes
anyone who didn't have a product
review. They may have had no
feedback. They could have had
transactions but we didn't
capture the product reviews in
our data points so there's
potential for bias there and I
will talk about how we tried to
correct that in just a second.
Taking those metrics we tried to
overlay some of the pricing
metrics. Thinking about our
average cost for data and the
total number of transactions
that take place. With our dump
sellers many specified they
wanted to sell data in large
amounts. In some cases their
minimum quantity buy might have
been a hundred. So we tried to
set up base lines for how many
pieces an individual might have
purchased in the course of a
transaction. For Dumps, we took
100 dumps per transaction.
Taking the average cost, if you
buying $102 for 100 dumps your
average would be $10,260, for
CVVs, taking 50 accounts that is
an average cost of $1,310. For
eBay and PayPAl accounts
thinking again about 50 that
gives us $1,362.50 average. If
we multiplied the number of
transactions by the amount of
money that we expect has taken
place this gives us some pretty
dramatic estimates for profit.
In the case of dumps we're
looking at $2,636,000. That's a
staggering amount of money. That
leads to the potential that
there's no way your math is
right on that. You could argue
that. So if we take the median
price for dumps, not the mean
that's $40. At that rate we're
still looking at a million
dollars in total transactions.
If we want to throttle that a
little and say all right we're
probably getting false positive.
If we're only getting 65% of the
feedback that was received that
puts us somewhere in the
neighborhood of $668,000 or
$1,000,713 so we're still
talking about a substantial
profit for dumps sells. We're
not disaggregating rippers from
non‑rippers either. This means
how much money one vendor could
make. This gives us total
economic estimate. We could run
this is couple of different ways
but this is a potential for loss
that we wanted to highlight So
sellers could make a substantial
amount of money. We might argue
this is a seller's market. If we
take the number of buyers that
provided positive feedback that
gives us a different sense of
how things go. FOr non-ripping
dumps we only had 117 instances
of positive feedback and our
ripping forums only 24 people
had a satisfactory encounter. So
there's a difference in what
individuals report. Buyers are
not going to come out as good
when we compare it with dumps
vendors. Let's try to figure out
how much money a prospective
dumps buyer might make. If
you've ever read any of the
reports, you know that they
provide potential loss metric
per person. It's $188 in the
2013 report but it varies from
time to time. What we've tried
to do here is take an amount
reported by the Bureau of
Justice Statistics for identity
theft. Victimization. For a
credit card losses in the US in
2012 Victims reported an average
loss of $1,448. The median was
only 300. When we compared it
against debit cards losses we're
talking about $500 versus $200,
so there is some difference.
Let's talk about the return on
investment for a dumps for a
dumps buyer then. If we had 117
instances of positive feedback.
Just assume for a second try to
throttle the amounts that they
received, that only 65 cards
they buy are valid and depending
on what metric you want to use
this creates a lot of different
outcomes. But if we take the
credit card loss average we're
talking about $94,000 in gain
per transaction so 8 on the ROI.
If we take the median the ROI
drops dramatically. But buyers
have the potential to gain
somewhere in the neighborhood of
$2,281,000 which isn't bad but
not as good as we might see with
regards to dumps vendors. If we
take the debit card amount using
the median loss we're looking at
buyers acquiring somewhere in
the neighborhood of $1.5 million
so it's a different type of
metric depending on what you do.
Thinking strategically. Maybe
dumps aren't the way to go.
Let's just say you use eBay and
PayPal for a moment. Let's
assume the 25 pieces you buy
from an eBay or Pay Pal vendor
are active. The ROI is way
better in these instances than
for any other type of
transaction. In this case it
could be $36,000 per transaction
using the credit card loss
average or 13,000 if we use the
debit loss average. So there are
dramatic differences here and it
would strike people, hopefully
in the audience, that the better
way to go is to be a vendor and
not a buyer. Because at least
you are always going to make a
profit whether or not your data
works. someone who buys from you
may not know you're disreputable
but they're going to pay you
anyway. So this economy is one
that is very very complicated.
unfortunately we're running out
of time so I'm going to have to
skip over the social network
analysis portion of this but we
can talk about it more in depth
later. Generally, what's the
take away from all of this. When
we think about the markets
themselves they are organized in
a unique fashion. At the
individual level we're talking
about a process where we're
seeing peers and colleagues. At
the formal forum level we're
seeing a more formal
organization that takes place.
The variation in terms of market
sophistication will tell us
these markets are insufficient.
We're going to see different
individuals acting different
based on their status based on
what they're told based on forum
moderators or administrators.
When we think about market
disruption, given all of this,
it's probably going to be a more
effective strategy from a law
enforcement perspective, or a
more strategic point of view,
the better way to go after these
markets based on how they're
organized is to take out the
entire forum. Given the number
of dumps vendors and product
sales that take place, one
individual can jump in and take
over another person's share of
the market. We have to think
critically how do we affect
individuals? A one on one basis
removal is not going to work.
Civil attacks are going to fail
most likely in a better
organized forums. Something like
a dark market procedure where
law enforcement sets up and runs
the entire forum. Taking out the
entire site is going to have a
much more dramatic impact than
just occasionally removing a
seller. Another alternative
strategy might be to go after
the payment processers that were
used. Taking out Liberty
Resevere for instance, has had
some chilling effect on the
market. It's very, very short
term but it's going to make an
impact because that means they
have to transition to another
service. That poses other
challenges but it's an
alternative venue that may have
a longer effect on markets
disrupting. In general this is
something we can look at in a
much, much more broad
perspective. But with all the
data that we have, one of the
most important things I can tell
you from all of this is the need
for greater participation and
collaboration. As an academic
we're getting one‑half of the
pie. We can see what goes on in
markets but not the individual
exchanges between people outside
of the forums. If we can set up
better relationships with law
enforcement and industry we
could get a different
perspective on what's going on.
For instance, if we could have a
direct partnership with law
enforcement or industry partners
we could look at trying to
disrupt a market and do
evaluation so at the time a site
goes down we can look at where
people go to. This idea of
displacement, if you take out a
market, individuals who are
interested are going to go
somewhere else. Where do they go
and how quickly do they move
there? We can assess disruption
and what it does to the markets
in a broad way. We can get some
of the external communications
through ICQ and other media; and
we can do different processes of
analysis with that information.
In general, we're going to try
to do a lot more with this data.
We're going to try to compare
our economic stuff with the
social analysis and see whats
going on. We're going to through
IRC channels and a few other
sites to and try to create an
even larger data set and we
would like to compare with some
of the sites and compare them to
what we see in more active
markets. So there is a lot that
we can do from here. With that
in mind I will go ahead and
stop. Does anybody have any
questions? Yes, sir. [off mic]
[inaudible] >> Sure. The
question is when people were
selling credit reports what were
they actually offering? What we
saw were people offering credit
report services so they would do
checks not credit report dumps.
Any other questions? Yes, sir.
[off mic] >> He asked what was
the average age of accounts? No
one provided us with that
information so we couldn't tell
without actually buying the
data. Any other questions? Yes,
sir. [off mic] >> So if I
understand correctly, the
question is what do sellers do
to review moderators? So the
question is how do sellers get
into the market and how do they
operate? The better organized
forums will stipulate the terms
for transactions or at least how
things should go. They can't
guarantee that you have to work
that way, sellers have the
ability to say I'm going to do
this, not that so there's
variation that is allowed at the
individual level but generally
speaking the disorganized boards
on our site were like the wild
west, you could do whatever you
wanted. There's no necessary
reason why someone would have to
act a certain way. If anybody
else has any other questions
come on up or I can go to the
chill out room and we can set
things up that way. Thank you.
[Applause]