participant lists and
the rest
okay
oh
okay i suppose we can start
okay
okay so um welcome everyone to the akri
meeting at itf
110 slide
so welcome to not prague
uh this is uh the note 12 this is
something that
rich and i came up with just
the other day oh really i'm sure by now
you've seen all this uh
many many times and now you've seen it
yet another time
okay so our agenda for today
uh we start with the regular um
administrivia
so we've seen the note well we need a
note taker
and um we don't really need a jabra
scribe i'm
monitoring the jabber on my phone yeah
joy of using multiple devices
and but we do need a note taker
so please volunteer now
you can't proceed without a note taker
so please volunteer
either on jabra or just
break into the conversation speak up
i'll do it if nobody else will
okay
rich i'll take notes awesome thank you
thank you russ
okay and i'd like to remind everybody
when when you talk
please identify yourselves as if we were
in a physical meeting because later when
you watch
the session on youtube you don't really
know who's talking
okay so we got a note-taker uh we have a
document
update and we'll talk about acne
integrations
and the dtn node and next steps
before we get to the document updates uh
a little public service announcement
rich has decided to step down as
co-chair of acme so
we're also looking for a volunteer to
replace rich you can contact me
or the ids but not right now
let's do this after the meeting
okay so let's go with the
document updates
so um the email last mime is
already in the rfc pipeline star
delegation
is an itf last call
acme authority token is waiting for ist
review
so the token tn oauth list just
submitted an update waiting for ad
review
and we've got presentations here for
dtn node id integrations and subdomains
regarding regarding itf acme client
no recent update or discussions
so next slide
did they know the c presentation okay
let's see the presentation
all right brian you're up yes thank you
um so some of this content is duplicated
but left in for
background so you can go on to the next
slide
for those not familiar with dtn it is a
store and forward kind of a protocol
similar to
mime and the way that the email systems
work
and so the workflow of this validation
method
is really taken almost exactly as the
same as
the s mime validation next slide please
and the point of why this draft is being
proposed
we talked about this on the last ietf
but the idea here is that
acme has all of the infrastructure and
bookkeeping and all the necessary things
to do
p kicks validation and
there's a need in the dtn uh to be able
to do this kind of thing
when a new node comes onto the network
and needs to be
validated the same way that
a new email user might for an sbm
certificate
and next slide please
so so the the flow that is in the
email s9 draft is um
basically duplicated here uh with this
other encoding this other transport um
we're going to define an administrative
record for
for the bundle protocol and then the
acme server generates a part one a part
two
transport those two different paths and
then
the um dtn client that's doing the
validating of their identifier combines
them and sends back the response
next slide please
so uh the
because the blackout period for the the
internet draft updates
i wasn't able to update draft until
um just early this week but i did uh
submit a zero one version of the draft
that had some
clarification and updates uh this is
experimental
uh draft the idea is that this would not
be widely implemented
in acme but it is a way to use
the acting mechanism to do what we need
to do for
dtn id validation
and i believe this is the last slide
right
yes so at this point now um
the last changes to the draft were to to
clarify some encodings
some data encodings um to use native
uh byte strings instead of base 64 just
for slight efficiencies
but this the structure is really the
same and um
a lot of some supporting text was taken
in from
the changes to the s mime draft um so
this is more in alignment with the what
was approved for s mime
and at this point i have spent a little
bit of time
on a demonstration implementation
just as a proof of concept and that's
where things stand right now
okay so this already is a working group
raft
but what are you looking
good for do you think that's ready for
our last call
uh because of the simplicity and because
the alignment with the s mime
um i don't believe that there are any
further changes necessary yes so
oh and the other thing to mention is
that the
the bundled protocol drafts on which
this
were relying on for encoding and for for
transport
those have been moved to the the editor
queue
so those are now stabilized whereas in
the past they
really were still in slight flux
so there should be no need for
for further changes
the thing i'm worried about is if i now
do the uh
one of these audience polls the show of
hands
and ask how many people have read either
version of the draft
um do you think we're going to get more
than five
um i doubt that
right um so we could do the working
group last call
hopefully get
some uh replies about it soon
um let's ask a different way
anyone opposed to us having uh
having a working group last call i think
i saw roman there for a
moment yeah go ahead all right i was
just gonna jump in
uh you know as brian has kind of
indicated this is a bit of a
very narrowly focused kind of use case
we did decide to adopt it
so an approach we could try is to go to
work group last call
and if we get enough folks to have put
eyes on it
we and we work the results we can
proceed if we don't get enough
review then we can have another
conversation about how we can get more
review here
okay has the dtn community looked at
this
guessing this is an answer a question
for you
uh there has been some uh
looking at this from the dtn side that
the two things
that are new
here uh the one that's stated here is
that this does
create a new claim type for uris so
just making sure that the text in here
for uri claims
uri identifiers is reasonable and
complete
that's one of the i think focus areas
and
if anybody has implementation experience
or feedback from the
s mime draft because this is the same
effectively the same workflow as the s
mime draft
anybody who's familiar with the s
minecraft should be able to
at least understand the workflow here
and be able to give feedback
okay so i guess uh we have a plan for
how to proceed any
objections to this plan of just going to
working with platco and
hopefully getting enough reviews to
matter
we're going once going twice okay so
this is what we're going to do
so thank you brian and
next presentation is acme integrations
um we can go on to the next
an slide draft that describes how acme
can be integrated with multiple existing
clients and device certain enrollment
mechanisms without requiring any changes
so what's documented in this version of
the draft is est
risking risky cloud and tip integrations
and it doesn't change any of the
specifications for a usd risky
or type it just stitches them together
next slide
so there's been one change since the
previous draft in igf-109 and there was
one open item
which is how do we handle the risky
requirements
that uh the briskey
and then to research the brisket
registrar itself has an identity search
with an idkp cmc ra
um eku set um and
the conclusion that we've reached is
that um even if the briske ra is
is in the middle acting as um
essentially a proxy that lets a pledge
get a certificate from
acme the briskey area itself cannot get
a
certificate from an acme server that is
not willing to give it an idk pcmc array
so for example let's encrypt is not
going to wish you an identity search
with idkb cmc or asset
and so if the ra even though the ra may
be
getting acme certificates on behalf of
pledges
the ra itself may not be able to get an
acme certificate for itself
the acme server it's integrating with
is not willing to issue the ra an idkp
cmc
an idk pcmc or am eku
and which just means that the the risky
registrar itself
may have to get uh one identity
the change and that's been clarified on
multiple mailers
and that has been explicitly documented
in
draft04
and that's it next steps
right
next slide please and this is just
discussion and we were looking for
reviewers
and uh feedback and we believe that
we've no changes
to make on this and it's ready for last
call and but we would like some
reviewers please
oh and i have a question um
on the id kpcmcra that's in
extended key usage oid correct
correct yes do
certificates have multiple end
eku's in them in general
for briskee do
you have multiple ek well the circuit of
multiple different bits set for extended
key usage but the
the one that's important for brewski is
the
the brewski masa checks for that page in
the certainties from the risky area
gotcha but yeah
so no my question was for example in um
i'm drawing a blank on what it's called
you know the the secure ip stuff
um there's multiple eku's defined
but the rfc says
you can't tell you can't fail to
validate if they're not there
this is different from that and you're
acquiring one
and the users could have other eku's in
there which
are unaffected is that true the
the users there was the relying parties
the consumers of the service
they could have they could have all the
requests in there yet okay
thanks
but but the the one that the one that
was contentious is the
is this one because yeah the drafts all
but acting integrations we know that
let's encrypt
which is most isn't going to hand it out
um
so they're just that caveat that the
brisky ray itself
needs to search from a different city
than the pledges
thank you thank you any questions yes
russ
so it's my understanding that that
particular eku will only ever be used
with
cmp if you're an ra so um
it's really hard to see how it would
affect acme
um but it's it's it's for the brisket
integration use case russell when
when you're using so the brisk array
the pledge talks to briskera and
actually i don't have a picture of i
don't have a picture of the architecture
in this
presentation but the breeze the slides
will talk to the brisk array and the
risk array will have two backend
integrations once in a massive server
one to acme
um and the ra will go to
the oreo will go to the massive first to
get a voucher and this will issue a
voucher to the pledge
and it's for that interaction that the
master will check that the
um the bruce keys the brewski
ras and identity cert has that bit set
and then it's a completely independent
interaction between the
or a and acme to get a cert on behalf of
the
pledge and that bit doesn't play any
role in that interaction so that eku bit
is only needed for
getting for the ra to get a voucher
from the master server and that bit
isn't set
when the ra is getting a certificate
from acme to hand back their pledge
so that's all consistent with what i
with what i know
okay okay and we're just like we're just
we're explicitly calling out in the in
the document that the
ra itself can't get its own identity
cert itself
from acme because then the r isn't going
to be able to present that
and then to research to the mass in
order to get a voucher on behalf of
pledge
okay hendrick
so this is henrik um don't please
correct me if i'm
wrong i um understand this extended
usage as the indication that this is an
array and this is
required by est in the the
7030 drop it is was
initially introduced by cmc and
we also tend to reuse it
also for cmp so to have one
let's say unique extended key usage
identification
for an array and therefore you're
probably right
an acme server will not issue or
enroll a certificate with this key usage
and
i feel like it's a good idea not to do
that
completely automatically just based on a
domain validation
because it's a specific role this entity
has the ra role and this is indicated by
by this extended key usage so okay i
think it's okay
okay good
um yes then
i have to say allow twice what um so you
can hear me
yeah um so the brewski
end of things is all cmp based
not cnc based the brisky
side of things is just getting the
signed voucher which
whatever the json route performance uh i
need to i can't
recall the rfc off my head and but the
brewski flow
the brisket float where the ore is
interacting with the massive servers
just to get designed vouchers to hand
back their pledge
so that the pledge trusts the ra
right russ's comment was that you need
that for cmp
um can we let russ talk
yeah ruskin duck so brewski's est based
and that particular key usage
is needed if you're going to be
an r.a and all i think they're saying
is that you can't use acme to get an
ra certificate and that seems fine
yeah yeah i got that part right and that
makes complete sense and i am in
complete agreement that you don't want
acme issuing ra search because
that would be bad very bad my question
is
do you need the extension the eku
for cmp or cmc they're doing est
which is can be both right
so it's needed for cmc it
is being added to cmp and lamps right
now
and i think est uses it but sorry my
memory's not
that good i think he so
est uses like you can do some things in
cmc and some things in cmp
like it's a sort of a mixed bag as i
recall
i'm asking because i'm debating on
[Music]
agreeing to review the draft
and i don't know much about cmp so if
it's all cmp stuff i'm not going to
volunteer
because i don't really know anything
about cmp
i need to go back and i need to go back
and read the read these to draft in
detail again
to answer that question deb right but
your draft is not
it's my question is whether your draft
is like cmp ish
or whether i can read the draft not
knowing much about cmp
you can read the draft you can read the
draft without not much about cmp
okay so i can read the draft it looks
like it's short it's like it's 17 pages
long it sounds like
it short and there's quite a few figures
in there
oh good pictures are better
so i can review if you would like great
thank you
and it does not go into too many details
in cmb or cmc
um okay so um
if no one else is in the queue uh do you
uh when do you think that uh this is uh
ready for working with last call we
will get the reviewers there i think so
yeah once we get to reviewers yeah i
think we're we're good to go with it
i don't mind anyways so obvious question
uh
anybody opposed to going to working
group last call
good i like this silence okay so we'll
start to working with last calls
um after well next week
okay so i think when you're also doing
the
uh last thing the subdomain so
which can you put on those slides
oh there they are okay so
quantum next slide please
so i can be allowed not a server to
issue search for given identifier
um without requiring a challenge to be
supposed to be fulfilled against that
identifier
and like for example an acme cert can
issue a search
for food that part of the example.com
where the client has only
fulfilled a challenge against one of the
parents authorized domain names part of
example the comrades
um on a server creation search for
multiple
for a number of um some of them inserts
that only require a single challenge to
be filled against the parent domain that
that's really nice when you want to
scale to use acme to issue certs
and automatically for a large number of
identity search for devices here
internet
cases um we do an authorization once for
a
top level domain or our apparent domain
and then we could use acme to
automatically
search for for hundreds or thousands of
uh
and density devices um
next slide
so changes and we've recorded the
submitter feedback
immediately one online we've
incorporated
and one of the strong piece of feedback
was to restrict the challenge type to
dns01 specifically for the subdomain use
case
so what that means is that um a dns of
one challenge must be fulfilled against
a parent authorized domain name and
author
in order to issue certs for a sub-domain
identifier
um we've also included and text in
the latest draft to address the two open
items that were raised
on the mailer and discussed briefly at
the last itf109
next slide
this is the first of the open items and
the open items does the client
need a mechanism to indicate to the
server that they're
willing and enabled capable of
fulfilling challenges against parent
domains so for example for the food
appear
that example the calm identifier should
the challenge
should the client be able to explicitly
tell the server that it's it actually
has like the dns keys or whatever it
needs to fill a challenge against prior
to example.com or example.com
and one of the things that was raised on
the mailer during discussions was that
we want to avoid
the scenario where a server could issue
a challenge against a parent
identifier that the client is not
authorized to fulfill a challenge
against
for example a client
issues an order for food a pirate
example.com a server issues a challenge
for example account but the client
doesn't have the dns keys for publishing
tax records to fill that challenge
against the parent domain we want to
avoid that scenario
um so what so what i propose and this
hasn't been reviewed in detail yet so
this is what i proposed is um and this
is based on
inferring some comments that ryan and
philippe and a few people have made on
demanders as well
is we could include an optional and
boolean flag
um associated with an identifier in the
new order new whatsapp request
and that optional flag indicates whether
the client has control over all parent
at the ends or not
and because i believe typically for for
cas
um they'll base your logic off the
top level domain example.com not off
things like birth example.com
um so if this flag is true then the
server may issue
if the client includes this flag and the
flag is through then the server
knows it can issue a challenge against
any of the parent um edn's
and the client will be capable of
fulfilling a challenge against them if
the client sets this flag as false
then the client is telling the server i
can't fulfill the challenge against any
parent domain the only thing i'm
authorized to fill the challenge against
is the explicit um
the explicit mfqdn that i'm requesting
so that's the only thing i want to
challenge for
um well this slide looks a little
smaller apologies but
uh i just cut and pasted some uh
text from the draft which shows what the
parent-to-main authorization looks like
it's just an extra brilliant flag that
is optionally associated with the
identifier
um and i think well we can debate we
should actually debate what the
logic should be if that isn't included
and i think if
the flag isn't included it should
default to true probably
and because that's the behavior that and
baseline acme
has baseline acme doesn't make any
assumptions about this at all so it's
left entirely of the server policy
um but so i've one follow-on question
for this proposal if you go onto the
next slide
so next slide please and the question i
have is that sufficiently granular
like um is there any need for a client
to be able to specify a subset of parent
ada into this control over for example
the client wants to search for food that
pair the example.org
and i it can control the power of the
example that are but not the top level
domain
and do we need that level of flexibility
and um i don't think we do
but i'd like to discuss that and other
documented interact for
is that we don't need that level of
flexibility and just a simple boolean
flag is efficient
and so what's shown on the right-hand
side again this
the rendering isn't that big in this
page but it shows
um underneath the identifier
is an array of videos that the client is
actually authorized to
fulfill a challenge against yeah that's
better so you scroll
over to this yeah you can see that the
client has issued a
an order for the food that part of
example.org identifier
and i've just included illustratively
the client could also optionally include
um a list of edn's
saying well i can confirm the challenge
against food that bar that example
org i can fulfill a challenge inspiring
example at all but i'm not authorized
with village challenges example.org
now i don't think we need that
flexibility but i'm just asking a
question here
okay and next on the next slide we can
go on to open item number two
and this is just from the server side
does the server need a mechanism to
provide a choice of identifiers
to the client and let the client choose
which challenge to fulfill
and there's some discussion on this on
the mailer as well we believe that this
is not needed and if this would make the
server state machine and tracking fairly
complicated and it's sufficient for the
clients to be able to signal
to the server whether it's capable of
fulfilling
challenges against parent adns or not
and so the proposal is there's no
provision to do this in the draft and
i've added clarifying statements in the
draft
that if the client indicates that the
parent domain authorization is true
then server policy controls which
identifier that the server can use to
which we challenge against
but all the client is indicating with
this flag
is that it's up to you now server i've
told you i can authorize against or
fulfill challenges against all of the
domains
you decide which one you want to issue a
challenge against and that aligns with
the baseline acme spec as well
um next slide please i think they're the
only two open items
yeah there you go there that you want to
open items um the draft has just been
published with those two open items
and closed and documented um
so i'd like to get some feedback on
those two proposals for the open items
and it is based on what was discussed in
demanders
a couple of months back um and then we'd
look for a final
review of draft zero four without any
feedback and i know ross you you
reviewed
version two i believe we've incorporated
all that feedback already
yeah you're in the queue
so um i'm thinking the single bit is not
granular enough because
it in different parts of the dns tree
you don't know
um exactly where to stop so in your
example food.bar.example.org
you're pretty sure that you can't put
the challenge in dot org but
you know in other parts
where especially in cctlds it's not
exactly clear where the
where the top of a particular
registrance control begins
so i think you're you're hey i can deal
with challenges in
in any of these places is safest
okay
anyone else
yeah this is rich um as an individual
i think we should adopt this as
um a chair uh
i think we should um you know send this
over to dnsop and get their feedback
once we've adopted
[Music]
so the obvious question is how many
peoples have read how many people have
read it
and perfectly willing to
do the show of hands let's try it
right
please don't raise your hand if you are
an author
okay this seems to be converging on
about two people
having read it and six people having
explicitly not read it
okay another one
um so yeah we can do an adoption call
i'd
rather not do it well immediately now
but
uh after we've done the other working
group last calls
not to burden people with too many
things at the same time
um but yeah i think we can do the
adoption call and then
okay thanks for that okay
so uh so i guess the next step is the
adoption column which means we're almost
done with the agenda and we got to the
open
mic part
going once
twice okay so
uh you're getting back a lot of your
time and i just want to
thank rich for all the years of being a
chair of acme
feel free to like and say thank you
awesome yeah i was going to say thanks
rich i don't know how to flip my camera
everyone's looking at my
monitor uh for those that might be
interested in
being a co-chair please do drop me a
note and to me and ben and we can sort
that out
additionally what would be helpful for
the working group is if we chartered a
little more specificity into what the
future work is
uh for example we have a we have some
drafts we're talking about we have some
drafts adopted we don't have necessarily
milestones
i see that there's some drafts that uh
that are related and we don't even have
on the agenda to talk about so if we
just had some dates
for when we think we're going to be done
and we have some notion of when we will
be done and what classes of extensions
we want to
we want to cover so it's basically a
matter of do we just need to finish
what we have or is there a new scope
that we expect to be talking about in
the working room
now's a good time to throw that out
metaphorically on the mailing list not
necessarily at this meeting okay
thank you um anything else for open mic
yeah rich needs to feed his dinosaur
more often
it's really lost weight
they taste like chicken
[Music]
okay so thank you all and
getting back uh 20 minutes of your life
back
bye have a good week everyone
i