good morning everybody
i think we'll give it a few more minutes
for people to continue to trickle in
especially
those poor souls on the west coast
yeah alex the guard is uh volunteered to
take notes
i'm sure that he would appreciate if
anybody else wanted to join him in the
um cody md
from the agenda page the detector gender
page
especially because i believe i'll
actually are you
you're one of the presenters on that
frame right so i need somebody else to
take notes for the period while you are
um
presenting
uh okay good and bernard seems to be
bouncing on and off so maybe he's having
network issues maybe we should wait
until he's ready
and this is very it will be your stand
in a.d
for uh for this session i think uh it's
4am from murray so nope here
mary's murray just came on all right
great
but
much bernard a few more minutes
hopefully i'll be back soon
i'd rather not run it entirely by myself
but i will if i have to
so
foreign
all right i guess i'll get started
hopefully bernard will be able to join
soon i'm not quite sure what's up there
he was briefly here but then tone
disconnected so maybe it's having
network issues so anyway welcome to
uh avt core at the virtual idf
um i'm your chair bernard is your
hopefully your other chair soon
uh alex guyard is taking notes on cody
md
if anybody else wants to help out there
i'm sure he'd appreciate it
uh let's see meeting tips
um hopefully if you're already
successfully here
you know most of these things um
please use your headphones when speaking
if possible to avoid echo
um other things
let's see and let's see this
um andrew you can enter the cube by
using the raise hand tool
um you'll need to unmute magnet yourself
manually
uh video is separate and audio video is
appreciated if you want but remember you
have to
unmute audio also separately
uh no well that well applies hopefully
everybody is familiar with this if not
you can follow the links
on this slide here
or go to many other places on the ietf
website
it's hard to miss it if you go to the
idf
this here are the links to various
things
um the jabber room is uh
bridged here in the web uh
in the midico so if you don't need to
uh do anything special for that it's
just there in the
dialogue balloon tab and
uh if
anybody actually um does anybody if
anybody
is not able to talk out loud for
whatever reason maybe your family's
asleep
um we can say mike at the room if we
could have a volunteer
to relay anybody want to relay from the
chat
uh if not i'll try to keep an eye on the
chat that'll be hard with
if i'm to steal the chair here um
but i know you have some i'm doing this
and also dr uh alex
yes uh jonathan i'll keep an eye on the
chat
wow great thank you
okay here's our agenda
we've had a few tweaks
for things uh
so if anybody has any comments let me
know we've got a few
um uh work working group items that are
going to deal with relatively quickly
and then spend most of the time on
asp encapsulation
any comments on that
good all right uh we've had
a number of drafts published in the last
idea so that's very exciting
many of those were cluster 238 so that's
even more exciting
uh so uh good work keep
doing teamwork uh we've done pub wrecks
on the party rdt mix
we've had a few working class calls
which many of which will have commentary
on
we have one expired draft we're going to
mention in a moment
and we adopted three day work items
frame marking we had an interim meeting
and
had a consensus
on this that we're planning to
help move into experimental because of
this limitation status um
and we're going and we're removing the
dependency of vp9 on it
this was the discussion on the list
so there's still a few items to resolve
but i
think uh we're going pretty well there
i don't think we have this on the agenda
but i don't remember
um
yes i did just publish uh uh an update
that
watches all of the uh the benign
information
the things um and i try to dig into the
the issues that the implementer reported
about
i think we need to drill uh down to a
little bit more because from what i can
tell
it's nothing to do with vpa it's it's
it's in both vpa and vp9
and it's really a non-issue i don't i
don't see anything that mandates
uh sfp rewriting of anything um
or requirement for incrementing by one
so maybe we need to you know follow up
on the list and figure out
what really needs to happen there if
anything
all right yeah so probably uh let's
raise that on the list
yeah i i opened a thread this morning on
it sounds good
yeah so if anybody has any comments on
that please respond on the list
uh the tetra draft um
we aim the chairs emailed the draft it's
expired more than a year ago
uh the chairs emailed the draft to
authors and no response so our proposal
is to drop this milestone and work item
for now
and if uh interest returns in this
always obviously be adopted does anybody
have any objection to this
um i'll mention this on the list also
um but sounds like there's no objection
so that's good
uh so um
that's it for the chair items now i'm
the first
person on the agenda should have to be
relatively quick
um and so unless there's anything else
on the chair items so
about that
so uh status of this uh we published
after
eleven all the authors of um infinite
effort working for class call
um all the authors i'll
uh acknowledge their bcp 7879
obligations
um we have uh
christopher raised a few issues uh
entering working class call which will
be on a
slide in a minute uh there are some ipr
disclosures
which i'll also mention and our proposal
is to send to pub wreck
after 12. um
now there's any objection to that
a list about uh what looks like an
omission in the vp9 draft i don't know
if it was intentional or not but
something that was in vp8
was uh emitted in vp9 and um
it it impacts on marking and i think
it'll impact any
anything similar to frame marking like
uh 81
dependency descriptor or anyone that
wants to do
any kind of intelligent marking or
analysis
of the vp9 streams without having to go
really deep into the
bitstream um basically it's difficult to
identify whether something is a
reference frame or not uh just my proper
inspection of the headers
to figure it out and i'm guessing that
may be an omission or an oversight
because it was their vp8 um
and maybe just uh you know
fell off the table yeah i think
par part of that is you know whether
it's um it's a somewhat of a complicated
question
if something is uh once you have
temporal scalability i mean
because you know are you going to want
people to
rewrite as a dependency for this for the
layers that are actually being forwarded
but um i'll take a look at that uh in
more detail
um i mean i don't think we want to try
to actually change
the bits of the wire at this point given
how much vp9
deployment there is but i'll try to take
a look and see if i can
figure that out i mean it may be maybe
that you do need to dig into the actual
vp9 bitstream
which i agree would possibly be
unfortunate but um
i'd rather not change the uh like i said
we've got a
very wide deployment of ep9 at this
point uh so
i'd rather not change the bits of the
wire if possible but um
i think the biggest thing is to figure
out the biggest thing is to figure out
whether it was a conscious
decision to omit it from vp9 whether it
was a mistake
i think that that would that would be
the first yeah i mean
i guess my questions are people actually
i i think
it was you know the people who were just
those of us who were designing the
excuse me uh the vp9
this stream weren't they didn't have any
use for that flag so
you know we we didn't see i think we
didn't i mean
we didn't think of it when we designed
it because we weren't using it so
um i guess the question is is there are
people using that flag
from vp8 um rather than using temporal
scalability which serves
i'd say much the same purpose to a
somewhat uh
with somewhat more flexibility but um
might be better to answer this on the
list when i'm more awake
uh sam bernard i see you now are you
actually here at alberta because that
would be awesome if you were
uh yes oh excellent good
i saw you were bouncing in and out
before so hopefully you're stapled now
all right so um next week we do have
some ipr disclosures
on uh the vp9 draft
yeah i had sent those to the list
earlier and they have
been posted as they came in to the list
that
they related to um so the question for
the group is
is there anything that thinks we should
do about this
we did not hear anything uh any
suggestions on the list
uh or should we uh just
ahead
so is there anyone uh let me put it this
way is there anyone who objects to
moving
forward with vp9 uh given the
disclosures that
uh we've seen
anyone uh put up their hand i don't
think so
i don't see anybody there anything in
the jabber room
nope okay i think we have our answer
and finally we have so crystal raised
some
questions on the stp uh issues
um as a meta issue he sort of raised
that we probably should be sending these
things to the stp directorate but
we didn't so we'll try to do that more
of that going forward but
um specifically on this he raised some
issues on the sap negotiation
um my proposal there are
three parameters on vp9 profile id max
frame rate and max frame size my
proposal is the profile id
it needs to stay unchanged and answers
updated offers
um if you want to do profile id use you
know negotiate a new payload type number
whereas max frame rate and max frame
size are declarative
either side can add it or change that in
either an answer or an updated offer
um and then relatedly we don't actually
say
christopher also pointed out there
wasn't any language saying what um
you know somebody who receives an stp
and
this is a media sender um actually it
has to do in response to these
and uh the important question there
is whether max frame rate and max
size you should not or must not exceed
them
excuse me so
i'd say there my inclination is to say
would be to say should not um but
i see justin in the queue so he can get
some in the bands
kristen
should is probably appropriate here
simply because of the fact that
uh you know primarily it's a pixel rate
you know limitation if one exists and
like for a screen chair or something
like that you may find yourself
exceeding like one of these dimensions
um
i think it just looks like a pretty
heavy hammer you know given that this is
marginally advisory
all right that was my inclination too so
um
i guess like i said the important the
other important question is
do you know before both of these things
do browsers will any
existing browser applications choke or
will they just they just read this as
advisory and we'll try to decode
everything i mean my suspicion is i try
to decode everything but i just wanted
to make sure that was the case
um are you still in the queue for
uh justin or i don't know i need to
remove you all right
all right um so yeah so it sounds like
that we
i'll make that it should um i'll just
and
make do the rest of these i'll just say
one more
uh comment there and i'll publish
a draft 12 and then um our
belief is that we don't need to do
anything further
uh we don't need to do any update work
with less call because these are
basically just the
verses for the issues if i'm working the
last call so we'll do a public once all
the 12 is out uh well i guess
once we also do address the
uh issue that pedal raised
all right so that's it for that and next
we have uh jpeg access
everybody i hope you can hear me well
yes so this is about the rtp input spec
for a
jpeg's content
so the wglc
announcement is concluded on
february 23 3rd and there were five
responses three positive and no
objections and there were two
uh questions most of the questions came
from christos
regarding the sdp and one came from
india
also regarding svp uh so next slide
please
thank you uh so uh the sdp questions
from
uh christopher uh were about uh the
section six
to four in our uh rtp payload spec
which basically contained just a single
uh sentence saying that all
uh parameters are declarative uh but we
wrote it
to be more uh correct and and more
information more contain more
information to describe what we actually
uh want
um so so that's that's a
rewrite and it's a full paragraph that
was added to the to the document
and then there was a question on
optional versus mandatory parameters
but uh we believe that this was already
clear in the text because
we really have one uh part where it says
like
uh mandatory parameters and and then uh
another part it says like optional
parameters so i don't
think this was really an issue unless we
um misunderstood the question
uh so to be clear all parameters are
optional except for
the rate parameter and the transmode
parameter
and then we used wrong
terminology in the text so we replaced
the wording of sdp object everywhere
with the sdp media description i think
that's correct
unless somebody tells me if it's not
please
let me know if it's not correct still
and then
from india there was a remark basically
one of the optional parameters the
interlaced parameter
was accidentally spell corrected to
become interlaced
in revision 7 of our draft so i
changed this back to to be to be
interlaced again as
is intended and this uh reflects with
the other rtp
uh standards and also with the 70 2110
specification so so it should be
interlaced that was a good
fix and then we also had a small
side question on the clock rates so
indeed we specified originally that the
clock rate should be 90 kilohertz but
uh this is this this
took like a an extra liberty and i think
indeed the comment was correct that it's
better to say
it it must be 90 kilohertz so we changed
that
and made it a mandatory uh setting and i
submitted draft 09 which addresses all
the
the questions and remarks uh normally uh
uh so i think uh yeah the text is done
uh and uh i would like people to review
it maybe again
or uh or to move it forward
in the in the pipeline so that's it
thank you
i yeah i just want to add i i don't know
what the next step would be so that's a
question to the
chairs so if they if they could
point us in the right direction be very
very helpful and appreciated
uh well i how about submitting a draft
with the sdp changes you described here
the draft online so i i did that
okay yes all right so then
uh the next step i guess would be uh
chair review and publication request
yes if that if that's possible yes
yep that sounds um
go ahead please uh put that in the
minutes
so we know what the next step is on
everything thank you
okay yeah and if any questions pop up uh
i'm
available uh at your disposal so
let me know thank you
so yeah so well uh chairs will do our
chair review make sure everything's
reviewed and then we'll go with
publication requests and we'll
figure out whether bernard and i are
driving that one
all right next is cryptex and justin
uh okay so you published the new version
of the draft just the other day
um one version of the draft or the oo
is a working group document um
01 basically changes the name of the
parameter used to negotiate support for
cryptex and stp
we had a discussion on the list a month
or two ago and
a equals cryptex or came out as like the
prevailing option
that's been incorporated into zero one
and there's some other editorial cleanup
next slide
up yeah so the things that the one thing
remaining right now is inclusion of the
test vectors
um you know to demonstrate proper
encryption using cryptex into the
document
uh once we have that i think we should
be ready for for last call
uh sergio is currently working on those
test vectors
um so i think you know for last call we
should be looking at
it's probably like this period between
now and the next itf will probably be a
good time to start that
that's everything
cool anybody else have any comments
if not uh hopefully they'll be able to
get that done soon
justin do you think we should be ready
for uh
implementation very very soon
for implementation yeah
yeah um i i don't know the time frame
of uh you know when when that would be
actually implemented within chrome or
whatever
uh no longer my exact sort of remit now
but um
i've discussed it with the team here and
you know you know probably something
that
people start to look at uh you know in
the coming months
i see sergio just point out that
uh for performtp
including cryptex with the test vector
that are used in the in the spec
and also by jonathan in his
implementation
um so it should be just a matter of
complaint of putting
yeah as sergio said i have an
implementation for the jetsea srtp
library also though it's not wired up in
the rest of the system yet
it's good to hear
all right uh that's it next is evc
all right ready to check can you guys
hear me
hello
yes oh that's great okay
all right morning uh cup of coffee
so this is gonna be a quick update for
ubc draft
uh thank you already um so just kind of
quick recap whatever you
have decided for you is a draft a couple
of millions back
which is no purse parky and also no
support of a multi
uh rtp stream is mixed with multiple
transport and all
also no download basis signaling forever
uh for regional support so that is all
have been great for um
i think i believe it's two minutes back
and the last two items no support or
framework
um that's really the decision co-author
made things the last intermediate
um agreement defense free market removal
to experimental
um so that doesn't make any sense for us
to support it anymore and
then also we remove the slice
authentication
and also the psr support that's also
basically trying to
align with the bbc um
bbc draft next slides please
next up so uh ubc driver was adopted as
a working group drop since
108. um we recently
um uh very honored to have a young quest
from samsung
uh as co-author i'm not sure if you want
to save your word
after that so i will leave it to him um
the recent
revision which is the zero one working
group draft
uh we mostly focus on the uh ubc codex
specifications
uh i think everything is getting there
um there's only a few
uh there's only a few edited notes left
um but i think we're going to get it
down
on this uh codex specification part very
soon
uh next slide please
uh you actually skipped one yeah there
you go
um so there are still uh a few
placeholders
we're trying to address in in the draft
and the major thing we have left
which is a section 7 the optional
parameters for the stpe
um we believe we have agreed that the
ubc
pillow draft will be following bbc and
we bc draft
is almost getting there we we have a new
version which is going to talk about
later um
has mostly parameters down so we
actually gonna start
to fill up this blanks in the ubc draft
um let's we will be probably gonna
follow
closer look with the bbvc draft um
so it's really i i think it's reasonable
for us to target working group law
school around
summer 2020. uh
you know uh at that time i think bbc
should be done already
i mean working with glasgow hopefully um
yeah that's a pretty much we only have
our two divisions since 109 and that's
all the updates i have
any questions oh you okay i'm not sure
you want to say a few words up to him
thanks for having me as an author of
this uh
you know uh internet prep um personally
i've been
involved you know for
i will do my best to particularly
progress
this one in the right direction thank
you
thank you okay we're very happy to have
you here
well i think that's so that's all for uh
ubc uh
it's all seems very reasonable to me um
so
i mean hopefully you know we'll make
good progress thank you
yeah i think either welcome basically
run summer uh it's really
reasonable for us without stressing too
much of that lines
sounds good thank you
all right still me again and good
morning here's the update for the bbc
um and next slide please
so we did a three revision since 109 and
most trying to uh there's lots of
echoes all right so most trying to
address the
editor notes as we promised since the
last meeting
um there were 24 of them so lots of them
but we're getting pretty good progress
uh only i think four or five laptops
at this moment uh revision08
is actually a submission just couple
days ago so i doubt anybody has time to
review it
um so uh uh in this slide actually
summarize what have changed from
zero seven zero eight and mostly zero
eight um because the summary changes on
zero seven has been set up by email
um that was a kind of a while ago
uh i think uh uh next
next slide please
uh this is kind of quick look at what
happened to your seven as i mentioned
that we have a new one zero eight
and that was zero sum is the first batch
edit nodes so we're trying to resolve
basically the opi assume has to be
perimeters um
a stefan west center i sent out a really
detailed rationale why
we want to do that so i don't want to
just kind of repeat it whatever he said
already um
so if you do kind of forget that email
somehow uh missed it please just go back
to
that email and if you have any comments
we do um
love to hear that uh so since there's a
little comment to received
during the period reactors implement
whatever you were
whatever we have proposed during uh from
the immediate discussion
uh
yep uh yeah right here yeah right here
okay um as i mentioned earlier it was a
little submission so um
please go ahead review them um we did a
more than dozen updates and
i probably don't have enough time to go
through each of them but uh here i'm
just going to kind of bring up some
things that we think is very important
uh but we uh we i will do
uh sent uh the updating from the media
list
um looking for the comments so three
things i want to mess up here so
um so bbc draft is already in the final
publication
uh stage and we pretty much finalized
the baby security information
and in section one i think it's great
progress and we also made the same
decision
uh no to supporting free marking i think
it's also reasonable
and um we actually from last two
meetings we'll be asking
a pin at working group opinions
regarding if we should remove
the slri and rpsi
rtsp feedback mode and no support so
from our
point we don't see the usage of that and
we simply remove that
um the one last thing i want to mention
in this meeting is really um
the reserved arbit in the fragmentation
unit
uh header that's also something we
brought up a couple of minutes back
already um
but we never propose anything so in this
minivac i have a
slide to to discuss the things that we
propose for the rpg
uh we can talk more in next couple
slides
next slide please
next slide yeah right here uh one of the
things we actually removed is one of the
informative notes under the market bit
for the http header the similar content
which
is because we copy paste from hevc and
then
um make a line with bbc but the
co-author just found
the confusion is about it is actually a
bit of the benefit
therefore we decided to remove it to
make this much cleaner
but let us know if you think you have a
different opinions and then we can
discuss that through the main list
we also removed a few
stp parameters inherited from hevc and
things like
maximum video bitrate and picture size
perfect size and etcetera
uh just from our experience and and the
co-author i think there's
less usage of practically no usage at
all from the hevc
so we decide not to support it
again if you have any different opinions
that we do want to hear that
maybe we missed anything so we don't
want to do that
next slide please
next next
here we go so here's the uh reserved rb
that we talked about in the fragment
unit header
um so we brought this up um
uh things zoom 107.
uh so we the proposed text in the
following is
really from our uh production team they
have their usage
um so what is this what we proposed here
is really
we're trying to say use the orbit to
identify the signal if the last are not
the last and not unit in the fragment
unit header
uh when it says when i said it's one the
rbd
simply said is the last non-unit
for the fragment unit header or you
could still
equals to zero which is not the last
line here um
it's it's a similar i would say the
concept wise is similar like
the ambit the market building the rtp
header unit
but we don't see much of usage for
marker
bits for the video site maybe we missed
anything
but that's the current conclusion we had
and we think that's a pretty
good usage for the rpg otherwise just
leave it blank
as we call it reserved again
sorry we don't send this early
do provide your comment in the middle
list and see if you did anything
which is a right usage or not
and last the next
slide
that's going to be the last one so um we
only have four
edit notes left uh down from 24
which is great progress and we only have
one large section which is the sdp
offering answer
sections uh which is uh um
not going to be very difficult things
that we have all the stp congress
already
and we are targeting the rocket glasgow
around
june 2020 first
i think i think probably earlier than
that but i think
um june should be a a good time
and that's all for bbc
yeah i wanted to thank you by the way
for making good progress removing things
that weren't required
uh that's actually uh makes suspect much
more readable now
i think that's the design philosophy we
agree the first meeting to try to
simplify the process so i think we are
doing that
thank you
all right uh should it be offline right
uh yeah all right i just i just had one
comment i mean i'll probably better
erase this on the list but on the r bit
i just um
i'm curious how your use of the art that
interacts with the spatial stimulus
facial scalability
i'm curious how whether that's last bit
of the
whole picture or last bit of us the
spatial layer would last fragments
if we want to if we go back we're going
to go back to one last slide
up
yeah so it's actually for the whole
picture instead of the code of the
picture it's gonna be a whole picture
all right yeah so um all right well we
can just cut that on the list
oh yeah yeah yeah okay appreciate that
okay thank you
any other comments on this search
let's go all right now
the big topic for here we're a little
bit ahead of time so that's good because
i think this will probably
take a fair bit of time
so oops sorry i keep
like i said my my slides tab seems a
little jumpy so i apologize if i'm
suddenly on the wrong
wrong slide so who's presenting first
i start a little bit and they will take
over or okay yeah
sure okay um so
i'd like to present a few slides and up
to
getting to a set of requirements that
with sergio and alex we we gathered and
maybe from there
take take questions so
uh yeah so we'll we'll hold the queue
until the u.n has
finished or u.n and sergio have gone
through these slides
yeah five slides i think also
next slide
so yeah the question why could a
packetizer
why should we try to evolve the current
architecture
um so there are products
like google duo or gtc that are
inserting a transform step between
encoder and backetizer
and they do so for a good reason which
is to
achieve and create encryption and i'm
sure we're
we're all excited about that feature
that said uh they they do that currently
in a very adult way
and um that's true we can say it relies
on a few hacks as presented
as the link is showing and what was
discussed in ietf 109. so
we think it would be good to uh
rationalize what is being done
by these products make sure it stays
as consistent as possible with the rtp
ecosystem
and at the end of the provide either
technical solutions
or guidelines
[Music]
so with sergio analex we
we looked at that and uh we we thought
that
um the current architecture like the rtp
media pipeline we we can probably
adapt it to allow these products to do
what they want to do without too much
changes
and that's why it's relying on this idea
of a
codec agnostic packetizer and
the proposal we are trying to explain
now
um so at last avt core meeting and
also on tuesdays spring meetings there
were a lot of questions
uh on this speculizer and how it would
deal with
avc or redundancy mechanisms so we have
slides
that are explaining that
and i will present some of them now next
slide
so first how is it working with
like the simplest example h264 or vp8
so we have a typical start with
you take a row frame you encode it
and then the encoder is producing two
things
first it's producing the content itself
the frame
the encoded frame and it's also
generating
metadata then in a browser like
chrome there will be a transform which
is
implemented in javascript where the
encoded frame
and the metadata will be exposed and the
transform
using javascript will typically encrypt
the frame
with a current api design the metadata
is read-only so you cannot change it and
that's
that makes sense so after the transform
uh now we have some transform data so in
in the
slide it's in red and we keep the same
metadata
and the transform data there is no
longer
uh valid https for valid vp8 content
but the metadata is still applicable to
what was the underlying content so
the idea for the packetizer there would
be
to use metadata to
generate precisely vrtp headers via
extensions and so on
and for the payload to split the
transform data
using a heuristic and the current
heuristic is
to use vmtu to produce
as little as possible a number of
packets
so i just want to point out also
that uh the metadata it can be also
audio
so for instance uh the voice flag that
you can
find in some rtp head extensions is
typically
produced by by the encoder and you you
cannot
use the transform data to try to
generate ltp it extensions like the
voice flag or what or any kind of
ltp head extensions because it's
encrypted basically
and that mirrors well what any
um proxy
will we will also have to
to deal with meaning a payload that is
encrypted and just use vrt header data
to do its processing
next slide which might be
a bit more interesting is
what about vp9 hvc so there it's very
very
very similar um we have a row frame
and the encoder will produce uh like in
this example
three subframes so probably a base frame
and then two dependency frames and each
subframe
is uh related to some metadata so you
have sub frame one separate to do so
frame three and each one has
meta data and then there will be a
transform
and again the transform will be applied
separately to
each subframe and so you will have
transform one transform two
transform three and and so on
um after the transform the packetizer
will first deal with transform one plus
metadata one
and it will produce a first set of
packets uh
again it's the same strategy payload is
done you like you you practice with mtu
and you only rely on metadata one
uh to generate headers and you
first transmit uh the base layer
related packets then the dependency
transform two
then transform three and in
in a typical case they will all share
the same timestamp
um like in a
single stream single transport case
so in the drive we do not have any
notion of subframe
we just call them all and coded frame
and it's really the role of the encoder
to output individual
independent frames that can be
transformed individually
next slide um
second i asked i put my hand up to ask a
question about two slides ago
is it all right to ask a question uh
i would prefer to to go to the
requirements so that there's only two
slides
and then we can take you if that's okay
okay
thanks um so getting back to
the point of uh colon in uh last meeting
in tuesday at frame meeting where
um we we do not remove
any like there are two places
two different processing there's a codex
specific processing which happens
before the transform and a codec
agnostic processing that happens
after the transform the transform itself
can be codec specific
or in the case of s-prime we hope it
will it will stay
categoristic because that's simpler but
clearly
uh the the rtp media pipeline is codec
specific
and uh the code specific processing
can even be application specific in the
sense that
um there we are saying vp9 will
produce three different uh subframes you
could say
an application will tell its https one
encoder to produce
two subframes as well in whatever
heuristic they want and then the
proceeding pipeline should be
roughly the same um
and last slide before taking questions
um
so we with sergio and alex we gathered
some requirements
um and we listed them and
we hope the current proposal and the
current
small changes in the architecture are
actually
fulfilling these requirements uh the
first thing
is that we do not want to disrupt
existing mechanisms like the mapping to
have tp streams
uh redundancy mechanisms or existing
feedback mechanisms as well all of that
should
work well and maybe they could be
optimized later on but that's fine they
could they should
still be uh usable out of box
and in terms of applicability we
really want it to be able to apply it to
simulcast
to support single attribute string on a
single media transport
for svc we also think
we we need to do negotiation there to
negotiate that uh
that payload format and we also think
that
to succeed
this payload format should be
complemented with
whatever side channel information like
rtb head extension
that will allow the sfu to perform layer
selection and packet forwarding
precisely on the rtp extensions and not
on the payload um
so killen since you're in the queue
sorry just took hitting unmute a couple
times to get it to work
um okay so let can you go back a couple
slides
anyway
let me forward one slide this one might
be easier
um so my so
first of all the describing the
packetizer as being after
isn't isn't really accurate this is sort
of wrong i mean
the the encoder the what came out of the
encoder had to be packetized
before it was at some level of
packetization
before it got passed into the transform
okay there may be further packetization
later of a different type but it was
packetized up there
and my concern is around having
in two places to put information so like
the whole idea of some sort of generic
type i
you know i in for information content
for for a generic for codex like i
at some level i don't think we'll ever
achieve it there will always be things
that come up
new like when we move to holographic
content when we move
to um even even the 360 degree stuff
probably would need some metadata that
isn't covered by the current draft so
there always will be extensions to it
but i i do like the idea of like
particularly for you know flat 2d codecs
we should be at the point of getting
pretty good at this so like i support
the general idea
but the question is about does it go in
the payload section or the header
section
and you know the rtp architecture we've
really gone down that this goes
is a header is the header is where we um
put this information
and i don't see that as being very
incompatible with this information
i just think that here basically you've
already packetized at the encoding at
least partially privatized
you're passing into a transform and as
long as the transform can modify
the header that's going to end up in the
rtp as well as the data that's going to
end up in the
thing that's just like an implementation
detail of your specific implementation
it's not like something we should drive
the whole standard by
um and you should just do that and then
the transformation you know then we can
have this metadata
sitting in the header data where we
already have like you know
a whole bunch of stuff to do it and the
reason i like that better is i'm really
worried about the case of having
the data two places and not matching and
that will inevitably happen and i think
that that's
you know this is just trying to flip the
architecture of rtp of where we put this
information to be
completely wrong um and you don't need
that for any reason you can just put it
in the right place and have the same
information you have right now
um and and that that's that that's no
big deal so could i mean could you talk
a little bit about
where i'm going wrong on that whole sort
of set of assumptions
um so so first thing you're saying
there's a
first step of packetization um
so a packetizer is generating an rtp
packet
and that's the difference you know
advertising seriously
a stream of data out of a codec into a
such set of chunks of data yeah so
but i agree uh it's it's chunking the
data and the encoder
either the encoder of the application is
doing that
and what what we're seeing is that the
chunking
is really application specific right and
uh as part of the challenging
application specific or kodak specific
that's a big difference there those are
two very different things
um so
to me in our use cases it's codec
specific but
i don't see why some applications will
not be able to specify
like yeah i want to use h264 in a
specific way so that this style there
it's its own subframe and i will output
it separately
but that's fine as well um i don't want
to preclude it i don't want to define it
yeah right um
so about the data
being somehow redundant
if you look at frame marking information
like
uh or dependency descriptor
you will have it like easy to reframe or
not it can be articulated
it's also in the payload at some point
uh and so there's always redundant data
there
and that's fine one of these redundant
data is for the sfu
and the other one is for vm recipient
and we need to extract some of the
information from the user the encoder to
the sfu
and this extraction
should be carefully studied because it
has privacy implications
and i would like us to provide
guidelines there so that we say
okay this particular information
is not privacy sensitive it's useful for
the sfu
so yeah let's allow it or let's say that
yeah you you can use it it's safe and
this information uh maybe not
you know like audio level maybe maybe
not things like that you know
look i agree with you that i'm i think
that my question is about
why that data needs to somehow now
though the rtp architecture is to stick
that in the header why it now needs to
be somehow stuck in the payload that's
that's my question
like why don't you do the same thing but
stick it in the header no but
we are we are putting it in the head
yeah
and uh if you look at uh
the vp9 packetization somehow you you
you have the information in the payload
but it's uh that
it's a keyframe and it's also in vrt
header
and what we're saying is that since the
payload now is encrypted
we don't care whether it's there or not
we will not
use the payload information and we
really need to put this information that
is really crucial in the headers
so i'm not sure i'm clear but i think we
agree
um
okay well there's a bunch of people
lying behind me let me go here
bernad you want to say something so yeah
i would like to follow up
uh on what cullen just asked
and uh here's here's my framework for
asking these questions
they're actually i think your
architecture maybe is a little bit too
tied
to the insertable streams architecture
but even within if we're just talking
about the chromium codebase right
there's more than one architecture
because you can also do this with web
codecs where you actually get access to
each of the uh encoded chunks you can
call them encoded frames
and you have the ability to build your
own uh rtp
header as well as getting access you
know potentially to the payload
so um and the reason i'm asking this
is that and following up on codex
question uh
colin's question about application
versus codec specific
is we've just heard for example that
some of the codex
will not use frame marking and
the the issue i think that comes up when
we discuss this is the metadata
isn't necessarily going to be encoded in
the rtp header the same way for every
codec
for example for something like h264
avc with temporal scalability you might
find frame marking is fine
right but what we're saying here is the
i think there's an issue if you're
saying that every codec
will have its metadata encoded the same
way
in uh the rtp header
um you're going to get you're going to
get into issues there
whereas in the web codec kind of a
framework right you get this
you can get the metadata the metadata
actually comes as part of the
encoded frame but then you can do with
it whatever you want you could decide
i'm going to take this metadata and
output frameworking
or i'm going to i'm gonna i want to put
uh instead
dependency descriptor in the header or
anything else that the itf or anyone
anyone else might come up with
so that that yields a different
conception here
so i would just ask you to to try to be
clear about what
codec agnostic means exactly
um does it really mean that everything
is the same for every codec i think that
that
that kind of uh is a promise that might
be difficult to fulfill over
over time or does it mean that just the
generic
process is somehow the same for every
code but
codex might handle it differently i just
i just think
not asking for an answer right now but
just to think this through
can i can i can provide a temporary
answer
um and that's maybe something we are
discussing with sergio and
we do not align precisely but i i think
i think it's a very good question
um my understanding is that
the general uh processing like the
processing that we're seeing there
could be applied to any any codec the
packetizer itself
like the construction of the payload
using ntu
can be uh codec specific now the fact
that you use one ltp extension
for one codec and another rtp header
extension
to pro to transmit the media data for
another codec
um i i'm i'm thinking that currently
we we should not close the door to
anything
it would be ideal if we could just have
the one rtp extension that would fulfill
all cortex
my understanding is that it's very
difficult
and and that's fine and i'm not sure
that existing implementations uh
currently needed for instance
implementations using h.264
or vp8 might stick with a frame marking
and as vp9 or av1 they will use the
dependency descriptor
if we have a good proof in the future
that the dependency descriptor is a good
fit as well for h264 p9
then it's even better um i don't think
that decision
impacts how we uh define the packetizer
and the
payload format because we have an
extension point
which is rtp head extensions and we can
combine
the payload format with various rtp head
extensions
and basically it's the application
designer but we'll do that at the end of
the day
jonathan all right i'm next in the queue
as an individual
so um i feel like
um you are making life too easy for
yourself by showing the encoder half of
this picture
um i feel like if you showed the decoder
half
then a lot more of the complexities
would be apparent
in particular because basically the the
decoder process which is to say
the depacketizer i mean the d transport
hopefully is obvious but the
you know the reassembly in particular
and then
um before the decoder proper is where a
lot of the complexity
arises which you need to worry about um
so
uh in particular the thing that you you
need to be able to do
is to be able to tell as a you know
receiving pipeline
do i have all the you know have i
received
you know have the packets i've received
the packets i've received contain
enough information for me to
successfully decode a video frame
or do i need to knock something and wait
for it to come in before i actually feed
things to my
uh codec um and
so you know in the process of arbitrary
packet loss and packet reordering and
so on and so forth and so that's where i
think a lot of the trickiness is going
to arise now if you say
you always have something like av1
decoder description that's probably
sufficient
if you don't then i think you need to
figure out how that works
and that's where a lot of you know
especially in the start guide
yeah um so that's true and i thought
about adding slides for the decoder but
i was maybe too lazy
and it's true that the encoder is a good
example so that we can
uh start uh precising all these issues
so um yeah i can go ahead with uh
providing information for the decoder
uh you're right about um the packet
reassembly
um so in the vp9 avc case maybe sergio
can correct me if i'm wrong
but you will set the mark a bit uh
that will tell you okay you got
transform one
uh you should not expect to receive
transform two and
and then and then you're good and yeah
that's how you would do things
yeah that part is relatively go ahead
yeah that that first is
that the current graph at least we plan
to use the ab1 dependency descriptor
that provides us information
but anyway um
i think that it makes
is probably just well we are using
ab1 independence industry that should be
able to cover that
right yeah so i mean i think you know
reassembly within a frame is relatively
easy it's across frames as you know
you've had a
burst loss you don't know what would
know what you
don't know whether those packets you
lost
uh contain um contain a reference frame
or not
well
yeah because that's exactly what the
dependency the research tried to
try to provide is to know sally if you
have received a frame it
that frame or sub framing and special
yeah
and this calibrity codec is decodable or
not without having to
check any further data right so yeah if
you assume you always have dd then
but hold on one minute john right you
may have the dd info
at the in on the on the sending side
here right
because you could decide to encode that
metadata with dg
and send it but you might not right if
you if you're doing frame marking
instead and on the sender you got the dd
info but decided
not to use it all and just do frame
marking then you might not have it on
the decoder side so i think your
question is
valid still yeah i think so so we need
to figure out if there needs to be
at least some minimal information at the
um in the
in this itself and then relatedly as you
mentioned
if you're you know your question of
whether how things are
chunked into the stream are you know
you seem to be saying well you know the
question of whether it's codec
specific or application specific if if
it's an encoder choice how
the raw media stream is trunked
into the pre-transformed frames then
you need to figure out how much of that
decision does the
um the the reassembly product line
need to know can it just you know does
it need to be prepared for any chunking
decision whatsoever that the encoder
might have felt like doing
or do we need constraints in the spec of
what the
what encoders are allowed to do
yep uh all right so yeah i think those
are the
big things and i think
hi yeah um so
i am a little concerned that for
something which is supposed to be codec
agnostic
uh all the discussion we are hearing is
of a very
small number of currently popular codecs
for interactive video applications
and rtp is used for a lot more
applications and in a lot more different
scenarios and with a lot more different
types of codec
than we are just currently hearing about
and um we hope it will continue to be
used
in a bunch more scenarios in the future
and i think i'm not seeing something
which is really code kegnostic
i'm seeing something which might work
for a small subset of current video
codecs
um yes so if you take the previous slide
and replace h64 vp8 by
uh opus it's working fine
and for instance audio is less of an
issue there
just less of metadata to provide to to
make it work to make
and to an encryption work and uh
we we want to have it in scope so
we definitely want to have audio and
video um
as of over kind of metadata
uh maybe maybe you we could think of
subtitles time text for instance
um so currently my understanding is that
it's more sent as part of a data channel
in webrtc
environments we could definitely see it
being used there in the same manner but
not every application that uses rtp
uses webrtc
yeah but anyway that but i mean this is
not meant to be a replacement for rtp
a packet is it i think that in fact if
you
if we talk about in later in the in the
spec we are only
going to we are going to
to make the the the the negotiation of
the
canonistic packetizer the to
to be done within or together with the
with the normal packetization so
it is this is not precluding or
preventing
to to use any other
any other codec or packetizing
packetization that it is already
available or featurely implemented but
it is only be
meant to be used when you are
using this frame or other transformation
that may include the
the content so that you cannot use the
the standard rtp packetization
but in fact i would also say frame like
frame marking either rtp head extension
that you
may want to use or you may not want to
use in your application
frame marking does not make any sense uh
outside of a given scope and the payload
these packetizers there would make sense
for some applications
and for some of the applications it's
not really applicable and that's fine
but
it no i don't think it is fine because
if you're trying to define a pillow
diagnostic
your codec agnostic format it has to be
codec agnostic and it has to work for
for all codecs um because rtp is a
generic framework
um some given definitions of
encoders and decoders yes yeah but just
no longer codec agnostic it works for a
particular subset of codex
uh yeah for example thinking of
of real-time texts and since other stuff
that it is not audi audio
um i'm not even convinced it works for
all audio and video codecs
we're hoping to have it work for audio
and video codecs
at least the ones that are in use
will be yeah i think that i think that
this should be
i mean i would like to to the idea is to
be able to to work with all the audio
and video codecs
not real-time tests for example uh so
that's uh a reduction in the scope of of
this has not been only for the video but
i would like to know if
do you have any concrete example in mind
that we will have to
check just just one question from from
the chair
i think we've had at least three
questions about the meaning of the term
codec agnostic
uh and i think i would suggest that that
needs to be
clarified in the draft because for
something that
just the meaning of that term i think
colin had that question we've had at
least three questions about that so
um especially when you start talking
about differences between codec
and and use the term codec agnostic it's
a bit confusing
thank you yeah i mean it also seems that
um in order to decode this
and in order to packetize the media
sensibly you need to know
what the what is the underlying codec
and you need to know um how um
you know whatever the equivalent of a
null unit in in this particular codec or
a frame or
a an independently decodable
piece of the codec output is and all
this is
is payload format specific it's all
codec specific
um and so unless you're just arbitrarily
chopping
uh according to the mtu which is a of
course a very bad idea for performance
you need to know the underlying payload
type
and the signaling for rtp is also based
uh
fundamentally on the idea of knowing the
payload type
now i think the idea of it of enter and
encryption of the
payload is a perfectly reasonable one
and
we've seen a number of examples of um
different applications
and different uh organizations defining
ways of doing that
um but this seems like something which
can be done within the existing
rtp model of payload formats which
identify
a codec by defining a
a common way of encrypting the output of
particular codecs
and it would seem that that can be made
to work with these middle boxes
and these selective forwarding units in
a way which is compatible with the
architecture
um so i i think before throwing out the
entirety of the way rtp has defined
media handling and the entirety of the
way rtp
and the associated signaling specifies
codex
it will be useful to see if we can make
this work within the existing
architecture
and i see no reason why we can't do that
um
so i think rather than just diving
straight into throwing away the the
entirety of the last 25 years of work
here
uh in in defining payload formats we
should think about
what are the actual requirements and is
there a solution which is compatible
with the existing architecture
so from what i understand uh what you're
asking for
is saying so you propose something
is it efficient and can we compare
it with uh another way of doing things
that would be code specific
let's compare it apples to apples and
then
if there are some advantages on one side
yeah let's look for it and if there are
advantages
on the other side yeah why not also
specify
it is that correct uh i
i'm saying that that the rtp
architecture
fundamentally relies on knowing the
codec and fund
fundamentally relies on things being
codec specific
and i think you can achieve your goals
uh
in a way which is generic and works with
the middle boxes
and it allows you to do the same sorts
of transformations whilst doing it in a
way which fits with the architecture
if if you try to design the system that
way
rather than making the assumption that
you throw away the existing architecture
yeah i think as colin just said right
something like srtp
would be considered codec agnostic but
that doesn't mean everything in the srtb
architecture throws away the knowledge
of codex
right i think it would also be possible
to define a a
a common way of transforming a payload
and sigma
and signaling that um such a transform
has been done and using a different
payload type to indicate that and that
would also
let you know let the decoder know how to
decode it
um
so to be clear that's what you just said
colin that's the thing that is codec
agnostic
the rest of it is and that's somehow
yeah one option that it is quite in the
draft
no but but i think that what colleen is
saying is something different i mean
what i think that is what he's asking is
to is for his friend to not work on a
framed level but work on a per packet
level
so i think that it is reasonable but um
i think that this frame must change to
the order
be able to be able to implement this
and that that's why i was asking about
efficiency because
we we can we can do this approach where
it's per packet
uh as fermentation or perfect
fertilization and
we will see there will be differences in
terms of efficiency as well
and that's something that people might
i'm not i'm not sure that's necessarily
true
i think it would that would be an
implementation you know that depend how
you implemented it
i think here that the question is is
going back to the fundamental issue is
if we do a frame encoding a
sorry upper frame encryption we need to
have something that it is
agnostic because the packetizer is going
to be handling
uh encrypting the data encrypted the
media data
i don't agree that that is true
i think you can split thing you know i i
think this can be done
in an agnostic you know i think you can
you can encrypt a frame at a time and
split the resulting uh encrypted frame
up in a way which is consistent with the
rtp architecture and signal it in a way
that's consistent with the rtp
architecture but for example would you
be willing to help
in defining that no no but
i mean we have i i have studied that and
it is
difficult to do it i mean for example in
a 264 you have to increase each of the
null independently
in bp8 you will have to
leave the first bytes of the
of the payloading so it is a very huge
effort i mean if we want to go there it
was
also the first slide and when we
explained
why the current packetization does not
work with the
with the current codex and also i don't
think it is a good thing that
you are saying that you are going um
that you are sending normal for example
excuses for
and data when you are just sending
encrypted data
because nobody suggested that what what
i am suggesting is
is that you send a payload format you
know a payload type that indicates that
this is an
encrypted h.264 data rather than a
payload
type that indicates that this exact you
know a generic
encrypted data and that way
that's what we are that's that's what we
are doing
yep but we are not defined we have not
yet
been able to present that but we are
doing that we are saying that we are
saying
estrus is for encrypted data it's in the
draft
yeah but then it can't be coded agnostic
that that's what i think there's some
bits that are
if this is codec specific then it is a
payload format and it's defined in the
usual way
and if it's codec agnostic then it's
throwing out all that architecture
so what we're saying is that we we do
not plan to have like
to define an h.264 encrypted payload
format
but we definitely want the
uh stream to acknowledge two things
first it's encrypted using a frame
second
it's h64
i i i am really struggling to see how
this works with the signaling and
with the architecture if we can get to
drain and then let sergio go on with the
presentation
yeah sounds good
stefan
no i cannot hear you
can you hear me now yes
i cannot hear you again
the danger of implementation driven
standards work really
as as nice as this may be normally here
there's just too many oversights so on
on the terminology front i think we have
something like a semi-codec agnostic
it's agnostic for certain codex but
agnostic to certain codecs but not to
other codex
so the the applicability here of this
technology is limited
to a number of codecs and what they want
to do
is to
[Music]
to create a mechanism that would work
with all the codex they had in mind when
they were
doing this thing but hopefully without
assuming or without hoping against hope
in my opinion
that it will apply to all future codex
and we have already had an example so
the the example here
why it wouldn't work with future codex
is
for everyone i just heard from the from
the thing that jonathan pointed out
that you need the dd um in order to make
sense
of this type of stuff in the decoder
when you have scalability
there are tons of tons of um
[Music]
uh video codecs which do not necessarily
have
the same uh the same concept
for temporal scalability at least
as the dd right shvc doesn't have a dd
the video parameter set doesn't express
everything the dd expresses
the vbc doesn't do that evc doesn't do
that
so don't tell me that your generic
architecture would work with these
codecs when
when during a brainstorming session
for of of a few minutes it came already
out that it would not do it no but but i
also understand that you will want to
express that
and that a middle box that's
making use of this can cope with a
limited set
of codecs and not only with h.264 or
h.265 and
or or vp8 and bp9 and you also want to
express
and you also don't want to replicate the
same thing in in multiple
documents specific to say h.264 and h265
so okay um the way to do this would be
don't call it generic
call it um or make an applicability
statement this
this specification is intended to and
believed to work
with the following codex and then comes
a list
and uh in the title tone it down a
little bit
and then go for it that's how i would
approach this generic versus non-generic
problem thank you i have one other
comment
and that is
the let's not forget
that the vast majority of bits that are
going over rtp in this world today
are not webrtc bits and
i know webrtc is the itf technology and
blah blah blah but
but let's not forget that the vast
majority
of of uh
interactive video today is not using
webrtc
and i would not want to uh
um use this uh
type of drafts as an i would not like to
see others to use this type of drafts
as a pusher for uh for itf technology
uh for no other merits as being a push
thank you um so
i agree with you that um
[Music]
it will be very difficult to come up
with
uh sfus that could be implemented in a
fully codec
agnostic way and uh we're not trying to
solve that
what we are trying to do is to
migrate the information that might be
codec specific
from the payload to the rtp head
extensions
and um you you you took the example
that uh the dd descriptor will be good
for ev1
and we think so we are not saying that
the dd will be good for all codecs
it's then up to the application to use
what we're proposing and select the
right rtp head extension
that will cover uh the cases
and hopefully
the header extensions that we that we
are planning to use will be
supporting enough codecs uh enough video
codecs enough audio codecs
that there will not be a huge
replication effort but certainly it will
evolve
so i will also agree that we should
remove the name agnostic
it's definitely
a term that is not specific enough
also i would be interested in knowing um
the specific details about
a bbc and and how this codec does not
work with the dependence and distributor
i mean
because i i think it's interesting so if
you can provide
in the list how the independence
industry
wi-fi may fail to do to include the data
from
from bbc it will be right
it should it should not
be particularly hard to come up with
examples why the technology is currently
specified would not work
could you provide that please i will i
will try
uh i'll try um i'm
so that said uh
you know you can't i think if you are
going in the direction of
of of trying to create
um of trying to
resurrect your dream of creating
something generic at least to the known
codex as of this day
then i will try to do some work there
but don't expect me to specifically
argue with you about whether this is
true or that
is true um if it is if this were
uh if you are if you were continuing to
exist that this
is an agnostic thing then it's your
burden of proof to show that it is
agnostic
and not by my burden of proof that it is
not agnostic you you see my point
yeah so i'm helping on best effort basis
but not
uh on a you know on an obligation basis
thank you
justin
yeah so i i think it should be fairly
clear that the compactization is it's
possible to
to be you know generic you know the the
packetization is strongly
straightforward
uh you know in terms of basically how it
breaks up packets to fit within
mtu and like i think it can be argued
fairly easily that like
you know things that produce you know
essentially datagrams
can be you know generically packetized
the you know the only other sort of
requirement that's been placed here is
that there can be some way of splitting
the metadata in the the payload
and assuming that can be done for a
given codec format
then the actual payload can then be
packetized using this generic packetizer
so the question that then remains is can
the metadata be described in a generic
way
and i think that's what a lot of people
are sort of latching onto here
like can this packation be generic or
not because like
it definitely is a complicated problem
as to whether or not
the metadata for all codecs can be
described in like a generic way
like i i think that's a totally
reasonable thing that people can
can differ on the thing is though i
don't think that that is really
fundamental
to the this document here it's like if
you have a generic format for metadata
then it makes the sfu's life easier
because it has a single way to look at
what's coming in
and they can then act on that
accordingly but even without
a generic metadata that you know codex
could still
you know sfps could still sort of work
in the way they do today
without end-to-end encryption where
they're forced to look at these pieces
individually
on a codex specific uh you know in a
kind of specific way
to determine what their behavior should
be and there
uh you know even if we you know still
had things that did not fit the generic
uh packages or generics or metadata you
know sfus could continue to do that
so what i would want to do is just sort
of say okay
take that off the table yesterday can
still be useful you know even if it
doesn't have a completely generic
metadata
because it still allows like the
transmission of the end encryption
formats
uh and the separation of metadata and
payload which is the main things that
is required to actually work
yeah i completely agree with you also
just one thing that the metadata the
metadata that it is needed
is only the one that the svu is
requiring for work i mean we are not
trying to provide all the metadata in
the world
to inaccurately work only the ones
only that the specific data that is
required
for the svu to work
exactly yeah now whether that can be
fully generic is still an open question
uh but i think that we have a good set
that seems to work for
well you know critics that are known
today and even if there are ones that
kind of go beyond that tomorrow
uh you know like i said it's not really
a critical issue sfus can deal with this
custom metadata
uh the only in critical piece is that
you have things that produce packets
and then those packets have their you
know uh metadata and actual payload
separated
and i think that you know all the codecs
that we're talking about can do that
can i just respond to that very quickly
call them please go ahead and respond to
that and then i'll go back to that so
i'm not sure i agree with justin's
statement that we can build a generic
format
i think at the minimum you need to know
where the um the independently decodable
units
uh you know the null units or whatever
it is for that codec um
start and finish so you can packetize it
in a way that you don't split these
units across packets
and that's that makes it specific
you need to identify the codec so you so
you know how to decode it
how to decode it and as justin said you
need to
to separate out the headers and the
metadata information from the payload
uh and from the encrypted content and
this is fundamentally what rtp payload
formats do
and this is the fundamental point of the
the payload format concept is just even
if all you're specifying is how you
split this thing up into
into pieces how you label them and how
you separate out
the the contents from the the headers
that's what a payload format does it
doesn't have to be more complicated than
that
so i think what you're just describing
an rtp payload format
uh and i think rather than fight against
that architecture
you know just accept that what you are
describing fits within the architecture
and work with the architecture rather
than trying to throw it away
can i just respond to that giggling
yep i mean i i think that
you mean those things that you sort of
mentioned of yes we do need to
identify the individual units uh
but really every um you know every
payload format is doing this
uh and it does seem kind of strange that
you know every time we have a new format
we have to go define really the exact
same transforms
uh you know for that particular format
when
like if we got a structured sort of
input from the encoder that sort of said
here are the frames and independently to
credible units
uh then like you could have a fairly
generic way of describing that on the
wire
and i think that's really all that's
trying to be done here
uh that you know if you have this you
know meta information that describes
like what it is you're trying to
packetize
you could then have a single
packetization format to basically fit
this into rtv packets and you know empty
use
uh accordingly and then you know
separate out the
uh you know the meta information so that
that stuff is not
encrypted you know for for the sfu
that's really all it is and i don't
really feel
we're throwing away rtp here we're just
basically saying
here's the same thing we're doing every
single time with a new payload format
and trying to come up with one way we
don't have to redo this
uh all over again for every single
encrypted
slash format tuple
so so define a stand a common way of
doing that that fits with the existing
set of payload type names
and the existing mechanisms for signal
signaling
i mean well that's what we have here uh
you know first of all
justin let me break this i don't think
that is what you have here at all here
so let me let me try and give some very
pragmatic
suggestions to get to what you're saying
um and i i think this this gets the
heart of my comments
one i think that we mean very different
thing than packetizer
i think that what most people here mean
by pack and this is just terminology
what's important is we line up what we
mean okay
but taking the stream of bits out of the
encoder and figuring out the logical
places to break them based
on things you'd want to lose so breaking
the mcnally units or whatever the moral
equivalent of that is in your codec
is something that's happening on the top
half of the slide that's currently
displayed it's happened before the
transform
okay and that is what most people think
of packetization
i understand there is also a point where
we take things that were larger than the
mtu and split them to be smaller than
the mtu
i understand that's how you're using the
word privatization but i i think that
i think we should i think we should get
a different word for that second
transform
where we slice them smaller um because i
think that's causing some of the
confusion
in in the discussion and then look no
one
like the i like we all sort of have like
as far as
so one thing's about packetization and
then i'm going to talk about metadata
for a second and then esprit
so packetization i think with some
confusing terminology which is
really not helping the conversation here
in a huge way then
because packetization is inherently
codec specific there's no way for
packetization to not be codec specific
right in the way i define packetization
obviously splitting up things on his new
size is by definite guaranteed to be
codec
agnostic right totally agree right so
that's part of the
terminology confusion then we have the
metadata
so look like audio levels is already a
great example of
four audio types a fairly generic works
with
you know most things i can imagine of
type audio media
way of sending that up to the sfu that's
great i mean i don't think anyone would
like let's do some of those for video as
well whichever ones make sense
we don't have to claim that they work
for every video type ever
we could say like look here are some
ones we believe these ones work for the
list
you know here's a hammer up here's a
definition of some metadata
and we believe it works for at least
these
common webrtc video codecs and we
suspect it'll probably work for some 2d
video codecs in the future
uh you know and video codex could figure
it out we don't have to
to pretend that it will work for all
video codecs that haven't been defined
yet or not
we don't have to pretend that future
video codecs might not
need additional metadata for the sfu for
some reason right
and we get what we want here on the
metadata
and then the third thing is with s frame
um i think that part of what's causing
confusion here
is in is we're sort of overreaching on a
generic transform here well i think
that what i see we need to do here is be
able to indicate
um in the sdp in some sort of
negotiation way or whatever
you know that like look this this
vp9 was was s was s frame encoded
um and let's just step back a little bit
to think about like
what would be the way if that's all we
wanted to indicate um
and we wanted to be able to do that for
a bunch of the major
video and audio codecs how we would do
that in the sdp
the indicated s frame now i think
the other thing here is you know
is the unit of encryption
span multiple rtp packets or do we do it
per rtp packet okay sort of the frame
versus the
the the the other issue and i keep
hearing the efficiency issue here
but for the the the where the overhead's
high
um is actually the audio packets because
they're small right
and actually it makes no difference it's
exactly the same whether you do it per
because it's small because the audio
packets are always smaller than an mtu
um it makes there is no efficiency
difference between doing it for every
rtp packet and for every frame
for the video packets i mean when you're
talking about
i mean we're talking about adding one
extra iv vector or something maybe i
mean it's a very small amount of bytes
that we're adding as
overhead and i maybe you gave me the
estimate the other day when
we'd add one or two percent bandwidth if
we
encrypt for the large video packets if
if we did it per rtp versus uh per frame
i think we should really seriously
reconsider that
decision and think about if it would
make more sense to just have
the s frame applied on per rtp packet
versus per frame
and but to collins point regardless of
how we come across
on that decision i think that we can
easily find a solution that continues to
work
um so you know and part of the reason i
like about that is it makes the losses
of the packets
more um decoupled from each other
uh so that it makes some of the
recoveries and other things easier to
deal with but
you know anyway there's pros and cons to
that but the saving one or two percent
bandwidth on large video flows is just
totally irrelevant like
i see no no gain in that whatsoever so
let me
let me just let you respond to that sort
of stuff the authors respond to that try
and clarify things but that's how i'd
like to think about
how we could really make good progress
moving forward on this
yeah okay uh i mean i i think that was
i i agree with a lot of what was just
said uh
you sort of just jump ahead to that i
mean i i think that
we should agree on what is meant by
packetization
um i i the authors and and i've been
using the term of basically taking
something that's already been
broken up into you know now use with
equipment and then how do you put that
in the wire and i think most of us agree
that you know once you have now used
putting that in the wire it's fairly
straightforward
uh i like i like colin's representation
of like the audio levels as the same
type of thing we're trying to create
here for video
i think that's a really good analogy and
i i think that you know it's something
that is
worthwhile to pursue um as a relates to
you know the the actual sort of
encryption and the overheads
uh i i would you know still disagree
that one to two percent you know savings
is uh
you know worthless uh you know there are
people who work on transforms for codex
and spend like you know big parts of
their careers to save one to two percent
but i agree it's not the driving factor
you know here it's an additional bonus
uh and i i think that the chief benefit
of processing things as frames rather
than
as rtp packets is largely just the
logical separation
that if you can split it across multiple
frames like you're not forced
to you could break everything into
slices
so you have better independent
recoverability but if you want to send
it as an entire
large iframe then you can amortize this
encryption overhead
and i think that's an entirely nice
because then it separates the encrypting
the
video frame versus encrypting the
packets
as two different things because they're
in two different layers
which is an actual correct description
of the situation
anyway you know i think we talked about
that
yeah i think that it's complicated yeah
anyway i think i'd like to move on to
see the rest of the prisons in agreement
here so i'm gonna
move on uh but i think there's something
we can work from here
okay so uh as jonathan said we'll let uh
sergio and yuan finish their
presentation
so here do you want to take over from
from now
yep let's go quickly in the rest of the
presentation
so a couple of next slides i think
two or three more
okay that's a slide
okay so this is what we were speaking
about
my packet decision we are where no well
one before that
so uh the idea is that the
what we will get from foreign for the
transform is uh
is a blob it's a binary blob that we
don't have
as it is we are talking about this frame
it is going to be encrypted so we don't
know what are the boundaries of
any underlying codec uh obus or null
units or whatever
so what the packet decision is going to
do is to split this uh
this this blob
these bytes of the of the frame
into several rtp packets and as we don't
have any boundary
that we have to preserve because if you
lose one
um you need all the packets in order to
be able to decrypt the
the the original frame
and the with the packet decision will
just split them into several
rtp packets just ensure that they don't
exceed the mtu
and the last one will be set
the market bid will be set according to
us the same as it is specified in
rfcc3551
and in case of the video codec is
supporting a special scalability
in each of the spatial frames
the whatever the call is in in in the in
the specific codec
because there are different names for
each vp9
maybe one and things like that it will
be sent with um
in order this the special layer will be
answered in order
and the last one with the same rtp
timestamp and the last one in the
rtp packet and we'll have the market bit
set to one
yeah next please
so the idea is to then that
as as schoolnet was
as colleen was was saying that we are
not
going to to to just negotiate in
this in this new packet decision format
on its own it will be always relying on
the
on the new session on the standard one
and in order to
try to reduce the amount of payload
types that we are having the sdp because
we have
already in webrtc at least
we are already using the payload types
for in the 35 frames and things like
that
so we are going to use a single um a
single payload type for this generic
packet decision format and then it will
be needed to
um to multiplex the codex
inside this this pilot type
and also this we are doing that by
sending the
original or the associated pilot type
that will cause a minor network overhead
and also it requires to negotiate
different and
the generic value types for audio is one
for a different
a clock rate effort
so next slide please
before we go on to the next slide i i'm
a little
confused here because the payload type
is the way
uh rtp identifies these things so why
introduce another level of multiplexing
when we've already got an identifier
here
because it's not we will have to
duplicate or replicate the number of
pallet types and i think the webrtc
where
we may exceed the maximum limit i mean
it's just if i have to say i have i
think in webrtc we have
20 or 30 already period types
so going to 60 is is a no-go
because at some moment in time we will
reach the
the the point that we cannot we don't
have any free
pilot type to use so that's what we have
decided to use
a single one and just um
have to include the original uh
pilot type within it just to mention
that the draft is exposing various ways
of doing the same thing uh some of which
would require more parallel time being
consumed some of which
would require less and
we are certainly interested in getting
feedback there
in what would be best appropriate so
representing this approach which we
think
is fine we know it has some drawbacks
but we think it's
it's fine as well and uh we welcome uh
reviews of the current draft for
the other uh alternatives
i mean i think a lot of the problem here
is that the payload
types in rtp are defined to be media
types and i'm not sure that
you know i mean essentially you're
signaling applications flash architect
stream and then multiplexing everything
inside it
and yeah
i i think we should let you in and
sergio finish
and then open the queue again
so just very quickly so we can take
questions again i mean um
yes so we are using a single uh instead
of for example doing like
what we do in rtx that win rtx we have
uh
one payload type for rtx
for each of the media types and other
codec media types
that is causing the payload ties to to
be double
if we use the same approach with in this
general mode generic packet decision we
will have to triple the
payload types and again this is we in
webrtc when
with all the h264 profiles pp9 profile
vp8 profiles
we are reaching the limit when we cannot
do have any free payload types anymore
so that's what we have decided to do a
payload type multiplexing
yeah we can just use one
one pillow type per codec but then we
may
have the problem that it is not
implementable
so the this this value what it indicates
is
what is the original format of the of
the
of the generic packetization if it was
x264 it was say bp9 profile 2 or
whatever
so next slide
so it just be recovered in a header
extension just say
and as we have one extra byte
we are going to use that byte to
indicate
and for audio is
is not really useful but we can avoid
having
uh to send more information in a
metadata
a header extension for the svu in case
that it is not
a scalable video stream so you what we
have tried to use is
this extra by to indicate when the
when the specifically if it is on an
iframe so the sv you can
start forwarding and this specifically
the the video packets from from these
packets and on
so next slide
so regarding the frame metadata what we
have discussed before i mean what we are
focusing is what is the the potential
metadata that we
uh that we need specifically i think
that we should focus in the
in the ones that help the svu to do the
larger forwarding and selection
and the ones that helps the the recovery
mechanism to
to work in case of of loss and meaning
for example if deciding if a package
that has been loaned
has been lost it was actually required
for the coding
the full frame or and we have to to take
some actions about rtx or
even request a picture load indication
or
a larger refresh request and
this is mostly for for for video and for
audio maybe
the one method that could be used is the
output stock
to know the frame length that could be
used in recording scenarios
uh there are several solutions that
could be
that could be used like for example
trying to
get back pre-marking and study somehow
uh you say b1 dependency descriptor that
it is the one that it is currently
proposed in the in the draft and we
think that it fits with with which it
will
it has been required and i would like to
to here if
there is some scenario that you think
that it would not be covered
or we can try to design a new rtb header
extension
for things that are not covered by the
iv1 dependency descriptor
so next slide
so there is regarding redundancy
this does not require an exchange to rtx
it will just keep working with knack and
rtx as
it is working today effect both ulp
effects and flashback will also work
the only thing without any change the
only thing is that
now the heuristic that it is done by the
application
to which package should be a should be
more protected or not is has to be
changed a bit in order to reflect that
and that the payload is encrypted and if
you lose one packet you will not be
um able to recover then the full phrase
anyway
so we have some some consequences but it
is how
the applications decide
how the effect everything are applied
and next one
that it is the last
is just too red can still be used
the only thing is that that and
the redundant primary data will be the
content that
has been encrypted so inbred will not
the encryption will not be applied to
the full
red packet but to the to the resumed and
data parts and there is uh
overhead in this and applied by the
transformation because
you will have the overhead and this
frame headers for the redundant data and
the primary data so we'll be
so basically you are sending the data
twice
and there is here there is a small
limitation that we have
when using the what we call the
association paleo type used for
multiplexing in an rtp header
thus red only has allowed us to have one
header so
this header and this the value has to be
applied for
both and for both the
data data blocks so it makes that you
cannot send
a one block that it is supposed to one
block that it is
i don't know so it has to be both of the
same codec
that it is only in this
it's the only limitation that we have
not if we think that it is
important to to solve we can't move the
payload
and then the payload type for
multiplexing into the payload and
it will also work
so at this point sergio i think we're
almost
out of time we only have two minutes
left so what i'd like to do is just try
to understand from the working group
how we move forward but one way since we
are
exhausted even more than the hour uh
here should we be thinking about an
interim
um to get into this to allow some more
time to get into this
um say like sometime during late may
does that make sense i don't know
jonathan if you have an opinion
before our time runs out
uh yeah i do think that you know some
sort of interim would probably use
into um discussion of this um there's a
lot of interest
and not a lot of convergence which
sounds like sort of the
sort of area where interim is sort of
ideal um
i mean we can work out the timing on the
list if we do various uh
um whatever
it is in the meantime i i would
encourage
for people to to read the draft and also
start
uh sending emails on the mailing list
issues
to the current working draft so that we
can uh continue
in the media list not work for the
intern
okay
okay uh i think we're just about to be
out of time
for this session so uh
maybe you know jonathan do you want to
take maybe one question
one final question and then we can call
it a day
um yeah i mean if either call in your
first and q so if you have something
that can be handled in one minute but i
know i guess he dropped himself out no
i guess if you have something quick
or yeah just something quick um
i i think uh we're all uh
probably more concerned about the same
things than we realize
um a lot of the stuff that colin was was
mentioning
um it really is mostly applicable to the
new codec
that i that i presume the the the people
that presented this care about which is
81.
i think maybe people don't realize that
81 is basically identical to h.265
as far as high-level syntax um you know
it has the same
value structure and it has the same
subframes
that h.265 has there's tile groups you
could split a picture into into
tiles and slices and things like that so
i think we need to
you know all agree that we're on the
same page about the richness of
of the new codex that we do care about
and figure out
did rtp make a mistake in providing
packetization for that richness
and we really don't need it or is there
value in that richness
and we need to somehow preserve it
crypto happening
and i think the people that want to
deploy 81 should take a good hard look
at the 81 packetization to figure out
do they care about any of those things
uh or are they willing to forego them
in end-to-end situations
thank you very much mo and i think on
that note uh we will declare the
session that itf went over thank you
everybody
so
it's
hmm
hey
so
uh