i don't see share application okay
yeah so when i click on the share icon
what i see is share screen it's like do
you really want to share
it's like you were sharing earlier okay
with some incoming share screen
browser are you using
i'm on safari that's your problem
um for whatever reason at least as of
the last ietf
you couldn't share anything other than
your full screen with safari
okay let me uh okay
and if you're using uh so i think that
both chrome and firefox are known to
work well
um you do end up having to enable the
allow screen recording or something like
that um in the security part of the
settings
which then requires you to restart the
browser also
okay do you guys see what i'm sharing
now
yeah if you maximize that it should be
fine
okay
[Music]
icon at the bottom right of the screen
it looks like a
little plug-in thing add to your left
nope keep slide your left keep going
keep going
one of those two there you go so that's
normal slice order i think the next one
over is the full size
so two icons to the right
no no no not the slider
there are four there are four buttons
there what yeah the slide show one
left to the slider oops
you've stopped the screecher actually i
think we lost him completely
i will look for the chair slides just in
case uh i have to do the projection
so rashad if you like i can go ahead and
run the screen if you
would like me to do that
and by the way you're still on mute
okay jeff you can share because it looks
like i'm having i mean i don't want to
change to chrome now
okay in the middle so i'll take notes
okay that'll work
should we get going yeah
yeah and actually just before we get
completely started is there anybody that
like to check
tester microphone to make sure that
things are working fine
greg i know we've heard you recently
we heard from mahesh
okay since nobody is actually asking
and it looks like we can see full screen
rashad take it away
okay thanks uh thank you everyone this
is
uh bfd at itf 110
rashad co-chair and whoop jeff
next slide please
this is the usual note well which you
should have seen many times by now
it's the usual stuff
you're basically agreeing to everything
the itf policies
uh the agenda so that's the chairs
update from
jeff and myself uh then we'll go
to bfd and sold sister that will be me
bfd secure numbers i believe is from
mahesh and not so now right now
mahesh will continue vfd stability and
then
we'll have bfd on our feet an affiliated
echo
next slide please
so as you guys have seen we've had an 80
change we'd like to
thank martin for his support during the
past few years
and welcome to john uh who's our new id
john would you like to say a few words
how your love of bfd started from
childhood or something along those lines
returning from childhood i believe i was
there at the
very first meeting um between it was
i think the people in the room were dave
katz dave ward and me
but uh it's you guys baby now
appropriately so and i'm looking forward
to working with you
thank you
okay here's an update on uh the
documents we have in urfc rfc 8971 which
is bfd for vxlan
would like to thank everybody who
contributed reviewed the authors and a
special thanks to greg for
pushing it over the finish line which
is always a tough job
bfd for large packets um
there's been discussions there's been a
relate that was
in uh working group last call there's
been
a um a more recent draft regarding how
to
other if you guys remember but bfd
large packets allows you to have large
packets to detect mtu
issues but it doesn't address procedures
to alter
the uh bfd padding size and that draft
bf debating alteration describes
procedures to do so
the authors have decided to merge
documents together that's a good that's
a good idea
and i guess we're basically waiting for
a new revision of the document
very quickly that is my near term queue
after ietf is finished
thank you um
bfd yang document it's been a while uh
we've had to send diffs to the rfc
editor do a change in one of the modules
it depends on
the t's yankee that document has been in
miss ref for
close to three years now uh i haven't
checked what
are the state of the other documents i
mean the ones it depends on
so i don't have a good idea what a
potential eta would be
so a quick point on this one it was
mentioned in one of the other meetings
uh this week
i have to pull my notes to exactly which
one i think was in the chat
that one of the options we could
consider doing to maybe move things
forward is to
uh take the document back from the rfc
editor and split out the mpls component
and ship it without the mpls component
in the main document and do a second
document with mpls
i'm not saying this is a good or bad
idea it is
just potentially an option for the
working group if we care to get
ourselves unstuck from mpls
or alternatively we ask our ads to lean
on the mpls group to finish their work
hello jeff that was me who suggested
that this ac
and lsi suggest that in lsr because i
had done
i had done some homework and i saw that
not only are you work
waiting on yang te you're waiting on
yang t-e-r-s-v-p
which t e references so you got to get
both of those done
just to get that one reference to the
tunnels
or those i mean those those references
to the tunnels in
the mpls document
thank you ac i'd forgotten that uh it
was you yeah um
so and i think uh part of the relevant
point here since was mentioned lsr is
that uh
we're also holding up other people that
are importing the module that we asked
them to use as the grouping to make
you know life consistent for the rest of
the bfd users
so unfortunately what we're trying to do
the right thing for everybody
mpls is sort of messing that up
yeah so we'll sync up after i did not
attend the uh where that was said i
think it's something of the but it's a
suggestion to be considered
i think next in the queue is mahesh okay
uh so richard and jeff actually
i did have an opportunity when i was
writing the yang module for one of our
drafts to actually test out
and yes richard there's a minor change
in the tease document
which i was able to address by changing
the pft module to get it to compile
but i do second the fact that we
might want to split off mpls just to get
the rest of the
the pft yang module
out of the door
okay
sorry about that
yeah i'll just add i i would i would
hold you know you're holding it's
holding up uh
ospf isis and pm at least
okay
okay we'll uh sync up on that
and my is the fix you have to do is it
do you remember if it's the same fix i
had sent to the rfc editor
or should we sync up on that yeah i
don't remember exactly
what you changed i think it's uh one of
the plurals and
one yes there was yeah there was one
thing for lsps versus lsp from
what i remember right okay
um bfd unsolicited uh it's expired
recently we need eurovision there's
going to be a quick update immediately
after
the bfd authentication docs there's been
updates recently
based on the uh comments from the
shepherd
we should be done working group last
call soon there's going to be an update
on two of the documents
after i think it's fairly minor
minor stuff left well the document has
come a long way
i think we're close to being
there yes greg
i'm premature so for the development of
interest
comment okay okay um
and that was for this document of
interest you know i want to take a look
that i did not have time i don't think
there was any feedback
and i believe that's an rfc now
no it's a an rca editor queue so yes
it's got uh needed votes from
isg and it's uh in rfc editor q
but if i may i wanted to
mention other documents
in mpls working group
uh before we move on to those greg for
the one that's displayed here the mvp
and fast failover the thing that's sort
of an interesting sticking point on this
one
is that uh you know best is defining it
but it's sort of a core
php path attribute that be used to
provide
bfd discriminators as glue so that's one
of the hold up points it didn't get uh
you know the wider review even an idr
and i think the uh
it hasn't hit my iq as a new idr chair
yet but uh
john may have a better sense of what it
was last status wise
but uh the need for you know this being
a more generic
mechanism is i think one of the sticking
points we have to figure out what that
goes on with there
matthew did you want to respond to that
point or did you enjoy uh
um so speaking of specific um
best coaches it's currently in the rlc
editor's queue
um i believe it went through invest
mostly because it's fairly specific to
or is considered fairly specific to
to um to vpns
but that may be you know some people
have different different opinions on
that but i'm not sure
um stefan my co-chair was actually
shepherding it so i don't know if he's
tracked the
he's not in this call um
attract any of those issues that you
mentioned more closely
yeah i don't know that there's serious
issues i did leave some specific
comments uh
you know as part of my own review of the
thing um
and that was before i took on the chair
job so i think a conversation will you
know probably need we need to close off
on those points minimally the
point libraries need to be addressed and
past that point
more eyes um
as editor of this document i hope that i
addressed your comments
so yes i appreciate if you can check
uh the current version i will do so
thank you
so my interruption being done uh greg
you said you had further documents to
bring to attention
uh yes um so
there is a one mpls working group
document
um it's
bfd directed um
for traffic engineering environment or
path engineered environments
what it does it extends
mpls lsp ping
that can direct their reverse
path for their bfd session or
path for the reverse direction of the
session
uh to this specific um
lsp pad this document been
stuck for a while and i appreciate their
um
dvd community uh to look at it and share
comments
on vfd and ls working group documents
uh mailing lists uh
in addition uh there is a document
um its individual trust not working
group document
it's on mtls encapsulation for point
multi-point uh dfd sessions
and how to handle it for
uh
active tails and just regular
okay that's all thank you and uh greg so
that last one you said the mps
encasion's point to my point in what
working group is it
mdls working group mpls working group
okay
and you mentioned the previous one the
uh
the um bfd okay directed is stuck um
in in what it's stuck in what state now
and for what reason
uh okay it had um
wrote a routine directorate review
uh there were some comments uh the
technical comments
uh i believe that uh these technical
comments
uh have been addressed um
but reviewer believes otherwise
and we're kind of stuck
uh in our own opinions
um mpls working group seems
um
ambivalent to that so i
hope that um
i know uh i recall that uh
jeff looked at this uh draft and
shared his uh expert opinion
on uh working group chair
but i don't think that it really was
uh accepted because it was not on the
mailing list
it was a small group discussing
so uh if um somebody
or some experts from the group can share
their opinion
on mpl's uh mailing list
whether it's uh useful whether it's a
reasonable solution i would greatly
appreciate that
okay thank you
next slide please are we done or
okay vfdn solicitor should be visible
uh it's coming up yep thank you
okay uh richard again i'm going to be
just giving a quick update on this
document on behalf of all the authors
next slide please
so here's
that's a recap of the current state of
the document
it was last presented at itf 104 so
exactly two years ago
we had added a yang model
for this feature you know when when the
document was adopted we had a young
doctor review which required a small
change in the
main bfd young model that was sent to
the rfc edit that was sent to the
rfc editor and because of the yang model
we change the document from
informational to standards
uh we'll talk about that on the next
slide and then
uh working group last call was um
was requested last august
next slide please
so we the main comments we got during
the last call was
um on the comments one of the few
comments we got from raj was to
make sure that the procedures described
worked on
unnumbered interfaces uh we
the authors need to address this uh the
comments were i think
yeah specific to the subnet check and
the source address
for uh lookup so that's something which
we did not give reply to
and we have to we have to look into and
update
the document accordingly um
the other uh discussion which happened i
believe from uh
that got started by less i believe was
all the
well the two were related was first
whether the yang should be in the same
document
as the future the consensus seems to be
to keep the yang
in the document then the next related
question was whether it should be
informational um there was no consensus
here
uh and there seems to be i had sent an
email
to the ops ads
rob wilton replied i think i got reply
from somebody else i forget who
there seems to be no itf rules as to
whether having a yang requires the dock
to be standard struck
personally i don't really mind either
way
whether it's informational or standards
tracked
i know there was a push to keep it
informational because there's no
protocol changers there but there is a
yang
okay model so john we may need your
well not me we will need your help just
to close on this
and also got comments from greg uh there
were some clarifications
so one of the reasons just i mean for
informational purposes one of the
reasons this document stalled
was uh three of the full authors changed
jobs in the past year or so
so we need to get back to it
next slide please
yeah we need to address the comments
from the bfd
working group and
move ahead with it but the main thing
you know from a non-technical
uh viewpoint is we need to address the
uh
standards track versus informational
and thankfully this document is
literally at the the last gates now it's
ready to be published once those are
dealt with
john yeah comment
enough for me to be educated about the
standards correct versus
uh informational i have a question
which is um what's the downside of
moving it forward as standards correct
from your perspective
because that would appear to address the
ambiguity
by making it move
if you'd rather take it to a side
conversation that's perfectly fine i i
think the general consensus
from the working group is their
ambivalent about uh what the actual
status of this is
uh originally without the ang module
there is absolutely no protocol change
this is more about
here's how you use existing mechanisms
mostly via configuration
and that sort of thing so that was the
real reason to have it informational
and the ambiguity is strictly what does
having a yang module inside of your
document
do to things uh
the the question effectively devolves
down to we're polluting the ietf
namespace for modules by putting our
stuff in there
and ietf effectively has to manage that
so while we're not changing bfd
we're changing the yang tree that ietf
as a whole manages
so i think that's really what the
question evolves to
it doesn't hurt us to have it as
standards track and i think we just need
a
declaration right yeah i get the reason
why um
the the you know bfd may pull standards
crack in with it i'm
just trying to understand why the
working group wouldn't just say
okay find standards track but as i said
we can take it offline
further questions before we move to next
slides
okay secure sequence numbers will be up
next as soon as i find it
all right uh so i will be presenting
secure sequence numbers on behalf of
sonal
who could not attend this particular
meeting
next slide please
so as rashad mentioned in the
chest status we've been going through
trying to address the itches addressed
now i think there's still a
couple of minor comments still left
uh which i think we will address in the
next revision
um so we should the latest version
should be bumped up to online after
its 10 110
next slide
so one of the questions that was raised
as a result
of the shepherd's comments was has to do
with
the fact that we do talk about
symmetric algorithm that is used to
compute the ciphertext for this sequence
number itself
um the suggestion from richard was
whether we should mandate or even
propose actually
uh a minimum algorithm i don't remember
richard which is the one you
maybe said as the minimum
um that we might want to propose
in the draft for the purpose of
interoperability um that of course
leaves the question of what happens
if that minimum algorithm ever gets
obsoleted or deprecated
um at that point would become have to
come back and drop the draft
so typically iitf has not been very good
at
being able to specify a minimum set of
algorithms
so this is a question for the work group
to answer and then
if not then um should
the trunk leave it to the implementers
to decide what algorithm they're going
to set up
as a minimum or whatever they propose
in their implementation so
um that's pretty much all i had and i
would pause and see if
anybody in the work repair has any
comments or suggestions on
how to resolve this question of
algorithm
uh personal opinion you mentioned that
and you're correct that this is usually
not done to suggesting algorithms for
the reason so i think i'll
if this is something which is not done
for the reasons you mentioned
we should probably go along the same
lines
see john john
it was a little thrown off when uh
maheshu said that
uh you might put an algorithm into the
document
for interoperability reasons isn't the
uh sequence number a local matter
the when you say local matter meaning in
terms of
um how you secure the sequence number
how you how you generate it yeah
that is local uh the question is if
uh as part of this draft a proposal if
you're trying to secure it
by uh using a symmetric algorithm
then both ends have to agree on that
algorithm oh okay yeah thank you
sorry
and mahesh remind me didn't we have a
conversation originally with ellen
decock that had recommended
a specific algorithm that is extremely
low cpu use that's uh
a good have a good fit for this
you know the i must be missing or
forgetting something
so probably will need okay let's let's
take that back uh
so the uh somewhat to john's point the
purpose here is to provide
uh the ability to do bfd security
when you're not actually doing
signatures across the entire bfd packet
you're just trying to
do something that effectively from the
outside world looks like a random set of
sequence numbers
and we're using a crypto mechanism to
basically uh
allow us to generate what the next
sequence number looks like
without actually doing something as
strong as sha2
and we'd received some feedback during
the initial discussion phases about this
that there exist some low-level hashes
that
are extremely cheap to run the challenge
is once we get to anything that's
too complex uh we actually get rid of
the bone
uh the benefit of this feature which was
intended to
not have to do quite as much crypto and
bfd
okay so i'll take that back to the
mailing list and see if we can contact
alan
um john did you want to respond to that
as follow-up
easy yeah i noticed that the
document when you do this you still have
to have a greater
sequence number than the previous so
anytime you do anything other than just
replacing it you're gonna
have a lot more wraps with 32-bit value
that's not discussed in the document
though
um so are you saying after
you have generated the ciphertext
version of the
sequence number no it's that
you you're taking a monotonically
increasing sequence number to begin with
and then the you're competing the
ciphertext for it
and inserting it oh okay okay
oh okay but okay but both sides would
have to use the same of course then okay
i understand
this is the obscuring mechanism
all right um so if there are no other
comments then i guess
jeff we're going to take it to the to
john and then our mailing list
yep well we'll take it back and again
the challenge is
we don't want to use any ciphers that
actually make it more expensive than
solving you know
bfd signatures at speed anyway
so yeah got to go back to there
is no nothing further the next schedule
of presentation is bfd
stability
this should also be a fairly short
presentation
so um next slide
so just like um secure sequence number
this one is uh
also gone through the shepherd's review
uh one of the questions
that came back during that review
process from
albert was that the draft mentioned
being able to track the lost packet
count
but there was nothing described in the
draft as to how that
could potentially be tracked um
so the suggestion was maybe it needs a
young model
which is uh next slide
which is exactly what we added
so it essentially extends
the idf yang model
to add iftf bft stability
um documents for each
one of the potential uses of pft
in this case what you're seeing is an
example for
a single up ip bft
where it's adding a lost packet count
a very fairly small yang module but it
does require
i guess now a young doctor's review
which i think richard has already
initiated
and it also mis
necessitated an update to the ayana
consideration section
and the security consideration section
so those
were the changes for this particular
draft
any questions
i took a look but i don't remember is
there a feature
defined for this counter or is it i'm
not saying we have to i'm
i'm just curious
well um good point it's the only thing
that is
there in the yang modules so either you
implement the yang module and you have
the capability i guess you don't
okay okay question
even so wouldn't you want to see this in
your netconf hello to
know that the module is present
um right so if you're
even implemented in that case it's
sorry maybe you can clarify
well sorry i didn't mean to keep in
trouble just saying i mean if the
i mean if you don't support i think what
you were implying
my ish was if you don't support this
then you don't
there's one counter so if you don't
implement this
you don't that module would not be
in the yang library and all that right
and whereas if you do it's the only
counter
that's what you were implying that is
good
okay okay the yang library
considerations were the ones i wasn't
thinking of thank you
okay i believe this takes us to our last
presentation
which is bfd unaffiliated
okay watching
hello could you hear me yes
excuse me ciao created me
yes we can hear you
so next page
yeah this is uh the intention of this
draft
because there are some people
uh asking uh some questions
so we would like to clarify those
questions
here uh and uh
this is uh a new use that
is not yet been documented
in the current offices and
the second one is a ppi for tr
114 6
[Music]
documented the similar use
but in that tr the detailed
procedural text is not clear
and the third point is this draft
adopted by pfd looking group
last year due to the fact that
this draft updates ifc
58 80
in many aspects so the
intended status exchange
to the standard track next page
so uh the main change uh from uh
last revision uh the first point is that
add a new
session two to list all updates to
rfc 5880
the second add more
details on procedures
into section 3. the third one
improve the section four on the
application applicability
of a uniquely data
bfd ico functions
the last one added a new section 8
to list contributors and
we move one course to contribute because
the number limitation for the courses
next page
yeah this page gives the details
updates to fc
5880 so the first
point is uh the bfd ico
functions is uh a drink
to bfd asynchronous
model or bfd demand model
but it in this chapter
uh on a fleet kitted
bfd ico removes this
restriction as a second point
in previous rpc before
the bfdi code function work
the non-zero required minimum
i call x must be signaled
by the remote system uh this dropped
the uh on
afflicted vfdi code removes
this signaling uh procedure
and the third one the bfd ico
packets must not be
transmitted when bfd session status
is not up in this draft
the bfdi code removes the
limitation and the next page
and this page
this slide gives a detailed
procedure in this draft
firstly the
device a creator
the session and
it will settle
such as a transmit interval and
the detector mode
and the second
point the device a will send
the packet reusing the bfd control
packet format
to one hope we device b
with the ip address destinated
for itself so the ttl may be
set to
the the maximum number
the destination udp port
is cited to
[Music]
37 85
and the
the the next action the device b
will look back the received bfd
ico packets by the normal
forwarding wii without any special
processing and
the last step the device a
will receive the the bfd
ico packet and
lead to bfd change
so this is a very simple
procedure next page
so currently we have a tune i'm sorry to
play
to interrupt i think greg has a question
and if it's one on the on one of the
previous slides greg so yeah gregor
cases oh that's
another question it's um something i i
wanted to note
and uh we discussed it before so
uh the updates that you are listed
for um that this document
uh updates 58.80 um
my concern is that it affects the
security considerations because
uh the reason for this uh restrictions
put in 5880 uh
to use um echo function
was for the uh remote ad and
to be able to uh either
uh regulate uh their rate
of echo packets transmitted to it
or even
not to accept them at all
so for example by setting this
value to zero it indicates that
the remote pier doesn't want to receive
any
echo packet so uh removing this
and allowing to start
transmitting echo packets without
reaching the up state
during the normal um pole sequence
uh creates an opportunity for anybody to
start sending
at any rate packets
uh to their um system bfd system that
cannot handle it
yeah understand so maybe we need and
some note to describe the risk
right yeah uh and uh
to the procedure so um you probably
didn't include
in the slide that uh in order to
use returned packet
packets
your discriminator and progress the
status to
up uh these fields has to be initialized
by the sender it's uh
itself oh yes so basically
the sender has to set the status to up
and send the your discriminator to the
locally assigned
uh associated with this bfd session
uh discriminator value so
thus on the receipt of this packet it
will be able to proceed as you describe
it yeah so thank you
upon the outtake uh i think it
we did not release it in the slides but
the content you mentioned now
we documented in the draft right
okay okay all right casey you had a
question
just a quick one uh i've somewhat given
up at my own company trying to get
people not to write yang with a capital
y
and the rest lower case but it's yang is
uh is is originally an acronym
so could you please not use that
uh that version of it
okay
mark
up comments uh we got into greg's
comments
i think for this uh uh affinity pfd echo
process this is uh it is totally
transparent today
to the remote uh system so it's just
like
just like a data packet you don't know
you don't
know any thing about the whether it's a
bfd packet or
a data packet so same size for me as
there's no security issue
uh so i'm going to insert myself into
the queue ahead of greg uh potentially
make the point that greg would
it would be normally a security
consideration in the sense that
one of the reasons we have signaling for
echo support
is so that the systems can do regulation
and also indicate their willingness to
do so
the whole point of this feature
originally from broadband forum
is that there is no bfd control protocol
running between the two systems and
simple packet loopback is permitted what
this means is that
you have an unprotected system
so you are correct in the sense that
there's not much going on
but it's still dangerous
yeah i think mark
gives some comments
that if that is in normal
forwarding way the packet will be
looped back because uh
if the remote side just
[Music]
rotates the packet based on the ip
address
but there is some risk that
if the remove side treated that packet
as a bfd ico packet
it will do some other action
that that may be the risk yeah
yeah in security terminology this would
be considered a reflection attack
so that that is the thing that the
security considerations will need to
discuss
yeah i was dead greg
uh i have a further point but greg did
you want to finish one
no uh thank you jeff um uh it was very
uh one small note i i wanted to mention
in regards to the reference to uh bdf
document
uh i discussed it with their um
dbf and uh they're not really proud of
this
document and what is written there in
regard to the
bfd so they're not going to revisit it
but they are not advertised
and not really supportive of what's
in the document in regard to bfd echo
function
well that is good to know it also means
that they will be happy if we clean this
up for them
yes if we can provide some foundation
uh i don't think that there will be any
effort to
revisit their tr 146.
but yes uh they would appreciate if we
provide more uh strict technical
ground for this mode so greg just to
clarify they're not proud of their
document you're not referring to
this no no no i i'm referring to tr
uh 146 in the part that discusses bfd
echo function use
okay
right and make one last point and then
return the presentation
back um using your own slide
uh one of the discussion points that
will need to be in the document
is that uh by entering you know one of
the down or in it states
that normally implies that uh
the bfd async mechanism
is running and will be generating
packets so part of our procedure changes
that need to be in here
is that we're allowed to be in the down
state
without transmitting packets
and i'll take that comment also to the
mailing list
yeah thank you very much so uh
could i go uh a hide for the open
issues
please yeah so
yeah we there are still two
issues uh open uh if possible we hope to
uh have some discussion here the first
uh
issue is that
printed version
to reviews the both statistical machine
and the multiplexing key
which will simply simplify the
implementation
so in this draft uh the pfdi
code packet reuse the
bfd control packet format so
we would like to know is there some
other proposal
and the second open issue is that
i think at the beginning we talked
about the bfd model
and if possible we hope
this uh the
mechanism in this draft can be
pfdr model also so
if we
decided to
handle the bfdr model draft further
i think we can consider
this point in also thank you
greg you have the mic
um beijing um thank you for bringing
uh this open issues um
my understanding of the status of
bfd echo is that
the format of the packet the payload is
not defined
so and that's the question
to offers of this document and to
the group itself so if
in this document is defined that it uses
their bfd control message format
would that be interpreted as in all
other applications of bfd echo
they must use bfd control message format
okay so that's something that we need to
consider
the impact of a
decision made in this document on all
other applications of bfd echo
okay thank you very much
so as individual i would say we need to
clarify that
if we do use the bfd control packet
format
for this it's only for the unaffiliated
and all the other uses of echo existing
ones don't change
i don't know i'll wait
also as an individual my employer is
doing something very similar to this
they did choose to use some portion of
vfd
echo packet processing because they
already had code for doing so
that said i'm not clear whether or not
we have to specify the contents here
you know one thing maybe for the authors
to consider
is do you really need to specify the
contents
and if you do one of your options is
that you can make it
uh an option rather than you know you
this
is the mandatory implementation this is
after all local feature
yeah uh i think we can do it we can
provide the proposal
to working group after the meeting
and let's see the
okay and we'll obviously take these
questions to the mailing list as well
thank you so
next type i think
we need more reviews and comments
and we've got
quite a lot of feedback and comments
just now
i think we will revise this draft to
resolve those comments as well as
some further action will
be taken after the meeting
and then we would like to ask for a
working group last fall
thank you
thank you very much
thank you so i believe that completes
our agenda
right on time we have a couple of few
moments if somebody would like to bring
an
other issue to the microphone otherwise
we may adjourn
give it a few seconds to see if anybody
wants to read something
there being silence let us adjourn
thank you everyone thank you everyone
see you soon