okay
we are on the clock shall we start
okay uh welcome everybody to this first
uh co-working group session at the itf
110 meeting uh
charizard marco tilocami and jaime
jimenez
who couldn't be here for this meeting
and
we have the next slide to give a hint
why next please
so jaime is happily busy again
uh with his newborn son and as we like
to think training future working group
chairs
and this place we haven't standing chair
for this meeting
uh carson bormann thank you very much
for uh
kindly being supportive in in this
occasion and congratulations again
to jaime next please
um yeah a bit of practicalities of
course as usual we assume
uh people attending the session to have
read the documents
uh discussed today uh we are trying to
make good use of the time during this
meeting
to solve open issues especially the note
well applies
more on that on the next slide and as a
reminder blue sheets are automatically
compiled
in this myth echo mythical meetings uh
i will be jabra scribe for this session
and i understand we have
michael richardson as minion taker
confirmed michael
well he's typing
all good thanks thank you very much i'll
also help
otherwise uh not well apply as usual
please get familiar with us
uh if you're not already it's not only
about uh ipr and payments
it's just it's also about a code of
contact so be polite and nice with each
other
next slide please
uh okay uh please use the key request
feature on miteiko to
enter and leave the queue the hand on
the top left of the window
uh you can just jog there i'll be
described i can relay your comments or
questions
and this meeting is recorded and again
no need to fill
any attendance list explicitly
next please
all right and more nice news for today
uh we are again changing
aed uh the leaving aid uh very labor
right now and during the week there will
be the
uh the formal end of to uh francesca
palumbini's new id
in the earth area and responsible um
especially for core
uh so thanks to barry again uh and
welcome francesca and if you two want to
say something please do
okay i hesitated i saw francesca try to
jump in hi
everybody thanks thanks for the support
you guys have given me over the time
and uh thanks for being an easy working
group to manage
uh and getting a lot of work done so um
you'll still see me around
yeah just want to say thank you marco
looking forward to working with you
and everybody
thank you both of you next slide please
right this is the agenda uh for today
which is essentially including
uh all the security related works uh
also to avoid a collision with the
danish buff
on friday and we start with group
communication documents
continuing on other security works and
cachable score and combining
oscar with edoc and the recently work on
cypher limits especially apply to the
oscore protocol
next slide please yeah anticipating the
agenda for
friday we'll discuss something points um
on one of the core comp documents
currently under shepard write up
and look at the advanced uh twos and ml
documents now active
same for new block and dialing these are
all working group documents
and we conclude another two documents on
resource directory extensions and
a new proposal on data centric
deployment for co-op
so before we move on any agenda bashing
or
comments on the agenda anyone
okay next slide please
just done that so next
and next so uh
i think in january uh 8974
uh was published as an rfc used to be
the core stateless document uh thank you
very much to
klaus and michael especially in the
final stages
and to the whole working group for this
achievement
next slide please
and then we have a bunch of almost there
documents uh dave urn is already in the
editor queue
and for the resource directory uh we
could finally see that day
yesterday when it was uh formally
approved and there are other
working groups and documents that have
uh as many reasons
to celebrate about this uh like
especially
one document in in l week uh
echo request tag uh also requires some
uh
final editing from christian if i
remember correctly to address
comments from from ben and roman
otherwise it's also very close to to
take the final
the final step thanks a lot for all this
work
next slide please
uh right uh we have two of the four
uh core conf documents uh meaning young
sieber and seed
that are right now in las colon till uh
mid next week
and as francesca suggested we also
requested
for both of them a review an additional
review from
from young doctors
next slide please
right as to the other two qr code
documents uh they are under shepard
right up
young library uh seems to be essentially
done
while there have been new open points
raised during the write-up
for the comic document and they will be
discussed also
with eva law in the friday session
otherwise we have a three document
post-working group plus goal
one is a group of score for which a new
revision was recently submitted and we
have especially two
more open points to work on uh
sentimental data ct
has just incorporated working groups
called comments and
with a little synchronization about the
content of
another document that was also discussed
in dispatch today
uh is possibly ready to move forward and
and same for the new block uh draft that
has also incorporated working
plus comments and is also in the agenda
for the friday session
next slide please though i think that
was all for the summary
yeah uh so i think we can
take as next step the uh the set of
group communication documents and and
the first one in the list is
group combis with esco presenting
yeah i'm just checking the audio it
works we can hear you well
okay in that case i'll turn on the video
as well we can see you too hi esco
hi and you you can do the slides i think
right
cars then we handle them no question
yeah thanks
so it's still being started
no screen yet not talking my
usual way of showing slides in chrome
doesn't work
so i'm using a different uh thing and
that of course doesn't always
work either so just go ahead and talk
oh yeah okay i'll open the slides here
then
so i'll present the group communication
for the constraints application protocol
draft group convis
and just as a reminder of the goal so
this is intended to describe
co-op group communication as a successor
of the experimental rfc
7390 now we
aiming for standards track documents
meanwhile the slides are visible great
so we'll
skip this one because we've presented it
a number of times it's just a reminder
of the scope
of the document so currently focused on
any
udp multicast based group communication
for co-op
so the general updates i will now go
through them
so we have uh adapted the text to allow
this thing basically so one server
that's
responding to a group quest can give
back
multiple responses in principle
although normally it should give back
one response
but still due to circumstances you could
get multiple and now
question was how to handle this
um so if the yeah in this case the proxy
is
proxying a group request the idea is now
to
based on inter experience state that the
the proxy will just forward
all the responses and then the
application layer the client
needs to handle it
so that's also visualized in figure so
we can
go to the next slide
so what we do did is we had already
guidelized on forward proxies were
revised
now also some more information or
reverse proxies is
added um
let's see yeah so the
reverse proxy can basically
[Music]
do the group request so the client will
do a unicast request to the proxy the
proxy will do a group request
the proxy can also handle following
unicast requests
so um
yeah that's basically a reverse proxy
and it's made to look like
a normal server basically
and we now also reference specifically a
signaling protocol
for proxy so as we listed before a
number of issues for
forward proxies and reverse proxies we
now have this reference to drafty loca
core group proxy that's
authored by marco and me and it also has
a signaling protocol
as will be explained later to address
these issues
okay let's go to the next slide
now one major addition is the caching
model
so we already have the clash caching at
the client side of course
responses and now we basically
add the caching in the proxy as well
um so for proxy's caching uh
we did at least marco did a quite
thorough analysis on that and it turns
out you have to work with two types of
cache entries so one is the individual
cache entry for a single response from a
single server
the other type is an aggregated cache
entry so
that's basically one cache entry that
represents an entire
group of responses that corresponds to a
single group request
so we have both types and in the draft
we will
basically explain some rules
how to handle handle the cache entries
for for both types
okay go to the next slides
yeah so the caching model is as follows
so a proxy can receive a group quest and
then get responses from the
origin servers back as shown on the
picture
so what it does it is it forwards each
response
back to the client and
also adds an individual cache entry for
each response
also the responses get added to a list l
and that list l
will basically later be used to make an
aggregated cache entry that collects all
the responses for that particular
request
and at the bottom of the slide you can
see there's some
lifetime handling also to be done for
the cache entry so it looks at the
max age of all the responses to
compute combined max h or the aggregated
cache entry
ok next slide please
yeah the caching model continues so uh
basically your unicast request can also
be sent
to the proxy and then it can receive a
response from the server to that
so the response is forwarded and then it
creates an individual
cache entries or updates the existing
one
and it also will look in the aggregated
cache entries basically
let's see what it does then which ones
yeah it can also basically update the
aggregated cache entry with an
individual response
and also that
may influence the lifetime so
we'll basically scan all the entries
again and correct
yeah the lifetime so the lifetime of an
aggregated entry is always the
minimum of the lifetimes of all the
entries that are in there
okay let's go to the next slide
so also the validation model is a
separate section uh
from caching um
[Music]
yeah so in the code rfc this was not
addressed in detail now we try to do
that
so the validation works between client
and servers and for that
we introduce a new option the multi etac
option and this can only be used for
group requests so it will basically uh
yeah be like an e-tag only that's in the
e-tag
it also encodes an identity of the
server
so that it can basically direct the
e-tec option to one particular
server
and the nice thing of this is that at
the server side the
the server doesn't have to think about
okay what kind of
e-tech should i generate so that
clients can
can distinguish between all the possible
servers but it just generates an etag as
usual and the client can use this option
to
basically pick big responses that it has
cached and to validate if they are still
correct
so the proposal is in detail in the
draft so we have
some addressing information added
encoded yeah in the same way as in the
group from proxy draft
okay let's go to the next one there are
no questions at least
there's also between the client and
proxy
validation possible yeah another quick
question if i may
this show this shows an x
in the r column yeah this is repeatable
here yeah but it's also a simple
sequence
so that's right
how do i know whether i start a new
sequence in a new option
or continue the sequence in the existing
option
yeah the existing option is to target
one
particular server in the group
and it has an basically a sequence of
etag elements in there so that's for
this particular server if you wanna
address multiple servers so you say
tag one on server one and tag three on
server two for example
then you need two of these options
so that does not fit in one option in
the current definition
okay thank you yeah
okay yeah so this was between client and
proxy so that's basically
only meant to address these aggregated
cache entries that are newly introduced
so you can basically validate an entire
group
response as a client
and in case yeah in case that is still
fresh you can basically get the
validation confirmation from the cache
like okay this is still
a fresh group response you can use the
entire thing
and there's no need to do a new group
request in this case
but it can be used in get and fetch
group requests
and yeah it works quite for the rest
quite similar to
the normal co-op validation so using the
group
e-tec option
um yeah okay let's go to the next one
taking the time there's also the
security question of course what we have
discussed so far is without
security or at least without end-to-end
security
we also consider it what can we do uh
going through a proxy
with end-to-end security can we still
cash
well it turns out it's not that
straightforward but it's possible
by using the deterministic requests that
are
introduced in this draft ralph hamsu's
core
cacheable score
and it's limited to restful safe
requests
that have no no side effects on the
resource
at the server as like a guest and a
fetch for example
so the client has to prepare this
specific deterministic request
to be able to do this and response
revalidation
that's not not possible in all cases so
we have listed
a couple of cases below
it is possible between origin client and
origin servers
using the multi-etag option
but there are some complications when
doing data so if you change the request
only a
little bit then it means oh i have to
use a different deterministic request
so it's gets into quite a lot of
complexity uh
to do this so that's what we
basically yeah try to provide an
overview of what you can do and what you
cannot do
okay next slide please
so we have an open point one of several
actually in
github i think that's uh the question
what is the most appropriate
place for these new items that we
introduced
so one number one is the general rules
of cash ability
of responses at proxy and proxies
so this looks appropriate to be in this
document
but on the other hand we could also move
it to the group
proxy document
to clearly separate that
the other thing was the multi-etec
option that we introduced
so that's basically for a client to be
able to validate individual
responses from a group of servers
that looks like it could also be yeah in
separate dedicated documents
because it's really a new new thing here
and not yeah not something existing in
co-op that we want to
explain in the group communication
context but it's really a new
new feature
personally i think we could also add
maybe how the normal e-tec
option can be used in group
communication scenarios because that's
also still possible
with some limitations of course and then
number three
is the group etec option so that's
basically specifically
validating a group of responses at the
proxy
that could go typically also in the
group com
proxy document that's what it's about
or maybe it can stay in group combis
there's a bit of discussion points you
have
so where where does the content go
okay then the next slide please uh there
is
yarn in the queue uh please go ahead
yeah um uh hi esco yes just a few
questions
on this um and
i'm trying to understand the multi e tag
and the group beta do you have do you
have any simple examples for when i
would like to use
one or the other option here
why would i want to validate the number
of group
the number of requests for example
or sorry number of responses in the
group b tag
yeah so that's yeah i don't have any
real concrete example but you could say
that
suppose you're reading status
information of a group of
devices and yeah like one of these
devices for example has a particular
large status report that i
already got last time and i maybe don't
want to get it
next time so you can basically
put it multi-etec in
yeah just stating okay i have this
version of your status report um
yeah don't yeah don't send it if that's
still the same basically
right and that that you could say yeah
and that you could
that's basically that you could you
could have multiple of those
uh yeah and it can be multiple different
servers yeah um
okay and the security for that there was
some part of the antenna security was
not possible i mean that that's
definitely proxy to
origin server so that that's not an
end-to-end security
uh secured option right
um yeah the detail for the details of
the option itself
maybe marco can answer that i think it's
in the previous slide
oh sorry sorry for stopping the
presentation i just was curious how
but yeah as you said you're in the the
group yeah here
the the groupie tag option would
essentially not be possible to use
if you haven't on security and the multi
tag option would not be possible
for the proxy to use acting as client
to the original servers yeah
okay but is that a problem i mean that
this could be an outer option right
right now this is mimicking uh the etag
option
in tesma properties so you'd be
processed in the same way and this would
be the result
okay but it was basically yeah
it seemed like this amazing go ahead no
no go ahead
what really remains possible is for sure
end-to-end between the client and the
servers
right okay
good well yeah i can think more of it we
don't need to stop uh stop the
presentation now please
thank you yeah it opens up many
things possible things you can do and a
lot of questions
okay then let's move to the next slide
oh there's already next steps yeah i
think we're
very quiet uh so the next steps for this
draft we have uh review comments
received from
john still to be addressed i think
there's quite some
good comments including uh okay can we
uh
yeah i think that was one of the
questions too to make it more generic as
or not only
target co-op group communication over
udp multicast but also
consider which which part could be
applicable to
yeah another transport layer like a
ip group cast for co-op
and more reviews would always be good of
course we have quite some new content
added so that
there's really something there to be
reviewed
we want to address the open points
introduced today
and that's what's the issue 11 about
where what goes where
and of course there are other github
issues open
and yeah doing some more testing and
implementations it would
also be nice so i think this concludes
the presentation more or less
if there are any questions let me know
nothing on jabber either
christian please um
from from the levels of maturity between
the
the e-tags and the um
the e-pads that and the rest of the of
the
group compass and i think it
might be a good idea to to treat the
etag into
more in something like the proxy
document that doesn't
that has no ambitions to progress in the
same pace
as the group of other the group
companies because i think that
the the group com is get getting good
compass
out is valuable and the and the e-text
thinks
things are valuable but they will need
time to to hammer out the details
yeah maybe some implementation work as
well for the
group etag for example multi-etec yeah
and the plus one from carsten on jabra
okay yeah no that sounds sounds
reasonable all
yeah then for the milt the group ejac
can certainly go into proxy documents
for a multi-etag
it's not really proxy related so
do you think it could be a completely
separate document in that case
it's not proxy related but it's related
to the
to the um transport address
stuff that up in the proxy document so
maybe it could still
look there because it has commonalities
there
yeah now that sound yeah that sounds
like a good observation indeed
so it could be combined is what you're
saying uh
because of that
all right thank you esko and all for the
feedback
we can switch to the next presentation
which is the
group score document
and i take that one
right yeah this is an update on the
group of score draft
now revision 11 was submitted by the
cutoff
next slide please
all right uh this latest version was
mostly about addressing
a very good and useful review that we
got from christian on
version 10 thank you very much for that
and a number of other points we
discussed and agreed on at the november
meeting uh
last year following that uh we think we
have still
two open points that i will overview
shortly later
uh one discussed with christian during
the hackathon about admitting
uh the recycling of group ids in the
same group
and one related to a comment we got from
ben cadoc on the list about the current
usage of
identity keys for both signing and
diffie-hellman
operations next slide please
right first of all we eventually
converge to a
single and simpler format of external
led
to be used both for the encrypting and
designing operations
and in simplifying it we remove the used
to be
par counter sign key
as inner inner element describing the
algorithms
uh used in the group or actually the
property of the key type
and this is also a much more consistent
and aligned with the common context
we also clarified why we are introducing
the last two
elements of the array in the first place
so this is what the document body says
and it works right away with all the
algorithms we have registered
in cozy today but also based on the
discussion at the november meeting
we added a new appendix providing a
general
template to follow to build the par
counter sign parameter
in the external led and the
corresponding parameter
in the common context uh for the future
case when possibly more cosy algorithms
will be registered
with zero or more than one capabilities
so it's essentially just a future
friendly to be followed and
if you take it and use it today with the
algorithms registered today
you end up with the main definitions
that are already in the document body
next slide please
okay then we also realized that it was
possible to
optimize a little bit response messages
uh by not necessarily including uh
the kid in the oscar option uh of such
messages
the kd must still be included in the
response
uh if the respond is intended to a
request
that was protected in group mode because
the responder could be any of the server
in the group
uh but otherwise the exact mode used to
protect the response
doesn't really matter and that
especially
when the pairwise mod is used allows the
save
uh pretty much buys on the wire
and we also relaxed the rules uh that
were
previously preventing recycling center
ids all together in the group
uh well now it's forbidden only uh under
the same
group id if that changes because of the
group ranking
uh it's possible to reuse sender ids
under
the new group id and according to all
the changes i mentioned so far we have
also
of course updated the uh examples of
protected messages in the draft
next please uh
right this is very much following
christian's comment
we we try to improve also um
the reasons why there there may be a
loss uh
even if partially of a security context
in case due to memory limitation
eventually um
a node in the group which is the maximum
amount of recipient contexts that it can
have
so if one more has to be created it has
to
to delete an old one to to leave room
for the new one
but the moment this happens uh from now
on
any newly created recipient context will
be created with an invalid
replay window that has to be fixed
assuming uh
replay checks are still important and
they are
and in order to do that well uh either
uh the node in question participates to
a group for king uh which of course
results in changing its sender id
uh sorry is sequence number reset or it
has to run a proper uh
exchange like with the echo option as
with defining appendix e
and as a positive side effect you also
get a freshness of
the just received request that that was
resulting into
the university and context this was also
an opportunity to make it even clearer
that
remaining able or becoming again able to
enforce anti-replay
and achieving freshness are a few
different things
and freshness is the one
related to achieving synchronizations
with the sequence number of clients
which can be achieved
uh using for instance the the echo
exchange
next slide please
uh right some editorial changes
is still pretty major i'll say we
reorganized a lot the section uh
discussing in fact
uh the loss or partial loss of security
context trying to
uh to express in a much clearer way the
pattern uh
cause effect uh causes can in fact be a
loss of mutable security context because
for instance of
rebooting because the
the maximum number of recipient contacts
have been reached or the exception or
send the sequence number
and the effect would be of course to uh
request new uh key material for from the
group manager that can just be end up in
getting a new sender id
uh but in a way or another this node
will reset
its sender sequence number anything will
be adjusted again
uh section nine defining the pairwise
mod was
essentially rewritten of course to keep
the same mechanics
but now it's written as a delta from the
oscar rfc
as christian also requested adding also
a small number of things picked up from
this document again
and it's group mode especially when it's
about support for
observe and for synchronization and
achieving freshness
now we have only the echo exchange
approach
as appendix c while we just removed the
other previously
included approaches as they simply
became when thinking more
more about them
next please all right uh the first of
the two
open points uh first of all as related
uh we realized uh something we
intended all along is not explicitly
mentioned and it should
um even odd rejoins the group and
when doing so of course it gets a new
sender id it must explicitly terminate
all the
observations it has ongoing and
just as a reminder in fact observations
are supposed to survive
a change a change of
group id you for instance to to a king
in the group
so so far we were forbidding the
recycling of group ids
all together in a group meaning that
groups cannot live forever
and that was forbid the forbidden
especially to avoid a possible problem
with
uh long-living observations in fact
so for instance you can have a a client
see one that starts an observation
with that tuple current gid kid of the
client
uh partially one so to say uh later on
for some reason that same client gets
a new kid totally fine the observation
continues with
the same original tuple then the group
is rekeyed
several times the gid changes because of
that and
eventually the gid drops and gets back
to
gd1 still fine problem is if a new
client
gets accidentally the same kid that
c1 had when he started the observation
and by
really bad luck uh that second client
starts
totally legitimately any observation
with the same tuple
and now you have troubles because you
can have one notification that matches
either observation which is bad
so we had to solve this problem uh to
admit recycling of group ids
and next slide please we discussed about
this during the acaton
and we found a way to to fix this it's
sufficient to introduce a little more
logic
on the group manager uh basically when a
node
joins and gets back from the group
manager the group id to consider in the
group
at that moment the group manager
stores for long term that group id as
the perth gid of that node
and same for other journey nodes so say
at some point the group manager for
whatever reason has to rekey the group
and distribute a new gid the group
manager checks
uh if any current group member has as
its birth g id
the new gid to be assigned to the group
uh if that's the case well
uh the group rakhine that the group
manager is going to perform will take
that into account and it will rekey the
group in a way that
those nodes are excluded logically
so they are locked out they will start
not being able to decrypt any further
message
eventually they will just get back to
the group manager to ask for
a current key material and they will get
back error responses because they are
not members anymore
eventually they will rejoin and if they
do so
they get a new sender id and they reset
their certain sequence number
and they have to kill their ongoing
observations
and the original problem that
forced us to forbid group id recycling
would be gone
and bottom line then with this little
addition
on the group manager groups can live
forever
if we didn't miss any detail here
so there be any objection in introducing
this update to admit long live
what are you saying is that you actually
keeping track of group members
uh for the purpose i mean in in terms of
the birth
gid then for the for the purpose when
they
later rejoin if they are if there are
conflicts
so you you can handle those later or
what or how does this solve
you check the conflict the moment you
want to rekey
anyway for whatever reason and you see
if the new group id you are going to
give
is the birth jetty of any of the current
group members
then you have a problem and you need to
exclude those members
yeah okay but they will rejoin
and then the problem will be gone
yes okay so you push the problem to the
group manager
essentially and by the way this applies
to group members that are in the group
for a very very
long while to be witness of a round of
group id
yeah yeah i understand it's according
case but still
okay thanks thank you
okay uh next slide please
second and last uh open point uh not at
all less important uh this was raised by
ben keduck
uh on the list um supporting the
pairwise mode
uh here we are essentially using the
same identity key
for two uh for two possible usages
uh one is well signing messages in group
mode and one is deriving a different man
secret to be used to generate
the pairwise keys and overall uh
it's all about the same single policy
protected communication in the group
uh with the value security context but
still this this double use is not
exactly
a common best practice so if you go for
it you really need to
to to prove that what you are doing is
secure
and there is in fact ongoing uh work to
prove that
uh possibly with some minor uh minor
addition in
in the exact derivation step uh this is
in fact secure
at least for group of score and the
the ongoing proof is uh trying to be
built on the paper we're already
referring that
was focusing on the ecis settings
although it was not limited to that so
that proof can in principle be readapted
uh to be valid for for a group of score
and just as a note the the pairwise mod
per se is actually um
all fine uh the the comment here is on
the actual
uh double use of the same key
in the process of key derivation so um
just to be on the safe side uh there
would be an alternative although
uh inconvenient to make this a key
provisioning problem and just go for
two separate keys one for signing and
one for defeatment
but they would be just inconvenient and
the last resort because you'd mean
more provisioning and more storage
overhead with the provisioning most
likely to happen
in the ace document defining
the joining and the key provisioning
with the group manager
so there is work ongoing on this and we
should be
able to come back on that in the coming
months
okay next slide please we should really
be the rope up
yeah next steps are addressing both two
open points
uh in version 12 submitted hopefully
having addressed both of them in a good
enough way
and most likely that version would be a
candidate to be considered to be stable
to move on
please you're
probably muted yeah yeah i was talking
um
so how is how is this draft aligned with
the co-op
group com is there any reason to to move
this
before the sort of co-op group
commission the same
they are actually referring each other
normatively so
they really have to go together
more or less so it will be this draft
will sit and wait
in in in the working group before uh
until the other draft is is ready
uh yeah the same can can be true for the
other one depending on which one is
finished first
okay so what do you mean by ready to
move on uh what is the meaning of that
okay but will you do that before the um
before the group come is in the same
state the original idea was to request
publication for both of them together
yeah cause after all yes
okay good then i know thank you thank
you
esko yeah i just question
you you mentioned doing the the proof
uh for this uh usage of the key for two
purposes
are you going to wait basically until uh
that paper is for example accepted and
reviewed
uh before moving on this draft or is it
kind of independent
uh it's in between uh it's an ongoing
research effort
and ericsson actually so probably euron
can give more details
so there is already a
a draft of a paper which
is intended to be a pre-print this is
a colleague of mine who's been working
on that and
whether that's going to be a published
paper
or just a sort of a preprint it's it's
basically
building on other papers and putting
things together so so it's
that i mean this particular researcher
asked if
is this uh do we really need to publish
this or is it just do we
could we have this as a as a note
basically but it's obviously good
if we get some some review on that uh
on that proof um so i think that's that
should be an ambition but i don't think
the working group
i mean it's sufficient probably that
someone
from from the itf community reviews that
it doesn't have to be a
sort of a presented paper at least not
i don't think that's necessary for for
progressing
this draft
thanks
thank you so if there are no other
comments we can move on
to the next document we should be
your score discovery with christian
presenting
just as a time check we are plus eight
minutes but we have ten minutes of flex
time so overall we are still
fine i'll try to keep it crisp
so this is about how can uh how can
a device that is supposed to be in a
group discover all the details that it
needs to join the group
um just next slide please giving a brief
recap um the device
may only know the the key material or
may not only know
something about the group manager but
not the full joining resource and the
group manager may not even be here yet
so this is using um the regular um
mechanisms we have in co-op with a focus
on the resource directory that
makes the whole process more efficient
throughout research lookup it receives
where the where the particular
joint joint joining node is on the group
manager
to join that to join that um to join
that group
next slide please we've updated the
document recently
to reflect to lastly reflect changes in
in other parts of the ecosystem
it's now well aligned with with all
most of the documents that it's
referring to the um
there are a few new target attributes
that are that allow the
joining node to identify in advance the
possible groups that it could join
and to see how it would join them so
making the drawing processing itself
more efficient
um there is now a document format
and we have additional text that says
that
there are um parties looking this up
may not necessarily be joining in full
but they could also be gateways just to
cover the use cases a bit more
completely
next slide please
um our examples are now up to date with
both the link format and with coral
and during the um before and during the
hackathon we've had this running
on an off-the-shelf resource directory
and michael performed basically all the
single steps that are involved in this
in this process um against the
resurrectory and i could in parallel
see how things work from there so it's
tested and it's tested to an extent
although not
from interoperability between one group
manager from here and another part from
there
next slide please the points that we are
currently working on
are mainly security considerations most
of which really
are inherited from the resource
directory so of course a
resource tractor that is um that is not
fully trusted
can do all basically can all do all
those things that it can do that is it
can hide the presence of a group it can
give wrong addresses because everything
that's happening on
on the on the oscore side is agnostic of
the
of the addresses so traffic could be
redirected even though
the um the encryption itself would not
be
endangered and that's probably the worst
of those and
we are still looking into how this is
best addressed and which attributes this
needs to be addressed
um false information obtained by the
client could lead
to it using a non-preferred cypher suit
and this definitely needs to be
addressed more clearly
let's start please
other than that it needs a bit of a bit
of updates
referring with respect to the examples
with the latest resource directory
changes
um but most of those are really on
tasks that can be done in in the course
of time
so for us it's really
really the next step would be to get a
bit more comments from the working group
as to is this now something that the
working group could see
um could could see is useful to to have
inside the working group
or what do we what kind of comments do
we need to expect when when this is
moving forward in general next slide
please
so that's it from my side thank you
questions comments
and nothing on jabber either so
we can move to the next one um on
multicast notifications
which um which like the like the q
group communication is something that
i've repeatedly presented here so i'll
cut the recap short again use case
so the group communication documents
we've talked about so far
are all about the case where request
goes out to multicast
and the responses have so far always
been
unicast only with this we describe next
slide please
how responses can be multicast and where
this could be useful
uh which is primarily when a lot of
parties
regularly request something and want
this to have this new
in an observation um
where they can all share the data and
don't have to re to
register separately next slide please
um mechanically this happens by having a
took
having a token that the server
that they agree on and the point and the
and the
party that makes the final decision is
the server because it's the
best point we can come up with
um with all score this also means that
they have
to have a particular request that they
all refer to because otherwise the
unprotection
um would simply not work next slide
please
this is all these details are all
communicated
in an error response which contain which
tells the client that i won't answer
this particular request
but you can if you had sent if you were
sending this request
then you could be observing you could
receive the notifications on this
particular token sent to that particular
multicast address
and in the protected case with this
particular external aad
next slide please
so what changed in uh since dash of five
uh since dash
o5 well not so since before uh
in the latest revisions is that the
format we have
is now a bit more well defined and also
aligned with the other work
we've talked about earlier with
about transport addresses as they would
be used in proxies for group
communication which is
which really need parts of the same data
so
aligning this makes it easier for
implementers to
to use code here
um so what it contains is the
information the the ad the server
address the
the group address the token and then
a request that would the client would
have needed to send
and possibly a response so if that last
notification is not present
this behaves like in regular co-op an
observation
with an empty act yes i heard you
the observation is fine i just don't
have data for you if there is data in
there
that can be expressed just as well next
slide please
um that array is just like in the
processing case also extensible so if
the
currently there is only one transport
that can handle multicast that is code
over udp
which is something that involves a
server host a server port a client host
a client port and a token
if we ever have any other transports
that
behave completely differently we have
the extension point there to say
protocol say two is or probably some
higher number because
proxying would might take um might take
different
use different numbers as well that
number is co-op over
what's i'm not playing laura i don't
know
slightly we are now more explicit
in that we do not negotiate for this
feature
this is something we had in very very
early drafts um but removed it because
the use cases that we see are the ones
where it's not feasible to
cater for an individual client's request
so if you do have use k if you do
see use cases where some clients might
be
observing resources individually and
others might just switch to the large
pool of multicast recipients
um please tell us let's talk about it
and then we can figure out whether this
is something just
specify right here or whether this is
something that still can be addressed in
a
in an add-on document uh either way
the server can announce its support for
these group observations
within within with the target attribute
that we now
describe other than that we've
updated um all the examples to
work correctly with the text that we
have next slide please
and also cover
how this could still be improved by
using a deterministic request as a
phantom request
um thing is um thinking back to the to
the examples
uh when you compare them it's like such
a such an exchange for the unprotected
case
and such an exchange for the protected
this really doesn't go well with the
story that
we'd like us to have all score as
something that you can just
tag on to co-op and then with a minimal
overhead that's cryptographically
feasible
um do all your exchanges but do them in
in a protected way
um by using deterministic requests we
can get this whole litany of exchanges
uh down to the complex form that we have
in the
unprotected case and
um just not to forget the point um
another update we did was
we now describe better how a group meant
how a device can act as its own group
manager for those very simple cases
where there is no pre-existing
infrastructure around
next slide please
so there's still a bit um work to do in
giving concrete examples for these
deterministic cases
and in exploring a bit further
how that would work in in a reverse
proxy case which
might to some extent also relate to the
to the reverse proxying work ongoing in
the
um with the prop with the general co-op
multicast proxying document
um but as with the other document we are
at a point where we can
we can still improve things but
we would be improving those parts can we
start improving on details
where i think this can profit this could
profit a lot from
more interaction with the working group
and for people reviews
possibly in the in the course of a
working group adoption
um yeah next slide please so
this this summarizes what changed here
and also how we could
um how we would like to have more input
from you
thank you
please let's go yeah just the question
um
on the appendices so there seem to be
quite quite some appendices
now uh are these then intended to be
just examples or clarifications or also
something normative
um let me just go through them in
so most of them are currently examples
um the the part about the
uh the deterministic requests is really
just
um illustrating how those things
interact so that there is no
need for normative inter for any
normative additions
but more like more explanation and
implementation guidance
especially with deterministic requests
it helps a lot to
if you if you're in the right mindset
then you understand why this
all works if you if you're viewing it
from the wrong angle
then it sounds awfully complicated and
this is more to
more to get you on the right track okay
appendix c is something that would
probably have normative content but not
interfering with the
with the rest of the document but more
specifying
registering additional attributes and
specifying a method
basically specifying a very simple way
of managing a group
thanks
any more questions
so what are the main things
you think are missing here except from i
mean
reviewing and and testing this scenario
what what
is that is this uh are all the
components in place now do you think
the components are in place yes and
only the details on on exactly how they
how there are a few details to hammer
out and
on on kind of coming back to the part of
the on the on
is everything in place like many group
communication documents this is all
assuming that the groups are set up and
that we are starting in this from a
situation
where everyone knows which group to be
in etc etc
um so possibly there could be
enhancements there
um frankly i don't know all the
documents that are in progress around
that well enough to
see whether there are maybe things
already there that we could just
reference
okay so i mean so looking at this from
this particular piece
of handling handling the the multicast
notifications then that this is
um this is fairly complete in your view
except for for details and and reviewing
and testing okay
thank you
yeah there was a point on on possible
adoption in the last slide carson you
want to take over on that
yes um
it takes considerable energy to jug this
environment i'm sorry
um
yeah so we this is a document that is
uh in version 08
um sorry for already putting up the next
set of slides
um and uh
there is uh
sorry carson just to be sure it's the
right document should be really version
five
yes sorry okay i'm very confused here
yeah so the the multicast notifications
has been
discussed uh for a while and
it's it's a version of five and
uh what we have to decide as a working
group
is is that something that we want to
work on
and uh is is the the draft actually
doing the the right going into the right
direction
not is everything already exactly
like it needs to uh be
so i'm going to start a poll
on that
so please go to the yellow thing at the
top of your
window and
raise hands if you think we should adopt
it
okay the numbers still increasing
okay i think we have reached our
final count here so we have
13 people who think we should adopt it
and now let me ask the
opposite question so he who would oppose
adopting this document
a lot of people make sure it's known
that they do not oppose it
okay so the number is still increasing
okay so um that looks like a pretty good
in-room consensus and of course the the
question is
uh who's going to uh provide
uh reviews of this
document can you just use the the shower
fan
q thing to indicate if you are
interested in providing reviews
esco
yuan
okay and let me ask you about the
implementation
status who has implemented a version of
this
euron no uranus going away
so who is planning to implement this
christian
molecule
yeah would be nice to have a non-author
implementer to
make sure that that this is actually
implemented for
implementable for people who haven't
invented it
he said do you want to say something or
are you still in the
showing hand with you no i just didn't
get my hand down on time while tapping
okay thank you
yeah okay but uh that's not a
prerequisite to
to adopting uh the document so we do
have energy
implementing this but again it would be
nice to have
uh implementers outside the the author
group
but then one one problem we often have
is that
people to who implement something uh
are being uh sucked in
as authors and so
we we never get somebody who is not an
author as an implementer
um okay so we need to
validate this consensus on the mailing
list but this looks like a pretty strong
result for in-room consensus for
adoption
okay with that i'll hand
over to esco
just time check we are plus nine
so well uh the examples i think because
that takes some
quite some time to go through okay now
about the
proxy operations for gore group
communication
in the next slide please
so as an overview uh well we have of
course group communication and co-op
and this document contributes basically
what
[Music]
a proxy could mean in doing group
communication facilitating group
communication
and its aim is to also address the
issues that were found
well already a couple of years back and
now also written up again
in the group combis document
so these are addressed by providing a
signaling protocol
between the client and the proxy using
co-op options
and responses are individually forwarded
back to the clients in this case so
that's the
basic idea
okay next slide please
so we can take a look at the picture to
see how it works
so the client sends a new cast request
to the proxy
and basically should indicate there in
an option
that it's interested in handling
multiple responses
coming back from a group request also it
should indicate how long
this proxy should collect and forward
responses
so we assume here a proxy might be a
generic one that doesn't know
how long the client wishes to collect
responses so it can basically signal
that using multicast signal link
the proxy will remove this option and
then send out a normal
group communication multicast request to
the servers and
when the responses come back in the
proxy can
basically see from what server the
responses are coming
and it can add this information in a new
option so this is the response
forwarding option
so this helps the client to distinguish
the multiple responses and also
different servers where these are coming
from
security can also be supported here so
end to end for example
between client and servers using group
au scores
and in addition also normal score can be
used
between the client and the proxy as
shown in an appendix
or it can use dtls for that unicast
connection
okay next slide please
so the updates that we did
yeah so we have now a new
yeah i think a new format format change
for response
forwarding option so uh
yeah we basically uh have this
uh alignment in the format that
christian also showed before
sort of a specific transport information
encoding where we use the value one
for example to denote udp stands for
protocol
and also the iep address where the
server
was located and optionally also port if
needed
so that yeah information is then
communicated back to the client
so it can if needed also contact the
server directly
or via proxy using unicast
yeah okay next slide please
so also there is this registry that is
being used so
i already explained the value 1 being
udp there can also be other
values there so that are encoded here in
the table
so that's what we want to add to this
transport information registry so you
can have things like
udp dtls secured co-op co-op over tcp
co-op over tls web sockets
and then also web sockets with tls
um yeah this can normally you could say
the value is always one there because
the
yeah the server responds back in
udp unicast so that would be the
transfer
protocol one but there are some specific
cases uh
for example with re reverse proxies in
which other
transport protocols could be defined
also
for the responses okay let's go to the
next slide
yeah one new thing is that now uh also
reverse proxies are considered before we
had
explicitly only the forward proxy scope
but since many things apply also to
reverse properties we can
take that in i think
yeah there's one item here that i added
a note that
could still be on the discussion so the
initial idea we have is that the client
basically must be aware of that the
server it's contacting which is the
proxy in fact
that it is reverse proxy and it also
must use the multicast signaling option
to signal that yeah i think there are
some cases where it can also not use
that option and the whole
[Music]
proxy can still work as a reverse proxy
this case the proxy then picks the
the time basically how long to collect
the responses based on its application
knowledge
furthermore for the rest for the reverse
proxy uh
the client x acts similar to the case of
the forward proxy
it's only that the encoding of the
request is a little bit different
we also added in obviously that option
that the proxy can
basically it looks initially like a
normal server but it can reveal
itself as being a reverse proxy by
sending back this
multicast signaling option with an empty
payload
okay that's new go to the next one see
we have some more
updates oh this is the example so i
would like to
uh just go over that because i think it
takes quite some time but you can read
it in a
slight material it shows basically what
is added there and also what the values
are in this example case
there's a forward proxy and a reverse
proxy example
i actually would like to also add in the
future an additional
reverse proxy example so that shows a
bit of a different
different way in which it could work so
it's i think there's quite a
broad spectrum of reverse proxies and
how they can operate
and we'd like to show some examples of
that
so now for the security uh of course we
again
depend on oscore group communication
security
um yeah so we can have
score between client and proxy
co-existing as i said in the beginning
with
group cost oscar end-to-end between
client and servers
and then there are some well intricate
things about
the options class u and class e
so the proxy will have to treat some
class u options
as if it was class e to make that all
work
um of course yeah there the point is
what about
future options that that will come in
co-op um so do we already know how the
proxy should
treat those so for that we have a
more general rule added
still a question if this this rule is uh
yeah
accurate or simple enough to understand
um yeah i think it's also written there
in text so what is the
general rule for that not your marker
that you
want to discuss that now or take it at
the end maybe
this was mostly echoing an input we got
from kristen about this
to simplify the text more or less this
way i hope
otherwise the bigger open point is the
next one i think
okay well then maybe move to the next
one just
to see that
yeah this is about the nested oscora so
the idea is to have end to end or score
to the servers and also
was scored between client and proxy
independent from that
um so before
it was actually forbidden to do that so
because there was no
no use case and it seemed complex so
yeah that's why it's not supported at
the moment
in oscorp but now we have a use case
basically
so at least we see that can work
work well in principle
yeah then the question is of course what
what to do with this as a next step
so now we have it in an appendix
[Music]
and it takes quite some explaining i
think to to
to get it right how how everything works
with nested or score
so i think the question is should it be
maybe going to a separate document
that explains this like an update to the
rc
please jordan
yeah yeah i think this makes sense as
you said this the reason why
this was not defined was we didn't have
a good use case
and and that all these
considerations around up the
class human class e options whether how
that changes when when you
when you designate certain information
for the proxy i had one
question though about what is um
so so i mean there is also always the
option that you can have a separate
communication with the proxy
sort of one or score communication with
the proxy one
one with the um with the other endpoint
so what what is the information carried
in the
that needs to be that needs to go the
same
in the same message
so i mean the question is why why do you
need to have two separate
but we need to have one one connection
instead of two separate
connections
the idea was that you want to reach the
the outer servers
or server in the first place through the
proxy for different reasons
and you want to protect and to end but
still the proxy has to
identify uh the client in order to
proceed with the forwarding in the first
place
right okay so there is a good reason why
you want to do this yeah
in one message yeah okay yes yeah
authentication of the clients yeah also
at the proxy side yeah
okay i i think this should be defined
separately
uh rather than uh built into this
this document um and and the analysis of
the
of the the different uh
values of the options should should then
go into that document
i think that uh that makes sense there
also the question is is this something
we should define
uh as i mean how
should this be recursive so you could
have
a lot of proxies along the way
and you protect for each in turn or
should we have a limit to that
we need to think about message expansion
uh if you add
if each proxy or each for each proxy you
add a tag for example and
the message grows so there are a number
of things to think about
and i think a separate document would be
the right place to
elaborate on that
thank you john go ahead
yeah yes i think one
problem that we discussed when we wrote
the oscar document was
collision of recipient ids and sender
ids
you need to have you need to basically
divide it between the different layers
of proxies and
end points nothing that can be solved
but
thank you and christian
i think this collision issue will turn
out to be much
less of an issue than it seems because
the messages
in which the the messages that are sent
all have their routing information to
wind up at the right device and
information that that targets different
device will only be forwarded from there
and not arrive there
we'll see when implementing but i'm
pretty confident this is not
really an issue
and you are also supporting a separate
document on jabber
for the minutes
great okay thank you
right and maybe let's move to the next
steps if no more views on that
so in summary we have uh yeah defined
proxy operations for
communication with an explicit signaling
protocol
using these two new co-op options
and yeah as a next step
what we thought about was also to take
http
in the uh yeah in the content basically
so we could could you imagine that the
proxy can be accessed via http
um so then the client can talk to a
co-op group in that way
so that can actually build on the
previous work of the http to co-op
mapping proxy that's already in rfc
and there's also a couple of other
issues
listed on the gitlab so
we also need to continue with that
i think more reviews that's the standard
end line for these
type of resolutions
i see okay there's two promised already
okay that that sounds promising
christina's carson
great thank you thank you oscar
okay next in the list is
christian again with casual law score
um just to set my pace how are we on
time because i didn't find that
we are plus 14
okay then i'll try try again to make it
sure
um topic of the topic of this is
kashuk is deterministic requests as a
means to obtain cash and loss core next
slide please
stop um what um thing is
um so why do we want caching basically
for the same reasons we wanted
in general in particular here firmware
updates are something where we can
reduce the amount of traffic we can also
hide how many devices are behind the
proxy if they just
um produce cache hits and we've in
research work shown that kind of this
greatly increases
the reliability and latency as is to be
expected
and last but not least this greatly
enhances
um multicast notification next slide
please
the reason this is not trivial is for
one
oscar requests are designed not to be
cachable because generally they can't be
um they can be useful to uh to another
uh client and even if we could magically
produce a cash hit
the client would still need to know some
data of the original request like the
kid the partial of e
and even if it knew that it couldn't
verify that the original
client really sent that request and it
was and it's not handing you
another request just hand so that you
interpret the server as a good response
to that
so that's the the rough setup set
the rough um problem area where this is
coming from
next slide please uh the mechanism
that's proposed and i'm
including parts of the upcoming o2
because
those things just became apparent in the
in the plug test and
i think now this is the best way to go
um but lastly
is unchanged is there is a deterministic
client
that's a role inside the group we define
that's not
pertaining to a particular host but
every group member can
take that role and generate requests
from there
to make sure that these requests are not
do not collide on anything accidentally
and thus commit nones reviews and thus
make all the crypto stuff go boom um
we introduce the request hash which is
which is the hash of the send
the sender key the external aad and the
plain text
that is everything that goes into the
encryption mechanism so provided that we
have a deterministic
encryption algorithm which all of the
current algorithms are
we don't really commit nonce reduce
because we're using the same nouns to
encrypt the very same thing and thus bit
by bit
produce the same request um
this hash is then fed into a key
derivation mechanism that is very
similar to the one that we use for
pairwise and generally the mechanism is
very light
very much like a pairwise request sent
from the deterministic client
to the to the respective server
how this is done in particular is still
open to discussion because you haven't
already gave very good feedback on
this and this just needs to be evaluated
and made into complete
concrete steps the server then
recognizes the
sender key id obtains the key material
and latest there notices
oh that's not a regular client that's
the deterministic client
it can use that hash that is sent along
with that message
uh to reconstruct the key material
verify that it's
it's a correct that the authenticated
decrypt encryption um
works out and verify that this hash
really matches the
sender key aad and plain text that it
that it finds so we have additional
protection against all those
things that we'll hear about in 10
minutes next slide please
that leaves open the question of how
does the client when receiving the
response
verifies that the response is good
because so we can't we can't have
pairwise responses we have to have the
response from the signed by the server
so that every client that receives the
cash request
cash response can be sure that it is
really from the server and not just from
someone else who is member of the group
for that the current way to go is to
have a class i option that includes a
request hash this does not necessarily
need to be sent on the wire
in fact it's recommended not to send
this because it's redundant
but it's placed in the co-op message
before it's get
it gets handed to us core and thus
we get this strong message the binding
between the request and the response
and the client that produced the request
can be sure that
the response it gets is for that
response and by verifying the signature
that is
coming from the server next slide please
there are a few limitations on this of
course
thing is we are trading this for that so
um no new features without giving up
something
um this only works for safe requests
kind of i mean it's it needs to be
casual so it can't just be
you know process blah and then the
result is different every time
it only works for things that don't have
additional access control based on
social authentication
because we lose source authentication
deliberately
we're limiting the set of algorithms a
bit we lose the
chronological seek the the basically the
freshness guarantees that usually you
know score request gives you
because we want to get responses that
were created before
the particular client even created the
request
we lose on request confidentiality
because we want a proxy to be able to
collate
different requests for the same
for the very same answer into the same
bucket
and we do lose replay protection because
that um which is which is
which is okay because we're only talking
about safe requests
next slide please so during the
hackathon last week
marco and i interoperated to the point
where we could
um decrypt each other's deterministic
requests
and if we do a few more steps i'm very
confident that we can even
pass the response for that um
we have comments already from yarn that
we are still
reviewing but once uh that we are still
incorporating into the document but once
they're done
it would be really good to get get a get
a
review from this in kind of in the sense
that
people who are not who did not come up
with this
go through the claims and verify that we
are indeed
preserving all the properties that of
course claiming
in parallel of course we'd like to
continue our interoperability tests and
just give this a bit of a more practical
testing
uh yeah thanks for listening uh that's
it from my side and
comments questions esko
uh yeah just question uh so for the
details deterministic request basically
uh
you cannot really determine the order
right in which request for sends or
yes you cannot prove this one was sent
later than the other one
yes because any any cl any other client
in the group could have come up with
that
request earlier already or could produce
the same request later
they are not ordered but you can
actually for the server responses
that you can probably order uh easily
yes
so i'm not sure that's um
the the ordering of the server responses
is still good and thus you can still use
it for observations and
see what the latest is but you cannot
know that the response you're getting on
that observation
is really later than the request that
you just said
yeah and then not exactly which request
it was
linked linking to but yeah yeah no okay
thanks
okay thank you very much
uh next in the list is ricard
presenting a combination of adult
and oscar
yes hello
hello
yeah so we're just waiting for the
screen sharing but as marco said
yes i'll be presenting a work that's
ongoing about how
oscor and adult can be combined
yes yeah next slide please
yes so just to recap what this work is
about it's about
an optimization for combining ad hoc
over co-op
with oscore and this means that
you want to combine the edward message 3
and the first subsequent oscar request
in a single co-op request transporting
both
and the basically the point of doing
this that uh
it reduces number of round-trips
round-trips
uh required to set up telescope context
and also to complete the first score
transaction with that context
and the point is that
after a client has received the
end of message two it's already in a
position to
derive the actual score context so that
point the client can send
an oscar request and we want to combine
that with the ad doc message 3 from the
client
and the exact contribution that we
propose is
first of all how to signal that what
you're getting here is a combined
request
a combined message uh also the format
and the processing of the edoc
cluster request and we also show an
example of
the data here there they can also
request encode and how that would
actually look
how that combination would look uh next
slide please
right so basically this is the original
way if you would do enough
first end of message one end of messages
two doc message three
and then you derive those core security
context and then you do the actual score
request and response right
so that's that's the original way
without this optimization we propose
um next slide please
and then you can see here the the
optimized way so basically
the client sends setup message one and
gets adopt message two
but at that point it can already derive
those core security context
uh on its side and at the same time it
can improve
it can produce add-on message three
which it does
so then it would send one single request
here combining add-on message three and
that oscar request
and then when the server receives that
um
it can you know take care of message
three and derive the score security
context
and then actually um let's say decrypt
the old score request and then provide
an oscar response
um yeah next slide please
so basically the updates now to this
latest version is that we decided on
a single method for how to signal the
combined message
and that method is basically using an
option a new option which is a serial
length option
class u for score and its intended
use is only for this end of class oscar
request
so when you get such a request you can
you can understand that okay this is a
com
combined erdogan oscar request by the
presence of that option
and the reason we chose this is uh
partly because
of preference expressed during the itf
109 meeting
but also feedback from implementers
because we have
we also have an implementation of this
and got some feedback from
the person implementing that and we also
propose in in the draft as suitable
option number 13
because we want to keep the size of the
option
to be one byte right and the idea is
that like i said the
is a zero length option and we assume in
in this combined request the oscar
option will always be there
uh so we know that you know if we pick
option number 13 the delta here for that
option will be less than 12 and in such
case
um it will be a one byte option and
as a note option number 21 would be
another
suitable value that could be taken
next slide please
so here is basically an example of this
combined edu class oscar request
and where you can see in the top box the
blue box
yes kind of the structure how it would
look so you have the
normal header there with the oscar dummy
method you have on
the oscar option which is with its
normal content then you have this zero
byte
add-on option and following that you get
the actual add-on
payload and then also the
oscor ciphertext so you combine the in
the payload of message three and also
ciphertext essentially
and in the lower part you can see kind
of the message overview
so you have those corruption and that
lock option and of course any other
options
if there would be any yes next slide
please
and yeah further updates within we have
done
so just overall section restructuring
editorial improvements
and since now we decided on a single
method for signaling
we restructured text to suit that better
we also have a better step-by-step
description of the message processing
where you can see detailed steps on
exactly what to do on the client and
server side
so as a kind of an overview what you
would do on the client side
um when you are the initiator and you
would prepare end of message three
and an also request combine those two
as shown earlier and send that to the
server side
and on the server side you receive this
combined request
you can extract and process edit message
three
and that allows you to derive those core
security context
and then that allows you to process the
actual oscar request which is also a
part of this
combined message next slide please
and we did also another optimization
because there was some redundant data as
things
were in the previous version and the
redundancy is due to the fact that
the uh the sender id of the client is
actually present in two places in this
combined message
as things were it's it was both presence
in
present in the cr in the end of message
three
and in the kid field of the oscar option
because those are basically the
yeah the sender id of the client
essentially the same value there
so we thought that um yeah we could
avoid this redundancy
in a clever way so the basically the the
combined record we
request we send only has a porsche badok
message three
that does not include the cr but only
the ciphertext three as a silver buy
stream
and this optimization can actually save
uh
two to four bytes on the wire um so
the point is that when the server then
gets this request since the
endometriosis
doesn't include cr it needs to get that
value from somewhere
but that same value exists in the oscar
option in the kid field so it can simply
take it from there
encode it as a bisting identifier and
revealed
the full edoc message tree as it would
have initially been created on the
client side
and then we can process that as a normal
end of message three
yes next slide please
right and and for the updates we
improved the error handling
uh on our points on the server side so
basically we
detailed exactly what should happen when
the ad doc part of the processing fails
and this included um suggestions for
what error code
to respond with and the fact that the
error should have a content format
to help because you have to disambiguate
in a sense between
the failure on an oscar processing and
failure on an end of processing
so we added some some considerations on
that can be made easier
um so in the case of end of processing
failure
you return an add-on error message and
this is a non-protected response right
to an actual oscar protected request
um so here to be consistent with those
correct see
uh you should use cop error codes like
for sale zero five zero zero for
instance
um and it should also have the content
format application adapt like i said to
distinguish it from all score errors
and but as far as oscar processing is
exactly as in
the oscar rc 8613
next slide please
and yeah next steps we have planned so
the first one is basically to keep in
sync with the main add-on document
there was some discussions on what
points fit better in the end doc
document and what points fit better in
this
edit combined with oscar document for
instance some things
specifically about co-op anal score may
fit better in in this draft here rather
than the main add-on documents
so we should think a bit with with the
work on the main add-on document
and of course any further feedback is
welcome
um that they want anyone wants to
provide
and as the last point uh yeah we got
good feedback
i think from the from the last meeting
and also good feedback from implementers
so yeah from our point of view it's it's
uh
it should be ready for uh working group
adoption at this point
yeah next slide please
yeah thank you that was the last thing
you can see the link there to the right
where this work is ongoing
is yeah um just uh
quickly maybe you could recap so what's
the
yeah the purpose of ad talk
about because maybe not everyone knows
on this call what
what it's doing and what it's for and
the combination
yeah i mean the purpose of that look is
basically establishing keys
for oscore in in a
secure way and the point of this
optimization is just
to reduce the round-trip times and
because you you have an opportunity to
combine
uh the last basically out of message
three with an actual first oscar request
so you reduce the round-trip times
rather than doing ad doc and then all
score you do adult
and you combine one of the messages with
those core and
um you basically you can yeah you can
more quickly establish
communication with oscar in this way so
that's the main point
yeah thanks okay
yeah any other questions
uh there is also plus one for adoption
on jabber from
john and from christian
okay
so i don't know carson if you want to
take it over again on this
yeah i think we we need to do a formal
poll here uh again
um so first of all a quick sanity check
yes i think we can do this in the car
working group because it's
not actually changing the security
content of
uh ad hoc it's just transporting the
attack
message in a corrupt message and that's
within our
purview so i think that that's an
important
um observation and
so i asked the
question should we adopt
what's called adhoc
so i assume that all the people who have
plus one in in the jabber will raise the
hand here as well
okay so we we have one
do not raise hand so that would be
[Music]
interesting
to find out why let's
finish this i can maybe uh explain that
uh
so i thought um yeah there should also
be someone
not not raising their hands basically
yeah that's
uh because i wasn't quite sure
so it's not against but it's just not
not raising the hand
yeah so i i do the real
oppose question so
to really oppose it you can raise your
hand here
yeah i know that's not the case
okay so we seem to have a strong
non-opposition
to uh adopting this so again this is
in room consensus and we need to take
this
uh to the list thank you so we are
seven minutes late so i'm not going to
ask about implementation this time but
please
if you are working on this send a
message to the list
so we can gauge this
so regard your next
as well yes indeed yes
yeah we have 13 minutes to go so
please try to compress your presentation
if possible
yeah i can try to keep it brief yes
start talking oh yeah there we go yes
so again record again so i'll be
presenting here uh
i work on aad key usage limits you know
score
next time please
so basically this work started uh or
discussions about this started in
earlier
meetings like ifta itf109 also related
to lake
and basically the overview here is that
the oscar uses aad algorithms to provide
security properties
uh but there is this forgery attacks
against a
aea the algorithms that have been
described
for instance in this cfrg draft that you
can see there
and the point is that adversaries may
break under certain circumstances the
security properties of the aed
algorithm and there's a need
uh in the case of boscore to consider
how this
attack uh you know impacts the score
basically how does this fourier attack
and the limits a factor score
and what steps should you take during
message processing to consider these
findings next slide please
so essentially to avoid this or to
protect yourself against this you need
to count certain things
so you need to count this q value and
the q value is
the number of messages protected with a
specific key
um and you also need to count the
v value which is the number of 4g
attempts that have been made against a
specific key
which means the amount of failed
decryptions done with this
key and for all score there will be
essentially two relevant counters the
number of times you use your sender key
for encryption
and the number of times you use your
recipient key for decryption
next slide please
and this is a an overview of how you
could calculate these limits
for aes ecm 1664 128 algorithm
and some of these depends on what
probability values you chose
and we chose the same as in the uh dtls
1.3
document you see linked there and by
applying these formulas and inputting
certain probabilities
it will give you a cap like a limit on
the q and b values
and essentially what it's saying is if
your q counter
encryptions reach your q limit
you should stop using this key and at
the same time
if your v counter reaches the v value
you should stop using this key so it's
like limits on when you shoot when it's
not safe to use these keys anymore
see orange raising his hand yeah i just
want to say that john is coming back to
these limits you don't need to go into
depth of those yeah next slide listen
yes we can proceed
so this is just overview what you should
introduce in those core security context
like i said you need basically a counter
for q
and a counter for v and associated limit
and associated limit for v and if these
limits are reached
you must stop using that security
context and you must rekey
so and also by the way this updates rfc
8613 del score rfc because he introduces
these new things in those core security
context
next slide please
okay and also the draft goes over
existing methods for a keying of score
and presently you basically have four
methods which is the appendix p2 of
score you have the oscar profile of ace
you have the end of protocol
and you also have manual reconfiguration
of the nodes which is not practical
and in the draft there is a brief
description of each of these methods and
what benefits they bring
next slide please
open points one point is if we now
produce more limits for further
algorithms which our intent is
um what's the best location to add this
is it in this document or is it in
even some higher level document because
this could be general per
algorithm or it could possibly also be a
per use case like
specifically for you know second point
is what about these probabilities we
assume
would they be different in the case of a
score as
you know what etls 1.3 will define and
the third point is
is there a value in adding an expiration
time to the oscore security context
meaning an actual time limit saying that
when this many seconds has elapsed this
security context is no longer valid to
use
the similar to the exercise parameter in
ace and by the way grouposcore
also does something similar to this when
you join a group
you can get an expiration for the for
the
group security context material so that
it basically expires
at a set moment in time so an open point
is
if there are value doing this from a
security perspective
next slide please
yeah and this is our plan next step so
basically the summaries
we're introducing counting of q and b
values cross score
you have to stop breaking if the limits
are reached and we provide an overview
of current your keying methods
next steps need to cover more aad
algorithms we only cover one which is
the default and mandatory to implement
now so we focused on that
and it also has a short text so we felt
it was more relevant
secondly yeah synchronized with other
online work like edokin lake and
now the presentation upcoming from
beyond also and finally we plan
optimizations for constrained devices
and further implementation guidelines
next slide please
yeah thank you that's it and here you
see the link for the record
thanks rickard
so next is john taking this problem from
a broader perspective even
yeah let's see if i can summarize this
in
five minutes so this is more uh
review of the process that was used for
dtls
tls and quick and the findings based on
that
especially how it relates to oscore and
next slide
so i think that has been summarized but
rickying also have a lot of
other benefits so i think you should
always do
breaking with forward secrecy if you can
next slide so
basically this a80 work in tls
and c4d and quick has four parts you can
see
it starts with inequalities and these
are inequalities they're not
tight it's they illustrate the worst
case
then you have a process and some
limits and these are these are not
objective mathematical objects differ
these are very
subjective as we will see they have
they can be improved a lot especially
for ccm8
then you come to aad limits and then you
use them in the protocol as we can
and i think the 80 limits for tls and
dtls are
mostly nice until they started to do
dtls limits for ccm8 then you start to
see the
limits of these process the next slide
uh first i think this is just
they are aes is basically assumed to be
perfect a perfect fermentation in all
these inequalities but
cha cha 20 is given a horrible limit
in fact in the paper it's assumed to be
a perfect
set of random functions so i think
it will be more reasonable to set ca
equals to zero for that
the doesn't really matter you can move
on
then analysis of the
step um this
the process yesterday used in etls leads
to a lot
of strange things
for example that you should re-key the
ideal
mac like the perfect mac which doesn't
make sense
uh it also gives the
image that you can with frequent
re-keying you can reach
arbitrary high security which is
not at all the case in fact some of
these inequalities
does it doesn't benefit to re-key at all
next slide
and you can basically see that very easy
from there
from the inequality of its benefits to
reiki if it's
linear then there is no benefit
to re-key you can press down the
advantage per key but that doesn't
really matter it's the wrong thing to
measure
if you have quadratic or super linear
inequalities in general
then there is a benefit to
reiki next slide
so and also notice some other things
with the
the values in dtls q equals 2 to 23
and 2 to the power 10
[Music]
uh are a bit high this leads to that ccm
deviates more perfect mac for low v
just lowering these numbers a little bit
fixes this
and yeah i we think a
better solution but we don't
argue that that's the optimal solution
but a better thing to do than the
process
in dtls seem to be to
either just look at the inequalities the
graph from them
or to calculate security levels
based on these inequalities and the
easiest approach seems to be to
calculate security levels
and that is next slide
these have the benefit that they
yeah so here are
some graphs in general and you can see
security level the security level you
need to
re-key before these graphs
drop down to too low security level
but in general the security level is the
minimum
of all the allowed values on the x
axis and the different colors here
blue is the dtls values
and purple here above is if you
reduce these numbers a bit so for
example to
q equals 2 to the power of 20 and l
equals 2 to the power of 8.
and notice that all these are
inequalities the security
level is between these curves and the
green
line up there and next slide and i think
we're running out of time
what do the shares want to do
yeah we're just on the clock uh in case
considered to skip to the conclusive
slide
we'll go back to this during interim
meetings for sure
yeah basically but i haven't
conclude i think we need to go back to
the slide somewhere but basically there
is
perfectly fine to use ccm8 it can be
used for a
long long time without re-keying and
re-keying doesn't really help at all
perhaps we can continue five minutes is
that okay with with
i mean those who can stay couldn't we
stay uh it's mostly me takeo that can
close the session in a few minutes but
as long as we can stay
sure
then i let's go back
uh two slides
here you see how to calculate actual
security
limits the security limits are not where
this horizontal line
crosses the curves but it's the
minimum of everything to the left
then we can go to the next slide this is
maybe
now the two more interesting slides for
for core so this is ccm8
and to the left you see the security
level using the dtls values
you can see that ccm8 deviates a bit
for low values of v that's for your
attempts and also for
high values but in the middle it
it works like a perfect 64 bit tag it
couldn't be
better
and to the right you can see
that changing these
values a little bit so you have a little
bit lower
shorter messages and a little bit lower
q
than ccm 8 or 8
byte ccm behaves extremely close to a
perfect
mac all the way until
2 to the power of 35 forgery attempts
and re-keying here doesn't really
improve the security at
all so we can't my conclusions are
the opposite as the dtls values
ccm8 is as long as you can accept
64 bit tags then ccm8 is basically
perfect so next slide
so conclusions what rich child proposes
is definitely necessary you need these
counters you need re-keying
uh reeking is also good for other things
uh ccm8 is
perfect as long as you can accept 64-bit
tags
and 64-bit tags should then can be
accepted
basically especially for constrained iot
to produce a signal for you you
basically need to send 4.3 billion
messages per second for
68 years and this is very infeasible in
constrained radio i think
should consider using some smaller
values for q
and l then you get the then ccm8 starts
behaving
for a long long time has the perfect
mac and then last down on this slide
some some suggestions
either to do a little bit
different values for the different
algorithms for example 2 to the power of
20 for gcm
ca and asccm
but you could allow v equals 30 for csm8
without
problem at all even a bit higher or
should oscar do something simple and
some simply say
q and v is 2 to the power of 20 for
all algorithms and then also i think
the message sizes should be lowered a
bit
maybe to l 2 to the power of 8 which is
4k which would be instead of the 16
k in dtls
comments questions
everything is perfectly clear
great
there is iron in the queue yeah we
probably don't have time to
to discuss details here but uh i think
we need to think about where
so what what uh what work goes where and
and
where we would put this type of um
if this would analyze some separate
uh documents do you have any idea john
on where this work
would be published and how it would be
published
which working group and so on i'm
not sure it should be need to be
published
here is to give input to how oscar
chooses it
its limits and also i think one
conclusion is that i don't think the
dtls
process should be published by cf
audience
recommendation i think it's quite flawed
and the actual values that are used in
gtls and tls on the other hand are are
quite
good and improved security except for
ccm8 where where i think
the process starts to have limits
but the actual process updating is not
really something for
uh the documentary card presented right
something for
somewhere else i guess yeah i'm not sure
it needs to be
published at all i think this is
recommendation how rick edge document
should
choose the limits for q and d
[Music]
maybe it should document shortly how it
did it but
not in any long text
thank you any other
quick input for john
no okay then with seven minutes over
time
i i think we can adjourn the meeting uh
thank you everyone for attending today
and the discussion
we have a concession on friday at 12
utc enjoy the rest of the week thank you
everyone
thank you thank you bye-bye