this
all right everyone let's go and get
started greetings
i know it's morning for some afternoon
for others and
grueling late night for a few people
this is the deprived session for ietf
your glorious host for the day or myself
brian and
my sidekick tim
so first thing we want to do is do a
quick check on on all the logistics uh
you know eric is our our continuing area
director so he gets to keep an eye on us
for another couple of years
um probably much to his chagrin jabber
room if you're not actually following
along in
uh in meat echo is is deepprive at
ietf.jabra.org
the only thing i would ask for for a
jabber scribe today is is if there are
people who are actually following along
just in jabber with without audio if
if there was somebody willing to to to
channel any mic comments that they want
to make
tim will try and keep an eye on the
jabber room just to double check but if
there are people who are willing to to
do that relay that would appreciate it
and the minutes are going to be kept in
the um in the code emd site
so the link is there tim is going to
keep track of the major action items
uh if people want to follow along in the
minutes and and correct uh whatever
typing errors he has because i'm not
sure if he got his
requisite level of caffeine yet for the
day
before we get too far along uh the the
inglorious notewell
just remember that you know these are
the rules that you agreed to when you
signed up for the meeting and
are participating in the ietf
i will i will state that some of the
bcps at the bottom there are probably
the best material you could read
if you are having problems with insomnia
uh agenda we'll do a quick check to see
if there are any updates that we want to
make
uh before beforehand uh blue sheets uh
will be collected
automatically via meet echo
uh we'll start with some updates of
older current work
move into some of the current working
group business and new working group
business
and you'll notice that we did not keep
them completely separate
because we wanted to intermix a couple
of presentations to keep them adjacent
to one another for for coherency's sake
information on the on the materials that
we're working on are in the data tracker
if you have the materials downloaded you
can simply click on the link and it'll
take you to the magical location for
deprive
the one thing that uh i'll bring
up as a part of keeping track of
of what the working group is doing we
did get
a revision of 76 26 biz
tightened down it was not able to get
submitted
for official publication but we do have
a link sent to
alissa who is the the sole discuss
holder on that so we're we're hoping
she'll be able to review it and
agree that the changes that we made
address her concerns
so within the um uh the next couple of
hours we're going to
talk about dns over quick and um
and we'll talk about oblivious dns over
https
as the kind of the first block of of
time for the meeting
and then the the second uh second hour
of the meeting will will be
more towards discussing the the more
general dns authoritative encryption
discussion so this will include
uh the document that we just recently
adopted that uh paul and peter have been
been uh authoring and then we also have
a new document that that ecker
and a few other people have put together
that they wanted to
compare against the the
pollen and peter's draft so those are
our four discussion topics for the for
the day
uh anybody have any updates changes
modifications they'd like to make
and i think this would be the point
where i'd like to poke scott hollenbeck
if he's online to raise the question
that he had for us
in the in email
scott this is paul hoffman i believe you
can just like
yourself and talk
okay um brian this is scott holland back
sorry i tried to enter the queue in
there but
didn't see anyone get recognized anyway
so just a quick question
if we're going to be talking about the
solution
and that's what i'll call the two that
are up here on the slide could we also
have a quick update on where things are
with the requirements
sure so one of the one of the things
that
that we noted during ietf 109
was um there seemed to be some
discrepancies in
in some of the the statements that were
in the um in the requirements document
and for the most part the authors
you know were trying to incorporate
things that they thought were important
and they weren't getting a whole lot of
feedback from the working group
as best i could tell i would encourage
people who have
topics they would like to make sure get
addressed within the
requirements document bring those up on
the mailing list and we can actually
have that discussion because i know that
there are
there are going to be needs for those
requirements in order for us to do
anything useful with these two documents
that are sitting on the uh
on the agenda list right now so um
i believe um benno as one of the
co-authors of the requirements document
did chime in that he was going to have
time to work on this
um i hope that there are
discussions on the mailing list that
actually help iron out that document
because i like i agree with you scott i
don't i don't think that there's are
ways that we can make a
definitive statement as to which one of
these if either of them
are going to solve the problem that
we're trying to address here
benno did you want to say anything from
the from the co-author side
yeah okay thank you um
[Music]
well yes and no i i i want to chime in
indeed
so i'm i'm more than happy to work with
the working group
on this requirements document um
and indeed incorporates the recent
discussion or the
discussion that itf 109 and on the
mailing list
but also indeed so for
i think um
one step back i also would like to hear
from the working group how useful this
document is indeed
so i'm happy to work and spend time on
this
but also i know scott and some others
really value this document as it gives
direction but also as cuts remarks well
if this
document is not being updated and other
drafts are being developed so what's
what's the use of this draft of the
requirements draft
and if the working group at large agrees
that
this is very useful also in making
progress and
give direction to the to other work
items i'm
really more than happy to work on this
but it's it's
i would like to step one to make one
step back and ask the working group
is this useful document do we want to
have this document i
know that the chairs like this document
i know that some individuals
including myself want i think is a
useful document
but um yeah what's what's the working
group
at large thinking about this document
yeah that's a that's a good point but
we're not expecting the authors to
to to do this lift on their own because
that's that's not going to accomplish
what we need here
yeah so um what i'll do is i'll ask tim
to actually put an action item on
on our list for the chairs to actually
solicit the mailing the mailing list to
raise any points or comments that they
have on the current instantiation
requirements documents so that we can
we can come up with a set of concrete
recommendations for the for the authors
yeah
okay thanks yeah i see a lot of plus one
on the on that
on the jabra so that's good thank you
cool thanks ben and
thanks scott for bringing this up
because you know that is a document that
we need to um
we need to keep um moving in order for
us to understand what it is we're trying
to do yeah
yeah thank you
all right any any other comments or
suggestions changes for the agenda
before we get started
looks like you have paul and peter in
the queue
so paul do you want to start sure
um just two things one is i wanted to
emphasize something um brian you said
that we need
the requirements document to know which
problem we're working on
it's really clear that there are at
least two problems that we're working on
and one of the issues with the current
version of the requirements document is
it's trying to shoehorn things into one
um and but but i think from the mailing
list
very clear some people care about
opportunistic some people care about
fully authenticated so
as long as the requirements document
can cover more than one that would be
great and quite frankly i think it would
be lovely if we had the requirements
document we could then
if if there's one or multiple documents
that are solution documents
they don't have to cover what is the use
case they can point
to the use case document thank you
thanks paul
hi this is peter um as i mentioned to
berno maybe privately a long time ago
to me a requirement document is not
necessarily a full list
of requirements that all have to be met
but it definitely is a list of things to
judge a solution by and this
fits in with what paul said there
there's a lot
in the solution space we probably have
to distinct but somewhat overlapping
problems and solutions going with those
so maybe requirements is too strong a
word
but regardless of what you call it i do
like having
such documents thanks thank you peter
yeah i agree that that
you know it's you know the requirements
documents are kind of the
you know the common terminology for
things like that but um there are other
ways of thinking about what we list in
those documents so
you know i think this is is an important
discussion point for the
for the mailing list and we need to make
sure that that
that we're all in agreement on on what's
going in there
okay if there are no other comments on
that
then i believe sarah is up to talk about
dns
quick
okay just checking your audio again yeah
do that yeah
i suppose you want to go back to slide
one for some reason
yeah okay all right
all your sarah okay thank you so this
is an update on the status of the dns
over quick specification next slide
please
um so a little bit potted history i was
quite surprised when i looked at the
data tracker that it's now
four years since we first proposed uh
dns over quick
at that time the draft actually went
into the quick working group
um there was some interest at that time
a couple of years later there was a bit
of work in the hackathon
and this time last year the draft was
actually moved into deprived and then
adopted in april 2020 next slide please
so more recently there was a
presentation at the last ietf
on the status of the draft and coming
out of that i
think it's fair to say that there was
still some uncertainty on the exact
direction
that the working group wanted to take
this draft in the original version was
specified
only for stub to recursive there were
some questions around is it still needed
given that we have
two protocols standardized for that path
and questions around its performance
we were also asked to consider extending
the draft
um we were asked to think what it would
take to extend it to cover recursive to
authoritative
and in particular xfr and the latest
version of the draft begins to
talk about that a month after that
presentation
ad guard actually launched the first dns
over quick resolver service which has
been running since then and they've
given
some presentations on on that service
um two related
developments last month one is that the
core documents describing the quick
protocol are now in the rsc editor
queues that's going to be published very
soon
and last month the zopdraft also passed
working group last call
so we now have a specification for
encrypted zone transfers on the way
next slide please
so we did a update to the draft last
month
and there were four main changes to the
draft content
the first one was that we had an
implementation section and i've got a
slide on that shortly
the second was that we added an appendix
trying to address the xfl question again
i've got a slide on that
um one other thing that happened after
some discussions with paul hoffman was
that um the very early versions of the
draft had suggested using
port 784 for experimental
implementations
but we now think it makes more sense to
go ahead with a port request for port
8853 which is available so it would be
good to get some feedback on what the
group thinks about that
i think that possibly given some of the
discussions it
might be a little bit early to move
ahead with that but it's
it's a proposal for the future um and
there are some minor updates related to
transport parameters based on some
interop work next slide please
okay so this is a quick summary
of the current implementation status
we've got several implementations
um the first four of these here came
from the ad guard folks who have
wonderfully open sourced all their
implementations that they're using
for their stub to recursive service
so summer and go they've got some c plus
plus libraries
there's a couple of basic
implementations
and there's also an experimental
implementation of flame thrower so we do
have a few code bases that we can play
with
next slide please
what we don't have yet to my knowledge
is
any um rigorous performance measurements
of
quick compared to other encrypted
protocols
one thing i will say is that the
presentations that the ad guard folks
have done
um they've said that they're finding it
performing
just as well as other encrypted
protocols they they support the full
range
and in fact they argue that they think
it's coping better in mobile
environments which they have a large
user base in
and that's all the reasons that you
would expect with quick because of the
characteristics
of the protocol next slide please
um so to move on to the question of what
we would need to do to support recursive
to authoritative
um we think that in terms of discovery
doc and dot are analogous in the sense
that
both can have dedicated ports and they
both use the same authentication model
so it's not a lot of
difference there next slide please
the picture gets more interesting when
you
look at what the current mapping is and
then you think about trying to support
xfr um the current mapping that's
proposed
is incredibly simple it's it's very
clean
and all it does is map a single dns
query response
pair to a single quick string so each
end immediately
closes the stream after sending a single
message
and that means the content of the stream
is is udp
like a minor difference is that in quick
the query id is zero because we can use
the stream id to
identify the message instead but we have
no
two byte length field in the current
mapping
but of course xfiles can have multiple
responses
so this would need to be modified to
support xfr
next slide please
so the o2 version of the draft has an
appendix
where we have a initial proposal for one
way we could update the mapping to
support it
and there are two changes that proposed
for this solution
one is to prepend all the dns messages
with a
two-byte field length and second is that
we
relax the mapping so that we allow
multiple responses on a single stream
so that xfr can work so in practice this
means
making the stream content in doc
more like a tcp connection
now the pros obviously this will allow
us to support xfr
and also because doc has an alpn
and all existing experimental
implementations should be using that
alpn
augmented with a draft version we can
cope with a change in the mapping
the cons are that it complicates the
mapping from that
very simple clean one uh there's a small
overhead introduced
and we have a few new error conditions
that we need to handle
particularly at the client end but other
otherwise it's a relatively
straightforward revision if we go
down this road next slide please
now of course this isn't the only way to
do it there are some other possibilities
ranging in complexity
and if the working group decides it does
want xr support obviously we can
enumerate them
um and evaluate each and decide where we
want to go
um so that's this is something that
we're going to need input
in from input on on the work from the
working group
next slide please
so at this point i think there are three
main questions
to put to the working group
one is that we now have implementation
and operational progress with this
specification at least in the stub to
recursive space
so are there any reservations about
moving forward
with the specification people still
think more performance data is needed
or shall we move forward with the
specification in the hope that that
and enables more experimentation
the second is probably a bigger question
about the exact scope of this
should we do stuff to recursive
recursive to authoritative or both
and if we do both how if should we
handle
xfr support so that's where we are at
the moment
so i would appeal for people to have a
look at the draft and
review it uh and hopefully i can get
some input from the group today as well
on
current thinking uh that's everything uh
if we could
open up to questions that'd be great
thanks sarah john
hello sarah thank you i read the
document it looks really nice
and i would like to comment on whether
on the xfrp's or xmrp's in particular
uh i think i think it'd be really really
nice
if uh this draft covered like everything
that we need to encode in the protocol
now
i don't know if we should like cover
like especially use cases between
different types of servers like stop
records if accuracy alterative
but i think it would be nice if the
protocol itself could encode anything we
need now and i think
xfr is one of the things that we need
[Music]
you mentioned that the problem is with
the multiple messages
that my discipline might return for
transfers um
i'm actually wondering if this is a
problem or i'm actually wondering
whether
uh if the server used uh dns or quake
um for transfer uh whether it actually
needs to send the
multiple answers because the limitations
come from uh
from dcb because we said that on tcp we
need some framing so we added this
to by prefix so we are limited to a
message that has
65k but for quake we have a
different signaling we can use the
stream fan
uh so we can essentially send much
larger
response uh for xfr so maybe
we could make it work with like this
simple approach where you have one one
stream that is used for single
query and single response um on the
other hand i've been thinking about
uh use cases like proxies because
uh if we change this then then the
proxies wouldn't work uh we would have
to
yeah so i'm just just asking whether you
have considered this alternative or
because yeah i don't i don't like the
65k limit
and the question is whether we should
like keep it here in in quick as well
uh yeah so it's a really good point so
in the very
early versions of the draft we uh
included that limit but it was pointed
out to us that
the same thing happened with dough which
was that in principle it could have
supported much longer
larger packet sizes but that again was
limited to the 65k limit for exactly the
reason you mentioned which is proxying
and compatibility
uh with with other transports so
we updated i think it was the o1 version
included a limit on
packet size um i mean of course we can
revisit this
but in in some senses i think we'd be re
hashing the argument that happened in
dough and i expect we would come back to
the same conclusion that
it solves a lot of problems to keep that
limit
okay okay thank you yeah in that case i
just suggest
using this uh like proposed to buy
prefix
and i suggest to do it now so that we
don't have to
handle the incompatibilities with all
clients thank you uh good work
yeah and i agree sorry i didn't mention
it in the talk but proxy and compa you
know compatibility with other protocols
is another good reason why
the current proposal we have would be
quite a natural solution
thanks john uh ben schwartz
hi ben schwartz uh i
i wanted to uh put in a
in a a vote for port 853
udp you know i
we the the dns over dtls draft
is experimental it is
minimally deployed uh and quicken dtls
are as i understand it fully
demuxable there quick was designed
to be able to share a port with dtls
so i think that
we should we should aim to have the
final
port number when we have a standardized
protocol b853
so that was a conversation that was had
off list
and others can probably speak to the
details of the port allocation
process better than i can but part of
the concern was that that would make it
a longer process
if we had to go through that set of
arguments as opposed to
just requesting a dedicated port for
quick
and that ultimately it didn't
make um a huge amount of deployment
difference that if port 853 was blocked
port 8853 might well be blocked but
um it i mean it's something we've
considered so
yep i would be interested to hear what
other people think about that as a
proposal
so sarah i think that's probably a good
discussion point for the mailing list
because
my guess is is that we're going to get
all sorts of different views and
opinions on that
so we'll make a note to discuss that on
the mailing list
thank you
jim reed thanks
sarah i'm a little bit uncomfortable
this idea about the idea of a
pre-painting a bite counts in the
packets that smells a little bit too
much of a layering violation to me
and i'm wondering maybe the best thing
to do here is to
to advance the document more quickly is
just to draw a ring around the ex of our
staff and say
this is still to be worked on and we'll
deal with that later
and just get on with the cool job of
getting a basic
protocol spec which deals with the most
common query response type stuff
and just simply pack the extra first off
for further discussion later
okay so thanks jim um i mean it
it does mean that if you do have
proxies uh translating from other
protocols you do have to then have a
special case for xfr
um which just if we are talking about
applying this to recursive authority it
feels like a bit of a
a walt um yeah i appreciate the idea
that
uh simpler is is better um
but then if we had to modify the
protocol
later to be able to handle something
different we'd probably have to define
it as a different protocol with a
different alpn
so that was why we wanted to fully
assess uh
if we could support it within the
current one
um and and in fact it's just a sense of
that the two by length is just uh
framing the answers within the stream
content which is an honor
by stream so um it's
really just providing additional
compatibility with the existing protocol
um but yeah these are the discussions
that we we need to have about
which direction to take so thank you for
that okay thanks sir
uh watson some lad from cloudflare
uh so my one question i read the draft
and i couldn't really figure out
why this is preferable or what is
advantages and disadvantages are
to doing dns over http
3 it might be useful to have a short
section in the draft
explaining that right yes so
um i think there was a little bit of
discussion about this in the
presentation at the last itf and the
argument is
that particularly for one of the
arguments is particularly for recursive
to authoritative you're then packaging
the whole http
layer around your dns queries when i
i think what we heard at that meeting is
that most
recursive and authoritative implementers
see that as an unnecessary overhead
on that path in particular and would
much
rather have the cleaner lighter pure
quick mapping that's proposed in this
draft
but again if other people have
have other recollections for that please
speak up
right david
hi uh good morning uh oh happy to take
you to the list but i wanted to make a
very short point
about the port number uh
we did um some so sorry i used to be the
uh tech lead for quick and chrome
uh when we did some experiments uh there
a while back
uh not all udp ports are created equal
and getting over the internet
so i might suggest uh like actually just
going and using 443
quick uh demultiplexes by lpn so that
that would allow you even if you wanted
to share both services on the same port
it would just work
i totally get your point about um
you know fighting an uphill battle with
with purists
but uh this might be the best deployment
strategy just without
okay that's an interesting point thank
you yeah we'll take that board
all right any other questions for uh
sarah on dns over quick
all right so i think we have a couple of
discussion points for the for the
mailing list to try and
iron out the the details of what we want
in the draft
so we'll make sure that we get some
discussions started on the mailing list
once the
once the meeting is over thanks sarah
thank you very much everyone
all right next on the agenda is
oblivious
are you presenting chris
awesome thank you um all right good
morning everyone
um here to talk about oblivious dns over
https
this is something we talked about in
this group i think
back in singapore and there's been a lot
of work
uh both on the specification side and
the implementation and deployment side
and so we wanted to bring an update to
the group
remind folks what this was and talk
about next steps
next slide please
so at a very high level the pitch is
quite simply that obvious still
or dns hps
it's a protocol to proxy though queries
between a client and a resolver
such that uh the resolver in this
particular case only sees the queries
and the proxy only sees the client and
the target
and is not able to link the two together
next slide please
to actually use the protocol the client
requires sort of very minimal
information on the first of which is the
name and public key of a target resolver
um like quad one for example
the second is the address of a proxy
that's willing to
actually support the protocol
um the the sort of minimal privacy
assumption that we're making here is
that the
proxies and targets do not collude um
and noting right now that there's no
technical measure mechanism for
enforcing that other than like checking
certs and
seeing that they're not you know the
same entity organization
um but uh that's just sort of part for
the course here
and as i was saying earlier the privacy
goal is quite simply just to
ensure that only one party in this whole
entire system that is the client stub
resolver
has access to both uh the the contents
of a query and response
uh or the plaintext dns messages and the
ip address
um and no other party be at the target
or the proxy is able to link these two
together
next slide please
so the protocol um works roughly
as follows there are more or less three
or there are more uh three or more
entities in the system there is a
a stub resolver there is a proxy there
is a target
and then upstream there's the rest of
the dns or we're just referring to this
as a sort of resolver
and most often um at least based on uh
performance considerations and
performance
results art experiments that we've done
um it's best if the target and resolve
are sort of co-located one
like right next to each other or the
target is itself a recursive resolver
but we've split them out here just to
illustrate that how odo is sort of
built on top of dough next slide please
so the very first step is the client
stub
somehow discovering the target public
key um
there are there is a a mechanism in the
draft to actually put the
key in an hp service record right now um
but this is not mandatory
um and i'll i'll touch on this a little
bit later there are other discovery
mechanisms possible in fact we've
implemented another one
in production as well next slide please
stub and then proxy then establish sort
of persistent hps connections
between each other so this stuff would
connect to the proxy
and then proxy would in theory have a
persistent connection to the target
next slide please and then through
that persistent hps connection it sends
a public key encrypted query
uh from the stub to the target such that
the target can decrypt it
using its private key uh recover a query
and then send it upstream to its
resolver to be
answered next slide please
and then the response flows back
naturally um from the resolver
to the target where it's encapsulated
again with another layer of
sort of application encryption and sent
over the these https connections
through the proxy back to the stub
next slide please
um so there's obviously a number of
different ways we could go about
building this sort of uh system
uh that achieves this unlinkability goal
um the first of which is
you know simply using connection to
oriented proxies like connector socks
the the trade-off here or the the
difference here is that oda was
specifically designed such that every
single query is unlinkable
so a target upon receiving two
consecutive queries can't tell that they
came from the same client
unless i mean the proxy could do
something very silly and that is to say
open up a fresh https connection for
each query
but again for performance and deployment
reasons we assume that to not be the
case that proxies would do same sensible
things
so if you were to use a connection or
your proxy and do end to end https
between
the stub and the target in this case you
would either have to pay that
connection setup time for each query if
you wanted unlinkability
or you'd have to permit some sort of
bounded link ability which is sort of
the approach that
um uh tor i guess dns over tor uses in
that
circuits are established for a short
amount of time you can send queries over
them
for a short amount of time um and then
the circus turned down and then you want
to spin up
and get you the same properties but
again you're trading off link ability
for
performance reasons um and then tor
would of course work here as well it's
kind of in the same bucket as connecting
sox pro keys in sec in fact there's a
presentation in ndss this year um at the
dns privacy workshop describing
sort of someone's experience running dns
over tour for a long time
uh over the course of um several months
i believe
and basically the conclusion was it's
not that bad
um however tor is sort of a very
heavyweight solution for this particular
uh for this particular uh i guess
problem we have here
particularly requires multiple hops it
does a bunch of things to mitigate
traffic analysis
on uh on top of
just regular proxying and encrypting
um and it for that
particular reason it's not sure we're
not sure that it's the best fit here
um also the tour is now sort of widely
deployed in
you know most most user agents and in
most servers
um uh there's also oblivious http uh in
fact uh martin thompson will be speaking
about this at
dispatch later in the week so i'd
encourage you to check that out um
and uh it should be not surprising that
there is a strong overlap between
oblivious hdp and odo
and in fact that's very intentional um
oblivious http is sort of the successor
to odo
sort of v2 to the v1 um
but odo is in its current state um
something that is um will be considered
to be fairly well refined
um analyzed um and uh shipping
um and so while certain aspects of
generalizing a generalized ohttp
protocol are sorted out in particular
you know concerns around
this proxy supporting ohtp and becoming
sort of an open proxy
we think uh odo is a perfectly good
candidate for a v1 in which we can
experiment with
used to sort of build the system
assess its capabilities and its
performance and then when ready
shift over to something like ohttp when
the protocol is more stable
next slide please
so there are obviously a number of
deployment questions that will likely
come to mind
if you're if you've read this draft or
if you've um
or if you're been thinking about this
for a while um the first of which is
uh undoubtedly key discovery uh as i was
alluding to earlier
and i think this will vary most likely
uh by deployment scenario
um so the the aft as i said has a
current uh mechanism for
uh you know packaging up all the
configuration and public key information
that
a stub resolver might use and it
specifies a way to shove that in the dns
because that's our uh i guess that's
the answer to most things these days um
but
uh we also in our production endpoint we
also
um package up and advertise this
information
in a well-known http endpoint um
and given sort of that's likely the
direction that ohdp will go as well
um very well might be
that's that's sort of the what becomes
the de facto mechanism here
um all that is to say that uh key
discovery in particular is
definitely out of scope um similar to
how like
discovery of you know doe resolvers is
out of scope for dough
um uh what we're describing in the draft
is
just sort of the the the the packaging
information
uh for this configuration uh material
um the second important question that
might be on your mind is who will
actually proxy
um so in our deployment um we partnered
with equinix
to offer up uh proxy services
specifically for odo
for user agents that are interested in
and we expect this to sort of be the
pattern
um of the deployment pattern for uh
protocols of this type where we have
good samaritans
or just entities acting on the behalf of
clients um proxying for
well-known targets that support the
protocol or
proxying two targets that they can
verify support the protocol
and the last of which is this uh this
notion of non-collusion
as i said there's no technical mechanism
in place to ensure that this doesn't
happen
um in fact that's very much sort of out
of
the the point of obdo is to sort of put
technical barriers in place such that
people can enforce
whatever sort of policy they want in
terms of
uh you know which proxy they're going to
talk to which uh
target they're going to speak to through
that proxy
um and to make it sort of difficult for
uh
entities to to to do this link ability
um that i was alluding to earlier um
um but of course this non-collusion is
sort of
uh necessary and of course required for
the privacy guarantees that we're
talking about here
next slide please
um so just to give you an update on the
status um this is used in production
um we have uh the target support uh
at cloudflare's edge right now there are
a number of different
uh client libraries and uh proxy
implementations available
um these are uh i mean people are dog
foodiness right now
uh it is uh the proxy is running and
we're actively using it
we're trying to uh i mean we're standing
up this infrastructure
first and foremost to sort of uh do
these performance
uh tests to see you know what is the
actual user experience impact
uh in terms of this sort of proxying
protocol um
we have some preliminary data that was
uh published at ndss this
this year um or discussed in andy says
this year
um that that shows uh without getting
into the details that you know page load
time and response latency are not
quote i should have quotes around
significantly but significantly impacted
and i say quotes because there's a lot
of there's a lot of variables in terms
of you know where the proxy exists on
the path between the client and the
target
whether or not connections are reused uh
appropriately and connections are full
so there's there's a lot of room for
improvement on the results that are
there
um and so we're continuing or we're
continuing to
we're committed to continuing our
experiments with still resolvers
to get more data to do
more performance analysis to make sure
that this is something that's
sort of livable on um i'd also like to
state that
thanks to jonathan hoyland we have uh
backing format analysis in tamron too
just give us confidence that this is
something safe to do right now
um as it's currently specced next slide
please
so the the question for the group is um
uh
given that there is a sort of a interest
in
in in this month i i i'm obviously a
little bit biased here um
there appears to be interest in this
particular protocol people are investing
in it
um it's it's shipping um
the question for the group is is there
interesting to document us as
an experimental v1 as
something that we can deploy live on
um and get confidence in uh before we
move to
some future v2 uh be it based on oh gdp
or
or whatever and with that i will
um pause for questions
um just noting you may hear some like
snoring in the background it's a small
tiny dog
go ahead paul so
thank you chris actually especially for
that last comment i was going to
actually ask on the chat is anyone else
hearing that so
congratulations for your dog it's four
in the morning um
so i think this is a reasonable
experiment but i don't think it's worth
bringing having the working group
working on it because as you said
you've already got you know it deployed
we know that there's a v2 that might be
more generalized and such like that
i think this would be perfectly
reasonable straight to take straight to
the independent submissions editor
as in we thought about it there was some
discussion
it's clearly not crazy we've actually
got some
proof that it's a reasonable security
concept um
the other reason why i'm i think i would
be hesitant to take it to this working
group
is i still and chris you've heard me ask
this many times
i don't know how many users will
actually understand
the advantage of you know like i don't
know how many users there are who say
i don't trust my immediate upstream to
not
collude with the upstream beyond them
particularly when the best performance
is when the two of them
are the same organization um i think
that'll get answered better
from the the general http this working
group work
and so i would say don't bring it up in
the working group but get it published
so that people can take a look at it and
bang on it
thanks
um i agree that uh explaining to users
what one of the privacy benefits here is
tricky um
and i i hope that we don't have to go to
sort of technical details here because
um even as experts i guess
sometimes it's hard to reason about so
yeah thanks uh eric
yeah just comment on that last point
about explaining to users i
i don't expect this to be something that
can easily explain to users either but
we can get
good benefit out of this if the browser
is implemented we can do things without
the users having to understand anything
at all similar to how we do go auto
upgrade today
just so i i like this proposal just my
one concern is
similar to a lot of people chat just the
all upcoming alternatives and such it
seems like
if this just is just a temporary thing
before new stuff like oblivious hps is
very likely to take over then
this doesn't seem like something that
should be a full-fledged adopted
standard track rfc
yes definitely not standard
yeah let's do this right now but it's
the alternative it's getting me
scared maybe this isn't time to do
anything other than just an experimental
just try to get some stuff
in the meantime well this works for now
yeah sorry i i didn't mean to cut you
off um there's a lag
yes totally agree um we are not
interested in making this proposed
standard given that there's something
uh slated to be better oh dp in the
future but
um there is a use case for this right
now um we are actively shipping this
right now
and we want to actively experiment with
it so
um experimental is is great from my
perspective
um so i'd be happy with that
okay yeah sounds good thanks eric tommy
all right hello can you hear me
good hello can you hear me yes we can
all right sounds good um
yeah so just to kind of echo what's been
said i think
experimental is the completely
appropriate thing for this um
if the working group doesn't want it i
think then
it would make most sense for it to just
kind of go directly to
independent submission or maybe sponsor
something to be experimental like that
um however i would as an author
express that i would prefer to see it
adopted as a fairly you know quick
processing
thing for this working group just to
have the opportunity for
the working group to have the reviews to
give input on some of the text
um particularly around any language that
we can improve for dns considerations
considerations into the architecture
since if we view this as
a step towards something that's going to
be
um generalized with oblivious http
and used for dns in the future having
the thought and consideration of the
group
on how kind of best to think about this
area
i think would improve the document um
so if people would like to do it that'd
be great
um i'll also speak as an implementer
that
we are planning on having support for
this
at some point from the apple side and
that would be able to reach a lot of
users
and you know it can be done in ways that
don't require them to have a deep
understanding
of the trade-offs here but still provide
a benefit
to them in their privacy overall so
yeah i think you could go either way
experimental is definitely the right
thing and
i would ask the chairs maybe if we could
get some type of
pull on just interest on the best way to
go forward with this
thanks tommy yeah so so just a quick
response to that tommy i mean we can
we can either do a um
we can either do a poll now or
we can just repeat the poll again on the
mailing list so that everyone can
participate
so um you know my suggestion unless
people really want to do a poll right
now is is we'll we'll make an action
item to
to pull the working group on adoption
and we'll we'll
elaborate on the on on the three primary
options
assuming that experimental is what
everybody agrees to
then it's either the working group
adopts it uh independent stream
or ad sponsored and that the third one
will require us to have a
a chat with our our area director to see
if that's something that he's
interested or willing to see so brian we
could use the show of hands tool that
seems to
even even eric negron said it works
pretty well i can fire one up here real
quick if you want oh go ahead
okay with the toys why do you do that i
just
reply to a comment uh in the chat um
which was that uh discovery is going to
take a long time to sort out
and i definitely agree which is why it
is distinctly out of scope for this
particular document
we are not trying to solve the discovery
problem here um
that is something that specific
deployments of this problem can solve
um future specifications we can solve um
but it's definitely not for this
yep thanks and i always have the opinion
we could adopt something and then decide
never to like do anything with it we can
noodle on it for a bit and realize it's
not you know
um but some people feel that's a
that's burning a lot of working group
time so i i think the opposite right i
think sometimes you get folks really
thinking about stuff like this you come
up with a
bunch of different you know
possibilities so
while we're um rolling the while we're
rolling the poll um
uh acura's comment i am stuck in our rfc
dep ended up for now but i'll just say
what i think about odo versus ohtp which
is i like what's on the slide but
hopefully i'd like to see emerge i guess
we have odo as experimental in case
there is no merge
as we expect odo to eventually be
replaced there's a bunch of plus ones in
the chat too experimental
thanks watson uh ben thanks watson
hi ben schwartz i uh i said earlier that
i
i supported adoption but i just heard a
sort of
change in the the
the context of the discussion with the
the authors you know
noting that there's substantial
deployment already i think that actually
suggests
that maybe this isn't really a great fit
for adoption
because uh you know i think adoption by
the working group
really means change control passes to
the working group and and we would need
to think
you know i think it would be it would be
right and reasonable for the for the
working group to
take a step back and try to figure out
what is really the right
long-term solution here what is the
um you know what is the
what is the integration here with
multiple protocol discovery how does
this
work in a in a world where there's dns
over quick
in in play
uh you know what is how does this fit
into the broader dns architecture
so uh you know i think this would i
would be most interested in
in the working group taking this on you
know as a
sort of to to design a version two
and let this version go out um
you know basically as is from the
authors
so i definitely agree those are things
we need to sort through and that's
specifically why
i think adoption uh as experimental
in this working group is perhaps the
right move here
so that we can work through those issues
um i i don't know
that means i i don't think it means that
we need to be like focusing on v2
um the point of this exercise as i see
it is to
make sure that we we sort of work out
all the kinks
uh for this initial v1 for this
experiment such that when v2 is ready
um we will have a much easier time uh
getting that out the door
but that's right it sounds to me like
you're you know
like basically it's too late for
compatibility breaking changes
in the specification
uh and and that suggests to me that
that this should probably just go get an
rfc number
and and they should just move ahead and
it's and we shouldn't try to mess with
it here basically
so uh to be clear um we are totally open
to handing over change control for this
particular document um
should that be what's in the best
interest of the document um we're not
like just seeking an rfc number right
here we're trying to figure out what is
uh
um the right way to shape this protocol
such that uh it is deployable and people
can live on it and
so i'm not sure i see an issue in that
particular respect but
there's more people in the cuba maybe
and maybe tommy or david want to
specifically speak to that point
so actually chris i want to jump in from
the chair perspective and i think
there's a little subtlety in what ben is
saying there
is the question is is given given the
amount of deployment that you have
do you want a document that reflects the
current deployment
or do you want a document that that is
going to be potentially
changed that doesn't reflect the current
deployment
we expect the document to change um and
and that's the whole purpose of this uh
i we are
by no means uh you know
uh rigid with respect to what's
currently in the dock
be it on the protocol details crypto
details what have you um
so yeah i hope that
is clear okay ted
uh thanks uh the point i got on cue to
to make a while back was
actually on the caching semantics and
what the experiment is going to tell you
it sounds like there's a great deal of
interest from the proponents of the
document
to use this experiment uh to to work out
what
uh the relationship is of this work to
the rest of kind of the
the way the dns works and i think that's
very valuable and i supported an
experimental on that behalf
i want to be a little bit cautious
though in drawing any conclusions
about what that experiment means for a
broader use of oblivious http
in particular because the way caches
work
is sometimes subtly and sometimes not so
subtly different between the way dns
caches work and
and http caches work and i think
one of the concerns i would have is
uh us presuming that success in
a protocol design for the more limited
uh set of mime types and the the dns
caching
mechanism was necessarily
a harbinger of a good result in the http
side
so i i definitely support this going
forward
and i do want us to be a little bit
cautious though in in thinking about
what the results of the experiment
would mean because i think there is a
strong chance that you will end up with
an oblivious doe
that is divergent from oblivious http
um because of the different caching
semantics and in particular some of the
risks
involving the relationships among
different caches
in in the two different uh arenas
thanks thanks that's a
that's a great point um uh there are
subtle differences between this and oh
gttp
such that we couldn't just lift the
results that we get from obdo to ohutp
and call it a win
um we certainly have to be careful and
mindful in how in terms of how we do the
migration
um but our hope is that we can
use odo and track it alongside ohgp as
close as we can such that
the divergence and delta between these
two protocols is very minimal
and um it's not the delta is not due to
any like like a security or
crypto or whatever changes it's more
about like the differences between the
sort of underlying technologies like dns
versus http
um tommy
all right um yeah so first i think
ted for that point i think that's very
true and i think that
difference of scope is precisely why i
think it's interesting to
pursue the odo
experiment on its own now because that
scope is
i think more tractable um in the short
term
to the overall point of change control
um that was being brought up earlier
by ben and paul
i do want to make it very very clear
that
you know if it's adopted deprived as the
working group would of course have
complete change control
over the document over the protocol the
document is
already designed to be versioned
when we've been doing deployments
already
it essentially has a draft aligned
version number
this is very much taken from the
experience in quick
so i think you know that's a model in
which you saw that you know
quick has seen you know a lot of
deployment prior
to it being an rfc and
while i do strongly want to express that
you know we will be using this as an
experiment
and doing a deployment um it's also one
that's versioned and we would try to
keep it up to date and in line with
whatever the working group
wants if the working group was working
on this
so i don't think that should be anything
that
blocks us and um
yeah the authors would be very happy to
have
the beneficial input of the group on
improving the document
yeah thanks david
thanks sorry waiting for the microphone
to kick in so yeah davidskenazi
in this case my relationship to this is
uh my job for the last two years
has been making google quick
be itf quick and if we had said when we
started that effort
oh no no we can't bring this to the atf
because it's already deployed
we wouldn't have quick and i think
quick is a great thing for the internet
and the atf has brought great things to
quick
so not to believe the point and repeat
what tommy has said
we should do the exact same thing here
the fact that this is deployed
is a huge argument in favor of making
this happen at the ietf
not against we discussed running code
at this sdo and so i'm fully supportive
of moving this forward
even if we want to make it just
experimental at first or what have you
but the fact that there are deployments
is an argument to do this work
not to push back on
thanks david eric
yeah just a point i just thought of in
favor of why we want to have
oblivious doe be a thing even if h o htp
is potentially coming up soon it's
entirely
not necessarily likely but entirely
plausible to me that we could easily
have
we could easily find the proxy ecosystem
developed
for dns but not necessarily for the
general solution we
it seems to me that dns is a specific
case where the web is used to having
good samaritans servers show up and
be there without any necessarily direct
income potential and we could easily
find an ecosystem where
everyone who runs wants to run a public
odo resolver also runs a proxy to point
on the other public auto resolvers
versus
we could easily find ourselves five
years down the line that
no one wants to run ohps or proxies at
scale but we have
odo proxies at scale and we'll be very
happy we have odo as a possibility while
we still are trying to figure out how to
make the ecosystem exist for oh2p
yeah good point sir thank you
all right um thanks chris so just as a
note
uh the poll showed 25 people interested
in adoption
and 13 not interested in adoption
uh we'll ask the same question on the
mailing list so that we can get
more participation from from other other
people who may not be able to be in
today's session
so we'll we'll make that as an action
item for the chairs to
to solicit input from the working group
all right moving on uh we have peter
talking about
the opportunistic a dot work
yes hello can you
bring up the slides i am
in the process i see that
all yours peter all right can you hear
me well
yes we can all right um so my name is
peter van dyke i have been working with
paul hoffman
on a draft to basically solve the
working group charter's problems
or this part of them um
next slide please
just a reminder this is an adopted draft
although
a lot of changes have happened but if
you want other changes we will make them
next slide
the terminology slide is just for people
reading this later so we can skip that
next slide yeah thank you um so the
basic principle
of the this draft that has been
unchanged over various revisions
is the unauthenticated case uh if we
assume a resolver with an empty cache
it gets a query for say www.example.com
it goes to the root it goes to dot com
eventually it will learn the name
service for example.com
this resolver having no knowledge of the
availability of dot or any other
encrypted transport
for these authoritatives will ask this
question
over plain classic dns over port 53.
the resolver gets the answer from the
name servers it sends it
sends the answer to the clients to the
client and the client is now no longer
waiting so any magic happens
outside of the brief instant where the
client is waiting for an answer
now that the resolver is done responding
to the client
it goes out and learns whether these
name servers support dlt
the mechanism by which it learns this i
will cover later
the resolver then remembers that ns1 and
ns2.example.com support dot
then at some point another client might
come along ask for mail.example.com
and the resolver now still remembering
that dft is available
will do this query over the encrypted
transport
next slide
so a brief history of this draft the
first version
published by paul tried to do full
opportunistic as
described in 7435
um it's also at the mechanism
where the discovery happened after a
client was handled
discovery mechanism in that version of
draft was probing
the dft port being 853 or perhaps
another port if we decide that's
recursive to out dot we'll use a
different port and stop to recursive
uh that we then found out that the
working group
also had interest in a fully
authenticated
protocol for encrypted transport from
recursive to outs
so in the second version we added a
skeleton
of fully authenticated operation this
was definitely not fully worked out
but the point of this was to allow
unauthenticated opportunistic or
whatever you would call it to be
compatible interoperable with some fully
authenticated
defined protocol we switched to tlsa
here
because this avoids adding another cache
to
to the resolvers which the first version
called transport cache and the beauty of
using some dns records
for the discovery is that dns resolvers
generally already have
a record cache then shortly after we
publish this
the the draft from ecker and other
authors appeared
which uses svcb as a discovery magazine
mechanism
which means these two drafts now overlap
in some places conflicts
in some places and i suspect the next
version of our draft will be
shorter than the seconds but we will get
to that
next slide uh
just to put everybody on the same page
i'll be going through some
comparisons between the two drafts the
first two lines here are about my meme
my pulse drafts and a docs is the
draft that ecker will be presenting
after this so we use tlsa on dns name
for discovery
addox uses svcb on the ns name or
perhaps in the additional section from
the parent
if it turns out parents can and will
cooperate in that
we feel that we could change to svcb
to be compatible with the authenticated
draft
next slide
tlsa is very suitable for dot and doq
i think sarah mentioned something
similar in her presentation earlier as
well
but tlsa is not suitable for doh
the a docs draft that uses svcb
would make all three transports
supported and that is another reason it
might make sense for us to also change
to svcp
next slide
as for authentication we define two
modes
in the current draft for the undertaken
authenticated mode the tlsa or svcb is
just a signal there is no authentication
for the authenticated skeleton protocol
we defined
the tlsa from service discovery would
currently cover that
and for the adults draft if we read it
correctly and i'm sure
ecker will do a better story on that
after this than i can right now
the authentication might be web pki tlsa
from
from a second request
tlsa chained in the tls handshake
etc next slide
here we get to the interesting
differences um
this title is written very specifically
the resolution
if no service is found in the cache
so as i mentioned earlier when
describing the protocol
from an empty cache
the unout case would just use classic
dns over 53
then later go figure out if tls or
the oq whatever is available at all
for the authenticated case of course you
need to do that look up
first while the client is waiting and
the a doc's draft which is i think
authenticated obviously also needs a
lookup first
next slide
now assuming that things are in cash
either from previous from a previous
attempt or
because the lookup has been done before
the client
even can get can even get results in the
authenticated case
we try every encrypted transport to
every server
if all of that fails again we go back to
do 53
for our authenticated case if
encrypted transport is available but we
cannot make it work
we fail the adox draft says you should
try all
and currently is a bit open on the
handling of the full error condition
next slide please
now if you can connect but you cannot
authenticate
then the unauthenticated case just
ignores the failure and
might get encrypted transport that has
not been verified but is still
safe to passive attackers etc uh
the authenticated case in the adopts
case
of course fill the connection then and
here it is clear that's the first two
items being
being in our draft and it's the third
item being in the a doc draft
is a weird split so maybe our
authenticated case should go away or
move into the
adopts draft next slide please
so to recap our document started as
opportunistic
then we added at least some room for
combining or being synchronized with an
authenticated case
when there was no other document doing
that now that the a docs draft is under
active consideration
we think it would make sense if we
remove all authentication
from this document while keeping the
discovery mechanism in
although we've probably switched from
tlsa to svcp for that
and depending on how things play out
in publication it might make sense to
move discovery into a third document
that would then come before both the
unauthenticated and the
authenticated document that is all i
have
and i agreed with the chairs that ecker
would present now first
and we can do all questions after that
thank you
thanks peter
all right okay you're saying this line
it's great
uh there you go perfect
um so i'll just yell next slides already
um so
that thanks thanks for that overview um
uh peter
um uh so um as you said this
that came in a little late um uh
hilariously the draft is actually called
draft for squirrel d private's the
latest because uh when the secretary had
hoisted it out of the
repository they didn't substitute latest
with zero zero but there we are
um so um in some future version of what
we only
will not have latest on the end um uh
but thank you
for the secretary for doing and thanks
for eric for approving that um so
um uh there's always been a bunch of
discussion about
uh about how you would do this and so we
try to take a crack at it
using service b next slide um
and um okay so um i'll actually want to
take a step back um
from uh uh the uh the question mechanism
and talk about threat model first
because i think it's helpful to think
about
a lot of discussion has gone back and
forth but i think has um
you know left us in kind of a confusing
situation um about what can and cannot
be done so i want to talk first about
like what we're trying to accomplish and
then what the constraints are
that i see are and those kind of apply i
think regardless of whether exactly what
you know how you spell
indications so um you know there are
three threat models we talked about i
think
um uh one is um uh you know the classic
352 threat model um
where the attacker controls is on path
and um
um uh an active attacker on path between
the recursive and all the authoritatives
um you know this is like often the
critical calls that don't live yeah
attacker
um then we have a passive attacker on
pathfinder curse of all authoritatives
and then we have some edge case um where
the password hacker is on top of the
recursive and some authoritatives
um so that's probably worth considering
but i'm not considering it here
um so i'm assuming that the the attacker
at minimum can see all the traffic
coming out of the recursive
um and and um and maybe can tamper with
it um
and that becomes relevant shortly when
we think about um uh uh what works or
what doesn't work
um um also um before i move the next
slide i want to point out that like
we're gonna we're in a bit of a funny
state here where um and we'll see as we
get the dns sec where
uh you know where we're tls is providing
we're
although dns is the ultimate backstop
for integrity um
integrity and authentic and on data
origin authentication
um are intertwined with confidentiality
and sort of annoying way
um that will make our lives harder next
slide
so i think the first question we have to
ask is what needs to be encrypted um
and um and i think this is obvious but i
want to like just hammer it home
um generally need to encrypt the traffic
of both the parent and the child
and the reason for that is that um the
sort of common case is effectively that
you're resolving
like example.com right um and
so um uh so um
you know if i go to the if i go to dot
com and i ask for example.com
well that that query reveals asking for
example.com and then i go to
ns.server.example
even if it's not run by example.com it's
run by somebody else that also works
with the querysample.com
um and so both these need to be
encrypted or you don't get any real
value
um and like there are there's edge cases
that's not true um
you know we're asking for like
x.example.com where like x is like you
know
not just uh you know where we're where x
is uh part of some large anonymity set
uh it's not like www
but um basically we know when
example.com only has
uh you know only only has like two like
children under it
um male and wwe like or worse yet it's
just example.com you're not getting very
much value
um out of um only encrypting the second
query or the
to the the real authoritative if you
don't also encrypt the create the parent
so um so i think that that's like a
really important insight to have because
it means that some of the things you
might
naturally think you want to try will not
work properly or will not get you the
value you're trying to get
um um i hear people um i i did see there
was asking
for uh um uh uh questions at the end but
if anybody's like strong disagreement
with something i'm saying
like i think it's like actively wrong i
suppose just dumb like please do pipe up
because like
it's important to get these things clear
um and like and everything i'm gonna say
proceeds from this basic analysis
next slide so okay so the basic idea
here um
um as peter suggested is to use service
speed um so
um uh http is also saying we've been
working generally
um so um so the key idea is the
authoritative has an svcb record
um and the sgt parker indicates two
things one it supports encryption
and two what protocols um you'd like to
support um it actually may serve on
three things
um uh it may also serve um which
form authentications you expect to um
authenticate with but we can um
do that in a minute um uh i probably
should highlight this point um
i think for uh for operational reasons
it probably generally you're gonna want
it served by the parent initial data but
we can get to exactly when this needed
whether it's not in a minute
um but that's definitely part of the
concept here um so once you have this
vcb in hand
you're you connect to the indicated
server with whatever the negative
protocol is
um and you authenticate um as i put it
here in the usual fashion
um namely this is not take a position on
how you authenticate um though again
i'll get that later
um if you um you you if you can't
once you've gone through like all the
different options of like all the
different name servers all different
protocols you support
um then you hard fail uh when you can't
negotiate um uh
uh if the others work hard fail um there
is i think um
one special case which i'll get to in a
minute um where you might fall back
um uh uh roughly that case is that
none of the authentication mechanisms
that the the server
claims the support you support um next
slide
so um here's like the same diagram
except like with you know
um me not bothering to color things in
um uh you know
um that they're tls um and indicating
this uh glue record being sent
um so like this glue we're gonna like a
real point of contention so i'm gonna
get to
i get that in a second but i think
there's like important reasons why you
probably need it um
next slide
okay so right so so what if you can't so
some people
the real suggestion that you can't use
um the glue in the digital data
um so um uh
basically um so the fallback in case you
don't have glue is the recursive
can connect to the nominal authoritative
namely we would receive an ns record
and ask for sc f svcb um
um given that you have no indicate in a
naive case you have no indication that
the nominal authoritative
um has um uh um
um uh has um
uh you know supports tls and so you're
gonna do it over 253 at best you're
gonna opportunistically because again we
have this we have this with this uh you
know we have this uh chicken egg problem
where i i only have the ns record i
don't know i don't know the server that
i'm gonna support connection with tls
actually supports tls
um so like this only like really works
properly in two cases
um uh or in one actually i guess in one
case that has two requirements
one of which i didn't lay out um first
um it only works if the authoritative
zone is dns signed
the sx signed because otherwise um then
whatever information you receive about
like whether it supports this pcb it's
just like lies basically and you have an
active attacker
on on the pipeline it also only works um
like really well
um if uh um
if there's um if it's in if
it's a
if it's a zone which doesn't like not
responsible think itself because
otherwise
um uh other otherwise you're asking for
the so if
if you know if example.com is served by
ns.example.com
then when you connect with that for
example.com you're just kind of like a
hulk you've already asked for it and you
didn't use tls so it's kind of like game
over
um so um uh so so
again i think so i think this is only
the glue is actually pretty important if
we want to get wide deployment given
that we don't have anything like
universal dns to deployment
um yes paul
oh now my
i can't make you live
paul
okay i guess i'm going to move on i'm
gonna pause that behind you on a pole or
bend
hi uh so i think there's even another
reason
uh that makes this insecure which is
that
uh the the ns the name that you are
connecting to
even if it uh is the nsx signed
and has a service b record could be the
attacker
because you didn't get it over an
authoritative channel even if the parent
is signed
because the parent can't sign the glue
records right right
exactly right so the the child assigned
the glue records but you've already
asked for the child
uh right even if it's out of baileywick
there's there's just no
anyway uh i think there's one more
reason why
why this doesn't work okay so
um paul if you ever forgot how to get
water bowl um
i'll shut up i don't let you talk um
okay next slide please oh sorry sorry
can you back for a second um
uh back back one slide uh
um i will note there's one special case
which is um paul i think observed an
email that people aren't going to want
to serve sc
fcc in blue in glue um um however um
currently the root zone actually for
busy serving as as vcb
um at all um but like there's a like as
a temporary fix where you like basically
pre-configure the recursives or the tls
status for all the tld authoritatives um
which
aren't like an enormous number it's not
amazing but it's like possible um you
certainly wouldn't want it for the next
level ones
uh next slide um
so like i want to hit on this like i
think ben was just saying this like
aren't you trusting the parent and the
answer is absolutely just apparent
um and the re and this is the part where
like tls is actually writing integrity
and
and data identification and not just um
um
and not just um uh um
uh uh and and not just uh
uh confidentiality and the reason is ben
just said you need to get the ns record
for the child otherwise you like have to
worry about like the hacker lying to you
um so i'll finish this i'll finish
talking in this slide paul and then go
out of your way um so like dns does help
here in the sense that like
um that even though the ns represents
the parents that are unsigned by the
time
um when you catch the child you can tell
like that you were just lied to but at
that point you've already connected the
server and found out that the ns records
are like bad but you've already sent
stuff over
so um um and of course you've also
already revealed what you're trying to
do to the parents or the parents lying
you're kind of in real trouble
um so basically the bottom line is like
you need to trust the parent and the
child together or like the things you
just came over
uh paul okay so so we
came here now yes yeah okay great sorry
um so it's not about like
people not wanting to serve as vcb
records at the parent right it's just
the infrastructure we have currently has
absolutely no support of
of sending those via ebp and other
mechanisms from the child to the parent
and it's really hard to get new records
into this system you know we're still
trying with things like
cds and c dns key to work around that
system to get records there
so there's absolutely no way svcd will
ever have a realistic chance of being
there
at the parent like it's not my thing
it's not like some people don't like it
it's just
the reality of the the operation of dns
and and
registry system so that's that's one
thing
so then i totally agree you can do svcb
um at the child
um and um and and for
for those name servers that are in
baileywick you just have no chance of of
keeping your privacy and
a lot of the privacy is based on the
fact that your name server
that you're resolving uh initially you
know doesn't leak
enough data and then subsequent domains
you know the thousands or millions of
domain hosted on that name server
you can prevent from leaking um if you
trust the connection you have to the
parent
thank you um so like i have no
particular brief for svcb versus
anything else
um i think my fundamental thesis is
something i think the point of the point
of this light of arguments is that
something has to go in the parentheses
it's not gonna work very well
and so if there's some other thing we
can shoot horn with a parent i've got no
like you know
if it's like svc being coded encoded in
an s record like i got no particular
brief for that
um but i don't i don't i don't believe
this will successfully start something
in the paragraph um
if you want like so i i i wrote to the
list like if you there's only very few
options you have if you want to encode
something at the parent right you either
encode it with the dns key flex but then
you need dns sec
and then gets encoded in the ds record
or you're going to encode it into the
name server
name like you know the dns curve style
from the past
um and then you you're gonna have the
question of whether you're going to put
a pin
in or not for this or are you going to
put the public key in or not and you
know
we can discuss that further on the list
i think
sure i'm perhaps less fatalistic about
people's willingness to like to solve
technical problems about putting this in
the parent but okay
uh jonathan
yeah can y'all hear me um so i i think i
i've seen this in the chat too but i
also i i don't like this idea of
we can never do anything new in the
parent because
that's gonna strongly limit us and
result in
hacks where we're abusing record types
for things they're never intended for
if it really is the case that that the
you know registry ecosystem today is so
uh you know so frozen that we can't ever
do things like this
then let's say that let's go into dns op
or something and say okay we're never
adding anything new to the parent
everything new has to
you know have to work with the child
because i i just don't see a path
forward we all agree the parent is the
right place for it and then
you know we say but we can never change
the parent so we've got to find a way to
get past that and if that means that
there's
uh you know some a number of interim
methods until we get what we want in the
parent that's great
that's fine uh but you know i to me this
idea that we can never change the parent
is just a non-starter for
for any of this
jim
yeah we can consider things with the
problems around provisioning at the
parents
that's one set of issues but the idea we
stick more information the parent will
complicate the zone cut semantics and
we've already been very badly burned out
in the itf with dynastic developed
deployment so we need to think very very
carefully not just about
the provisioning concerns but also about
the implementation concepts
for resolving operate for for people
writing resolvers
thank you thank you okay i'm going to
move on i think
um uh someone easy mute
um okay so next slide please
okay so um uh the second contentious
point was how you authenticate the
resolver um
as you see i'm somewhat dodging this by
saying the usual way um
um uh you know but my basic thesis is we
shouldn't take a position on this
um so um you have the ns record in your
hand um and hence you have the name
or maybe an ip address um and so you
have um and you and so we have
conventional choices for how you
authenticate people once you have their
name and use tls
um um we have a web pki and we have date
um
and obviously for dane um to avoid the
security concerns you're gonna want the
tls extension but we have a tails
extension
um i think in the iseq um so um
um uh i i know there's contention about
about exactly how that should be done
but like it exists
um so uh um uh so i think like
uh i'd be kind of sad if we were i think
it's
a mistake to try to like um you know
nail down this too early um i think
there's an organization made
i know i've seen the arguments for and
against both web pki and and dane
um and i don't want to recapitulate them
here but i think like let's let the
market sort that out
um so uh one important point here is
that um or what happens if um
if like i try to connect to you and i
i'm i'm more cursive and i only sport my
pki
and your result and you're authoritative
you only support date and that looks
like a
misconception there's no way to
authenticate that so um um and so
we don't know and so and so um i don't
want a heart fail because like actually
it's really cool
um but i don't want to fall back because
otherwise we have an attack problem um
so i think we need some way for the
authoritative to indicate what
credentials it has um uh and the idea
would be
that um you know the authoritative would
say look i support
what pki and the if the if the recursive
only supports
then um then you don't treat that as a
heart fail um and i think uh robert
evans suggested that what you do is you
under those circumstances those
circumstances only then you fall back to
opportunistic um because you might as
well do tls and you just don't follow
the search but the point being a secure
indicator that you can trust that says
you were never going to validate this
sir as opposed to just like discovered
accidentally you couldn't validate the
cert
um uh next claim
um right sorry i forgot the slide here
here new
this is also potentially useful for like
retrieving um this vcb and ns records
um uh from the child next
right so i mean like and the bottom
weight of the reason about this is it's
like tls all the way down
right um so like um
uh you know th this this works if
um the certificate like is good and um
you have some some
strong way to get to you know some
reasonable way to understand what the ns
records look like
either because you got them from a tails
connection initially or because they
were somehow dns signed
and like again do you have some reason
why we trust svc
records um and so as long as you like
basically
um you know start with start with
something secure then you can continue
walking down
the t the changes in tls where there's
things you're dna second method or not
so the question is how you start with
things that are secure um
and so like there really are like two
main options um one is
you have some sort of um thing you've
retrieved over um over j53
uh three main options one or different
three anybody has a dns sec
um one of which um you retrieved over
tls um
and so you're trusting tls um um whether
or not there's dns sect and the third is
something is manually configured and i
imagine we're gonna need some
combination of each of these three
um but the point is once you get into
some secure loop um then you're good to
go
um and so obviously like you know um at
the very top um you know things are
getting manually configured whether
there's dns sect or tls but then as you
start moving down you can
once you get into a secure zone your
security as you continue downward
um next slide
right um so i guess next steps um so i
think you know
peter kind of keep this up um um uh you
know
um we think this is an interesting way
to proceed um we've been interested in
seeing the working group um
take it up in some fashion um uh with
the document mechanics to be determined
i think by the chairs
um um i think it's been floated um that
um there's some
interesting ideas from anna's tooth you
might try to pull in um as i said i
think you know um
if you had to ask my co-authors may want
to speak for themselves
but um if you had to ask what i think
the important points here are
um i think it's first of all um you know
understanding uh where the indicators
have to be and understand how to read
about security
um and understanding how to think about
like um
what uh you know what what you're trying
to say from the from in these records
about
what i want what i want the recursive to
do and what kind of authentication i
support
um and i think like the exact mechanics
of like what how it's spelled i don't
actually care very much about it
i don't think of my collaborators i know
i'm had a lot to do with svcb so i
imagine they think svcb is the right
answer but if it does not be the right
answer i don't think it's going to like
make us cry um but i think that the the
key point is that the data flow
architecture
is important um so i'm done now
oh i'm sorry i'm not uh i'm not done ha
um let me just finish what i was going
to say
um so i think there are three
contentious issues here um there's dean
versus web pki this dot versus doe issue
um
and our position on both is like what is
why take a position um you know we have
plenty of
ways to indicate this um let the market
sort it out um i think it would probably
be better
if we knew for the answer for one of
them was like like definitely better
like we we choose but like there's no
particular reason to given that we have
ways to indicate both and we can
negotiate them
now i'm done thanks eric
all right so i think what we want to do
now is
is we've got roughly 20
25 minutes uh and and what what tim and
i would like
to see is discussions over both of these
drafts
and how they relate to what what the
working group wants to do and how we
want to go forward so
um with that i'm going to open the queue
up uh first up is
kirsty payne hi thank you
um yeah it's just some clarifying
questions actually on the presentation i
just saw
so um could you just go back a couple of
slides
i think it's called like how security
works or something
is the title of the slide
thank you uh yeah so i just want to like
kind of clarify here you've got a couple
of things where like the connection is
secure if
something's okay it's like sent over tls
or signed by dnsec
and just to make clear that those
provide different security properties
obviously so i wouldn't want to like
bundle them in together
um and then just going right back to i
think maybe like one of the first slides
you talked about the threat model
um and talking about how you would
include
certain groups of attackers but not
others i think you said
considering a passive attacker between
recursive and some authoritatives is
worth considering but not here
so i guess just a question like how do
you make that value judgment
what is the threat model that you're
working to and how or like where would
you consider that
if not here and what security do you
lose by not considering that
that attacker so just a couple of
questions really about the security and
the threat model
thanks sure um so it made taking the
second first
um so that's a that that attacker is a
strictly weaker
attacker of the attacker we're
considering um so i think what you're
losing is there might be some things
which work against that attacker but not
others
um so as a concrete example um like i
argued that you needed
to um that you needed to have security
between both the
the recursive and the parent and the
recursive of the child but um
if for some reason the attacker could
not interfere with your connection
between the between the cursor and the
parent and was not on path for that
but was requested it was was on path
between the records of the child then
you like wouldn't need to lost
connection with your cursive from the
parent because
they'd be off path um so um but i think
like trying to figure out who has who's
that situation is like super hard to
reason about so i just don't think it's
worth it
um the um um you're absolutely right um
that uh that dnsk and tls are providing
different
different values here um uh uh
you know um this is what i was saying
earlier about the sort of confusion
about like
exactly we're trying to achieve um but
for the pr um so
um i'm not primarily interested in this
discussion about providing
um integrity for like any records other
than or data or justification for any
records other
than the n the ones required to like to
get tls going
um so i assume that the properties you
get whatever properties you get and
dnsec is providing or not providing
security for all the records but for the
purposes of um
of authenticating the ns record and the
svcb then
like tls and nsl and dns are like
roughly equivalent in this set in this
setting
okay few points uh one i said this in
chat
i think we uh this is really about the
first draft uh
in the of the two what's missing from
that draft in my view and what we
we had in the previous iteration was a
way for authoritative servers to get
some
traffic on a new protocol without
guaranteeing that that protocol has
uptime
that's the full off time of the service
the current draft as i understand it
makes the
choice between uh authenticated and
unauthenticated a choice of the resolver
which means that there's no safe way for
an authoritative
to deploy a a new protocol
in public get it get some traffic on it
get it tested
before they they give it their full sla
uh okay point two requirements drafting
is really hard i think
this this discussion really points to
the difficulty of formulating a
requirements draft that
that gets to what we need for example we
need to
do we need to figure out is it a
requirement not to require
changes to the epp specifications
and icann registry agreements and all of
that stuff
i think that's a real puzzle
and the third point is
i think there is a path forward here
that
that sort of blends a lot of the ideas
that have been coming
in uh roughly i think it looks like
we use some kind of ds hack to encode
just a flag
that says this child is is playing this
new game
um you know go ask go ask the child
for the for an svcb record to find out
what you're supposed to do
and that's
that's opt in it costs latency but only
for the zones that opt in to play the
game
uh and then eventually we get out of
that extra latency
by uh by
putting svcb records in the parent and
uh having the parents also do tls
or um in the case of the root zone md
zone digest uh that also
only works for out of bail eq name
servers but i think that that sort of
lays out a roadmap where we can people
can start getting protected
now or soon and in the
very long term we can remove the
performance cost to make that more
attractive
all right thanks ben um i believe
peter's in the queue to respond to your
first point
uh actually this is paul um i've been
chatting in the back so
i'll take it uh so ben thank you uh
uh yes we on on your first point we
totally
missed that and of course it should be
added um
the the ability to do this incrementally
is
hugely important um and so yeah
and again we're in the very early stage
please don't think that if we didn't
include something is because it's not
important it certainly is
um on the general point
of adding records to the additional
section and the parent
i think that that's going to be a real
issue
and we on the opportunistic side
don't really care how it comes out we're
happy to follow whatever the working
group does on that
whether and it may be as ben just said
we don't do it at all we do it as a ds
or whatever but to be clear
um doing anything adding anything
to the you know the additional section
takes not only
unfortunately contracts and stuff like
that it also takes updated software a
lot a lot of authoritative software
isn't prepared to add willy-nilly to the
additional section
um but having said that i said this in
the chat
i i believe if that's the way we want to
go we should go that way we shouldn't go
like oh it's impossible
this will never happen um i think
getting
this kind of encryption is important
regardless of if it takes a while
and giving up now is silly and on that
last point is um just to be clear what
peter said
in the second slide is since we do have
one working group document now
where we we slammed one idea of fully
authenticated in and now ecker has a
much
you know much more full explanation
including a use case um we're totally
happy to split it out again and i
i would you know it's up to the chairs
but my recommendation
to the working group is that we actually
work on these two
in parallel and not jam them into
um one document even though
it would be easier for implementers if
we only had one document i it looks to
me like the two documents are going to
move at different speeds
so however the working group wants to go
on that that's just fine
thanks
thanks paul uh daniel
dkj
if you're talking we can't hear you
there you go here we go sorry about that
that's probably too bad can you can you
hear me now apologies
yes we can i wanted to follow up on
uh uh what then and um
paul we're talking about about how we
get to the deployment phase
if it's if the signaling is a hard fail
um
that's a problem um uh
this requires more thinking about how
like what
what if if signaling is not a boolean i
don't believe it should be
because it because people will be scared
to deploy it then
it we're going to need to think clearly
about what that intermediate state is
in other systems it's often a report
only state
but then that requires a reporting
format and a reporting mechanism
so people can learn uh you know when
there have been failures and figure out
what the
what the failures are we see this in mta
sts and a bunch of other
situations so
we've kind of glossed over that in these
two pieces i actually think it's a
significant amount of engineering work
and i want to make sure that we keep
that on the table because if we don't
offer an intermediate option between no
signaling and signaling means hard fail
i can't imagine anyone turning it on
all right thanks uh next up is kunit
hi can you hear me yes we can
hi this is puneet here from google
speaking more from the google public dns
position
so i agree with dkg i was going to make
the point that
we do need the transitional support for
resolvers to be able to move from doing
no
auth dot to uh doing partial or dot
right opportunistic or however we define
it
and one of the things as i listen to the
presentations i think
i don't see much of a conflict between
the
first document and the one that ekr
presented
i see the one which ekr presented as
more defining the signaling protocol and
how you get there like all the
information needed to do
secure transport while the first one is
more focused on the
recursive so i think if we look at it
that way i don't see
overlaps there the
paul and peter van dyke's document
should really
lay out the the user profiles or the
authentication profiles one
a recursive resolver could use to
connect and
uh yeah that's that's all right now
all right thank you uh robert evans
hi this is robert evans uh i'm the i'm
from google and i'm the tech lead of
google cloud dns so here on behalf of
the authoritative server
uh interest the the a doc proposal that
eric is working on is very interesting
to me
and our i have
been focusing primarily on the
authenticated case and i wanted to point
out that
the idea is for there to be a number of
paths to security
the incremental adoption of svcb based
tls negotiation provides a road security
and as as uh
if if the elements if we go back to the
slide that had the uh the security
there's three points there that are
important which is that
if the if the tls certificate checks out
and the ns record set is validatable and
you have a secure signal of sdcb
then that makes a secure connection how
we get to achieving
all three of those elements could vary
it could begin with
a ds signal in the parent or it could
begin with doing a do53 query for svcp
et cetera et cetera et cetera over time
as more elements are adopted or future
drafts
provide for paths like a ds record that
has a specific format
or a parent svcd with all the
appropriate proposals
adopted by the right folks then the
security increases
um so the last point i want to make is
we can have
fully secure from an integrity point of
view
sjcp negotiated tls connections today
without parents as long as there is dnsx
signatures
for the nsr set and the svcb are set
at the name server zone
thanks robert jim
thanks brian i'm a little bit concerned
of the discussion we've been having over
the last few minutes
we seem to be looking more at solutions
and i think that might be a little bit
premature because
i'm not sure we've had a proper
discussion of the risk and threat
analysis
and have we got a clear understanding of
the threat models and what needs to be
done about them
before we start talking about solutions
i think we might be jumping ahead of
ourselves here a little bit
thanks jim and and i believe that's
going to play into some of the
discussions that we have on the mailing
list about the
you know the quote-unquote requirements
document and and does it need to have
some kind of
of threat analysis to back up the the
rationale for the items we put in there
brian i mean i think some of the stuff
that sunday e dot operational
considerations draft
isn't really all that well aligned with
what we've been discussing today
okay uh paul
uh hi just since a couple people in the
last couple of
my comments have said we might need some
way of reporting
especially like if if a authoritative
server somehow is a signal saying
i do this and then they actually don't i
just pasted a
link in the chat for a draft that will
be
being presented at dns op um i guess
that's two days from now
um that's not yet adopted by dns off but
um i think it will be of interest this
specifically is for
general reporting from recursive to
authoritative and even though
the use case in that document is mostly
about
dns sec failures it certainly could be
used here as well
so i'm not as concerned about a
reporting mechanism
and i'm not i'm certainly not concerned
that we would need our own reporting
mechanism
i think a generalized reporting net
uh should be assumed once we work on it
a bit thanks
thanks paul chris
uh yeah thanks i just wanted to follow
up on jim's comment and say
yes totally agree that it's important to
nail down the threat model and make sure
that we're solving the right problems
um and as an authoritative server we're
interested in like figuring out what the
threat model is
in particular and also sort of figuring
out what are viable solutions within
that front model
do not care whether or not it's svcb or
whatever
um as eric was saying during the
presentation
um we just want to see this problem
solved
hi chris eric
i mean i i i certainly agree that's
important to understand the threat model
on the requirements which is why i
started without my presentation
um we tried to lay that out um in
our document um at the beginning um
which
is not to say we did so successfully um
i guess i'd be interested in seeing
um you know uh uh in
in some form which is again up to the
discussion that shares
um you know some way to workshop that to
get the point we have agreement that we
have the right threat model um and if
our
our test could be helpful there that
would be of course great
um um so i guess i guess i guess my
question is i don't know
i personally am not quite sure what else
needs to be done on threat model um
uh so uh um someone else to weigh in i'd
be great
so it's just just from my own uh
opinion eric you know i just want to
make sure that the other people in the
working group
agree on the model that you laid out
and and if not you know what
modification do they expect
or or want to see
yes definitely all right
ben ben schwartz i
i agree with the threat model on ecker's
first slide
uh i do think that we should be clear
that our
our aspiration is to solve the the whole
thing
and that we are going to produce
some solutions that solve um only part
of it
uh the essentially matching matching the
weaker threat models that ecker
also mentioned
thanks ben all right
i don't see anybody else in the queue
so i'm going to ask tim to run through
the
the action items that he's been able to
recover from them from the meeting and
maybe you can get some corrections on
these if people see anything that's
missing
yeah sorry thanks thanks brian um the
three that i had was um
recommendations for the authors on the
requirements document
um via scott um
more interest in the oblivious http work
um with the working group on adopting or
not i think we're gonna take some of
that to the mailing list
and work with the um peter and paul
on facilitating new edits for their um
opportunistic draft i don't think i
think that's everything if i miss
something please
yo
uh paul paul paul's ready to yell i
i prefer not to yell there's somebody
sleeping in the other room it's still
before six o'clock here
um i think a question for
a next step is where do the requirements
get specified so
tim you had that as as you know like we
need to work on the requirements draft
but um it could either be
that there is the unauthenticated draft
talking about its requirements and the
fully authenticated draft talking about
it
or they go into their into the
requirements document
the worst possible case is that we that
there's three documents talking about
um requirements yes agreed so
the chair should figure that one out as
to where it goes uh
i'll speak for peter here we're happy to
throw our requirements over to the
requirements
document as long as that document's
going to get worked on which
it hasn't been lately on the other hand
i think that it would be better to have
them
in that document you know next to the
fully authenticated ones
yes i think it's good to put it all in
one place we brian and i weren't sure if
like even if we did
a lot of work in the requirements
document it would ever get published
rather than just be a working group
document right um
so that was still something we were sort
of chewing on but i agree with you on
your points there so that's something we
will have to take back
but mostly what we're trying to do is
get more feedback from the working group
um per scott's note on helping them try
to figure out where to go with that
and the queue vanished the queue
vanished any other
comments on on tim's list of action
items i think the one thing that i was
curious
about maybe eric's going to talk in is
uh
adopting the document that he talked
about today is that
what you're asking eric um i mean i mean
i'd be fine with that um i'm also fine
with i'm also fine with like
not nothing right away though um i guess
i like to understand i guess
more importantly like you know more
importantly than exactly what documents
get adopted let's understand how we're
going to move forward
and in particular like i don't want to
spend like the next like nine years
workshopping requirements i want to like
get solutions
and um so i'd like to understand what we
need to do in order to get the solutions
and then um and and then what documents
we're going to use to start with those
and so if people think that like i guess
what i would say is if people think the
requirements
like laid out in our document are like
roughly suitable and that the solution
is like
in vaguely the right shape then like we
should probably adopt that and go
forward
um and if they if they think that those
are wrong they're likely to understand
what
what would be right um
yeah yes and i think i don't want to
workshop requirements forever either i
think that's a very good point i don't
think the working group does either but
um so thank you
all right so do we have any other last
minute comments
in the two minutes and three seconds
that we have
okay so what um tim and i will do we'll
go back we'll have some discussions um
on on what what how to drive those
requirements
discussions within the working group and
we'll get the other action items kicked
off
if there are no other comments we'll
give you a little bit over a minute back
so that you can prep for your next
session
thanks all for participating and enjoy
the rest of your week
yep thank you guys thank you all
you