and i think we can get started
okay do you want to take it pete or
should i
i don't know if you can hear me
beat
and now i cannot hear you
something went wrong
you started everything i can hear you
francesca but i can't see you
everybody's talking but pete i can't
hear you i don't know if other people
can hear you pete
no so far we've not been able to hear
pete
it might have lost sound let me ping him
i was able to hear pete earlier but he
doesn't see me talking now
just looking confused i appear to be
deaf at the moment very thing now we can
hear you
it was a little little faint but
we can hear him but he's probably
gonna come back
he looks happy though that's nice
you look happy too but it's only the
beginning of the meeting
let's wait a little longer and i will
see
pete is back
let's see if he can uh connect to audio
otherwise i will get started then
can you hear us now pete
now i can't hear him i don't know if
so
okay but let's get started um i would
like to know if pete can hear me hear me
oh now you can i can okay okay
can you guys hear me now yes yeah
oh joy okay
okay do you want to take it or should i
take the introduction
i'm happy to do the intros um
sounds good so welcome everybody it is
dispatch time uh
so we will since we are still early in
the week note well
please be aware that if you are new to
the process or even if you're not new to
the process
you should read over the bcps
which define the processes and policies
of the ietf
and if you are participating in this
working group
that means that you are agreeing to
follow those policies
please make yourself aware of them there
are lots of them with regard to
how we behave in working groups and
there are lots of them with regard to
how intellectual property plays in
please
review
so um if you don't mind please have your
video
off unless you're uh presenting or
speaking
um and definitely mute your microphone
unless you're speaking uh that will help
both folks who are
listening and keep your bandwidth pretty
low
um if you can use a headset please do
that will stop echoes from happening
the blue sheet is automatically
generated from the list of folks
so there's no need to write your name
down anywhere we'll
check that with the meat echo things and
uh the chat that is
taking place over in the chat room on
meat echo
is also taking place on jabber you can
connect to both and get to the same
place
and there are some urls which you can
find to
get information on that
uh if you would download from the
agenda page you'll find
most of these links you'll find this
presentation it will have all of these
links
and so if you need to get to any of
these places those are all the nice urls
and we'll talk about the incoming and
outgoing chairs
in a moment but those are links to email
addresses as well
so remember that gen dispatch does not
um adopt drafts itself unlike other
dispatch working groups
we only recommend net steps for new work
which means we're either going to
recommend directing
work to an existing working group
proposing a new focused working group
proposing that an ad sponsor document if
that
ad is willing ask for
additional discussion or community
development if that's required before
making a recommendation
or saying outright that we don't think
the ietf should work on a particular
topic
please do keep these outcomes in mind as
we have discussion
we're looking for answers to the
question of what do we do with these
proposals
uh not necessarily arguing about the
contents of the proposals themselves
those cannot always change after we
decide
how to dispatch something
so uh we will see your name if we're
participating in
meet echo but for those folks who are
only doing audio please do state your
name before
you begin speaking um again
keep the dispatch question in mind that
is the key so if you're making a comment
always useful to end that comment with
and therefore
i think we should do x with the working
group or do
why with the document or whatever it is
um please try and keep your comments
limited so that everybody gets a chance
to speak um
the buttons there if you want to join
the queue just push the little hand
button which is below your name on the
left side of the screen
when you are given the floor by the
chair
please unmute your audio and
unmute your video if you want to show
your smiling face
so that you can send that we don't
control turning the video on and off
um so please do so at your leisure
um and then the other controls that
little um
uh chatty button is the jabber if we say
that we're going to do a show of hands
up on that top row of buttons the one
that looks like a little bar graph
is the show of hands tool and so we'll
ask you to go there
next so uh let's do a little agenda
bashing
um we've been in the middle of the intro
and administrivia
so you don't get to change that um but
we have two items for the agenda
uh john clemson is going to do a quick
presentation and discussion on possible
futures for
rfc 2028 and then uh fernando
and keith moore are going to do a
presentation on
uh general more general than we've been
talking about uh previously
diversity inclusiveness in the ietf and
then we've got
plenty of time to either extend those
discussions if they get long
or to do any other business and then
we'll do a quick conclusion do
does anybody have any bashes to the
agenda
things they want added etc
listening listening john corrects me to
say that
his is not a presentation but a rant
that's okay
um okay so this is our agenda
we will go forward as such
um is that the end of our
first round of slides is it time for
john
and francesca is clicking around good
sign
slides up
[Music]
all right you're up to bat john i'll
meet myself
okay in in the process of working on
something else i
think the rfc editor issues
um i had occasion to look at
uh at rfc 2028 for the first time
next slide please
in uh in many years not quite
since october 96 but close
this is a 20 it's a quarter century old
document
uh which has substantively
except for intellectual property rights
issues been uh
unchanged in the last quarter century uh
except for the iatf llc terminology
uh and uh unsurprisingly many things
have changed
in in those last 25 years um
so the question i would oppose today is
a little bit different from the
uh usual one for gen dispatch and the
pete summarized earlier
uh there is no draft to replace this at
the moment
uh i'm uh i'm looking for a sense as to
whether
there's uh there's any way to move
forward on this whether
people care uh and uh
and if uh if the answer to both those
questions
is yes then uh then it's responsibility
of either this group
or the ad to uh to solicit volunteers
and uh and figure out how to move
forward uh
next slide
uh so uh as i said in the process of
looking at this
i found a uh a number of interesting
problems the document contains
normative pointers to things which the
authors believed were being worked on at
the time
they may have been correct but those
documents have never been completed and
published
um the document is a particularly
interesting comment
still believes the ietf chair is
appointed by the iab
which would make this working group uh
a rather interesting situation uh and
there may be some
uh iedf llc loose ends
um uh including things which
point to this document uh and then point
elsewhere
for details that aren't there that's
also true of a number of other places in
this document
where it's pointing to things for
details which are not there
along with documents along with pointing
as i mentioned earlier documentaries
don't exist
um it claims the secretariat not the llc
is responsible for uh maintain the
formal
public record of uh of what's going on
um that
that may be true in practice but whether
given the llc's organization that's true
in
uh in theory is an open question
and again those are just examples the
document
is relative to actual contemporary
practice
contemporary organizations and how
things fit together
uh in uh in relatively bad shape
uh so uh next slide i think there is no
next slide
ah yes uh
uh the document predates as i say it's
old
so it predates the current chart of the
internet architecture board
uh the current charter of the isg uh
and uh and all the changes the rfc
editor function
and its relationship the iatf
uh to say nothing of those changes which
are
further changes which are now under
discussion um
so as i say document which is not a good
shape
document which he we have told other
organizations
to refer to and trying to understand the
iatf what's going on in the ietf
uh we're probably still telling
newcomers that uh and
and it just doesn't reflect contemporary
reality uh next slide if i'm not
finished
ah uh so possibilities
uh one possibility is we've been
successfully ignoring this problem for
at least two decades
and we could continue to do that uh
second possibility is make it historic
erected tombstone
and tell those who look for it either
where to go instead
or they're on their own those two
options might be equivalent
um and uh the third possibility
obviously
is to revise and replace the thing
that's not probably not a small
rewriting task
because some of the things one might
replace it with our
are probably controversial and uh and
there may not be agreement of what to
say
uh next
ah that's where i run out so i didn't
need 20 minutes
um back to you co-chairs and open for
discussion
okay so well let's open the floor
and you know and again please
um we're overtly looking to dispatch
this thing so
let's talk in those terms
thoughts anybody
andrew go right ahead
uh well firstly thank you john for
succinctly setting out the problem
uh which has really helped what
impressed how quickly he managed to do
that
um well on your three
uh so substantive options um
i i guess i'm struggling to see
any viable option other than revise and
replace the thing
because it would seem to me to be more
for a standards body
to to have set some standards of how it
behaves
the the just plain wrong um i would have
thought that undermines the whole
premise
of everything else the itf does dare i
say it if it can't even get its
procedures right
um not without and that's not
trivializing
the task um because it clearly would
need people with a lot
of detailed historic knowledge of lots
of things in order to actually do it but
i think
in my view it's something which now
you've identified it and drawn attention
to it
um it needs to be done so that's my view
thank you
i i didn't volunteer among your comments
um steven i believe you're up next
yeah i put this in general i'm not clear
of the downside of continuing to to
ignore
this uh i agree that you know from a
purist point of view fixing it will be
fine
i i think it might be counterproductive
though so what's the downside
of continuing to ignore the problem
i see the downside as as closely
connected to what andrew just said
we're pointing other people this
document we've got other documents which
point to it
uh we're uh we've told other standards
bodies in the past that when they are
trying to sort out the iab iasg
ietf and isaac relationships
that this is where they should go look
uh so there's a a little bit of a
credibility problem
there's a little bit of an introduction
to newcomers problem
uh and uh uh and and like andrew i
i don't consider those first two options
viable
but uh but as i think i told uh
at least francisco a few days ago
uh i'm i'm more than happy to try to
work with someone or advise someone on
on writing and editing this but i don't
have time to do it myself
since you mentioned it john do you want
to talk about the downside of making it
historic and
and say we're just not talking about
this
um
i think it makes us look silly
um uh maybe we don't care
and in particular maybe we don't care
that anybody to whom we look silly
comes to that conclusion but uh
but it strikes me as um
as a little as as a little disorderly
and unprofessional
uh but again my uh since i'm not going
to volunteer
my opinion doesn't count very much and
it's a matter of uh
of community consensus and uh and
whether or not they're
whether or not anybody's going to do the
work
uh rich europe
um yeah the other day
john touched on a couple of the
downsides i think um
having you know the dow the itf
which is way too long but for newcomers
to look at but there are people
having run a bunch of the newcomer
sessions over the past few years
it'd be really nice to have a short
document that says this is how we are
structured
um for newcomers uh for people who
and newcomers come from various places
they come as engineers who want to work
on things
they come as industry consortia
who want to reach out and talk to us
such as
pick one recent one the inclusive naming
initiative
they come to us as you know full-fledged
heavyweight international standards
organizations who want to get
liaisons and we don't have a single
clear document that says here's how
it goes um and it's kind of embarrassing
to say oh yeah this is
this it is what it is ask around which
is really what the only alternative is
now
does does that mean that either rich or
andrew are
volunteering i i guess is always the
question
i volunteer andrew no
i i will certainly yeah i i'll
put my hand up because it's got to be
done
all right um bro go ahead
popping on exactly the same bandwagon
here that it not only is it really
unprofessional it is really unwelcoming
to anyone new coming along to to see an
organization that can't even
that doesn't even know how it works in a
defined way
i mean yes everybody knows but the
everybody knows and the only way to find
out is to ask a bunch of people
and and build tribal knowledge build um
cargo cult your understanding of how it
goes all these terms
um it's that's not the way that any
serious organization
has its org chart you know that is one
of the most basic things that you do
right at the start is you say this is
how we are structured this is how we
work
and to be working for a 25 year old
document that's not correct and have
that real normative definition of who we
are
is is pretty bogus um having said that
i'm not volunteering to write it because
i haven't been around long enough
i'm still working on tribal knowledge so
your recommendation for dispatch is
is uh dispatch the iasg and say
fix this you're you're running this
organization
all right uh keith you're up
um so i think i would say that
to me i've been looking at this you know
inclusiveness problem and this seems
like a big part of it
that the organization organization
structure is rather opaque
and not only to newcomers i've been
around over 30 years
and i can't hardly keep track of who's
doing what anymore or where to go
when i have a certain issue having said
that so i think
i think this information needs to be
updated in some form i'm not sure that
an rfc is the best way to do it
because rfcs are there's so many of them
out there and we don't remember which
rfcs do what anymore uh
it's almost a way of hiding the
information so i think
rfcs are good places to put details so
that if you have a lot of details that
need to be specified
you know and someone wants to go read
the fine print sure
point them to an rfc that's fine but uh
probably the sort of primary
presentation of this
should be something attached to the
website
and that whole website i think needs a
whole bunch of thought because i think
the tools are great but the website is
pretty uh opaque itself
so um there's some there's some need to
sort of
come up with a fresh approach of saying
how do we explain ietf to our
participants and as well as to people
who are
external and make that information very
clear and accessible
okay jeffrey
i think for this document to be useful
it would have to be a living document
that
that kind of is the way that you change
the organization
rather than is a documentation of
changes that have already been made
um looking at it it has been updated by
kind of references to other rfcs rather
than by
being a single place you can look to to
learn everything
which is not which makes it not useful
um
so i would suggest making it historic
and saying that that the website needs
to be the way to document
kind of the structure of the
organization
all right um elliott
elliot thanks pete um i agree with
jeffrey
uh by and large if i look at the
information that's in this document
we have a we have other documents that
cover
that information far better at this
point some of it
is in fact in the tao of the ietf
uh some of it is in other rfcs and some
of it's on the website and other places
i think probably somebody just need if
somebody wants to they would just go and
maybe work with somebody like greg wood
to really identify the right places for
this information
you know on the website and then we
could leave a tombstone after that would
be my suggestion
thank you
thanks elliot uh dkg europe hi there
uh dinocon gilmore so um
i think this com this conversation is a
difficult one to have because people are
hearing it as two different things
i think people are hearing this as the
itf needs to be reorganized
and they're also hearing it as we need a
better documentation of what the current
situation of the ietf
is if we're talking about getting rid of
this document because someone wants to
write a better description of how the
ietf works
then that's one project but if we're
talking about revising this document in
the sense of
we let's let's normalize and regularize
our organizational chart
that is an entirely different project
and so i think we need to be really
clear
if we're asking for a better
documentation of what is going on in the
ietf
that is the living document project that
i think other folks are saying doesn't
fit well with the static nature of the
rfc
and then the tombstone is totally
adequate to just say you know we realize
that our organization doesn't work in
this in this static way and you can find
better documentation
in the following places and i think a
tombstone would be sufficient
for for what it's worth i hadn't heard
i mean other than in the chatroom people
questioning it the suggestion that
whatever comes next is somehow going to
regularize or do new stuff
but more by way of documenting existing
practice
uh i think that these things are pretty
tightly entangled
right i mean when you start asking
questions about who is really
responsible for a thing
um whoever writes that document is going
to find themselves coming up against the
well
this person is nominally supposed to do
it but in practice you actually bring it
over to this group
and they know how to like turn the
machinery correctly
so i think it's going to be really i
think they're going to be
more closely entangled than we'd like
them to be and that's why people are
responding fair enough
i i hear that thank you that that helped
um colin you're up to bat
so uh
uh-oh my audio is working or is it
working yeah your audio is working there
was a little echo there for a second but
it sounds okay now
i just got a message mid checkout that
wasn't working so i
like i agree with a lot of what dkg is
saying there and this is
largely i view this more like a
constitutional sort of
fine detailed document that nails down
the exact details of our process and yes
it's totally embarrassing that it's
wrong
but this is not we could should not try
and revise this to be the thing that
helps newcomers or other organizations
figure out how work actually happens
like we need stuff that does that but it
doesn't need to be a document like this
in the slightest so i i think those are
two very completely separate problems
um but on this document and updating it
uh
i mean yeah it's embarrassing how wrong
it is but
i it seems colossally difficult to
get agreement on all the stuff that
updates it so i'm i'm a little bit on
the
the version of um you know you can troll
through the updates for other documents
that that have
updated this one obsolete and whatever
uh
and figure out what's going on i'm i'm
not totally sure we
you know unless somebody has a huge
amount of energy to put into
dealing with that the use case of fixing
the sort of
constitution of this stuff not fixing
the educational
documentation of what people use um this
sounds like it's just going to be a huge
quagmire so i
i would want us to be really clear on
what the scope of change is where we're
making before we open this up
or what we're going to do and i'll
remind people that dispatch one of the
ways to dispatch an idea was always to
stuff a sword through it right that's
one of the meanings
yes well and in this particular case
i believe john's choice number one is
the equivalent of
no we're not going to do anything about
this so um
thanks uh colin
hey uh i should know better not to join
the queue immediately after cullen
because i'm always confused about who
you're
calling on um i mean i
you know i i i sort of read this
document and
i have to admit that i first started
coming to the itf about a month after
this was
published and i haven't read it in the
in intervening time
uh and to be honest from reading it it
doesn't say anything which isn't already
on the website
uh and you know making sure we have
crisp definitions of
you know the charters of the the iab and
the iasg and the irtf and all these
other organizations
i think is important this particular
document just seems to be describing
stuff which is
um you know we already described it well
enough on the website just you know
label it as
as historic and move on
you did you put yourself in the queue
john
mr clinton yeah yeah
um i want to slightly push back at some
of the comments that you've been
made recently uh including in jabber
um newcomers do look at this
because the website turns out to be very
pretty but impenetrable
and maybe maybe we should fix that um
other standards bodies look at this uh
uh either because we've pointed them to
it or because they want one thing to
look at
or because the website is uh
impenetrable and the towel is too long
to pay attention to um
uh and with regard to living documents i
understand the argument uh i appreciate
the argument
but if our organizational structure at
the level that this document
is talking about or ought to be talking
about
is evolving in real time then we have
another set of problems
and again if uh if one of the concerns
we have again referring to some of the
comments in the chat
is that other standards body look at
this
and other things and want to prove that
we're just a bunch of amateurs and
children who should be
to whom no attention should be paid then
then the state of this and saying uh
go read the tower go read these six
things
is not helpful uh and uh
um so i think there's really a
strong argument for a document like this
there's a strong argument for a document
like this
being more than stable enough to keep in
the rfc series
even though that doesn't necessarily
mean it should be in the rfc
series so let's try to
calibrate this relative to newcomers
external impressions
uh people trying to learn what's going
on
uh one could get rid of it
and replace it by crisp reference as to
where to look
but again that's not really a
satisfactory solution
although it might be a good intermediate
stage uh thanks
thank you um ecker
yeah i mean so it seems to me like
you know the having for this document
like if the task at hand is
this is their two tasks at hand one is
to provide like
what do you need to be a newcomer and
like be successful at itf
and like a document shape like this is
like whether it's in rc
or whatever it's like fantastically not
helpful for that because
like there's like what you need is a
certain kind of task orientation that
this does not bring to the party
um if you're looking for a description
of like the idf's overall thing
um overall structure well i i guess i'm
not sure what that's used for
but um but that's not that probably the
newcomers really need
um and um while i agree our organization
um um as sort of colin pointed out um
you know
there's this question of like the sort
of constitutional stuff and like
documenting things
um in in very in the in a precise format
and there's a question of like what you
need to know when you're first like
trying to get into it
and i think i made the example on the
chat like um you know
if you want to like understand tls um
you know
you wouldn't go to a46 you'd like want
to have a document described like how
sales worth the high level and then you
dig 84 46 for the details
um so you know uh while i understand
that our um
our process is going to be changing that
rapidly um
um the uh um and so one might imagine
like
that whatever document you produce to
explain them um you know
does not need to like change also i
don't that's correct um because you know
as we iterate through
like people coming in and people trying
to understand what's going on um
you know it will be helpful to be able
to revise the documents easily in order
to make them clearer
as we understand people find confusing
people not and the sort of like rfc
formula is not particularly well suited
for that so while the while structures
may be stable
the documentation in this case for
newcomers not to be stable unnecessarily
and like this is like what the web is
good for so um like
so to close that relatively one comment
um i'm on team
tune's done this and right input on the
website
okay uh keith you're back in the queue
a little bit has been mentioned about
this in the chat room but i think that
separate from any efforts to
document the structure of ietf
we have gotten to be very complex and
bureaucratic
and i wonder if that really serves us
and that's an even bigger thing to
contemplate than documenting what's
there
but i do think it serves as a barrier to
participation
and uh i feel like we we're dealing with
a structure that we
developed in the late 1990s
and have have since embellished since
then
that for an organization which was
actually much larger at the time
and i'm not sure that it serves us well
for the current
somewhat leaner organization or
uh for the organization we have and the
current needs we have so i guess i would
like to see
some effort in looking at you know do we
need
all these separate organizations can we
streamline this a bit
uh but it needs to be done very
patiently of course
so anyway
thanks um colin you're back in the queue
no colin didn't want to be in the queue
harold please go ahead
so that document has no
real problems it documents perfectly
well or
perfectly well what we wanted to say
about the situation 25 years ago
the point is to the documentary problem
because the pointers imply
that the state of art that we tried to
tell other people
25 years ago is the current state
so i think we should make it historic
because this i think we should uh
go hand for pointers to it and destroy
them point them to the tower
i mean if we have a towel that is
unreadable then we have
within the tower we have a tower problem
so middle alternative for me
dispatch it to go is go historic
and and get those pointers fixed
i'm a simple man
never has anybody claimed that um
andrew you're a backup thanks
um well so reading some of the comments
in the
uh chat um if i was being unkind i'd
characterize them as saying
john's pointed out that we're running a
restaurant with with dirty cutlery
um and a few people are suggesting we
should just ignore the problem
um i think having dirty cutler is not
not a good
a good look for a restaurant and that
needs to be fixed
so you can either make it historic which
i think personally
well or revise it but ignoring it
seems um unhelpful may get closed down
when the
food inspectors come round so i think
that's asking for trouble
um not changing it because the website
the tao and
assorted other documents that people
might think are very equally
um wrong out of date impenetrable um and
nobody uses them anyway it also seems
like a really bad argument
uh to me um yeah that just talks the
fact that there's a whole bunch of
things that need to be fixed
but you've got to start somewhere um and
finally i'm sorry just laughing at
elliot's comment in the chat
finally dare i say this this does link
with the next topic uh on the agenda
uh because diversity doesn't improve
if you've got enormous barriers to entry
to an organization i think this is just
one of those
barriers to entry so putting up with
barriers to entry is a bad approach as
well
so in my view something has to be done
ignoring it is not the answer
thank you
um okay uh wes you're the last one in
the queue
yeah so um interesting problem thanks
for finding it
um my my view is
probably slightly different i'm not sure
that historic is right because
i don't generally think that we should
remove important information although
the historical still exists so maybe
that's you know not actually the case
i actually think we ought to update it
not to
make any changes no modifications
whatsoever just
only clarifications to what the existing
state is right what are the things that
are wrong
document that reword it throw out
anything
that you know is no longer relevant and
throw out anything
or mark as no consensus where
we have disagreement about what the
current state is i think one of the rat
holes will be
you know one person says this and the
other person says this about
i don't know how the iab works or you
know pick any random
one of the organizations during that
document and uh just documented us no
consensus at this time
with respect to a living document i
don't think that the state of
the the leadership bodies and all of the
organizations you know change super
quickly
we should make rfcs easier to update i
you know i think everybody probably
agrees on that i don't know that it
needs to go to the state of a living
document but i would argue that
a rewrite as long as you promise not to
make modifications and structural
changes
you know shouldn't be as hard as
everybody is saying if we agree to do
that
that's the tricky part
[Music]
all right um and alexi jumped in at the
last moment alexi
yeah i think i pretty much want to uh
second what
was uh just said um
maybe it's a wishful uh thinking of
hearing but uh
i think um maybe we should decide that
we want to do something
and then we can figure out whether it's
a web page on the website
maybe post a draft and then see if you
want to progress to rfc
to replace it or whether it just becomes
a
web page on the website and when people
uh talk about tom stone i'm
again i'm not entirely sure is this a
short rfc
saying that the original rfc is obsolete
and here's where you want to find the
information and
again it's one of
possible outcomes for this
all right um
heaven help me i i might actually want
to use the little polling tool
because i i'm trying i'll turn my video
back on
uh um i'm trying to get a sense of
how many folks think that
going through any of these processes to
um re-document in some way whether it's
you know another web page part of the
dow
um a new rfc whether
those folks um are
outnumbered by the let's just kill it in
some way either by
ignoring it or making it historic and
moving on um
uh what those numbers are looking like
um
i think we should have three three
show hands for the three possible
yeah the list here and
stated so that would you be okay with
the first option would you be okay with
the second one
so you're very welcome to to say i'm
okay with the
first or but absolutely not the second
and third
or i'm okay with the first and or the
second
and third um that might give us a better
idea of
bronn yeah
i'm realizing that continue to ignore
the problem is one of the offered
options because that would certainly
need to be one of the one of the things
that people say whether they're okay
with or not
yeah right that that is one of the
options yes
and john
yeah i i've realized this process this
discussion that
uh that my bullet two is really two
different things is maybe two different
questions
uh one of those is to publish a document
somewhere which says
uh that's obsolete hold your nose uh go
look elsewhere
and uh and the other is published
document which says that's obsolete
and these are the specific places to
look for these other things
and that was one of these came up at
least in jabber and it's clearly an
option here
uh i uh i have problems with it because
uh telling people to look at a list of
things
becomes a different kind of barrier to
entry coming back to some other comments
you made earlier
but uh but i think that's really two
separate options
yeah i mean it's sort of why and
and i'm happy to split it up but i the
first thing i want to get a sense of and
and maybe we'll ask these questions
sequentially
um and and have a little discussion
between if we need to first thing i want
to get a sense of is how many people
really want to leave things exactly the
way they are
um how many people want to
make this document historic or otherwise
say this is obsolete
and go no further um and and
with those two answers i think maybe
we'll have
a little better so um okay i'm gonna
take my hand at the tool here um
everybody hang on tight
um so um
i i i think
it's best to not do
anything um
so i'm going to start this up if you
raise your hand that means i think it's
best to not do anything
if you actually click do not raise hand
that means
no i don't think that and if you ignore
it you're just abstaining
so
yeah ecker go ahead while we're chugging
along you please just
yeah could you just please list out what
all the options you're going to have are
before so the next one is yeah yeah the
next one is going to be because i
i wanted to um hold off on the later two
but the next one is gonna be um
i'm i want to um
uh obsolete the document in some way
uh and and
pause there and then ask separately
questions regarding what to do after we
obsolete it if that's
the case um so this this one
came out um or is coming out pretty much
the way i thought it was going to come
out
which is just a few people
really think it's okay to just say meh
um
and as far as i know you can't uh choose
more than one thing
yeah and steven explicitly says in
jabber
meh all right um well
that's um four okay
um okay so i'll end that
and now um uh
this one is i want to
at least mark this document
as obsolete or historic
if that is a sufficient way to put it
anybody object to me put it in that way
uh okay um so here it goes number two
please uh say what you want to say about
that one
good okay so so my guesses as to where
the room were are looking pretty
confirmed on this one
um people at least want to mark the
document
as historic and just you know
in general
give it a little bit more time
d to d anybody else wanna
yeah good okay so yeah the the general
sense of the room
is doing absolutely nothing there's a
few people who think that's a good idea
but for the most part
people want to at least mark the
document as historic okay so we'll um
that that seems like a good start so now
um this is all the next two we're going
to go on the assumption
that we mark the document as obsolete or
historic
um the two choices are going to be and
we're going to do these sequentially
um i want to replace it with a new rfc
and the other choice is i want to
replace it
with a new web page and i'll give you a
third choice
i want to replace it with some pointers
to
other uh web pages or information
it can be bought for more than one of
these
yeah absolutely no i i'm trying to get a
sense of
where the room is uh stephen go ahead so
pete i think you didn't have the option
there is to just stop
and do nothing else other than market as
historically all right
sorry yes no i i and i meant to yes
you're absolutely right so yes that will
also be uh colin did you want to follow
up there
i i was going to say the same thing as
stephen so but basically i think the
same thing
at the web page stuff like i mean i
think completely
nothing to do with this document we need
to improve our web pages for newcomers
and whatever that's
like a no-brainer but that's that's i
don't i i i don't want to
i think it's bad to confuse those well
right so um yeah um the
when i say i want there to be a new web
page
i'm i'm asking whether people think that
we should have a focused web page
on the organization and same thing with
new rfc
and then you know the choice of well i
prefer
a new web page that replaces that
that provides the information content
this document was trying to provide
right that's that's what i'm looking for
yep yep yep yep
um uh wes and
and then elliott when you say replace
the replace with the new rfc or a new
web page you don't discuss
what the content of that will be again
going back to what i was saying earlier
are we going to just
first document because otherwise you get
into the question of yeah hey i'm
raising right right
right in both of these cases i'm the
question i'm asking is
just document existing practice if we
can with understanding that
uh you know uh you know dkg's comment
that
that's inevitably fraught with is this
really
the the current thing are we pushing for
um
stan you know uh adding structure where
there really isn't
some right now uh elliott go ahead
yeah pete uh thanks the my confusion
is that uh as as i think alyssa pointed
out
and others a lot of this information
already exists on the itf webpage so
which option do i choose if i just want
to augment
whatever is missing yeah um
i think um and uh
i'll just call i i like that framing of
it because that could be
you know either some additions to the
current web page or
some web page that has better pointers
um so
i'm i'm scribbling down for myself so
nothing beyond obsoleting
um uh augment
current web pages
uh new web page
or new rfc
alyssa go ahead
so we had this experience when
we converted from the previous
version of the itf website to the
current version
which is that there's like a lot of
croft
and um the team that did that i think it
felt compelled to like
exactly reproduce what was on the
previous um
set of web pages in in the you know the
current cms
which is very painful process and my
was something that i took away from that
which is this sort of like
um design of information
in a collection of web pages by a large
group is not a great strategy it doesn't
yield
really what you would want it to yield
so
if there can be sort of a generic option
about
you know ensuring that some set of
information is available
on the website or something like that
that might be good
getting into like really granular
different choices about whether it's
just
augmentations or new pages or new
sections of pages or whatever
like it's it's very constraining for
the people who actually have to like try
to make the website usable
right right fair enough right fair
enough
um eve sorry go ahead
eve you have to unmute yourself i can't
do it
i'm so used to being co-chair and just
having the mic open sorry
[Laughter]
anyway i don't know if this has been
discussed before um
but it it seems to me like part of what
we're getting at is that there's this
new class
of document that when we have our keys
and they get rewritten or updated
there's betrayal
around what populates other things when
in fact
what we're hinting towards and marching
towards seems to be
um a lie a living document
and is has there been discussion about
what these obsoleted documents point to
is a living document on on the web
somewhere
hosted on the ietf website
we did something like that with the tao
right is we decided publishing this as
an rfc
has all sorts of problems and we
tombstoned it and pointed to
a website that ostensibly is supposed to
get updated more frequently and
and be a little more live um plus or
minus that's true
so is that considered a um
something we have to do more regularly
and should that be
a new category of thing that we created
as part of our rfc
series yeah well that's a good question
um uh i mean that that's sort of what
i'm putting into the category of
make a new web page um but i i hear
alyssa's concern that um
maybe we'll whittle this down to
something needs to be done to keep
things up to date on the web
and and then uh if people
are sort of leaning in that direction if
that's the direction we're going
um maybe we'll you know we'll uh
uh figure out what it is people mean by
that
um so let me at least start asking the
the easier questions
so i'm first going to ask the i want to
do nothing beyond obsoleting or making
historic
and seeing if there's a lot of support
for that
um so go ahead and raise or
don't raise your hand to that one
that's that's more interesting than the
other ones
also we have rudiger in the queue oh
sorry while we're doing this go ahead
yeah
okay so see not sure i'm
hurt yeah we can hear you no
does not look like i am
it appears that we can hear you but you
can't hear us
rudiger is going to go and try to figure
out what his uh
his tool is doing so we'll we'll get
back to him
um yes uh i think
uh there was mention of
a couple of pointers to the obsolete
document
pointers out of the
rscs and
if there are any such that are
actually significant like being used
in other bcps i think
those need to be identified and kind of
the dangling links
dangling pointers need to be satisfied
in some way
at the bare minimum at least the
potentially dangling pointers
needs to be identified
good point no i appreciate that thanks
all right um well so that
that particular one um yeah the the
uh the people in the minority are
certainly more than rough
as we might say so let's read it out for
the for the minutes
maybe um so we have
10 people who raised end and 25 who did
not raise a hand
on a total of 58 participants for i i
want to do nothing beyond
obsoleting or marking historic
um so now i'm going to put
the i want a new
replacement rfc
documenting existing
practice with all of its caveats
so that is now up feel free to poke at
that one
well now that's amusing
and one person who's flipping back and
forth that was very that was very funny
thank you
i i believe that is the um
quintessential
uh there ain't no consensus so for i
want a new replacement rfc documenting
existing practice
it is uh 17 people click the raise hand
button and 19 people click the
uh don't raise hand button
out of 58. i kind of like that elliot
you had a comment
pete um it seems to me that
if this is how 17 people feel
um then there should be at least some of
those 17 people who are willing to do
some writing
and if they're willing to do some
writing then we have something to talk
about
otherwise we don't in that context well
sure although i will say that i
take a good portion of those 19 people
who
click the do not raise hand button as
explicitly not
wanting there to be a new rfc to replace
this one
but if what i'm getting at pete is it
it's one thing to abstractly say i don't
want a new rfc but if somebody's going
to write it
then i think people might actually read
it and then they may have a different
point of view
it's possible um
so we can ask a couple of years
and we got rich we got maybe alexi
in the chat it's worth
asking if anybody else is
would be willing to to help with this
effort
um and then the last question i want to
ask is um
uh and i'm going to ask it the general
way that alyssa
sort of did is i
want web pages
updated to
um what do i want to say properly
include
the current state of this information
boy that's obnoxiously long
people okay with me asking that
no one's whining loudly there you go
have something to poke at i want web
pages updated to
pro well i didn't even get the d and
updated
also we are uh time check
yes sorry and
the yeah are aware yes
and john go ahead in the meantime
yeah i just wanted to point out that one
could want to update the web pages
and still believe that having an rfc is
a good idea
absolutely absolutely i know and we did
not limit
people to one choice yeah and and to a
certain extent
uh the amount of work needed is overlaps
very heavily
getting back to early support yeah
i took a lot of the do not raise hand on
the
the rfc thing is people actually
indicating
i i think doing it on the web is fine
but doing it in rfc is not
so um okay
yeah and we've got um 26 to 2
out of the 58 on that question um
i think that's enough information to
bring back to the list
and get uh you know a dispatch out of
this of some form or another
um and people i mean elliot's point is
well taken
we we can sort of re-ask of people
would be it would doing an rfc be okay
if someone else was gonna write it not
me um
and and find out how that goes but this
is at least sufficient information to
bring back to the list and get some
get some feedback on um to dispatch this
but i i
i at least smell where this is going i
think
um anything else on this john go ahead
yeah another observation along those
lines in terms of what to write up
in which i at least if we're going to do
this by webpage
we'd like to see the same degree of
community consensus
about what that web piece says as we
would expect
from rfc so let's
let's not pretend that the web page is
easier in that regard
even though it might be easier in other
respects
sure sure sure uh echo
and echo will be last and then we'll get
to our next uh go around here yeah so
actually i think i disagree with john
said i think that like
one of the key elements or web pages is
not have to have this interview
community consensus and it can be just
largely written
and then we can take you know feedback
um
and you know and revise it as we go um
but the the the
you know part of what makes our
documents inaccessible is the fact that
they have the workshop so that everybody
like you know loves them in exactly the
same way and every because they're
decent
and that would not be helpful in this
instance
that then we're at risk of ending up
either with eckerd's opinion or my
opinion
about uh about what it is the
organizational structure is
and that's different from an ietf
statement or what the organizational
structure is
uh that doesn't necessarily have to be
that way but it's a danger
i think we need to cut the discussion
here
we have uh yeah thank you okay
good well thank you all that was useful
and i think we have uh
good stuff to bring back to the list uh
and
um thank uh uh who is i'm sorry
who was doing the uh minute taking here
uh michael
and kirsty and and and kirsten um
yes who are who are taking um close to
seconds
not minutes but but very helpful
nonetheless
all right uh fernando keith you're up to
bat
and you have to hit me pretty much the
rest of the session yes
just fine go ahead okay um
so i'm fernando and i will be uh
presenting the
document on diversity and inclusiveness
in the itf um it's a document that we
co-author with keith moore
and this document arrives as a result of
the
discussions that um we have had on the
gen dispatch mailing list while uh
chartering the
the term working group okay so
next slide
okay um i think that one of the things
that you know became
uh you know clear while we were uh
discussing
uh this topic of diversity and
inclusiveness is that
you know to a large extent um you know
uh different people were referring to or
were implying different things
when they were uh you know talking about
diversity
and inclusion so in order to you know
to frame the discussion in an upright
way uh
let's clarify what we mean by each of
these things
um so the first of the terms is
diversity
which essentially throughout the
document we
use to imply us showing a great deal of
variety like different things so we look
at the organization the itf we look at
itf leadership
and we expect to see variety okay then
there is a different term which
uh is related to diversity but implies
different things
which is inclusion which essentially
talks about
a culture and an environment uh where
everyone has equal chances to
participate
so this means that inclusion has to do
with providing
providing an environment uh that
essentially fosters diversity okay
um throughout our document for the most
part
what we try to work on is on inclusion
and have diversity um as
a side effect of that inclusion okay so
what do we mean by variety
which i referred to before and this is
something that you know also was
discussed on the mailing list
we essentially you know um mean
every possible aspect that you can think
of like
range of different social and ethnic
backgrounds different genders different
sexual orientations
different countries and regions uh
different types of organizations company
non-profits etc
uh this is just a sample of some of the
things that
uh we mean by variety but this list is
uh non-exhaustive and is in no
particular order
okay so this means that when we talk
about diversity
we want to see we want uh you know
variety or diversity
in each of these uh different aspects
and categories if you wish
uh next slide
uh okay so what we try to do in our
document which
you can think of as a problem statement
document
is to try to analyze uh different
aspects that uh essentially are
structural issues
that um make the ietf
not as inclusive as we might wish okay
so there are uh several categories that
we have identified perceived return of
investment
effects of current participation
diversity in its groups and leadership
roles
processes etc etc so um
obviously we will not discuss uh the you
know
the details of this that's what the id
is there for
the draft is there therefore but we will
um you know simply
skim through uh you know some of these
things
uh next slide
so first one is uh the perceived return
of investment
uh like you know when you know obviously
participation
take uh takes time efforts money
at times too um and uh you know
for people that people and organizations
that you know participate
in the itf they are obviously have a
motivation for doing so
uh in the case of you know organizations
companies uh
among the possible reasons are that they
might benefit from
iprs uh they might also benefit for
example from
leading leading the leading or
participating in the standardization
effort which at times can result in an
improved time to market
for example for independent participants
that might be done because they they
believe in making a difference
uh by improving internet technologies
something that might apply too of course
to organizations
and also for uh you know improving their
career opportunities
uh now if you think about these things
this possible return of investment
they can only be realized by a small
subset of organizations and individuals
for example there are organizations that
or companies that don't manufacture
products
so obviously they wouldn't be able to
leverage from an improved time to market
so to speak so
i mean we won't get into the details but
you know you get the idea of what we are
talking about here
next slide
uh second one is the effects of current
participation
okay so obviously uh current
is reflects you know the previous slide
that we have seen
and uh you know for obvious reasons uh
the current participation results in a
bias in a number of areas
first one is perception perception of
structural issues
okay um it's obviously uh you know
harder in a way to
to to perceive or understand uh let's
say
a problem or a challenge that yeah you
are not uh you know facing yourself
um current participation obviously has a
bias on the
face-to-face meeting rotation normally
meetings are held
in you know areas where most of the
participants come from
so one thing leads to the other uh
the other thing is that uh obviously the
diversity that we have in itf groups and
leadership
reflects the diversity that we have in
the community to some extent or another
okay and you know finally this has an
effect on you know how new work is
um you know considered by the idf
next slide
um so part of that uh
you know part of the you know lack of
diversity or reduced diversity that you
know we have in participation obviously
reflects in
uh in the diversity in atf uh groups and
leadership roles
uh and the effect of that is that there
is a
small number of interests essentially
you know judging
uh working group consensus community
consensus
all appeals in the case that there are
appeals uh
something similar happens for you know
for the case of the non-com
and the aib similar stuff and
in some cases you may also have uh
arbitrary decisions
that uh you know are produced and
enforced by such groups
uh you know without a lot of uh
community consensus on them
uh next slide
uh other things uh processes there are
some things there are some of our
process that are kind of like
loosely specified um
and this can be beneficial in some
scenarios that because you know it gives
freedom for example to work in group
chairs
regarding to how to handle processes but
in other cases uh you know it can be
problematic for participants because for
example they don't know what to expect
like the the expectations uh um you know
are uh you know are uh don't necessarily
match uh you know what actually happens
you know
in our processes uh one example of this
for example is ongoing work on
um working group adoption of documents
with you know tries to you know improve
uh
in that aspect next slide
uh another one is the difficulty in
joining or participating in the ietf
uh well first of all finding interesting
groups and areas there are so many of
them
that at times particularly for a
newcomer it may be challenging to
identify uh you know what's the uh
working group where they might
be able to contribute uh which working
group they should
you know take a proposal if they have
any and so on
uh there are also challenges that um you
know involve
authoring and submitting internet trust
uh
this of course has to do among other
things you know
with the requirements that you know
internet reps have to comply with per se
which nowadays i guess you know for most
of most of us
if you need to produce an internet draft
there's not
you know you need to rely on on some of
the tools to do that
because of the number of requirements uh
that may be a challenge for particularly
for newcomers
um there are also for example in the
case of
xml to rfc there are different versions
i
for example i uh you know you might be
able to handle version two
kind of like quite well maybe not so
much version 3 etc etc
and when it comes to discussion there
are also challenges there
there are people that you know find uh
you know the discussions on the mailing
lists uh kind of like challenging
you know from from having to subscribe
to specific mailing lists
long threads etc etc etc uh
and for some of them the use of github
by working groups it's
you know can be a great improvement
whereas on the other hand there might be
uh people
that you know uh might be used to using
the mailing list but
might not be that familiar with github
so for
you know that other community github
might represent the challenge
and obviously the decision on you know
on what to use and the
extent to which these things are used
you know represents a trade-off
necessarily uh next one
so another one is economic constraints
um
you know obviously the the the process
uh well
not right now because of the pandemic
but you know uh you know normal time so
pre-pandemic times
uh the processes obviously favor uh you
know people that kind of
that can attend face-to-face uh meetings
uh there are a lot of expenses
associated with you know
uh with attending meetings travel
accommodation
you know dinners breakfast lunches and
so on
uh most of them you know in a way we
don't control
and there's also the um you know the
issue of
meeting phase which you know is
something that is you know more in
under our control um you know in this
respect
i do believe that you know this document
in the schmo
uh working group uh is a really really
good thing
and it's a step in in the right
direction obviously
it doesn't and it can't i address some
of the other expenses which are you know
impossible to address
by the itf but i do think that it helps
a lot in that area
uh next slide
there are also educational constraints
um you know normally in order to you
know become
involved in the ietf uh you need uh to
have at least some knowledge of
you know a lot of uh you know different
topics
uh you know and you know a little bit
about internet protocols a little bit
about transport protocols
congestion control dns etc etc
uh that may be uh you know um
a challenge uh you know for many people
uh
we are talking about newcomers in in
particular right like you know people
that
would like to join and participate and
at times uh there is you know another
related uh
issue if you wish is that uh you know
normally if you want to work on
improving
uh you know protocols uh you not only
need to uh have knowledge about the
protocol itself but
you know you also need to be able to do
some critical thinking
uh such as you know not just taking the
technology for granted and assume that
that's the best way to do things but
understand the pros and cons
and also understand that you know in
many cases what you have in protocols
are essentially
historical artifacts that probably if we
were to reduce some things we wouldn't
do them in the same way
so that's important for um you know um
you know if you want to contribute and
the other one is real-world experience
like for example operational experience
uh
next slide uh i think this is the
the final one when it comes to the you
know different aspects of
areas it has to do with cultural issues
first one is language
like for example the recent discussion
on on the gen dispatch mainly this was
uh you know about inclusive terminology
um but language itself you know can be
challenged
can be challenging in you know many
different ways like
uh i would uh probably argue that for a
large number of us
um you know we speak english as a second
language and that can be a challenge
uh at times uh you know uh people that
speak english as a native
as a native language might use uh let's
say expression
expressions or jokes that for a
non-native english speaker
you know might have no meaning or might
might be difficult to
comprehend uh you know at times during
presentations this can also be a
challenge
uh you know for those that you know
speak english as a second language
uh using email effectively might also
be a challenge you know long threads uh
you know the way in which
uh we you know technical community
employs email you know no
um no html email you know we we
uh quote parts of the you know the the
email that we want to respond and so on
and there are also issues that are
associated with the
you know with the comfort zone uh they
may be related with
culture itself you know in some cultures
at times the kind of discussions that we
may have in the ietf
might not be let's say culturally
culturally acceptable for them
uh there are other issues like there
might be people working in certain
fields
that you know the fact that they occupy
a certain
role or certain position in the company
means that you know they
uh they don't get involved into certain
kinds of discussions whereas you know in
the itf
essentially you are supposed to be
willing to uh you know what to debate
your ideas uh proposals and
and so on uh next slide
uh so before actually uh you know the
the discussing
the slide and the moving forward thing
um
let me just mention that you know while
talking to the
to the chairs um we agreed uh to
essentially uh split the presentation in
two parts uh the first part
uh the problem statement which is what
we have here
and the second part uh to have some
proposals
for some of the topics that uh we have
discussed
so uh we could now uh you know
focus and discuss you know what could be
a good next step
for this problem statement and uh you
know once we
make a decision on that then we can
discuss
the you know some of the proposals that
we have for um
uh you know for addressing some of these
issues among the
you know among the possible options i
guess uh is uh an ad sponsored document
the other possible option would be the
creation of a you know new working group
to
you know work on the problem statement
and possible solutions but this is of
course for the you know working group to
to discuss
yeah and i think um you know a
subcategory
of new working group is well not quite
sure given what you've said
uh this could use a buff a full boss
devoted completely to this topic to sort
of sort out
whether this is worth the working group
or not um
so should we have a little discussion
here on the moving forward piece
is that the plan yeah definitely
i think like the two parts are separate
like we have some proposals for some
things
but you know first of all i think the
most important thing is to agree on the
problem
yep all right so do people want to talk
about the
directions forward whether this sounds
like a
way to go forward um keith did you want
to just jump in since you're
co-authored here go right ahead
um so
if we're really going to try to improve
uh diversity inclusion in itf it's a
very
broad topic and any kind of
remedies would i mean it's the sort of
thing that you would address
differently in different parts of the
organization or in affiliated
organizations
and so it seems like a lot for any
single working group
and it's especially because
some things could be tools some things
could be structural changes some things
could be better documentation
it's possible to imagine um
some sort of ongoing organization
probably not a working group
that is tasked with keeping track of how
well we're doing in this and maybe
making recommendations or maybe
whatever there are existing efforts
and maybe some efforts that have existed
in the past that
didn't go as far as we would like
i do believe that diversity and
inclusion basically require
uh a commitment to continue its
improvement
that's not the sort of thing that go
ahead
yeah i i just want to say that um we
probably
don't need to necessarily get caught up
in titles because of course we've had
sort of long long view working groups
that
last forever like this one for instance
which
sort of either do dispatching or say
this really needs to be handled in this
way
so whether the structure we use happens
to be a working group
i think what's important is laying out
what we
what we want that whatever that entity
is to do
um so it doesn't necessarily have to
look like a traditional working group
with
particular um you know uh milestones and
goals for
you know this document that document and
i
kind of don't care what it's called but
uh i do think that sometimes we get in a
habit of working that is
conditioned by working in so many
working groups where
the goal is to publish some documents
and be done and
i kind of think if the structure of
whatever this ends up being doesn't
encourage that
that habit maybe we're better off but
it's
uh i think it's a topic to be sort of
discussed among
uh leadership because clearly i don't i
don't think we're going to be able to
figure this out it requires a lot of
sensitivity to different parts of the
organization
um so anyway exactly what it looks like
i don't know
i'd like to see some sort of effort
appreciate it and stick
and go ahead and feel free to leave
yourself either unmuted or on the screen
as we go through this and same with
fernando um
so andrew you were next in the queue uh
yeah so on you know given that there's
some i think some good recommendations
to come
um i think this is a helpful
um presentation i think it captures
uh and identifies a really important
topic for what it's worth i think this
is far more important than the
already potentially challenging topic of
uh how to handle a few
problem phrases um i think this is the
significant underlying issue uh that
needs action
and i think an important first step is
acknowledging that there is a problem of
diversity in in
many forms um uh perhaps
measuring that in some way um and then
looking
at what actions to take but i think just
at least getting agreement that it's a
problem that needs addressing is a
pretty decent start so
thank you
um stephen go right ahead uh
so i don't think this topic is ready to
dispatch in the normal sense
i do think it would be great to see work
of some sort continue
uh a buff sounds initially attractive
but kind of has a catch 22 doesn't it
uh because if you don't do it face to
face it's going to be lacking enormously
and if you do it face to face it's going
to exclude everybody you want to
kind of get attracted
so yeah there is amazingness as i
pointed out in the chat it wasn't
necessarily intended exactly for this
but it might be useful
of the topics covered in the draft
personally i think the
economic exclusion is by far the biggest
barrier
uh that's significant for what we want
to do uh if there was some way to tackle
that i'm not convinced there is but if
there was
that could be you know a sub-topic that
might produce something tractable
somehow that could produce
uh some improvement and and just to
highlight something just explain
something from the chat
when i say that i think time is the
biggest barrier it's the ability to
spend the time
on the stuff the itf cares about and not
have to work on your day job because
you're
you know a bus driver is i think the
barrier that's what i mean
um it's not the case that i'm not
talking about a consultant who has to
who's so busy making
a thousand books an hour that they can't
be asked uh so
that's it so yeah i think madding this
discussion continues probably the best
yeah concrete outcome
well perhaps we need to spin up a
mailing list for this topic so that it
doesn't
uh conflict with other discussions on
gen dispatch
and and stephen uh mentioned in the chat
that there is a diversity
at itf.org that exists and was last used
around three years ago
i can take a look at that i think it is
uh i think it's important to
understand that diversity and inclusion
or the inclusiveness or whatever word
you want to use
are somewhat different things and uh
we it's easy for us to sort of lump them
in together it is actually possible for
them to conflict
so i just want i just want to try to
tease those apart and be careful
about which we're talking about in which
we're understanding you could make
ietf more inclusive and the result be
that it's less diverse
i don't think that's necessarily a good
result it is possible
so um anyway just try to keep the topic
separate in our minds i think and just
they are somewhat different um
both desirable
yeah i think we should try to learn from
what other standards bodies are doing
um for example the w3c has an inclusion
and diversity community group
um it's so i think
at least in the long run probably this
belongs as
as some some persistent body rather than
just a mailing list
um i don't know if that's the time for
that is right now
um i think 80 sponsored would be a
mistake even for the problem statement
because
uh like we're we're seeing that lots of
people have things to
to put into it um that kind of one
one set of authors isn't really
sufficient to to cover
and i also asked on the jabber room
um if perhaps an ib program is is better
than
than a working group because the scope
is is
the scope of things that need to change
is potentially bigger than
than the stuff that a working group
tends to to tackle
uh elliot go ahead
and uh hi again uh first thanks keith
and uh fernando for the work you did on
this draft
um i really appreciate it this is a
problem
that we can't not uh
talk about we have to engage on it uh
two a couple of observations first of
all this isn't our first
attempt at this um and we've had at
least
some success here or there um and uh
i'm thinking of the work that kathleen
and uh
suresh did a while back um that they
presented in berlin
and that was a big a good beginning and
i think it
did it has helped at times
um there are a couple of other efforts
that i always think about when we talk
about this like the i saw fellows effort
in terms of bringing people in who might
otherwise not be
um available and i think of the
uh 1-1-1 star
policy that we have in terms of how we
meet and how we've been meeting over the
last year
and i say this as the person who wrote a
draft that was that is entirely obe
called draft leader we got to stop
meeting like this
um so i'm wondering then if there are
multiple paths to dispatch this is sort
of in parallel
um to a point that that's been made in
the jabber and elsewhere
um what is it how do we know when we've
succeeded
usually involves some amount of
collection of data and analysis
we have people who can help us i think
do that they need to organize to do that
they should be
doing so in a collaborative way with the
community and i wonder if we can
dispatch
some of this off to jay um
in order to to ask for his help uh in
terms of finding out what sort of data
we can collect
that might be useful in figuring out you
know how deep of a hole we're in what
sort of problems we have
and then uh what we could do to to
address them so
as as uh steven opined uh
he thought most of the problems were
economical okay that's that is
definitely one axis
um there are others and the question is
uh who's affected in which dimension
and by how much and so uh that's one
area and then the second i think is i do
like the idea
of this community finding a place to
continue this conversation to develop
the ideas
to talk to to develop a problem
statement draft to continue to work on
on the work that keith and fernando uh
continue so i'd like to see that work
continue even if it's in gen dispatch
for further development but i'm happy if
it goes to another list and
that would be fine with me too but the
analysis aspect has to come along with
this before we take any action
thank you
thanks elliot richard europe thanks
um so i i want to plus one what jeffrey
said about learning from what other
groups are doing here um
i think that uh following the w3's
example and starting up some sort of
group where we can have these
discussions is really important um
probably a good idea here
obviously i think this is an important
topic to talk about um the reason i got
in the queue
was that the notion of a problem
statement
kind of makes me nervous um because this
is not like a fixed problem this
problem is not fixed for for all time
it's not really it doesn't really make
sense as
um you know an rfc to me um and
i think this is an area where the sort
of waterfall
style of development that the ietf
sometimes falls into or we do a problem
statement and some requirements then
you know many moons down the road we get
to a solution is
is really antithetical to solving this
problem like i think there's there's
points of urgent action here
we should obviously make sure we
understand what we're doing when we do
something
but i don't think we need to understand
the entire waterfront of problems before
we take action on specific things
[Music]
i will agree with that i think the
purpose of the
quote problem statement isn't to
completely define the problem
and then we can go off and fix it uh
it's more like just to give the
community
a sense of the breadth of the different
issues and also a chance to provide
input
so that we're hearing from lots of
different people because it's very easy
for a couple of authors or a few people
to say
oh these are the problems and completely
ignore other things that other people
are experiencing uh but i don't yeah i
don't want to do a waterfall stop thing
this has to be an ongoing effort and we
have to
do what we can when we can
um kirsty go right ahead
thank you yeah so just to say thank you
for writing this draft i know that can't
have been um
the easiest undertaking so thank you um
i just have a kind of
philosophical question about to what
extent the ietf
itself or attendees who currently go can
really understand
the uh inclusion issues so we obviously
all feel included to some extent that
we're able to at least defend and turn
up
and i don't know if there's a kind of
question here about how you could reach
maybe people who came like one time and
then were like thanks but no way
um and left because of the inclusion
issues they faced if there's a way to
reach out to those people
um just really aware that we're gonna
have this self-selecting bias of like
well i attend ietf and i have done for a
while
and i find the biggest issue like is the
tool
the tool system and like okay but you're
already here
so in terms of inclusivity maybe you
know you feel included enough that you
are still able to participate
so um yeah i think elliot said that we
can kind of opine as to what the reason
the main reason we don't have a a vast
um
diversity in the itfa is why people
don't feel included but obviously we're
coming at that from
our perspective and yeah just to kind of
i guess a question or like a caution
that you know we can form a
an icf working group to have a good
think about why people don't come to itf
but obviously that's
not the best breadth of representation
you could get there so
kind of a yeah for moving forward i
would just like to see some conscious
effort to reach outside of
this sdo maybe look in other sdos or
other technologies or um
look at the kind of newcomers that never
came back
thanks
yeah i would i would really like to find
some way of
capturing feedback from
not only people who attended once and
they didn't come back but people who
maybe even didn't get that far because
uh
um you know if you manage to attend and
participate at all you've
you've crossed several barriers uh and
probably
gained access to resources who could
help you move further but
we don't we have no idea about the
people who sort of don't even get that
far
and i suspect that's a very underserved
population
so i just want to say that we need to
cut the queue here after daniel
so that we can continue the presentation
after that go ahead occur
thank you um yeah i mean so some of what
other people have said i think
you know i think it's good to have a
sort of survey document that kind of
covers much of the space
these are issues which i think the
entire industry is struggling with with
more or less success in various axes um
so i think you know it's important here
to um you know when we figure out things
that we can do
like find out some find some way to do
them um so i i definitely in favor of
having some sort of mailing list and you
use that as a brainstorming um you know
kind of a
incubator or a nursery for new ideas and
then when those ideas become
uh you know become right for for work as
the um as a
as the term work did then we take them
on and actually give them an itf so
um you know i i i don't think that we're
not gonna solve like the entire thing in
one shot um
so especially in favor of like you know
uh you know i think having a venue where
we can try to like make incremental
forward progress
yeah um so uh i want to thank the
authors of the document this is uh
this is overdue for the ietf and i think
that
there's a pretty good initial statement
here um i want to point out that the
comfort zone point
that they raise um is actually pretty
critical
and the organizations that i've been
part of that have tried to do this kind
of work
have struggled a lot internally and i
can't imagine that the ietf would not
also be struggling this is going to be
difficult if we take it seriously
and if we don't take it seriously it's
pretty irresponsible
um to do that difficulty to handle that
difficulty
particularly for groups that have
already sort of
kept out people which i think includes
the ietf
we are going to need to think about
bringing in folks outside the ietf to
give us
actual critiques actually listening to
them and the process of doing that
is not something that is done for free
if you want to get somebody to come and
give you
a organizational analysis you often
legitimately need to pay them for their
time and their effort
and they're going to you're going to be
paying them to tell you things that you
don't want to hear about yourself
and so we can talk about trying to do
this ourselves and i
think we should be trying to do it
ourselves but i don't think we should
only be trying to do it by ourselves and
we need to we think about how we
allocate resources
towards um towards addressing these
problems it's not going to be for free
and it's not
going to be fun but it is necessary
just to summarize i mean i'm at least
hearing a general sense from folks that
this idea of setting up a mailing list
either reusing
one that is currently uh stagnant or
creating a new one um there seems to be
at least some momentum for that's a good
idea
and then figure out what structures to
put behind it as we go
so you know that seems like
at least a positive step and then i
think talking to lars about what kind of
structure to put
around it um since he's going to be the
stuckey
at some level in in all likelihood is
probably
a good next step as well i would say in
in
oh sorry to interrupt let me know okay
cool i i certainly want to see a mailing
this discussion but i
i think in a way it's easy for those to
get buried and so i think it might be
useful to have a mailing list
and also some expectation of having
additional meetings just maybe to raise
the level
of awareness of this that this effort is
going on
um and maybe not a long-term commitment
to doing that until we know what the
structure is but at least maybe at the
next ietf meeting um
and again uh lars
or other ads or whatever can call it
whatever they want but i'd like to see
something to raise the level of
awareness a
long drawn-out buff um
yeah that never ends the buff that never
ends
um okay uh we'll we'll go back to that
um so keith did you want to do some of
the uh
solution space stuff um and and then we
can wrap up from there
sure so these i would say these are uh
suggestions
and uh brainstorming and we
part of the hope i think is that it will
solicit other input so if you don't like
something here and you want to suggest
something alternative that's awesome
um basically i would just like to see
a lot of different ideas come forth and
some of them
may or may not be workable but don't
filter them because you think they're
not
just try to get some input into the
process
so uh next slide please uh
some disclaimers um a lot of these
problems are not
problems i think that can be fixed by
publishing rfcs
again that's kind of the normal thing
they would do and we might get in a
habit of sort of doing that
publishing documenting something that's
done is great and sometimes you will
need an rfc
but sometimes again you might need tools
sometimes you might need organizational
changes sometimes you might need
just to uh recognize existing efforts
and work with those to be sort of a to
have them dovetail with things and
sometimes you might need to solicit
support from elsewhere like i soccer
anyone else
for instance that could fund
participation for people who can't
uh as easily participate so lots of
different things
um again as we say we
probably need effort from multiple parts
of ietf in related groups
there are some past efforts which i
would like to recognize
uh and if they're still ongoing uh
maybe encourage them some some and sort
of uh
build some more cooperation uh we will
need some new efforts also
uh as i said earlier i think we need a
commitment to continuous improvement in
this area
so this is you know it's not a we do
this once and we're done
it is a change in the attitude of the
organization
but i will say that i've always seen
nietf
a genuine desire to openness and i think
it still exists i think it's
i don't want to say we've been doing it
all wrong we need to completely change
things no i think we just need to
continue
and add to what has been done before
and and continue this uh
high value of openness and realize we
can do better than we've done
and conditions have changed and
sometimes we need to change too
uh and the last problem last point about
different time scales some things can be
fixed quickly and some things
are going to need longer term efforts so
next slide please
um so this is uh an idea
not the only possible idea but a way to
promote more diversity in ietf
groups and leadership roles the
essentially rotating people through
working group chairs
would actually would train more people
it would make more people
available for potentially other
leadership roles
and uh perhaps also
a bit more churn within a working group
and maybe an additional chair within
each working group
would uh give a wider variety of people
um recourse if they didn't think
things were being handled properly so
just promote a better sense
of fairness and inclusion than perhaps
we have now
next slide
uh the suggestion also is you don't want
in general if the
if the sort of appeals chain or process
chain of a document
or a working group involves several
people from the same organization
that could be a barrier if if there are
efforts that
you know a certain company doesn't see
is in their interest and wishes to
discourage
so um we'd like to see perhaps more
diversity of
uh the sponsors of different working
group chairs
um and uh some again some rotation of
this
um next slide
uh again for iesg it would be nice
if perhaps there was uh and this would
affect nom-com
uh but that basically we we sort of you
shouldn't have more than one isg or one
more than one person from the same
organization on isg at the same time
uh and this would probably have to be
sort of gradually phased in rather than
we're going to kick some people out
but um but again
just less opportunity for
any single company to uh stack the deck
so to speak um and this the last bullet
here
again if if a working group uh is under
a particular hd
then they should be from uh different
companies
next slide
uh similar idea for iab members
uh and uh
i guess a gap between
moving from one role to another uh so
that
maybe there's just more churn next slide
um this comes from uh i think fernando's
experience in nom-com
where there was a uh strong assumption
that
uh nom-com members needed to show up for
face-to-face meetings
and uh there was even a suggestion that
i think he stepped down because he had a
hard time doing this
so uh i think it's a fair point that the
the rules that we have for selecting
nom-com while they've tried really hard
to be fair
uh they come from a somewhat different
era and
uh it's harder for people to attend all
the meetings now in in some ways than it
was for the participants back at that
time
um so in some ways that's because we're
more diverse and that's a good thing but
maybe
uh if nom com could adapt to
relying less on face-to-face contact and
more things online and also the
suggestion that
nom-com members should recuse themselves
from discussion or
of a candidate that's from their own
organization
i'd like to think that happens already
but maybe that's not the case
next one
uh fee waiver for face-to-face meetings
uh
obviously that's gonna require um
well we can understand why that might be
difficult but
uh that certainly the the cost of
participating in face-to-face meetings
is a barrier
and i think anything that we if we can
find
sponsors or ways of of uh
providing economic assistance to people
who have a hard time attending
face-to-face meetings i think that would
be a good thing
and whether that's done by the
organization making things cheaper
whether that's done by finding
you know sponsors or scholarships or
something has been
done in the past i don't know but i
think it does need to be
kind of an ongoing thing and not just
like hey you can attend one meeting and
that's
not going to really improve the
inclusion and diversity in the
organization so
next slide
so and i guess if we have discussion
time i guess we're kind of running low
um i maybe maybe it's better for a
mailing list if it's created or
something like that but
we we were sort of fernando and i were
kind of unsure about how to proceed
because this
this would be kind of a weird effort and
uh there was a question about
whether we should just sort of have lots
of standalone proposals
uh for to address different points that
have been identified
or or what and i don't know that's just
uh
probably a topic for discussion um and
that i believe
is the last slide or nearly so let's say
what i have here yes
so uh i'll defer to the chairs but i
think in some ways we'd like to discuss
we'd like to have a sense from the
from the group of uh proposals for
moving forward
uh more more perhaps than brainstorming
about solutions at this point because
we're kind of short on time
yeah um i think if you know again
it was sounding to me earlier and and uh
what you
laid out doesn't um uh go against this
is that there is some momentum for
let's get a list set up and and start
talking about it there
i think we do have to talk about
structure of moderation whether
someone's gonna be the
um chair or some sort to keep
discussions going but um do folks wanna
make any comments on these particular
and like keith said
it's probably not worth going into you
know diving into the details of any
given proposal but
um any comments on this so far
the the uh jabber room by the way has
been quite helpful uh
and and interesting uh as you were
talking uh definitely worth going back
and taking a look at
what some people said uh sorry i
couldn't follow it while i was talking
but yeah
definitely take a look andrew you wanted
to make a comment
yeah it was just maybe picking up on the
suggestion pete you made near the start
in terms of uh next steps
um well firstly i think the points you
covered
um both authors here in the paper and so
on
were good and i think a good starting
point a solid
foundation there's maybe a few things i
would add extra but
we don't need to discuss those here um i
do wonder whether a good next step
to put more substance to this though
could be uh above
uh going back to one of the points that
you suggested at the start uh
pete there's another next step um
which could be arranged i think quite
quickly so it needn't delay things
just to get just to maintain some
momentum
because just doing something on a list i
think it would lose a lot
if that's all that happened next
so that would be my suggestion right
because a bath doesn't necessarily i
mean above doesn't necessarily have to
be working performing it could be
okay we're trying to figure out the
direction that this stuff is going and
so
maybe calling it a buff um is a way to
continue momentum
yeah um
and it's certainly served again a
meeting at the next ietf
so yeah yeah yeah yeah and and then you
know maybe the
lars can give us some feedback on
different structures we might use or or
ways to approach this that might work
out best
since
anybody else
well i think we have some direction here
um i think at the very least
um we're saying let's get a mailing this
set up
and then i think um
you know uh once we get that mailing
list set up let's at least start the
conversation
um by having lars who by tomorrow will
be our
new ad sort of step in there um
and say okay you know start the
discussion of how we should structure
this
um i i think i'm hearing um
a good deal of support for going forward
with something
um but people aren't really sure what
that something would look like in the
end
um does anybody disagree with that
assessment
sounds like having a venue to continue
the discussion not only a mailing list
but
like an actual meeting is a good idea
yeah yeah yeah
um and yeah to alyssa's question why not
use the existing list i i think that's
um not a problem um
i think uh and keith can correct me if
i'm wrong but
i think the only concern was that that
had sort of a a charter of its own at
some point and we wouldn't want to
conflate it with that but beyond that if
there's an existing list and
and um you know we want to use that i
think it's perfectly reasonable
yeah i don't know i'd like to look at
the list charter just to refresh my
memory of it uh
and um sometimes it is good to start
fresh it's just
psychologically speaking but i don't
have a strong opinion about it at this
point
yeah alyssa go ahead
the description of what the list is for
can be changed
so it's not like it's set in stone
whatever whatever it says there that's
what we did with many couches
recently
all right good well we have five minutes
left
and um i wanted to give the floor to
alyssa and or um lars
our outgoing and incoming ads
and talk about uh what we're doing going
forward
um thanks so first of all i'd like to
say
a huge thank you to francesca for her
leadership of this um working group
she's as you all know
moving on to the iasg tomorrow so she's
going to be stepping down
but really appreciate everything you've
done hasn't always been easy
and um you know this is kind of an
experiment with
bringing the dispatch model to the
general area so i'm really thankful for
all of your efforts and um
lars do you want to talk about who we're
bringing on
i can it'll be pretty quick uh in the
sense that as you can imagine
the handover procedure thanks to cove it
hasn't been quite so
uh great as it has been in previous
years so i'm
still coming up to date so so for the
foreseeable future the next couple weeks
maybe until the next meeting
um continue steady as you go um
i'll keep a closer eye on what's going
on um and i think sort of we're gonna
have a discussion then uh with pete and
kirsty about
what we're going to do uh going forward
with some of these larger topics right
because it's
clear that dispatch style isn't really
suitable for them but but for now this
is what we have and i think that's where
the discussion
has been happening and should continue
and big thanks to kirsty for um being
willing to volunteer and
uh take on the role as co-chair welcome
kirsty
congratulations all around um thank you
so much
all right with that any other business
anyone want to jump in quick
three minutes of your day could be
returned to you immediately
three two one thank you all
and thank you very much to our
notetakers you did a fabulous job
yes thank you see you soon everyone
you