good morning good afternoon
good evening everyone the
grow meeting starts in one hour
the grow meeting has been postponed for
one hour
to accommodate a scheduling conflict for
one of the presenters
and because to grow agenda allows
to be shorter than two hours so
feel free to get coffee tea all at your
own cost
we start at 2 pm
central europe european time in about 58
minutes
hey job are you gonna start soon
hey jared the grow meeting has been
delayed by one hour
it will start in 56 minutes because of a
scheduling conflict with one of the
presenters
and the fact that the grow agenda was
shorter than the two hour block
allocated to it
so get some water get some tea some
cereal
i'm gonna put up a slide that indicates
that we're starting a little bit later
apologies oh okay got it
all right i'm going back to spring
hi everyone we are going to start in
about
four minutes so this is last call on
coffee
four minutes then we'll start
good morning microphone check
jeffrey i can hear you loud and clear
okay thank you
test
hello everyone welcome to
the global routing operations working
group meeting at ietf
i think today's meeting was originally
envisioned to take place in prague but
unfortunately all of us
are gathering in our houses wherever
that is on this planet
that will not take away from the joy of
this meeting
but before we start i would like to draw
attention to the itf
note well this is a reminder of itf
policies that are
in effect on various topics such as
patents
or code of conduct
if you're not familiar with the itf note
well please review
the reference documents at a later point
in time
as mentioned before we started one hour
later
this was because there was a scheduling
conflict uh
that we could not resolve at the last
minute but it appeared to
be a simpler solution to just start this
meeting one hour later
in today's meeting we're gonna cover the
administrativia some bmp
and young related reports from the
hackathon
a new initiative called bmp seamless
session
and a update on the internet draft
about as path prepending
if you have questions please
drop them in the chat or raise your
hands
in terms of staff completeness
christopher are you around
yes you are
uh so for the administrative side of
things
we need a minute taker is there a
volunteer
who wants to contribute a
summary of what is being discussed on
the ether path
i think i can probably do some etherpad
i just need to find it
it's really easy you go to itf.org you
don't click the live
but you click itf 110 online and then
you don't click agenda
but click agenda html and from there you
can
easily go to
you forgot where you raise your left
foot
all right so we got a minute taker in
the shape of christopher morrow
uh and then i will volunteer to monitor
the jabber room um
oh an update about the charter
uh at last at the last meeting we
uh discussed that a charter refresh was
requested by the area
area director and we uh
faithfully labored to produce an update
to
hopefully align the work of this working
group more with what was described
in the system and this um
charter update was discussed in the
working group and
to me it appeared that most in the
working group had
an idea of what the update meant and
what this working group does
but when it was brought forward to the
iasg refuse stage
a lot of questions came back where
apparently
there is still some work to be done to
make this charter understandable not
just by the working group participants
but also by
people who review our output so i have
it on my to-do list to go over
the feedback from the ist review round
and incorporate that feedback
into a revised charter proposal
which i'll then share with the working
group mailing list
and if people feel that that is a good
update then we'll
try again with ist so
the report the update is that the
charter update
is an ongoing process and might take a
few more months
other administrative things we need to
discuss
i think that's it for now um i'm gonna
hand over the microphone to thomas graff
who is gonna share with us an update um
the bmp yang hackathon
ok can you see and hear me
we can see and hear you take it away and
how about the screen sharing
i think i requested you just need to
grant and then it should work
yes excellent
okay can you see the screen
yes we can thank you oh excellent then i
will start with
the first slide deck on blastrix itf
1010 hackathon so i'm representing here
the bmp
and the young group so
in the hackathon on the bmp part
we were focusing this time solely on
performance
and not on functionality so here our
interest was basically we want to see
how bmp adjacency in
out locally including path working tlb
is affecting the the cpn memory
consumption
but also uh when
congestion on the network is happening
so uh
bgp start sending a lot of updates and
withdrawals
back and forth if on such
circumstances we can ensure that the hip
which is collected through bmp route
monitoring
uh is always like the mirror drip is
always
representing the same state as we have
on the network and last but not least we
also want to understand
if uh router in transit
if pmp is enabled or not uh what the
difference is in terms of bgp
without propagation delay so that's from
the
bmp part where on young push
briefly we are focusing on an open
source implementation
on these two drafts here and
focusing there also on performance tests
this was the software we've been using
throughout the
hackathon that's the the network
so on the very left hand side we had
extra v2p
generating the the bgp updates and
withdrawals
we had here 61 router being a route
reflector
another round reflector and 62 basically
a provided edge
router receiving and installing the
rounds
and basically here in orange at various
points
we were enabling bmp
either adjacency out or in pre-post
policy
or also local hip coverage and
and basically doing the described tests
so what we achieved was this time uh
on the lab environment that we have now
a fully automated test setup
in terms of generating the sequenced pgp
updates and also initializing the vmp
the right way how you want to do it
and then basically collect bmp metrics
from the network and through young push
the cpu
and memory bgp process usage
so we can monitor basically prefix loss
as a metric loss in bmp
and cpu memory usage we can go down to
bgb process
level uh as a next step for the next
hackathon
we defined that we want to do the same
tests also in a multi-vendor environment
and
cover different operating systems
and also we want to work on some
timestamping approval
this is uh basically what we did on the
udp notif
side uh here mainly the focus was
implementing
a data collection library
which was written in c and also a mockup
producer
both supporting segmentation in udp
and it has been integrated into the
pmact
open source network data collection
that was a test message we generated
into apache kafka
for young push and this was a test
performance setup we did with the young
push
very impressive the throughput we
achieved
with young push i think this is one of
the most fastest implementation
currently available so on one core
with 500 000 messages
we were achieving up to 10 11 gigabits
per second with the jumbo frames
uh so here basically the test setup
from the network side so uh as i
mentioned we enable bmp at various
points and we're
measuring the effect of the bmp what was
really
impressive was that even though we had
congestion
so a lot of uh we were generating up to
one million rounds on the network
that under no circumstance we had loss
of metrics
so in all cases basically the hip state
could be achieved that's
uh one good notice here
the other one is in regarding php
propagation delay we
discovered that the accuracy of the
timestamp being
was not accurate enough so therefore we
could not
draw final conclusions how much
impact bmp brings to the bgp propagation
delay
so there we're going to improve the time
stamping a currency and we will gonna do
the
tests in the next itf hackathon
here are some examples on
uh on the tests we did so the test setup
generated 1 million bgp vpn before
unicast passed
and it was advertising it as fast as
possible
to 10 piers and as you can see
here on the very left hand side the cpu
usage
uh basically during the bgp propagation
period
whenever bmp was off or on did not
change
but later on basically when the
propagation was through and then the
basically the cpu usage back
back down to to normal the the export
started uh to do to perform
and during the export period we
basically
had uh the same uh amount of peak
that we had during the pgp propagation
period of time
in regards of memory consumption we can
see
that once the prefixes are being
propagated uh initially we are consuming
more
memory on the pgp process but throughout
the test cycle that did not change
that was on the route reflector and
the same we got experience also on the
provider
edge router with the same
hips enabled so
no change in there
then we did another test uh basically on
the heart reflected verb
while propagating the the b2p prefixes
we were flapping the vmp
and here uh basically we could saw
that uh there are no impact in memory
nor in cpu usage when the mp session is
flapping
so what we learned this time in the
hackathon
it's basically since it's the five fifth
time we were
more prepared than we were before uh
testosterone
test automation was very important and
also
um being connected throughout the
hackathon with slack and damage teams
and of course since it's all virtual we
all miss beers and cocktails afterwards
many thanks to all the participants
any questions on the test results
[Music]
i see jeffrey stepped forward to
the queue sure has jeffrey
thank you thomas uh first a question
about the
test methodology for the reflector on
the slide there you're showing that
bmp is kicking in much later than the
bgp convergence
is that because bmp is being enabled
after the fact or is there actually a
gap there
where the system's converging in some
fashion
uh actually the the implementation
looks at the cpu usage and at that point
in time
when the congestion is is happening on
bgp
the cpu level is is higher than normal
and therefore the export is being
delayed
okay so the implementation in question
is choosing the weight
and defers advertising bmp exactly
okay thank you and my second thing is an
observation about the time stamping
i certainly cannot speak for other
people's implementations
uh no junos has second level granularity
for its timestamps it does not
waste the extra space to keep know
something no less than that
we put in effectively a increasing
counter in the
uh additional field to make sure that if
we have more than one event within the
same second
that you get something of no use you
know the sequencing
but so the the two observations are that
the timestamp
will be closer to second level
granularity for at least one
implementation and the second
observation is that
the time stamping is going to be
somewhat separated from the bgp events
in some cases based on pipelining so if
you just think about
the time it takes for a packet to be
placed on the wire by a transmitter
and maybe tcp delays before it's
processed in the queue uh potentially
with some additional uh wiggle room
you know within a second granularity as
is being run
through the pgp pipeline
okay thanks thank you very much for the
input we
take that as a notice for the next
tested
and we do saw different vendor
implementations have
different implementations on on
time stamping and we noticed that the
juniper juno has does both seconds and
milliseconds
great any more questions or remarks
if there are no additional questions at
this point in time
i would like to invite you to
uh continue with the bmp seamless
session
uh presentation sure then i will live
over to the second slide deck in here
can you see the slides
yes we can perfect so
i will start since i'm representing here
swiss comma give a
short overview where we stand currently
on network telemetry
data collection i think probably the
easiest is to look
on the very right hand side the three
graphs
uh basically the first one shows how
much
how many messages per second we are
producing in terms of ip
fix the second one in yang push
and the third one into uh bmp
and as you observe that bmp is quite
bursty and if you look at the count
basically
uh if you have a burst
that you can easily have been higher
than
the highly fixed data collection
so from an evolution point of view i can
say
that as the end of last year we were
collecting roughly two and a half
thousand uh from two and a half thousand
devices
uh network telemetry delta with bmpi
prefix and yank push
and we had up to one million uh messages
per second
in peak and we are considering uh
onboarding
up to 40 000 devices this year
and then with up to 10 million message
per seconds
and from this 40 000 most of them
38 000 we will have bmp enabled
so if we look at
from this two and a half thousand
devices only
300 currently have bmp enabled and those
300 devices contribute basically
in peak to 600 thousands messages per
second but in average
very low 8 000 messages per second so
that
gives you more or less a picture uh
how much data is being exposed from
from the network and the burstiness of
bmp
especially with the adjacent silicon
and this is the point which we tried to
address in this draft and or
basically to optimize so uh
one angle is we wouldn't we want to try
to avoid data duplication and
uh the reason why we want to avoid data
duplication is because
in the b2p network basically the amount
of pgp pass or in a service provider
steadily increasing
but also on the other hand thanks to the
new support of emp now results
are json series in adjacency out also
locally
has been it's been supported so
therefore
uh basically more and more matrix
are exposed and those matrix thanks to
the tlvs
contain more and more additional
information so
overall basically the amount of matrix
from the routers is steadily increasing
so duplication needs to be prevented and
we see
that those duplications happening
most of the time when the bmp session is
re-established and we
see basically there are two main
contribution factors why
this bmp session is reestablished one
is a grief loss of connectivity between
bmp client
and server and the other one because the
bmp server
is taken in maintenance being restarted
and then the bm precision is
reestablished
so if we look a bit more closely
into the bmp session handling so section
3.3 in rfc 78 54 describes basically
that
if the tcp session towards the the bmp
server is established
or closed then also the bmp session is
established and closed
and in section five uh basically
uh that it is described that once the
bmp session is established the initial
rip dump withdrawal monitoring messages
is performed
and this rib dump is performed
regardless if a bmp session is
established
or re-established
uh tcp fast open is defined in rfc 7413
and uh basically it gives us the unique
capability that we can distinguish
between a niche
initial tcp establishment or a
re-establishment of the tcp session
and this draft is not only suggesting to
use tcp fast
open for the bmp session but also
on the bmp application on the bmp client
extending the bmp session life cycle
so the bmp session should not be closed
immediately when the tcp session is
closed
there should be a configurable timeout
value
and if within this timeout the tcp
session is
reestablished then basically the bmp
session is considered
still up another
angle is that with that the
client needs to buffer messages between
the tcp
re-establishment and the bmp session is
declared terminated when either the
buffer is full
or the timeout is reached of the bmp
session closure
what we want to wanted to preserve in
this draft is the key principle of pmp
that is it is still a unidirectional uh
collection protocol
uh the suggested the
extensions are optional so either
the tcp fast open tcp session is
supported
or not and as described
in already in rfc 7854
uh that a buffering on the
router can happen uh
and in most implementations today we've
seen that it
it is happen and this draft is making me
makes basically use of such a bmp buffer
so the message can be preserved
between the tcp establishments
so this is zero zero version we are
looking very much feedback from the
go mailing a mailing list we would
love to hear your comments and feedbacks
and also
if this draft has married or not
and whatever you think about tcp fast
open
or whatever you would prefer to have an
implementation be done within the
bmp application but keep in mind
if the implementation needs to be done
in the
bmp application we cannot preserve
the main principle of bmp that is a
unidirectional
protocol
that's all from my side any questions
remarks feedback
speaking as just working group
participants i
would encourage you to continue this
work
i i think that the effects on real life
networks of
session flapping and the consequences
for
subordinate downstream systems should
not be overlooked
i see an analogy to the session id
uh in rrdp and how sessions are
resumable in
rtr uh similar to how tcp fast open
cookies
are handled and i think uh mechanisms
like this
are are useful and arguably help
conserve
resources so i would encourage you to
pursue this work thank you very much
i see a question on the chat
lars pen asks how much down time would
currently deployed buffer sizes allow
for
if you are not currently in a burst
uh we were thinking about that and in
the draft we were specifying a default
value
of 60 seconds so the main goal is
basically
if you have a small interruption in
connectivity between client and server
or you just want to restart the pmp
server
that within that period of time the
router should be able
to do to buffer the matrix but of course
um memory is limited on the bmp client
and therefore you cannot buffer for
unlimited time so
if the time would be longer or the
buffer
would be filled then you basically fall
back to the
previous principle that the bmp session
is
normally established again
answer your question
large types thanks cool
thanks any other questions
i see that there are some
implementers in the room and i was
wondering if
maybe the juniper people or cisco people
have previous experience with tcp
fast open would this be an entirely new
feature or is it something that where
existing frameworks can be leveraged in
the operating system
jeffrey so i i don't know if we actually
support
tcp fast open in either of our bit two
big stacks
uh i'm vaguely familiar with the feature
uh the thing i would i guess comment to
thomas is that
uh the amount of state that needs to be
sort of kept
in flight is stuff that the colonel
would have already owned anyway from the
tcp
portion of things and you know maybe
some
state that bmp had serialized at that
point
but anything that's not in that category
is basically
uh unserious state that's still in the
state machine
and you know that shouldn't cost any
additional memory
so the main considerations from my
perspective without having
read the rfc in detail for some time is
that
really as long as your colonel can hide
the details about the session
being lost from the application to some
extent
i don't expect there to be much
difficulty in implementing this so i
think that this would probably be a
good mechanism as you know if the rfc
covers the necessary things
if there's any chance for any lost state
the problem we have here is that there's
really no way to easily recover this
sort of thing because we don't have
sequencing present in the bmp protocol
so those sorts of losses are problematic
but if that's not the case this is not a
bad thing
i think the major challenge for most
vendors for real routers rather than
you know easy to host stacks is that
non-stop routing tcp extensions
are very messy and complicated as it
already is
and to some extent well i think that the
fast open stuff has uh
some good balances with those features
the interactions are already very
complicated
i see very useful thank you for your
feedback
this this working group should realize
that the seamlessness can be solved
at multiple layers of the stack so the
current proposal
is to leverage existing work in for
instance the linux tcp kernel stack to
allow to to resume a session but it's
not the only path we can also
resume the session within the bmp
protocol itself
and there's pros and cons to both
approaches but both approaches
will will give us the same result namely
avoiding duplicating uh
avoiding resending information that was
sent previously and is still in the
buffers of the client
but with this in mind
let's just explore one path and if if we
somehow
encounter an issue or if there are
negative interactions with
uh graceful restart or
who knows what what crazy things uh
exist in the wild
then we can can revisit it and
the resumption mechanism can be put at a
different layer
jeffrey has comments graceful restart
should not be an issue
i hope so
good then thank you very much
thank you for your time thomas
and with that i'm looking into the room
to find michael mcbride to give
us an update on
aspar prepending
the floor is yours
i can see you but not hear you yes
yes we have audio i just took off
bluetooth yeah okay good
do you want to share your screen yeah
let me do that
we did you see that
let's give it another second on my
screen it says a screen share
is being started
so i'm not seeing the slides yet
i'm seeing your desktop if you go full
screen i think
yeah perfect all right i'm going to mute
myself take it away
all right very good so i thought it'd be
a good idea to just to give a
brief update we did present this draft
last itf
we've received many comments thank you
so much we've incorporated all of them
we just received one this morning from
thomas thank you very much we'll
incorporate that comment in the memory
section of this draft
in the next rev that that comment was
regarding
um bgp's impact on ipfix
uh netflow and so
jacob uh wrote that section and we'll
make sure we get
that section updated so thank you thomas
and we've had some we've also had
several people uh
several authors changing affiliations so
we updated that as well
so the background just real briefly is
that doug midori
he did present as path prepending at a
nanog
and there was participants asked if
there was any sort of a pcp
coming out of ietf or any other sdo and
there was uh the answer is no and so we
thought it'd probably be a good idea
in this working group to have a opinion
on es path prepending the problem is
that
excess of aspartame has caused
routing issues on the internet and so we
intend in this document to provide some
guidance with how best to utilize the
as path prepending in order to avoid
negatively affecting the internet and to
also offer some alternatives
we've also per the working groups
requests anonymized
the real world examples
and we've used documentation prefixes
and asses
we've included a variety of use cases
where it's
as path pre-painting is in use today
including preferring one
isp over another isp preferring one asbr
over another asbr
utilizing one path exclusively and
another
solely as backup to signal to indicate
one path may have a different
amount of capacity than another
and then isp doesn't accept traffic
engineering news and bgb
communities so pre-panning is the only
option
so some of the examples of the problems
um again you can look at the draft but
um
you know you could have an attacker
wanting to intercept or manipulate
traffic to a prefix and it enlists a
data center to
allow announcements of that same prefix
with a fabricated shorter
as path and that malicious route would
be preferred due to the shortened ps
path and that
has happened um and then there's also
been some
routing leaks from one country that are
being preferred over another country
because of excessively prepended aspas
and in that case illegitimate routes are
preferred
can be preferred over legitimate routes
um and as was mentioned and this is the
comment that
thomas made was long as fast can cause
an increase in memory usage among pgp
speakers
there are alternatives to aes path
prepend you can use predefined
communities that are mapped to a
particular behavior
when propagated you can announce more
specific routes on the preferred
path um robert
is a fan of using igp
or egp origin which
takes precedence over an incomplete
origin code and keeping the
path lengths the same and so we include
that in the draft
there may be others but i think probably
that's all important but i think
probably the most important is the best
practices
and in bold here is what we've added
since the last
rev jeff houston offered these
suggestions and so we included those
um so let me just go over them real
quickly so network operators should
should ensure pre-painting is absolutely
necessary as many networks
have excessive prepending and it is best
to enumerate when the routing policies
are intended to achieve
what the routing policies are intended
to achieve before concluding that
prepending is a solution
and he also pointed out that the
neighbor you are preparing may have an
unconditional preference for customer
routes and pre-pending doesn't work and
so it's helpful to check with neighbors
to see if they'll honor
their pre-pinned and so that was a good
point that we included
we based upon analysis that doug
had done that he presented at maddog and
we included the draft that there's
no need to prevent more than the then
five asses
and we include a diagram that shows that
um ninety percent of as path lengths are
five as
passes or fewer in length don't prevent
prepend asn that you don't own
and prepending to all is
is needless
so we welcome more comments um
including right now if anybody has any
uh in the chat i see a comment from
jeffrey haase
for aspaf pre-pending communities are
effectively scoped
one as over which doesn't help stop
asens
in many cases
jeffrey perhaps uh elaborates
uh sure
presentations in this working group as
an example people talk about their
community policies people are very
strong about how they actually do their
filtering on stuff
you know the chair as an example is part
of an organization that you know very
strictly scrubs the communities that
pass through their system
so the the problem with the uh
with using communities to shape traffic
is that if you can't
get your behavior that you desire using
some sort of
community addressed to your adjacent isp
there's probably not anything you can do
about the next hop over
so for traffic control for you know as
single hop communities can be very very
helpful
especially if you're doing things like
selectively leaking more specifics
but once you get past that point the
practice that has held up over the years
you know for more than one hop
unfortunately has been pre-pending
and while i generally agree that the
number five is probably uh
fairly reasonable the sort of challenge
that you
end up running into which jeff houston
would recognize as a bjp wedgie
uh from the rfc that he put out on the
topic
is that uh if you don't have something
that is strongly prepended sometimes
near the beginning you know it's like
maybe if you think you only need string
maybe two asses away
if you only add an additional two asses
into the path there's a
there's a chance that route selection
may cause something the wedge a little
bit earlier
one or two asses closer to things
and unfortunately a lot of these
headaches just have to do with the
topology of the internet
we've gone very much closer to
hub and spoke uh the core has now
continued to condense over the years
but if you happen to be a stub as that
was purchasing multiple streams of uh
you know service from different
providers sometimes if you're
not close enough to the core your
traffic forwarding is not as you expect
and
especially as a smaller provider your
circuit costs can be wildly different in
terms of
how much you pay for such things
okay next up in the cube ben madison
can you hear me okay perfect go ahead
um so i just want to um make a point
about what
jeff was talking about about the scope
of communities
um i'm not sure that that
one hop radius is true in general
um certainly for us we scrub
anything that's um in the well-known
space or starts with a you know
starts with a private as and we're very
strict about
what we accept in our name space
um but everything other than that we
leave
untouched so for example one of our
customers
can send a community in one of our
transits name
space and expect that to be honored
at our transits boundary um
and i know of customers that do use that
i think the limitation is that if your
transit happens to be a
happens to be a you know inverted commas
tier one
or a transit free network the next hop
over is going to be a parent
or another customer and then unlikely to
honor traffic engineering communities of
any sort
um but i don't think that the i don't
think that the scope is limited by
virtue
of any scrubbing that necessarily
happens
at the your immediate upstream's edge
um whether or not that's worth including
in the draft or not i'm not sure but it
certainly does
mean that whether you've got
alternatives gets complicated
um i think that i think the additional
text that you've
you've added about the fact that people
will typically
use local prep to prefer customer routes
is important
and i think you can probably go a bit
further than it sounds like you've gone
and point out the you know save
resorting to very very aggressive
aggressive de-aggregation you may find
that there are scenarios where you just
can't make the traffic come in the
direction you want it to and you've got
to make peace with that or change
provider
there isn't always a way of making it
come in
the way that you want it to because
we're talking about destination
forwarding oriented protocol
thank you so those are more good
comments
something along the lines of you may be
up against a brick wall you should
probably stop banging your head on it
sure okay
a challenge with documents of this type
is that there is
a multitude of
um audiences
that that have to interpret this
recommendation
and apply it to their local situation
and on the one hand there's the group of
people who
self-inflict harm by needlessly
prepending themselves
which negates the efforts of say origin
validation
but on the other hand there is of course
legitimate use cases of traffic
engineering
or traffic engineering use cases that
applied in the past but conflicts did
not get updated
so it's a bit tricky how to navigate the
what what it is we want to teach the
reader
um and i i feel that the number five
appears uh almost arbitrary
but on the other hand some
recommendation is perhaps better than
fake hand waving keep it as short as
possible
but these are commons uh with just my
working group participant haddon
i see that rudiger joins the queue
rudicar the floor is yours
ridiculous i cannot hear you
there seems to be some kind of
connection issue
some there's been some good comments on
the uh chat as well that will uh
yeah let's roll up to those yeah see if
we can uh
just we we should be able to add some of
your comments jeffrey and others
into the draft as well as useful
so large print says can you explain why
the average as path length
affects the number of used prepend sizes
if i want to differentiate between the
preference of
n peers i need up to n minus 1 different
prepending sizes
from my own experience the average
internet path length should just limit
the maximum useful difference between
any two of those and minus one
sizes yeah so the thought there was that
you know if there's
maximum or if there's an average of five
a.s paths in their net then
pre-pending ten times doesn't do you any
good that's the general
reasoning behind us putting in there um
and to another comment on you know if if
five is arbitrary it i don't
i'm not sure how arbitrary that is and i
think i think the draft is trying to
show that it's not that arbitrary
because that's
you know ninety percent of the as path
lengths
in the internet um are five as
uh paths or less so um
that's why we put that number in there
if that's if you think that's not a wise
thing then
um we can avoid doing so but like you
said i think we should
have some recommendation in there
yeah i i see friction here between
having a recommendation that
currently 2021 is sensible
but on the other hand it is hard coding
a constant
and this is always an internet drafts a
and a balance must be struck what what
is
uh useful in this this context
um i think largest comments
another approach might be to say that
you should not prepend
more times than you have ebgp neighbors
that might apply to some
smaller isps as a useful rule of thumb
or perhaps there are other mechanisms to
arrive at the number five but not
prescribe it as five as the magic number
but i'm doing a lot of talking uh let's
go back to the queue i saw
alexander and then randy bush so we'll
go through it in in that order
alexander it's your turn
do you i can hear you
great well paul is good to hear me too
so
speaking about this draft is not
limiting to this draft
as far as i as i understand the
idea is to limit
the propagation of the leaked roots
by uh making the
length of ice path of the village roots
uh less or just
preventing it from uh being
meaningful meaningless uh big so it's
easy so
the idea that you should not prepare
more than two or three times or whatever
it's uh very clear and there is another
side of the middle and maybe it's a good
uh
opportunity to cite it in one of the
documents
that if if you uh here you are speaking
about from the perspective of
the victim of the source of the uh
route of the prefix of the other space
uh
whose traffic is uh redirected by the
route leg
this is another side the sender
the receiver of the route league
who sends the traffic you know into a
black hole
or in them in the middle uh it
doesn't really matter and
there is another simple stupid idea here
that if you have a flat policy
i mean that uh for example if you are a
content provider if you have
just same local preference values for
all your peers
you are getting really good protected
again against rotlicks
because the route league will have a
bigger ice path and
you know it will be
it will not become a best route for you
so maybe a suggestion that
do not use multiple uh layers
of our local preference for example
making
one layer for i access another layer for
the
uh private peers it's
really not that's useful and can become
harmful
i'm not sure it's if it should be part
of this document
but maybe it's a good idea to be cited
yeah maybe so thanks we'll think about
that
comments questions i
took my hand down because my elbow got
tired
um the floor is yours if we can't
describe a clear and simple algorithm
for the recommendation of how many to
prepend to whom
then we shouldn't be talking about it at
all
right then we're blowing smoke
so i think we should be discussing
a clear and simple algorithm
for how many prepends
speaking as participants i think i agree
that a draft merely stipulating
too much is harmful without us being
able to quantify what too much
means in a various number of
scenarios is indeed not productive but
i hope this working group will be able
to come up with
a recommendation because
there are measurable effects to people
pre-pending more than is good for their
own environment
then medicine the microphone is yours
so i agree that it in a perfect world
would be able to set out exactly
how the reader can arrive at the magic
number
but i don't think that there is
necessarily a one-size-fits-all way of
determining that because it's
dependent partly on where in the
internet you're performing
the calculation um i don't
think that there's anything wrong with
saying in the draft that in 2021 that
number appears to be approximately five
but if you're reading this in ten years
time your mileage may vary
um i think that's a reasonable
compromise between
additional complication and making it
relatively useful
um just quickly another point that i
forgot to make when i was
talking last i think that the the stuff
around the origin
code um is a little silly
um i think mostly the reason that it's
effective
is because most receivers tend to just
ignore it because it doesn't actually
change their path selection process
meaningfully and i think that if people
started actively using it at scale to do
traffic engineering
you'd find that people just reset it on
their borders and the effect goes away
i don't think that's a recommendation
that we should be making to people
okay
next up jared march
uh yeah i find myself agreeing with uh
with
randy and ben to some extent of
the shape of the internet has changed
significantly over the
past you know 25 years or so that i've
been meddling with it
and the
question of what the diameter is and
what service providers support
what and have what capability i think is
is something that lends itself to how
how do we measure this
how can we describe what is harmful
and then how can you know we've been
damaged
uh in the past with prior
implementations and so we have
uh asp limitations implemented
in the 20940 network
that limited limit as paths to 128
which is probably a safe protectionist
number but is also driven by prior
software defects
and so identifying a number that is
that is appropriate and based upon what
service providers have what capabilities
i think is uh
and and coming back to that with a way
to describe that to protocol
implementers
to say this this number is okay and this
number is not i think is
is going to be really difficult for this
group to
undertake just based on
you know the role and position the
apology of the internet
that's it
thanks uh
two people are in the queue randy and
jeffrey
we'll start with randy and then there's
an opportunity for mike to answer
if there is an answer and then it's up
to jeffrey
randy go ahead
uh ben if where
i am in the topology is part of
the consideration for how i prepend
then that's fine i didn't say the
algorithm is based strictly on how many
peers i have or what color wednesday
is but if we can't give
solid guidance then
this isn't going to last and saying this
worked well in 2021 but
you know take a flier in 2023
that's not really reasonable i think
if we can't give guidance here then we
really don't know what we're talking
about
jeffrey
uh so the the one thing i will follow up
on from
the jared invention that might be worth
discussing in the document
is the bugs that have happened from
pre-bending
and the uh the single biggest one is
just simply
you know segment overflow and the as
path as path basically
says here's the number of ass for this
segment type
there could be at most 255 in a given
segment if you want to go to
you know no two segments in a row that
are the same type
you have to add a new segment and an
awful lot of people had bugs
you know for a number of years that
didn't get exercised until people like
ripest are playing around with these
things experimentally
which people found to their horror when
the internet started crashing
so it might be worthwhile mentioning
that uh
this is one of the possible contributors
towards long
paths being bad not necessarily that
it's broken in bgp but
implementations often are broken in this
respect and something to watch out for
i agree we'll add that and it looks like
there's different opinions on using
origin code so we'll have to
work that out as a working group
the difference in opinion on origin code
what i understood from razor's
contribution is that he merely posted it
that
it is possible to it may be possible to
use the origin code
as an alternative mechanism to
accomplish the same
as what was set out to accomplish with
the pre-pending
not that origin code is a
better practice than prepending just
that it's
it was enumerating was my
understanding of it
but yes origin codes is not a reliable
mechanism
uh just as as path length also is not a
reliable mechanism for traffic
engineering in the wild wild
incidents
so since we're deprecating uh as sets
from the as path attribute does the
group feel that that frees up
for longer as paths no i'm calling
joking
um mike
my summary of of uh the feedback
on this presentation appears to be that
the effort should be focused on seeing
if
nobody's questioning whether 5 is an
appropriate number
today based on the data it was derived
from
but to make the document more future
proof it would be good to
set out to see if the number five can be
constructed from different data sources
uh that perhaps are more applicable to
the local environment
in which operator recites reading the
future bcp
the chairs are available if you
want additional help in this regards or
maybe
you have goals and plans but i look
forward to continued updates on this
draft
great thanks yeah this has been very
helpful
thank you for your time mike
um with that we have arrived at the
top of the hour and i would like to
conclude this grow session
the next itf session will be or will not
be
in san francisco but it will be numbered
itf 101
and we hope to see everybody there again
thank you for your time today thank you
for your contributions in chat
and at the microphone and i wish you
a pleasant day
the chats are saved yes
so how do we end a meeting
it's going to be a long while because we
need wraparound to get to 101 in san
francisco
sorry can you repeat
san francisco will be 111 not 101.
oh did i mispronounce
rudiger i could hear you for a brief
second
uh leaving the meeting i guess
the uh the chair just leaves the room
i will try that
we can hang out here close your brush
yes we watch it
okay no it did not work
but well okay that's that's not really a
hard problem
by the way are you enough you said five
was
the right number right now please write
down
the justification for that
algorithmically
and i am closing my browser ciao