and welcome to the uh the hackathon
closing
hope uh hope you had a good week and
uh we have uh thanks to all you for
joining i see we have a good list of uh
presentations lined up i want to wait
just a couple minutes for those people
who are still joining
[Music]
so
while we are waiting for people to join
i want to uh
just cover a couple things that i'll
cover again at the end
but i figured uh you know some of you
may not be able to stay for the whole
time although i hope you can
so let me just uh briefly share this
first of all there is a
survey um for the hackathon
it it the link has been added to the
wiki so if you go to the hackathon wiki
uh you'll find it but i also put it here
in the slides and i've
uploaded these um to github so you can
grab them from there as well
then the other thing i wanted to mention
is a draft
um and actually uh
uh first shared this and had it
discussed at the last ietf meeting
and there's been some updates to it now
and it'll be discussed again in the uh
working group and it's basically
covering the hackathon
how it works uh kind of as a
from a process perspective just to
capture
you know this is how we run the
hackathon and why we do things the way
we do
and also part of the thing the reason
why
it was created was and the whole schmoon
working group
has to do with um
[Music]
uh you know dealing with meeting online
as we are now
both for the itf meeting for the
hackathon and so
the draft isn't specific to that it
really covers the hackathon overall
but um also aspects that are either new
or different
when you're running it online so i would
appreciate
uh if folks here while everything's
still very fresh in your mind if you
could take a look at that
it's it's not very long it's maybe you
know 10 pages or something like that
with a lot of
kind of boilerplate stuff so it's a
pretty quick read
and if you have any thoughts i'd love to
hear them on the list
a pull request uh it is on github
there's there's the link you'll find
that at the
on the data tracker
and with that i think i will go back to
the start and we will get started here
okay so um just a reminder
some people maybe didn't attend the
beginning but i think it's always good
to
uh you know attend the kickoff i think
it's always good to just recap why we're
here and that's really
uh you know for the hackathon the whole
idea is to advance the pace and
relevance of
of ihf standards um
to really bring together the that spirit
of collaboration that we get with the
open source community
and uh and work on code that's related
to the things we either have
standardized or in the process of
standardizing or have some ideas about
you know anything really related to ietf
standards
and uh the goals of that are both to
you know make the standards better right
because we're getting feedback from
actually having uh coded things but also
just to attract
developers and new people into ietf and
to
take some of the stuff that you know to
progress
really from just uh the specification
which is great
to if you actually have some code that
can help you get started
uh with implementing or adding support
for the draft or with testing things
about you know a protocol
that's all great too so those are the
the big drivers for the hackathon i want
to remind everyone of the note well
we talked about this in the opening that
the code you work on is governed by
whatever the license is of that code
hopefully it's open source code that
makes it easier for everyone to
collaborate and share but anyways the
you have to look at the license and the
rules and restrictions there regarding
the code
but when it comes to the presentations
that we'll all be enjoying
during the closing those are you know
your
your normal ietf contributions and fall
under the note well
okay the agenda so we have two hours i
don't think we'll need the full
two hours but based on the number of
presentations
uh my guess is we'll take a bit more
than uh one hour
so you know one hour plus we'll
definitely finish before
the end of the two hours and we'll have
some time for discussion
at the end and
the way it's going to work is we're
basically going to run through
the list of projects in the results uh
presentation schedule
and this is on the wiki if you want to
take a look at it i might have a
slightly dated version here
but it's pretty close i just grabbed
this maybe an hour ago
and the plan is to just run through an
order uh we'll start at the top
we'll work through them if anyone's um
not able to present during their slot
we'll try to go back again at the end
or if someone knows in advance that they
have a timing issue and need to present
in a different
order we can do that too but you know
this is just to make it a little bit
easier for everyone to to know when to
expect to hear something
or when to talk and and the idea is that
each of you can drive your own
presentation
so when your slots coming up if you can
put yourself in the queue and then share
your screen show your audio
share your video that would be fantastic
and if you run into any problems with
that i'm here to help you along
barry's here and uh alessandra i see is
here
uh from me techo so we should have all
our
support that we need to run this
smoothly
just a quick reminder here the the
presentations as we mentioned before
the ideas these should be quick
presentations short presentations just
covering some highlights
uh kind of up level to um present what's
real
you know relevant to the ietf community
even to folks who aren't deeply involved
in the technology you're working on
the idea that you can this is just to
give people an introduction to what you
did
and share some of the highlights and uh
and then you know people can always
reach out to you for those more detailed
discussions
but you know we like to focus on not
only like what we actually what worked
but just what did we learn in general
and especially feedback that you're
going to bring into your working group
that may help with the work that you're
the working group's doing on various
drafts and standards
and then also it's nice to see when you
worked with some open source code or
with people from an open source
community
or from another sdo because what we
found is that
code is actually a great way to
collaborate across the the typical ietf
sort of boundaries of a draft and a
small community
it's a way of expanding uh the scope
there because
we know there's a lot of great code all
over the place that isn't just
relevant to the ietf community it's
relevant to other communities as well
so this is a great way to engage with
them and we like to just
you know be aware of that that's
happening
okay all of the projects should be
uploaded to
this repo in the ietf github
uh if if you haven't uploaded yet that's
okay you can
present just you know the version that
you have on your laptop that's fine
but just you know afterwards please go
ahead and make sure it's been uploaded
and if you've already uploaded it that's
ideal
because that way people can follow
follow along with your presentation if
they want to
so um this
repo will remain open after the
hackathon closing
is done and so you know if you find
things
if you continue to work on your code the
next few days whatever
that's great you can update your
presentation to capture that
okay so with that uh we're going to get
started on the
the presentations um this again is a
snapshot
i'm going to pull up the actual list and
go off of that what's on the wiki but it
should be quite close
and any questions before we
begin
okay uh so why don't we get started then
uh application aware
uh gsr v6 networking
hello hello yeah
yep i can can hear you and let me stop
sharing so you should be able to
share your screen you see your video
don't see your screen yet
okay great
how to share uh
you should i've just granted you
that so you should see something and pop
up asking me
when you see my okay can you see my
screen
yep looks good okay thanks charles
uh hello everyone my name is jaiway mao
i'm glad to introduce our project for
you
it is application aware gsrv6 networking
our plan is to develop gsrv6
on the linux kernel and combine gsrv6
with apn6 here are some related iutf
drafts
for your reference and we have built up
some open
communities for you now let's talk about
gsrv6 first
as we know srv6 is the latest routing
technology nowadays
gsrv6 can resolve a critical problem
of srv6 the transmission overhead
of srv6 is too high for example
if you want to use a streaked te tunnel
with 10
seeds the seeds will occupy 160 bytes
in your packets that is not accepted in
interactive control and iot scenarios
which package length is under 128 bytes
so how about gsr v6 the key point is
gsrv6 can reduce 75 percent
transmission overhead that means the
size of seed list
is cut down moreover gsrp6
can reuse the locators of srv6
that means if you want to deploy gsrv6
you don't need to apply for new ipv6
address blocks
and advertise new ipv6 routes into your
network
so you can deploy gsrv6
incrementally and on your demand it is
full
compatible with srv6
by the way there are above 12 vendors
their devices have passed
test of gsrv6
next let's have a look at apn6
avn6 allows devices to identify
application related information and use
ipv6 extension headers to convey
the information along the packet to
traverse the network
the information contains app id sla
level
bandwidth delay requirements and so on
so network can quickly adapt to specific
sla requirements
of different applications okay based on
gsrv6 and
apn 6 we present application aware
gsrv6 networking it combines
their advantages to enable
application-aware
fine-grained strict te with lower
transmission overhead
in this hexane we implement a demo for
each
based on linux kernel and huawei router
in detail for gsr v6 we build a kernel
module to
identify apn 6 information and select
the most
suitable gsr v6 te tunnel for specific
application flows after that
you can encapsulate gsrv6 routing header
to packets
for apn 6 we developed we developed
some functions to encapsulate apn 6
options with application specific
information
in ipv6 hall by hub options header
we set up a three layer topology for
this demo
and we tested the performance between
srv6
and gsiv6 in this demo
we programmed three te pass for
three kinds of applications all of the
paths
are with above 10 hops that means
there are above 10 seats in the seed
list
the three applications are first file
downloading
with security tracking in a service
function chain
second interactive control which is
using
leave and short messages third
high definition video on demand
for the result of performance test we
can see
first forwarding rate of gsr v6
is 55 higher than srv6
second for the interactive control
scenario
which package contains only about 128
bytes in the payload
the transmission overhead is reduced by
50 percent third we can see
the bandwidth utilization of gsr v6
is 10 higher than srv6
finally for this hexane activity we can
bring some feedback to
working group the most important is
gsrp6 can improve the utilization
and value of bandwidth significantly
and guarantee sla better for
applications
by the way we have made some future
plans
we plan to make some pog tests in wider
aerial networks such as cine in china
and you are welcome to join us to
improve this demo together
okay here are my teammates if you have
interest
for our project please send us an email
thanks for your listening and thanks to
my teammates thank you
okay well great presentation yeah thanks
for getting us off to a good start
does anyone have any questions before we
move on to the next presentation
okay well great thank you very much
and thank you thank you very much
we'll move on to network telemetry
thomas
can you see my screen uh yes
looks good perfect excellent
so uh yeah i'm representing bmp
and uh young push from the grow and net
conf
working group so uh here
uh our plan on our hackathon plan
is uh we are
on the bmp side we were focusing on
on performance so basically we are
interested
just one uh if i could interrupt you
quickly at least on my side as
uh pop up on top of your the title of
the screen
about sharing maybe just minimize that
or move it yeah that'd be great
thanks sure i think let's put it
somewhere else yeah
okay great thanks a lot so
on the bmp side our focus is basically
uh we want to understand what is the
impact
of bmp onto the bgp process
especially if uh jason silip in
out with local vip and path marking is
enabled
onto cpu and memory consumption
on the other hand uh one of the
interesting part of
bmp is that you can get an exact copy
of the bgp rip state and we want to
understand
here uh if when
b bgp congestion is here
uh if under all circumstances
we can rely that there is no loss
present and on the other hand when bmp
is enabled
we will also understand what kind of
impact it has
on the bgp route propagation
so that's about the bmp part
so on yang push
there basically we're working on an open
source implementation
of udp node event distributed
distributed notif
so we have a data collection implement
data collection implementation and also
a mockup
publisher and we are we were
integrating it into the pmacct open
source
network data collection uh
in this hackathon we were also focusing
here on
testing the efficiency and the
throughput uh
on on udp notif uh
the main focus on udp notif is that
basically yang push can be implemented
directly on line cards on the network
processors
so here important for us is that we can
maximize uh efficiency and throughput
this is the software we are used in this
hackathon
[Music]
this the network so here on the very
left hand side
this is basically where we are ingesting
the bgp
vpn v4 unicast routes
uh these two routers are basically route
reflectors
and on the very right hand side this is
the
provided edge routers and these little
boxes in here show basically
uh the bmp coverage so
what we are exposing towards the
data collection which is in here
so on the lab environment side uh i mean
this is not the first time we were
participating the the idf hackathon
so we are from each academe steadily
uh improving so in this time we were
focusing on test ultimate
automatization so we are
in basically generating uh
sequenced pgp vpne for unicast routes
uh we are basically before we are
starting test
initializing the bmp state
collecting then the bmp metrics from the
network
to see to detect any loss or delay
and with young push we are measuring the
impact on cpu on
memory onto the bgp process
so here this time focus was on bmp
route monitoring where we wanna
which we wanna use to detect any loss of
metrics
and also delay into the bgp
propagation now
we are the next step where we want to
improve in this test that we use this
time
uh we were focusing on huawei vrp
we have also is6r and tuning patchunos
in the testbed
present but because of the time
restriction we were not able to use it
so in the next
itf hackathon the next step is also do
interoperability tests among vendors
and since timestamps are important
on detecting delay
here we saw some improvements we'd like
to add in the next testbed
on the yangpush site and we were
focusing
on the implementation on the udp notif
here uh we have an implementation now
open sourced
in c it's supporting the segmentation
option and it's in integrated into pmact
it will be soon after the weekend
available on github
below the github link
and we are working now since several
months towards this goal so this is
basically the first
udp notif message which we captured
during the itf hackathon in a kafka
json message so this
was like like a like a child's birth
moment for us that we finally reached
this goal
from a throughput point of view
in udp notif uh to be honest this was
like
uh really a big thing
uh for us uh because one of our
big aim was to bring performance and
scale into
uh young push so in this test setup
uh we had one
uh we were focusing on one core and we
want to understand
how many um basically how much
how many megabits with 500 000 messages
we can bring through and depending on
the message size we were able to
to to get a throughput between 400
megabits and 11.5 gigabits per seconds
and to be honest compared to what we
have today
in our networks uh with grpc this is a
huge difference
and i think this is a game changer
now back on on bmp
uh so on our test cases we were focusing
on the route reflectors and provider
edge routers
were json cited in pre-policy localhip
and adjacency outpost policy was enabled
with path marking support
and one of the key findings was
on the stress conditions basically
that the cpu increased after
the bgp was converged so
and for the memory part there was a
slight
overall increase throughout the test
cases and i will show
some graphs afterwards
and what was
pretty impressing and was also a big
surprise is even on the
stress condition uh the outbound bmp
monitoring was always uh be
very consistent so at the end of the
test cases
the state mirrored with bmp
and the state on the routers were always
matching
so we did not lose any metrics
regarding the pgp propagation delay
uh when bmp is enabled and not enabled
here uh we we found out that basically
that the testbed was not
accurate enough the delay is actually in
a in a very
low sub second area and in order to draw
a final conclusion
uh we need to improve our test bed
here just an example on uh bmp eastern
yeah let's just let you know we are over
time so if you could kind of wrap up
that'd be great and then we can look at
the results
then this is just basically the the
final results on
on bmp wherever they are
or not disabled and here basically
you see basically if bmp is flapping or
not
uh there is no impact on it
so the good thing about what uh about
this hackathon was
it was good well prepared we had a good
test automation
we were thanks to slack and teams very
well connected
same again as last time we were missing
the beers and cocktails and
thank you for uh all our colleagues who
participated this hackathon
thanks thanks for the presentation um
hopefully we're getting closer to the
cocktails and beers
i did have one question on the uh the
time stamps
uh i didn't quite catch this is that uh
a change that you would also need in the
draft or is that just
your test bed to test what's going on
with the draft
uh know that basically the draft
supports basically timestamps
in seconds and also in milliseconds
but in the vendor implementation it was
not
a q and it was not precise enough to
measure the
delay so we need to improve basically
the vendor implementation
okay so perhaps there may be some of
that could feed back into the draft that
was a recommendation of a reason why
implementations even if you could do
just the seconds
you know like why to use one uh
implement something rather than you know
at a deeper level
i don't know if some guidance could go
back into the draft because
it obviously wasn't wasn't evident that
those time stamps would be needed at
that grand clarity so
it seems absolutely this is this was one
of the key findings that
uh in order to measure such a
propagation delay such time stamp in
such final candlelight disease is
does does make a difference
great anyone else with any questions
okay thanks thomas thanks a lot
are you here yang model for network
[Music]
tester
i don't see uh vladimir
he'd warn me he may be a little bit late
okay
let's uh let's go on to the next one
then and we'll come back to vladimir at
the end
uh tom if you're here uh ns3 models
do i see tom
okay uh actually vladimir i can see
you're
you're here are you ready to present or
would you rather we come back to you
[Music]
all right well then we will go on to uh
sebastian
hi can you hear me yes
and you should be able to share your
screen now
[Music]
um
i'm just fiddling with the screen share
okay i'm gonna get the right window
excuse me
[Music]
okay are you seeing the slide yes
okay uh thank you very much this is my
first ietf
hackathon um it might be a little bit
different from some of the other
projects big bang is a
is a software toolkit that's for
studying collaborative communities in
general
and especially standard setting groups
so um what it does it is it ingests
uh email get repositories
it ingests stuff from the iutep ietf
data tracker
as of this hackathon it ingests uh
listserv data which some other standard
settings groups use as a
communications tool and then it combines
those with
data science tools from you know the
scientific python stack
for entity resolution social network
analysis natural language processing
time series analysis uh we're expecting
to
start working with a group that does
information extraction soon
and it's a little bit different from uh
arcos
rfc stats uh which we love and are
inspired by
because it brings in a wider range of
data sets and supports different kind of
research questions so the big bang
research community has both social
scientists that are interested
in uh standardization collaboration
and the ietf in particular and also
computer scientists developing new
kind of data science methods for using
this kind of data
so uh it's got a number of different
groups contributing
article 19 is an ngo there's several
university researchers that are involved
not on this list is some participation
that's very
very vision from the university of
glasgow we're building
a python interface to the data tracker
and uh for this sprint we saw
a number of new participants uh growing
uh including you know a new user
and um a new software contributor who's
made a lot of
uh very great improvements we
uh did a lot of just sort of basic
maintenance and updating of
sort of the installation procedure to
keep up with changing
underlying dependencies uh we produced
an instructional video
about installation basic usage did some
debugging
um and built in this listserv
sort of scraping tool which we want to
apply later to other organizations like
3gpp
we also did some more substantive sort
of analysis
or even and science with the data um
one about uh one project that nick doty
did was about uh
attendance analysis and there was some
other work about
looking at organizational involvement
via email data
so uh this is from nick doty
this is a plot of uh ietf meeting
attendance by country over time
and what he was interested in uh in
particular was the last three meetings
had been remote
um you can see they've got some of the
red x-axis
tag uh and he was pleased to see that
there was
increased attendance relative to uh
prior
meetings because the meeting was remote
though not quite as high as when at the
peak of ietf attendance which was
i guess around 2004 or so
but the other thing that he noticed was
that um you can see say
uh in um let's see meeting 76
or 94 where there's a higher
uh higher percentage of of people
attending from japan that's because of
the location of the meeting so we can
see
swings in the nationality of attendance
based on
uh the location of the meetings the
remote
meetings um it seemed to lose
that locality effect uh which
i suppose is expected um but
uh is something to keep in mind i
suppose going forward
the other thing we really dug into in
terms of data analysis was
uh some of the research groups that are
involved in the project are very
interested in which organizations are
which
are influential in which working groups
um
and while the there's author stats work
that uh
definitely supports this sort of stuff
it doesn't generalize to other standards
groups that don't have as wonderful
a tool as data tracker so we're trying
to
explore this using uh email domains
uh for participation in mailing lists um
so theoretically you could use the email
domains basically everything after the
at sign uh but there are some challenges
there's a lot of people
especially in the itf community that
have personal email domains
and um there's also generic email hosts
like
gmail or gmx which
you know encompass several different
individuals
and we're trying to work out data
cleaning methods to make this
a little more useful we were
experimenting with a kind of
entropy threshold of email
just on the distribution of email
addresses per domain
and we found this quite effective at
filtering out personal
uh email domains we're still trying to
figure out what to do about these
generic email hosting
um issues uh but uh
so far we've been pretty good at
successfully isolating when
an email domain is uh coming from a
corporation
uh or organization uh as opposed to
representing like an
individual which is what we're kind of
trying to get at
um so for the future we plan to
release some improved documentation uh
hopefully make a containerized
environment
so that people could uh interact with
the data through an interactive notebook
as opposed to having to sort of download
and install the whole thing
we want to we've got some plans to
refactor the core code
for better encapsulation and
we want to develop a kind of
standardized process for looking at
organizational involvement that works
not only on ietf data but also through
gpp
w3c ican etc and we are
looking to work with another group in
the future that specializes in
olive knowledge graph construction and
we're very excited for that
so you can find out more about the
project on our github
uh page and there's a mailing list there
which um which you know you're happy to
join in and check out and join the
discussion
and that is all thank you
oh great well thank you very much uh
that's that's some some new information
i look forward to
seeing is that more analysis comes out
of that are you are there plans for
like sharing any of the data that you're
generating in it
i don't know in the ihf plenary or some
other format
it's cool the hackathon community from
the tooling perspective but
a lot of people if you're interested in
the results so that's that's a great
that's a great point
as i said this is my first itf
attendance and i've been working on the
big bang software for some time there's
others in the big bank community that
are
weren't tied yet but i'll bring that up
with them i think we'd love to present
this
at the plenary cool all right
well thank you
all right let's go on our next
presentation i see yari you're
you're here i'm here but i was wondering
if i could ask
still a question on the previous one oh
sorry sorry yeah
yeah so just uh really great stuff very
interesting and
and indeed we should hear it in a more
uh general setting in the itf plenary or
something
i i did have one comment on on this
generic email stuff and and there are
ways
to deal with that one of the things that
worked for author stats
was that you could by hand basically
list the most important
generic email domains and by hand at
least the
most interesting companies or most you
know
companies that many people work for and
from that you can actually override
the email domain information so you
could actually
analyze a little bit of who that's what
because people sign their
company instantly uh in the in the
documents
with the company um or provide the
company name in the documents
so that's what that's one way perhaps
that you could consider
that that is awesome and thank you for
your question of course we
um we're paying attention to your work
if there's any way we could
reach out to you and get you know your
list of hand-edited um
email addresses of dreams that would be
incredibly valuable but i think
that's something we're thinking about
doing down the line it's just a lot of
work
yes you could let's let's talk
bye-bye okay
and you're also our next presenter so
yeah so so this team worked on uh
quick measurements and um quick of
course is an
encrypted uh transfer protocol which
means that the
measuring it is is much harder than it
was for say tcp where you could just
look at the x and so forth
the quick standard does have some
features for enabling some
specific or explicit measurements
whereas the spin bit allows
some things to be measured and
we've built some software in earlier
times
two or three years ago already started
work on something called spindam for
instance that
i can look at quick flows and understand
what's right
okay should i see
ah do you really want to share your
screen yes i really want to share my
screen
do you see it now
do you see my screen uh i it shows your
arc of the screen but it
says it's all black i don't know if
anyone else sees more than that
no it looks like it's next screen same
here
yeah charles could you perhaps share
instead
just about the problem
yeah i think so let me uh
oh okay
yeah let me pull up your your
presentation i'll download it
hold on maybe i just need to do no
yeah no it doesn't allow me to do it
okay
yep just kind of yeah
now i'm seeing a black now yeah perfect
thank you so um we built the software
called spin dump
uh to help analyze some of these uh
encrypted traffic flows of the text
that we can and we've been working on
that and expanding that
uh in various directions in in several
uh
hackathons actually over the last year
and a half or so
uh this time it was these people from
telecom italia
huawei university of hasselt and
ericsson who participated there for
ticker the next slide
and so we worked basically on
four things uh this week the first one
is
like new research on different types of
measurements that we could do with
encrypted protocols and there's a
there's a draft
and there's an implementation of the
draft in in spin dump
integrated into the software you can get
go take a look at the draft i won't go
into details of that
today to save some time i've also worked
on
android tooling so the idea is that
users could
run this measurement tool on their
phones
and provide some measurement data to a
central point
instead of having the network do this
these measurements and one one thing
that we actually were
surprised by a little bit in this effort
was that
that it's it's quite uh possible to
measure
quick flows at least when there is the
spin but
spin bit is being used uh but it's quite
difficult to use
uh or to observe tcp uh for the reasons
that
some of these platforms um
hide some of the uh some of the traffic
from
from us uh on the phone platforms and so
forth
and and it's it's not possible to see
all packets
um even with this like packet capture uh
interfaces or
alternatively one would need more
permissions to to see everything but
um so it's been kind of an interesting
side effect of this encrypted protocols
that they actually go through
everything uh on the uh points and
internet work
and and you can see what you can see
obviously you can't measure everything
but you can
you can see the things that were
designed to be seen uh everywhere
we also do uh quite a bit of uh sort of
monthly maintenance of the software so
we need to update it usually with
new versions of quick now fortunately
the quick protocol is being released as
rfc so the version has been set as one
and uh
and that's it uh for the moment at least
but we did
integrate a few pr's and uh fixed a
number of issues added some features
some interrupt testing and one of those
features that we added
is is q log and uh q lock is like this
logging format that is
supported by many endpoint
implementations so quick
it's mostly used initially at least for
for debugging purposes there's a couple
of drafts you can go read them
and we chose to add q logos
as a possible output format from from
spin dump
and the idea is basically that you would
get information from several directions
you'll get it from the host
implementations you'll get it from
network tools such as spindom you would
get it from the server
implementations and then you can
put all of this thing uh information
together and then use tool
tooling built for q log to to look at
like
what is the situation from different uh
viewpoints
and uh if you go one step forward it's
the last slide
so this is kind of um
sounds may be complicated but it's quite
simple uh quilo
clock q lock is uh
jason essentially and it consists of a
basically an array of events client
events and then there's
information about the protocols and and
so forth and what we've been
able to add there is is measurement
events
um and there's various kinds of
measurements that spin dump
does this what is shown on the screen is
just one example
well that's that's basically it and uh
uh
looks interesting i think we we are
going to
have to stop the coding for a moment and
think about some of the
drafts going forward the class are being
discussed i think
tsv wg in the coming week
by robin um but
but since they started from this logging
debugging perspective and not from the
measurement perspective then building
those measurements
capabilities into the formats will
probably take
a little bit of effort so we sort of
identified
opportunities for improving the drafts
or writing the awards perhaps
so that's it
great thank you you know one question i
had
so you can identify that the flows are
quick
and within the quick flow can you
identify kind of
sub flows within it like or is it just
that this traffic is quick or
you you can identify a particular quick
connection
or a pair of connections uh going
between two
parties and but like what uh in subflows
or
or streams are inside one quick flow you
cannot see and that's
that's by design of course you can see
what what the encrypted traffic is being
fixed okay good
thanks
uh any other questions
okay great well thanks sharon thank you
okay let's go to our
our next presentation i need to get back
to my list here
oh it's me
okay um so uh karsten
unfortunately couldn't be here as uh no
one from the uh
asdf wishy team uh was able to be free
at this particular time slot so i just
have a very quick update from them let
me pull that up
and i'll share it with all of you
okay
so uh on behalf of the uh
asdf wishy team just wanted to give you
a
a brief update um so this project
it was it's a joint project between the
asdf
group and then the chairs from that
group running it along with the
tdtrg group um
and that's really where wishy is being
uh discussed
and so the goal for them um
was to validate sdf 1.1 i believe at the
last hackathon it was 1.0 they were
working with
the semantic proxying trying mapping
files etc
a link to their github code wiki
can get more details a rather
exploratory
hackathon is how karsten phrased it
but you know two pieces of code did come
out of that that
that will aid with model transformation
so
the good news is these uh
the results of the hackathon are already
expected and planned
to be discussed in more detail in the
actual
working group and research group session
so i have them listed they're both on
thursday
so for those of you who are interested
in hearing more
that'll be a great opportunity to engage
with
those groups and discussions around the
hackathon
and what they accomplished and learned
and with that i think we will go back
to our next one which uh paul we have a
couple presentations from you
and uh great i see you're here
let me hello this is paul can you hear
me
yes i can okay great you should be able
to share your screen now
okay sure okay
okay we can see it uh we're on your
wrap-up slide though
and now it just switched to presentation
mode which you know may not be the best
format
okay yeah so it is great right okay
yep that's good and then just one more
thing there is a little pop-up
near the bottom uh which maybe you can
just move that
it's okay oh
okay what's going okay
okay can you okay it's good right yeah
so
uh okay so hello
uh this is uh i'm poor jung
from seongyun university
i will uh share our hackathon project i
to nsf
this time so this is our poster
so this time we want to implement
itunes f monitoring data model
and also we want to
show the approval concept
of security management automation new
draft
so especially this draft proposed
application interface for delivering um
feedback
information from itunes to analyzer to
security controller so basically
this is a typical i2 nsf
framework so this time
denial of service attacker generate the
tcp plot traffic to web return
network security function a and then
analyzer
collect the data from
nsf a and then using a machine learning
ml it detect nsfa
is affected by dios attacker
and then using application interface
analyze deliver a bit of information
such as the dos attack
from somebody else and then
security control and translate that
feedback information into new
security policy and then deliver
over nsf facing interface and then
a new descriptive policy is imposed by
nsf
a and then it can drop tcp sync messages
so this is a monitoring data such as
cpu memory other resources
are monitored and also
using the observation of
tdos attack and then we iterate the
analyzer can detect
so this is the information the attacker
source and this is the frequency of
tcp um plot
so basically uh what we got done
so we implemented the monitoring
interface and then analyze
the dos attack also we deliver the pwa
information
over application interface and then
security controller
translate high level security policy
into
a lot of very skilled policy and then
deliver that
new skill policy over nsf
phase interface and then nsf using
firewall and then it can drop the
tcp flat so what we
learned this time so we implemented the
monitoring interface
and also we recognize monitoring
packet flows in nsf to detect the dos or
ddos attack we need to
flow based traffic monitoring is
required so this time we
show the feasibility of application
interface this is uh
nearly a proposed by itunesf working
group
for security management automation so
next step
we have five items we want to extend
monitoring young data model monitor
packet flows
and also we want to use as pro along
with the
itunes monitor interface to observe
that traffic monitoring also we want to
improve
iterative analyzer in terms of machine
learning
and also we want to
update automatically solved function
chaining of
nsf corresponding to
the security policy and also we want to
enhance
security policy translator for security
management
automation now this is our uh
ito nsf open source project at github
so this is a new repository for
at this time so
this is my team okay so this is a
collaboration work with the sunshield
university from professor young kim's
lab
and from actually doctor zhang chobak
and
mr ninja choi and we have
a student so patrick he is a main
player this hakason and dr jinyoung kim
and jung young kim and yosef ann are my
student and my phd and also
i have more moji school uh he is an
intern from liberty university in the
united states and also i have a
visitor student gyeongshi kim from
kyungbung national university
so we work together with ipwave
and vmware working with teams so
those are our sponsors thank you for
listening
listening your mi presentation thank you
any questions or comment
uh yeah i did have one question on the
the yang model that you mentioned
for the uh monitoring is that
is that an ietf like uh is it the best
model that's being developed oh this
one oh there it was okay
okay okay so yeah yeah and it's in the
i2 nsf working group
yeah this one is i2 and as a working
group
so recently a young doctor
approved this young mother is related
to the working rash core so currently
this draft under walking or rust core
okay okay ah thank you
okay great
so okay
uh charles can i uh move to next
presentation
yeah i think so unless uh did anyone
else have any other questions
otherwise yeah we'll move to the next
one i don't see anyone in the queue so
go ahead
okay great
okay this is a if you wave
a basic protocol project my name is jam
for zhang i'm from uh skk or sungyeong
university
so this is a foster
but basically uh previously uh we had
three hackathons the first one
is we demonstrated the ip2006 to packet
transmission over ocb
wi-fi modules and also
the 108 case we implemented simulation
of
context aware navigation protocol and
last hackathon 109
we started the implement context of a
navigator protocol
so this time we use the r1
i1 lobotics robot it
can be controlled manually or autopilot
mode
so this time he manually controlled next
time we tried to autopilot mode
so it sport the linux corner in terms of
real-time linux so it also
like to be a sport ip wave
wave stack but still we need to
implement ipv6
step stack so this hackathon is based on
a context of a navigator draft
so basically contact aware navigation
protocol means
this is a highway vehicle to
hit some obstacle you know highway and
then
it delivers some emergency contacts
messages to neighbors and then this guy
and these guys and received this one and
then
already their exchange using contact
corporation
context message having position
direction speed acceleration
behavioral drivers this one can be
spray or a lot of cluster header and
it can adjust the maneuvers
of neighbor speakers to avoid extent
those are our previous components and
the
internet draft so basically our
contact over navigation protocol based
on a neighbor discovery message option
is called the beaker mobility
information option vmi
so this is a and the option so we
support the
corporation context messaging and the
emergency context message
so basically we implemented and tested
using a robot
r1 a1 uh robotics
so they exchanged a message ccm
and the ecm but this time we you
implemented the udp instead of i76
this hackathon will try to implement
icmp
version 6. so we try to extend the
ubuntu linux corner for nd
it turns out there is some high
complexity
so we just yeah designed
how to extend the neighbor table
that is the neighbor cache and also it
has
entry for neighbor using neighbor
structure
so we try to take advantage of the
current implementation
and we want to extend the and the option
so still uh ongoing work uh hopefully uh
next hackathon we try to
finish so next step we
will continue developing and debugging a
new option
called the speaker mobility information
option in linux corner
and and also we also will export
context over navigation uh protocol
based on this
new option and then we'll test
this uh ip46 neighbor discovery
and also we will sport the autopilot
mode of robot cars
such as cmp contacts
or where navigation protocol max is
changed such as there is some accident
over optical ahead of it
speakers can exchange the message and
they can avoid
that obstacle or the collision with each
other
so this is a ip wave open source
project at guitar
also this also uh collaboration work
with the social university professor
young
game and my pitch student
vienna me and chris and
don they are my phd students
and son from sunshine university and you
know
national university in the same way we
work together with the itunes sf
and the vm working group teams
those are our sponsor especially tta
provided
uh r1 a1 low ticks
robots thank you for your attention
and thank you any questions or comment
okay charles that is my yeah
presentation
any question or comment no uh thanks
that was great and good to see the team
uh coming back and uh
yeah my students gathered together here
okay thank you
yeah yeah thank you okay bye-bye yeah
okay uh great next presentation
ratson company thomas
hi charles hi thomas
yes they want to show screen
uh
wait a second presentation
okay can you see uh yes
yeah it's uh i mean we're seeing uh
we're not seeing like
like presentation mode
but but you know it's okay okay okay
let me try and see okay so um
we came here with a verizon project the
reason project is a
project we launched uh four or five
months ago
with the goal of building a bunch of
open source packages that can be
composed into another station
verification service
um these packages tend to cover you know
several different facets of data station
verification pipeline
so we have data formats we have apis to
vacations to
with each other we have um evaluation of
the appraisal policy
uh endorsement and trust anchor
configuration storage query whatever
all that stuff um so this is the second
microphone we do one verizon
and last time itef 109 we
implemented heat and cost sweet from the
rats and
second working group and this time
around we wanted to put together a bunch
of the components
we have built into an instance of of the
rats architecture
and specifically the so-called
background check model
and we wanted to do that using a
specific attestation format
which is the psa psa attestation token
and using a specific interaction model
which is a challenge response
um and this was one thing we want to
cover the other thing
we wanted to do was bringing up to speed
our 8 implementation
uh with with the latest version of the
working group
draft and this was very important to us
because uh
the latest version contains a new claim
that is critical to our workflow and we
wanted to play with it a bit and see if
it worked
right so
the thing so worked on uh
four drafts uh three working group
crafts
and one individual draft which is the
draft strategic
uh psa token which we want to
progress through the independent stream
and what did we do
we did a considerable amount of
development and integration
in four different packages
of the verizon project
and apart from that we spent a lot of
time
discussing new ideas about uh you know
uh
missing um tools and
and and stuff like that or evolution of
the api implementation
uh to cover other um scenarios uh
we have you know pr's uh that have been
merged we have issues that have been
opened
and all that stuff uh wherever demo
we've put together a demo based on
docker
that you could run if you wanted to and
it's there
[Music]
at that url at the bottom of the page
and we did
not do any interrupt for now but we
chatted with another
uh it's stack to to decide the sort of
inter
test which we wanted to perform and and
we agreed with them to to schedule a
an interrupt test uh soon maybe a
virtual one
instead of waiting for the next cycle
but um
um what we learned is
um as i said we wanted to have this
profile claim
implemented and we did it uh thanks to
yogesh
and uh and that was very interesting
because we realized while doing that
that the spec
as it as it stands is not a hundred
percent correct and
uh we need to have more precision around
uh interesting bits of it and
so there's a there's a new issue that
has been raised um
and there's some discussion already
ongoing and
and i think that this would be
a will be in fact uh some kind of
feedback that needs to be taken into the
youtube discussion next week
to wrap up yeah the team members is uh
jokers myself in sergey
and yogesh was a first timer and i
think he enjoyed it very very much as we
did
that's it thank you
okay well great glad you found that uh
issue in the draft
now rather than afterwards yes
exactly what we want to do so all right
i'll talk to the team for that
uh any anyone with questions
okay well thanks thomas uh cheers
next up we have willam and presenting on
xot
rather than uh oh sorry i skipped a
kj sun um
yeah see you're and sorry willa we'll
come back to you later
uh kj if you can request to share your
your screen will do that
okay
can you hear me yes we can see you too
but not your screen yet
ah okay you should see uh requests now
allowing you to uh
to share
oh my screen sharing is
not working so could you pop up to my
slides
yeah let me uh let me do that
all right i'm just looking for the uh
the right one here
i will not open that
[Music]
okay and bng let me find it
okay i got it
okay thank you
okay now i can see okay
great yes so this is
yeah so can i start yes go ahead
okay so this is the about the bmwg
considerations for benchmarking network
performance in the containerized
infrastructure
so this is our the third hackathon
and please go to the next slide please
yeah so the main goal of this hackathon
is
to figure out the container talking
performance impact
by the various resource options so based
on
our draft so we set up two main features
the first is implementing containerized
infrastructure with the
various network models and second is
verifying performance impact depending
on the
various configuration settings next
slide please
yeah uh so the last two
are the hackathon so we set up the
environment
and then test some new technologies and
network networking models
and then at the time in this hackathon
we first our first vlog is to discuss
about the current status of
ventrac for in the containerized
infrastructure benchmarking area
so the we the survey and then checking
the other walks
not only our our works so the one of
them is the
uh the open source activities
which such as the bs puff in the opnfp
and another part is that the industry
the benchmarking test results such as
the fdiu
and then the pdk performance report so
based on that so we
are mapping
our defined networking model category
and the test scenario
to map to the uh to
to the other activities and then based
on that
we want to generalize our test
architecture and then some the test
cases
and the next slide please
yeah at the same time after we
check the other activities and then we
want to
we are validating the other benchmarking
works into the our lab environment
uh so first is uh using the obs dpdk and
then ppp memory
and sriv and we
set up this environment and then we
measure the through food and the latency
and the package drops in the some single
port
to the external traffic generator and
the other is that the multi-post test
scenario which is
uh supported in the vpp memimp
uh so and then based on this multiple
port case and then size function
chaining case
we follow that scenario and uh and we're
validating that
and at the same time we using the
uh the other or the technologies such as
ostpdk
with the same testing scenario so we we
are
comparing with the existing the test
result for us
compare their performances so these
works are still on progress
and then we will get the results soon
okay next slide please
so the uh based on the discussion and
then validator
uh so we need to update our
related draft uh to rearrange
our chapters and figures and words of
uh uh it's more need to be more
generalized and then up-to-date
technologies
and adding the other the benchmarking
activities
and then for the next hackathon so we
are finding a remaining area for the
benchmarking containerized benchmarking
area so the first we choose is
uh we choose multiples in a single host
case
or with the different acceleration
techniques so there is
some two-part one partition multiple
to market report and apparently
we send to the packet to the multiple
two multiples
and then another one is the
training scenario which is traffic
should be forwarded sequentially to or
through the multiple ports
uh and the other uh the testing scenario
case
uh can be the port or with
multi multi interfaces so the using
when the port using the multi interfaces
and then going traffic simultaneously
through
the multi interfaces so we uh
we want to the uh
the venture came for them and and want
to find some issues
of which impacts to the performance of
the containerized infrastructure
okay next slide please
okay so here is our team members so the
professor young
kim and then uh some guys uh in the
uh iistrc the research center
and then professor jayang poor zhang
from sushi
san jung university and then dr henshi
yang from the kt
so this is our member and then thank you
for listening
okay well thanks for uh for sharing and
for the presentation
any questions thank you
i don't see anyone in the queue so
thanks again
kj and now we'll move to uh to well
thank you
and i need to stop sharing sorry about
that
no problem
uh let me see
right can you hear me
yes excellent
yeah so these are the results from
project
dns which turned out to be project
zot so
just like previous time we used this
i used the metalmost chat surfer of the
dns
operations in analyzers research center
because quite a lot of
open source dns developers already there
so it's a convenient and appropriate
place to communicate
and i it's also open to anyone
so anyone can join
in a chat on
about dns hackathon projects they
might have i have a link on the hexon
wiki as well but so one
month ago i changed
the channel name into itf 110
dns hackathon and
just when i did that people started to
complain a little bit right because uh
it's a pity that we have to do
online hackathon again and it would
it would be better to have the in-person
hackathon
and you know with online hackathon
i only have 15 minutes three times over
the week to spend on this
i would rather spend a lot more time on
it
and because dns developers actually
have to work and are
working all week and you know so
anyway um so
i decided well why don't we
organize in-person hackathon day at
the netherlab's office and i proposed
that on the channel
and most people were hesitant but
at least one person was enthusiastic
about it which is the dice
and so we will have an in-person
hackathon
day tomorrow at the email network's
office
i'm looking forward to that one but
besides that we also did the online
hackathon
so there were quite a few ideas for for
dns
people wanted to work on dns of quick
and
svcb came along catalog zones
but those were all
intentions which didn't actually turn
out
in actually actual work done
unfortunately
because you know we have to work uh
except for
this one zot so this is what i could
find
on the wikipedia which is like wikipedia
but then in the
star wars universe on zot it's
apparently a sentient species
but it's also a
proposed a draft internet draft still
it's a working group last call has just
finished
it's now in ad review state
about having the zone the dns zone
transferred over tls
and so there's a lot of things
that are involved with that uh like
authentication that you don't if you
really want your zone to be private
you may not leak it
in in clear text basically so there are
some things you have to watch out for
and related to salt this the transfer of
tls is also the extended dns
errors which is a part of salt if you're
doing zot
they assume you're doing extended dns
errors too
but actually not that many
implementations yet
of extended dns errors at least not in
our software and also not in bind i've
heard today
so we had to work on that too
sarah dickerson set up this excellent
hackathon planning document
in which you know everything surrounding
salt was mentioned
and other other steps and plants
unfortunately sarah herself
got ill this week so she could could not
participate
but chiffon palavi and han
they were a unit that worked from
east coast united states i think they
had a
mini group in which they
talked over a google meet at an elnett
lobs
we have new guy named tom capari he
worked on ede
and all the work from pallavi hung and
chifan was reviewed by walter weinhardt
paid from dyke he worked on shots for
power dns
in my ties making i don't know if he is
already working on or
will work tomorrow on salt for a bind
and
yes so
part of the planning was also setting up
a
interoperability testing environment
and from this i registered the domain
name
zotrox so i spent up a few virtual
machines
and gave everybody access to
install their software and try out
interoperability transfer zones over tls
from
each other with appropriate
authentication
so what got done tom capari
he made extended dns errors for
anestheda
our authoritative name server from
analyte lobs
and this was quite interesting he found
some missing error codes in the rfc so
for example a specific error
if your d name expansion
overflows if you end up with a too large
domain name this is possible
it has a very unspecific response card
currently
pallavi worked on access control lists
now if you're doing shots you should not
do a zot
on for the whole of the internet without
t6 or without t6 is okay but then for
specific ip ranges and
yes interval probability testing of zot
so what did we learn learn we
all we still miss all miss the in-person
hackathons
that will have a mini one tomorrow yeah
just me and matthias basically but
that's i'm
very much looking forward to that
from ede maybe we need a update on
8914 or maybe we come up with some more
codes that are missing from that so
that's nice and
swot just works rocks so
that's all good
so these are the people that
participated
more hacks are coming tomorrow
but maybe next week as well
because the dna shop is on thursday and
we can still do
we want to do still catalog zones
interoperability testing because it
happened quite a bit
on that draft too that's the end of
my presentation
on the azot hackathon results
yeah thanks willem uh tom you're you're
in the queue is that for the next
presentation or do you have a question
and if you have a question you can go
ahead and and share it now
um otherwise uh william i thanks
you made uh dns and privacy and security
look like a lot of fun i'm glad you have
all that infrastructure in place
i think that'll help uh with your your
in-person hackathon
i'm a bit jealous i have to say
and i hope that uh you know we don't
know about ihf
111 yet i guess there's still a chance
to
do something in person so we'll see
we're working on it
yeah okay
okay great thanks and we'll
turn it over to tom tom if you uh
request
uh screen sharing you should be able to
share your presentation
okay can you hear me can hear you can
see
you don't see your screen share yet
this says it's starting but then it
kind of stops
oh maybe it looks like you have the
ability to share
yeah i'm getting an error um
get display media must be called from a
user gesture handler
on safari
okay
is your
is your presentation have you uploaded
it to
to github yes i have
all right let me go ahead and see if i
can find it
it says i'm sharing now or it's at least
the request is going through
okay i see you requested i granted
access so we'll see if we have better
luck this time
now it says it's shutting down so
if you don't mind sharing yeah let me uh
let me find your presentation
okay uh
let's see what am i looking for here all
the ns3 models
just look for the name of yours
um
what what's your presentation named i
don't see it it's um
let's see
hmm
should be iatf110 hackathon presentation
ns3
and i had uploaded it about 20 minutes
ago
try to find it okay
i don't see anything that's come in in
the last
hour maybe it's not in the 110
uh projects
do you see it now i mean reload
no nothing
all right well why don't i just uh in
the interest of saving time why don't i
just give it verbal
okay
okay so yeah sorry for the technical dif
difficulties um
so my name is tom henderson and i'm here
representing typically the group that
works on
ns3 simulation models in the context of
the iutf hackathon
and i i think we've been doing this for
five or six
ietfs now in a row this time i was
pretty lonely
um it turned out that's many people who
usually participates
were busy with other things this week so
i
i basically worked pretty much solo
i had one student stop by and
he was able to help on a starter project
essentially
doing some validation of our tcp model
but it was mainly just me hacking this
week
the topic that i focused on this week
was
protocols that are being discussed and
under consideration in the transport
area working group
in particular there's a proposal for a
new ecn response
and protocol the
initiative is called l4s and
i was working to freshen
our tcp prog congestion control model
as well as a new aqm structure
called the dual q which is a draft in
the
tsvwg working group and
working on aligning those models both
with our latest ns3 development tree
code as well as linux
performance results that were conducted
using the linux kernel implementations
of those
last year i also worked to finalize
a couple of merge requests
for different aqms we have
from last year we had students working
on
just as there's fq caudal which is the
default q disk
in linux there's also an fq pi
aqm and we have an ns3 model for that
as well as fq cobalt which is
a component of the overall cake
q disc which is popular in the buffer
bloat
community and so i was able to finalize
both of those
and those will probably be pushed to the
main line
in a couple days
as well as let's see
so i would share the links maybe after
the
after the presentation people are
interested can download the slides
uh all of our code is uploaded to git
lab
um our finalized uh proposals have been
uploaded to
the mainline ns3 gitlab.com
instance
and i would share some preliminary
results of alignment between our code
and in linux results but
i guess that will have to wait or you
could download the presentation at a
later time
in terms of what we learned this week i
think
it's really there's nothing that would
change any of the existing drafts or
rfcs it was more
us getting our models aligned with the
latest drafts
but it's really just a capability that
we'd like people interested in the
working group who
may want a simulation model rather than
working with linux code
to experiment with these protocols so
it's just a capability to be
advertised to the transport area working
group for people who wants
simulation models of this work and it's
just two credits
we did have one students sachin nayak
who
was his first hackathon and i worked
with him a lot on wednesday
and otherwise it was just me working
this week
uh any questions for tom
all right well tom thanks for sharing
and uh we'll
we'll get the uh you know where you're
oh it looks like there is a
is there a question and a chat yep
uh yuri was just telling you good stuff
tom um thank you
yeah i agree we'll we'll get it
straightened out where your presentation
is and make sure it's it's uh
it's been uploaded if it's not there
already so that everyone else can find
it
and uh with that let me see
if we have a vlad because we skipped
over vlad
earlier as well for a yang model for
network tester
i know vap let me know offline that he
was working furiously to get
uh things working and i met and that's
what he's doing now so we'll prob he'll
probably have something to share later
on
i'll encourage him to just send what he
has to the list and
an update to the list letting people
know uh
what if he uploads a presentation that
they can go and grab it from there
so with that i think
let me jump back
looks like i may be getting a problem
with screen sharing now too
crest is not allowed by the user agent
in this context okay
i'm going to try reloading
reloading uh me protecto
and coming back it seems like i can
share now but sorry i was gone for
a couple minutes there um
so i think we got through all the
presentations is there um
tom i still see you in the queue but is
that from your previous presentation
or did you have something to add
oh yeah yeah i didn't just probably
okay
great well i believe we got through all
the presentations just a reminder
uh they should all be here in the 110
project presentations
um if any of you have updates because
you continue to work on your project
uh over the course of the next you know
week or two
or you know all the way up until the
next hackathon that's fine you can
always update
what's here if there's something you
think there's useful to share in terms
of
your results from from this hackathon
and
i do want to you know say a big thank
you to icann
they've supported us uh throughout this
whole uh
virtual uh online only hackathon and we
really appreciate that
and uh look forward to having them and
welcome new sponsors i don't know if any
of you follow um
i don't know if it was on the ietf list
there's a new
structure for how sponsorship works they
specifically call out things around
running code of which the hackathon is
of course one
but there's other things too like the
code sprint and
you know other ways to get involved with
code so hopefully
uh that will help and we certainly
welcome more sponsors especially when we
get
back to in-person meetings those are a
bit more expensive for us to run
so we can have the food and of course
the beer and cocktails that everyone
mentioned
[Music]
i just want to remind you again please
uh
for those of you who aren't here at the
very beginning of today's
closing we do have a survey for the
hackathon
and it'd be great if you could take a
few minutes this is just for the
hackathon i think it's like
10 questions maybe even fewer depending
on how you answer the first few
and uh that'll help us we'd love to have
feedback that'll help make
future hackathons better whether they be
online or in person
and then um also i mentioned the the
draft that i've put together that covers
the hackathon
really from a perspective of how to run
it so that um
you know i don't anticipate being a
hackathon co-chair forever
uh and i think barry has other uh things
that he's probably going to do so
in any case it's like everything else in
the itf we like to have drafts that
cover what we do and this one
specifically the reason
it came about now and it's in the schmoo
working group
is because um you know with the nature
of having to meet online
because of the current circumstances and
other circumstances that may happen in
the future
uh it forced us to rethink a bit about
how we run ietf meetings and certainly
the hackathon
and so this isn't specific to running it
online it really covers all facets of
the hackathon
and um so especially for those of you
who just
you know you know participated in this
one things are fresh in your mind
it'd be great to get some feedback on
that draft
from from that perspective as well
because i have my view of how it works
but uh but would love for you to point
out things especially things that you
think are important
and that aren't mentioned in there at
all that i need to call out
um so that'd be great it will be
discussed in the shmu working group
meeting which i forget what exactly
which day that is i think it's wednesday
or thursday next week
we'd love for you to be in that session
but feedback directly to me or to the
working group would be great too
and uh with that uh we're going to wrap
it up
and certainly hope to see all of you
next time
and hopefully in person as we've
discussed uh also
if anyone has any questions any thoughts
um
uh happy to to take those now as well
and actually i have one question for the
group i see some people have already had
to drop off but
we had a new um template
this time that people could use we've
had a
powerpoint version of that template that
i know many of you have used in the past
i think sarah put that together for us
initially and it's been very helpful
and this time benson um oh yeah i see
benson's on
he helped put together or he did put
together an html version of that
template which uh you know we talked
about the kickoff
just wondering if anyone did use that um
if you did love to hear about how that
experience went
and uh as with everything with the
hackathon we
look to make it better next time so
enhancements to the templates new
templates
anything else to make the hackathon
better whether we're in person or like
this would be
appreciated
okay well i'll close them by by thanking
all of you
and uh you know hope you have a good
weekend rest up and uh hopefully a busy
but productive ietf
week next week i look forward to seeing
everyone there
and thanks a lot for participating in
the hackathon really appreciate it
and uh good luck with the rest of ietf
110.