hello everyone
can you hear me richard
ah very good
all right we'll just give it
a minute more
but in the meantime if anyone
would like to volunteer
to do um to take down the minutes
that save us some time going through the
presentations that give us more time to
do more interesting discussions
let me put it that way
[Music]
are you volunteering richard
i will take that as richard is
volunteering
aha there you go well done
thank you sir so um
i'll call you out in a moment
and if we
do we need a job ascribe for this i'm
tempted to say no unless somebody says
we should
i'm not gonna ask for a job ascribe
well
if i can get this going right
i'm going to try to share my screen from
here
do you want to share your screen yes i
did not change my mind
all right i think people can see my
screen
yes i can see it clearly
all right very good
there you go even better
um all right
let's get started it's a few minutes
past the hour
and uh welcome to iccrg everyone
um it's ridiculously early for me it's
four in the morning for me
hopefully it's a more sane time for many
of you
um but uh i'm
looking forward to this session
hopefully this will wake you up
and hopefully you'll be engaged as we go
through this
um so let's just start off
with a couple of notes
at a high level just uh note well oh
hang on
let me fix this so you can actually see
it there you go
i'm reading chris's note here
all right chris if you're willing and
able to do this i would very much
appreciate that then
all right we'll go through that in a
second so that's the note well um
if you haven't taken a look at it please
do uh
please read it before you you uh
participate at the mic
i'm not gonna walk through all of it in
in in detail
but uh that and then you note on the
code of conduct
that we are bound by the iit of code of
conduct if this is important
uh please make sure you've seen this as
well
and read this as well before you
participate
um and here's the high level goals for
the irtf and reminded the folks here
that the irtf
is not a standards development
organization
it is a research organization and
uh with that i will jump into the agenda
for today
so we have a several presentations today
and we have a
an excellent uh agenda here uh with
with uh events which are we i'll talk
about the first one in a moment
but um we have a number of presentations
and i hope uh that
everybody stays engaged to the entire
meeting
i uh um i'll thank richard
for for uh taking down the minutes
and as chris pointed out on the chat
if somebody wants any comments my any
comments to be
voiced at the mic please prefix it with
mike in this chat
and chris has offered to kindly
deliver them at the mic and i'll take
him up on that
that is about all from from me
i am going to now kick off the first
presentation
from rui now this is a slightly unusual
presentation in that we are actually
going to be talking about
a congestion control that is more
um it's more geared towards
data centers uh we will kick it off with
that presentation
rui do you want to
i'm looking here to see do you have to
come up and ask for
camera and mike uh
can you hear me now yes we can hear you
okay let me get you going
okay perfect go for it
um hi everyone this is raymil
from alibaba group so today we were
trying to introduce the hpcc plus plus
so we use use http plus plus to
control the conjunction precisely which
you can
achieve near zero q in our data center
and also
maintain very high throughput so this is
our work
we publish in sitcom 2019
and then after that we actively deployed
this
technique into alibaba cloud and with
many
other vendors so by that time we think
like
we are working with many vendors to
want to standardize this algorithm and
this design so
we can be aligned in the in the same
setting so
next page
okay so so the motivation for our design
is like
today in the clouds we design very high
performance networking
so there are a couple of motivation uh
for our design
first is the first um
application in the cloud right now is
very sensitive to
latency inflation for example in the ebs
elastic block storage the sra guarantee
on the latency is 200 microseconds
and some other like key value
application memory id application
also requires some millisecond latency
so we we think that makes the network
become one more important
the second is that this many
applications
such as high performance storage and the
distributed
deep learning application that use
a device hardware that can generate
the data orders magnitude faster and
also require
outer low latency for those applications
so that network become a new bottleneck
in our system
and the last part is the new
architecture is happening
in the cloud for example the resource
disaggregation
which separates the compute
memory and the disk into separate
resources pools
so even memory access will go through a
network in the future
so in this case the network becomes
very important require very
low latency for those settings
so please next page
so to support those applications
the silicon manufacturer
generate fast asics because the
traditional softwares that cannot keep
up with the speed
so the hardware offloading is inevitable
so however using faster hardware
can generate traffic more aggressively
the network congestion becomes a severe
problem for our clouds
for example we running rdma in our
network we
we find that there are lots of pfc store
and also data lock events so we find
it's necessary to solve the conjugation
control problem in this case
next please
so um we identify a couple of key issues
in our
conjunction control er high speed
network the first issue that we
observe lots of pfc store and the
deadlock event
in our rdma network and we
we find that's a cause of stability
issue
in our network however we cannot disable
pfc
because that will affect the application
performance as well
so the key the key uh
insight for this limitation is that the
current congestion control algorithm is
has
has a very slow convergence speed so
so that's the essential part we want to
address
the second issue that we want to run
application
mix of application in the same cluster
however
we cannot achieve both high throughput
and the low latency for different
applications
so the essential reason for that is
the traditional condition control
algorithm rely on the standing queue
so when the queue build up the condition
control works
uh start to work to react to the
congestion however
when the standing cube build up the
application latency
has already been affected
the last part is we we run dcqc which is
a state of art
conjunction control algorithm for the
rdma network
and that we find that those those
algorithms
rely on the heuristic to configure their
algorithms so for example in dcqcn they
use at least 15 parameter
so to to to work with the congestion
control
so in our case it's really time
consuming
to tune those parameters to work for
different
workloads
next please so this is why
we we want to come up with a new
condition control algorithm
which you can address our
currently issue in our production so
the new opportunity we found is that new
commodity asics
switching ethics have invented
elementary ability
which tells what the status
in real time that switch has
so the idea is to use inband telemetry
as a precise feedback for conjunction
control
so for example in this in this figure
so the sender generate packets package
of the user data
and when the packet goes through the
network
each hop of the switch will add a
telemetry information
into the packet so those telemetry
information
includes the q lens and the tx bytes
and time stem
so to allow us to calculate precisely
the the extent of the congestion so
um the packet continues forward around
the pass
and each switch will attach the
terminal tree of its own into the
package when the package
arrives at the destination the reservoir
will generate
acknowledgement packets back to the
sender
while putting those telemetry pack
information
into the act packet to allow the sender
to adjust the scenery based on telemetry
information so as i said the the
most important telemetry information we
need is the key lens and the tx
rates so which it tells precisely
if the buffer build up for this
particular egress port and more
important
that if there's no queue buildup in in a
in the eagles port we still can use the
txt rate
to quantify the the occupancy of the
link
for example we can control the link to
you use as a
95 percent utilization so in this case
we can maintain near zero q because we
have a five percent
bandwidth buffer to absorb the the
traffic burst
while still we can ensure very high
throughput
to saturated saturated link
uh next
so we we want to compare our
inbantanometry mechanism with the
traditional isin
marking easy as we know that a single
bit
notification of condition uh is a simple
and efficient
uh being supported by many vendors
we viewed that inventory is an advanced
version
of ecn which provides a fun green
network
load information um for example q lens
precisely
q lens uh in terms of bias or in terms
of sales
and also transmit bias which allows to
generate on the calculate the tx rates
on the egress port
based on the tx byte and the timestamp
information
the link capacity actually we use to con
to differentiate
a different link either is 100g link is
25g
link the benefit
or the key insight we get is first
we can convert to uh appropriate
uh just just a one round trip ton we can
adapt to the
uh corrector rates to avoid congestion
while traditional condition control if
you rely on the heuristics
every time you cut to half and after
multiple round trip time you can
adapt to the red sending rate
the second benefit is we can constantly
maintain a near zero queue
for loading latency while still we
maintain a very high throughput
because we can set a
bandwidth buffer to observe the
small burst without actually building up
a queue
so there are a couple of numeral
comparison
or overhead of using inventorment tree
the first one is we we use in the paper
we allow each packet to carry the
telemetry information
which uses up up to less than five
percent of the bandwidth
that's a uh ideal case but in reality we
we prefer uh to query
inbound animation information per round
trip time
in this case we use a standard rfi 1.0
which is iotf standard int
format and for those standard
we have 200 bytes metadata
for the for the int which is account for
only 2.5 percent of the
binaries so in this case we um
we see that because bandwidth is the
generally abundant
in the data center and we we treat we
use the
um those small bandwidths
for for low latency i think we think
it's a good trade-off
next page
uh should i address the question right
now just later for the after the
presentation
um that's up to you rui oh okay i can
i can talk about that um
l4s
oh ifrs i i'm not quite sure the detail
but
it seems like a another standard in the
tsv
vwg right so um
yeah they proposed to use the
fundraising um
um i'm not sure
how to compare it because uh i remember
ps
l4s targeting on the wide area network
and uh it focused on
the the switch support to to improve the
traditional ecn
while we're focusing more on the data
center environment
uh where the the ion team features
can be supported in those switches that
can give
us more information and especially
for the for the for the data center the
bandwidth is
uh abundant so we can
use the those boundaries to
send the telemetry information
if the protocol intend to be used
on the internet so right now we are
focused more on the on the data center
environment because
you know the because the telemetry
information
is more directed to the
data center or cloud provider so those
low level uh congestion information or
traffic load information is very
sensitive to
uh to the to the network operator so if
you
if we want to use the internet wide
environment
then the one issue is maybe
explode those detailed information to
the
to the other user maybe there are some
privacy issues um through
just a high level point the chat will
keep going on
uh you may you may want to you want to
finish your presentation and then see
if people want to answer questions at
the mic or you can continue
the conversation on the chat after your
presentation as well
okay okay okay thank you so we
will highlight our design so the the
key design is using implantation as a
precise feedback
we can quantify the condition and
precisely and react to it
precisely so that this gave us three
benefits
first the first convergence so the
sender know
exactly uh how to react to the condition
and and it can adapt to the precise rate
in just one round trip time the second
is we can maintain near zero q
because our feedback here doesn't rely
on the q lens
not only rely on the q lens but also we
learn the tx
rate and also in our case we have
few parameters we only have three
parameters
and those parameters is not related to
the
uh the performance just the trade-off so
in this case we don't need any heuristic
to infer the status because we can
directly get what what's going on in the
network
next
so this is the preliminary result from
our smarnic implementation
we deployed and
as we see that in the in the left figure
showed that the axis is the different
flow size
um the y-axis is a 99 percentile
normalized flow composition time
actually in this figure the lower the
better
the lower means the lower latency and we
compare
our design with dcqcn the
the purple curve which is the default
condition control
in rdma and we as we see that
for those small messages we can reduce
the latency by
25 and
even in a medium like 200k um
flow so we can still reduce the latency
by
50 55 percent in the right figure we
showed that overall in the
experiment uh the distribution of the q
length in the switch and as we see that
in the hpcc plus plus we say that
in even in the 99 percentile the q lens
is only
23 kilobytes which translate to
seven micro second and q delay in 25 g
link which demonstrates that we can
achieve ultra low latency while
maintaining near zero q
um that's all for for
my presentation i'm happy to take any
questions
right now
thank you roy um i see vidi
at the mic let me
okay i thought this was
sorry there you go with this
uh thank you rui for the great
presentation
i just have a question in the graph that
you were showing
um just the previous slide
okay okay oh can we switch to the
previous slide
if that's okay
so the first graph why does the why does
the
latency becomes normalized like for the
purple and the green i
was i was imagining in my head that it
would always stay low why does it become
the same at higher
oh yeah so for the higher which means
the flow size is larger than
one megabyte for example is
is a throughput oriented for those flows
and those flow maybe need uh tons of
rounds to finishing
all right but don't we have
much better feedback is is this assuming
some kind of
loss or is it like a real-time test i
didn't get the environment
yeah yeah it's a yeah it's a it's a
really just very very quickly videos
there's echo coming out of your mind
okay yeah please mute if you're not
speaking it might be the best way to do
this
yes yeah so we we keep the utilization
to
95 percent in this case we have a five
percent
bandwidth header room to absorb some
more bursts so
in the case the shuffles like a the the
number
in the in the in the left have very low
latency
because we don't build up the queue
however if you look at very tale
of this uh figure we actually perform
worse than the
dcq scene for those long flow because
they can use hundred percent
uh throughput we only use a 9 percent
that's a difference
thank you
ignacio you're up next
um hi um we we
just comment on the chat that this idea
is similar to a protocol discussed
in ippm group the er
aom protocol it's different because here
you are measuring the
the cues which is directly related to
traffic and congestion and
but there is several issues that you can
find when you try to do this in every
in every step or or you you flow
and the the question is
is if you already knew this
protocol that we are discussing um ippm
and how do you think that this
the second second question is how do you
think that is possible
to use your protocol when not all
all the steps inside in the path in the
flow paths
are collaborating with your protocol
because if you are thinking that this is
developed
very slowly uh okay you
you will get this this intention thank
you
oh you mean i don't get the related work
is mean
or ippm
so to answer a question i think for
uh for hpcc plus plus the up we need a
separate queue
for our protocol just like ecn you need
a separate queue for easy and for tcp
traffic as well right
so we need to have a separate queue
for hpc plus plus if you don't use the
hpc plus plus for
for some of the in-house
you might you might have to use
different queue
so you will use the queues in the switch
to separate different protocols
let's continue this one on that if you
would like ignacio
um stuart you're up next
hi hey um just a quick comment
uh i think i understand the confusion
uh that led to vidi's question uh
and this happens a lot when people use
the terms latency and delay
interchangeably this graph is not
showing the latency
uh in the sense of the per pack round
trip time it's showing
the total completion time for the
transfer
so when you have really large transfer
many many round trips
the actual per packet latency becomes
less important
yeah yeah that's why yeah so the left
more than per pack
yeah the left figure shows the trans
the flow combination time which means
the translation
uh delay for this flow the hot
how much time for the network transmit
this particular flow
yeah certainly need a couple of round
triple times for the for the figure in
the right
it actually shows the the the delay of
the network
because the left side shows the cdf of q
lens
and so if you if you add about the
transmission delay this is the queuing
delay right so this is a queuing delay
um distribution you can you can
translate into that
yeah my comment was just because video
was asking on the left graph
why the lines converge above two
megabytes
and i just anyway that was my comments
just oh i see
yeah help clear that up yeah thank you
thanks stuart chris europe
uh relaying for ayush what's the
difference between the hpcc
presented at sitcom and the hpcc
plus plus which is being presented here
um hpcc is more academia
like a style there are a couple of
different
first one is we use per package
int but uh in the production
once we because once we after the
published
uh on sitcom we we work on the vendor to
deploy this in in our production and
during this procedure
we'll accumulate a couple insights
or experience from deploying this
protocol
that's come with hpcc plus plus so it's
more
production ready and
it's a standardizable protocol
now some of the design is too
artificial in the second paper so
in the htc plus plus it's more
practical and design and
it's it's good to uh align with
different vendors because we
uh when we deploy this protocol and then
we actually talk to different vendors
uh to implement these protocols we talk
to the unique vendors and also talk to
the switch
vendors individually so that's the
common ways that
we want to standardize so that we can
we don't have to talk to each one
individually but we're talking a common
language
so that's the way we come up with this
htc plus plus
there are a couple of uh a detailed
design in in the draft
um that's quite different with the paper
version
yeah i would encourage people to read
the draft as well
roland you're up next all right just a
quick question
about multiple bottlenecks so did you
consider multiple bottlenecks or
are they occurring in your setup at all
and the
the network telemetry data does it allow
you to
identify the particular blocked neck for
a
specific flow um
in the paper version we consider the
multiple bottleneck design
and we actually we carry int information
for each hop
so that we can actually know where is
the conjunction
and we have of a complete design to
consider all the bottleneck
and we actually can change the scenic
ray
so both based on different policy so we
can see like
under the multiple bottleneck we can
achieve maximum fairness
or proportional fairness or something
between
that it's our fairness we can achieve
but the later in the in the production
deployment we found that
the simplest way is just to uh
uh do the the the
maximum fairness we don't store because
in multiple bottleneck cases we need to
stop all the information for each hub
that actually causes more resources
but the the the benefit is very limited
the benefit just uh how how fairness we
can achieve what what fairness we can
achieve and how quickly we can adapt to
the
uh the fairness point but actually we
we we care more about ut utilization
convergence
which which can avoid congestion
but we don't care much about fairness
convergence
so because the flows are actually very
short in our case
we don't consider so that that's why we
we
make a very simple design uh
that that works with the multiple
personality case yeah thanks
all right um thank you so much rui for
that um
i'll encourage this is this is uh a
presentation which was uh in part
there's some discussion on the iccrg
mailing list people seem to be
interested in
discussing and engaging in data center
construction controllers
so if people are interested in that i
would encourage you to
engage on this more on the mailing list
and i'll also encourage roy to
to bring these up on the mailing list we
are trying to gauge how much interest
there is
in topics around dc construction control
if there is interest please bring it up
on the mailing list it would be good to
know
yeah thanks i have already uh copied
these comments i will reply
in the email thank you everyone
thank you so much roy uh with that
we will move on to the next presentation
of the day let me see if i can
[Music]
robin get up yeah mike is on
yep all right um so
for those people who've seen this uh
yesterday don't worry it contains a lot
of new information
so you don't get too bored uh next slide
please
so qlog stands for uh quick logging and
its project uh
started about two years ago when we
identified that the new protocols would
probably get quite complex to actually
analyze
and debug in practice and we're going to
need some advanced tooling to do that
which would typically do for something
like tcp for example
next slide is we take a packet capture
somewhere
in the network right and then analyze
that using something like
wireshark for example this is still
possible for quick but
quite a bit more difficult because next
slide
quick of course encrypts most of its
transport level metadata as well
so to do this you would have to store
the entire packet capture including the
very large payloads
and also the tls decryption secrets um
leading to obvious privacy and
scalability issues
there's however a second more
long-standing problem with the typical
way that we do this next slide
which is of course that a lot of
protocol information isn't always
reflected on the wire
that's of course always the case for
congestion control information like
the congestion window which i don't have
to tell all of you
and so um to solve these problems
or to try and solve them for quick we
proposed a different approach
next slide where the idea is instead of
doing a network based capture let's
log this information at the endpoints
directly from the implementations
obviously or have all the salient data
right there available and they can
easily leave out the privacy sensitive
parts
this is of course not a brand new idea
many implementations have
some kind of debugging output for
example but the idea of qlog is to have
like a single format
a single schema that all the different
implementations can use
uh making it easier for us to create
reusable tooling
uh on top of that and so the next slide
um qlog really is not rocket science
it's
relatively simple currently we just map
this into json
and we define how for example i receive
packets
containing an acknowledgement frame
should look like or indeed on the right
side what
uh you should call the variables related
to for example
just control updates using this type of
log as input we were then able to create
quite a few indeed
reusable tools next slide which are
available in the queue this tool suite
one of those is for example here the
sequence diagram
where in the middle you see the packets
going over the wire
from client server and vice versa and
their contents
but on the right side you see
implementation side updates
including for example when when a probe
timeout
timer was set or indeed when the the
bytes in flight was updated
allowing for very fine grains debugging
of these
these systems next slide
the second major tool that we have in
cubist is is a kind of
you can call it the tcp trace for them
for quick
where because of this approach we we
don't just show the data and the
acknowledgements and the flow control
we can also show just the window bytes
in flight
and also the various round-trip time
measurements that are used
internally immediately and so for me
as definitely a non-expert in congestion
control
i really liked this type of thing where
you see the the very clear correlation
between the
congestion window rising and the rtt
going up
with that as well it's very interesting
to see this so
so graphically next slide
[Music]
this this tool has then been used by
quite a few implementers for example
this is from a blog post from cloudflare
who explain in detail how they've used
this to debug their initial
cubic and high stark implementation
for their quick stack next slide
but it's also going beyond initial
deployment initial
implementation debugging for example
what facebook has done is they have
deploys
q log at scale in their data centers as
well and so
they've been able to find quite a few um
relatively quick specific bugs in their
setup that were previously missed in
lab testing they only really surfaced
during their deployment
for example one of the things they had
was that they were underestimating
bandwidth
during the zero rtt phase because they
were relying on previously acknowledged
packets
which during zero rtt you do not have
previously knowledge packets
at least not once containing application
layer data
another one that is in a very
interesting paper that i'll link to the
bottom there
was that in quick you change encryption
levels
and that is accompanied by
you can do that with implicitly
acknowledging all the packets from the
previous
encryption level and the way they did
that was they they uh
mismeasured the rtt there so rtt was
only much much lower than it actually
was
because of the implicit acknowledgements
again causing a wrong bandwidth
estimation
but there you go
okay
okay so um the thing is that no no
previous slide please
so the thing is that this has been used
not just by
um the experts or the people that knew
that they were doing
uh to great effect but i think it quick
we have this um
very um special situation where you have
a lot of quick implementers
that are really not congestion control
experts
by themselves and they have to try to
make something working
based on the drafts and looking at other
people's code
and i think this kind of tool and
approach has really helped them to get
their things at least
somewhat working um next slide
and i think that's that's one of the
main reasons that qlog has found quite a
bit of support
within the quick community most of the
implementations actually
output this directly as well and as i
said facebook is using this
extensively in production it's because
of this that
the format has shown promise and the
tools seem useful
that we are now moving for adoption of
this work by the quick working group
next slide which is intended to happen
somewhere over the next months as part
of the quick recharger
one of the goals there is to flash out
all of this for for
quick we have some basic adjust control
stuff in there but for example facebook
they have added a lot of custom events
as well
to help them better debug their their
custom setups so it's going to be
interesting to see if we
how we need to update the default q log
stuff to to
match that the second main thing and one
of the main reasons i'm here today
is that we're also trying to figure out
if this can be extended
to more than just quick logically of
course things like tcp or
the multipath versions of these or
things like mask or general tunneling
also of course have to deal with aspects
of congestion control
and can get quite complex and we hope
this approach could be useful for those
things as well
with the ideal goal of creating tools
that can be reused across protocols
like slide
we also have a few proof of concepts
projects around that
for example for tcp we've been playing
around with ebpf
and using k probes to get this kind of
information bubbled up from the kernel
we then combine these with the raw
packet captures
from wireshark to get like a full view
of what the tcp stack
for example in linux is doing which has
led to some some
interesting observations next slide
we've also been playing around with this
for multi-parts quick
and we have an ongoing project looking
at it from multiple tcp as well
where we tag each event with a specific
path id
so we can split them out later and have
a comparison between the different paths
of course
so it shows definite promise it looks
like we will be able to do this however
we are also running against a few
challenges or bottlenecks next slide
for example we've recently started a
major push towards actual performance
testing of quick stacks
um and qlo currently as i said is json
based
which is flexible but it's also not
super optimized
uh for example in terms of file size and
so testing
um performance on gigabit networks
has turned out to be quite difficult to
scale um
there are however other people like for
example
big banks from microsoft they're using a
custom
similar approach but they are using a
more optimized format
and custom tools where they are able to
ingest
much much larger log files and much much
more information
to help debug this kind of high
performance scenario
so i think the general approach is is
good we just need to look at how we
implement it specifically that's one of
the discussions that we will definitely
have
for q log one of the problems that i
have there is
kind of the main puller of this thing
next slide is that again i am not
a uh i'm not an expert i don't i don't
implement these things myself i don't
test them
i don't do research um so i don't know
what what like what the
the typical way of working for this is
either research or
actual deployment i've seen things like
this come along here in
this research group this was from a
couple of meetings ago
which seems fantastically interesting as
a tool
it's unclear for example here i don't
know if you can actually log the
individual congestion control windows or
if that's even useful
right um and so next slide
the fact that i need more feedback
became obvious
earlier in the early days when i talked
to jonah um
asking you know how how can we improve
this tcp trace for quick
and he said the simplest thing you could
do is add a
type of thing a ruler where i can just
drag and drop
across the data line here
and it shows me about what the data rate
was and how how long it took
which is really really simple to
implement it did in about one hour
and i would have never thought of that
myself that would actually be useful in
practice
so that kind of input that was really
really useful for me to uh
to optimize this tool now where am i
going with this
final slide because of course the
itf does not standardize tools
and i don't want to make this whole
about the tools but i do think that if
the goal is to have a format
that can be reused across
implementations and protocols
and that we can then build reusable
tools on top of
that it might be a good idea to start
from the tools and then work our way
backwards
to make sure that we are not missing
things that are very useful in practice
or are actually being used
right now so we're looking for feedback
now
on formats and ideas you might have had
there
and also some things that you might have
had as input from tools
most of this work for for practical
reasons will happen in the
quick working group even though we're
also looking for other protocols
um as well and we will of course have
some very good input already because
there are
a lot of knowledgeable people involved
in quick with this as well but extra
feedback and opinions are always
welcome there are using the giz help of
course right now
as i'm interested hearing feedback and
questions thank you
thank you so much for the presentation
robin uh we have time for just a couple
of quick questions
but i want to uh uh quickly say that i'm
i'm grateful for robin for presenting
this here and of course for
the work that he's doing this is super
super useful
for quick but as he points out it's
super helpful for
for for transports as well people who
wanted to do
and use tooling that's um that's more
modern so to speak will find this to be
extremely useful okay
john john you're you're you're up
uh thanks um i just wanted to ask
what sort of compression algorithm
you're using to get the 18 megabytes
oh that's just normal zip
yesterday okay
so presumably a more advanced conversion
would get it down smaller
sure and for storage and transfer that's
fine
for now but it's mainly if you want to
load this for example rqvis tools are
all web-based
and your browser really doesn't like you
uploading a gigabytes
json file or or
or downloading the compressed version
and then having to unzip it in the
browser is also not something it likes
to do so
yeah okay
all right it looks like we don't have
anybody else in the queue but
oh jake you're a stretcher okay i'm
gonna close the queue after richard but
jake you're up next
yeah hi i i do think this looks very
interesting has anybody started doing
anything with this for
uh for tcp like
this seems like it does have obvious
um not not concretely like we have the
proof of concepts those are more like
research projects i do know that people
at facebook and google have shown
interest
in applying this to tcp as well and i
think even
apple as well to doing that but i don't
know of any concrete
efforts yet but i'm very interested in
hearing from people
okay thanks
so i would just wanted to uh basically
chime into the same horn here
and i think it's very interesting to
have a standardized way to lock these
um congestion control internal events
especially useful for tcp obviously
because right now at least i am faced
with at least three different
approaches how to diagnose and
troubleshoot
tcp and none of them are standardized so
they all need their specialized tool
sets they
may need the recompilations of the stack
and so forth
[Music]
thanks for that comment richard i'll say
that uh at high level
um just two quick points before i let
robin go
one is that the q log tool the q log
schema is different from the
visualization tool and that's actually
quite
quite an important distinction here to
your point uh
there richard which is that if you want
to extend the with the schema
to include more events in tcp and so on
and so forth that is an
excellent uh uh that that would be very
useful work i think
i'm speaking for robin here but at the
moment in the quick working group at
least
this is going to be taken up and the
focus is going to be what
needs to be logged for quick not for
other protocols but if there are
extensions that you need to make or if
you want to extend the schema for the
future
that work would be very useful to do now
because i imagine that if you want to
adopt this sort of work in other working
groups
then having that work done before it
gets there would be very useful
all right i will uh thank uh robin for
his presentation
and martin you get to jump into the
queue and say something
yeah hi thanks john i just want to say
yeah as as responsibly
for tcpm and psvwg
i think i would be very interested in
drafts for events in those protocols and
other transport protocols
appearing in those working groups to
standardize in the q log framework
thank you martin and thank you robin
to the next one
uh anna i think
europe i should
okay thank you jana so i
am going to talk about the congestion
control in congestion control in the
multipath
context and this is work that has
been done as part of our work on
multipath
dccp but what i'm going to talk about
today
is also applicable for for other
protocols so the general problem of
congestion controlling congestion
control for multipath
and this is joint work with colleagues
at deutsche telekom
city university of london and my
colleagues at college university
and in particular the results that i
will talk about today
is from our phd student at college
university
marcus piezka so next slide please
so first a little bit about the
background and context
so we are working on multipath
dccp as a multipath solution for
transporting general ip traffic or udp
traffic and this framework is using dccp
as the protocol so you have one dccp
tunnel per path and the two main use
cases
that we have in mind for this is
in the context of 3gpp and
access traffic steering switching and
splitting architecture
that is being defined there for
combining
cellular and wi-fi networks and
also for the hybrid access use case in
in home networks where you combine the
fixed and a cellular link for
better performance next slide please
so then let's look at the the problem uh
that we then encounter if we have
this type of multipath uh framework and
and this is generic for the protocol as
i said
so this tunneling solution of course
results in
nested congestion controls and this can
also be
a problem for for single bath a single
path
tunneling but when you move into the
multipath
context this encounters of course
an added complexity and
in our work we are using uncoupled
congestion control over the the two
parts
in all the cases as the use cases here
we don't see the need for coupling the
congestion control as the idea is to to
use the two parts and to be able to
to aggregate them and use them for the
better performance and we don't expect
the fairness issues to come into play
here so
you see the general setup on the picture
here you have a ue
and then you have a proxy or a
tunneling endpoint where you in this
figure have a downlink transfer so you
have the scheduling
component in this amp and then you have
two paths
two multi-paths with a congestion
control
a reordering component for the packets
and then
you have the also the congestion control
from the ue
and the to the server
next slide
so this scheduling and reordering
components will have a very
large impact on the performance in this
scenario so in this
results that i will talk about today and
also for a lot of the
the work we have done here we have
looked particularly as
at the cheapest path the first
scheduler or the the strict priority
scheduler
so you have a prepare preferred path and
you send
data on this path whenever you have a
space available in your congestion
window
and it's only if this
preferred path is not available that you
start to use your your other paths and
this is also of course uh
we think a quite reasonable scheduler
for the scenario that we are targeting
because you may for instance want to use
your
your wi-fi network and then only use
cellular quota if you if the wi-fi
network does not provide the
sufficient performance or you use your
your fixed
network in the hybrid access scenario
and then use your cellular
network for improved performance when
needed so this is a
scheduler that can have benefits both
from the user perspective and also from
the
operator perspective
the reordering component can also have
different
uh functions and i think marcus will
talk
particularly about reordering in the the
next talk
but in the work i'm presenting here
we're using an
adaptive time limit for
for the reordering to determine if to
pass the packets on
or not as we
may not have a reliable transfer also
over the the tunnel paths
next slide please
so i mentioned that if we move to the
multipath domain we have some
additional uh challenges uh for the
congestion control in congestion control
and particularly uh the challenge in
in this scenario is to be able to
aggregate the capacity
over the two parts so you're using one
path as your
preferred path and the challenge then is
to actually be able to also
use the second path when needed and in
particular
the end-to-end congestion control may
react
before and slow down before you are able
to actually start to utilize that path
if we take the the next slide
and here we have a example of this so
what you see in this graph
is a time sequence of four
different transmissions stacked on top
of each other
and for each one you see the the green
throughput is for the preferred path and
the red throughput is for the second
path
so up at the top of the
the topmost scenario you see that
things work as you would like it you
have
capacity using both the first path and
the second path
the second scenario from the top on the
other hand does not
work well at all you're not able to
use any of the second path so only the
capacity on the first part
is actually utilized and then we have
two examples where you
kind of manage to use some of the
the capacity of the second path and
in general the the use here is going up
and down a bit and this is
uh experiments with four different
configurations that shows how
different the outcome can actually be
here depending on
a number of parameters that impact this
performance
next slide please
so the results that i'm showing here is
using
a user's base implementation
of this multipath framework so there is
also a
kernel level uh implementation developed
by
uh the colleagues at deutsche telekom
available that
mike has presented the last ietf in the
tsvwd session some measurements from
there
but here we use a user space
implementation which of course offered
and
quite a lot of flexibility in trying out
different
protocols and different configurations
and this usage base program
do you hear me
okay something seemed to have happened
there with uh
good luck i'm back okay when did you
lose me
so i was uh explaining that we are using
a multi
the user space framework for this
experiments and this offers them a lot
of flexibility in how to
try out different scheduling methods and
and different
protocols so in this framework the
packets are captured through the
linux tune device and then the framework
encapsulates the packets with
information like the path sequence
numbers and the timestamps of the
packets
and then packets are scheduled over two
single path sockets so this means that
the framework as such
is not tied to dccp it also allows us to
use other protocols uh as tunnels so in
the
experimental results we have both
dccp and the tcp in the experiment
that you will see in the next line
and so this is the setup of the
experiments
on the end-to-end path it's the ip
tunneling where we have tcp
on top so we have used tcp cubic and tcp
bbr and in the tunnel
okay so i think maybe i will turn off my
video because this maybe is messing up
with the
okay so uh
as i said for the tunnel we are using
using both
tcp tcp neurino and tcp bbr
and then we are using a dccp with the
ccid2 which corresponds to
neurino and also a new ccid
ccid5 which is a implementation
of bbr style congestion control for dccp
and
we have uh some base
delays for the the two different paths
on the multipath and for the added delay
to the server 20 milliseconds on on
the preferred path and initial 20
milliseconds to the server as a baseline
and a similar trick path as a baseline
with 40 milliseconds to the second
over the second path and the same
bandwidth
and same q configurations on both paths
so next slide please
so now some example
results so short here stands for the
basic
configuration and what we see here
is the combination of different
congestion controls
on the end to end path and then in the
the tunnel and the results are relative
to the performance
over a single path so you see a
percentage of the the flow completion
time for downloading
a large file here so if you're below 100
you have gained performance as compared
to the
single path case and you can see here
that the
the performance varies a lot depending
on what
congestion control combinations you use
uh in general bbr is performing better
as a tunnel protocol
and this is as bbr reacts faster
when you start to experience congestion
and there is also less
loss over the tunnel
with bbr and you can also see that the
bbr at endpoints with reno in the tunnel
performs very poorly here because bbr
reacts before the the second path is
used
next slide please
so here we have another scenario where
we
look at the impact of where you
put the tunnel end point in relation
to the the server so the short
near scenario here the the proxy
is closer to the ue and you have more of
a difference between
the round-trip times end-to-end and
over the tunnel whereas the the short
distance then the
proxy is further away and closer to the
server
and you can see that this placement of
the
tunnel endpoint also has a large impact
on performance
and having the proxy closer to the user
to the ue as expected is typically
beneficial
because in this case you have more of a
difference between
the two control loops when you have more
difference in the rtts
and in particular you can see that
if the two rtt's are similar then bbr
over bbr performs quite poorly
next slide please
this is taking a little closer look at
this particular scenario
of the bbr uh over bbr
so what you see on the x-axis here is
the
end-to-end rtt and on the y-axis
you have the portion of that rtt
that is within the tunnel and you can
see very clearly here
how this has an impact on performance
and if you have
have a similar or similar rtt between
the
the two paths then bbr here is
reacting with the similar
attempt to fill the bottleneck and is
not able to move the the traffic over to
the
to the second path next slide please
um okay so to summarize um
the congestion control and congestion
control aspect has a lot of
impact on the performance on the the
multipath
tunneling problem and there's a lot of
factors that
interact here so the results that we saw
here
were particular to the the scheduling
mechanism of cheapest
pipe first and it also has a large
impact what the ordering mechanism you
use the different congestion controls
have quite the different
interactions uh the placement of the
proxy of course is also quite
important as well as the the path
characteristics
and if we should have some some first
general conclusions
uh from uh the the work we are going uh
we are working on we can see that
overall bbr performs better than
reno as the congestion control for the
tunnel
and having the proxy close to the user
as expected
is typically beneficial and
we are actively working on this playing
with the different
parameters and analyzing the the various
interactions so i hope that more results
will also
be coming and with the
next slide
and there are also a number of drafts
that are related to this presentation so
there's a draft for the multi-path tccp
protocol there's a draft related to the
the
framework multi-path framework some
draft related to how to
send dccp efficiently over udp
there is a draft on reordering that i
think marcus will talk about next and
there is also
a draft on multipath schedulers
and with that i am happy to have
questions
thank you anna let's keep this quick
because we have questions
after marcus's presentation next as well
uh i'll close the mic line here after
gauri but martin you're up
thank you anna this is very interesting
um how applicable do you think
these results are to non-multi-path
scenarios that have congestion control
in congestion fall like mask
so i mean the the particular problem of
of
using the second path which is the main
challenge here
will not happen unless you have have
multiple paths of course
uh some of the some of the
aspects that we see here for instance
the relation between
uh the different control loops in terms
of of rtt
and the impact of what what the
congestion controls you use in the
tunnel versus what you use and
will also come in to play in the single
path context but
the results are not directly
transferable of course
gauri you're up next
we don't hear yogori uh on side 11
i was curious with your heat map and how
this would play out if there was a much
larger rtt at place you know
is it so so can you just talk me through
a little bit more about what's going on
yeah so what you see here is
that the end to end rtt is going from
a very small rtt from you know
i think the smallest value used is 5
here
and up to about 100 milliseconds
and then on the y-axis you see
what portion of that rtt is
in the tunnel
so as you go up on the y-axis you have
more and more of the
rtt is inside the tunnel
which means that the the proxy is
further away from the ue
is the blue hole around 20 just an
artifact of the
analysis
uh the blue hole around 20 i'm not sure
what you you mean up in the top there
yeah yeah the top yeah i think that i
think that's just
a random effect so i mean what we have
done here is that we have sampled this
space
with the number of measurements and
so each measure of each measurement
point here is is
uh you know not repeated
many times it's like 400 samples over
the space
to create this heat map so there is
there is some noise in in this
graph of course but you can see
uh quite
clearly that the uh yeah
that the blue space is quite separated
from the red
so you can see quite clearly the impact
of the two control loops and and the
difference between the rtt's in the two
cases
thanks that's really nice thank you
thank you so much anna um we'll move on
to the next presentation
this would be the same space but i'm
gonna
bring this up marcus
europe
all right can you hear me
yes very good yeah
so i want to talk today about the
multi-pass sequence
maintenance what this means i will
elaborate in the next slide so next
slide please
yes starting with
how multi-path typically works which
components are
usually employed so let's have first to
look into the the picture
so on the left there's a sender on the
on the right you have a
receiver and in between that is now
very much related to multiples you have
at least two
communication paths
and on center side you have a scheduler
which
is responsible to distribute traffic
across
the multiple paths so you can have
different logics for this and you will
find the number of logics already
described
in the iccrg scheduler draft
while on the receiver side you probably
have a reorder
reordering mechanism so here is called
reordering queue and that's exactly
where we want to focus
on today on how can we ensure
the sequence maintenance when it comes
to to multiples
between sender and receiver a multi-pass
network protocol
takes responsibility to
allow the communication between sender
and receiver
and typically in such
scenarios when it comes to heterogeneous
environments you have a latency
delta between the multiple paths
employed in the communication and that
is exactly the issue
um where i want to talk about so
with this latency delta you can imagine
when we simultaneously
use the two parts so maybe we send
the packets in a round robin fashion
that will cause out of order delivery on
receiver side
and with that it completely differs from
the
characteristic of a single path
communication because in a single past
communications you're only dependent
um from from from the latency of this
single path
so keeping it short here having a
latency delta between multiple paths
causes some trouble and services with a
certain expectation on data sequence and
consistency
will experience issues
if you look at itf we see there are
multiple multi-pass protocols
defined or available as a draft that is
multiple tcp
multi-pass dccpa multi-pass quick cmt
sctp and so on
and would be interesting to see in the
next slide how they
behave uh when it comes to out-of-order
delivery and which mechanisms they have
um implemented to to overcome this
nevertheless typically scheduling and
reordering are not part of the protocol
specification
and it's left with the implementers um
to to take care and
that might cause trouble if an
implementation is dependent on
protocol mechanisms we will come to this
in the next slides so for mptcp
reordering is simple to do the strict
reliability
of tcp so it's a trust trust to weight
approach
on the receiver side
but if you look into the next slide
then we see that there are a number of
multi-pass protocols which claim
to provide no strict reliable in-order
delivery and that is for example the
multi-pass dccp
it's also the combination of a
concurrent multipass
http combined with the partial
reliability
functionality from sctp it's also
the multipass quick when it becomes
combined
with a quick data cram
so from from today's perspective
i think they should consider sequence
maintenance in their design
but i from my feeling uh that is not
complete completely given right now
um so
for the three protocols i mentioned on
this
slide the dccp http and quick
when it becomes combined with the unreal
of unreliable transmission
um then strict reliability is is not an
option obviously
um and the solution if we talk about
sequence maintenance will be a trade-off
between
maintaining the data sequence without
interrupting
the data flow
a special challenge in this scenario
is when it comes to to packet loss and
i think it's likely when when we talk
about multi-path transmission that
uh we will see packet loss to some
extent
and then this is all always combined
with the question
so how long do we have to wait in a
potential reordering mechanism on
receiver side
and at one point at which point in time
we can assume that the packet is really
lost and we have not to wait
for it any longer so during the
multi-pass protocol design
this has to be considered and possible
measures like different sequencing
schemes so for example sequencing scheme
for path
and separately for the multi-pass
connection
or a sender receiver signaling have to
be taken into account i will come to
this in the next slides
um yeah with this draft we have
available as icci the multi-pass
reordering craft now in version two we
claim
to cover all these aspects and provide
guidelines for design and implementers
of multi-parts protocols
next slide please
yeah okay let's have a
deeper look into what we have specified
so far in the draft
so we discuss uh several mechanisms
to support smooth and adjustable in
order delivery for multi-path
communication
and this draft scheduling is out of
scope so scheduling
uh maybe also provide some some
measurements to
to out to overcome out of order delivery
on receiver side
but we see is this rather as part of the
scheduler draft available at iccrg
so we discuss for example resequencing
mechanism with which we want to keep the
generated sequence
of data at receiver side and
there we discussed multiple
functionalities or multiple logics
so the first is the passive one so we
trust forward packets as arrived
for sure that will not reorder at all
then we have the exact mechanism that is
similar to tcp
and provides strict reliability another
mechanism is the static expiration that
means we wait a certain time
for missing packets until we assume
a packet loss and any packet which
arrive
in time will be reordered adaptive
expiration is similar to the static
expiration but
we do not have a fixed time threshold so
we
dynamically adjust the time uh on how we
how long we wait for a missing packet
depending on the rtt for example
or the latency on the part
then we have delay equalization strictly
spoken
that is is not a reordering mechanism
that just delay
the faster packets to match the latency
of the
slower part and last but not least we
discuss fast packet loss detection that
is probably something which can be
combined with the other logics
and that level the part and connection
sequencing
to to have a very early idea um
about if a packet is lost or delayed
next slide please
then we have two other areas identified
which can help to
overcome out-of-order delivery
that is recovery and re-transmission
in the recovery area we see that we can
overcome
packet loss when we spend redundancy and
in that
area we see forward error correction but
also network coding
and when it comes to re-transmission so
overcome packet loss by
by re-transmission we also see you see
three different
mechanisms which can help here on the
one hand we have the signaling
which is for example used in in tcp or
dccp
to signal outstanding packets to to the
sender
uh anticipated means we predict a
beneficial
uh early retransmission for for the
reordering
reordering purpose and last but not
least we have the flow selection
so the abil ability to retransmit
packages on a path different to the
original
one if this is if this supports the
reorder
as i said combinations of mechanisms are
in principle possible and most
probably useful
next slide please yeah
first of all i want to invite you to to
contribute to this draft
uh where i think that this is a
applicable to many of the multi-pass
protocols
um discussed or standardized at iitf
so that the draft itself is still under
development
and some content is not finalized
however
you have got an idea today on
which mechanisms yeah
about which mechanisms we think and my
question today is is there any mechanism
which is missing
so far and my second question is how to
proceed with this trough do you see
any value in that
yeah and with that i'm
ready for today and now i'm would like
to see some feedback
thank you marcus
i don't see anybody at the queue and i
don't want to spend a lot of time
waiting but i'll give it just
30 seconds if somebody wants to come up
to the mic and offer feedback
in the meantime i'll i'll offer marcus
that your question about
uh how do you want to proceed with this
draft i think the one thing i would
recommend is
is is engaging the group on the mailing
list
and and seeing if we can generate
discussion that's always a good way to
to to to get people interested um
andre is in the queue europe andre
andre we cannot hear you
i'm not sure what's going on there
but uh
i myself can you hear me now
yes yes go on okay sorry um
andre bondi software performance and
scalability consulting in new jersey
my question for marcus is how do you go
about setting the adaptive expiration
time what are the variables that go into
that
is this something that you're going to
do at connection setups that you can
establish what a floor on the latency
would be and how do you go about
increasing the expiration time because
if you make it too large
uh there's going to be an issue and
then there's a problem of degraded
throughput if you assume that you have a
longer latency on the slower pipe
yeah very good question thank you for
that um short answer here
we have some implementation in the
multi-pass gccp
available for that and there we
continuously
update the timer
with rtt information we get from the
sender
during transmission so we have some
signaling mechanism implemented for that
and
second point you are totally right we
have to set some
boundaries so it doesn't make sense to
let the reordering queue
grow to an infinite value that would
slow down the total throughput so
one measure could be here to set a
manual
limit yeah on the signaling is that
going to be in band or out of band that
is to say
along the connection the payload
connection on a separate connection
yeah yeah that is exactly uh
why i think we need this draft and that
is a question which should
should be mentioned there and then it's
on on the particular protocol to think
about
should this be something which is in or
out of bed
so we we would not give a final or i
don't see that we have to give a final
recommendation to a particular protocol
that is we just give some guidelines and
and such questions you have put now
um should this be something protocol
specific or out of band or
whatever that then has to be decided um
within the particular uh working groups
okay it may be service specific just the
way one uses out of band signaling for
circuit switch telecom ss7 for instance
oh that is that is now very specific
um ss7 from my knowledge uses stdp right
yeah it just goes along on a separate
trunk actually
this is old stuff yeah yeah okay
and then really old stuff like 30 20 30
years ago
yeah i'm gonna jump in here marcus let's
let's take that question
on to the chat yeah uh okay we do need
to warn but thank you for your questions
andre very much appreciate it
sure i'm going to the next presentation
and thank you again marcus and anna for
your presentations i think
we should continue the discussion on uh
on
on the list uh coming up next bbr
neil take it away
uh let's see can you guys hear my audio
um
okay great um all right uh so thanks
jana
yeah we just wanted to give a uh quick
update on
uh the bbr related work that's going on
uh in our team at google
uh and this is joint work uh with my
colleagues uh listed here
um next slide please
so i think this will be a a shorter talk
than many of our recent talks
at the itf just wanted to give a quick
update on
the deployment status at google where
we're
nearing completion for internal tcp
traffic
uh give a quick update on the alpha
open source release on github talk about
some plans
with respect to internet drafts and then
also talk about
our continued work on uh what we're
calling pbr netswift
uh and as always you know we're just
offering this in
in spirit of offering our experience uh
with
these kinds of experiments in deployment
and of course we are always um
looking for feedback or test results
issues people run into any ideas or
patches folks want to contribute would
be would be great
next libraries
so uh in terms of the um ongoing
deployment of
the bbr v2 algorithm within uh
google for google internal traffic
this is coming pretty far along right
now we're in the process
of deploying vbr v2
as the default tcp congestion control
for
internal google traffic and
uh we've gotten to a point recently
where uh it's used as the congestion
control algorithm for over
98 of the internal tcp traffic
uh as measured by traffic raid or
traffic volume
um just to be clear here so for this
internal traffic
uh we're using a number of different
congestion signals
uh you know we're using the core uh bbr
uh approach of modeling the bandwidth
and running around trip time but we're
also using
ecn and loss as signals as well
and as we deploy this we're seeing some
latency reductions at the tail for rpc
traffic and this is as compared to the
previous
uh congestion control which for internal
traffic
was um based on a shallow threshold uh
ecn
algorithm um and then we
also have ongoing work for
looking at bbr v2 for google external
traffic so
basically uh youtube and google.com
traffic over the public internet to end
users
and that work continues we're seeing
some reduced uh camera delays
um and reduced packet loss versus
vbr v1 um but we're still not
quite where we'd like to be and so we're
continuing to work on that
uh and of course we're continuing to
iterate in
internal lab tests and experiments as
well
uh next slide please
so in terms of the status of the
algorithm and code
as we've mentioned uh at the ietf a few
times
before we've got a release of the
both the quick and the linux tcp code
that's available the linux tcp code is
on github
and we've made a couple of recent um
minor updates to that code rebased it
onto a more recent version of linux
for those who are interested and posted
a few uh minor bug fixes
um and we think the the pbrv2
uh alpha releases is ready for
experiments and i think there have been
uh reports you know over the past uh
year or two from
other folks in industry and academia who
have taken a look at it both in
production settings and in lab settings
and there are just some links in the
slides to previous talks where we've
given more details about the algorithm
and the code and how it behaves
next slide please
so we um there have been a number of
requests for
updating the apr internet drafts
they the ones that are out there
currently uh
document the version one of the
algorithm um
and we are now uh planning to go ahead
and
uh update those to reflect uh bbr
v2 um and our goal is to get those out
there
by the july ietf so we can uh present
those and discuss those
um and you know the idea i think is to
uh just replace the drafts that are up
there with uh
drafts that are targeting bbrv2 hoping
that that will make it more clear that
um these are sort of replacing the the
earlier drafts
um uh next slide please
so we did want to mention uh briefly
that we are also
continuing uh another thread of research
work that we discussed briefly
at the november ietf on a
an approach we're calling for now
bbr.swift
which basically leverages approaches
from the swift congestion control
algorithm
uh which was presented at sitcom 2020
where the approach basically uses uh the
network round trip time
as the primary congestion signal and
there the the main motivation is that
it gives you uh for environments where
it's available it can give you a richer
signal with more information about the
current degree of cueing along the path
which has sort of two advantages
one is that it allows faster reaction if
there really are long queues right now
and then the other is that it allows you
to help
avoid overreaction when the cues may be
persistent but might be
short for example and you know there's
ongoing work for that
preparing for production testing doing
some
lab testing right now is the main focus
um as we mentioned uh tcpm
part of this uh research and development
effort
includes work to provide
time stamp information in the tcp
options
to provide the sort of detailed fine
grain
and more accurate round trip time
measurements that you need for
a scheme like this so there's a link to
the
extensible time stamp draft that we put
out last fall
and ultimately the goal is to allow this
as an optional
approach for contexts where
the target network round-trip time is
known which
might be the case for example in data
centers
and also where cases for cases where you
know that the other traffic sharing your
bottlenecks
is using an algorithm of this same type
and this might be the case for example
if you have separate uh
quality of service cues and you can
isolate this traffic
to its own queue to avoid interaction
with other
classes of algorithm and we do
ultimately want this to be usable for
physical machines and virtual machines
which will take some work to plumb the
time stamp information
up and down the stack to make these
timestamps available
but that is kind of the long-term goal
uh next
slide please
so um just in conclusion wrapping up uh
you know we're uh continuing to work on
both bbr v2 and this newer
approach uh bbr swift uh and we're
finishing the rollout for internal tcp
traffic for bbr v2
uh continuing to iterate on external
traffic or public internet
performance and are hoping to
release an internet draft in july and as
always we uh
invite um feedback or test results uh
issues uh patches anything like that um
and uh next slide please and i think uh
that's
that wraps it up also if there are any
questions
thank you neil we have a few minutes or
i am going to try a new experiment this
time which is that i will cut off
the q and a at uh at uh in
about in just under five minutes uh
doesn't matter who's in the line so i'm
not going to cut the mic line but i'm
going to cut off the q a
all right omer you are up
can you hear me yes
thanks dan uh can you share uh
do you have any data on what
kind of end devices bbr v2
is deployed on for the external users
are chromebooks uh androids uh
or something else and uh
but interests me the masters how bb2
interacts with the modern
modern cellular networks if you have
that if you if you have information to
share thank you
sure yeah so um to add some details
there so
where we're deploying bbr v2 um
in for the types of traffic you're
talking about
is for the google.com and youtube
servers that are sending traffic out
over the public internet
to end users and
um so since this is uh basically
um talking about all of the
users using youtube and google.com or
currently just
some a small percentage of them for
testing
uh this basically should be a
cross-section of of every kind of device
that connects to google
and youtube um and in our experience of
course that's a pretty diverse
set that largely these days i think
largely
the the dominant um bottleneck
technology is
wi-fi but obviously we do have a lot of
cellular users as well on the cellular
side i think it's still
mostly um 3g and 4g although we're
starting to see
you know obviously some 5g trickling in
now
and so the i don't have any numbers to
share
uh with you today um mainly because
this uh the public internet aspect is
still a work in progress
um but i can share that definitely we do
spend a lot of time
looking at the performance of both bbr
v1
and v2 for users that have cellular or
wi-fi connectivity since that is such a
dominant uh slice of traffic for for
google and youtube
excuse me does that answer the question
yes thanks
anna europe
anna europe i don't know if you're
unable to get yourself unmuted
and you're out of the queue
all right well i will uh thank neil then
for his presentation and i
will uh i won't speak for everybody here
but i speak for many people that
um very excited about the
the update to the draft looking forward
to reading
updates to the draft to the pbr
draft view
and that is now
oh give me a second
okay
all right gori get up
hi can you hear me
yes excellent okay
so um this short talk is going to look
at zero rtt parameters
for quick basically to exchange
transport parameters to let you do
something different in congestion
control
and there's a draft it's a revision
seven and it's with these people
on the side nicholas emile tom and me
next slide please
so this is a draft that tries to deal
with paths which are not typical
so we're talking about paths that have
something that's different
in them and maybe they're slightly
higher in delay
that could be many tens of milliseconds
it could be many seconds
they maybe have a very large bandwidth
delay product
they maybe have a sub ip layer
that is on demand and therefore
when you resume a connection you get a
different capacity or maybe
you usually get the same capacity but
sometimes you might get a different one
these paths are typically also have
other optimizations such as
asymmetry improvements and to get their
overall efficiency
at an acceptable level
if you have paths which are non-typical
then there's two options either you
dynamically learn that the paths are
non-typical or you have information
that lets you customize the
protocol stack to make it work and you
can do this
to mitigate the effects of delay the bdp
capacity asymmetry
our focus was primarily on satellite
paths
and that now covers a very wide range of
paths and we focus
just on geo in in the initial work here
and but you might see other paths that
have similar needs and i think
that's one of the important things i'd
like to kind of
bring up here is if other people are
seeing paths
that have other needs maybe slightly
different characteristics
we'd love to talk to you because we'd
love to make sure whatever we propose
here
actually works on across a variety of
different paths
next slide please
the context is to define some transport
parameters as extensions to quick
and these are shared during the zero rtt
phase
basically allowing resumption using
additional transport and connection
properties
discovered from a previous successful
connection
and what this is a lot like tcp control
block sharing
but it's also different because it's
designed for quick
we hope that the information that's
provided is useful for optimizing client
requests
there are cases where your web browser
automatically prioritizes different
pieces of information
maybe for the web client that's a
well-known bit of technology that many
vendors have already have in their
products
but for other applications such as dash
and
probably for a vpn applications etc
there will be ways to optimize the way
in which the network's used by the
clients
since this is iccrg the core
thing we're going to talk about is using
the information to make a jump in the
sea wind
the congestion window so that you
instead of starting a
session with a configured large initial
window
or with a normal small initial window
you choose something which is based on
previous history
and use that to initialize a safe sea
wind
and like any other method that's used
with tcp for instance
we'd like this information to be shared
across multiple connections
this is not a new proposal but it's a
proposal which we'd like to make
concrete for
quick next slide please
and why is this important if you have
the sort of
bdp and uh
delay that you might see in a satellite
geo environment
then it might take you many seconds to
download something
which you could actually send using tcp
and in maybe a small number of seconds
so quick is adding maybe two seconds of
extra
time in a typical configuration here
simply because there is no pep
involved optimizing the protocol so
maybe we can do much better
and this this slide shows two methods
which could be used to improve
performance that we've tried in a
spreadsheet analysis using a
a little tool we have to look at
different combinations of parameters
and we see the orange one is a jump to
of the last window and then two rounds
of rtt
to get to the full size window and green
a high jump method where we delay it by
one rtt
so we make the jump more conservatively
this range of options in the orange
green
area all the way across the glue area
where you can trade performance
against conservative congestion control
behavior
and that's the good reason for
presenting this in iccrg because
a lot of the issues are concerned with
how best to adapt but before you adapt
you need a method
of having the data about the previous
connection next slide
and the way in which to have this
information
we believe is to get the server to store
parameters
in a bdp extension which we then
communicate
from the server to the client the client
gets visibility of the information
it may also get a encrypted token
the encrypted talk can be returned back
to the server so the server could be
stateless if that's the design you want
and simply receive previous information
and about a floor that it had previously
struck with the same client
when you come to the second connection
to the same server
you can reinitialize the information and
of course there's a possibility that the
path to the end point
could have changed as a point there's a
path
change possibility in the amount of
capacity that you might have
of these two the most dangerous is the
change of the path
but um the method we propose will
validate the rtt
against the previous rtt and we're
suggesting that
we include some form of pacing when we
initially start a new um
higher congestion window and in this way
if there is a big rtt
change on the path then the damage
that's created
is very much limited and we believe
could be made safe
for wide-scale deployment and therefore
something that might be interesting to
standardize next slide please
this is the set of metadata we
expect to put in the bdp metadata
um three parameters bytes in flight
minimum rtt
encountered which is partly to configure
as a safeguard but also to configure a
pacing interval
and one of the issue one of the problems
is
is initializing the rtt of the pacer so
this information is quite helpful in
getting a
good response and the maximum packet
number encountered
so we say with these three pieces of
information can we now jump
safely next slide please
and next slide we don't need to talk
about this
um well we've approached this in
various ways one way uh was to perform
some implementation work in pico quick
and um there's a github that you can use
to
access this this is primarily focused on
the exchange of the cryptographic
information at the start of quick
of a quick connection so that you can
actually get the bandwidth
uh parameters exchanged and it focused
on a very
simple easy to implement change to the
congestion controller
we have a more advanced version of how
we expect that congestion control
um update to occur in the draft so
please leave
there to find more details about what we
actually suggest
but it's clear even from these three
simple results that
with out the option it took four point
three seconds
to exchange the two megabyte chunk of
data on average as the median value
with the zero rtt enhancement 3.4
and with the zero rtt vdp and 2.9
seconds so at least
saving what we would see um as people
evaluating satellite links a significant
proportion of the download time
and these are uh for
modern satellite length running at 50
megabits per second
next slide please
uh with also looking at uh how the
client might use this information
because
um the server can always optimize and
it be nicely optimized in a predictable
way so
the user didn't have to be concerned
about it but also there's a possibility
to optimize the client
if it knew about the
likely bdp aspects
of the path it's using and we did some
work in 2018 which is
published in the netsat days um
conference
it looked at dash and we showed that
using a
dash client we could take this
information
as one of the inputs to adapt the
results to produce a much more
predictable performance
in this case trying to avoid um
the strange behaviors that happen uh
when your predictor gets the
uh capacity wrong and therefore vastly
under underestimates the amount of
capacity you've got
because you've got a larger rtt and
there was talks in the irtf open about
the various ways in which
um dynamic adaptive streaming players
can play out and this is kind of like
one of the input parameters and a good
example of how
um knowing something at the client can
help you actually make better requests
at the application layer
next slide
and this shows a number of
different plots on the same graph i'm
first of all going to talk about the
blue plot this is
redo and the reno behavior is
that the congestion window opens in more
or less steps
stepping up each time it gets a round of
apps
and for a longer rtt
path this basically controls the amount
of capacity you can get
for small to medium sizes of exchange
this is totally the dominant factor
rather than the amount of bandwidth
available
when you use something like quake
because
if quit uses reno there is no protocol
enhancement along the path
so if we look at the jump
scenario we see here a different case
this is where the congestion controller
is initialized
with a previous rtt measurement
and we chose in this case to initialize
with 25
of the bandwidth that's 25 of the
previously used capacity
that means the following rtt there is a
step up
to use half the capacity and then
another step up etc
until after several rtts we've used the
whole capacity
now it would be possible to jump
immediately to use the full capacity
but if you're a congestion control
person that might frighten you
and because it would cause severe
congestion against any other flaws that
happened to be present
at the time when your new flow started
rather than when you previously measured
your available capacity
so we decided to initialize to around 25
and again and something we're happy to
experiment with
and there are ways of making this more
conservative we know this
next slide slight variation here i'm
going to talk about the
pink and gray curves the pink curve
is a method we call high jump which
delays
the arc the the increase and
we can talk about more of this in the
draft we also have high jump paste the
gray curve
what i'm trying to say here is that
there are a range of
congestion control decisions all of
which are
um safe to some extent
we would claim safe enough and a much
better performance than than reno
the hijab paste and paces the packets
out at the rate determined by
the previous capacity and we get this
more linear growth
in the use of the capacity and we could
talk more about that but i can't because
i need to move on so next slide
we talked about the client being able to
use the
information so this is not just a
server-side decision which is why
we're trying to standardize the format
of the transport
extension next slide
and we've also looked at the security of
it they the way in which to exchange the
the parameters the way in which the path
cannot
modify these parameters are important to
us
and we believe that we have a safe
mechanism here
that works with tls 1.3
next
there's some interaction um emil is our
tls person
um and there are probably things that we
should discuss
between quick and tls to see how
this initial exchange of data should
best be handled
and i think some form of synchronization
between the two working groups is
important
this isn't a congestion control issue
it's more a security
discussion but but it's still an
important part of the design of the
mechanism
next slide
congestion control safety is the
thing which probably is most important
for this group
and if we can standardize
or adopt a way of exchanging this
information we also need to adopt a way
of
safely using it and
we're assuming that any method we use
here will have a way of backing out
quickly and efficiently as soon as there
is loss detected
and the cw d has been artificially
increased so um we will we will
expect to quickly back out of any
problem but
um do we need a draft on congestion
control safety that updates 6928
maybe this might be something useful to
set the boundaries
here next slide please
we could use a new bdp extension
specified in quick
and we are wanting to do that part of
the work in quick
but there's obviously also a congestion
control piece which is why we're trying
to bubble this up here in this group
and attract some comments so
trying to stick roughly to time i'd like
to take comments now if possible
um very quickly
can you meet your mic there so i i don't
know that we have time
for q a we are already at time um
but i'll encourage people to thank you
for presenting this here
i want people to engage on this question
and i'll take my
my my moment to basically say that
this is something that we expect the the
the
us at a specific mechanism but the idea
of recording and
reusing constitutional control
information is something that we expect
will happen
in quick because there are places to
store this information at the client
this is something that is different from
pcb where a server can actually encode
this information and ship it off to a
client and then
use it on the next connection when
connection is established
which makes it much more likely that
something like this will get deployed by
quick implementations
so it is uh much more important now that
we actually engage on this topic
iccrg is the right forum perhaps we can
continue this discussion on the list
and at subsequent uh at the next meeting
as well but i'll thank gauri also for
putting this together very quickly
at short notice do you want to say
something cody
yeah i'd just like to say that we are we
are super interested
in not doing this as a group of
satellite engineers who've worked on
peps
and enhancement and modelling of really
long delay paths but to do it within the
ietf
where we can get other people involved
in this this is a super
interesting place where we can actually
collaborate between different people
and we'd really love to get feedback on
this
thank you so much gauri again for the
presentation one quick announcement bob
just announced that uh
a new draft uh describing product
construction control has been posted
please take a look uh we might end up
discussing that
at the next idea at the next iccrg
meeting um
thank you again everybody and enjoy the
rest of the itf
we'll see you next time