okay
giuseppe could you try my check
so
starting to feel like we caught
everybody you know stepping away from
the computer just before the session
started
uh so since giuseppe hasn't responded
yali could you also uh do a microphone
check please
could you hear me well we can hear you
thank you
thank you can you hear me
giuseppe you're a little bit quiet
okay
it sounds like you're talking to an open
air mic
let me change
and hello linda if you could do a
microphone check while we're waiting to
start that'd be great
can you hear me loud and clear thank you
okay good
all right we're two minutes into the
session so do you want to kick it off or
jeff you want to kick it off
i'll go ahead and kick it off today go
to the
folks welcome to the
wednesday session of idea we've got an
hour
if you've not read the note well please
do that
care will you show the next slide which
is the agenda
our agenda is close for
an hour so folks uh please be
tight uh if we get some more time at the
end we'll open it up to question
if not waymo you're first go ahead
hello everyone today i'm going to
present the hd
bgp flute spec for airsoft v6
next page
just give a quick review about the
document
so for ipv6 a packet head
for an sr package it has
special structures for example
its destination is a segment
id which consists of locate
located field auctions field
and arguments so for this special
structure
we define two new component types
so one of the type can consist at least
or for operators
with values to define
matching conditions on this special
field
such as locator field function field or
arguments field
so next page
so which for this latest version we just
made some editorial changes
next page
so we would like a welcome comment and
also we would like a request for
adoptions
yeah that's all for for me today thank
you
cool joel you're on the mic thank you
i had apparently not looking
sufficiently closely at this draft
if you're trying to point explicitly at
the lock field
and not encoding the length of the lock
field in this
spec then interpretation of
this piece of flow spec requires
processing and using other routing
information
to know how long the lock field is
yeah good question uh since uh so
in fact because these are actually just
just a very brief review
and we have uh uh for each operator we
have a value
so those uh lens for locator and a
function
is encoded in the lens
in in the value of in the in the value
field in the
variable so can you go to previous
slides
previous one that picture here we just
give
details about the operator in fact
where operator has associated with a
value
so those length field is
given in data value we have structure
okay yeah
yeah thank you so the length the the
length well it's not in the field type
is in the value that's good enough thank
you
yeah yeah yes yes
super jeff weibo uh my question to you
is
uh this is obviously targeted for
current srv6 related stuff
how do you foresee this interacting
perhaps with the work
ongoing in spring for you know the more
compact uh formats
are you expecting this to be a logical
format that you're expecting to carry to
the new compact formats
or do you think that you will need a new
flow spec for each of those
yeah that's a good question i think uh
uh these are
because we talked about uncompressed i
think for compressed one
because that structure may be a uh have
more information
will have additional information for
comprehension
so in that case we need a virtual
extension for
compressed seats right
i that is my question and one of the
possible outcomes
i i think the input i would give
as an individual contributor rather than
a chair
is that uh one of the things we know
about the sr related stuff is that
the differing formats are going to be a
big challenge and
i think we should understand what we're
looking to get out of flow spec
for the different formats before we go
choose any specific draft towards it
uh not so much that your draft doesn't
solve the srv6 problem
more that we may want to solve the more
general problem
yeah i think the first step is a focus
on the uncompressed one because for a
compressed one they're still working in
progress because there are
a number of proposals for compressing
the seats so different uh solution or
proposal for compression
they may have different information
attached or added into the destination
or c's
or some of them just put will update the
header some fields open field and flags
views
that is it thank you
joel you're next
oh sorry i pulled back up the draft and
looked
while i get how the length in the value
type works
for the lock how do you find
you you actually want to be able to
explicitly test the funk
and actually
there are multiple problems with
explicitly testing func separate from
lock
among them that it is not actually
required that they have meaning
that the encoding is the is constant
across things
that's not what's required by network
programming
and you don't know where the lock is the
length of the value field won't tell you
where
in this thing the lock is and it is not
required
that it be at a constant offset for all
sids used in a given domain even within
srv6
it could be but it's not yeah that's
yeah that's a good question i don't
think this works
uh this uh because uh
we just provide a this kind of component
and then and they use this one
the user or application will define
define those operators and then the user
user or application will have more
information about the size of locator
because for some of the because those
applications were used
were targeted for some some fluids
traffic flows
and then for those traffic flows they
will know they have more
information about the the locator and
the function
the interest you can't you can't process
this
without specific information from
elsewhere in the routing system not just
general config information i wouldn't
care if it required general config
information but you need to actually
know for this lock
i look at this funny bits to see
that that's the funk if if i have this
prefix on this segment
on the sid then i look at this many bits
and that's just not the way
even floatback has lots of problems but
but
i don't think you can do what you're
trying to do here the way you've laid it
out
i think you need to go back again at the
rfc on network programming
and on the encodings
for how things actually get transferred
remember that for example
the standards for the values of of funk
are not actually standards for the
values in the packet
they are only standards for the values
that get
encoded in the routing protocol that
tell you what the meaning of the sid is
so if you don't even know what the
meanings of the funk bits are unless
you've looked in routing
for the specific lock and it's encoded
separately for individual
locks so i think that the
srv6 network programming is much harder
to filter
if you want to separate filters if you
just do it as a prefix on the sid
sure it works i can't argue with that
and the length of the value will tell
you how many bits to test works but if
you want to separate out the funk or the
args
and test them it's not even clear it's
meaningful
as a test and it's not
findable as written joel and lama
i think this is a great i think this is
a great
thing to actually detail on the list
joel
waymo it might be a really good thing to
have
a discussion on this and confirm it
before you ask for working group last
call for working group adoption would
would you would that be okay because
we're going to
run i know you've got the time no
problem okay okay okay yeah yeah yeah
and also joellen
jolin waymo i think that
i think that the discussion would also
be valuable
either on idr list uh
because we're looking at the limitations
of flow spec
you may find that flow spec v1 or just
proposal
for expanding flow spec v1 may take us
into v2 which may provide us
additional aid so i really would like to
see this on the list because i think
it's beneficial
for our general flow spec thank you both
if we have additional time at the end
we'll open this up
uh joel and and waymo will come back to
this
okay thank you so much thank you emma
um next presenter uh linda you've got
two sessions okay so um
here i'm going to uh introduce a new
nlri
address family for the 5g edge computing
services
our next slide please
so um we presented this in 109
there were quite a few questions on the
list and and also during the discussion
so i just want to recap what we
discussed
so basically there was a assumption
that all those edge computing servers
they are in the local data network
close to the 5g core network
and the multiple
servers for one application and
the application prefer to use any cache
address
simply because make it easier for
deployment
so they don't have to readjust addresses
for the application
when they want to move a service from
one
server location to another with any
cache address
the network itself being leveraged to
distribute the traffic
to different um edge nodes
so um the the thing about
in our network itself we a network
network itself has been very good in
using the routing distance
to compute the best path to select to
the
the best pass and we also have te
traffic engineering taking bandwidth
into consideration
however for this kind of environment the
the bandwidth information and the
routing distance
might be similar so there's another
attribute being introduced
which is the running environment that
load information
the those applications themselves are
registered application services not just
every any service attached to the
network
only the ones the application that needs
network to
further optimize the distribution among
different locations
and so we introduced a new um
um mri and subtle v to carry those
information so that can help the
ingress node to choose the uh the
optimal path to the egress
router next page please
okay so um during the 109
and the mailing list discussion there
were three issues being raised
three major issues being erased right so
uh first one is how to select the
optimal egress router um
based on the information received um
second one is um how the english node
keep the packet
up from one flow to the same server
third one is when the ue moved from one
cell tower to another cell tower and
being anchored
to a different session
pdu session or they called which is part
of the
upf user plan function
then they will go through a different
ingress node how
that flow can be stick to the
the original server okay so
next page please so this meeting just
want to clarify those
issues so first of all um for the past
selection
uh there's assumption here right so only
for the register services
there's the application controller um
which is
identified in the 3gpp 748 project
the application controller will tell the
network which services they are
interested
for network to optimize the forwarding
with those information
appropriate acls can be created on the
ingress node
and other on the egress node uh which
service to collect
and there's a bgp
compute plugin that can compute
the optimal path or best path with the
information
about the running status in addition to
the routing distance
and the bandwidth information if te is
considered
so that's the assumption um so
this for the past selection that's
basically
we'll be able to take the application
metadata
um input into consideration so that
um when a destination has three next
hubs
r1r2 r3 and they can choose
to the the optimal optimal one
and in terms of forwarding um the
forwarding
the on the bgp compute download the
voting table to the
contract to the forwarding plan the
forwarding plan
will use the existing the flow
affirmative feature
affinity feature to support
to be able to make one flow goes through
the same path
this feature is supported by most
commercial routers
and when the ue moves to
a new uh sale size and
then the the traffic will ingress from a
different
ingress router we have a draft
in six man to show how do we use ipv6
to stick to the same
english egress router and
also if the ldn is
hrv6 based that approach
has been um described very clearly
in the six-man apn 6
to show how the srv6 is used
to stick to the original path
um okay next page please
so in the for the
app metadata information propagation
it's not to be distributed to every node
and the scope of the propagation
can be using we can use the ifc
4684 to constrain the distribution
um but there could be application
servers
many of the services needed so this
could also be
statically configured the application
server id
which is the anycast address and then
with the interested routers
next page please
so so here um
those are the main um subtleties we
propose
uh once the ri has attributes for the
application metadata
and today we only specify
the four sub-tlvs
one is the load measurements
and one is the capacity another one is
the preference
those information um can be either
actually um downloaded or
exchanged between application controller
to the egress router
or computed by the egress router so
those are out of the scope
how the egress router uh get this
derive those information but those are
the
roi needed to carry those information
in the future maybe more application
relevant data can be included here
but for now we are asking for working
group adoption
just for those proposed roi and
subjects that's it thank you very much
we've got a little
any questions for linda
linda you're on to your next
presentation oh
okay um so this is the sd1 edge
discovery this actually will be a very
short presentation
um thank you very much to the working
group
for the valuable feedback and we have
cleaned up the draft
and so i just want to give you an update
next page please
so this is what we discussed in ietf109
basically we
took the tunnel in cap draft
the mechanism described in the tunnel in
cap
draft and now it's probably on the q2ifc
now
using the separating the the underlay
um underlay tunnel property
advertisement from the
client so the client um basically use
the extended community
to describe the tunnel type and also use
the color
to coordinate correlate with the
underlay property
so um there will be two update two types
of update right
one is the client one is the underlay
um next page please
um so we cleaned up a little bit here uh
basically
if um ipsec um has been
ipsec security association has been
pre-established so instead of attaching
all the ipsec related parameters um
we just include the ipsec ids
and those ids are pre-established and if
those uh
episode has a certain uh inner
encapsulation
we'll attach the proper tunnel
encapsulation subtle beach which
is already described in the tunnel in
cab drive capture
so we i presented this on monday to the
ipsec me
just make sure those kind of
configuration and those kind of
method of carrying the information
doesn't cause any problems with episag
me group and people over there think
this this is good approach
this is slightly different from the
traditional ipsec configuration
which is always pairwise you always have
two end endnotes
and you have to establish authentication
you have to establish all the related
like traffic selectors admission and
routing information between the two peer
nodes
with bgp with the route reflector it's
scaled much much better than the
pairwise
when you have especially when you have a
large network
and also that with bgp you have
a raw reflector already connected to all
the edge node
through secure channel so the
authentication
is already done before even this being
established
it this before this message to be
exchanged so that's that's a good news
from the episode and e group
um next page please
so um but for the um
secure ipsec security association if it
is
needed to be exchanged through a bgp
update
they can also include it here with
detailed information
like the key sub trvs nouns
and proposals that transform all the
detailed attributes needed by ipsec
they can also be included as a subtle v
in the tunnel exchange
next page please
so um with a hybrid
hybrid tunnel which can include both
nprs paths and episode path
um this roi is introduced
um basically include the color uh
include the
site type because for hd1
deployment some sites can be far away
it's not like
controlled uh like mpls everything is
within
the within the wall so the site type can
have be
a simpler uh just the node id itself be
able to identify the precise location
there could be in a more diverse
at your geographic location that you
need to include the
geolocation information septuali to
indicate
accurate besides your location and
we have color to correlate with the
client
update next page please
so i we think that this draft
is clean enough and answer many
questions from the working group
and we are ready for working group
adoption
super any questions for linda
thank you so much linda great thank you
and we got four minutes back
in our next presentation uh giuseppe
hello everybody can you hear me okay
yes we can hear you fine okay yeah this
is an update about the bgtsr police
extension for
i fit the graph that's been adopted
during its 109 so next slide
yeah just a few words about background
and motivation
um if it refers to data plane on path
telemetry in particular in c2rm
and alternate marking and you can see
the
document the relevant documents for
these two methodologies
on the other end we we know that an
add-in may be informed about a graduate
part about
by using bgp and you you can also see
the
relevant document by combining these two
bot on part telemetry methodology and
using the
this bgp capabilities we this document
times to define
a new extension to digitally to
distribute
i fit information together together with
the sr policy this way
the telemetry methods can be
automatically enabled
so next life
yeah in this in this slide we report all
the changes after the working group
adoption in particular we received some
comments on list
during the adoption call firstly
from drew we he suggests to
add more text about the error rambling
actions the
ifit procedures to start stop
update the different type features
and also the backward compatibility that
need to be guaranteed
another comment from katan was more
about the
types of steering that would be possible
to be used
for sr policies and how this is handled
by the srpm
another comment from gun was about the
alignment with the sar policy and tunnel
encapsulation attribute
according to the idr segment drawing fee
policy graph
another comment from mike was common to
the companion draft in pc
regarding the possibility to consider
different effect methods for each
segment list
and we also added some consideration
about that
and in the end we added the new new
fields in the alternate mapping mode
to indicate if the measurement is up by
operant one
next slide
in this slide we summarize the changes
in
the main changes in the zero one version
uh the first one is about the
specification of how happened is
speeding into a nasa policy
basically it is the same as specifying
in the spring in the spring document on
segment routing policy
so once the airfit attributes are
similar to bgp
when the packet arrives at the at the
head and it may get steered into the sr
policy
according to the procedure they find
spring document
and i think methods can be applied of
course
if they are similar regarding the
all the possible cases of i feat
we adopt and in the draft a conservative
strategy so this means that
in case of empty i feed wheels or more
than one instance of the same subjects
or if there are two conflicting
iom subtle these uh if it is not
activated
so it's better to have the conservative
approach
if this is an optional functionality
the regarding the validation as
specified in the
spring document this can be treated as
all the other tlv so the validation can
be added by the srtr
the backward compatibility can be also
guaranteed because
if there is an implementation that does
not understand if it subjects v
it can be simply more and the same
applies for error rendering
actions because as described in segment
routing t policy draft in spring
a bgp speaker must perform the syntactic
validation of the
mli and can determine
if it is good if it is not formal
and if there is an error tritas withdraw
is a good strategy to apply
and these of course apply also to a heat
treat
next
now this is a quick recap about the
draft we
updated the sr policy encoding structure
and the effect attribute you can see
that we
draft added the effect attributes after
the gate at
the candidate part 11 as the subtleties
on the right you can see the format of
the general life it's subtle these and
the the detail of the different options
of the video
currently defined data file
next
yeah in this slide we have the detail of
the situation sub tld so
the top four for the pre-allocated race
option the incremental presuption
directly export option and edge to edge
option
all the fields of course are aligned
with the incident
graph in ippn
and next
yeah this is the the other subject
related to the alternate marking
as i said we added two new fields the
two flags
uh h and e about that indicated
that the measurement is up by operand
one
and this is also aligned with the rail
around drafting
in ipv6 on data plane about alternate
map
next slide please
yeah we added some more consideration
about
the operations uh we defeat attribute
for sr policy
basically we referenced all the
operations
of segment routing key policy draft in
idr
so we just updated
some added some consideration but the
basic operations are
the same uh since a fit attribute
subject are optional they can be
considered
in the mli by a bgp speaker but
of course the implementation may
unsupported subtleties
once the mlris have been accepted have
been considered
acceptable including the afib
information
this can be propagated regarding the
error rambling and the validation
this must be performed to determine if
they are formed or imbibed
but this is done by the srpm has also
stated in the segment browsing through
policy draft
so next that's like this
is the final slide so we are working
this work is in progress to make the
draft table
of course we welcome questions comment
to improve it
and to go to glide
thank you
any questions for giuseppe
super thank you okay
thank you
and i believe we still have one
presentation more
uh
from yali
i'm trying to get hold of the slides
okay thank you give me a second please
yeah sure
grab this presentation i have them hold
on
yeah can i give you the
screen yep
so you got the screen okay
ugh
this should be ellie do i have the right
presentation
yes but i cannot see the
slide make sure the screen
sure is being started uh i see
never mind give me a moment to go back
to the screen sharing
give it a second
excuse the few moments of
fiddling with this
okay just a minute you'll get the big
screen
yeah i can't see
i'll get you a full screen mode can you
go ahead any time you want
okay thank you uh hello everybody
my name is uh yali wang from huawei
so i'll talk about the draft
to propose to define the bgp extension
for advertising ipad capability
next slide please
do you see ellie yes yeah i think
maybe a little bit delay yeah thank you
so first i am going to describe
requirement
and goals of this uh proposal and then
i'll
introduce the definition of iphase
capability
and two optional extensions
next page please
your next slide is showing
yes i see it so yeah first of all
uh england uh ifit refers to a family of
data plan on paths
techniques including the in-situ oem and
alternate marking and
i need to indicate that the iphone
capability
of the devices can be manually
configured one by one so hence the
deployment
efficiency is low and menu configuration
may be
incorrect so and
when the i think the capability of the
network devices it changes
for example uh the devices change from
the
supported eye feet uh to uh
non-supported the high feed capability
so the
physical configuration on this device
need to be modified so
based on this uh crashing and issues
here
we propose a extension
to bgp to advertise the
tail nodes iphase capability
so in this one we propose two optional
methods one is to extend to
ipv 4 or v6
address specific extended community
and another one is to
extend to the bgp network capability
so here i want to answer the question
why we
propose list to option
optional extensions as i
uh as i mentioned before we need to
prevent
the information leakage which means that
we we need to avoid
the iv8 data
leak outside of the ipad domain
which may cause complete and errors
and another reason is that we need to
determine
uh whether i particular i fade
option types can be uh supported by the
tail nodes
it means that uh depends on the
information
i can decide which kind of the
iv option to be in
encapsulated in the english node
uh yeah this is the reason next page
please
so here we firstly define the
ifit capability format
assuming the figure is formed as the
16-bit bitmap and right now we give the
five flags uh used to
indicate different kind of option types
include the ion and alternate marking
yeah next
okay here uh this is the first option
extension and this is extension to bgp
extended community so uh
here we give the uh
true scenario firstly is for uh
the ipv 4 network
so let's just define a new type of btp
extended community called ipv4
address specific if a tail community
so it means this it can be used by the i
feed
the capsulation node to notify the iphat
capability to is its partner uh i mean
they i think it's encapsulation note uh
it because it is a uh traditive extended
uh unity so we
here we requests to
be allotted the subtype code number
and this another one is for the ipv6
network i think it's a
seminary i mean the seminary matter to
to extend the ipv6 uh
address specific i think tail community
yeah and uh as shown in the figures
or original address
is are defined as the ipv's
i4 address of the f8 capsulation node
and another one is is a ipv6 address of
i fit the capsulation node
next please please
okay this is the second optional
extensions
to a bgp next hub capability
and so here a the bgp next hop
capability attribute uh is an
uh is a non-traditive bgp attribute
so here we it is
modified or deleted when the network may
change it
here we define to reflect the capability
of the next hall
the hub of the iphat capability
so here the capability codes
we defined as a two oct octet
are signed by uh uh
binary intake lim integral
which indicates the type of network
capability
uh uh advertised and
[Music]
to identify an individual capability
and here we request to uh
less code as the i fit next
i face next hub capability and
here we also um to define the original
ip address
uh as the iphas the calculation node
address so so
uh at defined here we can see that
a pdp speaker that can send
an update with this
bgp next hope capability attribute uh
including the ifit network capability
so the increasing of the iphone x hub
capability with the network
layer reachability information
in the bdp updates indicate that the bdp
next club can act as the
iphat decaf solution node and
it can process the specific
eye fit package
yeah this is the second one next page
piece
okay yeah this is all the
content defined english swaps and
any comments suggestion questions for
let's draft
uh please let us know and
we also request work group to evaluate
this draft and consider it
be adopted thank you that's all
okay or you will need to ask for
questions and manage the money
for sure uh any questions uh
folks for yali's presentation
jeff
am i off mute now yes thank you sorry
about that
ali thank you for presentation and this
i think is
a more general question uh more
applicable to your draft than the one
that giuseppe has presented
um i have many concerns
about the security considerations and
some of the protocol behaviors for
this draft not that the problem is not
worth solving
but i i think there's two things that
are sort of clear from looking at the
initial presentation
the first one is that the ifit domains
have considerations as to how widely
this information can propagate
and since these things are attached as
extended communities you know they're
very likely to get
far away from where you want them to so
some discussion about that needs to
happen in the draft
the second item i see is an immediate
concern is when you're trying to
actually say that the next hop
is able to carry out certain behaviors
you're making assumptions that the next
hop is potentially not being reset on a
different spot of the network than where
the community was originally attached
so i think that also raises concerns
yeah thank you thank you your
comments and suggestions and uh
for your first question i think you mean
the
uh the i think uh uh domain
right how widely the fatal man
is and how widely the information can be
transmitted and because i think
the definition of life domain has been
defined in i mean
another drop and i think we can
make it aids the jobs as a reference
and make sure the domain
of diabetes but uh as i know the
ipad domain dependence and bounty dance
the
i face ingress node and the egress note
so um after
uh i mean when when the package had i
fit
uh i mean i fit a header
in the package so before
before the package transmitted to the
e-grades nodes
uh as shoe the header i think had
should be removed from the package so
let's
try to make sure the uh the security
uh in the trans uh i think domain i
think
but i think it should be a problem to
to consider it it's a right the
the specific concern is that the
communities that you're attaching to bgp
will leave the ifit domain so
let us say that isp a
is a ifit domain and it's part of you
know autonomous system number one
when the routes are sent for
destinations inside of that autonomous
system to autonomous system 2.
if the ifit capabilities are not
stripped
i believe this gives information that
suggests that as2
is capable of doing ifit operations with
as1
i don't think the expectation for ifit
is that that should work
but the capability propagating tells it
that
maybe it should
yeah uh i think yeah i i think i will
uh considering your suggestion
and uh if if you don't mind we we can
discuss this
in the main list yes i'll take it to the
mailing list
thank you very much thank you thank you
boris you're next oh thank you
yeah very short comment not question
would be very good to see
implementation status in the draft
uh you mean worth the time
it would be very good
okay okay i i think i will add the
part in a new version
thank you for your comments
tony hi a follow-up question to jeff's
comment
given that this is local and we really
don't want it propagating
wouldn't this be better served being in
the management plane
and not in bgp whatsoever
oh i'm sorry i i i don't catch your
opponent sorry
so why is this information in bgp it
seems like this is
information that should be provided via
open config
oh okay this is from it's
from the motivation i think from the
motivation of
this uh proposal we designed
because we consider to
take advantage of the btp protocol
to dynamically trans uh dynamic
dynamically detect the devices
capability so we consider
using the uh the control plan
protocol not the management plan
this is our uh motivation here
because uh here we we i think a
previous slide we have mentioned that we
we're considering
uh if we devices dynamically change
this its uh capability uh
to support the iphat uh application
right
so we need uh need have a matter to
dynamically detect its capability
so here we we give a uh
a matter to taking advantage of the bdp
protocol
to to catch its
capability information yeah this is our
consideration
here yes you are protocol i understand
that
why you stick it in routing this has
nothing to do with routing
okay you mean it relates relationship to
the
routing right so here i think
um because the
you mean uh you know that i feed uh
the i fade application can be inserted
into the
package the the traffic packet so
if we want to measure the
performance matrix using the iphage
i mean the iom or the alternate marking
matter to
to get the performance matrix so
the devices need to support
the capability to proce close process
the iphage
package so when we
enter the ingress nodes when we decide
uh which which
for example which powers a path or the
which
flow uh we need to use the iphat
application to measure the performance
matrix
we need to know
these devices along the path can support
this capability i mean the supposed the
eye fit
capability so you can affect
the uh affect application
on the other hand if you
want to calculate a path
can be used the ifit
application to to
measure the performance matrix to make
sure the
soa of list parts so
you need to know uh how
which devices cannot support
or which device can support the iphat
application along the path
so um kelly
this is sue um i think
you might i i think you might
need before working group adoption
to uh carefully consider tony's
question and uh
provide some pros and cons
uh on this i don't think
at this point perhaps due to the fact
you've just heard tony's question that
you've given
a uh response
that doesn't point back to the
management plane
so i may i kindly suggest that
you consider this question with your
co-authors
and provide
some additional details if you'd like
some feedback on an initial
presentation before you send it to the
list you are welcome to send it to the
chairs
but i think it would be wise to consider
and give pros and cons before you go for
a working group adoption otherwise
i think we're going to go through this
discussion again
would that be okay ellie yeah sure
i want to discuss more details with that
with yours
yeah or you can i encourage you that
this discussion should be
come to uh should occur will need to
occur on the list before working group
adoption
but if you are unclear on the question
or the import of the question you can of
course send the chairs
some some clarification
but you will need to discuss why this
is important to put in routing
on the list before we go working a group
adoption
otherwise i'm afraid it will just repeat
during working group adoption
do you understand what i'm saying if not
you can ask me
in email yeah i think i got your point
okay thank you
thank you again for your time and for
your presentation
i think we're out of time care it's your
call
yep no we why don't we take uh your
questions robin and kissabi
um on the mailing list uh
and uh close the presentation at this
point
sorry and thank you
so that was the last presentation and we
will see you again
at ietf 111
in three months thank you folks
[Music]