all right
welcome everyone to the ietf 110
administrative and operations plenary
i'm alyssa cooper
and i am the uh itf chair for a few more
minutes
hopefully everyone's having a good
meeting and i think we can kick off
next slide please
just a reminder i know most people have
been in meetings already this week but
for those joining by meet echo you're
muted when
you join both your audio and video and
we're asking people only to unmute when
you
are recognized in the queue to speak if
you are speaking in the
turn on your video and we strongly
recommend
the use of a headset if you need more
guidance there's a participant guide
available online next slide please
here's our agenda for today after this
welcome we will have
a presentation from our meeting post
google
and then we'll have brief updates from a
variety of people
and organizations in the ietf
robert do you have a question i'll see
you in the queue
no apologies it was just the side effect
of the
of joining okay welcome
so we'll have um updates from myself uh
from for the ietf and the isg uh from
the iab
the irtf the nomcom the itf llc
and the itf trust next
then we'll have a short presentation
about applying and evolving
quick we will be recognizing our
outgoing
members of the itf leadership and then
we'll have our three open microphone
sessions
for the isg the iab and the itf llc
next please
um so first off a huge thank you to our
meeting host for this meeting google
even though we're not meeting in person
these meetings still require a lot of
effort in the background
and the support of sponsors like google
is critical to
being able to deliver the meeting
experience that we all have so we are
deeply thankful to google for their
continuing support
and i think we have a video to queue up
next
hello i'm vince surf i'm vice president
and chief internet evangelist at google
but some of you
might know me as one of the fathers of
the internet
bob khan and i started the design work
on the internet in 1973
and the internet engineering task force
was started in 1986.
those of you who've been participating
in ietf thank you
those of you who are interested in
participating please do
yeah you can't become a member all you
can do is show up and share your ideas
why is that important well the
internet's been evolving for the past
40 some odd years and to first order
the reason it's been evolving is to meet
new demands
and to incorporate new ideas coming from
people like you
at the ietf and so let me encourage you
to continue all of that creative work
it's a huge opportunity to keep
expanding the functionality and utility
of the internet
as it spreads around the world
excellent well that was very inspiring
to hear from vince
um so thanks again to google and i think
we can move on
also wanted to say a huge thank you to
uh everybody who has worked to help
make this meeting happen and um and all
of our ietf meetings
um and that includes the secretariat
meet echo the knock team the llc
the tools team and all those who are
supporting the hackathon
again the the meetings couldn't couldn't
happen if not for the efforts of
a large number of people who
put in their time to make sure that
everything gets off smoothly and we've
had a really smooth
experience this time thus far so big
thanks to all of you
next
so this will be my report um just a few
topics first we're going to look at
participant statistics
uh look a little bit at the impact of
covet 19 on
activity in the ietf and talk about
planning for
future meetings so we go to the next one
so these are our statistics for this
meeting
same format as we've been doing for each
plenary during the pandemic
we have a good number of registrations
here
uh north of 1200 and we're pretty steady
on the fee waiver numbers as well
um a lot of people participating in the
hackathon virtually even though we can't
get together in person so that's
that's been great and um these are
especially for the meeting itself
these are the registration numbers we'll
have more detailed attendance numbers
um that get posted after the meeting is
over once we can um
identify actual attendance through the
whole week you can see here
also the country breakdown um
so we have a fairly typical split for us
but if we go to the next slide we can
look at this in more detail across the
last couple of years
so we thought we were inspired by
some folks who are collaborating during
the hackathon in the
who work on the big bang project and
nick doty in particular who
produced the chart that you're looking
at here so big thanks to nick
so what we're looking at is the
regional breakdown proportional
breakdown
for attendance at the lesson of
in-person meetings that we had 104 105
and the three virtual meetings that
we've had 107 108 109
prior to this one so if you look at the
first set of three 104
five and six um these show a fairly
typical
regional variation for us when we meet
in europe we have a higher
participation from people who are based
in europe
not too surprising same thing for north
america
same thing for for asia and the swings
there can be pretty
significant um some you know something
between 10 and 20
swings for each of those regions
depending on where we locate the
meetings
as we've switched to virtual it's much
more steady
um and caveat here a little bit that
ietf 107 was not
exactly the same format as 108 or 109 if
people recall it was a much shorter
day we did a much smaller number of
sessions so the data might not be
directly comparable um but nevertheless
we thought was interesting to look at
um so if you look here at 107 108 109
you can see that the the proportions are
much more stable
um and a little change there in 109 but
um some
something more in like a few percentage
points of swing for
for each of the largest regions from
which we get um participation
uh nothing like 10 or 20 um so that's i
think interesting
also because we have been rotating the
time zone of the
of the virtual meetings um but that
doesn't seem to affect
the regional distribution of the
participants as much as
um rotating the actual physical meeting
location
and then the last thing i'll say about
this is that the 104 105 106 numbers
these are just
the in-person attendees um they don't
include the remote participants
that might be interesting to look at as
well and and see what the differences
are
um all of this data is actually
available by the data tracker api
um so people who are interested can go
take a look at that
or if you're generally interested in
doing some analysis
on participation data of different kinds
not just meetings but also
mailing list analysis go take a look at
that big bang project
people are doing some some really
interesting work there
good collaboration next slide please
so the iesg's also been tracking a
little bit
the impact of covet 19 on a few
measures of participation we looked at
some of this data in the last
meeting but we've kind of built it out a
little bit more so i thought it would be
good to look at again here
so what you're looking at here is the
total volume of
email messages on ietf lists and we have
a four year comparison
from 2017 through 2020 2020 obviously
being
the dominated by the by the pandemic
year
and so for email traffic what we see is
that the email traffic during the
pandemic
uh last year was roughly in line with
what it has been in previous years a
little bit
a little bit higher um but you know
similar to what we've had in past
years we'll go to the next slide please
if we look at internet draft
publications we see
something fairly similar so a small dip
from 2019 to 2020 in terms of the total
number of internet draft publications
but not really a huge difference from
what we've seen in past years
so that's for total drafts published
and then if we go to the next one
well if we look at zero zero drafts
published here's where we start to see a
difference
so from 2019 to 2020
there's about a 16 drop in the total
number of zero zero drafts published
um which might tell us a little bit
about you know new work coming into the
ietf
and um the rate at which you know people
are
coming up with new ideas and thinking
that it's a good time to you know
publish a zero zero draft
i think a lot of people um
anecdotally who who do work in the itf
have
um have had this feeling that it's
harder to get new work
going without the hallway conversations
and the face-to-face interaction
um and i think this this particular
number um
illustrates that fairly well there's a
few things i'll say about that one is
that
there's lots of other ways that you can
attempt to measure
you know the impact of covid on
participation and the iesg is very
interested in people's ideas about that
we also had a little bit of discussion
about the rfc publication rate
and you know the rate of documents
coming into isg review those are more
like trailing indicators
this is more like a leading indicator
but it might be interesting to look at
trailing ones as well
um and we're also really interested in
people's
thoughts and ideas about how we can
try to make up the difference when we
can't meet in person so
if people have good ideas for you know
how we can sort of re-stimulate on some
of this new work activity
um or whether you you know even think
that this this isn't you know
cash accurately capturing um a trend of
of it being more difficult to start new
work um that would be
we're super interested in people's ideas
for that so please um you know come to
the mic at open mic or you can reach us
at our email address isg ietf.org
next slide please
so planning for future meetings people
may have seen
that the decision process for whether
itf-111
will run in person or not um began with
community consultation
last week it may have been the week
before actually when i'm not sure it was
last week when we wrote the slides or
actually was last week but feedback is
welcome on the mini couch's
mailing list there is like a very
structured and detailed
process that we've followed in the past
few rounds for
making the decision about whether to
move forward with an in-person meeting
or switch it to online and the proposal
is to follow that process again
so those who are interested please check
out the proposed process
and feel free to send your your comments
about it to that list
next
there's also a few other ways to to
provide more detailed feedback on
specific aspects of
of meeting planning so if anybody's
having any kind of
issues at all at this meeting technical
issues or otherwise
you can send a email to support ietf.org
that is the one unified ticket queue for
all
ietf support requests now um
so you know please avail yourself of
that if you're having any trouble during
the meeting
if you have feature requests for meet
echo or for other
itf related tools you can send those to
tools discuss
um and they will be triaged there as
always there will be a meeting survey
that comes out at the end of this
meeting so
if you want your input to be
incorporated into future meeting
planning then
please fill out the survey when it gets
sent around and then for a bit longer
term meeting planning we still have the
stay home
meet only online working group the
schmoo group it met yesterday and
there's a bunch of different topics
within scope for that charter
there's discussion about meeting fees
for online meetings acer
asynchronous meetings um uh potential
future discussion about the overall
meeting cadence
and length what to do with the hackathon
when it when we're all remote
considerations for cancellation there
was some previous discussion about the
show of hands tool and meet echo
so lots of good discussion happening
there and if people are interested
the list for that group is also the mini
couches mailing list
next slide please
we also have a bunch of other
information covered online
um we didn't have any appeals this time
so we don't have anything covered there
but reports from the iab the llc board
the secretariat and iana are
will are already or will be available
in the data tracker and we have updates
now and again on the itf blog as well
next slide please
all right ready for maria
yeah hello everybody from my site um so
i only have a very short
brief update i only have two slides and
we can move directly to the next slide
and one more actually this is only like
the cover slide
so um as always and as elisa just said
we have uploaded a report to the
community which is part of the
proceedings
and you can find all the boring
administrative details in the report
there
and we have another meeting tomorrow
which is the iab open meeting we do this
for a couple of
of itf meetings now um and we take this
as an opportunity to have more technical
discussions with the
um community to tell the community what
we're doing um
with respect to documents workshops um
and and programs and also to get input
from the community that session will
happen
um tomorrow afternoon and so i hope to
see you all there
and have some more um discussions there
if you have any questions about the
report
just send an email to iab or to me
directly
so next slide is already my my last
slide
and it's just a couple of quick
announcements i want to make
so first of all the ib has reselected me
as the iap chair
thanks very much i'm very happy that i
can surf in this position for another
year
um and this is also mentioned in the
report
and we have some more appointments we
made between the last meeting in this
meeting one is that we also reappointed
already a couple weeks or actually
months ago
um colin perkins um as the irtf chair we
got a lot of good feedback about him so
there was like
no other choice and uh warren kumari is
appointed for
the icon technical esl group but i also
want to take the opportunity here
to reserve to really thank everybody
else who is serving
as an appointment an important position
and serving the community here we're
currently in the appointment process for
the internet society board of trustees
um so we basically the iab already
selected the two positions
um it's now for confirmation with the
iesg but it will only be announced
later in may because we coordinate this
with ice hock
and then one last announcement
um we have created a new position which
is called the iab
liaison coordinator position and we have
created a new male alias
that you can use to post any kind of
info
questions or information about liaisons
to us
we are currently in the process of
reviewing the liaison management process
and
these are oversight and set up
so you will hear more about this in
future
and this first step this first new
position is really to
get everybody the community as well as
the liaison managers
a clear contact point because that has
been missed in the part
in the past um but
more information about this will follow
in the next couple of weeks this is an
ongoing process
ongoing discussions um and we will also
update you a little bit more on this
even so this is more on the
administrative side and not so much
technical side but it's a really
important topic for the iap so we will
also update you
with a little bit more details on this
tomorrow in the iab open session
so again thanks for everybody who is
currently has been newly appointed or is
currently serving in any positions where
point
and also thanks a lot for reappointing
me as the chair
that's it
okay uh thank you maria uh next slide
please
okay so uh my name is colin perkins i'm
the irtf chair and
uh i i'd like to to echo uh mary's
thanks uh
and thank you for again for the
reappointment uh and i'm looking forward
to
uh continuing to to work with the
community for the next couple of years
in the irtf
next slide please
so as i'm sure most of you know the irtf
is a parallel organization to the ietf
that works to encourage collaboration
between the research community and the
standards community uh it's organized
there's a set of research groups
uh and those of the groups uh which are
highlighted in dark blue
on this slide are yet to meet uh so look
out for them
uh later this week and we just had a
really interesting session from that
from the quantum internet group
uh so i think some some really nice uh
research happening here
uh if you want to learn more about how
the the irtf works uh rfc 7418
is a really nice primer for a
etf participants to introduce the way
that the research
the research groups work next slide
please
in addition to the research groups
we also run the applied networking
research prize
in cooperation with with the internet
society
and with sponsorship from comcast and
nbc universal
and the applied networking research
prize is awarded to
recognize uh some of the best recent
results in applied networking
uh to um recognize interesting new
research ideas uh which are of potential
relevance to the standards community
and to recognize and support upcoming
people that are likely to have an impact
on internet standards and technologies
and in particular
we try to some to some extent to focus
on ideas and people who
who would not otherwise get much
exposure
um who would not otherwise participate
in in the ietf
uh in the standards community and try
and bring them into the community
uh and encourage collaboration and
discussion
next slide please
so we we had two of these prize-winning
talks uh earlier in this week
um francis yan
from microsoft research formerly from
stanford university
gave a talk on his work on applying
machine learning to to video bitrate
adaptation
uh and audrey randall from ucsd
gave a talk on dns caching and privacy
and these were two really really
excellent uh really really interesting
uh
price winning talks so uh if if you
missed those talks
um that the recordings are on the web
page listed and also on the the ietf
youtube channel
and i'd encourage you to take a look at
those talks so there's some really nice
work there
next slide please
and the other thing we do in the irtf
is we organize the uh applied networking
research workshop
in cooperation with acm sitcom
and the applied networking research
workshop is a forum to try and bring
the research community the vendors the
operators and the standards community
together
to present and discuss emerging results
in applied networking research
i'm pleased to announce that the the
workshop will be going ahead this year
uh co-located with itf 111 in july
the program committee chairs uh andrew
lutu and nick femster
and the the call for papers for this uh
should be out
uh later this week and the paper
submission deadline will be the 21st of
april
so if you have um any interesting
applied networking research please do
consider submitting it to the workshop
and if
if you don't have any any such work then
please do consider attending
and that's all i have so thank you very
much
alrighty i guess it's my turn now so
next slide
please
and next slide
thank you my term is done i am now going
to be
you know unless something happens and
somebody uh needs a sudden uh nomination
um i'll be looking forward to whoever
andrew manages to rope into becoming the
next nomcom chair for 2021
um but i just have to say you know it
was it really actually was a pretty easy
experience
and i just don't know what problem all
of y'all have in not just uh
volunteering in maths and reaching out
to andrew
um but anyway it was a good experience
uh the voting members were wonderful the
liaisons were wonderful
um the interviews using calendly to set
them up
turned out to be pretty easy the ietf
provided webex worked great
um the nominees were wonderful and
followed instructions
um so it was time consuming
but you know if anybody's uh thinking
about it you know
as i know andrew's looking for people um
i will be there to help the next nom-com
chair and so
i certainly hope we get a great new
nom-com chair
and uh i really do think it was a great
experience
now moving right along i was asked to
provide a bit of info
on some takeaways next slide please
um and uh
right so oh sorry first
yeah no this is the next slide um just
you know if you're wondering about what
i think the required skills were that
got me through this past year of nom-com
um this is the list uh
and you know i i know that the rfc
actually said that somebody needed to
have a good sense of process but trust
me there are
so many people helpful people on the
ietf email list who are just
perfectly willing to help you out with
process um that that really doesn't need
to be the strong suit
it certainly wasn't mine um okay so
next slide um these are some of the
takeaways uh and this was something that
actually
was probably for me the most stressful
part of the entire hong kong
process was the uh considerable
disconnect
between what the ietf community thought
it wanted from an
llc uh board member and
what the posted expectations
and desired expertise were and
also what the rfc uh defining the llc
said that was needed um so this is
you know something that the community
may want to think about
because there is the um
rfc 8711 does say that it should be
revisited about three years after
formation you'll need to consider giving
input
um and also i did communicate to the llc
that there was this disconnect
i think it reconnected okay so
i was saying that um you know i do think
that the llc
is working on uh
getting better communication i know
i've noticed a lot more from jay i've
noticed a lot more from jason i've
noticed people
you know are being invited to the open
part of the llc board meetings
and so if you feel that there's this
disconnect i strongly encourage people
to take advantage of these opportunities
that are being presented to all of us
in order to take your step
in being better connected
next slide
um just some others uh some people in
the community thought it might be useful
if they had some more information
on what people wanted to accomplish as
part of being
um a candidate for
a particular position um so just some
things to
consider you know if anybody wants to
create a new rfc or organizer
i don't know what process is not my
strong suit but
you know maybe consider the the
existence of a pro
public profile with a statement for
nominees and maybe their picture
right there um consider a town hall
discussion for ietf chair which of
course won't be happening for
this year um where maybe people can get
a better sense of the candidates because
um while you know to be
widely known within ietf probably means
you're only known to about half of the
people in ietf
and other people might have opinions on
what you'd like to accomplish but may
not
have opinions on who you are
because they don't know you um another
comment
uh and this came from some of the people
who
are not employed by big vendors uh
and are individual contractors and such
and need to get funding for support
um there was a sense that maybe if
there's anything we can do to shorten
the duration
of time between putting your name in the
hat and
getting the decision that would be
helpful again this
would be something you know process
people might
need to look at um
and then you know just another takeaway
and i gave this one at the last uh
session is you know you saw the
statistics from
alyssa as to who's participating
and in none of those charts did uh north
america get over 60 percent
from what i saw and it tended to be
trending around 50 percent
and yet 65 percent of the nominee pool
seem to be coming
from north america um so i think this
is something we can improve on and you
know i'm
uh really intrigued by the work that
keith and fernando are doing to try to
document
some of the additional ways to improve
diversity
that they're putting a draft in gen
dispatch
and things like that so i do hope that
this
is a conversation that continues on how
to um make leadership
look more like participants
moving right along to the next slide
uh okay nominees did like the flexible
interview schedule
um you know i had times pretty much all
across the day there was a six hour time
slot
during the a lot of people's middle of
the night
um that we didn't have any but in
general it seemed to work really well
um that there was an interesting
concept that incumbency nomcom feedback
is the only way
they can get feedback on how they're
doing their job
so you know it may be useful if we
considered other
mechanisms for providing
current leadership with feedback
um it shouldn't be too hard to do
i think uh it should probably you know
feedback
should be separated from mom com nom-com
really
is not the best way for feedback to
happen
um there was a request to coordinate
candidate announcements with
uh press release and public relations
um and so maybe you know bring
in somebody like greg wood uh
before the announcement goes out so that
he could have things ready
from a pr perspective um
before the announcements that get get
shipped and i'll certainly work with the
next uh
numcom chair on that if maybe if that's
okay with
you know maybe we need a discussion on
the process of whether that's acceptable
um and then you know one thing i'd like
to
get help from that would be really good
from a tools perspective is we've got to
get rid of the 77 column pre-wrapped
ascii
for providing um questionnaire responses
and it would be really nice if we had a
web form
and you know a major takeaway is yes
numcom
can be done remotely i think it clearly
it can be done 100 remotely and i also
think
that it can be done remotely by just a
portion of the members and nominees
and so there should not be any
expectation or requirement
that uh you know going forward even
that non-pom members or nominees have to
be
present for interviews for meetings for
any of that
they we need to be able to support all
of this remotely going forward even once
we get to meet in person again
okay i think uh
let's see next slide and i do have some
things
that i needed to mention that i didn't
put on a slide
um so i forgot to put a slide together
about the community feedback questions
so i'm just going to run through those
really quick
um there was a question about iesg
expectations of proposed standard
um so they were unhappy people
and they were satisfied people and there
was no consensus on this
and it to me and it seemed that the
unhappiness was
mostly impacted by personal experience
with specific drafts
rather than general trends really
because we don't
have statistics on general trends
um iesg as servants of the community
um motherhood and apple pie
absolutely it was agreed that this was
generally how it should be
but there was some pushback that one job
of the steering committee is to steer
um with that said there were
views from some people that they
actually think
the various i groups are doing a good
job with this
and there are some people who felt there
did not and so i could not say that
there was any consensus
as to the current state of affairs as to
whether people are living up to the
expectation of iesg
and others as servants of the community
um and again
the view seemed impacted by specific
personal experiences
and how people perceive things you know
glasses half full or empty or things
like that
um engaging with external impacted
stakeholders
uh in general there does seem to be a
belief
that the ietf cannot exist in a vacuum
and needs to engage with open source
community opera
community with operators with other sdos
and with um others in order to remain
relevant and to avoid having
our efforts driven to other
organizations this opinion was not
universal some perceived ietf to be in a
position
of strength where it could dictate how
things happen in the world but i would
say that the consensus view was one of
engagement and humility
um recycling leadership and returning
incumbents
and this was not a direct question to
the community
but it did get discussed post
announcement
of the candidates and it was certainly
considered in a lot of the feedback on
specific candidates or specific nominees
um in i would have to say there is
strong consensus that people who have a
single term under their belt and are
doing a good job should be given a
second term
um there is a learning curve and so
there is
not a strong push
in any way shape or form to simply have
new leadership with
every cycle um now with that
said i did notice a strong trend that
once
uh former leaders are out of leadership
for
multiple years um maybe four or five
certainly more than five years there
seems to be a significant number of
people who prefer not to put them back
in
not as a.d um iab was a little less
clear but even
there there was a strong um you know
this person's already been there
done that um we'd like to see new people
um and that doesn't mean that people who
have been leadership in the past
shouldn't try but i can say that there
was
a fairly strong feedback
of that ilk um
there is a strong sense that iab seems
to be a place where ads go to retire
um but even there you know there's a
difference between
if you're a recent ad or current a d
who's stepping out of an a d position um
there's a lot of uh support for those
people
and so there wasn't a push to not do
that in the iab
but you know again the the recent people
there the feedback that i saw was
different from what i saw
for feedback who of people who had been
80s a lot
while previously and um
that simply is what it is and
i can't speak to necessarily why that is
um but i did see a lot of that and so
you know i hope the next mom com chair
has as good
luck as i did and uh
you all have fun it's not my job anymore
bye
hi uh i'm greg wood um
and i'll be presenting for jay today
uh next slide please
yeah i'm greg wood director of
communications and operations for the
itf administration llc
i'm standing in today for jay who is uh
the executive director of
the itf executive director and is uh
unable to be here
um it's great to see so many of you here
and it's been great to see people in
gathering in sessions over the last
three days next slide please
um as this meeting has been going on and
in past meetings that uh as ellis noted
they depend really on uh the sponsors
and hosts of the meeting so we're
very thankful to google uh for hosting
itf-110
and um especially that they have
continued to recognize
that there's value to meeting uh as the
meetings have
uh moved online so uh
meetings rely crucially on a supportive
host so thank you
very much again to google for hosting
itf 110
next slide please
you may have seen the announcement that
we've restructured the itf
sponsorship program and the aim of that
is to align the opportunities and
benefits of sponsoring the ietf so that
they're
more appealing to current and potential
sponsors they're easier to administer
and
they provide greater certainty for both
the itf and
sponsor organizations so um more more
details available on the idea of website
and jay also had a recent blog post that
talks about this so um
i first want to say uh thank you to the
amazing
equipment and services sponsors cisco
juniper
and webex they make super important
contributions that make this meeting and
uh other events and on the ongoing
operations of the ietf
possible so thank you to our equipment
and services sponsors
next slide please
thanks to comcast and icann for being
among the first sponsors to be
recognized under several new categories
of the sponsorship program with the
diversity inclusivity
sponsor comcast and icann and the
running code sponsorships of
things like the hackathon so thank you
to ikan for that
next slide please
beyond sponsors uh ietf meetings and
work generally
just uh would not be possible without uh
thousands of hours
really contributed by dozens of
volunteers and
uh you see these listed here the
individuals listed here
so i want to thank them the code sprint
adjacent to this meeting took place a
couple weeks ago and the participants
there as usual
helped improve the tools that we all use
to work online with each other
the network operations center has been
working for weeks
to ensure that the services and
infrastructure that this meeting
depends on and other events like the
hackathon have worked smoothly
a sincere thanks again to the volunteers
and thanks also to their
employer employers and and organizations
for making it possible for these
volunteers to get dedicate their time to
this work
thank you next slide please
uh beyond volunteers and uh there's an
extremely
hard-working broader team that are
really committed to making itf meetings
work
and uh that's whether they're in person
or online and really no matter
the circumstances a quick side note
uh as i was i just noticed a few days
ago that the first
message to the many couches emailed us
that alyssa mentioned earlier
actually happened about five years ago
around this time and the first message
is
included questions about whether or not
it would be possible to hold
meetings with people on the order on the
order of a thousand people
all everybody from home uh would that
even be possible and what are the issues
that we'd run into
so um i think that we've encountered a
lot of those issues
uh and some others uh as we've gotten
ready
for this uh and made this meeting and
previous meetings happen so
um uh this team along with
uh other members of the iit community
have found a way to make these meetings
work so thank you to
uh them slide please i know many of us
are already looking ahead
even if we're in the middle of itf 110
we're looking ahead to iatf 111 and
we're grateful to juniper networks for
hosting that that upcoming meeting um
and as noted
uh on the admin discuss email list uh
there's
a consultation and evaluation about the
location and other
aspects of that meeting uh and the
process around that
and feedback is requested by april 2nd
so i encourage you to
take a look at that and provide your
feedback if you have thoughts
next slide please
and juniper uh of course is an itf
global host who
along with cisco and comcast ericsson
and huawei
nbc universal and nokia
they reflect the highest level of
commitment among all t all
all ietf sponsors so um as global hosts
it's really uh the sustaining
partnerships that ensure the continuity
of ietf meetings so
thank you to all of our global hosts
next slide please this is just a quick
rundown
of the uh upcoming ietf meeting
schedule and plans um if you or your
organization are interested in
sponsoring an iq
upcoming itf meeting i encourage you to
contact the
sponsorship team at the email address
you see there
next slide please
and here's a very high level recap of um
participation numbers from this meeting
um
the important point i think from the itf
lc point of view is that
you can see that we've exceeded the
plans or the expectations
for and and the budget for uh
participants at this meeting so
we're in good shape there
next slide please
and finally uh here's a reminder of what
jay and i look like when we are
well lit and photographed and um
also just a reminder that we are
currently in the process of engaging a
full-time fundraiser who will be
focused largely on the opportunity
presented by the
itf endowment uh we also just posted a
position for the
senior software development engineer and
we're actively seeking candidates for
that so
feel free to point candidates you think
might be
good fits uh in our direction and um
there are details posted online but you
can also just drop me an email
and we'll get them headed in the right
direction and with that
i want to say thank you and i look
forward to seeing many of you
in meeting sessions and on gather over
the
coming days and i'll pass it off to
jason living good
thanks great thank you very much greg i
appreciate it
um my name is jason livinggood and i'll
be giving the
llc board update if you can please go to
the next slide
so this is our current list of board
members
you'll notice of course that lars is the
new person
on the board as a result of his new
position
so we're welcoming him to the board he's
joined our
official lists as of today and we've
been working the past few weeks to
onboard him and prepare him for
everything
related to the board uh next slide
of course we very very very much wish to
thank our
outgoing board member alyssa cooper of
course she was not only the
itf chair but she also served on the lc
board for
several years since its creation of
course and i think it's important to go
back and look at the entire
sort of life cycle of the process um for
iasa 2 if you will
all right hopefully i'm back at the
beginning of the iasa 2 process
alyssa was really part of helping
organize the ietf helping create a
working group
and try to achieve some consensus in the
organization of the itf
about where we needed to go and then was
able to get the lc
formed and cooperation and partnership
with isoc
and then able to serve on the
initial interim board and then of course
the first
full board so she's been a part of this
effort for many many years predating all
of us on the board
and we really appreciate her
contributions not just to the board but
to the itf
more broadly i would also say i'm sure
she's very eager to have some extra
personal time
to devote to other activities and
we are going to be sharing usually we
would do this at the stage but we will
be sharing
uh some gifts with her to help you know
her and her family enjoy some
much deserved time off and a little bit
of break and more family time
so thank you melissa really appreciate
your your contributions
next slide please
all right so upcoming board meetings um
we do have a board meeting
uh later this week on the 11th which i
think
is actually tomorrow um so you're you're
welcome to that
um you can find the links at the bottom
that get you the webex information
as well as the agenda i'll also note
that at this meeting
tomorrow we are finalizing the agenda
for our strategic retreat
which will take place the 24th and 25th
of march
that will also be largely open i think
there's only one small section that is
not open
so we'll be posting after the board
meeting the agenda for that retreat
and uh webex links and so on so you're
welcome to join us for that as well
and we've got comment periods of course
throughout to get feedback
so thank you next slide
so um some current work we obviously
concluded the
community survey um that was one of the
recommendations that came out of the
nom-com and we implemented that in
december
and i think had feedback open on the
survey through january to allow people
to comment through the holidays
and we circulated results posted a blog
about that
i think the only comment i would have
there is it would be great to have more
respondents
next year when we do it um number two
we're
finishing up a uh sort of the
preparation of the fiscal year
financials and completion of an
independent
audit as we did last year i already
noted the strategic retreat
i will just make a quick note of the
items that we
so far in our draft agenda are focusing
on one is community engagement
two is how to kick off the iasa ii
retrospective three is fundraising
four is improving diversity and
inclusion
five is what does postcovid return to
normal look like
for the organization and what
implications would that have
administratively technically and
financially
and then finally reviewing any
additional
strategic administrative or technical
debt that we need to have the
organization focus on
um so that brings us to item 4 here as i
mentioned fundraising
we're very close to having that
fundraiser on board
jay's working on that diligently the
iosa 2 retrospective
i mentioned that in our retreat that's
where we'll be really digging into that
for the first time
this was required it was put into the
the rfcs and bcps
when we kicked off the iasa 2 or
approved the iso2 structure
that we would conduct a retrospective to
see if there were any gaps
in the iasa 2 structure if there are any
things that we would like to tweak
i think the idea was instead of doing
this once every 10 plus years
to do it on a somewhat more agile basis
though i think three years still a
little bit waterfall but in any case
come back and see if there are
minor course corrections that we want to
do organizationally
and of course if there are and
identifying what those are going to
require a lot of community consultation
and sorting out how we're going to want
to work that is something we're
going to work on soon and i mentioned of
course i'm boarding our new board member
next slide please
uh so these are the the latest um
financials
based on december balances um
the only two notes here is the some of
the net income differences
um and we'll have more information about
this one the
financials are are shared this is
largely due to when we are
recognizing the revenue from the
internet society
and so we had a certain amount of
revenue that um
was forecast for this year based on
prior process
however based on the new deal with the
internet society
those funds are actually coming in the
first quarter of this fiscal year
um and there'll be more phones of course
so that will explain some of those
differences we'll explain them in the
notes
when the fiscal year is closed um and
then on investments
you know the only thing i will note here
is don't expect returns like that
in any other year um we really um
lucked out in a way i mean it was really
the result of good planning
but some of it was luck in essence when
we got
our investment funds from the internet
society
they were all kept in cash until such
time as we
completed the investment policy and once
we did
have the policy that said how we would
invest and what our diversification
would be
then we had to decide over what time
period to invest
and because of the the covid 19 pandemic
beginning
last year the stock market in the late
first quarter really took a nosedive
and so as a result of that we felt that
represented
an unprecedented opportunity to buy into
the market
and so working with goldman sachs our
investment advisor we decided to pull in
some of our planned investment timing
and were able to benefit from the uplift
in the stock markets
globally since that time so great
benefit now
but don't expect returns like that in
the future especially given our
conservative investment profile
um next slide please
so these are all the ways you can get in
contact with us
next slide
and that's it for now thank you very
much for your time
hello there i'm glenn dean and i'm going
to give the presentation uh update uh
on the ietf trust activities next slide
please
next slide please uh so the ihf trust is
made up of five members
uh i'm the chair uh kathleen moriarty is
our treasurer
uh the other trustees are joel halpern
john levine and stephen wenger
joel uh was just re-uh re-upped for
another three-year term by the nom-com
and so we welcome joel
to back and continue on his service as a
trustee next slide please
so a lot of people uh don't really hear
much about the itf trust and we're
probably the most
misunderstood part of the itf uh simply
put the purpose of the itf trust and the
reason it was created
was to manage the ip assets for the ietf
with the goal of making them easy to use
and available to use but while
protecting the ownership
of those assets so that the ietf retains
control
and and is able to do with its assets
what it wants to do
uh with one uh ex we focus on the if
one extension was done in 2016 uh as
part of the nti ayana transition
uh there's some material from the iana
that also came into the trust care
such as iana.org uh the domain
registration and things like that
and so we serve both the itf and the
broader community
uh so if you ever wonder who owns the
domains like itf.org and all the other
kind of stuff
and who takes care of the registrations
well that's one of the things we do
we also manage the copyrights logos
photos things like that
uh trademarks as well as software so
when tools and rfc tools and things like
the yang catalog are published
we worry about the licenses there and
make sure that everything's kept in
order
one thing we don't do by the way is we
don't do patents so we do ip but not
patents
next slide please
so uh the trust is a fairly quiet uh
group compared to
certainly groups like the llc uh the iab
and the isg
and working groups uh because hopefully
not a lot of legal stuff needs to be
done uh
but there's a few things we do need to
keep up to date one of them was the itf
trust website
i don't think it had been updated since
the itf trust was originally created
many many years ago so we undertook in
we restructuring the website updating it
refreshing it
uh so that no longer looked like
something out of the mid 1990s
we brought it up to date with you know
early 2000s at least
styling one of the big reasons we did
this by the way was
we wanted to create an easier way for
the community to engage where they
needed to engage with the trust
which is primarily around licensing you
know we get requests for licensing rcs
how do you do that we get requests for
licensing using our logos
stuff like that uh this is meant to
be a front door and help people
understand what that process is
how to engage with it and how to work
with it the other thing we've done
recently in
late 2020 we did a consultation with the
itf community
around some clarification of the iana
parameter registry usages uh
they uh themselves as stated if you look
at them they don't bear a copyright
uh statement uh we had to take a look at
that and decide what was the
appropriate thing we did a consultation
with the community
feedback our goal of course is to make
these things easy to use with
minimal uh process and so
uh in keeping with that we've heard from
the community and now we're working with
ayanna
and i can legal to get the actual
implementation the right way to
label that material on the iana registry
parameter registry site
and make sure that we get the stuff that
we want included in
the open access and make sure the things
which we don't have the rights to or
need to be
uh bran you know bracketed off and
protected uh because maybe the itf
doesn't have uh
rights over them to say what the rules
should be uh are correctly implemented
so we're working with ayanna
expect something uh to be coming
announced up hopefully
in q1 or early q2 i guess we're getting
pretty close to q2
uh 2021 on that next slide please
so we have some other stuff we've been
working on uh we of course
daily or you know as they come up will
handle license requests for trust assets
that's just part of our normal
day-to-day business
one of the things we however have been
taking a look at is we're looking at to
see
new situations that are coming up such
as around the github repositories
and what the appropriate way to label
things and make sure things are
protected
in addition we had requests suddenly
coming in for
things that are non-traditional uh
things
the itf would grant usage rights to
people outside the itf2 things like
wikis and stuff like that
this is above and beyond our traditional
rfc content that we already have
well-established processes for managing
or things like our trademarks we of
course ongoing we maintain
our registered trademarks that's uh we
do that around the world
uh they are not things you just do once
and you walk away from you have to
maintain them you have to
register them uh and make sure that they
are kept up to date and we also well
defend them
in case somebody infringes upon them you
have a requirement to defend the mark or
you can lose the right to use it
uh the other thing is we're working on a
couple of things right now uh
we've been re-looking at the early rfc
author assignments uh
that were done if you know some of the
history of the itf
the trust came into existence fairly
late into in the itf's long existence
and so the early rfc assignments uh were
handled a little bit differently than
the
ones that are today and so we've been
reviewing that and we're going to go
back and make sure that everything
all the transfers all the assignments
are in order and that we have all the
paperwork
uh in hand and that those things are all
really well done and documented
uh likewise we're going through and
reviewing and updating the list of
assets held by the itf trust
uh the iff trust is volunteers and
there's been a lot turnover through the
years
uh and so one of these we're trying to
make sure we've done is that everything
and all the institutional knowledge
including the list of every asset we
have
is well documented and published on our
website
next slide please
finally if you need to get a hold of us
there's a really
uh spiffy new design website
trustee.itf.org
or you can email at trustees itf.org
thank you
good day so i'm here i'm magnus westland
i'm here to talk about applying and
evolving quick for every one of you
so next slide and i'm the outgoing
transport lady
so uh i had the pleasure to quite
recently approve
quick version zero one zero zero zero
zero one and
http three uh and this is
it's been almost five years since the
buff
and seen lots and lots of github issues
over 2000 there's been almost eight and
a half thousand emails on the working
group email list
they've been 23 different meetings of
the group
and some 2021 interoperability drafts of
different points of
quick during development with over 20
different implementations being involved
they also been quite a lot of slack
discussion between implementers
and the result here is really six high
quality documents which i'm very
grateful
and i really want to thank everyone
that's been involved in this process i
do note that when you take the github
process
beyond the working group stage beyond
what rc
describes we did run into some process
issues should say with an atf class
called an isd review
one for example about collecting
feedback in idf lost call
and the review teams that don't see that
request
it's just one example so there's a few
things here for isd and the
idf is large to work on i think
next slide
so http 3 usage
is already quite extensive on the in the
web
it will continue to grow and will evolve
i also expect to see much more https
usage
with http 3 for other applications than
the normal web
and use quick as a transport protocol
maybe for your protocol so that's
it's been started somewhere we have two
known views in idf it's dns over quick
and mask
there's some more different cases under
consideration
it's not been adopted yet so it's time
for you i think to really ask yourself
if it's time to start using quick for
you uh or not
so let's see what you need to think
about if you're going to do that
next slide
so application mappings or high upper
layer protocol or highla protocol
mappings
onto quick http 3 is just one such
example
you can do it in your own working group
you can do it in other seos or
your organizations or companies
i would recommend you to read the
applicability draft
it's not yet ready for publication but
it will soon
and if you have any questions don't
hesitate to consult the quick working
group it's shares or potentially
transport ids so what's
good to know here is that if you trying
to do this
realize just missing something quick and
you would need a quick extensions to
solve your issue
you that's one case where you really
should start
discussing with a quick working group
because if this is general
extension then maybe it should be done
in quick working group
as that general extensions if it's
something very very specific
it might be fine that you do it in your
own group and another thing if you start
experimenting or working with this
don't hesitate to register a provisional
code point by jana for any of the
registration
so and do that as soon as you're ready
to actually start
having that implementation quick has a
lot of extension space there's no
shortage of code points
most fields are 32-bit longs and the
registration rules are very
open so to say so don't hesitate to
register
at this stage we're also doing a quick
recharging the
it's out for external review currently
it's uh
continuing in the working european
maintenance evolution of the basis
specifications it's also continuing
on the operational been started but some
new things like
q log for example is being considered
and and enabled by this new charter and
also general extensions is is what the
group is charted for
so i hope now you have some more idea
where
quick is and that it's ready it
hopefully it will be published within
weeks
the first basic specs so there's nothing
that prevents you from using it from a
reference point
and i have the possibility if someone
has any clarification question or
anything around this
they willing you can step up to the
queue and
ask your question before i hand this
over
so see if that was clear enough uh thank
you let's
go on
yes uh thank you magnus and then it's
actually back to me at this point
and we go into the recognition part um
if we go on the next slide
we start with the iab um we have this
times
uh four outgoing ib members and
one of them is of course alyssa who has
as the ietf chair has also been a member
of the iab i have to say um i really
enjoyed working with her the last year
but also the years before where i was an
ihd member and so had like even closer
contact with her
i think she has like a very pragmatic
approach very often and there has been
some very difficult
decisions she had to take in the in the
last couple of years
um but she's usually very good and like
kind of listening to
the discussion but then also finding the
right point of time where
the discussion maybe just goes in
circles and she can make a
pragmatic proposal to move forward um
and that's kind of that's an uh a skill
which i admire
maybe that's my german gems um but i
think that was also
a skill that was very useful on the ib
and the discussions we had over the last
year
where she was always actively
contributing
bring him uh bring him our own views but
also views uh
in her position um so i think she will
be missed there and
and we'll see if last can replace her in
that sense but like as his german i have
some hope
um but i also want to thank all the
other
three ib members who are stepping down
this time
i'm stephen has been on the iab since
2019 but similar to edisa i have been
working with him on the isg before
i'm always fascinated because he seems
to really all draft
that come up in the ipf he's always on
top of things
he's always on top of things that happen
in the ietf
but also outside so he's he's been very
active
uh in in bringing topics and and
uh and current um things that happen in
the world to the iab
in order to figure out if the ib needs
to discuss it and needs to have a
position um
so um in order to replace that kind of
uh
service you provided i think we all on
the on the new ib have to work together
and replace them but you know stephen if
you if you want to push an email to the
iv from time to time make sure we're
aware of the right things that
still we still happily take that um but
also
besides that stephen has been very
active on the iab he has created and
shared the model t program
um he has been active on the last
workshop and we had last november
and he's usually one of the persons who
raises his hand if there's any kind of
admin test that need to move forward
the thanks a lot for that
and mark actually has been kind of
equally active i have to say mark has
been on the ib
since 2017. um he has been
very active in the iab but i think he's
also very active in in the in the ietf
as a whole
really tries to drive things forward
really tries to make the internet better
um and and also brought like in that
sense his fuse into the iab
and have been very active in the eye
being in different position he was a
member of arsoc
um he has been the w3c liaison for a
while and then
um switched over in the shepherd role
and he's also one of the persons who's
kind of active in every decisions and
and take up tasks if needed so um
thanks for that part and thanks for
engaging very actively
and then jeff jeff together with mark
and eliza
and yari actually has been one of the
has also been on the ib since 2017
so as like three of those four people
are stepping down
uh and and like jeff was also one of the
persons
who was like bringing in kind of this
knowledge
from the from like the last four years
and the experience
and he was always a good person to ask
um
if if you need to know about something
that has been a long-term activity on
the iab or has been discussed in
previous times
so that's definitely something where we
will miss him and and
i think yari has to now pick up the
remaining
responsibilities here and step in for
all of them
so um again thank you all three of you
um you might wonder now why there are
these glasses on the slide
and uh on the one hand this is a little
bit of reminder that like the last year
i think where
was quite challenging for all of us but
um
on the iab i think it was also
challenging especially for new iab
members
to get to know each other because we
usually have those retreats or we also
meet in person at other meetings
where we really get to know each other a
little bit better and it's it's
part the retreats give us enough time to
talk about technical stuff about topics
that needs discussion
but it has also really important role
where everybody sits together and just
gets to know
each other better and we work together
as a group and get to know each other
so that was definitely missed out we
tried to have some
social involvement but
i don't think that could replace it it
fully so what we will do here is that
all of you
will get shipped some nicely iab branded
glasses
and the respective um
liquid that fits into these glasses so
at least you can at home have a little
drink
uh remember your good times on the iab
uh and and cheer on on the iab time and
then hopefully we all can have together
a dream even so you might not be on the
ib at that point where you will not be
on here before
at that point of time anymore i think we
can hopefully all have a drink together
when we're back in person somewhere
so thanks a lot for all for for your
participation in the ib
great um so we also wanted to
recognize our outgoing ihg
members i'm going to recognize my my
co-ads here first
um so barry deborah and magnus
they share the distinction i think if i
have my
information correct of each having
served six years
on the iesg which is
uh a long time i can tell you from
experience
and they um were not all consecutive so
barry and and magnus each served prior
terms previously and then came back for
a third term um magnus going back to
2006 i think was when he
um started his first term and barry um
in 2012
deborah served her six years um
consecutively
so a sort of different kind of glutton
for punishment there
but um just based on the the depth of
that experience
we will we will really be losing a lot
with these three
stepping off of the isg i think
for for barry um this time around
thinking about it barry and i were
co-id's previously in the art area and
thinking about the art area in the last
couple of years it's been a little bit
quieter than it was
um maybe in the heyday but there were a
few really significant milestones that
very helped
to shepherd peru the cap working group
uh has completed the capper architecture
and the catboard api
not the easiest set of documents to
to get through so that was pretty
significant
and then very recently barry also
shepherded
the process of taking rdap to internet
standard
as we all know there's not that many
protocols that have gone to internet
standard
um so that's definitely something to
to be celebrated debra has been
our stalwart traffic engineering guru on
the isg
for a long time um in addition to all of
that work she also had each of these ads
really had their share of
document suites that weren't the easiest
to get through the process
but they persevered and so for debra
what i remember very clearly was the
lisp
documents um she shepherded updates to
a suite of lisp documents
in the last year or two and again that
was
that was a long process with lots of
great feedback in particular from our
friends in the security area
um that that really made the the output
much much better
um and she's been uh uh overseeing
all of the the deterministic networking
uh work the detonate
uh working group which has uh recently
gotten a bunch of their documents
approved and out the door
uh really a major innovation um for uh
performance guarantees in single
networks so
that's that's very exciting set of
developments and then
magnus um he already talked about quick
uh i just have to say like
you know there's there's an infinite
number of jokes about when
when quick was going to be finished or
when quick v1 was going to be finished
um and it you know the we kept saying
it's going to it's going to be this year
it's going to be that year and he kept
getting pushed back
but magnus did manage an impressive feat
which was
to basically land right on time for his
own
isg cycle it's always painful when
big document suites kind of get left get
passed on from one ad to another when
they are
that far along in the process that they
are in isu review or they're entering
ihg review and then you have a new
person coming in
um so super big kudos to magnus for
pulling that off and actually getting
the v1 document suite
through the whole iesg process uh prior
to stepping down
there's there's a lot that goes into it
and a lot that's out of your control
as an ad so that's pretty impressive um
and then just
since you know highlighting a a more
difficult set for everyone
magnus also um oversaw
updates to nfs again
not the easiest one of those documents
is 560 pages long
and i think probably the longest
document that
has come through since i've been on the
ihg for many years
and and you can only imagine
if you weren't on the inside of that
process uh the
the trickiness of trying to get at this
document done at 560 pages
so again very impressive and
i know i will i will miss working with
all of you and your presence will be
missed on the ihg but
i know that everyone will continue to
see you
in the community and contributing in
different ways and so
really thank you for your service i
cannot speak to
the censored icons on the slide so i
will turn it over
to lars for that
all right thanks so much i hope you can
hear me um
yeah so so we snuck that on there uh to
surprise you a little bit um so what
this is
it's a gift to the outgoing 80s if you
can imagine and um
we unfortunately can't show them not
because they're censored but simply
because they aren't ready so we're
getting digital caricatures made
uh that you can use as your avatar or
you can like get them
we actually gonna send you a framed
version also um
so so the participants should look out
whether your data tracker picture
changes
uh soon um i think they're going to be
great the artist unfortunately was a
little overwhelmed and couldn't get them
done in time
so that's what that is in case you were
wondering uh next slide please
right so last i got on the incoming itf
chair i want to spend yet some more time
to praise alyssa so alyssa uh
became the ninth chair of the itf in
2017 as most of you probably
know she served for two terms she was
also our first female chair
and before that she started from the a
as an ad on the isg and
she served on the iab and then during
those four years and
and overlapping with some of her time on
those other bodies um she oversaw
quite a few really important changes to
the organization that had sort of
internal and external impact
so jason already talked about the whole
isr 2.0 process and the establishment of
the llc
um and lister had a you know fundamental
role here both
uh as a member of the um
iab and isg but also then as chair um
and she also sort of helped
significantly improve the the funding
structure working with eyesock to
align the funding stream from isoc to
the ietf and
stabilize that uh which is sort of
setting us up for a
hopefully much more comfortable future
um on a technical side
there's a lot of technical the important
work that happened uh with her at the
helm
a lot of the post snowden security and
privacy milestones that we worked on so
tls 1.3
the acme work dot and doh all happened
under chairman womanship um
magnus talked about some major
evolutions to their websites such as
quick there was also webrtc which is a
similarly sized uh
piece of work that was done while she
was chair um
and and the the struggle that's still
ongoing of how itf working groups use
github
started uh uh under her chairwomanship
and and then
uh got sort of formalized into the two
rfcs that we're now using to
um you know blueprinters work a little
bit better
externally um alyssa was extremely um
good there was a she played a key role
in a successful transition of the ayana
functions
she chaired the icg the iona stewardship
transition coordination group
um she dealt with a lot of geopolitical
consequences
of the trump administration there were
travel bans there were export
restrictions that
led to consequences for who could meet
and who couldn't meet anymore
in close doors that had a lot of
standards bodies
uh very worried for a while and then
finally covet happened right right at
the end of her second term and so
she helped the organization through that
entire experience which
surely wasn't easy and throughout her
service
in the various itf leadership roles
she's held and especially i think most
recently as chairs what i
most admired about alyssa was the
dedication that she
showed to the success of the itf and the
success of the overall
multi-stake holder model of the internet
governance
and and i think this is come through
time and time again
and i mentioned she separated the
organization through some really
significant
internal external transitions um and i
think that many of us will agree that
she's put us on a course i think that
will have a very positive momentum
for for years to come and and i will
certainly benefit from that i hope
um and what i personally admire most
about eliza is the clarity
with which she communicates especially
when she's in the spotlight
and under pressure and and she
continuously sought and found consensus
even when very difficult decisions
needed to be made
i think that is you know upholding the
core values of the organization
then i can only hope to measure up to
the example that she's been setting over
the last few years
and with that i want to pass it over to
alyssa in case she wants to say if he
works for us
um well thank you thank you for those
kind words um and and the praise it's um
it's it's truly humbling i
really just wanted to thank all of you
actually um
i think the internet is a marvelous
invention
and every day it still strikes me how
it's
changing the course of humanity
basically
and a lot of that comes down to all of
you
and the work that you've done uh the
collaborations that you've had here
in the ietf and the creations that
you've put out into the world
like it's totally breathtaking to try to
stand back and take it all in
so i am incredibly gratified to have had
a little tiny opportunity to participate
in that
and try to affect a little bit of change
here and there um but mostly i'm just
humbled and honored to have been a part
of this community
and um to you know have been able to
to play a role in the uh in the
evolution and
the history making of this thing that we
call the internet
um so thank you to everybody in the
whole community for that
um and to lars i wish you all the best
i have complete confidence in your
success and
if you ever need to let off steam which
i'm sure that you won't
because nothing about this job requires
the letting off of steam
um i think that you you know how to
reach me so
thank you and i'll turn it back to you
you and normally this would be the point
where we all sort of get out of the
chairs and give alissa
a well-deserved round of applause which
unfortunately coveted
is robbing her out of that experience um
so instead
um since we really can't do this in any
meaningful way i'd like to ask all of
you as you're sitting here in the
plenary typing away in the chat room
um to maybe take a minute or two and
sort of um send her an email
but and thank her for her for her
service and your words and maybe
remember an anecdote that you
shared with her or send her a photo that
you have and and you know
um tell her yourself how you feel about
her leadership in the last few years
thank you alyssa um before i continue i
sort of want to take a
minute or so to introduce myself to you
in case you haven't
come across me yet as the incoming itf
chair so my name is lawrence edgard i
work for netapp
um i'm german i live in finland for the
conspiracy theorists amongst you i live
in the same small town as yari arco
talk about coincidences i've been
participating in the itf
since year 2000 the 49th itf in san
diego was my first one which was the
biggest one
also i was a phd student at uscisi
at the time and was sent to the itf for
the first time to
present something related to ipsec um
there was a
research result out of isi and and what
i most
vividly remember about that entire
meeting was that stephen kent
did not like that presentation at all
um i kept attending anyway eventually
became working group share and transport
and then
ad of the transport area and and fun
fact
you can become an id even without ever
having published an rfc on the i-test
stream
so uh in case you're worried about that
if that's a qualification it's not
um more recently i shared the irtf for a
number of years and
following that i shared the quick
working group
and as i get up to speed in sort of this
new role um
i'd like to invite the participants sort
of to reach out to me
email me or ask for a zoom meeting and
uh let's chat about anything that's on
your mind this is what we would normally
do in the hallways or the bar
which we can't do uh at least this
meeting and
possibly the next one um i'll also be in
gather town
so if you see me there um before or
after sessions or in the breaks
reach out say hi and let's start
chatting and i want to thank you guys
for the trust that you've
placed in me next slide
which i think we can go to the next one
which is the passing of the dots uh so
so with this
uh funky eyes slide here um the the old
leds are off the hook
uh the new ids are on the hook
everything's transitioned over i know
cindy in the background has been busy
um operating at the data tracker so all
of us have like 20 million
inbox emails in their inbox informing us
what has happened with various working
groups and teams and so on
um and as we stare those dots
uh we're gonna open the microphone lines
uh for the isg part of the open open mic
next slide please
so this is the um incoming and outgoing
isg that are they're all still going to
be here at least for the open mic
part we have
uh gotten some questions uh by email
um i'm gonna read them
in no particular order and uh we're
gonna have some responses and then
you guys are also free uh to ask
questions um
over the meat echo of course uh but
let's start with those let's get started
with those two we've gotten by email
um and um uh since we didn't uh clarify
uh whether we're gonna um um have these
questions be anonymous or i'm not gonna
mention who sent them in if the person
who sent
the question then would like to identify
themselves in a chat or come to the
microphone
in response please do so but don't feel
obligated to
the first question says are you
satisfied you
isg satisfied there's a suitably robust
procedure to ensure a clear separation
of roles when a working group co-chair
is a co-author of an internet draft
just posting an email with a no hats
disclaimer sometimes seems a little weak
for instance when emails relate to
progressing the document
such as call for adoption consensus
decisions working with class call and so
on
rather than the documents contents these
potential conflict of interest
issues sometimes arise at working group
sessions too
i think if i remember correctly barrier
was going to speak to this uh
question barry go ahead yes
um hi i'm barry lieber and uh yes i i
think we are
satisfied in general the
um the general thing of uh
chairs having uh technical contributions
in their working groups and we expect
that
and for that i think giving a no-hat
statement
is is adequate when a chair is an author
on a document
that's why we have co-chairs that's why
we have responsible aeds
and there's always somebody to take over
the management of the document process
so that the author the chair who's an
author does not have to make the
decisions on consensus and any further
processing of the document
so i think we're pretty good on that we
have
uh in in the iesg we've had a number of
situations where an ad
is an author on a document and asks a
co-ad to
handle the the processing of that
document so in general
we have a good uh a good system for
handling this with all the
different people with their
responsibilities and their backups
on that i think that's all i wanted to
say about that
hope that answers the question i'm gonna
wait a few moments to see if there's a
follow-up
okay it doesn't seem to be the case then
i'm going to move to the next question
that we
emailed which says having asked the
questions a couple of sessions ago
i just wanted to ask given increasing
antitrust effort
enforcement efforts including recent
litigation are there any updates on the
efforts to enhance the transparency of
potential
configurants within the itf status
development or approval process
rather than asking an open mic it seemed
a question worth asking in advance for
possible reaction at the session or
elsewhere
some similar transparency concerns are
raised in draft going to diversity
analysis.00
and i think barry also volunteered to
take this one for us
yeah the uh the llc led this with uh
setting up a conflict of interest policy
for llc board members
and the iab has since also done a
conflict of interest policy
uh disclosure policy and the iasg has
been working on one for a while and is
just about finished
that you should see something public
about that very soon
um the disclosure policy specifies the
conditions under which we are supposed
to disclose conflicts
uh what sorts of conflicts we're talking
about and
i think that will increase transparency
on that for
a long time of course we've been
disclosing who our affiliations
are with and this goes a bit beyond that
and
expands on that so expect to see a
conflict of interest policy uh
officially from the iasg soon
thanks and i'm again going to wait a few
moments to see if there's a follow-up
from the participants
all right the third question we were
sent uh was about what the plan for itf
111 is and
i think jason talked about this a little
bit about pointing out that there's a
consultation going on
um but in any case this is mostly a
question for the llc and for jay which
is why we're punting it over to that
open mic
session and with that uh we come to the
end of the questions we got uh by email
um so if there's any questions from the
audience now please get in line and we
have
andrew in line already go ahead andrew
hi um good good day probably is the
best greeting um i i'll also post this
question in the chat in case it's hard
to follow
uh with uh audio um
yeah essentially um we see a lot more
groups
um moving work to github um
and they're using it in different ways
and often it strays
so beyond uh the original sort of stated
use of just
using it for some purely editorial
discussions
um and it seems in some places that
almost the entirety of the discussion
the meaningful discussion at least is on
github um
with just the conclusions being posted
back to the list
which i think i would argue does exclude
some potential contributors and
can have quite a bad impact on diversity
in the discussion and i wondered whether
the icg leadership had any comments on
this and whether
more guidance is needed on the
the appropriate use of github um thank
you
thanks yeah i i can speak to that since
the quick working group is maybe
the worst offender here in recent memory
and i'm one of the chairs
so um quick is really a very complex
protocol
and the short answer is that um i don't
think we could have done
quick if we hadn't used github in the
way we we've been using it
and we tried hard to not exclude anybody
for example
um we set up a second mailing list that
was uh
basically mirroring all the issue
discussion and pr discussion that
happened on github so every
comment on the web elicited an email to
that itf mailing list that people could
then be subscribed to and
follow along if they didn't feel they
wanted to
join github and it was also possible to
reply
by email and have that reflected back
into
the the github discussion effectively
i don't think we've seen that
been actually very much used i think i
remember the top of my head like
one or two participants that initially
used the email feedback but then very
quickly switched
to github i obviously have no data about
people who
never reply to the email
but i i simply think we could not have
done this without a
way to track issues that was allowing
discussion and allowed us also to refer
to
the the text in the specification as
part of the discussion in a way that
didn't involve copying and pasting text
um
so that's i think some of that is
reflected in in the rfcs that we have
that talk about how working groups
should use github um if if there's
anything else that can be clarified
there um i think we should do that since
i don't think the
use of github is going to decrease in
the itf and magnus already mentioned in
his section on quick that
um how we're gonna be you know extend
the github process into the isg and then
the rfc editor phase of the document
life cycle is an open question at the
moment and we
have one example where we did this with
quick but but we don't know if that's
the best way to do it
um i think barry wants to speak to that
too go ahead barry
yeah i guess i'm talking a lot here but
uh yeah i want to expand on one thing
that andrew
brought up was that if using git
excludes some people
um i i think over time the ia the ietf
has to
modernize its tools and move into
different tools and this is an example
of a situation like that where we are
moving to some hybrid of email and
github
um and and we're just anybody can get a
github account i think
so i don't i don't think we are actively
excluding anybody
we will have a situation where some
people are not comfortable with using
github
and that we've even seen that in the
iesg as the quick documents come forward
and the discussion between the iesg and
the authors started happening
in github and not all of us were
comfortable with that
i think the community is is going to
have to move toward becoming more
comfortable with that over time
as more and more work moves into github
and i don't think that's a bad thing
thanks barry
then go ahead
yes so i i just wanted to also add to
that you know we do have
people using github for issue discussion
but the text
ultimately makes its way into the draft
now we have lots of places that we can
discuss drafts
um and it's also
not the case that github is sort of
uniquely privileged in this regard
people can be discussing the content of
a draft
in the bar or in design teams or in
unicast email
and so yes it is a way to have
discussion that is not on the email list
but we have lots of those as well
and so this is this is change but it's
not
fundamental change and i think we have
enough
steps in the process where people can
see what is happening
and provide comments on it that it's not
a foundational change
so as barry says there's going to be
some level of evolution
and we can't stay fixed in our static
ways
thanks ben
i don't see any other responses from the
isg so um
let's move to the next question
i don't see anybody in the queue at the
moment andrew again go ahead
well it is i thought i'd give something
else a chance first
but uh well let's see if this uh also
provoked
promise of response but thank you for
your answers by the way um
i think there's a discussion that's
needed um
a slightly different attack but but i
guess also potentially
just hitting on uh diversity in in the
sense of
allowing people to be involved if they
wish there's an awful lot of work going
on in
interim meetings uh particularly since
coved for
obvious reasons um and there does seem
to be a risk of shutting out
so either people that are busy um or
miss
uh the the relevant mailing list post of
uh uh interims um happening um
or frankly just don't have the bandwidth
um
if some of the working groups are almost
having bi-weekly interims
which is quite a significant ask
of people and there is a risk i think
that that will really reduce
the diversity of views just to those
people whose sole focus
is on the itf um and will exclude those
that
have other jobs uh to do uh
so again does the uh sort of leadership
have
thoughts on maybe how to get more
representation
into interims um and or how to get
the the important discussions happening
um in the main
ietf meetings uh to ensure there's a
broader range of participation
thank you and again i'll post that on
the list in case that wasn't
entirely clear
andrew i think roman wants to respond to
that one go ahead woman
so great question i mean certainly the
cadence of meetings
uh can be challenging to include folks
but i i don't think we have
a new a new situation here in covit
pre-covatons i mean there was the
ability to have
the cadence in the meetings uh cadence
meetings at any any particular time as
long as it follows processes
i think that's really the thing we
needed to be very cognizant of during
cougar times
as everyone became very comfortable with
the the various kind of remote meetings
that we kept to the practices of
two weeks notice minutes as required
so folks can follow up as required i
will also say just anecdotally
where i've seen working groups have
frequent
frequent interim meetings we actually
see higher quality specs and we're
talking more about it
and we're getting documents pushed
pushed at a faster pace
um yeah go ahead
yeah i also i wanted i want to mention
because that's something we discussed in
the isg but also the problem um
we had any ib that of course dynamics a
little bit different when you meet only
online um
and you have to manage your time and so
i think it actually makes sense for
working group shares and all
participants too and to to
rethink about how they want to use their
meeting time i think it's actually very
um uh good to see that in the interim's
discussion is sometimes much more
focused on specific issues while
we use the planar meetings to have like
more cross-area participation and so on
i think we can do more in making sure
that on the one hand we can use meeting
her most efficiently and make progress
on our work
and why also have sync up times from
time to time where we keep other people
in the boat and work together
so i think this is this is something
where we um can learn from the current
situation
and we should reconsider and we should
have also previously
all been working on trying to improve
how we use our meeting time
and john wants to reply to john gomet
um yeah i at the risk of being glib
i will i will parody the question as um
uh you know can everybody please stop
working so hard it um
it disadvantages people who don't have
enough time to work that hard
um on that on the working groups uh
on the working groups work um which i
expect is not really
the intention um but
at least uh interims i've participated
in
i i want to agree with maria that they
um
or at least what i think she said which
is that they tend to have a more
focused and interactive agenda which i
think is a good thing not a bad thing
if we are having adoramas where we're
just reading slides at each other
um then that's that's a negative but if
we're having interims where
actual work to move working groups
forward is happening i
i see that only as a positive thanks
um let's go to the next person in line
which is philip if you look go ahead
yeah hi yeah
i just wanted to follow up that and say
i'm used to other
standards organizations where the
bi-weekly conference call
is the usual way of doing things so
i'm actually fully on board with this um
more frequent interims thing i suspect
that it's coming up
because of covered it's changed a way in
the which
people are working however there are a
couple of things that we
should maybe think around that in that
we should rethink the relationship of
interims
to the plenary meetings in that
you know i've not been involved in quick
and heb3 not because i didn't have
anything to say but because
you know there's hundreds of other
people trying to say
stuff and so i said what i had to say
and went away
and you know i think that that's one way
of interacting
and you know you don't need to be a
hundred percent
engaged in a particular working group
however
maybe what we need to do is to rethink
the way that we use plenaries
so that instead of thinking of the
plenary and the interim
just being the same thing and interim
being
more akin to uh an editor's meeting
in which the everybody who wants to
can participate and you work the issues
list
and the plenary meetings being more
outreach explaining yourself to the
wider community
explaining where you are where you're
trying to do and the consequences
of the design decisions made so the
wider group
can then say oh right yes you've decided
to do
this but that makes your protocol not
work for
green foots with souls and the other
thing
i'd say is that we really could do with
some sort of
tool that would aggregate information
on when all these meetings are taking
place
so that when i uh i'm planning out my
calendar i can look in one place and see
oh right the six uh interim
meetings in the next uh three weeks
uh these are the ones i'm really
interested in i will schedule that time
and i think that we could you know if we
thought of this as an
opportunity to rethink uh we can be more
productive
thank you phillip the one thing i want
to quickly point out that there is
actually
the data tracker has an ical um
subscription that it was
subscribed to that has all the upcoming
itf
interim meetings um so you can you can
at least see them in your calendar i
actually use that quite a bit
um and then somebody probably has
already put
the url in the in the chat if not maybe
somebody could do that so
that's quite helpful um thank you let's
go to the next person in the queue which
is abu salam
hello hi okay do you hear me
do you hear me
yes go ahead uh mike uh
actually it's a question and expectation
also
uh i'm expecting that from the directors
of the areas let's say we have five
areas uh
uh and the directors to direct the
working groups
so i worked with some working groups or
i had
attended meetings and there are some
documents or drafts
while they get to uh the last call or
the working group
last call i'm expecting the director to
okay to have let's say a meeting with
with the chairs and direct that document
it may be
uh interacting with other working groups
or
other areas with as out of the area of
the director
and the same time i'm expecting to be
feedback
getting a feedback that this have been
happened
but if i don't know what's happening
between the director and the chair
how can i interact with other
areas or working groups so i'm
in one working group this is my interest
and i'm expecting that there's some kind
of interaction
or some kind of information getting to
me
and also or a window or a channel i can
go to
it has this kind of drafts or
documents which is in the working group
last call
and it's interacting with other areas or
other working groups this way i will
make sure
i interact with these people or this
working group participants to make the
document
more efficient for the ietf
and it will be helpful also for the iesg
when we are participating and giving our
comments
in short time and also in a more
efficient way
i was expecting that but and i didn't
see that
much in iet if maybe uh there is
something i didn't know about but
anyway this is number one and i will
hope in the
next plenary meeting or the next meeting
that this kind of iesg gave us a report
which are the documents
that had went through some kind of
process which
went to make it more efficient and more
helpful
for our areas because usually internet
is
uh is a technology that
needs some kind of integration usually
now
technologies are more integrated so we
have to focus on the
the integration i remember that one
participant
uh i think jerry yeah he he was
interested in the cross cross working
group thing you know
so i think it was proposed before and
i don't know where this anyway this is
my
expect or my question you can say it's a
question or expecting
and i hope i get comments on that thank
you very much
thank you for your question i think eric
wants to answer you
indeed that's an interesting question of
course
and we should address this cross working
group or cross
arrears connection and reviews as early
as possible
and i must say a bit to my
um not so comfortable thing with it
does not always happen uh as the
interior
we see arriving document for instance
about dns or about
rpv6 that are lacking a lot of thing but
we see it only in the atf last call so
basically
the earlier this cross area crossed
working group
is addressed the better we do agree now
there is no real
process on this it relies on the working
group shares
and for the working group chess in the
participation here
i remind that you can ask for an early
review
in all the directorates right for them
the young doctors
the iot directorates or whatever because
you know the content
of the draft and so you can address it
to the different directorates and that
will be helping a lot
on the other end right so in the ing you
also have
informal telechart or from alternate
chat where we can say hey
this document is kind of linked to let's
say quick
or to ipv6 or to dns or to whatever
and then suggest to make another review
a working group last call or specific
last call review by specific working
groups and again
uh as i'm interested in ipv6 quite often
six man is involved in this
so yes it's relies on the human beings
so it's imperfect
but we it's really close to our heart as
the lg for sure
hope it helps thanks eric
um next person in the queue is elliott i
did go ahead
the wrong button there lars
first thanks for the opportunity to
speak i want to come back to the
discussion that andrew started about the
use of interims
so i'm chairing the rfc editor future
program
group which is an iab
program activity but we're running it as
a working group
this is a highly contentious
topic as people know but we've made i
think great strides
in the group um the the all the members
should be really proud
in terms of just how far the group has
come
uh in this regard um i don't think we
could have done that
without interims it took a long time for
us to level set
uh our our views it took a long time i
think for people to
to find ways to find common ground and
um having that quote face time
if you will uh had has really helped us
uh we did have to come to consensus i
think
on how often to meet uh i i wanted to
push for two weeks people thought that
was
a little too much for this topic and
they needed time to
to digest and to to consider and
of course there are other things going
on in the world especially this past
year
the one the two aspects rather that i'd
like to bring
bring forth though is that i think the
group was hampered a little bit
by the fact that we couldn't meet in
person uh
in that uh sometimes uh when you have
contentious issues it helps
uh to break up the with a beer in
between if you will or coffee if you'd
rather
um the the other point i was going to
make is
that the interim activities i think have
actually opened up
uh the um the the group
uh to people who might not have
otherwise participated
uh simply because uh they couldn't
travel
um in to the meetings that we might have
otherwise had we might have considered
having an interim
uh had we uh having the opportunity uh
so this
of course directly relates uh to the
discussion that's going on the gen
gen dispatch in terms of how is it that
we're inclusive
and i i don't claim that there is a
single
um recipe here but uh maybe other groups
work differently they don't need those
interims quite as much because you can
just do work in email because it's
you know very there's a nice synergy
everybody's pushing in the same
direction
but if you do have contention it really
does help to have people talk it out
thanks very much
thanks for the input elliot um next in
the queue is jim
jim go ahead
okay hi uh thanks uh i'd like to go back
to the topic of github for a minute
um so there's rfc 8874 and 88.75 which
are great
and tell working groups how to use
github and
thanks to the secretariat for reminding
the chairs of that recently
uh but there's also a github
organization that's just called ietf
and there's several repositories there
and
uh i have a couple concerns there one is
that it's
not clear what the status of those
documents are just the fact that the
repository that the organization is
called ietf
kind of makes it seem like they might
have some official status
more so than others and uh that needs to
be
made clear at least in the individual
repositories
i also don't see that the note well is
um
consistently uh displayed and so forth
there
and uh so i'd like to kind of ask that
uh we get some clarification on how
that's used what it's used for
and that we uh that we have all of those
usual processes in place to make sure
that
contributions are appropriate and that
the
the status of documents there uh
generally not representing iatf
consensus
is clear thanks
so i think one part of your question is
specifically about the github.com ietf
organization we're actually
recently sort of started in the
background um a little activity to
bring that use under a little bit more
rigor in terms of making sure that
repositories satisfy a certain
you know rough set of criteria like
they're like of
broad organizational applicability and
that they have descriptions
and they have websites and and you know
the notebook is displayed and so on
this is sort of an ongoing process that
i started and it takes a little
bit of time because some of those
repositories
need to migrate outside of the
organization
um but some of them belong to documents
into working groups that that
you know where that would be a little
bit disruptive so this is this is
ongoing
um the second part of your question i
think it's a little bit more about the
broader use of github and i think we
talked about this
uh already that um we we have the two
rfc's you mentioned that that
give us some guidance on what we should
be doing but i don't think they're the
end state i think they're sort of a good
start that um give us some some rules
that have
proven to work well but i think we will
need additional guidance
on how we're gonna use get up even
better in the future
right um tortoise is next and i'm going
to cut the
mic line after him since we have some
other open mics to get to
well let's go ahead yeah and uh not sure
if this is the right open mic but uh let
me quickly propose something
you know to uh to the organization and
maybe the
the isg would be the best one to drive
it in terms of
you know looking back and celebrating
the organization by uh you know
around itf 112 think about you know
setting up a one day workshop
uh to bring in you know the people we
may not have
any more in 10 years to basically give
presentations you know maybe 20 minutes
each uh
about you know the core technologies and
things that happened um you know
um in in the organization
and at that time and if it's not clear
what the opportunity is then look at the
publishing date of rfc 791 which to me
you know for the ietf would be the best
opportunity to celebrate something and
as i said right in
it's 40 years and in 10 years more we'll
we won't have a lot
of of the people who started it
that's a good suggestion and i i agree
that it's unclear whether it's an isg
um activity there's probably also an iap
angle to it
but um we'll we'll take that up
um keep in mind that idf 112 might also
be
the first one we've had in a while that
is going to be uh hopefully a physical
meeting again so there might be some
already some additional complexities
with organizing that so we'll see what
we can do
um i am i think i want to sort of
uh take the action item and we're going
to maybe start an email thread about
what
people would volunteer to help organize
and we can
take it from there yeah i think that
maybe if it's before ietf and would be
virtual i think there would be a lot of
people worldwide to
you know join in on on on a video um you
know live stream of that right so it's
certainly something that's for much
broader
community of interest than the ones who
made it happen like the itf itself
that's a fair point and we should
discuss uh maybe if you care to start an
email for example to the itf manager we
can discuss something
what format attacks is not quite clear
whether it for example would need to be
um you know in the itf week or whether
we
actually do a separate event at some
other time and have a smaller
like itf focused event during the
meeting week
for what we do yeah i think it's just
september right so it's
it's it's it would be a nice match right
thank you and uh with that i think the
isg open mic
is uh at its end let's move on to the
next one
[Music]
yes uh once more hello um so we didn't
um get any uh free questions to the open
mic
uh to be honest i also didn't ask
explicit fully for it but like um
as always you can always send emails to
iab iv.org
to me personally if you want to know
something but now we're here for the
open mic so
um please join the queue and ask
questions
we have andrew apologies i was
desperately hoping that somebody else
might
like go first but then i didn't want you
to decide there weren't any and move on
and miss the opportunity um
so i've got a question related to
when some new standards are proposed um
i i wonder whether um
now's the time to start assessing them
for their so
the potential to really uh exacerbate
the current trend uh towards century
centralization
uh rather like that there's already some
external input
uh on the security aspects
which doesn't mean to say that proposals
shouldn't go forward if there are
uh certain consequences on
centralization but at least
the trade-offs will be would have been
considered um and
uh documented um because in my view
the current driftward centralization is
highly unlikely to be in the long term
interests of end users
um so contrary to rfc
8890 um and therefore i think it really
shouldn't be made worse
um as more new standards uh are brought
on
and i wondered whether the iab
leadership had any views on this and
whether you think action
is indeed needed and now's a good time
to start
thank you
i'm just waiting a second to see yari is
joining the queue so yeah you can just
unmute him
yeah good question thank you and um
i think there's going to be different
differing opinions on this
in the iab and as well as the iit if i
personally do believe that that's a it's
a big issue and we should be concerned
about that
and uh i think some of the discussions
we've been having in some working groups
are
are actually about that to some extent
uh
of course that's not the only only issue
in front of us
um i should also mention that the iab
has promised to
write or return to the topic of
consolidation and centralization
and write the document maybe
people have requested that the token is
on me and i have failed to deliver so
far
but it's still on the task list so um
that is something that that we are
looking at
yeah definitely i just want to ask
because i wasn't sure andrew what we
proposing or having your mind or
whatever but um we definitely talk about
this from an architectural point of view
and we try to as always we try to
understand what the issues are provide
guidance to the community and hopefully
see an update and of yaris draft there
very soon and keep the discussion going
but then i'm not sure if you ask for
actually kind of process changes
i think if that should actually impact
process that's definitely also a
question for the
for the um isg and and see how this is
taking up and we have west there as well
thanks and and man yep here we go
thanks uh good question that's certainly
a topic that has been
hop very hot on my mind in fact on my
whiteboard behind me i have a list of
different ways
the internet is centralized because i've
been thinking about it for a while
um the one thing that i've learned a lot
in the last couple of years thinking
about it though
is that it's very much a trade-off it's
not just that centralization is all bad
i personally don't use many centralized
services because i think it's bad for me
but the other thing you have to
recognize is it actually enabled a lot
of
very strong usage of the internet that
wouldn't exist today without it
centralized file sharing services and
centralized easy to create
web management you know web pages and
things like that end up in very very
centralized
services which is which is greatly
benefited users
as well as in a recent academic paper i
co-authored
we actually measured ways where security
was suddenly fixed for a large quantity
of users because the centralized service
you know fixed some
pretty severe security bugs and it
actually or you know deployed dns
or didn't you know deployed https
everywhere on all of their sites all at
once so
uh it's a big trade-off issue um and
centralization is a huge risk to privacy
though so you have to balance all of
those so the
the the thinking is long and arduous so
thank you thanks mark
hello um yeah i'm i'm concerned about
centralization as well um i
i do get concerned that you know if we
have a bar for centralization or some
other measure like that
you know effectively we would never have
standardized the web because the web is
to be seen as just
a big engine for centralization to be
honest because of the dynamics of how it
it works
um i am interested in in more
concrete kind of measures uh especially
we
uh brian tram and i have a draft that
we've been living language for too long
about checkpoints in the internet
architecture and how we can
prevent their formation and i think
that's a concrete thing these community
can look at is
where does this centralize power so much
that it gives someone
inordinate power over uh people's
experience of the internet but but
having said that
i think we also need to recognize that
technical
limits on centralization are often not
going to be effective
and competition law ones may be and we
should be looking to
work with the folks who are looking into
that now uh
and then giving them good technical
advice where we can
um maybe i think tommy you want to
probably reply here as well so maybe i
take tommy first
yeah so just on this topic i'd also like
to chime in that
i think the centralization concerns that
people bring up
often times are
kind of pointing at certain protocols
that in and of themselves are not
fundamentally related to
being centralized or not i think andrew
i know we've had these discussions
around
the use of dns and encrypted dns and
dough and i think those are often
pointed at
fundamentally these pieces of technology
are not
necessary necessarily
centralized but it's the kind of the
market in the deployment models um
i think as far as what is it appropriate
for iab to do or the isg to do
i don't think we're going to be able to
say you know thou shall not have
centralization
and probably what is more useful is to
point out the areas
where we can
[Music]
provide mechanisms and technical
solutions to help
decentralize things to help make it
viable to have a non-centralized model
um and let's not focus on
you know demonizing any technologies
that happen to be
having to work well with centralized
models and decentralized models let's
focus on
what are the missing pieces that make it
hard to create
generic decentralized solutions um
so it's more of a call to action than a
call to stop working on things
very good point um so with that i think
we move on to
philip hi yeah i'd like to
address this and kind of recast it a
little bit
in that if you obsess about
don't just look at centralization look
about the driver
for centralization which is that the
user doesn't have
autonomy i cannot change my email
provider
because if i do my email account
address will change and the stuff will
be going to a different place
so of course you know i own my own
domain name
because that's the only way that i can
earn my account
but that cost me ten dollars a year
which is a significant fraction
of many people's annual incomes and
you know maintaining a domain name is a
significant
uh technical barrier for many people
a lot of the times when i see people
trying to design
systems that are decentralized they
obsess
about the decentralization piece and
eliminating any possibility of
centralization imposing enormous
cost on that design and extreme there
of course is blockchain current
currently consuming
as much electricity as the entire nation
of argentina
and so what i i'd urge people to look at
is
how do we give the user the ability
to own their own account so that
they can have a lifelong email address
that they can take to one provider to an
at
to another that follows them around
so that they can switch without
incurring a penalty and if you provide
that capability i can also switch my
social media account around so that
instead of being
forced into the same network that
everybody else is
i can go somewhere else so i'll be
making a proposal in that area in the
near future
it's it's not decentralized
but what i'm trying to do is to shrink
the border of the centralized piece to
the absolute bare minimum
and then create a infrastructure around
that that makes that public
goods uh in the way that we try to do
with icann and completely fail
thanks uh looking forward to that
proposal but that might be actually more
interesting for
um the ia the ietf as a whole and for
the ib but we also have the ib open
meeting
tomorrow where we can have more of these
technical discussions if needed
and then dominique
yeah i'm hoping we can pick this up a
bit more tomorrow in detail
i just wanted to say that this is
definitely it sounds like a call to
action and
and it's not about demonizing like one
technology or
the other but it's about list listing
the problem space right and all the
different issues that are coming up
um which i've started to do with um both
mark and
elliot and i have a draft on
consolidation that i can point
everyone to um but yeah let's definitely
continue to talk about it because i
think that there's quite a lot of
interest
so i am looking forward to tomorrow
thanks
thank you and yuri
yeah on the side philip and dominic if
you can put your hand down
and leave the queue that will be helpful
thanks
yeah thank you um there's a lot of wise
things said by many people
um i want to pick up on something that
tommy actually said i think that that
was the
essential piece that it's it's not
not that we need to sort of ban some
things but find
find the missing pieces and and work on
that
uh i think that's exactly right and this
is not about like extremes like a lot of
people bring these examples but we can't
have
you know the web or we can't have you
know or we shouldn't have the
uh the bitcoin architecture or you know
kind of like
um extreme ends of the spectrum
but but it really is about sort of
choice that you have like the situations
where
you know something works well you know
if you configure one ip address
somewhere
or one one name name somewhere that
doesn't have like discovery mechanisms
and tommy for instance has worked on
some
some discovery mechanisms before some
some protocol
cases so i think those are the kinds of
things that actually help us and
and uh dominique was of course also
right that
uh documenting the issues is a key and
understanding it's like
um sort of this pervasive surveillance
discussion that
we document the issues and then we try
and evaluate the situation when we
produce documents
um and then we have some understanding
it's not that we can totally prevent
some outcomes
but we can at least be a little bit more
aware so i think that's the
key yeah
gin
we can maybe now we can hear you
uh yes hello yeah
so for about a centralization i think
the internet is still distributed
architecture and decentralized internet
architecture is still decentralized
what about the centralization i think is
service international service is a
centralized internet application
centralized
for example we do use facebook for
social internal social service
and for uh gmail for our email service
so so because we are
a very uh service pro
internet application server service
providers
provide a very good service so we
a lot of users are attracted
to join the this
internet service service house
applications so it's providers so
uh so so yeah i think in the future
when our itf would provide
more good applications uh
protocols or some
so there will will be more
service in another service pro
providers so i maybe internet will
internet service will be decentralized
uh decentralized so my my point is
internet is still decentralized but the
internet service is centralized
my point thank you
and we have mark on the cube
um this is in response to gary a little
bit
and i'm really glad to hear that he's
going to pick up the pen
and do some writing but one of the
observations i have in listening to this
conversation
is that there are a lot of voices in the
room uh
and as yari noted uh sometimes some
conflicting voices
and i think um instead of trying to
find a middle ground i think it's time
to
let those voices speak and so perhaps
and this is a suggestion to the iab
perhaps this is a natural opportunity
for a workshop on the topic
so that the iep can hear uh in a
in a workshop setting from a variety of
voices on this topic
and and perhaps to do that before
committing the ib
to documenting a particular
architectural
stance i do think that the pervasive
surveillance example is a good one
right because it actually jumped the
chasm between the iab and the iesg
and resulted in real protocol design and
criteria for protocol design
and i think that that's what's needed
here is some architectural direction
that jumps that chasm again that leads
to criteria for good protocol design
that's what engineers want in this space
thanks
yeah everyone just to add and i think
that was already clear that this is like
a topic that the ib actually does
discuss
for a while already and and we also
discussed i believe the opportunity to
have a workshop but it's also very broad
topic with a lot of different thoughts
as you can see right now
um and and for workshop you have to
narrow it down to
to make it productive but i can
guarantee that we will keep discussing
that
and see what we can do beyond just
trying to work on the document that we
already have there
so at this point i don't see anybody
in the queue anymore
i cannot read up the whole chat now and
see if there's anything i need to reply
to
um but i think last year just here to
tell me that we're done with the ib open
mic or do we want to add something
no i would suggest we go to the llc
board open mic
definitely yes so thank everybody for
your input and your questions
thank you and we can now begin the llc
open mic session um one quick note i
forgot to mention during our slide
presentation there are
llc office hours this week they're on
the
agenda and looks like they are occurring
on thursday and friday of this week
i'll give it a moment i don't see anyone
in the queue just yet
so there was one question the isg punted
over to the llc board and that was on
what what the plan is for
itf 111 you you said that earlier jason
maybe repeat it now and we'll see if
that clarifies it
right uh well i will say a few things
one
it the sort of what is return to normal
if you will
um is one of the topics for the
strategic offsite
um and of course shmu is working on that
as well and i think they'll have to be
a lot of consultations of course the
for the next meeting the process has
kicked off
we agreed on a process for assessing
whether a meeting can proceed or not
um really right after the beginning of
the pandemic
so we're using the standard process for
that um
i think the operative question is
whether you know that
return to normal if you will whether
it's 111 112 or whatever
is a blended sort of thing where it's a
mix of online and in person and i think
you know we would all conclude the
answer that seems very likely yes
um but um exactly
you know what that will look like and
when we can return to normal really
mostly depends at this point on
vaccination
okay any other questions
all right uh hearing none i think we're
finished with this section
thank you thank you and if i'm not
mistaken this was the last
uh section on the agenda so if i tell
alexa next slide there shouldn't be any
correct
looks like it um thank you all enjoy the
rest of your day the rest of your night
and
see you around the idea for the next few
days
bye bye
you