so we'll give militia a minute to try
and start at his upgraded mac
and uh it's probably started about
two minutes past or so
okay so can you confirm this you can see
my screen
looks good yeah okay
yeah sorry about that
so we have a note taker timothy
will be uh taking notes would somebody
will be willing to help him
so christian has volunteered already and
uh robin is going to help with
javascribing so i think we're sorted
okay perfect
okay so in that case i propose we get
started
uh welcome everyone this is the lake
working group meeting
during the itf 110 my name is malicia
and my co-chair
is stephen farrell uh
so i will briefly go over uh
the agenda for today and before that uh
as a reminder this is an itf meeting and
the note well applies most notably
if you are aware of any patent uh
application to the patents that uh
during the discussions that we have
it is important that you disclose those
or not participate
in the discussion uh
so here is the proposed agenda for the
day
uh we will have a short report on the
hackathon and interrupt testing that
happened
uh an update on formal verification
of one implementation of echo spec
and then we will proceed with the
updates
on the ad hoc can be open issues
does anyone want to bash this agenda
i hear none so
we will be going through with this
agenda
uh and then uh before giving the floor
to the presenters i would just like to
bring up one
uh one point that was discussed with
uh with then our id and that relates to
the
uh administrative side of the working
group and
specifically the milestone on shipping
the uh ad hoc specification to the isg
so currently this milestone is set for
september 2020 which is passed
and this was initial this was an initial
uh estimation right at the time of the
chartering of the working group
so right now i would like to open the
discussion on
the uh best date uh
to have uh to agree on a date
that we we should aim for to ship
ad hoc uh there are
around 36 issues that are still open on
the github issue tracker
uh that is one data point and then
another data point is that we want
that we will be doing the formal
analysis work
so i would like to ask for feedback from
the authors
if maybe uh two itf meetings are enough
uh to uh uh to
resolve the issues and consider the
specification as
uh as in good shape and from
that moment which would be we should
count on i would say six months uh
for on formal analysis work to complete
before shipping the work to the isg
so uh you're on drone yes
so
okay
yes um
yeah this is i i don't know how to
predict this really
maybe someone else has better experience
and can do it but
um perhaps
perhaps we've fixed all the issues by by
the end of the summer and then um
i mean we so looking at the state of the
protocol it hasn't
it has hardly changed uh
during the last 12 months so it's been
really stable with some some really
minor
change in version four and
and now for for discussion today we are
proposing
a a change so which is also minor change
but still a change so
resolving the issues doesn't need to
change much of the protocol
processing and and message format
but uh but we are in we're still
changing things right now so we can't
say we are
are stable in that sense
i don't know anyone else has a better
estimate for
time
malicious suggestion sounded good
maybe a half a year to address the
issues and
half a year to uh for the
formal verification maybe so maybe set
the deadline
um for them i don't know
much meeting next year or something
ish yeah this is my initial proposal
yeah so yeah um i agree with your
and that the current issues will
probably be resolved
after summer i don't see any big changes
but
they keep popping up small
uh implementation things that are a bit
confusing or could have been a little
bit
better so in the like corner
cases and so on and i would not be
surprised if there
pops up more when during the interrupt
testing it's great
to have interrupt test and we need to
wait until
we have addressed all of this
okay so what i hear is that we can
proceed with resolving some issues in
parallel
essentially and keeping drop testing as
we were doing so far
so unless there are any objections then
i would
propose to ben to update the milestone
to
march 2021 as
a rough estimate of when we would ship
the uh the spec to irg
that would give us uh so essentially six
months
to resolve the issues in six months for
the
glorification work that we discussed uh
with kartik and his team
uh with parts of these two that could
probably overlap if there are some
editorial issues that do not impact
the formal analysis ben
so that would be mark 2022 right
oh yeah yeah sure
yeah that's very cool
i think there has been basically
no changes the last time that would
affect
celtics formal verification and i don't
see any future
changes that would affect that either
i'm not an expert in formal verification
but
um i think that could start or could
have started already in parallel
um yeah but then it changed the process
called john woods
would impact those right so i mean uh
ideally we would like to freeze the
protocol and
the format uh once
this work starts that's how i see it
i i don't think so i don't think the
kind of changes we have been doing
lately and we'll do in the here affect
any formal verification at all like
for former education doesn't typically
not
matter if you if you encode this like
this or if you encode it a little bit
like
this but yeah
yeah so i don't think i think on the
call so
but we can probably ask his input but uh
so do you propose then an earlier uh
deadline
for this john or you're happy with march
i think march is then we have a deadline
that we can
meet i don't know we could set the
earlier but that would probably be
optimistic and then we would have
we'd miss it anyway so yeah i think
march is
good okay uh
any other opinions on this
[Music]
uh i hear none so uh ben if this is fine
with you
then we should update the milestone date
for march 2022
all right sounds good all right
thanks so that would be all
on the uh chair slides i
i will give the floor now to our first
presenter
uh who marco yes mark is already
on the in the presenter's queue
hi marquez
okay uh thanks this is a short report of
the
slice disappeared oh there it is
thanks um this is a short report of the
tests we ran uh during the hackathon
last week and it's essentially the third
interrupt test overall um that we had
for dog
next slide please
right so we had test scatter throughout
the the whole week
and we considered in total uh three
implementations
uh mine for eclipse californium one from
libya isi and contikien g
and one from christian in io co-op
rebuilding uh mostly on the pya doc
implementation from timothy that we
tested in past occasions
and i think it was the first time that
we were testing especially
lydia's in christian's code
and overall considering also uh well
interested observers
uh we gather roughly 10 people around
this
and it was also the opportunity to build
a better framework to
uh to track uh which implementation
supports
uh what features and what tests um
were successful or were failing so you
can find
uh this kind of material together with
detailed notes
in that shared dry folder next slide
please
right so the the first pair of testers
were
me and lydia and notably lydia had a
constraint set up
uh including a soul constrained device
as part of an ipv6 mesh network using
rpl uh we consider server suite 2 and
authentication method
3 and we actually tested two different
credential types
uh kd and x5t and of course the female
keys were generated
differently at runtime um each time we
tested both directions and and both
combinations of roles and
it worked fine uh next slide please
yeah the other pair was uh chris and me
this time we consider surface with zero
and method zero with credential type x5t
and we followed pretty close essentially
the test vectors in appendix p1
of the draft using those same identity
keys and the same
no real uh certificate advice that you
have there
and again we generated the female keys
at runtime
and this also worked in both direction
and both combination of roles so
i actually don't have any failed test to
report
next slide please
yeah you learn a lot during this in fact
we were already able to to provide some
feedback out of this experience
to to document authors mostly related to
to the message format and how to handle
possible
uh error situations and we plan to run
some more spontaneous
interrupts in the coming weeks uh but
other than that we are trying to set up
um another actual fourth uh interop
event
uh about a month from now during that
week
uh we have a doodle for that uh so
please cast your vote if you are
interested to participate for actual
testing or
even just for uh observing
and that should be it from my side thank
you
okay thanks marco it's great to see uh
new implementers joining the
interrupt testing uh and especially as i
as i understand this was the constrained
implementation of
fba in quantity ng running in a mesh
network so
i mean seeing that uh think that code
run is really great
uh we also had uh have another
implementation that timothy lead
in open wsn and riot which
was tested uh with
the python implementation but to my
understanding this
timothy hasn't participated in the
interrupt uh
in the interrupt testing with the s
hawks the implementation so far
but he will give us a brief update uh
on this implementation and the formal
verification work that is going in
parallel
uh as the next presenter so in case
anyone else has a
question for marco i would give the
floor to timothy
yes
yes hi can you uh
can you hear me uh yes yes we
hear you so i think that was joran was
in the queue
uh jordan did you want to say something
or
i'm just curious about how many
independent implementations did i mean
this this
we look the all three interrupt tests
now how many independent implementation
has been involved
marco dio can you have you counted and
count five in total because the previous
events we posted also
stefans and team of these
implementations okay
thanks okay
um
[Music]
and malaysia already said that okay we
have a python implementation but we also
have a c implementation that's targeting
uh
can you go to the next slides please
yeah
just give me a second folding a little
bit slowly okay great
um so the c implementation of ad hoc is
targeting uh also constrained devices
and contains constraint settings
um so the goal is from this
implementation is to have
all authentication methods supported and
at least the first
four cypher suites um currently it's a
standalone
uh application that you can just build
and
run on linux but the final goal is to
integrate it
in uh riot and and open wsn and then
openwsn will be tested over
uh six dish so over constrained uh
wireless sensor networks
currently uh i've not like malicious had
not really participated with this
implementation
and uh the and the interrupts but i've
been testing it against
the python implementation which has been
uh participating in the end drops
uh all previous interrupts basically
um what is currently implemented is all
authentication methods
um and cypher suites zero and one
although i've only tested signature
paste and cypher suite zero
um and we started uh some initial
integration work
uh in riots with uh francisco
um so there's a pr ready but i think
we're still gonna wait a little bit
uh before we're gonna merge this into
riot
to make the implementation a bit more
robust and and integration open wsn is
also
uh upcoming this week or next week
um next slide please
so uh the work with uh the right people
is part of a bigger collaboration uh
it's a project called write fp where we
are trying to build a future proof
more hardened version of riot and
within this project we also work with
the prosecco team
at inria which is led by karthik and
as a work package within write fp we
want to formally verify
the ad hoc implementation so the goals
of this formal verification
is to have an implementation that is uh
that has memory safety that has
mitigations against
side channel stuff and in general which
is just
functionally correct uh with respect to
the to the
specification of ad-hoc
next slide um so we've had
two meetings so far with karthik the
first
meeting was uh basically a meeting where
we looked at
the ad hoc c code and we got some
remarks from kartik on how we should
structure the code
so it would be easier for us to
do the formal verification so basically
we have a user api
um that will be used by
applications using the ad hoc library
and then there are a bunch of internal
apis um
that can be formally verified
individually so we'll have a message
a processing api a formatting api a
crypto api
which can be mapped to a different
backends
so so far i've been using a wolf ssl as
a backhand
but there's also support for hackl
which is a project also led by prosecco
uh it provides a high assurance
cryptographic library
it's a library where all the
cryptographic protocols
are formally verified and there would
also be a credential api so each api
each api can be formally verified
separately
so what we'll have to do now is build
two
implementations so we'll have to build a
high level
uh obviously correct version
which will be written in hexback this is
a
sub-language or subset of rust and this
will be very short
only a couple hundred of lines of code
and then there will be a low-level
implementation
written in low star and this one will be
a direct translation of the ad hoc c
code combined
so we first need to compile the hex back
code
into a f star code and then combining
the f f-star code and the low
star code we can generate a formally
correct
c code basically and then each different
part of the formerly correct c code can
be
added to the addoxy library
so will be interesting uh once this work
is done to see the performance
of this code on constrained hardware
and see what the tradeoffs are
okay thank you timothy uh thank you
timothy
so uh as a reminder in the last interim
apart
from discussing the uh formal
verification
of the implementation we also had a tick
joining us
uh who discussed the science of his team
and
also doing uh the analysis of the
protocol
itself and that is the activity going on
in parallel
uh in the in the prosecco team where we
also expect inputs
useful for the working group
so do we have any questions for timothy
uh i hear none so uh i propose that
uh we might actually i have a quick
questions
um just on the uh the goals of verifying
the implementation
uh which do you have a pointer to
a description of uh some other instance
of doing this work
uh so they have their there's a paper i
think
uh at least one paper on the hackle
implementation
where they uh do the same uh
the same the same work so where the
heckle implementation also
i can maybe look it up also as memory
save
has some mitigations against side
channels and support
okay i see somebody's put a link in the
chat as well great thanks
okay thank you timothy so i believe the
next speaker
according to the agenda is iran
and uh so here we have consolidated
slides for
the next two agenda items which are the
changes
uh in ad hoc version
five and the open issues
so this will say i suppose the majority
of the meeting time
euron uh will you be presenting the
issues or
uh will or john is presenting the next
part
so i i will i will present the
slides but john wherever
oh okay okay because i had john leading
the the agenda item i thought he would
be presenting but
that's really minor so just let me know
when to change the slide
and that's what it's yours okay thanks
next slide
so yes as malicious said here the three
three parts of this
uh well there are three parts of this
presentation there's uh the changes
in last version uh and then the open
issues but there's a focus
uh on error messages which uh we hope to
resolve
uh this meeting and then there are some
like selected open issues next slide
version 5 is a minor update
and it's
i mean reflecting some of the comments
from the implementers and some some
minor
other changes um so there are
three main main comments that has
resulted in changes
in the in the specification uh
one is regarding the um
the optional subject name
in credits so so for cosy key which is a
map
we need to define a canonical credential
to be verified since that's not
necessarily passed
and in that format of the credits that's
dependent
uh on the
coordinates used and that that also
contains an optional subject name
uh which is the uh which is the
placeholder for an identity
that may be used withdraw public keys
so so that's that was uh that's missing
and that's included now
and there was also from that was from
michelle by the way the first comment
from
peter had a comment about transport on
certificate
and we now put in some text referencing
basically the code cx509
draft and finally marco had some
comments on
the os core secret and salt the length
of those were hardcoded and now we've
introduced
that configurable but with default
values
so those were the changes um that was
proposed and then we also made another
change
um which was basically the end now of a
sequence of name changes to this
key update function so now it's simply
called called ad hoc key update
and it takes us a parameter announce
and it's basically a straightforward
application of the extract
primitive with nonce and key so that's
very simple now we made some
clarifications to error messages
and where the second example is now a
little bit more elaborate than the just
uh simplest case to illustrate how
the cypher suite negotiation works
uh security considerations were updated
target security level was discussed in
an interim meeting there are more
details about that now
um key confirmation uh is also in
relation to message four
we'll come back to that in the issues
and some crypto algorithms that should
not
that must not be used with ad hoc is
included
and finally there were some updates to
the appendices
to appendix on test vectors which is now
actually a test vector for the
specification and
uh including what was in zero four
and now and also the updated text on
applicability statement
more of that later
so these were the changes unless there
are any
comments on this let's move on to the
issues
so the first one is an error message
next slide is thanks
this this we discussed in idf 109 and
basically the question is
we have we have a format for for the
error message what
diagnostic messages needs to be
standardized
and um yeah next slide please
so this is the work we've done since
it's 109 and i will show a sequence of
of
of things we've done try to find out
what what needs to be standardized
and uh sort of how we come back to
almost what we had
in the beginning but anyway let's let's
take the detour here around
how we how we worked on this we we
looked at other protocols
um and error messages so here are tls
error alerts and try to group them
into these seven different
classes and some non-applicable
next slide please
so that and that became sort of the
basis for candidate
error classes railhawk and
it's very um simple to describe it's
first one is related to psychosuite
negotiation second
about syntax and semantics third about
credentials
fourth about intake integrity
verification
fifth about extensions six about
uh authorization but uh
authorization and seven about internal
errors things not related to the
protocol
and then we map that to the protocol
execution
uh processing next slide please
so it's it's fairly simple to see how
the various steps map to
um to the error codes in red here for
the
receiving side and next slide as well
so so that seemed i mean that was sort
of from from the specification point of
view seemed to be
the right level of error codes um and
then we asked iot
ops which is this new working group
working on iot operations
what kind of error codes should we
standardize so next slide please
and they were very uh inspired and
provided
a lot of good input so
i think so you see here there's more
into the if you look through the thread
starting
with the link at the bottom but it's
basically a lot of input saying that yes
error codes you could encode them as
integer values use
a symbolic label reserve one status code
for success
to avoid complexity allow high level
codes with not too much detail
but those implementations that can
afford more complexity can have
detailed diagnostics can have sub codes
these codes could also be standardized
later on
um and then an obvious thing about
security that you
too much error reporting reveals
information for an adversary
and an error message there was a
comment about an error message related
to intermediate progress
was missing in this list of of different
errors um comment about creating a
registry
it seems like a straightforward way to
do to do the extension
and and uh several comments stating that
as few as possible
different messages and the difference in
the
in the error messages should reflect
actionable next steps
uh which is fairly obvious but uh a
little bit difficult to
to realize what what is actually
actually actionable next step and i come
to counter that later
but basically if there's no difference
then diagnosis should be the same
and uh best diagnostic would require
pronational
experience and there is currently no
operational experience about adhoc at
least
but other perhaps other related
protocols could be used and an
interesting
proposal for the type of error message
it could actually be
like the last bullet here saying uh only
my admin can help here's your ticket
though
so next slide please
so um apart from this comment about
intermediary
uh progress there were not many detailed
comments about these
particular error classes which we listed
so
we brought this to the implementers
during hackathon and we had
a couple of sessions discussing this and
as it turns out i mean the only
actionable
error message from the from the point of
view of the
implementation is actually number one
which we already have specified how to
handle
and the other messages they need some
involvement of an administrator
so so that that's sort of it's not
really clear that do we really need to
make these distinctions
from the point of view of the product
this this protocol
um for example number two might not even
be possible to
to send at all if you have a syntax
error you don't know who you
what the connection identifier is uh
number three
might on on the one hand side too in
specific because
uh you can't you could confuse it with
number four for example
uh but on the other hand if you really
want to to analyze this error you need
to be even more specific so
is this the right right level and number
five and six
relates to things that can only can be
determined by an application
and number seven while it could be good
to have a message like
uh an internal error it's my fault try
again
that type of error that could
alternatively be handled by transport
so it's not necessarily needed to have
an ad hoc error for that
so finally slide next slide please
so that leads us back to the beginning
what what should we specify what should
we mandate
uh who who should for whom should this
be actionable
and uh we don't want to add complexity
if it doesn't add
value diagnostic information should not
simplify an attack
um and may use transport error
messages and diagnostics instead and
certainly
you know i mean rely on that in certain
cases
so um that talks in favor of perhaps we
should group the non-actionable
errors into one class and allow
applications to define error message
content
and the proposal coming up of the
hackathon discussion is
what you can see on this slide so we
propose a minor change to
the error message
where we introduce an error code which
is an int
and an error message content
depending on the code
and we propose to make an iana register
but only mandate
initially at least two error codes
um one for an unspecified error
and one which could i could build let's
say number zero and with the diagnostic
message
and one for the selected cypher suite
not supported the error which we
described carefully
today um which also includes the sweet
the sweet supported by the responder
and potentially also define an
application dependent error
so that's where we are today and now i i
talked a lot
please comment what's your view is this
good enough
uh do you want something else
[Music]
so if i'm understanding correctly you
you would
essentially just go for the unspecified
class
and divide these error messages into
[Music]
negotiations error message
which is in terms of security in my
understanding
of and in terms of
the revealing the information to the
attacker the best
but in terms of diagnostics and
debugging
uh would leave many implement
many options to the uh implementers to
decide what they want
to implement this correct
yes i think that's that's correct
summary
[Music]
there's a comment by ben on the list
saying the proposal on the slide doesn't
seem to have the reserve and error code
for success
behavior suggested
yes so we could add a code for that as
well that's that's
correct thank you for reminding me uh so
that should be added
i i don't really see i mean then again i
don't really see
yeah we i thought that was a good good
comment but i didn't see the actionable
part of that so i think that was somehow
contradicting the actionable part
and what what there are
if it's success then you would use that
for
with a normal message i suppose go ahead
right
my understanding and this is of course
second or third hand but my
understanding was that
it's very uh useful to be able to have
like a single
data structure element in your
application
that would hold an error message if
there wasn't or would have would hold
their value if there was an error
and that you can put the success code in
if there's not an error and so you have
this sort of
unified data structure that
lets you know both if there was success
or an error
and if there was an error what the error
was and so it's not
intended to be sent over the wire but
it's
just to
have a value for local use that you know
is not going to be
sent out on wires so it's not going to
conflict
if that makes sense
yes well how would you use it then
if it's not sent
you would you would have it within your
implementation and maybe in some of your
log messages
or something like that yeah i mean that
certainly for logs that that that could
definitely make sense
so yeah we could we could specify but i
mean yeah
so maybe i'm stupid here but we're doing
protocol specifications and
this is not visible it doesn't come into
any any calculations as far as i can see
so yeah it's it's essentially just a
promise from us that we will never use
that value
instead of it is protocol visible
basically yeah okay
yeah that makes sense there's no no
issue to to define that
thanks
okay um yeah we've been struggling with
this as you as you hear
and uh i think that if
if you're okay with this let's let's
take this as a starting point
and when people can provide actions sort
of actionable
uh action things that actions that you
could do
when you get when you get some some
other error
then we add that error to the register
so i think it's flexible enough to
to change and we could we could add all
the i mean
in this allocation we could add the
others
the other five sorry other six probably
uh
errors that we have already worked upon
if
they are are needed um and if not well
then applications has to decide
how to use it so okay
unless there are for the comments we'll
move on to the next part
so yeah here are um yeah next slide
a few of the selected a few of the
issues we are working on
the there is a
dependence along among several of the
issues
and one thing that several depends on is
this notion of applicability statement
so i put this first here although that's
perhaps not the
most urgent um so as you
uh recall the applicability statement is
a list of parameters that needs to be
agreed between initiate and responder
for a particular use of ad hoc
and this this could be for example how
you detect
an ad hoc message uh what method
is being used what transport correlation
which optional message fields are
present or should be present
in in with this application what
type of of credits is being used what is
the type of
identifier of the credential is message
four used and so on
and it seems that um so this
seems to be a good start but we need to
make further clarifications
and to address the case for example that
one endpoint support
different applicability statements and
the reason why this is
needed um is because the ad hoc
engine depends on being able to
associate
a a protocol execution to this
applicability statement because there
are a number of decisions
for example for example the message
format and other things
the fields of the message depend on this
so you need to be able to
to make this association and
for example this could be determined by
the transport by the
resource the uri used uh
or something else so we don't want to
be to restrict on this to restrict it
but we want to give examples and see how
because this at the end of the day ad
hoc is used for a particular purpose
and adult needs to know what is this
purpose
so this is just an information point
that we will
[Music]
try to clarify this more and the
comments here are welcome
i don't have a particular question so
unless there are further comments
let's move on to the next
so here's one one case where this is
useful
so assuming that we have this uh
applicability statement in place
so the question has been around what
how do we distinguish received messages
and the proposal for changing message
one
and the reason is um
that currently we we're as you know try
to
minimize the number of bytes sent
so we don't have specific fields for
which is the type of message
and that that should be able to infer
from
the from the content of the message but
it's it's also dependent on the expected
processing
so what we think is missing is the high
level processing
so how you get from the applicability
statement
which in turn comes from how the message
is transported for example
and that gives you what optional message
fields are present
how you find the connection identifiers
and from that you get the security
context and
then the expected message fields in the
uh in in the received message
and when you process that then you can
you process that according to the
security context
so you know which message field you
expect and then you get either an error
or you get a success
so that type of processing we think is
that is missing and we think we need to
be clarified
better and so that should lead to
this to more simpler ways to
disambiguate to distinguish the
different messages
um just to be clear here there should be
no need
to a priori restrict the connection
identifiers to certain spaces
not even if the endpoint is initiated
and responded in multiple connections
and there should not not be any need to
parse the entire message
to retrieve the context and it should
work for for all messages including the
error message
so next slide no next slide piece
so this is the result of the discussion
so in addition to this
the clarification of that you need to
have the applicability statement
available to be able to distinguish
to understand what what is the message
format for example
we also propose to add one byte
to message one and this is
to to simplify we can disambiguate with
the
current messages but we wanted that to
be more simple
simplified and more robust and that
would be
uh adding a null byte seaborn null
this is only needed for message one
because all the other messages have
a connection identifier and by the
applicability statement you know whether
it's present or not
so that that would be the simple
distinction
and yeah so this is a result of a long
discussion i don't know if this
uh if there are any other comments on
this
otherwise we just add it and everyone
all the implementer seems to be happy
with this change anyway
any other comments
okay next slide please
uh here are a couple of slides on
message four
so as you remember message four was
introduced for
uh for key confirmation in the cases
where the responder
uh where the initiator does not receive
any message from the responder
and this is basically
a a mac over a transaction hash
a transcript transcript hash sorry
and that now there's been a request from
from one of the implementers to
support auxiliary data message for
so that's uh the reason for that is they
had some use case where
they wanted to provide a response for
data provided in
in message three and initiator is
commonly
implemented as in as a client so there
would be a response and that
uh yeah so basically that sounds like a
reasonable request
and it's straightforward to implement
because the mac
today is is implemented as a course
encrypt with empty
plain text so we would just add the
auxiliary data
and then we would have a encrypted
serial data does anyone have a problem
with this
no problem great next slide please
another comment related to message four
[Music]
so what we the actual text about key
confirmation or it is
like this it says that in deployments
where no protected application message
is sent from responder to the initiator
the responder must send message for
and then there has been a number of
questions about what if not
and in this case what if message four
not reaches the initiator
for example a lost co-op non-confirmable
and then the lower layers
may in uh initiate the resending
and how does the responder then act to
another message three
and we could um make it simple for
ourselves and say that well
we assume that the duplication will
handle this
and this will never happen or that
the lower layers will i mean the lower
layers will take care of it
but it turns out that um not all
co-op implementations support
deduplication because it's
it's a complication for constrained
implementations
and then there is it was a newly uh
proposal recently a proposal
and that's issued 85 on stating item
potency
so a solution to this would be
that we we state that ad hoc should
behave as an either important growth
resource so means that it would send the
same resource
in in response to an earlier message
and no and obviously we don't want to
have any
new security processing of an earlier
message but we could think of
situations where responses are cached or
uh in case of messages for actually
recreated
so christian do you want to say
something about this um
did i represent your proposal right
you're breaking up for me could you try
again
um i was just saying that if problems
um
hello can you hear me yes yes we heard
it well oh sorry yeah
something was wrong on my side i
uh i'm echoing says christian am i still
we here welcome so there was an issue
with uh christian while he was speaking
it was breaking up
so i asked him if he could write in the
chat uh
his comment
and there i see there's a comment from
from stephen as well
uh okay so christian is happy with my my
my statement i can ask if there are
questions um
and the question from stephen why would
a why would
ad in message 4 be conflicting
so my what i'm wondering is if there's
kind of application data or additional
data in message four
you don't know that that's not important
right
so that would be a requirement on the
application data
sorry auxiliary i i i'm not clear what
they the
bounds on the use of this additional
data for message for it might be
but it you know it could turn on a light
switch or something right
[Music]
i think yeah auxiliary data and i said
four is not
different than auxiliary data in the
other messages but
i think formulating this
the correct way is this i ident potency
is probably
will take a while and probably we need
christian here to
to help to formulate what
is actually required here i think
there's no we don't intend to change any
security aspects at all
but it's to make sure that
it's easy to implement on constrained
devices
yeah so i mean basically i i just have a
concern that
you know if you look at the web and http
get it supposedly is item potent but
reality is different
um so that's just a concern that if we
assume
item potency it might not be it might
not match reality well
yeah i
maybe in the end we will not use the
word item
potent but write something else i think
whatever we write should be correct
um but i think we are not
this was suggested by christian
last week or this week yeah last week so
i don't think anybody has thought about
the details
that much maybe christian
so on in chat christian is saying that
on application
side there might be the need for the
echo part to really cache
the auxiliary data path from the
application
so i mean i'm not
i don't know if that would be sufficient
because if
if the ad hoc implementation caches that
and if the auxiliary data means
change toggle the light switch then
resending that message could
affect the state of the world
so i'm not saying i i'm just raising the
issue i don't know what the right answer
is
but i think it might be an issue
good point stephen what do you think
about that
so i think this is better addressed by
placing strict bounds on what we can
have in the ad
than by requiring that everything be
handled on the lower layers because
the lower layers we have planned for
this
typically do not cannot do this
cannot perform the deduplication that
would be needed and would thus
let the protocol run out of sync
okay so so we need to definitely specify
this carefully and
make sure that it doesn't create these
type of effects
or else we need to yeah i mean that's
basically we have
something we need to to work on any any
other comments
what this let's not call it safe yes
that's agreed ben
um anyone wants to comment on that
uh comment from me you're on a there's a
lot of talk
application data but i think we have
said that
80 is not application data it's
auxiliary
data um yeah i mean we
we changed the name at some point and we
but it's it's clear that
auxiliary data is intended for as an
extension
for the protocol for certain security
protocols which
are running in parallel with with ad hoc
and we have one draft example of that
so that also relates to what what kind
of data that actually is
is passed in the auxiliary data yeah
i guess the point here is that we have
no control over what we carry in the
auxiliary data and that we cannot
uh guarantee either possibility on it
john did you want to say something no
yeah i kind of agree i think
even if you say this is auxiliary data
somebody might put something
else in it and even if we said this must
be important
somebody might do something else
so yeah it's a good it's a good
it's a good comment it might not be
sufficient we're just saying
what we what we intend to use it for
okay
great uh any other comments
yes hi
um yeah i mean stephen gave the example
earlier that this this might be an
instruction to a light switch say
which obviously is an end point with i
don't know in most cases binary state
yeah so in potency really makes um
some kind of sense there but i think
given that you don't know whether this
is going to be used
for that kind of binary toggle or for
other
kinds of application the key thing is
that the
behavior should be predictable
so i you know i think that's probably it
it's more important to specify
this is how this should behave rather
than try to second guess the
implementations
[Music]
yeah good point
so you're on how do you propose we
proceed with this issue
um yeah i think we have a small design
team in mind who could uh
tackle the question and try to get back
with the proposal
okay yeah so that sounds like a good
idea get back
on the github or on the mailing list i
think that would be ideal if we have
more
technical details on this yeah we should
probably take it to the to the list i
think
yeah yeah that sounds like a good idea
okay
so unless there are other comments as we
move on
yes let's go ahead
um okay so so that was basically
the um that was not strictly
the previous slide was not strictly
message four but it was not initiated by
the message for discussion
uh this is also related to message four
but this is instead on the initiate
sorry on the initiator side
so assuming now that that
[Music]
it's the applicability statement that
states that we should use message four
or that we should get key confirmation
in some some other way
and what what should the initiator do
when if not receiving key confirmation
and that's i mean this is basically to
the border line of transport the
transport issue but it's
it's we still need to have a have an
answer
and we cannot in general say for i mean
the questions in this issue
are things like for how long shall it
retransmit
uh when shall it clear the security
context and i think
we should need to be clear that in
general edo cannot answer those
questions
this needs to be application input
and we have so we need we need to make
this clear somehow and this is sort of
i think the result of these issues will
be some additional clarifications
it's just one thing to note that the key
confirmation
really coincides more or less with
reachability here that
if if the initiator can verify the
protected message it means that
the message has reached
the other end point and the right key
was used by the responder so
and vice versa so it's essentially uh
as long as the message has not arrived
the initiative cannot really tell
either and the current text is then
saying that
so it seems we lost the aura
can you hear me now yeah yeah okay
so yeah i just wanted people to reflect
on this is this
sufficiently clear
what we are stating initiator
can securely protect application data
the initiator should not store the
keying material that's basically what we
are recommending here that
that yes it might be that ad hoc has has
completed successfully
um but but the initiator has not
received
the final a key confirmation what and
the actions
is basically based on
on on what what is expected from the
application
so that's that's the proposal here i
don't know if anyone has it
any comments
or or marco do you have any comments on
this on how
how we can answer these issues
looks good overall and i think in the
end it boils down to the initiator
having as part of the
applicability statement on its side for
how long
it can leave it can still live without a
key confirmation received
yeah or if that is some something
something more application
uh i don't know if that is the part of
the application statement
but that's one way of solving it
okay okay thanks marco
for the input um i just wanted to check
if anyone has a better idea otherwise we
try to
clarify things um
in the way i proposed here so please
move on to the next slide
and now it's a couple of slides on on
test vectors
so there's been requested to have test
vectors in json
and that's already used by
by inria
and i was going to ask who will be
involved in making a template and then
timothy already sent some something
today i haven't looked at it
could you please tell me what you've
done timothy
uh yes can you hear me yes
okay great um yeah i've just uploaded
uh in a comment um what i've done so far
so
i've just put all the test vectors and
from the test factor file and adjacent
format where i have
three keys i have an initiator key
a shared key and a responder key and
basically all the
all the messages or all the
computational values that are being
computed by both sides
are structured under the shared key and
the json
map and the inputs that are really
specific to the initiator or the
responder
are under those uh keys in the
into json um the json map but it's
probably
clear if you just have a look at the at
the file i've shared
and the in the issue then we
want to explain great great thanks
thanks very much
so that's very welcome so what we'll do
can we do this i mean does this map a
particular
cypher cypher sweeto method or can we do
this in general for
for for all the test vectors
um i i think it can be done for all the
test factors i've been
using this type of template for for the
different dust vectors that are in the
test vector file so i don't really see
any issues with the
different types of authentication
methods or different types of
of um of cypher suites i guess the only
thing we need to be clear about is the
name
of different names of the keys in the
json map
so it's easy
for uh people to parse it but
otherwise i don't see any issue good
thanks very much for this so so then i
propose
that we actually start using um
those and and uh so what we have we have
had a problem
with actually creating uh
we'll come to that in the next slide to
spend more times on test vector so we
are we're happy if anyone else wants to
be involved and
and this is an excellent input here
so we should go in this direction and uh
and yes thank you very much for your
input i think i hear someone typing its
probability more
next slide please
another uh slide on test vectors
so um as i mentioned this is
mainly the work done by john on on test
vectors
um started off with francesca and then
john
and we realized now that the most wanted
parts here is to
to add real certificates and also
new cypher suites and that is actually
the
what is also most consuming here so
uh again we'd like to ask if anyone is
interested in in helping out and
provide the first run of either with
certs or with suite two and three
two or three in which case
uh we could have that as the starting
point and then we can make interrupt
tests and then we can
augment them to two test vectors once
they have been verified
uh so the the easy the the three
sub bullets here uh at the bottom we we
think we can
provide but we'd like to have some help
with uh
with the two bullets which are still
unticked anyone that is interested in
helping out
so there is mark in the queue
yeah i think with the tests we rank with
lydia especially we
essentially cover cyphers with two so
the output of those tests would be
already a starting point
i believe great yeah great perfect
uh who did cyphers with three was that
michelle or or who
was working on
sorry i couldn't remember of anyone
by the way yeah i said yeah michelle was
going to do this and i said i
would i was also going to implement this
but until now i
really haven't had the time to do this
so uh
i don't have uh cypher c2 or three yet
okay good but great great input marco so
we'll um
we'll try to make use of of of the
results of
last week's hackathon and and pulled
this together to
another test suite uh what about
certificates is there anyone
uh i think that stefan made some
certificate
uh wrong he said he was interested in
this difficult run i don't know if
he is stefan rusty so he's not in the
meeting i
i don't see him here perhaps he could
help up with that part
okay this was just an open call see if
there are people um
available that wants to want to
to help here how do we use the json
format now can can we copy it over
directly to json
or is anyone interested in helping out
with that
no volunteers yeah okay uh copying
to the json format if we agree on the
format of the json file
oh that's excellent thank you very much
so so we'll
um what we'll do is that we'll have a
look at your your
template we have a discussion uh either
yeah
perhaps on the mailing list and then we
agree on that one
and then it's great that you could help
us
to copy over the text files and then
we'll
we'll start filling in in the json
format excellent thank you very much
next slide so i just have a clarifying
question on this slide
related to the cyber native certificate
uh could you update us on the
status of this draft is uh this is a
draft standardizing cozy right
yep maybe john wants to say a few words
yeah
yeah so that's correct it's in
version eight or something now there has
been
a lot of discussion in cosy so
this has not been working group adopted
yet because the charter needs to
change there have been several requests
from
non-authors to from several different
non-authors to working group adoptes
and several of the codes in the reams
have been completely
taken by this seaboard certificate
now it's finally in working group
adoption
right now um but
i think it's it's moving ahead quite
well but it's uh it's
probably a bit off behind ad hoc
in maturity yeah but it's
i think it's starting to be quite stable
just to jump in uh i i'm the ad for both
lake and cozy so uh cozy is currently
in the rechartering process so there's
going to be
two rounds of isg review
and there's a public last call period in
between the two
and so we're currently doing the first
round the internal review
with isg and iab for the
new cozy charter that will allow us to
work on the
compressed certificates but i don't know
of any
uh obstacles to us doing that
okay thanks man so what i gather is
essentially that
the draft is not yet adopted but there
is a good prospect of it being adopted
once jose rechargers uh
so if there are no
objections i don't see an issue with uh
having test factors india cox back
using this using this format
so with that i propose we move forward
uh just a final comment from my side um
on on the certificate so there was
actually
uh two implementers requesting
certificates
as i remember steve stefan requested
cbor certificates and peter
requested ordinary dar uh encoded
certificates
so there is actually a request for both
but we'll we'll see what
what people can provide here and help
out with but eventually we should have
a both okay sorry next slide
uh okay um how are we time-wise i think
there are two slides
left essentially of the main slide we
have
one minute so we are i mean
[Music]
we are good on time okay good
so here is another um pretty specific
issue but still still might be worth
having uh
i mean open up for a discussion if there
is anyone that has a uh
a opinion so so as you as you remember
there is this
uh by-string identifier type
defined in ad hoc to make a
compact encoding of short byte strings
and
relying on the um
the use of seabor ins which can be uh
only one byte long
but it needs to be mapped back to a byte
string
since this is used for connection
identifiers and connection identifiers
are used as oscar sender ids which are
byte strings
so this is a slight complication in the
specification but it reduces the ad hoc
overhead uh it's always it's a note
that's also used for other things than
connection identifiers but that's the
main
use case and then there are two ideas
from christian
in this issue one is to
to use the same trick for efficient
coding of longer byte strings
so not only uh one byte zebra objects
but uh two by zero objects as well
and since we anyway have a mapping step
that that wouldn't necessarily make this
more complicated
although this this is a origin or
already a complication
and the second idea which is kind of
independent i think is
that we would decouple the ad hoc type
from
from the oscar sender ide in the sense
that we would allow adult to
just use either in or or byte strings
and then make the mapping at the point
when
when we do the rest of the oscar context
establishment
which would then um be more more
flexible in an ad hoc
and and simply in the adult setting but
complicate things when you when you do
the mapping tool score
i mean you're just pushing the problem
but but they would maybe be simpler in
the ad hoc setting so
so that was um that was if i understand
the proposal christian do you want to
add something
well the only thing i can add here is
that it's primarily about coding density
of ad hoc for cases that are not all
score because all score has this
requirement to have this mapped in some
way anyway
right okay any opinion on this
should we do any of those
i think we should analyze and
discuss i think it's a bit too early to
say whether we should do anything
no spontaneous ideas here
so i think that's i mean it's a really
late late issue so i i think that's a
good
good comment we haven't really thought
thought through
um but it's a good it's a good comment
it's a good issue
so those interested please
join the discussion and we try to
progress it
next slide
this was this is the final uh slide
where i
sort of highlight issues um
and then there is this there is a last
slide on on some
some other open issues but this slide is
on the
mandatory mandatory to implement cypher
suite which we have been discussed
for quite some time but it's still a
final comment here which we i think we
should just
bring up um so if you remember the
outcome of the previous discussion
we which was basically the problem with
supporting both ecdsa and eddsa in
constrained endpoints
and uh the result of that discussion was
that we said that the constraint
endpoint should implement either
sweet 0 or sweet 2
corresponding to eddsa or ecdsa
respectively
whereas less constrained devices should
implement both
and uh now malicia had a comment why
it's sort of reiterating why again uh
did we not mandate
sweet too uh the previous considerations
maybe at least when it comes to
performance
were probably not not accurate
so processing time code footprint and
message overhead is
is not is more advantageous from from an
ecd
sa point of view according to militia
maybe you want to add something here
malisha
so yeah maybe just a general remark when
i was going through this issue
my feeling was that people were mostly
giving
preferences not really based on uh
technical arguments
uh behind uh their preference so
i was trying to steer up the discussion
uh
in the direction of really discussing
the details
of both aspects that both performance
and security so uh my argumentation was
related to these three points that you
can see on the slide so processing time
code
footprint where ecdsa is
seems to be favored over edsa
uh and i was asking for more input on
specific attacks
and where how do those attacks on
ecdsa uh reflect
on start on constrained devices and
the hardware accelerators that are
typically
present on those
so uh yeah yes you are
yes i hear you
so that yeah great thank you um
and i well i mean for my from from my
understanding
we we had a discussion about security
properties
maybe john can fill in exactly what was
what was the reason but but i
i also remember the different
i mean having talked to different
implementers and different
companies here and and there is a clear
preference
for eddsa in certain uh
settings and uh what that is based on
i i'm not i mean there's obviously
is i mean initially there was at least
the security and performance
argument i don't know exactly what what
is the state of matters
so that was precisely my point i've seen
preference being given
on the on the thread but not exactly
technical argumentation behind that
preference
and i would really like to understand
uh if these are uh i would like to avoid
having religious kind of preferences and
really focus on the technical ones and
uh that's the reason why i
uh jumped into this discussion trying to
steer it in this way
uh stephen did you want to say something
yes uh so i mean i think i'm not sure
religion is available here
it's not really a religion it's more
what tools are available but what i
really want johnny cube to say was i
think at the interim we had
back in january renee stroke uh raised
this issue again
and if i remember the red you know the
discussion was that we were going to
have a discussion on the mailing list
about this
i can't remember if renee was supposed
to start it or if we were supposed to
start it as chairs but we didn't have it
so i think we should have that
discussion on the list anyway
so yeah that's correct i mean there was
an action point on behalf of renee to
start
to restart the thread of pointing to the
best current practice on selecting on
selecting an mpi street
uh which was not
done in the meantime so yeah we should
we should get back to that on the link i
suppose
right so i guess the bet yeah probably
better is that we take the action as
chairs to kick that discussion off
uh maybe it was just ambiguous as to
whether it was renee or us who were
supposed to do it last time
so that's all that's what i wanted to
say we should start that
next week or something
sounds good john
yes following i think
some of the companies wanting to have
eddsa express that
offline and not on the github so
um but i think depending on what
architect you have there is definitely
if you have hardware acceleration for
easy dsa that is faster if you
don't have that then probably eddsa is
much faster in
at least in some implementation seems
quite tricky to
compare uh renee stating that
ecdsa with the random
random noms is much more secure and then
there's
definitely security properties with
eddsa
which is much nicer it's much harder to
make something
wrong yeah there's one more aspect that
has been pointed out by
companies wanting to use eddsa and that
is
that curve25519 can be used for
threshold cryptography and
one company wanting to use ad hoc
especially asked for that and
said that was a main
benefit with that curve
okay thank you so could i ask you to
uh to send an email to the mailing list
summarizing these arguments that you
just mentioned in an attempt to restart
this discussion to converge on it
yeah i can do that okay
thanks
okay so jordan do you have uh any more
slides
yeah do you think there was something
i'm reading the issues
sorry i'm reading the comments on in the
uh in the jabber here
so there's a question about the type i
don't know if there's a typo here
this i think this is um
and then there's a question about a used
for threshold
yes that was what i think that was what
john stated is there some confusion
about that
and this seems to be some confusion
about what
which actually yeah go ahead someone is
talking i'm just joining
next thank you perhaps
so we have michael in the queue michael
so i was trying to understand the change
mandatory ambulance cipher suite to one
based on ecdsa
has negative consequences on performance
security
so is that comment based upon
the well first of all i wondered if that
was that was a typo for edd sa
um so i can imagine it has a negative
if you go to edd sa it has negative
consequences and performance because
it's not on hardware
um but i can't understand ecdsa has
negative consequences on performance
since it's usually in hardware as the
next point
makes uh in la but the security people
have
suspicion about certain curves so i'm
i'm is that what part of that comment is
based on i just
maybe we could have some so maybe i can
quantify
uh maybe i can clarify so this was uh
precisely the comment
the first comment describing the issue
that i reacted to uh
regarding the performance of ecdsa
because it seemed to be like an
underlying argument
that edds safer is both performed better
and is more secure
which is i brought this up again so uh
edwards that's yes that
the adwords ed dsa that performs better
and has
has better security so in response to
that
i i restarted the thread on github uh
giving the arguments on performance and
essentially summarizing the
the threads uh saying that i mean
most summarizing that since most of the
devices have hardware acceleration
uh for ecdsa the performance
uh the the statement on performance does
not hold
so this is just a quote of the old uh of
the old uh previous consideration that
uh that yaran
uh noted and then as
to the security aspects my understanding
is that
i mean there are speculations on on the
security of the underlying curve
of the ecdsa the the nist curves
but the to my understanding these are
still speculation
uh and there are attacks
uh to my knowledge mostly implementation
attacks on the ecdsa signature algorithm
which we might or might not be concerned
with
so i was trying to point the the
discussion
in the direction of understanding better
those attacks of ecdsa
for the devices that we target my
understanding is that
there's some ec ec dsa hardware
acceleration which will accelerate ed
dsa
equally but not everybody has that
flexibility yes that is correct and
there is a draft
that is led by rene that explains how to
do it how to represent
uh the edwards curve in virus transform
if i'm not mistaken
and implement and accelerate it uh
with these genetic accelerators that
provide
genetic parameters for the for the virus
transform
but this is not widely available
it's not it's not unavailable it's just
not widely available
yes exactly yeah that's great
okay so maybe john did you want to say
something
you're still in the queue
okay i guess not so uh yes
so i propose we move uh move on
with this on the mailing list because uh
it is an important issue that we should
carefully discuss and having the
mdr in the archives uh
so uh as i said uh
the next step is for john to send the uh
the mail summarizing the technical
arguments including
uh the reasoning behind the preference
of different companies
wanting to have uh eb dsa
uh as an mpi street
do we have any other comments on this
issue
no i hear none uh you don't do you want
to move on
yes yes thanks for taking the lead
okay so yeah there are a number of other
issues
as well i don't know i mean we can we
can
briefly talk about these um if if we
have the time or
we don't have anything else we'd like to
bring up
um i think that we've gone through
the main issues already now so and i
think we have
good way forward for for those
so um yeah i'm optimistic that we can
close a lot of a lot of issues in the
next
period here but there are there's been
raised some some new ideas and new
issues and there is also some old ones
which we want to
fix so one is related to
opportunistic use case the opportunistic
use of
of ad hoc um
i didn't bring up the issue here do you
want to elaborate on that
christian
just just a few words so this would this
would allow
use in cases where there's only one
party that wants to authenticate the
other
and that doesn't need authentication on
its own i think it should be possible
but it's
just not explored currently so
if if if we spend a bit of time thinking
of
whether this can work this might help
the document on long term run
um i think there's been similar
comments offline from a company wanting
to use
ad hoc with um
raw public key by value so basically
optimistic you
you don't authenticate the first time
like ssh you send the keys first time
and then you
the second third time you and all the
for the
future times you verify that you have
the same talking to the same um
device that you talked first time so
there's there's
there's two kinds of the one is as you
mentioned
with sending the raw public key by value
that's what ssh would do
and that's that this is clearly a value
and
might and would also apply for the
application to resource directory
where devices i have this key and let me
in again if i can buy this team
um but something that a device could
also do is i'm nobody and don't even try
to remember be me because next time i'll
be using a different primary key and
won't say anything
and for those cases it would be more
interesting to not send an additional
raw public key at all
but explore whether it's my suffice to
just
use the um the ephemeral key and not use
anything in addition and whether that
fmel key that's already
being sent can also be used to do this
kind of
non-authentication to just say i'm this
entity but nothing more
[Music]
so to me this is a bit
extending the scope that we agreed on in
the requirements draft
where i think uh we explicitly agreed on
uh tackling a mutually authenticated
case
explicitly so uh i don't have anything
against uh extending that scope but
this this should be discussed in detail
on the list uh
by the working group
yeah with my coach and also i mean
would we be wise to extend the scope now
or would we be wiser to try and finish
what we're doing first
if if that's an outcome of that
discussion i'm also happy with it it's
just
it's something that should be visible
somewhere if the outcome is
um out of scope find with me too
i i i forget if we had exactly this
discussion before with my shirt can you
remember in the requirements discussion
the discussion may have been had already
but i'd have to check on the detail
so i'm not aware of the i know that we
have
a text in the requirements document
requiring mutual
authentication and not mentioning uh
opportunity queues so that that is what
i was referring to
yeah right and that was kind of hard one
now it just happens that
all of the people who might argue deeply
about that happen to be off in the
deprived working group now arguing
deeply about
deprived but uh again if we bring this
up again
we may uh end up with a large discussion
so it'd be a little bit i think about it
ahead of time first
i i don't think this was discussed in
detail i think it was just um suggested
mutual authentication
but i agree i think we should have the
discussion but this might be some
extension
work later and not
now and sending raw public keys by value
might
require cozy work um
yeah i i uh if i make uh
um i think uh i mean if you
look at the two cases that christian
outlined here i think the the the
passing
passing publicly by value that seems to
be well founded
and that's uh that's issue 82 actually
that we like to have a cozy header map
for public key because that's not there
is no no
there is no header map actually defined
uh for that
uh but the other case where you actually
you're you're not sending a key and just
reusing in a female
i mean you're using that seems a little
bit more speculative
in my mind so i i would like to keep
half of the uh this case here but but
perhaps not everything in this issue
okay any other comments
and there's some ongoing uh yeah
okay so that's just michael and
christian then next
um deterministic seaborn encoding john
do you want to say
something about that
yeah so this was brought up
in a discussion with a
company implementing this and they
started ask question
about the terminus and uh
we thought i opened an issue i think we
should
go through the protocol and see if there
are
any places where things are not
deterministic
i think for example the integers are
probably not specified currently that
they are encoded in the smallest
possible way even if that was the
intention when we wrote the draft
and i don't think sieber forces you to
do that by
default so i think we explicitly need to
state that but i think this is not
anything that would change the protocol
but it would be a clarification in
in the specification that you cannot do
in any other way
but doesn't this really belong to seabor
specifications and that's why
i
i don't think seabor is
deterministic in this way there is
seabor has
several ways to encode an int
there might be some part of the seaboard
say this is how you get the
deterministic and coding and then maybe
ad hoc should
refer to that part but otherwise you can
encode an integer
as a single byte or two by 16-bit 8-bit
32-bit i think that's up to you i don't
think
c-board forces you to use the smallest
but if if i'm wrong please correct me
yeah so i'm not aware of those details
it would be maybe good
to have someone on the uh if there's
someone who is
familiar with seaboard details uh
comment on this
uh we have michael hi michael richardson
so seaborg does your you're absolutely
right john seaboard doesn't say this it
actually says that
it's up to us as a seaboard protocol
that we need to specify this
um i guess there's two issues i think
with these integers one is that it's
stupid to take more bytes than you need
to
however that's a a that's a sender
stupidity
uh okay and if they wish to
shoot themselves in the foot then i
think that's okay
um but we just have the signature
verification issue and then
i think that we need to specify that you
you you sign and verify
what you what's on the wire not what you
reconstructed
so that gets rid of any canonization
issues
and and then we need to simply say what
you just said that
that integers are always encoded in the
shortest uh
uh or should be encoded in the shortest
value possible
um and and that's our business
our at our it's on us to do this as a
user of seabor
and any other things that we want to say
like you know such and such can't be a
map or
you know map keys must not be strings or
whatever we want to say
yeah i agree i think there's a
might be security aspects of having a
signal encoding
also i don't see any direct attack but
if in protocols where you have a
weakness
then it's bad if an attacker can have a
lot of different
choices how to choose things um
so typically you want deterministic
encoding and security protocols
yeah so i think that's a that's a good
point and ben commented in the chat
uh giving a pointer to the draft
that takes rules from rfc
189 49 which is receiver i believe
okay so that's i think that's a good
good discussion
and then we have the final issue do you
want to say something about that as well
john
status of yep uh
yeah so right i guess some background
also but
right now the way you can identify a
certificate
in cosi is either by sending it
with by value or with a uri
or with a hash and
hash takes eight bytes has been
suggested
both discussed in both lake and in cosi
recently that it would be good to be
able to identify a
certificate with a kid currently
you you
cosi doesn't really forbid it but it
doesn't specify how
either i would say it's you have to do
it yourself and assign a kid to a
certificate
and do it i think kosovo discussed this
recently and there seemed to be
agreement that this
might be good but not exactly how
how to do that i think that is
discussion it has
not been any more discussion um
then i think a follow-up question
is whether you need whether you
if you have a certificate by kid you
then
also need raw public keys with subject
name in them and the
key key id is a key identifier
it's just byte string that you have
agreed
upon to use to identify the
the key it's similar as the
psk key identifier in in
tls so
i remember having the discussion in lake
and i believe
uh the comment from michael
was that i mean with this with this
proposal essentially
we are we are making certificates a sort
of pro public
key and from what i recall
uh he did not see much value in that
michael maybe you can confirm if you're
online
do we have a use case where the where
that would what this would be useful
sorry i i i missed what you said that i
said so i'm not sure that i
can agree or disagree yet
so uh i was recalling a discussion in a
lake on the proposal
to reference a certificate with the key
id
where i remember you objecting to this
change essentially saying that this
makes the certificate a sort of federal
public key
oh yeah
um
if if the endpoint the other end can't
identify can't validate the certificate
then it's just a container for a raw
public key yes i would agree with that
statement
um but i think i need more context for
what
when we when we're why we are going to
do that
um but i guess i'll just repeat that
yeah so why send the whole certificate
if you can't validate it
i guess the point
so my question then to john is john do
we have a compelling use case for this
either to save bytes
or to not have to extend cozy key with
subject name to comply
with sigma i would say
use a raw public keys without identify
might not be 100 compliant with the
sigma
academic paper um
but i think that could also be done
after the i agree with michael that
there's an
overlap with the raw public key
and i think i'm not saying we should do
this but i think it should be discussed
after the late discussion this was
discussed in
cozy with several persons includes
it was so yes i don't remember who
suggested it kusi not
me i don't know if it was for an ad hoc
use case
at all and there were several people in
cosi
seeming positive to the idea and closely
discussed
how to do this without reaching any
agreement
waiting for kusi to do this
okay so i guess in the context of this
discussion we would uh as a working
group we would need a little bit more
context and i guess this wasn't
this was just a hint to what could be
discussed if there was time and it is
indeed the case
so i propose that we keep this issue
open
and maybe present it in more detail
during one of the next meetings
of link
does that work for you
sounds good okay okay
[Music]
so i think yep i think we reached the
end the list of of the
of the hard open issues and then there
are other perhaps more editorial
so yeah i think that's uh that's where
we are
basically in in the work
okay thank you thank you for presenting
the issues and
uh leading uh the development of this
pacquiao and tron
and francesca so uh
maybe we could i think that the next
item in the agenda we have the next
steps
where we have uh i mean i could
maybe just summarize uh what we plan on
doing
in the future period so
uh i recall from the first presentation
by marco that we will have an interrupt
event
in april uh and uh
where we will be testing additional
implement uh we'll be testing the
implementations
uh so please continue with this work and
also it's all great to see these reports
coming to the working group this is very
useful
uh on the formal verification front
uh timothy is leading the ad hoc c
implementation that and in collaboration
with kartik's team at indriya
this verification is being uh
formally verified for correctness so
that is one one direction that we are
headed towards and then the second one
is
on the formal analysis of the protocol
what kartik mentioned during the last
interim
uh where we will hopefully have some
updates
for the next meetings i will be
coordinating i will take an action to
coordinate with kartik on on this work
and
uh update the working group as needed
other than that do we want to organize
interims in the next period
do you have any proposals
so there is your own queue yes
yeah i think we should i mean interns
are good we basically
uh take it take the extra effort to
prepare for the interim meeting and that
we close a number of issues and so on so
i think that's uh that's a means of
progressing and it's also a good uh
feedback channels for
for people and people to comment and and
provide new input and so on so yes i
think we definitely should
arrange uh injury meetings
uh should we aim for one interim or two
interims before the next idea
maybe two
sounds good so let's have let's plan to
have one maybe
mid mid april and then one in mid-may
from or towards the end of the may that
does that sound okay
yes sounds good and there is one uh
the interrupt the intro yeah i think
mark was going to say something about
the interrupt sorry go ahead marco
yeah i think for april the second half
is ideal for sure after
uh that interop session we take at least
we can report about that and possibly
i think a bit of issues that that can
come up
after those tests so second half of
april round end of april will be ideal i
think
okay perfect so yeah so a sheriff will
take the action to
to schedule the next interim for after
the
uh the next interrupt event and then we
will just
uh we won't schedule the one in may
until after the
internet so
with that i don't know we have any other
business to discuss
does anyone want to discuss some related
issue
so there is your run yes um
i just wanted to say that we are really
fortunate about this this input process
from the implementers
uh we don't have so much input from
people or not implementing
so if someone would interest just read
the
specification uh or or have some
specific
comments that would be fantastic
you could either send bails directly to
the authors or
even better to the lake mailing list so
yeah
even more comments are are welcome thank
you
okay so yeah
so we have nine minutes left in the
meeting i
propose we call it a day here steven did
you did you want to add something
i had very little to do which is fine i
could just
put silly comments in java it was good
thank you
so for me it was cutting i didn't hear
what you said except
thank you
but
okay so i guess uh i guess that's it for
the late meeting thank you everyone for
uh for attending today and let's keep
the discussion going on github and on
the mailing list
you