looks like it's working
there you go all right um looks like
we're all set thanks so much for testing
that stuff out
and we're ready to get started so i'm
going to
go back to sharing the intro slides
that's not what i want
oh wrong up
this one
all right i'm ready to go um
good morning or good afternoon or good
evening everyone uh this is the
measurement analysis for protocols
research group meeting
uh online for ietf110 um miria
my co-chair and i are both on here mary
is going to help with
watching the jabber channel and help
keep me on track if i forget anything
the uh you can reach us at maprgchairs
at ietf.org if you ever need to
this session is being recorded so it
will be available like all the other map
rg
presentations afterwards on the map rg
wiki if you search map rg wiki
at google you'll find it and
there's an index to each individual
presentation here's the irtf
notewell it's the same as the ietf noel
essentially
uh but be aware that speaking about your
work here has potentially consequences
having to do with intellectual property
and
familiarize yourself with that here's
the
irtf privacy and code of conduct
behavior yourselves you always seem to
but look at that if you need to know
anything
about the details here's a slide about
the goals of the irtf
for those of you new to it and i think
maybe you have a couple speakers that
haven't visited us before
on the irtf conducts research it's not
bound by the same rules as the ietf but
we
largely focus on uh research that has to
do with ietf things and we happen to be
co-located or coincidentally with the
itf
administrivia you can find our charter
online
uh i usually search for mrg at google
and that comes up
there we have a mailing list if you want
to stick with us in the future
today's slides are not at meeting 105
they're at meeting 110
so i'll fix that in the slides the media
go link you've already got and we're
also on jabber so feel free to
type things in the jabber session which
should be on the left of your medical
screen
if you would rather do that than speak
out loud
our agenda for today is uh once we get
past this few minutes of intro
is we'll switch to paul hoffman for
about 10 minutes talking about
collecting typical domain names for web
servers
and if you look at the agenda link in on
the website
the the document or the report that paul
wrote i think for icann
is uh is is listed there the link to it
then we're going to bring viet up to
presents uh uh work in
that was presented in an academic
conference the link there to the full
paper is also there
um for a 15-minute research presentation
again about the dns and tls and some
measurement results
we'll switch to fong for assessing the
privacy
benefits of the of domain name
encryption that is also
uh is or is going to be a published
research paper maybe i've got some other
way around one's upcoming and one has
already been published
the link to the paper is there uh we'll
spend a few minutes for a quick update
from robin marks about qlog
and then we'll close out with pete heist
and the last about 10 minutes and if we
get any time back along the way we'll
have you know more time for questions
but
we're going to try to fit the questions
and comments in between those or in the
time itself
so um that's the session for today um
any any uh opening comments or questions
or
issues all right so i want to quickly uh
thank spencer and oliver
for note-taking i found two note takers
so oh yeah awesome
awesome thank you so much okay so um
we've got uh paul up first so paul if
you
get in the queue to share your screen i
can approve it
oops i hit there we go
and i'm going to experiment with setting
this timer hang on a moment
well let's see if this just worked or
not
share my screen sorry it
should have done this one first um no
problem or right on time
um
uh
well hell i am not i'm just going to do
my entire screen
and so i'm not going to be able to see
the timer or anything like that
okay i'll i'll i'll let's oh wait
there's one that's uh yeah application
window
[Music]
i guess we always have to start in an
ietf meeting with uh hardware issues
would you like me to um stop you know
i'm just going to do my entire screen
i'm good
but if i'm starting to run over can you
just interrupt me oh
it's not even letting me yeah you know
what when we go to
next presenter and i i believe i have to
restart chrome
okay didn't you just share your screen
number no i did not
oh okay no we only did that yeah that's
the same thing i didn't do i had to
research chrome
um uh let's see yeah or if we have the
slides at hand we can share
for paul if you can if you can do that
that's that would be great
your your preference yeah
let's just so that i it stays with my
notes then we'll put we'll do you first
didn't keep yet where he was and you
just need to
have patience with me for a minute to
find the slides
let's see you are
this was collecting typical domain names
what was the last word in the name
servers got it thank you
all right so i'm going to share preview
i'm sorry um
there we go i've got beautiful thanks 37
minutes after the hour so i'll let you
know
when there's about nine minutes up if
you have not finished by then go ahead
and and i'm gonna zip through this
quickly um so greetings um
uh my name is paul hoffman i work for
icann this was work that was i did
under the auspices of icann but it was
actually initiated for the deprived
working group in the ietf so
next slide
so the motivation for this work was that
in the dns a lot of people
when they're doing um uh research on
like authoritative servers and such like
that
they want to to collect data from a lot
of
authoritative servers i'm going down and
up again but that happens um
and uh typically what people do
is they use um one of
the lists of the most popular you know
servers out there so like the alexa list
or the tranco list and such like that
um but those aren't typical
and uh the the request from
dprive was actually we were trying to
measure uh
the um how long it takes to set up a tls
connection on a typical web server
turns out we didn't end up using using
the research but it was fun to do
anyways
so the kinds of lists that people use
like i say are the most popular websites
and if you don't know about tranco you
should definitely look at the old map rg
slides on that
um the other one that people use is they
extract
um that that all of the gtlds the the
global
top level domains um
i'm sorry generic top-level domains
those are available
those lists of the domain names however
a bazillion of those are just parked
so they're not really typical either or
they get a dump from a passive dns
collection system
but that's not really typical because
those are often very local that is
you know for a recursive resolver in a
particular region it's going to be much
more regional
next slide
um so what i also just realized is that
wow wikipedia has
links to um a bazillion
small websites you know if you're if
you're reading the wikipedia page
you will see things like um
uh personal websites of academics and
lists of all of the elementary schools
in a particular
town in a country you've never visited
and such like that
um and also the nice thing is wikipedia
is not just in english that's in
um pretty much every spoken language in
the world
so uh this is these are examples of the
kinds of things that as i was looking i
was like oh this is great
these are much more typical than a list
of
the largest websites around you get
governments of small cities obscure
support teams things like that
so um the question was well great
without
scraping all of wikipedia could i get a
sample of these
next slide
um it turns out that they actually keep
a database
uh twice a month as backups a public
database
they want people backing up wikipedia um
basically to mirror it not so that
you're serving it but in case they go
down and such like that
and instead of them just having all of
the pages as one giant hunk
they actually have pages and some
subsets and one of them is
the list of all the external links so
that was perfect i grabbed that
for the research i did here i did that
at the beginning of this year
they updated it seems like twice a month
on the first of the month and then
sometime towards the middle so grab the
database
extract all the external links because
it's actually a database it's a mysql
database
clean up the lists because
wikipedia it being publicly edited
you have lots of broken links links that
just in fact don't make sense
and that's okay you know like not not
dunking on wikipedia at all
it's a lovely resource um picked out all
the ones that in this case were for http
https
which turned out to be the vast majority
of all of the links um can you scroll
down or keep it as a full screen
i can't that i wouldn't that's fine i'm
going to turn my mic back out so i can
see
no i'm thank you i'll bring it i'll
bring it back up to full screen
no no that's what's done that's fine i'm
just flying by the way so
um so and then because what i was
looking at
is um just web servers i didn't care
about the full url
i um stripped off the scheme
and everything after the domain name
which means i didn't know
which ones that had been listed as htp
or https
but that's okay because one of the
things we wanted to
see is if you're hitting on a a web
server that actually doesn't have https
how long will it take for you to find
out and such like that so what what this
gave me
was a list of all the domain names um
for all the links
and then i had to call the list because
of course there was a lot of duplication
a million things point back to um
sites like google or for example for a
large university
there might be you know thousands of
links next slide
so after i did all of that and again i
did this for january first there were
about 750 databases
i got about 7.35 million unique
domain names from the data set so that
was lovely and way more than i wanted so
i took a random sample of a hundred
thousand
um but so the good news is if you
want millions of unique domain names
uh to sample from this works just great
um um so and i wanted to test a hundred
thousand hosts
uh but many of the names in there are
dead
so i actually started with over a
hundred thousand um
and resolved them all so i found out
which ones actually
currently have an ipv4 address so i
think i started 150
and then 150 000 and ended up with about
110 000.
um and then i did the actual analysis
that i was
doing which was uh timing but i also
wanted to look just because everyone in
the ietf says how are we doing with ipv6
um and how well you know for those of us
in the dns world how many were dns
signed
so i did that analysis as i was doing
that's not important to this
presentation basically the presentations
about
hey look i found a new data set you can
find it too next slide
okay paul you got about two minutes yeah
and that's fine
i'm uh so this is the last slide so
if this interests you please take a look
at
this report it's called the same as this
one collecting
typical domain names from the web we
have our own
series in icann called the octo series
which is the office of the cto
which is what i'm in so there's an octo
number
um of of that um
and i don't actually give the code in
there because as someone pointed out
maybe wikipedia doesn't want is pulling
down the databases all the time and such
like that
but if you're interested in doing this
work please get in touch with me
um i do have a github repo that i just
haven't widely publicized
um for the steps i took which is a bunch
of
you know vaguely commented python code
but it actually
is reproducible so that's it um i guess
if
for those of you who care about the dns
and ipv6
um about 17 of the
of those domain names that had a v4
address also had a v6 address
and for those of you who care about dns
sec um
approximately four percent of those
domain names were dnsec
signed so great um and i guess we're not
doing questions right we're just
moving on yeah we are we have time i see
you okay
great so i think we've got i think we've
got about two minutes
okay great absolutely yep um
excuse me for shutting the slide down
but i can't no that's fine that's right
and the slides are available so yeah
yeah so so
uh for participants put yourself in the
queue um
if you if you're interested in speaking
or submit to something to jabber and
here you can relay it so we've got
alexander in the queue
thank you thanks paulo um alex mayor
from liquidity
i was wondering did you also consider
certificate transparency as a sort of
domain name because i i found that's
very interesting as well
so that's a very interesting question no
i didn't but then last week i did
all of a sudden someone had said oh but
there's every certificate you want in ct
so i will probably rerun this at some
point um
and see whether those numbers are any
different but no i didn't at the time
cool i like that it's always good to
know about another data source that's
differently biased than all the other
ones that we use
i i wonder if also it'd be interesting
to see after
a time how many stale names are in the
wikipedia and they might be able to use
that for some of their
update driving they actually don't do
automatic updates which i think is is
fine i mean they're really reliant on
volunteers and i think that
that's really good um uh and
the other thing to to note here is that
this is not meant to be a
typical of the web data it's more
typical for example
all of us uh probably in the last month
have ordered out from
a small local restaurant uh that had a
website
that is not in wikipedia there's
probably millions of those
so okay we got oliver in the queue why
don't you go quick
and we'll close the queue then yeah sure
um so this is oliver i have a question
so basically initially you started with
um the assumption that the top lists out
there are not really representative
did you also basically compare the data
set that you gathered from wikipedia
with the one that what you got from
definitely okay yep and so if you look
at the report you'll see that
um so very briefly ipv6
um adoption was almost identical between
tranco and um and this
uh dns second option was actually so i
remember i said was four percent for
this list it's about two percent
for the tranco list so um that to me
says that's a huge
difference that shows that in fact um
well-managed
popular uh websites are less likely to
use dns sect than typical
cool thanks thanks a lot guys um thanks
bill
thank you let's bring let's bring via up
and viet uh you got a 15 minute slot in
this short one-hour meeting
so i'm going to start the countdown
clock
and i'll let you know uh when there's
two minutes left or something
oh okay so perfect so hello everyone my
name is viet and i've
been honored to present our paper called
measuring dean s over t less from the
edge
here at today's memory meeting so as
they've mentioned this paper which was
co-authored by irena and viper who have
also
joined the session as i could see will
also be presented
at pam later this month and you can
already find a link to the pdf and more
details
on the paper is covered in this talk on
the github repository linked here
so first of all a brief overview of the
main findings right away
so as the title of the paper suggests we
will be looking at the adoption
reliability and response times of dns
over
tls or dot for short so during the talk
we will see that the adoption
of the dot is still rather low and that
we have higher fader rates and response
times for dot
as one may expect compared to
traditional dns but
we'll get back to these results at the
end of the talk again so
we will move on and um
as most of you likely also know dot was
standardized
in may 2016 so roughly five years ago
and its main feature is that it provides
confidentiality by securing the dns
traffic
with a tls session between the dns
client and the resolver
now previous measurement studies have
already looked at different aspects of
dot
and have measured dot from different
networks and vantage points
um however not from home networks which
is what
we were interested in and so we were
wondering how does dot look from home
networks
in order to find this out we kind of
split our measurement and
study in two parts and part one in this
case is the
adoption and before looking into home
networks in particular
we reproduced the first study that we
just referenced in which the authors
have
scanned the pv4 address space for open
dns resolvers
and then subsequently checked the open
ipad points that they found
for dot support and as of april 2019
this was at
point 15 roughly so we repeated this
management approach
and found that the number of
open dlt resolvers has actually
increased by roughly 23 percent
over the course of nine months and that
also the support for
um the new tls 1.3 has also
substantially increased among these open
resolvers
whereas on the flip side um the support
for older versions like pls 1 or tls 1.1
the support for those has been also
increasingly discontinued
so overall we have find some
decent progress regarding the support of
dot
and newer tls versions although overall
the
adoption is still somewhat low
then for the second part of the
methodology
this concerns the reliability and
response times we use
the drive atlas platform for
measurements
and this platform has been able to
run dot measurements since early 2018
roughly
so we reached out to wrap in cc and they
kindly helped us with our measurement
study in which we involve
around 3 000 residential probes
all of which are ipv4 capable and
version 3
ipadless probes in this case so what
these probes do is they
issue dns requests once a day over a
period of one week
this was in july 2019 and they do these
requests both over dot
and traditional dns over udp
on port 53 and these dnrs requests
kind of request a record resolution for
200 domains over ipv4
towards a set of 15 different public
resolvers which you can see here in the
table
on the right hand side
and on top of that we also issue the dns
requests to the
local resolvers of the write atlas probe
as you can also see in the table five of
the public
resolvers support dot already and
as for the local probes um this is not
really
or we weren't really sure if those uh
support dft or not so this ties back
into the
question of adoption of duty and for
those
we found that only 13 probes of the more
than 3 000 probes that we initially used
um had a point or received
the dot response successfully from their
local resolvers
which is roughly 0.4 only
nevertheless overall we collected around
90 million um dns measurements in total
which we will have a look at in the
upcoming slides
so okay first of all for reliability
we look at the reliability of dns over
tls based on failure rates
which you can see in this table which is
also
taken from the paper the failure rate in
this case is simply the
column of number of failures divided by
the
total number of measurement column in
this case
and obviously then the question would
occur what is a failure exactly
failure in this case is when a probe is
not able to send the
dns request to the resolver or on the
other hand
when the response was not received by
the probe so
in both cases the write atlas api
returns an error along with an error
message
which we had a look at and saw that the
most common errors in this case
for both traditional dns and dns over
tls
were timeouts errors related to sockets
to connect and tcp and tls related
errors
which is obviously dot exclusive since
dns over udp
doesn't use tcp or tls either
so when comparing the failure rates for
both protocols
in this case especially for the
resolvers that
use both or that offer and support both
protocols
you can see that dlt has higher failure
rates so
some inflation regarding the failure
rates which range
from just about half a percentage point
for google and cloudflare
over to a few percentage points with
what nine and clean browsing
and then lastly with more than 30
percentage points for the local
resolvers
um here you can also see that um
uncensoredness
has an inflation of more than 95
um percentage points which indicates
that there have been
issues closer on the server side um
for dot whereas for the other um dot
measurements we see that the issues are
closer to the probes
and along the paths um indicating that
the dot traffic is simply
dropped by some metal boxes which also
explains the high number of timeouts
that we see for our measurements
okay moving on we also take the previous
table that we've seen
and split this by region by the location
of the probe
to be more specific and this is
what it looks like so this matrix um
shows the median failure rate
for all the probes on a continent for a
specific resolver in this case
with traditional dns on top in the top
matrix and
dns over tls on the bottom one
so for dot in particular so the bottom
part of the figure
we see that the failure rates are
somewhat varying
regarding the different continents and
resolvers so some cells have
lower than one percent of a failure rate
whereas some other cells have close to
or even more than
10 and we also see that the majority of
the
cells which have higher failure rates um
are probes or belong to probes located
in africa and south america so
it seems like um there are more issues
um
with these on these
as for the local resolvers um on the
bottom figure you can see that we only
have
results for probes in europe and north
america
as i mentioned before we only saw um
local resolvers for
of 13 probes to return responses
at all and um these kind of were both
uh all of these 13 probes were located
in europe and north america respectively
um with both of the failure rates being
higher
by quite a bit so we have here failure
rates of
more than 30 to 40 percent compared to
most of the other
cells which are mostly single digit
percentages
for dot all right
moving on to the response times so with
rapidless this is a bit more tricky so
some background explanation of that for
traditional dns obviously you
simply send out the request over udp and
then the resolver will look up the
requested domain
either in its cache or recursively and
then send you back the response
now for dot you obviously have the pcp
and tls
handshakes before to establish the
connection session to secure the traffic
and typically a client would be reusing
this session
in order to get or minimize the overhead
of these handshakes
now for ripe atlas um this is a bit
difficult and different
since the measurements are designed to
be independent from each other
which means that these connections and
sessions are not kept alive in between
the measurements
meaning that the response times that we
measure here and present here
always include the full handshake of the
tcp and tila sanchex as a result this
will
roughly resemble upper bounds for the
dot lookups as
subsequent domain lookups would not have
to do the handshakes and
be or have a low response stamps
all right um so now also the part of the
remain
lookup may vary a bit so in order to
partially avoid this we focus on the
fifth percentiles
of each probe and resolver tuple and
given that we repeat the measurements
over a period of a week
and take the response times towards the
lower end of the distribution with the
fifth percentiles
this will therefore approximate the
cases of cached records
on this figure on the right hand side
you can see the cdf for these fifth
percentiles
and for dot we can see that the medians
are around 10 to 30 milliseconds for
most of the resolvers
whereas for dot um medians are roughly
130 250 milliseconds for the faster
resolvers
going up to more than 200 milliseconds
for some of the
slower resolvers and in this case
unsensitiveness is an outlier again at
one second for median
so when comparing both of these um we
can see that
the response times for dot are higher by
more than 100 milliseconds when compared
to the
traditional dns mostly due to the
connection and session establishment
and um before we saw that local
resolvers have more failures than public
ones
for dot but in this case the response
times are actually
somewhat comparable for these two types
of resolvers
now lastly again we split this by
original
um aspects i don't want to go into too
much detail here
so just briefly going over it this is
how it looks
and we see that before
the failure rates were somewhat varying
but also the response times
for dot dot is highly varying
regarding the cells on the bottom which
you can see
although again we see higher values
primarily for probes in africa and south
america
and also as mentioned for d.o.t the
failure rates were
higher but now for the local resolvers
we see somewhat comparable response
times between
local resolvers and public solvers
so just to sum it up um in conclusion we
saw that
the t adoption is still somewhat low
with less than half of a percent for
both the ipv4 address space
and local resolvers of the ripe atlas
probes although there has been some
decent progress regarding
the increasing support of dlt and newer
tls versions
for the reliability we saw that for the
failure rates are in some cases
comparable which was mostly the case for
public reserves when comparing to
traditional dns
and some cases much higher which was the
case for the public resolvers
and we've also seen some indications
that this is mostly due to
issues along the path with middle boxes
and lastly regarding the response times
we saw that
the unt is slower by more than 100
milliseconds
largely due to the connection and
session overhead as i just mentioned
although the response times for public
and local resolvers are
somewhat comparable and yeah finally
as mentioned all the measurement related
material is online
on our github repository um
and also the paper with more details and
if you have any questions you can
feel free to send us an email and i'm
also happy to take questions right now
if there are any
thanks fiat yeah we have a couple
minutes for questions so put yourself in
the queue if you'd like to speak
yes there was one comment about um do
compared to dot
in the chat are you planning to look at
this as well
um okay so with the wipe at list um you
cannot
run dns of https measurements
however there are some papers that have
um already looked at that
so this is probably not something that
we would be looking into
although there have been as i said some
studies that already did that
all right thanks fiat in the interest of
time we're going to switch on thanks for
bringing work
that we scooped pam on you saw the
results here before they're in pam
which is one of the things that mary and
i try to do in this group is bring you
the measurement result before it's
published
so uh thanks a lot okay thanks so much
so we have phone up next and
just to prove that his share should work
there we go
okay so can you see my screen now okay
thank you and i'll start a timer and
i'll let you know if it's looking like
you're having trouble
uh without two minutes in okay
so hello everyone my name is fong i'm a
phd candidate at stony brook university
and today i will be presenting our paper
with the title assessing the privacy
benefits of
domain name encryptions and this is a
joint word with a researcher at stony
brook university umass amherst and
uiuc and the word were actually
presented last year in
asia ccs
um so we all know that like the
adoptions of 2s is
increasing in recent years and more and
more network traffic get encrypted on
the internet
and just to give you a send of uh how
much this has been increasing
this is the screenshot i just got
yesterday from less encrypt
and they showed us almost 250 million
fully qualified domain has supported 2x
connections
and regardless of the use of tos and
https domain name is the last piece of
information
that you know has not been encrypted yet
and the
domain name actually can be considered
as important as and sensitive as the
content is hosted
so for example this domain name
just based on the domain name you can
actually tell a user say
online shopping activities health
conditions
religions gender identities or even
sexual habits
so where is domain name actually exposed
on the why
so this slide shows you like two common
places where domain
information can be monitored by an on
pad attacker
and these are packets captured when
visiting example.com
so the first place where domain
example.com exposed is through dns
queries and responses
and after getting back the ip address of
example.com
the client initiates connection to
portfolio 3 starter 2s handshake
and this is the second place where
domain name information is exposed
and this is because in previous 2s
version until 1.2 the 2s handset take
place before the actual encryption
happens
so it exposed the domain name
information
um on an extension called server name
indication
so the exposure of domain name
information in these two places
allow any on bad attacker
to tamper with user connections a
malicious attacker can
redirect a user to a destination where
malware is hosted or
state sponsor sensor can interfere with
user connections
based on the domain information seeing
on the dns or
sni field and so for the rest of this
presentation
i will first introduce the basic concept
of domain name
encryptions protocols and the
motivations behind austerity
the methodologies that we use to conduct
our measurement and then i will show the
analysis on the privacy benefit
provided by domain name encryptions due
to domain co-hosting
and the dynamics of domain-to-ib mapping
and finally i will discuss the potential
approaches for domain owners and hosting
providers
to help with increasing the privacy
benefit of
domain name encryptions so to address
the previous security and privacy
problems
of plaintext domain being exposed on the
y
domain encryption has been suggested in
several proposals
with dot com first and
here dns queries and responses will be
transmitted over
a 2s channel and with doh dns
resolutions you perform over uh https
and of course they're going to be
through port
443 instead of 853
and therefore inheriting all of the
security and benefits of
https protocol and finally starting with
2s version 1.3 the server name
indications extensions in the client
hello message
during the 2s handshake can be encrypted
and with this proposal the domain name
information
on both dns and ts handshake traffic
can can be secured so in this new
setting
a user and the dns resolver first
established a channel
um and this is an encrypted channel it
can be over https or
over 2s and after that all of dns
queries and respond as sent over this
channel
and similarly during the 2s handshake
process unlike in previous cos version
sim version 1.3 their server name
indication
will be encrypted too i mean this is an
optional option it's not compensate
so in the rfc say that it's it's
optional so
this news protocol will prevent any
unpat observer from seeing
plain tech domain name on the wire
so however in this new setting the
attacker can still see the ip address
of the destination server so actually on
this slide that ip address is the actual
ip address of example.com
so now the attacker will try to guess
okay if this
ip hosts only example.com or any other
website
so here come the motivations of our
study um given that the destination ip
addresses are still visible on path
to unpack observer we are interested in
uh quantifying the potential improvement
to user privacy
um that a full deployment of domain name
and christian could achieve
in in practice and the extent to which
the insurance can be easily met depend
on two factors
first whether all the domains are hosted
on the same ip address or not
and second the statability of mapping
between a given domain and it's hosting
ip address over time
so here's the experiment setup so we
first
create a set of test domain by
aggregating domains from alexis and
majestic top list
from the last 30 days that
give us a set of around 7.5 million
domains per day
and next we perform an active dns
measurements to resolve these domains
into ip addresses and finally we
analyzed
all of the domain to ib mappings and
study their co-hosting degree and the
dynamics of
domain to ibm mappings over a period of
two months
and since many domains and are hosted on
cdns uh
which is you know they map the domain to
ip
uh to different ip at different location
so we conduct our experiment across
nine different vantage points as shows
on the map
so we try to distribute our vantage
point in the way that their geographical
distance and maximize
from each order now to capture the cdn
behavior
if there's any and so we conduct our
measurement for periods of two months to
examine
the dynamics of domain to ib mappings
over time
so let's go back to the attack scenario
in which
the attacker can only see the ip address
of
the destination uh server so given an ip
address
there are two hosting possibilities the
first one we prefer to as single hosted
in which a domain is exclusively hosted
on
one or more ip addresses that
do not host any other server on the
order domain
so in this case let's call k is the
co-hosting degree
then the co-hosting degree of
example.com and all of this
associated ip address is one
and we refer to this hosting scenario
as privacy detrimental this is because
uh from
an adversary point of view only
you know seeing connections to this ip
address alone is enough to infer which
domain is being visited
and for the second possibility we prefer
to as mundi hosted
in which an ip address holds more than
one domain
and in this case example.com say
is hosted on one or more ip address
ip addresses that also host many other
domains
so the co-hosting degree for an ip
address in this case
is the number of domain hosted on it
and for the co-hosting degree of
example.com
we compute by taking the median of the
co-hosting degree across
all the ip addresses example.com is
hosted on
and for this case we refer to a privacy
beneficial case because from the
adversary point of view
they cannot easily say okay just by
seeing the ip address they cannot say
which domain is actually being visited
because everything else were encrypted
so analyzing our data we found
2.2 million unit ip addresses
of which 70 percent holds only one
domain names
so this mean visitor of domain hosted on
this addresses
will not gain any privacy benefit by
domain name encryption
because of the one-to-one mapping
between the domains and ip address
and the rest 30 of ip addresses holds
more than
one domains however when considering the
number of
unit domains so this plot is showing
the number of unit ip address but when
we look at the number of unit domains
this seventy percent uh of ib
addresses correspond to only 1.4 million
domain which is like 90
of our test data and the rest thirty
percent of ib address
hosts six point one million domains um
with its more than eighty percent of uh
domains of uh in our study which which
shows some
co-hosting degree uh among uh this group
of six point one 6.1
millions domains so next we analyze the
hosting degree
as the percentage of all domains so 90
of domains are single hosted which means
this domain will will not get any
privacy benefit uh
from domain encryption and the rest uh
eighty percent
uh sorry the rest eighty percent um
eighty percent of
domains uh are co-hosted with more than
one domain
and however you know like they're around
40 percent
here of co-hosted domain
host with less than 10 domains as we
we move um toward the right-hand side
the hosting degree
increase and so there's the privacy
benefit so we assume that
the co-hosting degree k need to be
greater than
a hundred to provide some meaningful
privacy because an adversary in this
case can only correctly guess
a domain being visited with a
probability less than
one percent so according to this plot
only about thirty percent
of domain will gain some meaningful
privacy benefit from domain name
encryption because they go hosted with
more than 100
domains so we investigate the top 10
hosting providers that offer the highest
score hosting degree
per ip address as shows in the third
column right here
the average number of unit ip addresses
observed for each
provider is very low um with half
of the hosting uh would have i'm hosting
all domains
on a single ip address and we use the
heuriken
electrics bgb toolkit to
confirm that this provider is actually
very small providers with many of them
managing
less than 10 000 ip address allocated by
their
regional internet authorities and when
looking at the popularities of domain
hosted on this provider
as shows in the last column the highest
rank one is
at 386 positions hosted on squarespace
why more than half of these providers
host domain at well below
top ten thousands so the takeaway here
is that
small providers um tend to host a large
number of less popular domains on a
small number
of ip and then we investigate the top
co-hosting degree
the co-hosting degree by major providers
that dominate the largest number of unit
ip addresses
so this two table lists the top 20 major
hosting cdn providers
with more than 5 000 unit ib address
that we observe
so unlike small hosting provider the
majority
provider the major provider hosts more
popular domain
and as you can see in the last column
most in popular domain hosted by this
provider are
well within the top ten thousands uh
rank
however in contracts to the small
providers the co-hosting degree per ip
address
offered by this provider is is quite low
except for
cloudflare in this case with the
co-hosting degree of 16
domains per ip address that we see from
our experiment
the rest of the providers host
let's say less than 10 domain per ip
address
so this observation show that major
providers
host more popular domain but having a
much
lower co-hosting degree so
the previous two plot you got sorry i
just want to let you know you've got two
minutes
two minutes okay so the previous uh two
slides show the true end of a privacy
spectrum that
on the right hand side um there's
there's domain that co-hosted less
popular domain that co-hosted on
uh together with you know benefit from
the domain christians
but on the right hand side there's more
popular domain but they're not co-hosted
with any
other uh domains and thirst you know
receive less privacy benefit from domain
name encryption
um so let me skip this line um okay
so let's go to the dynamic of domain to
ib mapping so we conduct our measurement
over two-month period and we see that
you know like
there's 22.7 million domain to ip
mappings and
the dynamics uh 80 of them
are very dynamic which means they
survive for only four days
and um only 13
of them are stable however if we look at
the number of unit domains
there's only two 0.2 million domains
that are
dynamic and the rest 92 percent of the
domain
are very stable so the takeaway is most
domain are hosted on static ip address
doesn't change over time so in summary
you know regardless of the trend of core
locations on the web domain
encryption cannot really provide
meaningful privacy benefit with
the current degree of domain um to
uh domain co-hostings in the ip address
information can still
uh visible to any unpacked observer
and um to that end we make these two uh
recommendations uh sorry three first
their full domain
name confidentiality must be preserved
on both dns and 2s channel
otherwise neither technology can provide
actual privacy benefit
just like via says in the previous
presentation that the adoption of dlt is
very low
and you we can see more more of that in
duh but still like the es and i
adoption out there is still really small
only cloudflare right now supporting it
and for the main owner they can seek
providers
that offer a high co-hosting degree per
ip address
or you know like high dynamic domain to
ip mappings
and finally hosting provider can help
increase the co-hosting degree by
grouping more websites
under the same ip or frequently rotate
domain to ip mappings
to further improve privacy benefit
offered by domain name encryption
and thanks for your attentions and we
we make our data set available in this
url
on the slide you can get it it's
publicly available
and if you have any questions feel free
to um send it to my email
thank you thanks thanks a lot phong okay
so
you can reach phong at that address uh
we've got a couple people in the queue
let's take them
that'll be andrew and eric uh let's make
it quick because we only have an hour
meeting here
um and uh and then we'll switch to robin
so andrew go ahead
yeah hi thanks brother i was very
interesting uh
presentation and and uh good good robust
data i just wanted to highlight a couple
of us made a point um
in the uh chat uh that uh uh
i think yeah you made a good case for
for the privacy
benefits of uh co-location and so on
uh or using cdns um did you consider
though the potential uh privacy risks
um and also security risks uh of
increased centralization
uh because potentially europe if you're
encouraging centralization to get
privacy
but you also sacrifice privacy with
centralization so i don't know if you've
given that any thought
at all thank you yeah actually this is
uh
another another paper that actually we
wrote last year submit to
nds math web about centralizing all of
the dns query just to a single resolver
like a lot of privacy
controversial happening especially with
cloudflare and firefox uh
to me that is terrible too like we don't
want to give all of our you know
browsing history just to one single
resolver
um say cloudflare so to me like this is
orthogonal to what i just
present here but uh in terms of dns
queries um
in in the paper in another paper we
suggest that we should split them out
distributed across number resolver so
that you know your browsing history
is not known by just a single actor
so yes centralization is terrible
thanks well that's my cue i think
uh erica scorland there's a lot um
so um we actually did look at what you
suggest in terms of spamming the
uh queries across multiple solvers the
problem is then every resolver gets a
copy of a partial copy of your browsing
history and given how much redundancy
the browsing this tradition makes the
problem worse not better
um so if you have a fix for that i'd be
interested in hearing it um
the um but the reason i got up actually
was um
uh to ask um um martin thompson and
yaryarco how to document this actually
um and ted hardy i believe um so uh the
reason i got up actually was to is to
ask
um uh have you done any assessment on
the uh
sort of relative impact of of you know
uh um the actual size of the
anonymity set so i mean like in some
cases 10 is quite good right if it's
like facebook
and you know telegram that actually
conceal intelligence traffic and
facebook is quite valuable
um on the other hand um um and also um
there's uh i think a question about how
much does reducing
an enemy set help with traffic analysis
attacks um because i know there's been a
lot of work on that and those typically
don't work well if you have a very large
number of days but
quite well when you have a small number
of domains
cool yeah um so thank you for the
questions so
in terms of sensitivity of a website
it's really
debatable here like what should we
consider sensitive what is not
and you know like if you go to just an
ip within the range of say
the as google you would whatever you use
youtube google map or whatever gmail
people don't really care but uh for in
term of sensitives um
the anonymity set here sometimes a set
can be a hundred and
if just one of them in their sensitive
then that whole set can be really
sensitive
um actually we have a follow-up work on
this and we actually
do traffic analysts on a single website
per website
um and for 200 we analyze 200 000
uh website include half of them are
popular and half of them are sensitive
websites
and just based on the ip address you can
pinpoint
more than 90 90 percent precisely
what even like the sensitive website in
the long tail
with the k anonymity really high but you
can still pinpoint
um with really high precisions based
just on the ip address
okay thanks guys um i'm sorry i have to
cut you off um we're doing this
experiment with these hour-long meetings
if you
write the chairs between the meetings if
you think we should do something
different
uh and i'm sorry i dropped eric from the
queue just because we're gonna be
we're gonna run a couple minutes over um
so that we can keep the
session links for the other two
presenters thanks a lot fong
um robin can you can you open your
slides or do you need me to do it
we're seeing your whole screen okay
yep thanks looks good go ahead i'll
start a timer and i'll let you know when
you have a minute left
all right so let's talk q log again um
so q log stands for quick logging which
is an effort started about two years ago
to make
the new quicken h3 protocols a bit
easier to debug
and analyze because typically what you
would do is you would take a
network packet capture at some point and
then use something like wireshark to
analyze that
and that's of course still possible with
quick but more difficult because
quick encrypts almost its entire
transport layer
as well so to do this you would have to
store the entire packet capture
including the full payload
leading to some scalability and privacy
issues i'm sure some of you have
experienced this with
encrypted application layer protocols in
the past as well
there's a second long-standing problem
with this and that is that not all
aspects of the protocol are reflected on
the wire
for example for transport things like
congestion control typically aren't seen
and so difficult to analyze so the
solution that we proposed for quick was
to instead move to logging at the end
points directly in the implementations
themselves
the core thing there is that we propose
to do this in a standardized way so it
is a single format a single schema
that all of the implementations follow
making it easier to create
reusable tooling and also to share data
in between and that's of course not
rocket science it's
relatively simple as you can see here
for now we are using json as a
serialization format
and we just define you know if you want
to log receive packets these are the
fields that you should log
if you want to do something with
congestion control on the right side
these are the fields that
you should log in this is what they
should look like and so on
using this across implementations is
powerful because then we can build some
tools
which we have done in what is called the
qvis project
giving us for example this kind of
sequence diagram showing packets going
back and forth
and also the metadata on the
implementations but also
quite powerful congestion control
debugging tools quite interesting
because in quick it's it's
much easier to experiment with different
gesture controllers
over time this approach of having a
shared format
and reusable tools has turned out quite
interesting and powerful
leading to the majority of the quick
implementations actually outputting
this format most notably facebook is
using this in production
to help analyze their deployment of
quick and hp3 at scale
because of this relative success um we
now have plans to adopt
qlog in the quick working group uh they
have been uh
separate drafts until now but so we're
moving to adoption soon
and our goal there is not just to flash
this out for quick and h3
but also to start looking at how we can
bring this to
different protocols and different use
cases as well
because as you can imagine this type of
approach can be very useful not just for
quicken h3
but also for example the things that
we've listed below here
one particular one i wanted to highlight
this is the bottom one
where we have a project that we are
trying to log both
very high level adaptive bitrate video
streaming
algorithm metadata together with the
relatively low level quick
adjust control parameters to try and
assess how we can better
match them up against each other
i think from a research perspective and
that's why i want to bring this to the
map rg
i think this approach will make it much
easier to compare different
implementations of protocols
which in my opinion is something that is
often severely lacking in the
academic research community to date i
also think it would be
much easier to make it much easier to
share data sets and to
reuse them or revalidate results and
then my hope is also that we might
in this way get a bit more access to
actual production or deployment level
data sets
if they can be properly anonymized first
of course
for example facebook has concretely
indicated interest
in exposing a larger data set
with of course all the salient data
removed again
to make it easier to do actual research
on real life network
data which i think is a bit lacking as
well
or at least difficult to get access to
for the broader community
one example of that is is christian
ritama who has already done something
similar using public
q logs from the quick interoperability
servers
so they have their public servers they
expose their key logs
for for debugging purposes and he
already tried to to measure for example
what are realistic
packet loss patterns and what are
causing them
using these public key logs um
thanks robin can you wrap it up yeah
this is the last slide
um cool so i would say if you're in any
way interested in this type of thing
join us in the quick working group
or let us know on github thank you
okay a quick question or comment
um thanks thanks robin for bringing that
update and accommodating our tight
schedule
uh and and uh pointing people to that
tool
all right so let's get uh so we're gonna
run about 10 minutes over here
and oh we got uh let's pee
yeah we got pete ready to go we're about
10 minutes over you guys got a half an
hour until the next itif meeting if you
want to catch one so
apologies for running late um pete i'm
gonna
approve your screen share
all right you got the slides yep it's up
and i'll set the timer for 10 minutes
and you're ready to go
thank you all right welcome to the ecn
deployment observations talk i'm pete
heist and i'll try to move through these
slides briskly in case there's a
question or two at the end
we've got jonathan morton here as well
for that part if needed
so why did we go to the trouble of
gathering data on ecn at an isp's border
router
well there are a few questions we'd like
to answer for ecn engineering
for endpoints we'd like to know what
proportion of flows are easy and capable
and how many clients are initiating ecn
for middle boxes we'd like to know what
proportion of paths appear to have 3168
marking aqms so we know to what extent
future experiments need to take that
into account
we'd also like to know about any
unexpected uses of the ecn field
since the signaling methods and failure
modes are crucial for effective
congestion control
my cautionary note here is we think of
this study as informative rather than
authoritative given its size and fixed
location however
some of the results should still be
useful and suggestive
so some basic facts about the isp where
data was collected these numbers give
some sense of scale
in any case i'm grateful to freenet
libidets for running my scripts and
collecting the data for me on their
production gateway
so how do we actually collect this data
we use linux iptables and ipsets
ipsets are essentially in kernel hash
tables using a specified key of interest
like ip address or ipn port and mapping
to a packet and byte count
the nice thing about them is that the
quantity of data produced is relatively
small
and easy to process and also you have
fewer privacy concerns than with packet
captures
as we're just counting packets meeting
certain criteria
on the other hand we don't know the
benefit of deeper packet inspection or
flow level analysis so there are some
questions we can't answer
like exactly what applications are
setting the bits
for performance we avoided anything that
could cause a hash table lookup per
packet
as some lab test caution does against
doing that in production so
that leaves us without much detail on
not ect packets which we can mostly live
without
so here's what we observed from the
endpoints there are two main things to
take away from this
one is that ecn initiation seemed
relatively low but also fairly
widespread
and the second is that server acceptance
appeared high
starting with the servers that should be
easy to explain as most server os's have
supported ecm acceptance for some time
now
start as for the clients since we
consider an ecn synag coming back to an
ip as indication that the ip has
initiated ecn
that 44 number may be a bit too high as
a proxy for the percentage of ips truly
using ecn
as port scanning or other unforeseen
sources of vcn synapse drive that number
up
for a rough sense of the distribution
though around 35 percent of ips received
at least
one thousand ecn synax which is still a
pretty high percentage relative to the
percentage of flows that are likely to
be ecn capable
now on to how we detect aqm activity at
a gateway or middle box ece is sometimes
a more reliable indicator of congestion
than ce
because if we have an aqm downstream
from the gateway we won't see any ce
marks since they happen after packets
have already passed through the gateway
but we'll see the reflected ece marks in
any case providing the transport headers
aren't encrypted
so we mainly look for non-zero ect 0 in
both directions and non-zero ec
in either direction however we did see
some anomalies in the signaling data
that appear to come from the os
fingerprinting routines of port scanners
to help explain how we attempt to filter
these out with the ip in the middle here
ending at 140.73
we have ce and ece marks with a ratio
close to one to one which
doesn't look like aqm activity what we
do is
if the ece the ce ratio is greater than
two to one we consider it possible aqm
activity
if it's less than two to one we subtract
the ec marks from the
ones in the opposite direction and if
there are any left over we consider it
possible aqm activity otherwise we don't
the detection isn't perfect there may be
false positives and negatives but we can
also say that
we likely missed some make you amps
because we need both ecn flows and
congestion to find them
and as we'll see on the next slide that
doesn't appear to be that easy
so now we want to take a look at given
that ecn was negotiated how often was
any aqm activity actually detected
first i should point out we have some
known aqms deployed namely fqcoddle is
being used for two subnets
since i helped break the scripts to
deploy these aqms you might say
pete you've affected the outcome of the
results and that is true
but it turns out that the knowledge of
aqm deployment also gives a better look
at what the stats look like when there
is a known aqm
and helps us pin down how well we're
detecting aqms but we do not include
these known aqm subnets along the
so-called
random paths since we influenced them
so what we did here is split the ips
into those that pass through a known aqm
and those that do not
in the table we see that 60 of ecn
negotiating user ips with a node aqm
saw possible aqm activity which roughly
represents our detection rate
well after observations for three weeks
why isn't our detection rate 100 percent
that's very likely because as noted
before you need both an ac uncapable
flow and congestion to see it so we
simply might miss it
especially if there are aqms and devices
that don't often see congestion
next that 10.3 value in amber that's our
rough proxy for the percentage of
random paths that may have an aqm
deployed
assuming that we've missed them at the
same rate as the known pass we could
arguably scale that up from ten percent
to about one and six
but to be more conservative we haven't
done that here
finally given that we've probably not
classified all the aqm activity
correctly and that we've missed some
aqms
ten percent plus or minus an order of
magnitude is about what we can reliably
say
as for ecn endpoints set for non-tcp
protocols i'll go through this
relatively quickly but
unlike tcp the data for non-tcp is less
clearly attributable to ecn because we
apparently observed at least some misuse
of the field
for one the proportion of marks from the
wan is higher than one would expect
even taking into account the ten to one
ratio of traffic between the wan and lan
and also note that we saw one ip with
clear misuse of the currently
unallocated ect1 which accounted for
some
97 of the ect1 usage in total
that could potentially have been a large
peer-to-peer download download from this
configured peer but in any case
this confirms that at least occasional
and sometimes spectacular misuse of the
ecn field does happen
so what are the possible reasons for ecn
use on non-tcp protocols at all
there could be tunnel dcn traffic but
since there are different methods of
encapsulation of the ecn field and since
those can be asymmetric it's hard to say
based on the ports we saw in use like
ipsec net traversal and wireguard
we almost certainly saw tunnel traffic
but tunnel dc in traffic we can't say
definitively
and this study didn't look at protocols
not supported by contract
which for example includes ipsec esp
packets using ip protocol number 50.
there was some discussion on the list
that we could be seeing quick ecn here
that's also a possibility in at least
one ip despot pair we saw but again we
can't say for sure without deeper packet
inspection
we think there's very likely to be
misuse of the ecn feel going on here and
we speculate by
bit torrent traffic the now obsolete rfc
1349 defines a value for
minimized monetary cost that conflicts
with ect 0
and if a developer also forgets to shift
that absolute value to the left by one
they might end up with an ect one as
well
we did we did not see extensive
marketing on non-tcp traffic overall but
what we did see is that misuse of the
ecn field can be expected
from time to time
so thanks for listening and if anyone
wants to repeat this experiment
somewhere else i'll try to help support
that
it should be possible to scale the
collection script up to larger networks
but
it should first undergo another revision
to address some of the limitations
mentioned in the draft
so with that i i don't know if you have
any time left for questions so i'll
leave that up to the chairs
uh thanks a lot pete uh we don't have
anyone in queue i think i'd like to cut
it just because we're running ten
minutes over
um i really appreciate you guys fitting
into our just hour-long meeting
uh and maria any closing thought no
okay i think okay go ahead
thanks for joining us thanks for joining
everyone we had about 135 people
uh really nice uh i would love to know
if you if
what you think about the meeting length
we did these two one-hour meeting
experiments
to try to throw as much as quickly as
can we can as possible to you
but we can certainly do something else
next time
take care have a good week bye
you