okay
my various clocks say it is the top of
the hour
this is joel halpern with bruno de crane
and jim gashard your three spring
chairs we are starting the second spring
session using the agenda as per posted i
hope we can manage to stay
on time we did a good job the first time
but still we want
conversation and discussion okay bruno
shall we go to
uh the replication segment slides and
daniel
you're up
yup good morning it's then
i will be presenting on behalf of the
author and update
so last time i uh we presented this work
it was in
in 2019 march 2019 i believe
since then we uh we started
a charlotte a little bit the authorless
as you can
see but we added that behind us there's
a lot of uh
heavy contributor i just want to call
out like i i think i saw
um andrew stone and and tax
this morning so those are av
contributors also behind us and behind
this work
uh okay we can go to the next slide
so that's my kind of an update on the
update
there are a lot of different pieces of
this work that
are progressing in different other
working groups
and since we've been able to have
working group adoption here
it unlocked the working group adoption
of the other piece of work in the
different working groups
that are shown here we recently
last year i also brought the mvpn
one that you can see there that is
adopted on the best
and that's kind of an iptv type of use
cases for the people that run
mvpn there we recently also
added uh the last one there is the ping
like a way to validate the tree
uh that where it's fairly new and it's
uh it's been
pushed into the paint working group
the pce is uh under conversations we're
progressing there too
and the idr is also something that we're
pressing progressing as well
we can move to the other slide
okay so really the update here is that
it's very simple we we just decided to
add this obvious x to the replication
segment
and more precisely uh we added like
the n replicate function that you can
see in the first paragraph
um but the essential in in compliance to
the network programming
framework that is now an rfc
but really what it means is is is
nothing different than
the mechanics uh brought up by the sr
mps version of the dragon
the first three versions covered at the
sr mps here
and really what's new here in the in the
context of the uh
replication uh is really an
encapsulation function that is done at
the root node
uh to encapsulate the s obviously
application so that is the
the uh n indicated function now that
works exactly the same
as it is in the sr nps where you have
the replication set label that
is associated to an application segment
that somewhere
along the side of the network you will
hit the replication node will decap and
then process
the host so we need nothing really
different from a mechanic perspective
we can move to slide four
all right so more specific about the n
replication function here
so that's a function that is local to
the replication node as you can see it
is associated to the replication cell
that will
serve in replicating the data towards
the lease
i have an example coming it
it will enable uh it is enabled on the
node where
it will replicate the incoming traffic
towards the
the lee for the other and the
destination uh
ipv6 uh host that's pretty much what
it is it's exactly the same as the
empress as i was saying
the leaf it would perform in the
encapsulation and forward the traffic
directly to the end hose
now we can move to slide five
now the text bottom top left
is the semantic about what's going on
with the drawing and then the
the bottom right is really what's
happening in this example
this example uh is been
it's the one that just to stick current
with what was presented by humanity
working group it's the
it's the uh example using the three
uh uh topology to explain this example
but there's also another way we can do
the same thing
which is the spray model now we just
chose to
use the tree version and it's pretty
easy to follow with the text that we've
put
there so basically the node one
here is the root and then the node 2 is
the replication point
node 5 6 and 7 are the leaves
and then node 3 and node 4 are just
transit node
in the context of srv6 they could be
just
ipv6 node and then it will go through
the routing extension
the routing header so they don't do
anything with
node three and four in this context um
at node two it will replicate towards
the leaf five
six and seven and at six and five and
seven it will decap and remove the srh
and then forward the traffic directly to
the destination
according to the ipv6 destination
address
and that's pretty much it we can go to
slide six
and open for question well i hope you
uh you were able to hear what i was
saying that beautiful speech and i was
not on mute or something
you were audible daniel and
understandable
no problems i'm not seeing anybody in
the queue
going once going twice
let's move to midpoint protection i'm oh
you're up
hello everyone can you hear me yes we
can thank you
so today i'm going to talk about srt
middle point protection next page
so in this latest version we updated the
section 1
introduction and we also made some
editorial
changes in this updated document
we described the problems we are going
to resolve
and also compare the difference between
our solution and the other existing
solutions
first let's look at the problem we're
going to resolve
with node n fails
this upstream node p as a plr
will do the fastway route so in this
case
we provide protections for
the node n failures however
after the igb convergence
the other nodes will remove
the routes to load the end with because
enemies failed
for example node b after igp convergence
b removes routes
to node n so from this point
the traffic will get dropped
until a new srt
routes will pass to to see
is installed so we can see
from the point itp converges
until a new path is
installed during this period of time
traffic will get lost
so this our
draft will propose a solution to resolve
these problems so the rough idea of our
solution is that
for any node such as p
if this node can provide
capability to do the proxy forwarding
then this node will advertise
its capabilities
so all the answer nodes will use
the rows to the capable
nodes after
node fails for example node b will use
the routes to p
for node ends sees
after fails so in this way
even bgp after pdp convergence
and then we can still provide
protections
that's roughly our solution there is
another
solution which is adopted last year
which is called a spring segment
protection srt
path so that's a informational
so the idea of data java is that
for every node or for some node
they will provide some extra functions
the function is that
the node will accept some kind of
configurations
for example this time computer configure
time
during this time will hold the routes
all the wrongs
to node so if that node supports that
functions
so after configuration and then if all
the nodes in the network can provide
this function and then hold up
hold off the rows for some
period of time even that node failed
and then they can provide some uh the
protections
however if some of the nodes
do not support these functionalities
and then we may not provide protections
during this period from rgb convergence
to the new road
new path is resolved so our solution
provides enhancements to the exision
solutions
so we'll let's look at more details the
next page
so also basically our solution provide
more coverages
and in addition our solution also
provides protections
for the binding segments our node when
that node fails
so first because for each of the node we
if that
if that node can support a proxy
forwarding
and then we that node will advertise
f uh capability for that
for that functions so all they are
so all the other notes we receive
the discovery for those node and then it
will
send the routes a cinder center package
to the least
capable nodes when
one node fails next to that node
so this may provide more protections
even though some of the node
doesn't support the functions
i know just a moment has been trying to
ask a question and
i'm not sure which slide it's on so
you ask
[Music]
yeah so my question um uh
uh is that so you mentioned that um uh
in the previous slide you mentioned that
uh
the draft ietf spring segment protection
srt paths has provided a solution
but your you are pointing out that
because that draft is informational so
somebody may not
implement it so are you suggesting that
trap should be made standard
do you think that will solve the problem
or what is the
that's another problem i mean the
problem is that
uh if some of the lows
do not support your draft right
so even though you either standard and
then maybe some notes
don't support you your function and then
some notes may not support your function
right
yes so if some node does not support
this function uh
uh uh then it may not um
the behavior of the uh network won't be
any worse
than uh uh you know
not having supported it to having
supported it right so
um uh so the solution is to
you know uh make that note to support
this uh draft is it so
so i i see that you are proposing an
alternate
uh where there is uh there is a proxy
for every
node there is a proxy so to me it seems
like it's
it has lot of operational overheads so
now operator has to configure
which node is a proxy for which one
right no no no no no no
no no no not that way so this one just
uh as soon as that node have capability
and then for always adjacent node i need
to wear device data capabilities in one
bit
don't need this for don't need to
configure uh
for example for p which other configure
this one is capable
and then we don't need to configure this
p is capable for
n for n1 and then for p1 no just
configure this
capable and then p will advertise one p
one one flat
indicate that p is capable to d to
proxy to do the proxy work yeah so i'm
not able to get what is the advantage so
the problem you pointed out is if
b doesn't support uh draft iatf spring
segment protection srt paths then it's a
problem
but if b doesn't support this midpoint
failure draft it's the same problem
right and this can do more because
for example we know which node is
capable and then we can send that
traffic along those nodes which are
capable and then we can
even so we can we have some those don't
support this capability
and then we can provide more coverages
compiled to just uh keep the older
routes
to not end with no damn fails i think we
need some discussion on the list on this
because i'm having trouble parsing
whether the real difference is the
capability flag or whether there's a
real difference in these solutions
and no i don't want you to to sort that
out right this minute
but i do think we need to discuss it
with the whole working group on the list
that makes sense yes okay
another another before you go on
bruno had a question okay okay
go ahead bruno bruno speaking as in an
individual
i have a comment i may have a comment on
terminology
which may also help on the previous
discussion
and as far as i understand
we talk about protection for behavior
which is pre-computed
at which which is done before the rgb
convergence
whereas uh i understand that your
proposition is behaving
after or during the igp convergence
in which case in general we call about
restoration
uh so if it's a correct understanding uh
that would help
uh make a distinction between the draft
from uh
its spring segment protection on your
draft
because they would one would speak about
protection while the other one
deals with restoration
yeah i think for the for the existing
draft
so they the astronauts don't know
one node don't know the other node
whether they have this capability
so he they so we just use the
old node all the routes to fail the node
for some time but our node
have more information about which node
is capable
and then we can send the traffic
along those nodes with capable and then
we have more chance
to get the traffic to
the node next to the phase of the road
we can provide the
protections even though some of the
nodes do not support
these functionalities
okay is there more you wanted to cover
because this is all of your slides and
we're
we've taken your ten minutes
yeah another enhancement is that we
provide protections for the binding
segments
on a node when that node fails and then
i think the existing draft
to mount does not support these
functions the
second bullet imported finding segment
protections so we provide
those protections
[Music]
okay thank you
let's move on to the next presentation
on segment routing for redundancy
protection
uh i'm not sure whether fun or zhu song
is
going to present but whichever you is
planning to present
please go ahead it looks like fun go
ahead fan
hi thank you um
um this actually this topic is includes
two
two jobs one is the segment routing for
the
redundancy protection and another one is
srh extension for this uh redundancy
protection
um so i will i will cover uh both
both drafts there next please
yeah just very brief introduction to the
redundancy protection
um it is it actually it is one of the
mechanism to achieve the service
protection
and it follows the prince the prey off
prince
so there is an example scenario there
that
when when the when the flow comes to the
um
there are there are two nodes one is the
red and once the merge
when the flow when the flow is sent to
the red node
and the red node to replicate the flow
into two into two
copies and send the two copies uh
from different paths respect
respectively
and when the merged node received the uh
received the first packet of each
sequence number
uh yeah i forgot on the redundancy node
and
there yeah
on the r1 or on the redundancy node uh
there is a flow id and the sequence
number are marked there
on the traffic on the packet and when
the
when the package when the first package
of each sequence number is received on
the merge node
it will be sent to the to the to the r2
and the other no other package
means the redundant packet will be
dropped
i will give more explanation about this
uh procedure there
later next please
and to support the redundancy perception
that we define this
uh several new new things there
and first is the redundancy segment it
is a new segment defined for the
redundancy note
and there's also the new behavior of
this redundancy
of this segment is defined um the second
is the merging segment
it is the segment used on the merging
node and with the
behavior of the of this segment is
defined
and to support the to to identify the
unique flow or
identify the packet sequence within one
flow
that there is uh flow identification the
sequence number
uh is defined there and
and last there is a redundancy policy it
is the
it is the uh it is a variant of the
sr policy and it is used uh
it is associated with the redundancy
segment
uh when the redund segment is is um
is executed there and the difference
between the redundancy policy
and and other normal sr policy is
it includes more than one other list of
the segment
and all of this other list of the
segment will be used at the same time
next
and we have the update since uh we have
the update the
the draft system etf um
yeah yeah i think actually i i think i
i refined the this is not the the latest
version of
uh of my presentation uh but i will try
to
explain there uh actually we we designed
the process
and of course update the the
specification of the redundancy
segment modding segment and the
encapsulation of the flow identification
sequence number and also add some
description of the
uh redundancy policy and yeah we also
split the segment description
into uh two parts one is the sr npr's
another part is as our v6
next
yeah as i mentioned that redundant
segment is updated
so it is updated as a variant of the
bounding seat
if we use the abundances that there you
can set
a whole list for the for the service
from the
from the ingress of the sr uh ingress
node of the sr domain
so uh there's also some um
some uh since it is it is defined as a
variant of binding seeds so there is a
change on the suitable node
a suit code and
another another big change is we
decouple the replication behavior
and the marking of the flow
identification and the sequence number
we think that these two um
these two behaviors once the application
another is the marking they are not
necessarily uh
bounded together um but it depends on
the
um on the other choice uh on the
deployment
choice i i give the the the two
choices i give the two uh i give the
examples of the two choices later uh in
the later slides
uh so here that um but
since uh from the uh
actually after we updated this uh draft
and we also received the comments from
uh from others so we actually
we define actually we should refine the
suit code later on and
i will i will not explain the suit code
here
because it will be refined later and
maybe we can just go to the next slide
and to explain the
yeah also the merging node the update is
we
specified that how to define how to
determine the pac
if the packet is redundant packet or not
uh because the sequence number is there
there
is used to uh to diff to determine
uh the pac uh the package is redundant
or not
and there is a there's a um there's a
suggestion that to
to use it to look up a local table there
but it's not um yeah it just give an
example that
uh the sequence can be uh
done in this way to the to determine the
the package is redundant or not
yes next please
um here we take the srv6 as an example
to explain the process of the redundancy
protection and i give here i give two
choices
two options there the difference of the
two options
of the the options are
whether we assign the flow id
and to generate the sequence number at
the
inc at the r
[Music]
and at the ingress note of the srv6
node or at a specific redundancy node
um when there when the redundancy node
is
not not the first node not the ingress
node of the
of the srv6 domain so
if we in this option that we assign this
flow id and generate the sequence number
at the
ingress node and it is not the
redundancy redundancy node
so this information will be kept as the
optional trv
the in the in the ipv6 header and
the packet is transmitted to redundancy
node and redundancy
node is a triggered is a bonding
bounding seat and this so it
added uh so if the bond is introduced
with the encapsulation mode
and there will be another ipv6 header
added
and in this case
the uh the segment list is
the is the redundancy is the r node
is the r and r3 or r and r4
and sin because why we are not including
these
merging node m here um because the mod
the one when the sequence number and
flow id are used in the merging node
and it's it will need the the
flow identification sequence number uh
in the ipv6
in the inner ipv6 header um or maybe
there's another
there's another alternative to use it
and you can also copy the
flow identif this optional trv from the
inner of
inner ipv6 header to the outer fpv6
header
when you do the redundancy note when
they do the
will perform the redundancy segment
uh it just uh the to to see there are
actually different choices different
options to define this
to to make this uh redundancy protection
work
okay before you go on to the next slide
fan
greg seems to have a question focused on
this material so it'd be good to let him
ask now
sure greg go ahead
so um if i understand correctly
what you're proposing you're proposing
uh support
uh um packet replication duplicate
elimination function
um as part of this um in a deadnet
um group uh there is a functionality
order preservation so
is it something that uh as well
you expect that merging node will do
order preservation
based on the sequence number
um in the current draft that we define
this
ordering as the optional function
currently we are focusing focusing on
the uh
replication and elimination part
but i think that is the that is some
something
that some work that we can do after we
finish these
uh finish the first phase
um greg if i may for a moment that does
raise the
more general point that given the
overlap and functionality between this
and
and the debt network we need to make
sure this is coordinated i'm not saying
it has to be done there i'm saying it
has to be coordinated though
yes and actually that yeah that's why in
my comment
i added.net uh to the distribution
list i had a question to this draft and
send this on the list
so you
implement something which is more
advanced than one plus one protection
so why do you think uh the complexity of
a pre-op function
has a benefit comparing to one plus one
protection
because oneplus 1 protection is much
simpler
the merging node selects the working
path
and one path is
backup the redundancy node
sends data on both paths and the merging
nodes
picks up data only from a working path
if the working path fails it switches to
the other feed here you do packet by
packet
selection from uh
two or more paths but
it comes with a lot of complexity
yeah but um actually i have i've never
um compared this to uh together because
there are
there are actually different mechanisms
um
yeah i i i i cannot
give you some um comparison result
about this because i've never um
considered they are they
they are they are the same or they have
the same effect
um yeah
but um i think i yeah maybe we can
discuss the in the middle list
yeah uh currently have left no answer
there
yeah thank you fair enough ron
ron if you have a question asked quickly
otherwise we're going to
move on to the next slides three i was
on mute
um this this proposal makes the merging
nodes stateful
the merging node has a finite amount of
memory to
maintain that state what happens when
that memory gets overrun
um what specific
um state do you mean i mean the to st
the state of the packet
a copy of it before
yeah i think that you mentioned there's
a actually there should be a sliding
window there
um i'm not sure if you mentioned this it
is
it is really related to the sliding
window that
how you compare the um yeah
how you compare the the the sequence
number with uh within the
amount of the amount of the package
right
well there is some policy stuff on later
slides ron i think we'll need to go into
more detail on this on the list
mock quickly we're running over time and
i want to give
fan the time to cover the rest of her
slides but go ahead mike
i think there uh there's a supposed to
be a controller to configure us
as a policy on the merchandise so you
should know
what's what's ability of the emerging
nodes so it will not let the
imaginary or overwrong if the memory
cannot support so many
flow so i think there need a way for the
for the container to to configure
whether
how many how many flows i can support on
the marginal
yeah i i agree i think that is something
um because this this draft is the only
current uh
cover the the data plane uh part i think
they must be have some
uh extra um yet they will have some
uh specification on on the part that
when
about about the issue john uh
raised it yes
uh next please
um so it is the updated one okay
uh yes the second option is the
difference is just when uh
where you you assign the flow id and the
sequence number
because on the on in this option that's
the flow identification the sequence
number is only used between the arm node
and the m node
so that's the two and two
um choices that you you can use this um
redundancy protection we'll use it from
end to end
or you use it as a part of the as a as a
kind of
uh service next please
yes and the second the second there's
another draft that we
we specified how the how the flow
identification and sequence number are
encapsulated in the uh in the in uh
in an srv srh optional trv
and so here we give this uh this
this proposal there and um
from the from the feedback from six men
that
they think that we should uh change this
draft
back to spring because spring has
already
uh can give these um
can have the uh
the power to give us the allocation of
this
optional tl srh optional tre
next please
yes here with that actually we we define
this
redundancy policy uh uh um
and through the tuple that there is a
redundancy node and redundancy id and
the margin node
there will be there are some more
details about this
uh the specification of the redundancy
policy
next please i think
yeah uh actually from the from last
since
last itf that we have already uh refined
this solution
and then we come back with the with the
optional
options of the solutions there and we we
try to refine this solution
and up and also specify the uh the isrh
encapsulation
and yeah i think that next step was
we'll specify the redundancy policy
another draft
with more details and
yes and we we want we want we seek for
the collaborations like
focusing on the uh uh segment
specification
in the sr and plc data plane and also
there are some
uh discussion has already been uh erased
there
in the mailing list about the flow id
flow flow identification the sequence
number
uh i would like to continue with the
discussion there
okay uh greg
you have a further question go ahead
in regard to your plans to do in srm pls
i can point to uh that net or in
mpls data plane that it already supports
uh packet replication uh duplicate
elimination and order preservation
function
so i think that
probably better to uh the discussion in
the deadnet working group
thank you okay
go ahead next question the first one is
about
all the ordering function actually we
have already considered that because it
has already been defined in the net
uh in this version we won't include it
because uh
for the simplest case the other is not
necessary for
merge node so perhaps in the following
versions we can
include the ordering functions to cover
more scenarios
and the second question about the
oneplus one protection
actually this redundant uh protection
can
provide a more uh high
provided service for more high
high ultra high requirement
applications because there is no packing
loss when the
when the uh when the flows is switched
from one part to the
standby path so that can require
satisfy the requirements for more uh
maybe
strict applications okay thank you
greg if you want one more go ahead and
then we've got to move on to the next
presentation
that i agree that uh packet replication
uh functionality uh minimizes the packet
loss
uh it might not
eliminate it completely and that's
basically the idea why that net
uh supports uh packet replication
function
uh but it comes at a cost
so that's why i i brought it up in my
earlier comment
so that uh compare the cost and then uh
versus the benefit
and as uh rowan correctly pointed out
it does create a state in the merging
node because especially
if you are doing order preservation
and packets can be reordered so
that comes with a lot of complexity
thank you okay
um zusang i don't think we can continue
this conversation we are
we're at twice the allocated time for
this so
we need to move on to the next item on
the on the agenda
yes strada is coming forward and uh
bruno if we can switch to the seamless
sr presentation
[Music]
yeah so um my name is shraddha hegde
from
juniper networks i would like to present
seamless sr
updates to seamless sr draft on behalf
of my co-authors
so we have presented this in ietf 108
and 109
and we got a comment that so the draft
had three sections use cases
requirements and solution
so we got a comment that you know uh the
use cases and requirements should be a
separate document so
in zero five version we split the
document into two one
document is covering use cases and
requirements and another document is
covering um
solutions next slide please
yeah so the first one is talking about
the requirements and use cases
the second one is about the solution
next slide please
so uh just a recap of uh
the basic uh motivation for this
seamless sr architecture so
when the large networks organized into
multiple domains
and uh you know
seamless mpls kind of architecture gives
an end-to-end path across these multiple
domains using
bgplu so um evolving requirements
um you know need multiple end-to-end
paths between
two end points in these multi-domain
networks
and seamless sr is trying to address
that and the solution
that cms sr is focusing on is a
completely distributed solution
so where there is no single entity which
which has the database of all these
domains and
uh computes the path it's more of a
distributed solution where the
paths across these domains get stitched
together
so in terms of requirements so we have
reorganized the use cases and
requirements section and clearly laid
out
the requirements categorize the
requirements into multiple categories
such as
asn domain requirements and sla
requirements
merger and migration requirement or
scalability
availability requirements and so on so
just to quickly cover
asn igp domain requirements so these are
different ways
the slide shows the different ways the
domains can be organized
we have covered the most common use
cases it's not
a exhaustive list of all the types all
the different ways
operators
deploy the multi-domain networks so the
first one is where there are multiple
ass and connected via ebgp
the second one is where there are
multiple igps and there is a common
border node
on which on the left side there is going
to be one igp and right side another igp
and the
end to end connection is via ibgp
sessions and there's a third
category where there are there's a
single as
if you see on the bottommost right side
diagram as1
is the as and there is domain one domain
two and domain three and there's no
common border node
and the um kind of endurant connectivity
is all via ibgp sessions
next slide please
yeah so this is uh tunneling
requirements like underlay tunnels what
all
different categories of tunnels
need to be supported i think run to next
slide i have
talked about it multiple times already
so next slide please
so various sla requirements again
latency bandwidth
in link node and domain inclusion
exclusion and end-to-end diverse paths
and constraint applicability to subset
of domains and service function chaining
is something that we cover in this
section
next slide please so
mergers and migration requirements
mainly focuses on
changing networks you know when evolving
networks and
requirements arising out of those
network evolution such as
during migrations you will have to have
the interoperability with bgplu
and we should you should also uh have
the
native support for best effort paths
like if we come up with some new
extension that should also have support
for
uh end to end ability to create best
effort paths end to end and
as the network evolves we should not
have the requirement of running two
different families
um option a and option b use cases and
also
in case of mergers there may be a
necessity to you know
the color mapping may vary from one
domain to another domain so there is a
need to
have a ability to translate that intent
from one domain to another
domain and then there is also a
requirement for um you know interrupt
with other tunneling technologies like
your ability to do srv six in one domain
and
mpls in another domain is kind of an
example
next slide please
so uh this slide lists down the
scalability aspects support up to one
million nodes access
low i mean devices having low access
node capabilities
and scalable response to network events
and automatic filtering of routes on
access nodes
an ability to reduce fib scale on the
border nodes next slide please
yeah we also cover other requirements
like protection
end-to-end protection including
intra-domain as well as border node and
egress protection
operations and automation and i would
like more input from
operators community on operations so
right now we have covered
like counters and ability to ping and
trace route
and um it will be useful to see
what what requirements people come up
here i mean if if
operators have to deploy this and have
to debug this at 3 am in the morning
what would they like to see and
give that input to the requirements
document and we also cover
various ways of traffic steering
mechanisms and
interaction with other approaches like
existing centralized approaches
so we also cover multicast tunneling
requirements like if the network is
built this way and is getting operated
this way
how would the multicast tunneling and
what are the requirements
for getting an end-to-end multicast
solution
next slide please yes so we will
we request more review and comments and
uh so recently there is also another
draft um which is talking about similar
use cases in bgp car problem statement
and
we are in discussion with authors of bgp
car problem statement
that's all any questions comments
or i wait someone to call me
daniel go ahead thank you
good presentation there are there is
another um
srmps to a services document
as well which i happened to also water
and i wonder if um
you could have a economizations also
on your point that you're making in the
next step to also try and merge and and
hopefully not having another design team
to get together to uh
you know define which one we're going to
pick at the end
would you be interested to have this
conversation
with on the other draft it's uh
it's srmps and it's isn't the working
the draft yeah so dan this particular
draft is mostly covering requirements
so i would i would first like to cover
what are the requirements in terms of
srv6 and srm pls interrupt
uh yeah solution discussion on solution
um
that's that's definite that definitely
should happen but
let's at least close on requirements
what what are the requirements for you
know this
at a high level you can say srv6 and
mpls interrupt but it would be useful to
cover
the details as well so the car draft she
mentions here is the next thing on the
agenda and i believe
the interworking draft you referred to
daniel is the one after that on the
agenda so we will be going through all
of this
okay good i gotta come back then
okay keng lee
go ahead changly
do you have any implementation or
deployment of this
extension uh yeah so
what i talked about is a requirement
yeah but we do have a solution document
that uh
that covers um how these requirements
are stated in this document can be
achieved using a bgp protocol extension
with bgpct and yes we do have
implementation and
some testing going on in the lab and
this was presented
in idr as well as
yesterday before yesterday
okay is he done jimmy
i'd like to ask her can you hear me
yes go ahead yeah my
question is can this uh do you plan to
support srv6
in this uh like a architectural
in this problem space yes definitely so
we we have already listed as an srv6
both srv6 end to end as well as uh
srv6 to mpls interop use cases
yeah definitely okay so the draft name
may
may be better to change to not just at
least the
amperes so that
the name of the draft is seamless sr
um so it covers srm pls as well as sr
uh v6
okay okay we're i think we've covered
the material let's move on to the next
one namely the car
problem statement draft i i see the
presenter is already
online and i will avoid inappropriately
pronouncing your name
my apologies that i can't bruno you
bring up
the car slide
thanks joel can you hear me folks yes we
can hear you
oh okay great uh thank you um hi
everyone
i'm dhananjay rao from cisco and i will
be presenting on behalf of my co-authors
and contributors on the
bgp color aware routing problem
statement draft
this draft was also presented at idr and
best
next slide please
the objective of bgp color aware routing
is to use bgp
to establish an end to end intent aware
path across multiple domains
both igp and bgp an example of an intent
is
a low latency path next slide please
a quick reminder i mean here in the
spring working group there is a solution
defined for
inter-domain intent or sla based path
computation uh
using srte this is a mature and widely
deployed
solution the solution document defines
the
notion of color to represent intent in
the network
control plane and we you know intend to
use the
same next slide please
uh we just see here an illustration of
the color
um uh concept uh an egress p e3
tags a vpn route with color c1 uh
expressing a request for a particular
intent
any ingress p such as e1 that installs
this route
will try to steer traffic for this
vpn route through a path to e3 for color
c1 color is signaled using the bgp color
extended community
next side please
in the sr policy solution the ingress
pe1
may request a srpce to compute the
interdomain path since the srpc
is the one aware of the intel domain
topology uh the srpc
will return computer path for that
particular intent and
return a label or a sid stack that the
ingress pe will then install and use in
the data plane
the rest of the network nodes uh are
stateless uh you know for this
path next side please
now here in with bgp color aware routing
um we have the same automated steering
uh you know uh requirement as the srpce
case
only here the color aware path is set up
using a bgp hop by hop route
distribution and
uh you know best path computation um
in this example route uh to e3 for color
c1
uh is originated uh say from a border
node 32
um may be redistributed from an igp flex
algo
it's propagated by hop across the
domains till it you know reaches
e1 at each hop a best path is computed
for that intent you know recursing over
the appropriate
intra-domain color path a vpn route that
is
uh you know colored uh for with c1 will
then get steered via this uh you know
bgp e3 comma c1 route
uh next slide please
uh here we see you know an example of
multiple intents so for the same uh you
know egress p e3
we have two color aware routes c3 c1 and
e3 c2
uh they are independent routes you know
and may uh
end up getting set up via completely
different paths through the inter-domain
network uh to complete the example we
have two vpn routes one
um colored with c1 the other one with c2
each route will respectively get uh
resolved and steered via the
appropriate uh e3 comma c you know
star route next slide please
um when we come to looking at the
deployment requirements
the reference you know topologies are
well known
um you can have multi-igp or multi-as uh
designs uh but a significant uh
difference is the increase in scale um
you know there are some networks where
the num the scale can go into
the order of hundreds of thousands of uh
you know pes in the
network um and then we also have the
case where
we may need multiple intents to be
supported in the
network uh you know some common ones are
listed here
um you know we have best effort but then
there's low latency
um two disjoint planes and then an
avoidance use case
uh perhaps with you know links nodes or
or domains
so just with this reference example we
see the number of routes in the network
um can go up to um you know 1.5 million
routes next site please
here we just list uh you know a number
of other
intent uh use cases um the draft goes
into
you know detail in terms of illustrating
the key ones with reference topologies
next slide please
the focus of this problem statement
draft has been to have
uh you know a concise technical analysis
of the use cases
and deployment constraints and then
enumerate the resulting
protocol and design requirements uh some
key ones to call out
of course consistency with the deployed
srbc a
policy-based solution as well as
coexistence and interworking
a key here is the you know the use of
color to drive automated steering
uh we also extend the problems space
um intentable paths need to be supported
in the vpn
service layer as well and needs to take
into account nfe service chain
integration next slide please
there are a number of deployment
requirements but a key one is
uh you know the setting up of paths
across
heterogeneous domains you know where
there's different technologies and
encapsulations being used
uh then the and the sort of the most
significant one
is the the impact of scale
on the you know on the on the solution
both
on the data plane especially where mpls
is used
as well as on the bgp control plane so
we clarify these aspects in the draft
next slide please on this work is the
result of
a collaboration with many people both
among the lead operators
and vendors so we acknowledge their
contributions
uh we also recognize that there has been
work in this area
specifically by the seamless sr
co-authors um
we you know as as shadow mentioned we
reached out to them back in november
december and there is
ongoing uh you know effort to uh come up
with
a joint uh problem statement and you
know for subsequent
work next slide please
um yeah so of course this is ongoing
effort but
uh you know we request uh a new review
from the working group
thank you
correct you have a question go ahead
hi uh thanks for the presentation this
is stark with juniper
my question is there seems to be an
assumption that the
color has the same meaning when it's
crossing multiple domains
has a uniform meaning what is the
guarantee that the same color means the
same thing
in multiple domains is there a need for
translation for example
do you think there can be a need for
translation and this is a key aspect
that we call out
you know in the draft clearly defining
the notion of a color domain
that has differentiated from uh network
domain
the draft does goes into you know
requirements that come out of it
tariq this is jim uh just just to add to
that and i don't i don't want to go down
a rat hole but
um that question is actually covered in
the solution document which is not part
of these slides so we can't discuss that
but if you if you want to look at that
go ahead and look at that solution
document i believe it's covered there
okay go ahead linda yes i have a
question
um what's the difference between your
color and the raw target
so firstly a color is uh you know is a
construct that is you know used to
represent the intent
and depending on the protocol being used
it would be signaled using different
mechanisms
in in in the sr policy solution
to signal the request for that intent
the bgp color extended community is used
to carry this color
now when it comes to bgp color aware
routing
uh you know depending on the the
solution it would be uh you know
a particular
bgp construct would be used to you know
signal that color awareness
so you will have another update or
another
instruction um how to forward
the colors how to steer the color that's
separate
is that correct i mean i
don't want to go into the solution
detail since this was a you know
a presentation on the the problem
statement
but as jim pointed that you know there
is a solution document
uh you know proposal that defines uh you
know how
color is used and signaled
okay thank you okay
ran go ahead
just remind me that we have a draft uh
solves the same the same problem
uh the draft name is drafted
idr entertainment lcu
and this stuff describes describes the
colored bdplu
lsp in which the routine prefix not only
carries
carries a label but also carries a
unique
color attribute which helps to select
other
underlying logic slides please
review and give us some comments
okay i suggest you type that draft name
into the chat
because i doubt very many people were
able to figure out what it was so please
type it
and uh i imagine the authors will go
look
we're getting it move on to the next
actually it might it might be better
around if you could actually send
something to the mailing list
that would work too yes okay sounds good
thank you ran
and now we go to the srv6 mpls
interworking uh
swadesh i believe you're presenting this
material
yeah hi i'm uh yes i will present
yeah hi i'm swadeesh agarwal working for
cisco systems
and i will present this srv6 mpls
interworking draft
on the behalf of all my co-authors
listed here and next slide
so this draft describes a solution for
srv6 and mpls interworking
as you know srvs is getting deployed in
the customer networks
and we have a brownfield mpls so such
interworking is it
is a requirement and this draft provides
the simple building blocks
to make this interworking happen
the this the initial version was posted
in october 2018
and this is a ref five which provides
the additional details
the draft describes both the data plane
as well as associated control plane
procedures to achieve
uh interworking for data plane this
draft has
introduced new and dtm dtm
behavior as well as it it updates the
existing
n.b.m behavior which is defined in the
network programming
and which is used in this draft in this
draft now
for the control plane we could go in
both into srpc based solution
as well as the bgp based solutions to
provide such interworking
next slide please so
this in this slide i'm trying to what
we'll try to do is we'll try to
generalize the interworking problem
into a simple problem in which i'm
trying to show a central domain
which i'm showing in different example
it could be different
in this case okay the green is uh
representing the srv6 domain
and the orange is representing an mpls
domain and the
dashed oval represents an interworking
function that happens on some border
router
okay so if you look at this draft
proposes two
main scenarios one is a transport
interworking
another is a service interworking at the
transport interview
what it means is our l3 or l2 services
uh i have a ah have a same control pin
continuity
so what it means is if you see the first
uh on the right side first
diagram it says srv6 on is on the leaf
on the edges
and mpls is in the central domain so for
simplicity we have shown this
but it could be any cascading domains
any type of
in any order also but edge domains is in
this case is an srv6 and therefore they
will have a srv6 vpn services
therefore what we need to achieve is we
need to tunnel the ipv6 or srv6 traffic
through this mpls domain
the second use case for transport
interworking is we have the edge which
is an
mpls which runs the mpls vpns and we
have to transport this
and lsp through the srv6 domain and the
third one
that interworkings now that we look is
is a service interworking where the
service the l2 l3 services
itself is srv6 vpn services or bgp mpls
services that is shown on the edges as a
vpn as
a srv6 vpn and the mpls vpn
and here what we need to provide is we
need to provide the quantity
connectivity for these l2 and l3
services through this interworking
function
next slide please so this
draft defines a new and dtm set behavior
that the what this behavior does is it
decapsulates the ipv6 header
and its extension headers and then look
then
mp the following mpls packet top label
in the mpls table
and forwards the packet accordingly and
this function is executed on the
interworking box between srv6 and mpls
domain
there's a pseudo code listed in a draft
i will not go through it but it's just
that
after doing the decap we look the top
label we carried in the packet
next slide please
also this draft introduces the srv6 and
hidden behaviors
here what we say it we have introduced
two behaviors one is to
h dot end caps which is applied to an
mpls label stack
here when we receive an mps label stack
we
pushed an ipv6 header along with it
along with the srh
together the empirics label stack and
the its payload becomes the payload of
an ipv6 packet
and the next header field of an srh must
be set to 137.
also there's a reduced version in which
the first segment is not put in the srh
but it is just put in the
destination address uh next slide please
yeah as i described earlier interwork we
have we have broken the interworking
scenario transport interworking
what it means is we need to provide
reachability to our locator if it is
srv6 vpn services
or to a lsp to a pe if it is an i
ampersa vpn so this draft provides
two mechanisms to provide such thing one
is a a known as
existing srpc which satisfies the intent
across the multiple domain also since
srpc's
learns the topology through bgpls from
each of the domains
it is aware of the data plane
discontinuity at certain interworking
box or the border box also disk draft
provides the
best effort connectivity through bgp
where we advertise the pe locator
or the mpls lsp through such a
discontinuity of network next slide
please
so the for my examples the the way i
will show is the green circle will show
an srvs capable node
and here we will show a locator which
would be represented by b colon k
k would be the node id and f is a
function on that
node and the mpls node would be shown
with the orange with the k
represents their label it would be the
prefix seed label
which would be represented by 16 000 and
k would be the node number
and green and orange that i'm showing is
a node which is both sr mpls capable as
well as srv6 capable
next slide please so here i'm taking an
example of
srpc a solution to provide the transport
interworking
here node 1 and node 10 are running srv6
vpns because that's hr srv6 in this case
so now what happened node 10 which is
running an srv6 vpn service will
advertise a vpn prefix
with a srv service set here which is
shown as b colon 10 common
toner dt4 because vpn service as well as
color red because it's an sr
srt based solution and it has a certain
intent in this example red is showing a
low latency intent
node 1 receives this update and node 1
doesn't know how to reach node 10
it will make a request to a to the sr pc
to provide a low latency path which is
represented by color red
to the node 10. will compute the low
latency path and i am showing its
compute through node 2
5 and 8 and srpc figures out that
there is a discontinuity of the data
plane at the border node 4.
srpc installs the mpls policy at four
along the same low latency path till the
note 7
and then that policy is installed on the
note 4
as shown in the example it has a segment
16 05
and 16 07 and it will again take you to
a low latency path through the mpls
domain
but important aspect is that this policy
is
bounded to an ipv6 instantiation of a
binding set which is n.b.m which is
already described in the network
programming
and we are using the exact same n.b.m
function here
and this this segment now srpc will send
this update
back to the node 1 because that
requested in which one of the segments
would be this
n.b.m behavior so if you see the
segments on the node one it takes
through the
low latency path through node two uh and
then there's a binding set to on the for
the node
node four and then through node five in
that and nodes
eight and if you see the packet power
packet that it received on the note 4
the packet that received on the note 4
would be that with that android bm
function on note 4
and what that n dot bm pseudocode is it
will
update the next segments in the srh as a
destination
and then it will put a empire stack in
that is involved that is uh bounded to
that policy and sends the packet out
into the mpls domain
and rest of the on the note 7 it will do
a lookup of that ipv6 packet that is
following the impeller stack and packet
will flow to the
back to the srv6 network uh next slide
please
exactly same procedures we can achieve
for the srpc for m over 6.
the difference here is our central
domain is at srv6 therefore the policy
that srpc will install
on the note 4 here would be an srv6
policy
whose segments would be again to for the
sla part to the note 7
in which in which in this case again i
am showing the end function of note 5
and then important part is the last
segment of this policy
is a new behavior that we already
described is a
dtm function which causes us to look up
the
following mpls header and send the
packet further into mpls domain on the
right
and if you see that in this case again
the now srv6 policy
the bcd is represented by an mpls bc and
that
srpc will install on the note 1 as one
of the segments
which will cause the stitching or the
interworking function on the note 4.
from the packet path point of view on
the note 4 i will receive the packet
with an mpls pc
it's shown as 3007 here which will be uh
which will push the ipv6 header with the
destination as the first segment as a
node 5 and then the la and and the next
segment would be going into an srh would
be
which would be the dtm function of node
seven and on node seven
once we hit the dtm function it would
see it's my my
it will hit my sit table because the
locator is of the note 7
and it's a dtm type and the next header
would be 137 so it will do a lookup of
the top level
which is 8 16 08 and it will forward to
the next
segment that is note 8. and next
before you go to the next slide dhruv is
trying to ask a question go ahead drove
yeah thanks uh joel swades uh with my pc
chair
hat on uh i would request you to uh
talk to the binding sid authors it's a
working group document it's almost
we think it's gonna be ready for uh
working group last call as well
so what you are describing seems to be
supported there is no limitation there
that for a sr path mpls path you can
have a binding segment
which is both srv6 binding segment or an
mpls binding segment so it seems to be
allowed
but i would prefer if it is made
explicit so it is
uh that you have a use case for this and
i think it's a very valid use case
so maybe just talk to the binding set
authors and add one statements there so
that it is very clear
uh second second comment i would have is
uh
we also have multi-domain case that we
handle in pc
uh quite well and most of your document
is focusing
on a single pc that is taking care of
all the domains so just think about
even handling inter domain aspects as
well thank you
sure thanks drop i will talk to the for
the
binding sid as well as the other aspect
you mentioned sure
okay next slide please
so here we have described both the srpc
solution for six over m and mo6
something similar we can do for bgp base
in transport interworking
so here we know h domains on srv6 so our
services would be srv6 vpn services
so what we need is when we add when the
node 10 advertise such an
srv6 vpn services and node 1 receives
node 1 receives needs a reachability
over the central domain for the
pe locator because the srv6 services
would be advertised with an srv6
services
which would be the locator of node 10.
now this reachability is like an ipv6
reachability over an
mpls domain which is already supported
like a 6pe functionality
and so therefore we can use exactly same
functionality when an ipv6 prefix is
advertised through node 7 to
node 4 it would be it would be with a
label
bgp ipv6 lu address family and it would
be
transported over an sr mpls intra domain
tunnel whatever it is
next slide piece
so next one come the our h domains is
mpls and our central domain is srv6
so what happens today in such is this is
running and bgp
mpls vpn so what we need is we need your
reachability from node 1 to node 10
which is an mpls lsp what today existing
mechanism is
a bgp3107 which cause the label cross
connects wherever we do next top cell so
in this case
on the note 7 and on the note 4 and
there would be a cross connect for
loop back to node 10. so exactly same
mechanism would be used the extra step
that would be required would be
instead of tunneling from the that bgp
lsp from
note 4 to note 7 over an mpls lsp we
will tunnel that into an
into an ipv6 tunnel whose destination
would be
of the behavior dtm and or dtm which is
already described
and that what so what note 4 is supposed
to do is
uh it need to do a label swap as it does
today on
on the note 4 in addition to that it
will put an ipv6 header
uh whose destination would be n dot dtm
and
ah and put that ip and send with an ipv6
encapsulation to the node 7 with a and
it would be of the dt
and the behavior of that destination
would be of the dtm type
and on note 7 what will happen is since
it's a dtm type we will decapsulate the
ipv6 header and its extensions
and do a lookup of the next label would
be which would be the again the bgp
lu lsp label and packet would be
reaching note 10.
so this draft also proposes uh carrying
uh
this n dot dtm function as an srb6 sid
in the bgp lu update and we have added a
new tlv
for for carrying that update uh next
slide please
so till now we were talking about
transport interworking so there is a use
case of interworking in which we have to
make a
control plane which is running srv6 vpn
and the
uh mpls mpls vpn so for that we
propose there's already a sub a gateway
solution a gateway is a box which
supports both the srv6 vpn as well as
mpls vpn
and what happens in on this box we do a
service termination so that means
there's a
l2 based on service whether it's l2
service or lt service there's a lookup
involved
so that that does that terminates the
both the underlay
as it is overlay and therefore we can
provide the interworking using a gateway
solution
next slide please yeah so
we have covered in this draft we have
made sure there are building blocks
being taken care
and these building blocks cover all the
complex interworking scenarios
and therefore we would like the working
group to review this
as well as adopt this document thank you
questions for swadesh before we move on
to the next one
which is a different n dot dtm
okay hearing no questions ron you have
the floor
all right daniel you have a question go
ahead quickly
just last minute question but that was
the point i was
trying to do with shredder or um
on her presentation because i see some
similarities although
sure you seem to be very focused on
defining the problem but
there's a piece that in here what was
just presented that
is also referring to defining a problem
so i was just wondering if
this work should you know start from
the beginning to looking at merging or
contributing
instead of waiting that were too far
along and then end up with two different
ways of doing the same thing
sure sure dan we can discuss and see how
go ahead with it yes should
thanks thanks
can you hear me yes i know you
okay yeah you have the next one up go
ahead
this is ron bonica and i'm presenting
end dtm
on behalf of my co-authors and to
maximize confusion
the ndtm is named exactly as the same as
the ndtm
that you just heard about it has many of
the same functions
but a few small differences
let's go over them first slide
okay this draft introduces a new srv6
endpoint behavior called
ndtm it's for interworking between srv6
and srmpls
and like any uh endpoint behavior it
contains a function plus
arguments the function causes the
processing node
to de-encapsulate a packet that is to
remove the ipv6 header and all its
extensions
to impose an srm pls label stack and to
forward the packet
as per the mpls label stack
um the arguments determine the label
stack contents and anything that might
be encoded in the label stack
next slide
next slide okay here's a typical use
case we have an sr path that goes from
node one to node five
there's an srv6 part that has nodes one
two and three in it
and an srm pls part that has nodes four
and five in it
um node three is the one saddled with
the
um with the task of translation
so node 3 has to be both srv6 and srmpls
aware
1 and 2 or only srv6 or only need to be
srv6
node 4 and 5 only need to be srm pls
next slide
so how do we process this um
and here's where you'll see the
difference between the ndtm you just saw
on this end
dtm if segments left is greater than
zero we discard the packet and send an
icmp message to the source
um when uh
if it is not zero we do nothing until
we're processing the upper layer header
when we process the upper layer header
we de-encapsulate the packet
we push an mpls label stack that is
associated with the dtm arguments
we set the mpls traffic class and ttl to
reflect
the traffic class and hop count that was
in the ipv6 header
and we submit the package to the mpls
lookup
for transmission to the new destination
so there are two big differences between
this ndtm and the one you just saw one
is that we allow
any payload not just mpls and the other
is that we make a point of setting the
mpls traffic class and ttl values
appropriately
next slide
the next steps um we're asking for
working group review and a call for
adoption
um we've heard a request from dan
to talk about merging solutions so
that probably has to happen too and
that's it okay there's a question from
swadesh and from daniel swadesh first
yeah yeah hi ron so isn't
what you are proposing is the when we
receive that function and its argument
you have to put an mpls stack based on
its the arguments
correct yes so isn't that
n.b.m that is already defined in network
programming is just that it's a decap
variant of it
i'm just saying because today it's very
programming
it's very close to n.b.m yeah that's
what i'm saying it's uh your
lookup function and arguments already
give you what's it stack to put and
that's the difference between
n.d.m where we are proposing to do a
lookup
into a whatever is falling in the
impellers header and that
lookup will give you impeller stack here
okay yes whatever there is
so i i'm saying is that this is in some
says n.b.m it's just a d-cap variant of
it
it's very close to n.b.m um
also the mpls stack may not fit in the
arguments
so it may be that some implementations
have to do a lookup
um the draft is silent on that
yeah but i from my point of view i just
looking at it i felt this is the end of
bm that's what i want to point out
it's very close
so my question run as well i'm assuming
i'm
free to go run go ahead now
it's close to the that the end but it's
not quite
you are you're gonna propose an
a new end function or yes you're gonna
be chosen
we're proposing a new end function so
yeah i have the same comment to
can we look at merging before the
the chair stick comes in and
we end up with the design team yeah
that's a conversation to have probably
not in the next three minutes but
let's have it good thanks thank you
changly you're next
see these two documents define the same
thing
and i'd like to see the uh end of
this story and by the way gsr6 for
amperes also defined a similar uh
mechanism so
maybe we can combine these kind of
things to discuss
in the main list thank you
okay any further questions
hearing done we'll move on to the next
presentation
so far i believe you're going to be
presenting
uh building blocks first sr building
blocks for slicing in
you don't need to put yourself on the
queue just
oh so i'm i'm here okay good many things
so i'm going to present this draft on
building blocks that i need for creating
slices in sr network on behalf of my
co-authors
next slide please
okay so let's first look at the scope of
the draft this trap is an informational
draft
it lists essential building blocks
needed for
network slicing it
basically explains how these building
blocks work together as
independent pieces and works seamlessly
to to provide scalable
uh slicing solution and
solution that is that are
defined for incremental deployments in
mind
next slide please
a very brief history of the draft we
started the work in july 2
2018 the ref 2 was presented
in ietf 106 in spring
next slide please
so in the left two when when
the presentation happened we covered the
following
building blocks the
sr policy which is which enables
steering of traffic
along an arbitrary path that arbitrary
part may be
low latency path or a path that avoids
certain resources
odn use case allows service traffic
to be carried on paths that meet
customer
or application slas automatic steering
is possible into network slicing using
that constructor
then we talked about flexible algorithms
the complements srte policy solution
by adding new prefix
segments with a specific optimization
objective
and constraints so it allows
uh so this is an example of what why we
call them independent
uh cooperating building blocks uh
because sr policies
are supported with or without flex algo
flex on the other hand flexible
leverages odn and automatic steering
uh construct of sr policy
then we talked about ti lfa which plays
a role
in providing order 50 millisecond
protection in the underlay
as these are the building blocks that
work together the way that
say for example tlf and flex algo works
is that the backup path for tlsp
lfa is express with prefix sid
of flux of a specific flexible elbow
the backup part is optimized per flux
elbow
so we don't have so you don't have we
don't have cases where
traffic for a flex cell go which is low
delay
can be back up on a path that are
not delay optimized path
then we have vpns that provide means for
creating
logically separated network to different
set of
users to access
the common network infra
then service provider programming
provides
supporting orchestration of virtualized
service containers
and is fully integrated with sr policies
this is how the building blocks work
together on mpm provide
useful mean for collecting topological
and service data
that is used for first implementing
slicing
and then we have ip amperes disk surf
architecture
that enables network devices to provide
differential treatment
based on exp or dhcp marking
here we would like to draw attention
that qos
works independent of topology
or routing
and then slice orchestrator puts things
together at the management plane
since that revision we also now
added references for
stateful slice id these references
so later on when we go through this
we're going to go through this how the
stick
less slice id fits together as a
building block
uh that does not disrupt the picture
from routing uh point of view or from
topological point of view
but works to provide additional
differentiate treatment so next slide
please
so let's have a look at a few people so
far
so far before you go to the next slide
we have a couple of people who
apparently have questions about the
history that you've presented
so greg you're up
uh maybe i can finish this and then we
can take a question i think it's not so
important
um well so far uh i have a question so
um what
uh which definition of the network
slides
uh this refers to
is it uh 3gpp network slice
or itf network slides
could we uh wait so that you you're
clear later on
uh once i do the can we come back to
this one
once i'm done with the presentation uh
well
i i think it's a basic very fundamental
question because
uh we need to understand the context of
what the network's lies we're talking
about
let's let's wait i i'd like you to
understand the
solution and then uh
without this point i understand why
you're asking but we have to let him
continue at this point if he thinks the
rest of the presentation
may clarify it yeah
okay so next
next slide please
so in the context of the attributes
needed
to create a slice which is independent
of routing and topology so one of the
attributes of
slice id for differential treatment is
that it's supposed to
is to be independent of routing and
topology
what does slice id does what size id
does so is in this picture
we have a picture on this slide we have
a picture on the right
that shows cueing treatment given
to two slices slice one
and slice two and
these two slices
there is some information that is uh
in in this in this picture the slice
green slice is identified by slice id1
and the blue slices identify the slice
id2
traffic that the green and blue slices
carry is aggregated using hierarchical
queue
so it is not possible for green slice
exp 0 traffic to disturb
blue slice exp 0 traffic
and what other attribute that we like is
that
slice id should be independent running
topology it should be stateless
and it should be done in a backward
compatible fashion
for incremental deployment next slide
please
so now let's take a look at exemplify
why slice id construct needs to be
independent of routing topology
so i like to draw your attention to the
picture on the right
which ignore the block the big
box in that picture for now
here within that you have a network
with two flex algo low latency flex sell
go orange
128 and
low cost flex algo red 129.
i did i did mention earlier that if you
have a failure let's say if you have a
failure between link one and two
then what you like because the low
latency slide traffic
you you like the low limit let's say try
traffic to use backup resources that are
also
a backup bar that is also low low
latency optimize
and and indeed this is what happens for
flight circle
case so there's a failure between node
uh between on link between node one and
two
then the traffic is diverted to a low
latency
delay path which is shown by orange
now it makes sense to extend this to the
differential treatment
that the slices provide and
in this case now let's take this picture
which is
half blue half green and this is like
that because
it's a common infrastructure or a common
flux algo so we are not replicating flux
algo per slice id
but reusing the same flux algo
again topology and routing independence
is important
using the same instance to create
differential treatment
now what happens
when you have a failure
in the same link node 1 and 2
but now slice id
1 and slice id two traffic
that is going over that link one and two
is destructive you re
redirect traffic through four three and
two so we are going to focus on node
number four
when node number four received the
packet and packet is a stateless
instance of slice id in the packet so
when node number four
receive the packet with slice id do one
obviously it applies
the differential treatment given and
reserve or program for slice id 1.
when the traffic comes for slice id 2
then it gives the same differential
treatment
that that is programmed at node number 4
for slice id 2. so in this
fashion you really need
the tlfa flex lgo
and other building block completely
transparent
to the differential treatment that is
required for
for slicing slicing really slice id
really
act like a qos which is independent of
routing topology next slide please
okay so regarding the seamless
working of this building block we saw
that flex sell go
how it works it's the same thing like
you have
you have a construct which is a
differentiated treatment on a node
but you don't need too many instances of
the differential treatment
because you have other construct like
vpn policies
qs differentiation that make you scale
and on a device you're not going to have
too many behavior for differential
treatment so this is how
the slice is scaled
next slide please
so we're going to take an example this
is with the reference of house
stateless life id information is carried
for srv6 network and in this picture
we have an sr domain
and we show that traffic
is in green payload is supposed to be
supposed to be classified into green
slice
and a blue payload is supposed to be
classified
in the blue drive slide so we're going
to focus on
sr node ingress one where
which always encapsulate the packet
in an outer ipv6 header an optional srh
this node when the when the with this
node may classify the packet so when the
green packet
comes then it will be classified into
green slice id
and then the green slice id is carried
in the
eighth most significant bit of four
labels so far
so far can you possibly pick up the pace
you've spent
rather more than your allotted time
already and we do have some more
questions
sure uh so uh so good so so basically
then then
then what happens is is that node number
two which is
which is a transit node uh if it slice
aware
then it look at that field uh that is in
the packet
and apply the differential treatment
that the that is programmed at node
number two
uh if it is not aware
of slice id treatment then
it just forwards the packet
without any any further differential
treatment using other building blocks
or we can call it forward the traffic
using the default sleep so that's
enables the um the difference at the
that enables uh the incremental
deployment
next slide please
so now for the npls
uh draft for there is a draft that bruno
presented to mpls working group
it worked for both uh segment routing
and non-segment routing mpls
uh and it's similar to what
what the other reference i just went
over
the uh the exception is that
the slice id is carried
in the entropy label
and the ttl of the entropy label
is the is where slice id
presence indication is provided
a node that is able to that is capable
of doing the differential treatment
applied to differential treatment
other nodes work
work seamlessly and provide
load balancing during the true label
entropy label
with with that i would uh stop here
for the next slide please please let's
just take questions this is the last
slide so i stopped here
and uh basically would like to get
provide
get feedback from the working group and
would like
working group uh to adopt the farm
questions
yes you're up
yeah this is judo my question is first
the first part of this document
presentation is a good summary of the sr
mechanisms which have been defined in
this working group
to make it more network slide specific
perhaps
i suggest to reference the resource
aware segment
and sr4 weapon plus drafts which are
also
the working group documents in spring
working group
the second comment is the sharing of
topology between multiple slides
was proposed in the scalability
consideration draft
institute which i hopefully i can
present
in the end of this session and the last
comment is
for the data plane slice id mechanism
in my understanding this is based on the
ipv6 data plane or ampere's data plane
extensions
which will belong to that relevant
working groups
okay all right so the many things
for for the comments uh uh so i i
agree we can work offline on the
suggestions
that you made and this is informational
document
this document does not so
so far i'm going to cut in here we've
got literally uh
not much time left we've got one
presentation left on the
agenda plus two that are there if we
have time where we're going to run out
of time so
uh i think we need to cut the queue uh
with the people on here let's get these
questions through quickly and move on
please
yeah and quick answers thank you i will
uh follow up greg
with you offline or on the mailing list
thank you
greg you're ahead of the queue go ahead
i i didn't understand
are we cutting off queue the folks
on the cube can go but okay then
can you give me a chance
uh i i listened for the whole
presentation and still i don't
understand to which
definition of network slicing this
proposal is applicable to
and another one is just minor net
that uh exp field in mpls label element
has will remain traffic class for
10 plus years so uh just
please use the proper identification
thank you
yeah and answer that on the list or
other discussion
chang thank you
changly you're next
do you really think eight bits is enough
for the slice id and
like for also for amperes as amperes
is it appropriate to use the entropy
label because each node we
try to first whole c stack
get the entropy label so so what's your
opinion on that
sorry chang this is jim um please take
that one to the list
if if their comments please give the
comments quickly then we can move on if
they are actual
technical questions please do it on the
list
here let's see thank you
thank you for bruno that comment thank
you
thank you hi this is tarek uh um
you didn't number your slides uh i i
can't tell you which slide to go to
i'll i'll tell you what i remember you
you you flashed on the slide
it was about uh a slice is independent
of the topology
in fact there are requirements that
a slice can be steered or should be
steered on
certain topological elements i'll give
an example
you want secure links or you have
diversity requirements
uh which aren't under under discussion
uh in these working group
uh a slice has topological dependency
it's not
uh independent i don't know which slide
you were
maybe the previous one or this one
you're saying that yeah
this one we we could use this one the
the previous one i think that they also
had uh
same comments i i think yeah i think
this is a topic that needs more
discussion than we can get through
daniel you're the last one and then
we'll go back to tarek for his name
not to turn for go on daniel
so greg about the question about the
definition of the slicing that you had
i know that someone from from huawei
robin sent an email with
like uh in this working group on the or
the test one that there's about like
eight different document attempting to
come up with a definition of slicing
and i read them all in in this document
here that
tarak is just a presentation if we zoom
out a little bit
especially with that slide or the one
previous
we're talking about the fundamental
block and i don't think when you look at
those fundamental blocks here
that one exactly that one it violate any
of the
attempted eight different document
of the definition of slices i don't
think it'd violate that even though if
the meaning of the slices
is not that really clear i think those
building black are still required and
that's pretty much how i
i see it myself as a co-author when i'm
thinking of designing
a network that requires end-to-end
transport slices across the backbone
but the point is that we could have a
summary of
the definition of of of what's
a slice added to this one or having a
reference once
we make up our mind about what's the
real definition of a slice and
maybe i can jeffy were behind me but i'm
pretty sure you wanted to highlight the
definition of slices
who still have the time on the chair no
we're out of time
i'm there is a lot of work going on on
defining slicing
to the degree this is a definition
independent building block that's great
to the degree it's definition dependent
it needs to be clear about the
definition
that the relationship needs to be
clarified in the draft and be discussed
on the list
and with that we move on to terex
presentation
i don't see the slides yet hello this is
uh tarek and today i'm
going to give you an update uh about a
solution to
realize network slicing over an sr
network
i am presenting on the behalf of the
co-authors
uh i would like to thank all of them
next slide please
so i'll give a timeline or a history of
uh the updates on this draft and then
i'll dig into the
maybe a review or recap of the solution
we're presenting and then close off with
the next steps
next slide please so timeline revision
zero was introduced as a companion
document
to the solution document we presented in
teas
and it describes how we can realize the
solution
in nsr network rev one included
updates to align with certain
terminology that we
added in the based document and we
addressed feedback from
uh working group members and we thank
them for that
and we have new co-authors who are
joined our work
next slide please so these are key
terminologies i'm not going to go
uh word by word in details i'll just
high level uh mention that the slice
policy
is a is a means to
instead to install a set of rules uh on
a network element so that we can realize
a slice aggregate
and i'll uh i'll let you read through
these uh uh
terms uh offline um and i'll i'll be
using the slice policy
uh in subsequent slides so
um next slide please
so very high level overview a router
that is
going to process a slice aggregate
packet
uh will require to do a multi number of
things
the first is to identify the packet
belongs to slice aggregate
that's number one number two we need a
way to select the next hop
to forward the packet on and this is uh
determined by the topology of the slice
and the optimization criteria that we
are seeking
and the third rule that we need to
enforce is the forwarding treatment
uh this is uh you know maybe a certain
percentage of the bandwidth on a shared
link that you want to assign
to a slice aggregate so all these rules
are part of a splice
policy definition that we are
introducing in the base document
uh on the right hand side i'm just
showing high level
structure of that slice policy
definition next slide please
so we have we are presenting two
approaches to realize the solution
and an sr capable network the first one
is by
assigning uh uh associating a slice
aggregate with a sid
so so that packets uh using those
specific sids will uh will get the uh
the identification or association to the
slice aggregate as well as
the forwarding action the next top
selection
so the the extensions the to advertise
the slice aggregate prefix and the jcc
sets
were presented on tuesday there's a
pointer to the draft
the second option we are proposing is
carrying a separate id in the packet
so this is uh very similar to what
you've seen
zafar talked about it we are part of
that work and we have proposals there
so the idea is to carry an identifier
that will associate the packet
a slice aggregate uh i'm i'm putting
three pointers here just for reference
uh three
we the working groups the respective
working groups are still
working out the details on which
proposal is the best
and uh but we are advocating this
proposal as well
next slide please
i'll go with the first option that we
are presenting to realize the solution
uh as i said
we uh we will advertise sids associated
with a specific slice aggregate
so uh um the forwarding action in that
case
is dictated by the top or active segment
be it prefix or adjacency the topology
is defined by the
you know if it's a prefix set it carries
the empty id and
a flex algorithm algo number and the fad
will be will dictate the the topology
that is used uh
to select the next stop um this the
forwarding treatment is the
is is a rule uh uh part of the slice
policy definition as i
i mentioned in the earlier slide now
some scale impact to this proposal we
we are not proposing a flex algo
definition
for a slice aggregate so the same flux
algo definition or multiple slice
aggregate can use the same
flex argo definition this is a good
point
other proposals are advocating a flex
algo definition per
slice or per slice aggregate whatever
the term would be
the second point is the igp topology can
be shared among multiple slice
aggregates
uh it can be and that will allow more
better scale
the computed path uh you know a result
of the optimization criteria
can also be shared by multiple slice
aggregate
sets next slide please
so this is an example where a packet is
carried
by a top sid that is associated with a
slice aggregate
i have uh a sa1 packet
with a top set of 16 05 and
sa2 packet with 17 05 both of them are
destined to note 5.
on any transit node let's assume it's 3
we have a slice selector which will put
the packet
based on the top active segment into the
respective
queue and then there's a hierarchical
queue there that you can
apply differentiated treatment based on
the exp
as well but but the high level what i
want to
share here is that the top active
segment is the one
that is used to identify the packet uh
or associated with the slice aggregate
next slide please
the second option is carrying the slice
aggregate
selector or id in the packet
the forwarding action in this case is
determined by the
top active segment whatever the top
active segment would be
next stops are computed as usual by igp
based on the topology and the
optimization
metric the the forwarding treatment as i
mentioned is part of the slice policy
definition that we
install and in terms of scale impact
here we
are reusing the sids so multiple size
aggregates can use
sids that are defined uh or instantiated
in the network
they are not specific to a specific
slice aggregate
the fads can be shared by multiple slice
aggregates based on the topology
requirement
uh again the second bullet is about the
topology can be shared
and the last point is that the computed
path
as a result can be shared by multiple
slice aggregate
packets depending on the top active
segment
next slide please
here's an example where we have a packet
destined from let's say one to five um
and you'll notice the top active segment
for
sa1 packet and sa2 packet both have the
same
uh segment routing sid 17 05
the selector in this case is carried in
a different field in the packet
i did not put details because there are
multiple proposals there
one of them was mentioned the entropy
label
encoding it in the entropy label is one
option but
the selector can be simply in the packet
and it will put the packet in the
specific slice aggregate
queue and we can achieve the same
hierarchical
treatment that we are after
that's what i want to see on this slide
next slide please so
we we welcome feedback um uh
on this proposal um we think uh
um this will allow us to realize the
solution
and sr with with automation required
with the slice policy
uh the automation we are providing the
uh the ease of instantiation of a slice
aggregate in the network
um i would like i would love to answer
any questions that anybody has
okay zebo
gebo you put yourself on the queue if
you have a question
please speak up uh hi
this is the ball from huawei and
multiple sites is the same topic it's a
can use pesticides as id auto slice
extension
intel plan this solution has been posed
in sr for vpn plus and vtn draft
in 2019 and earlier 2020
and it's practically just right
aggregate id is same as we can id
i think it's no need to support
yeah um my feedback on this we are aware
about this
vtn proposal uh we did talk to the
authors and we had a chance to talk
about it i
we there is an email thread that was
started we think the slice aggregate has
some key differences to a vtn
and we would like to take that
discussion further if there is any
alignment that could happen we are
welcome we we would welcome them we're
happy to do it
okay don
[Music]
as we discuss in the test working group
the terminology consistency will be
important for people to
understand and compare the solutions
and then since this is a sr specific
document
one commons is is the essay specific
seed
a kind of resource aware segment
i didn't catch the remaining part so the
the second half of this question was to
note that
the the the sid you're just defining
here
seems to have some significant
similarity with the adopted resource
sids that we have and
let me save some time i think we need to
sort out the relationship
and tune both of them to get there
okay um so g i acknowledge the first
part
uh we will follow up on the second part
uh there is some key differences between
s asid and resource
aware sets that uh
at one time you were not proposing
extensions uh to associate
a sid with a slice aggregate or a slice
i don't know if that changed we can take
a look no problem
there were no protocol extensions
originally
last last topic so far
you get the last question so far okay so
uh my question is that when you use mpls
label
to carry the slice id um
can you comment on the backward
compatibility like if you have a device
in between the two nodes that are
participating
and what happened do you need all nodes
to be upgraded
uh depending on the solution that we
there are multiple
solutions that we are presenting uh
depending on which working group you
mean
uh we would like the solution to be
backward compatible such that a
slice aggregate packet traversing a node
that doesn't support uh that capability
and that the packet will be forwarded
still and
it might get the forwarding treatment
that it's after but
it will not be dropped and other than
the entropy label usage
uh i was i was specifically talking
about the option
where mpls label or top label carry the
slice id
with bruno's draft i understand and
that's what i was talking about backward
compatibility
in bruno's ground but my question was
for the others
there are multiple proposals my answer
is there are multiple ways to carry the
slice aggregate ids one of them is the
inside the entropy label
other ones are there i left pointers and
backward compatibility is
is required in all yeah it'd be
good to see that description in the
front draft thank you
okay thank you all
it has been a set of interesting
discussions i wish we had more time for
more of the discussions
please take them to the list just
just one comment uh we had two uh
presentation if time arrows
uh for your information there are a
schedule in other working groups
so you can uh have a look for example
for um
associated channel over ipv6 there is a
presentation in rtg
wg tomorrow and for scality
consideration for vpn plus
there is a presentation in teas actually
it was yesterday
thank you
[Music]
so thank everybody thank you all for
that for your time
okay
bye