so i don't know why these things happen
but let's try and avoid extra things
like this so yeah we will present slides
for you
thanks very much
shhh
that's all correct we now have slides
foreign
[Music]
okay can people out there hear me
and i'm assuming we'll still need a note
taker
yes please
oh
all right well at least get the first
two slides this is the note well you
should be familiar with it
uh it applies to you as a participant in
this meeting um
and now we're onto gory's item we need a
note taker please
um let me see if i can get get the
relevant portion agenda pasted
into uh the uh the notes uh tool
so
all right there we go
okay we give you the knot taper it's
going to be
your health
supposed to be 7.2
so okay
so we just need somebody to volunteer to
please
try to to capture the important things
that important things that happen we
don't need the blow-by-blow but we do
need
uh we do need to record uh important
points and important decisions being
made
i will try to do notes i hope other
people are willing to help out
i'll be doing that anyways myself
if you just do it in the editing tool
that'll be excellent thanks thanks wes
we'll try to do it that way
um speaking i will also help thank you
all right and let's just simply do this
collectively notetakers also please try
to pay attention to the chat just in
case something comes up in chat
that needs to be said at the set at the
mic or we need to
to get a break at the mics the person on
check and speak
okay
so this is um uh this morning's agenda
it's today is entirely l4s
uh i got one more slide coming as you
can sort of see in my site in
in my my little bar on the side uh
that'll be in a gender recap
then we need to look at the operational
guidance draft
for which adoption has been requested
and there's a call in progress
deal with the main alfred's ecn drafts
and then ingomar has some slides on the
relationship
of on something about l4s and 5g and let
me let me take back relationship word
let ingomar speak to
exactly what he intends to tell us
uh this is the agenda anybody want to
pass it
hearing nothing yep
can i go ahead
um the um i thought we'd made it clear
that is doing 7.2 and i'm just
wrapping up so i just sent a note saying
i don't think you've got slides in
the
um meeting materials but he has sent
them because
he cc'd me at 7.3 right the ecm drafts
okay agenda bash uh is
a presenter for item
seven point three which we it's and
me and me there's two there should
be two sets of slides i'm just doing
some at the end
okay can you check the proceedings now i
think i've uploaded one david can you
find them there
there's two lots for okay hang on
uh i hope the screen doesn't go away
when i do this
um
so many places i could click let's click
on the one that actually does something
useful
um
give me a minute um okay
okay so if i hit reload here
give me a minute i can take it
and talk everybody's retrieving their
meeting materials right now
um
yes i now see 27.3 so we'll be able to
get to all the slides from there
um all right
let me go do the let me go do my last
piece of the fun here
okay so um
upshot here is agenda has been bashed
um i can click on the right window
there it is uh uh agenda bashed
uh second set of slides
has been added me materials okay
so the first thing we gotta do
is talk about what we're trying to get
done this is the chairs
uh view of what needs to be done
uh on the lforest drafts so i'm gonna
read this and with luck uh between
myself
other chairs and some discussion we'll
have some clarity what needs to happen
so there's two there's two items um that
coming to this meeting
need attention the first is transfer
protocol independent requirements to ucl
forest service
and the goal here is um
interoperability multiple transfer
protocols able to meet requirements
specs
and or implementations working group
gets to decide what is sufficient
um and that uh the dock that is crucial
to this
is the ecn l4s id draft
the second uh thing needs to be done is
safety of internet wide
authorized experiment we really do not
want to break the internet
uh in doing this uh goal is
that the uh experiment is unlikely cause
it can damage the internet
and any damage results is expected to be
tolerable
the draft for this is the l4s
ops draft and i'll reiterate something
you said before
working with last calling alphas office
draft is not required to meet the safety
goal
so that that's not required what is the
criteria for
both goals is working group rough
consensus that each goal
has been reached and the working group
chairs
we'll put on our kevlar we'll put in our
kevlar vests and figure out how to run
initial consensus calls before the next
ietf meeting week okay
questions comments dead cats rotten
tomatoes
dead silence i was not expecting that
this this this those slides can't be
that good
all right i will call people bob
greg kuhn is this reasonably clear
and within reason
can i say um go first um
yeah i i that it's relatively clear yeah
um i just wanted the answers to the
questions i put on the mailing list
which is which is more about the text in
earlier emails and and just just to get
a confirmation that
you didn't mean it rather it just
disappeared you know
um because this has become a bit of a
no i don't want that rocket go and get
another rock sort of um
type thing okay so okay to continue that
in to continue that
this this slide contains the
descriptions of the two
rocks get those two rocks and we'll and
and we'll be and and we'll be in good
shape um
i um the crucial question i think you
asked about whether i meant it was
do we need two interoperable
implementations of the transport
protocols
honorable for us the answer is no
working group gets to decide gets to
decide what suffices
the chairs will be satisfied the working
group believes that
um um that uh the requirements uh on the
transport protocols
are interoperable yeah i mean
so um we're talking about the
a specification with some requirements
and our implementations but we're not
talking about interop here we're not
this isn't ps
status this is just existence status
right does that help
basically we we the group the goal is
the working group needs to be convinced
by rough consensus
that the requirements and transport
protocols are transfer protocol
independent
i'm not i'm not worried about the
interrupt thing i'm worried most of the
requirements about performance
and and that's not interrupt and so it's
you know or relative performance and
stuff like that so
um i'm you notice that word doesn't
appear on this slide
that was that's deliberate okay
um performance and safety are not the
same thing
however um complete absence of
performance i.e you can't
get traffic there from here starts to
look a whole lot like scenes yeah yeah
yeah i mean
okay and we're on the same page here
because
fundamentally yeah this is fundamentally
a a the working group is going to have
to make
make a to bar to borrow a badly used
phrase rick was going to have to make a
i know it when i see it decision on
safety
okay let's move on um unless one of the
other guys wants to say something
go ahead yeah can you hear me um yeah
maybe
the the the presentation that i will
give will give also some insight on
on what implementations or plant
implementations that we have so
um hopefully that will help uh to decide
whether it's the first point at least is
sufficient
sounds good that's good thank you
jake
uh yeah hi um one one question about the
uh last bullet point on number two
uh
is is this a like already determined
uh criteria or is that like
a sort of goal in number two or
the the working group last call on l4s
ops not required to meet safety goal
like i wasn't yeah the the the primary
reason for that point
being here is that if the working group
believes that the l4s ops draft
lays out a reasonable safety case
but there is still quite a bit of work
to be done on it that's not a reason to
hold up work group last call on the elf
restaurant on the alphas drafts
okay um and this is a point for
discussion
so important for discussion it's a point
jake we discussed last time
round where we talked about would the
experiment actually help to inform the
operational draft
to inform how operators did things so
did we want to close this before
we started the publication process or
did we want to make sure it was
reasonably good
shape and then allow that draft to
mature a little bit in the working group
and we didn't really decide on how much
maturing was actually useful needed
so this is the space in which the
adoption call is being held
uh okay sure i mean
i guess
so this is about reaching consensus on
these points right
my only point is like i i am i tend to
be of the opinion that
uh that i i would like to see
a normative normative language
somewhere in the experiment uh perhaps
referencing the draft
i'm not sure whether the uh whether the
core l4s drafts
uh go forward but in the in the uh
in the i guess we can get to that uh
later after the adoption call perhaps we
can certainly get to that
at working group last call on the
alpharestraf requesting a
normative reference from the alpharest
uh drafts to the l4s ops
so they have to go forward as rfcs
together is completely reasonable
uh as a last call topic if not
yeah thank you
jay can i can i ask a question about the
normative language what are you saying
there might be normative language around
the operations
aspects that we somehow have to capture
in the working group is that
the comment uh yeah i guess
um i mean you know i'm not sure exactly
what form it would take but um but
uh sort of the the to rephrase the
opinion i
put forth before i think that the sort
of current
um tcp prog implementation seems
incompatible with classic cues et cetera
uh in source sense and uh
therefore like the sort of guidance
around um
as a l4s sender ensuring that that
you're operating on paths that do not
contain uh
classic cues is
is part of the safety story in such a
way that that
i i would prefer to see some kind of
at least should uh to that effect and
and the details of how the drafts
precisely point to each other and
whether it has to be an rfc first
i'm i'm flexible on but uh okay
that flexibility was the primary point
of that bullet let's go
and let you that is an excuse to
transition to the office draft
oh thank you let's see am i supposed to
greg slides or greg do you input your
slides
you could do it that would be fantastic
but all right which means i gotta go get
not tried
um hang on a minute i gotta go get him
okay
and i guess the position of the chairs
on the normative languages if we need
normative language for the ops
work if that's what the working group
concedes then there will be a place to
put that normative language if that's if
that's what comes out we'll find a place
to do it
if the working group needs it so the
fact that this is put up for adoption
as informational doesn't constrain the
working group from making
um rst219 language if we need it
all right let's go blink the screen and
a little bit few more clicks
we ought to have slides
yeah those okay all right greg i
should be up and tell me when you want
what want me to advance slides
okay thanks um all right so this is the
second
or except the third iteration of the
alphas ops
draft and just to reiterate what
i said last time i presented i'm the
editor of this document
um the contributors include those listed
at the bottom as well as
probably others on the working group who
have done reviews and
um and made suggestions um hopefully i
didn't miss
uh folks but uh um
contributions of text to improve the
draft are
welcome and i assume if this gets
adopted
by the working group that we'll see more
of you and and more contributions so
um our next slide
uh the scope of the draft um so as the
the name
of it is operational guidance for
deployment of l4s and the internet
that may sound like it's covering more
ground than it actually
is the scope of the craft actually
is specific to the issue of uh
coexistence of l4s traffic and classic
traffic
in an rfc 3168 bottleneck
it has expanded uh since the last
iteration and to now discuss vpns in fq
bottlenecks as well as single cube
bottlenecks um although more
elaboration that could certainly be
added
the goal is to provide guidance for
operators of
l4s hosts as they deploy all for us
on the internet also guidance for
operators of networks in particular
networks that are currently running rfc
3168 links
and then finally recommendations for
researchers
and the goal of this document is not
uh just to cover in-band detection and
fallback
and that's an aspect that's been
discussed um within the working group
paramount over the last
year or more um it does include that but
it also includes some other aspects
related to safe deployment of l4s
greg he's still there
we seem to have lost greg's audio
i lost great video as well so um he'll
be back in a moment i guess
okay
probably needs an l4s service to run
effectively
gee that was coming wasn't it
say to the standard qn would work
all right all right
i think that was the problem
[Laughter]
well we'll we'll wait a couple of
minutes to see if greg rejoices since
he's in the middle of a pitch for
adoption
miracle helpfully says in the chat that
greg lost connectivity and left
and left the room well that's very
helpful
we could check in the meantime if people
have read the document and uh
yes excellent why don't we start to pull
can we work out how to do that on the
tools i'll let you go
fight that i'm i'm just trying to make
sure this lights work
for many people
so i just started a poll if you go to
the little bar
chart at the top this one's an easy one
how many people have read
the oh you spelled people correctly i
didn't
i have read the ops draft in one of its
versions just so we're going to feel as
a working group
if you click on that please if you've
read one of these versions so we know
whether we're judging something that
people have actually seen
i see jake's looking for the pole in the
meat
echo uh icons the upper right is the
thing that looks like a bar chart
not the most intuitive icon i think that
was designed for the chairs the posts
and people who are who are supposed to
uh participate
okay so she i currently see
14 people have raised hands 25 have
not pressed the do not raise hand button
of 85 participants so we have
um a number of people who've raised
their hands saying that they've read
this
and i'm going to end the session just
now
and then we'll go back to greg's
presentation
i'll report for the notes how many
finally
finally we had 17 people said that
they'd read
this or a recent version of the ops
draft
so 17 had read it and we'll continue
this
after greg's talk if greg's able to join
us now
uh hopefully you can hear me yes welcome
back
great i'm not sure when uh when you lost
me
um uh did i get through the school play
probably about the probably about at uh
somewhere after uh provide
recommendations to researchers if you
quickly cover the last two thirds of the
slide let's see if we
move through the rest of the slides
quickly okay um well the middle bullet
is um
uh just a high level scope well it's a
little bit more detailed than the
top bullet um but in a couple slides
we'll go through
the a summary of the contents um so i
won't spend time on that one
um the last bullet is just to point out
that um
general requirements for the experiment
etc
are intended to be included in the core
l4s drafts
not in this one but this draft does rely
on requirements that
exist in the l4s id draft including the
ability for
a host to disable the l4s functionality
and
for a host to monitor uh or provide
statistics that can be used to monitor
for presence of rfc 3168
all right next slide um status
this is the third version of the draft
previous ones were discussed on previous
ietfs a new
material this time addressed some
comments around
uh mentioning mentioning vpns and fq
coddle that combination
as well as uh added discussion on
fairness
and purple awareness and um
and then some general text improvements
um which we can
just go on to the next slide do you
think greg do you think the draft is to
the point where review by
uh operations folks would be helpful
it's visually complete and operating
that having operator folks look and tell
us whether whether
whether it's reasonably useful would be
good or do you need another spin on this
i think it's at a state now where that
would be useful
cool we'll have to see if we can do that
okay
all right so this is a summary of the in
the contents of the draft
um and um
i think an interest of time how much
detail to go through here
um top piece the draft graph does
discuss
uh prevalence of the issue and severity
of the outcomes um that
that was a comment that was made
recently on the mailing list that
more material there could be helpful so
i don't disagree with that
um so certainly would welcome
contributions uh
in that section um but the general
uh uh statement of the draft is that l4s
coexist well with classic traffic
aside from this issue with shared 3168
cues
um and the two uh
uh scenarios where where that um
that comes into play um then that's and
then it's primarily an issue for long
running flows to high data rates with
long rtts
um and the result of it is lforce flows
out competing classic flows
to one degree or another depending on
the scenario
and then has a summary of some
historical issues around peripheral
awareness
uh the next bullet um there's a section
that
that is dedicated to talking about
detection of
3168 bottlenecks via experiments
and then that section is uh um
essentially a intended to be useful not
just for
researchers doing experiments but also
for
l4s host deployers to do experiments
prior to turning on l4s or as part of
their a b testing
as they enable a new congestion control
right now that section is essentially a
pointer to the fallback report
um the link on the lower right hand side
um but the intention is that
we will summarize some of the most
important
um uh methods that are in that
that report in the draft itself um but
now it's just
just a pointer um one thing to note and
there was some discussion on the list
about this idea of having l4s nodes
disable 3168 ecn so disable
ce marking of ect 0 traffic in order to
facilitate
detection of l4s versus classic
3168 and
uh bob did a fairly in-depth
um analysis of that and then thinking
through it and put together some slides
um which come to the conclusion that
that may not be um as useful as
we maybe thought it might have been a
few months back so
um so currently the draft does not
recommend or
assume that l4s nodes are are doing
um that disabling of 3160 adcn
and then the last two bullets guidance
for operators of
of hosts and guidance for operators of
networks that have bottlenecks or the
specific
[Music]
guidance and uh and recommendations for
those two constituents and particularly
on the host side we've
broken it out into general purpose
servers
eg web server servers versus more
specialized servers for example cloud
gaming cloud vr
type applications your non-tcp
applications and then also a partition
between edge servers which serve a small
population of networks or hosts
versus more general hosts that may be
serving
content across longer paths or a broader
set of
hosts all right next slide
um there were some comments on the
mailing list since the posting of draft
02.
um as this summarizes those um
and how are we doing on time do we have
time to discuss these or should i just
mention them
we should probably just simply i think
what you want to do is say that you've
uh taken a look at these some of them
dealt with some haven't been and let's
get on to some open discussion here
so that sounds good yeah so this is just
a summary of those issues
um we'll work on um
well we'll be the mailing list as well
as um you know people have contributions
with text
that will improve the draft certainly
those would be um useful
all right okay last slide then is um
some site says adoption call in progress
um and i think it's productive to leave
this slide up
and uh open for discussion and comments
jonathan you're first go ahead
okay now i could say a lot here but
i will restrict myself to uh talking
about the
long flows thing from the previous slide
um and i'll just say that i disagree
with that statement
and we should um open a discussion about
it on the list
in the interests of meeting time
okay thank you okay
are there any more questions or
clarifications for people
on what greg has presented
all right i think we probably got to run
a sense the room poll
on draft adoption you want to do the
honors corey and maybe people can find
the uh
uh and find the tool this time
i have done it so we're asking here
how many people think this id this
internet draft
forms a basis for a work item in tsvwg
i.e they support adoption and
progression in the working group
this is a basis for preparing a
milestone for work on this
please raise your hand if you support it
please do press the do not raise hand
if you think this is not a basis for
work
and don't and don't press either option
if uh
you prefer not to express expression
opinion either way
or if you haven't read it yet so
we won't hold that again we won't hold
that against you
okay so the numbers are settling down
um please go to the um
graph icon and press it if you wish to
raise your hand
to help us judge that this is ready for
support
and please note that this is an
informative poll
we do this usually in the working group
to see how many people have read
the document we do monitor the list and
we also take this as input but we do the
actual call on the working group list
where the adoption call is in progress
so that will conclude
after the ietf meeting so we won't be
making an announcement
at this meeting okay we have a stable
entry we have i'm going to close it and
report the numbers
so 25 people think this id forms a basis
for work
in tsvwg to support adoption and
progression in the working group
thank you greg for presenting that
please make sure
you record any comments you might have
on this in the working group
email so we know if there are any more
concerns or comments on the adoption
process itself
i will make a determination at the end
of the period david very good and as
as noted in the minutes we have one uh
one
one do not raise hand uh
uh i think that that i think that that
that qualifies
as sense of the room uh or since the
virtual room is to adopt is to adopt the
draft
thank you for the sign yeah i've noted
that one against
25 for man
okay it's customary at this stage if you
wish
to allow you to come to the mic and
say why you think that the
position against is one that we should
consider
but we don't need to
it might be best to to consider any
discussion on the list focused
on focus on the meristed draft
excellent good car do you want to say
something
nope hit wrong button happens off
okay all right um
so next up i need to go find um
which deck am i looking for to start
with bob
uh that should be mine it's the
right requirement bingo
all right and
okay um and there it is
how about that okay thanks um
so this presentation is about the prague
requirements survey that
we did on the list you might have seen
it hopefully
um so it's uh an overview
a quick going through it in
matters of time so maybe next slide
so these are the the results
that we we got so the goal of this
survey was to
uh to get uh a view on
how feasible realizable the the prague
requirements are at the moment and
whether they were supported by broad
community mainly of course people who
would implement congestion controls
so we provided a template which
listed all the normative requirements
and the three performance requirements
which were also part of the initial
tcp prague requirements set but are not
really requirements
but anyway sometimes considered as
important
uh performance requirements
and we asked two questions uh whether
you agree with this
uh whether you want to meet this
requirement
or not um and to what level and and then
also another column
to to get more explanation um
any issues experiences or even
objections you have to the requirements
maybe next slide
so we got multiple responses of which
three were publicly shared so that was
our own template because we also gave as
an example
a fielding template of the tcp prague
plus
then the scream congestion control by
ingimar ericsson and then we also
received geforce now congestion control
by nvidia
um so they are listed the the detailed
responses
they were collected on the link uh you
can have a look at them
uh for for detailed responses
we also got other responses shared
privately and at this stage we didn't
get any confirmation whether we could
make them public so we kept it we
respected that
but we made a consolidated summary
which is also available on the the same
well on the same page but directly in
the document that you can find there on
the link
next slide
so to give a a a quickly a big overview
um so these are requirements
which everybody was agreeing with let's
say
they would be compliant and support it
or plan to support that
um it are obviously the obvious ones
which you need to make it work you could
say
um maybe zooming in uh
so alpha sender must set ecte
field to ect1 ecn field to ect1
there was a concern or or a remark
mentioned that operating system apis and
kernels
did not support it yet so it would be
interesting to know
what stops these operating systems and
kernels to put
these functionalities into their
mainstream uh
is it really the the the release of rfcs
of these documents or
or something else so if
if there is some insight in in that um
that would be useful because it is it
would be useful to have these
apis today already and that the kind of
rollout could begin to
to be less uh hurdled by experiments
and then another thing maybe i zoom in
um provide feedback to the extent of ce
marking
everybody wants that of obviously but
for the accurate ecn for the tcp
protocol for other protocols there were
not really
there were not any problems mentioned
but for
tcp itself the accurate ecn there were
still some remaining concerns
i think they need to be handled in the
tcpm working group
as soon as possible let's say
also the most reduced rtt bias was
broadly accepted
and also not part of the requirements
also for the long-run trip times
they would implement or already
implement this
um and also another one the rack
requirement let's say you should should
take loss by in in time based units
uh all of them did already or are
planning to
to do this the also the non-normative
performance
suggestions were all accepted and
seen feasible and and the results on the
draft were only minor clarifications
let's say that were asked
next slide
the the only strong objection that we
got on the draft was
related to the documentation only
requirements i call them here
so must specify in in detail
how the congestion control works or how
you define quantify and justify burst
limit approach
um so the objections where are these
documentation requirements really needed
how can we be enforced
uh may not be possible for proprietary
protocols that don't want to share this
so and it would also create kind of
precedence i think in itf drafts to to
have
uh requirements a mandatory requirement
to describe the
implementation in detail so we we remove
these
i think that's fair enough um if you
have could you
uh yeah could you put in some language
encouraging people to publish this
information
for you for for um uh
use for the knowledge of the community
um
um uh i have no problem with removing
the must requirements i think
encouraging people to publish what
they've done is always a good thing
yeah i well i don't know whether it's
still in there but
it's indeed we can do
that i guess um then there are a set of
requirements
which needed experimental data um
two too high level ones at least the
first one is to scale down to fractional
congestion window
so not all everybody is convinced that
it really will be a problem on the
internet
and they are not planning to implement
it even
multiple other ones already supported
or have research code available
or plan to implement it so um
i think the shoot here is in the right
place
um and it is also not really a safety
issue per se because it's
already handled by the by the aqm
uh when when the the signal starts to
saturate it should
use drop anyway so it would only be a
kind of performance improvement to
prevent latency if there is only alpha s
or or drop on
on coupled equipments so it's
it's fair i think to to look at further
real experimental experience on on that
during the experiments there was some
updates on the draft based on
discussions
i have no idea where the shoot is
appropriate please make sure the draft
uh reflects the develop further during
further during experiment that this is
one of the things the experiment is
investigating
it does already good
okay gauri has a question or
i think you're muted curry
um anyway okay
um next
requirement that needed experimental
data
uh we all know is the um
the classic ecn detection um
so there are a set of uh normative
mustang shoots defined currently in the
draft
there there was some let's say uh
confusion about what it exactly means
meant is the detection itself required
is it is it uh well the
obviously the robust detection scheme
needs real deployment experience
and and others say but the combination
with delay based control
would minimize potential issues so it
could also be a reason
not to to have this detection per se
there because it's already
kind of circumvened by the latency
aspect of it which is currently not in
tcp product but several
implementations have this um so
um so so first of all yeah it should be
clear whether it's only the monitoring
which is
required or also the detection is
required
and i think the detection
needs to be developed um well it's it's
part of the discussion and it's also
what greg already mentioned in the
operational guidelines draft
also clarifications on this
automatically fall back
so the next requirement says must be
replaceable
while it could also be that the alpha s
part is disabled so it becomes in the
same congestion control so it becomes a
normal
uh classic response only congestion
control so there are multiple
implementations possible and also
whether it it is required on active
flows or only on new flows
especially if it it is being replaced i
think because of that hard statement it
could be
uh so so anyway uh also some
um clarifications and and disambiguation
uh is required there um
and i think the requirements need to be
aligned when the operational guidelines
draft is adopted
so that needs probably some further
clarifications um i see jonathan and bob
ask a question or
jonathan you're there first let's see if
we can do this
briefly here as i'm sure we could have a
multi-hour discussion on this if we
wanted to
uh yes um well mostly i
noticed that the references currently
are to
bob viscose paper on the subject
we have seen one of the algorithms uh
from that paper implemented so far and
uh last year and the results from that
were not
encouraging shall we say uh there is a
second
algorithm with a more active profile
which seems to have a better theoretical
basis
but i would question how practical it is
due to the volume of probe that are
needed
to establish a uh statistical
relationship
so um of course we will need to discuss
this
in more detail
yes
i just i just um wanted to come in i
will also respond to jonathan
what originally came to the cue just to
say that we haven't changed any of the
text in the draft
based on all this feedback from the
survey until the adoption call is
finished because it
you know that that makes a difference as
to what the text is likely to be you
know so
um but to to respond to johnson's point
yes that
you've picked up the new idea we've put
into that paper
on using the spacing between marks to
distinguish between
um classic and um and
um alpha s and um actually
had another idea since then which isn't
in there to um
use a pulse or a chirp um to
find whether the aqm is smoothing
its response or whether it's an
immediate response which i think is even
possibly even even more um uh
specific way of of um finding the two
after it's finished it's slow start and
it's found some capacity and it's
got some ce marking to um
to do a pulse okay so i think
let's see if we can get back to those
slides i think occlusion slides sounds
about right which is more work
more more more work needed
in this more work needed in this area on
the draft
and potentially also the the deployment
experience
because um well the effectivity of all
these schemes
can only be evaluated during the
experiment itself
i think um then there was uh another
compliant or at least to the intent of
how i think most people will interpret
the requirement
but it could also be interpreted very
strict
specifically coexist safely with tcp
renault congestion control
a lot of concerns are what does it mean
i don't want to be as degraded as reno
for long rtts
so so there there is already a
discussion on the working group list
to find the correct wordings for this
requirement because
indeed we don't want that the congestion
controls behave
exactly like reno and especially not in
the
pathological cases then the last topic
maybe in general over all the
requirements is uh the balance between
openness to innovation and to allow
multiple congestion controls
and guidance and recommendations uh we
saw
quite some requests for how should it
work how should
this be done so so the
the goal of the draft at the moment i
think is to keep it
open for for multiple congestion
controls
even that certain people might or
interpret certain requirements very
strict but
that's definitely not our goal so if you
see like
specific mechanisms being defined that
could be done
otherwise i think the result is
important and not the mechanism
shouldn't be
defined which doesn't mean that maybe
certain numbers or
interoperability requirements
are needed um for for practical examples
uh we have now also the tcp product
congestion
control drafts in iccrg release the
first version
um so there it's described what
tcp prac is doing currently um but there
are other
open source implementations already
which you can
use for let's say mechanisms
that could be interesting in in solving
many issues or or
mechanisms that can be used to to for
for better performance
on the red text i'd suggest a two-prong
approach one is i see a list discussion
on picking the precise words
and the other thing i would would
suggest is pick
one or two well-known examples that do
co-exist safe in tcp reno but don't have
reno's long rtt
behavior and include those and that that
should get the point across
okay
okay thanks um as a conclusion um
well it's uh i think it was a very
useful exercise to get a better view on
on the different positions
the strong objections were removed
okay there is still the suggestion we
have to add
but it also made clear that live
data is is needed for for those two then
at least um and and for the rest that
there are quite already some
implementations
uh and and all the requirements are seen
feasible and our plans to be implemented
um by most of the congestion controls
so other inputs are still welcome
preferably public
but if private we can also
take those for the next iteration
if needed okay that's it
okay comments questions
i go get bob's slides
so my comment was was rather
um quick it was that um there are other
congestion controllers out there apart
from reno
and this isn't the place where we should
in tsvwgb describing
the complexities of sharing with
different congestion controllers so
we need to use language which is wide
enough i think
not get bogged down in the details of
reno versus bbr
this is cubic business yeah
yeah and for that matter if the examples
exist the examples
will both example out of the examples
would have two two benefits one is they
would
um clearly show people that you don't
have to have reno's
uh long rtt behavior requirement and the
other is they provide additional
examples congestion controls with which
alpha
traffic ought to coexist
uh vidi i see your next in line
the question in similar lines like i
wanted to ask if it's
during the experiment if we have seen
whether uh l4s
conduction controller is fair or does it
coexist with cubic
with cubic you know like just doing the
classic ecn
um well yes the current implementation
is actually reno
tcp prague falls back to to reno
behavior
on drop so it is
definitely even even with reno
let's say almost compatible but um
um well these are these are things that
most of the implementers for real
deployments want to improve obviously
and um well it's
it's at that level that we probably need
the correct warning
okay richard um just a clarification
question
did you ask for the response um after a
loss
or after uh the l4s has
given you a proportional metric
by which the congestion control should
react
and then and then scale that scale that
um
depending on your arena or cubic
i think for both
loss is definitely i think one thing i
think it's same i guess
that's what uh coin was saying that it's
same
for loss it reacts in the same way for
feedback
what's the what's the difference or the
accurate feedback maybe as a clarify
clarification i didn't say that the tsp
prac requirements expect that it has the
same
response as uh reno
we want to in the tcp prague
requirements or in the prague
requirements better we
want to leave that open um not describe
the mechanism necessarily i think
is is the question here when i say tcp
prague
implementation in linux this is now the
current implementation but
it's not like every congestion control
should do this
so we we have to be also tcp prague is
not
the uh congestion control for l4s
or or rock requirements maybe we should
never have called it
tcp prague because it's uh
the confusion is like these requirements
mean
that the performance is not optimal in
long round trip times or whatever
claims i think there are other
implementations
uh we are kind of building a reference
implementation
for for research uh we are even not
service providers and or not plants to
to develop
robust and and very performant
congestion control
so it's it's up to other people who have
the right
uh um
how do you call that the right need for
it to to develop it i think um
and and it shouldn't be like relying on
us to
to do that job for them um i think
expectations we've got a few minutes
left let's go quick switch to bob's
slides and bob if you can be
really really brief we might be able to
let ingomar squeeze a word inside
in a way i'd rather you yield to engine
markers i've had a look at these slides
but
i'll i'll just tell people what's in
these slides and they can then they can
go and look at them if you can jump
next slide this summarizes it all really
that we're focusing on the
congestion control implementation
particularly faster getting up to speed
which
the abbreviation is guts and so faster
guts
and um the the other activities that
just been talked about are going on in
parallel obviously
next um
so there's a new draft um documenting
the
the prior congestion control published
yesterday
um some summaries there about it being
protocol
and os agnostic and you know this point
about it not being the one true prague
that just said next
this one i think yeah just what's inside
here's where you are that's a summary of
who's helped on all the drafts and
what's changed and
um and um where we are
and that's it
and uh ingamar go for it
uh yeah can you hear me or uh
did you hear me yes yeah great
i know how may i know roughly minus one
minute left or
no how many times minutes do you have
before you cut the line
um give yourself at least the five
you're planning to take and those who
are interested will stick around
okay okay this is our
ultimate about the master thesis is just
also done by
brunello roughly one year ago actually
and uh
it was a published and you have the link
there if you want to read
all the stuff and it's about uh
get on or online and cloud gaming
in 5g more or less and it's based on l4s
and an implementation you find your own
for the alpha
we can skip this glossary and read it
after after presentation if you like
but the outline is that we use a
simulation
a system simulator a proprietary one
that models a
typical 3dpp deployment or a 3dpp
standard deployment
with 21 cells base stations and
you have a rather narrow bandwidth and
uh
use a screen congestion control as a
baseline for
for a typical uh congested control
algorithm that can run
with or without and
you have a variable load that's a sort
of increasing
intensity of users and also a number of
background
traffic loads that hammers the links to
get more
credible scenario and we run with
various scheduling algorithms which
means that they're settling you're sadly
one user at a time in a
in a in a five-year system well
first we have a round-robin settling
that is typically used for a
normal mobile-back
mobile broadband traffic and then you
have something called called quality of
source they give
enhanced priority for the gaming users
and you can skip the next slide
and we use here a cube based uh
look it's okay it is a how we can
realize it in the 3dpp network is that
we use a quality of service
framework where you sort of put set up
as an extra barrier actually for the
alphas flows
that means that you can keep the latency
low or that flow and
it of course it assumes that it's on the
l4s traffic then you can help first mark
that and for that we can use the traffic
filters that are available and
remap the flows that have this uh l4s uh
other thor also is capable to that flow
and you can call possibly combine it
with the ip5 tuple if you like also
and next slide
okay i'm probably perhaps you need to go
back to the slides
here okay
then we have uh what we're using is this
cube based l4s marker which means that
you actually
you measure the queue buildup up and rsv
layer
but you mark on the pdp layer and the
reason why you do that is that the
ip packets on the rlc layer there are
hidden by encryption so you need to
actually feed
up the marking to the pcp layer rather
ip header is uh visible and essentially
that is a
call you can call it tail marking or
feedback and
forward or whatever or you call it in
the ihf
nomenclature and you have something
typical thresholds and you go to a
probability marking and the threshold
the
in the stimuli in the simulation studies
that you have with a higher and lower
threshold that are five and ten
milliseconds
that can depend on the what kind of
numerology that you are using on is it a
time division duplex or is it frequency
division duplex
so we can uh you probably need to tune
those depending what kind of
raw nectar that you're running you can
skip two slides i can believe you can
jump
and this sort of uh shows a time trace
comparison
when you are using uh not for us in a
congested network in a contestant
situation where you
though the bit rate needs to go down to
like 30 megabits per second or even
lower to avoid you build up
first you have a note 10 for s and use a
round robin scheduler and you see it you
have a
the network k2 delay spikes up to like
um almost 150 milliseconds and that can
and that can sort of uh seriously harm
the performance
for for online gaming or cloud gaming
and then you have a you enable l4s you
keep the same uh
scheduler that is use a normal mobile
broadband
you can see that you reduce the bitrate
a bit but on the other hand you get a
much slower q delay
and then you have if you have used q
quality of service you can actually
increase the bit rate a bit because you
push back
normal mobile broadband users
and you still keep the same low delay
that's what the what the keyos gives
next slide
here we look at the video frame delay
and here i must say that
this video friendly also accommodates
that you have some
capturing and uh and coding delay also
in the soup
that's why the minimum is 40
milliseconds here
what is important here is to see that
without fresh marking you manage to keep
the
video frame delay low up to
a relatively high high load in the
system
guess compared to those when you know
not using l4s
and you can probably skip
the next one here
and also one important okay perhaps won
back
yeah okay you're really really in a
hurry here
but okay now what the important is
that what the alphas manage is to keep
the the network q delay low and that is
shown here
that you managed to keep the network q
build up very low
and that is the main purpose
the purpose of the of the l4s here
and also if you you add use additional
quality of storage of course you
improve improve the performance because
that means essentially that you can push
back
other users in order to keep your q
delay budget
next slide that's the shoulder
transmitted rate and here it does
is something that is up to discussion
here is uh maybe online or offline on
is that you actually trade off a bit of
a throughput in order to get
a lower delay and part of the reason is
that the video
encoders typically have a very varying
frame sizes which have shown up in our
upper right grapher and
another one is that you have in the
cellular access you have
fast fading that means that the
throughput tips occur on a
millisecond basis so you need to have
some extra headroom in order to get the
q delay
build up so that means that you actually
push down the bitrate to be
a bit but that is a trade-off that you
need to do and
there are also shortcuts here
one shortcut is of course if you have a
very
strict priority scheduling you can push
out all other users then you can get
your
throughput but get other problems
instead
and i believe us probably stops there
unless they're all questions and we're
running out of time and
think about where do you where do we get
the full details of this
we've uploaded the sides in the slide
deck is the thesis available
yes can you repeat that i didn't take
quite
where do we get more details of what
you've just presented
where can we find well yeah you will
find it in the multi-thesis presentation
if you
in the on the link on the first page
here
yeah thank you
it's 116 pages let me go
carefully copy that link into
the minute since i can do the cut and
paste
okay great
and thanks everyone who presented thanks
for keeping
time we we had quite a lot of stuff
going on in tsvwg this time round
and it was good to have lots of
participants
we have a number of adoption and last
calls coming up on the list please
look out for them and we do look forward
to seeing you in other ietf meetings on
the next tsvwg meeting
and we've clearly demonstrated that we
need to go back to asking for at least
four hours
in the future three hours is not enough
this time sorry about that
was of you anything finally to say
excellent okay um if you're going to uh
prepare presentations for the next
meetings
please do stick by the deadlines and
send them in advance
uh last minute presentations are really
challenging in agenda planning
but apart from that we just wish you the
best and um
keep talking on the list
thank you very much everybody