[Music]
so
that might have been our time to start
the meeting uh sound
what makes daniel is aware that this has
opened mike
or if you should nuke him i guess his
work for gorydon
ah he made it himself good
okay gory you ready to start
yes
audio from glory
okay i think i can make this work
outside of slideshow mode so that give
me some
some access to it to me echo
um all right folks we're ready to go
so yeah everybody's apparently on
mute at the moment gory we'll see gory
social is offline
wes um are you there
make that two working group chairs
offline all right
i guess i need to go ahead and get and
uh and
get get this started there's
cory hang on
looking at the jabber shot i think
miteko might have some small issue
because it seemed it dumped
quite a lot of users
and that's
yeah it looks like my show okay no no
end of fun
gory are you there
you just muted yourself try again
okay i'm not mute okay i am here now
uh a long name yeah
it's just wonderful it's very easy to to
double mute yourself then you have to
left
left meta shift click just to figure out
how to get out of it
all right i think i've got things set up
there's enough uh the slide's big enough
i think people can see it so i can
probably
toggle back and forth between windows
and we'll try to make that work
all right um welcome to uh
uh to uh the transport area working
group meeting at
uh ietf 110 uh online
all three group chairs are here uh we're
all remote
this is the note well um reminder that
uh as part of registering the meeting um
you agreed to this this applies
this applies to you um all kinds of
references there which
uh which uh which i will not go through
okay do we have a
lead notetaker
we need somebody to
us i was planning on taking some notes
okay um and if you could start by
pasting the agenda
in that that tends to work really really
well with
all right let's do that i mean
remo we don't need the blow by blowers i
suspect most people don't
read read the minutes for blow by blow
we do need to record
uh any any any major decisions
uh that get read
okay um
need some people to watch jabber um
all you need to do is if is if you've
got your your eyes on jabber and you see
something turn
up in chat raise your hand and with luck
one of us will notice
and we'll get somebody on uh we'll get
you over
or we're making the comment in jabber
onto the mic
um as usual we always need reviewers for
our working of drafts and a reminder
folks please
uh do add um
tsvwg to the uh name of any internet
draft submitted
that way we might actually notice them
okay some meet echo usage tips um
both the chat and the meeting notes can
be separated
into separate windows or tabs it's
actually quite useful because it means
um that you can toggle back and forth
between windows on your screen to change
context as opposed to
having to find the right icon in meet uh
in meet echo and it leaves you meet echo
window focus
on speakers cues and slides we just had
discussion about this
um the icons have changed in fact
this is hand uh
hand icon mic on please don't use
um the mic uh icon
until acknowledged by the chairs you
just saw uh a demonstration of this and
what you're looking at will be
will be uploaded some point as a yet yet
new and improved version of the chair
slides
um in general we need uh reviewers for
documents
um if you are interested in your
documents reviewed please review
other documents both here and help out
other working groups by
uh reviewing their documents best people
uh will help will help us out
uh and listed on this slide is some uh
uh idc new review
uh sctp core standard update uh
the the main 4960 bis draft is is
getting mature
udp options uh and all the various other
dots related to ec in this working group
okay close to the status first of all
um the diff server rtc webq
os uh draft has finally been published
as
uh as an rfc the infamous webrtc cluster
um was uh uh popped out and we did in
fact managed to get the process rc
underwrite
it includes the updates we need to make
for the
uh uh lower effort of php which itself
is documented rs8622
we have one id at the iesg finally
the transfer hair confidentially density
impacts i expect the isg will be taking
this
up not long after this meeting week we
have one ids with the ad
review in progress um this is uh the
sctp net draft
i've seen a major review from the ad
within
in the past 24 hours it's funny how
meeting week uh
cause uh is a forcing function for stuff
to happen anyhow
um uh expect to see more on that draft
in the near future we have two ideas
from the chairs and authors jefferson
last call and again the meeting week is
functioned as
as a forcing function in that new
draftsman posted with
with what might be close to the final
text um
yours truly who is the shepherd for this
direct these two drafts
um is getting tired of reading off the
status um
these drafts will be submitted uh to the
iac publication
by the next uh next uh i i etf i think
we're fairly close and i'm gonna
going to put in the effort to get it
done okay
here are the additional working group
drafts there are six of them
uh sctp three alphas drafts
the the non-queue building php and udp
options
and as we get things out of the working
group we'll have some bandwidth
uh uh with which to take on uh new work
one of the pieces of new work that it
does look like a really unique take on a
fairly short order
is um there's a credit card request is
meeting to
adopt uh the alfres uh operational
guidance draft
okay whole bunch of related drafts let
me
go through them quickly path mp
discovery continues to be an active area
um uh gory has a draft on how to do this
with for udp with udp options
there is a draft over in six man and how
this ipv6
uh and a draft in the tram working group
on how to do this for the stun that
traversal mechanism
for sctp michael tuxen has a couple of
drafts one on edp encapsulation
one on multipath and diffserv dhcp
selection
uh anna kastura has a draft on this this
sort of very close to the meeting so we
did not
put it on the agenda however it is a
very promising draft please
read this as it's likely to be a
candidate uh for working with adoption
this is trying to roll up all the things
we've learned the hard way about how
about how to assign and how not how not
to assign uh
uh dscps to uh to new
new new perhaps behaviors
more related drafts uh improv digital
guidelines
uh multipath dccp i have a status slide
on that which we'll put up
in a in a little bit network layer
multipath
application air aware networking oh gee
i misspelled that word didn't i hang on
one of the nice things about being this
this mode i can fix my fix my mistakes
in real time um primary draft to read is
the gap analysis draft
not for discussion here this is a top of
interest uh to a lot of
areas in ietf the primary discussion
forums for this will be the routing area
work group meeting on thursday
and the int area working group meeting
on friday
and we have a uh new draft uh
uh on uh transport for satellite um
yet another uh chapter in this in in
this on ongoing adventure
okay uh we're about to go bash the
agenda
um but the basic outline is
dr collins accomplishments and status
today which we're in the middle of now
milestones review coming up shortly
drafts wednesday agenda more drafts and
in particular
uh the game plan is that uh wednesday is
pretty much
devoted to the l4 s work
on which we are endeavoring in
endeavoring to make uh
make progress and so that that's what
the entire wednesday agenda is going to
be devoted to
also notice that this agenda is
completely full it looks like we may
want to ask for four hours next time
three is no longer three appears no
longer enough
okay milestone milestones review and i'm
going to try and take notes we go along
we had this optimistic notion that we'd
be able to publish the l4s uh
architecture uh draft uh
before the the two main protocol drafts
not happening
um so el forest architecture needs to
move
to uh october 2021.
um the next two milestones
are for our two uh each and cap drafts
have been
hanging around for a while um i just
promised that those will be done by the
next ietf
uh so those two milestones change to
june of 2021
sctp michael
if you're on please turn your mic on and
tell us
what a reasonable time frame uh
uh for uh sctp might be go
go ahead
so what i mean we can just from my
perspective it's ready for working group
last call
all right david i've done a review of
this
and i concur with michael that we should
ask the working group
if we can find reviewers for a last call
this meeting
okay we'll we'll go look for glasgow
reviews during this meeting
and i will put september 2020
21 on that as a new date um
that way we've got uh if things happen
and summer and
and and summer occurs um we've still got
got a got a plausible milestone it would
be lovely if we could get this done
between now and next ietf
but uh i've been through the we're gonna
get everything on my next meeting and
then discovering that
uh a third to two-thirds of the things
in the next meeting bucket don't
donate um all right
transfer options for udp
this one's been running slowly i don't
know
genu uh push it push it glory what do
you think a time frame for this one
might be
well it depends after this meeting and
joe's going to present very quickly
the changes and there looks like little
needing to be done so we're looking for
reviewers here to understand whether we
can working group let's call that so
that could be quite soon as well
all right i will make a note discuss
that in joe's session
um nqb is approaching completion
um we think we're going to get some
viewers attention to it i think i'm
going to apply the same algorithm to nqb
that we just applied to uh sctp
and put a revised date of
uh september on that greg if you're on
the call
feel free to turn on your mic and uh and
revise and send my remarks for me
um hello um yeah i think uh
the draft itself is in good shape and
we'll have a longer discussion
later today on that um and only one kind
of
new aspect that was introduced since the
last meeting that needs some discussion
other than that the uh the draft is
is in pretty good shape okay so i'm
gonna put a september
uh date on that draft and uh the scpp
draft with that that gives us that gives
us a meeting cycle to work through the
one new issue
um then we've got um
the lfrs uh the two l uh the three alpha
s
wraps including the one previous slide
are currently uh
set for october uh that's not
that's not a not a bad date yet
let's leave that alone
okay quick review of the
agenda we've just done the chairs
update announcements and heads up that's
going to come
after i run through the agenda one of
the things we've got we've got a couple
of
liaison the statements that i need to
briefly call attention to the chairs i
have to respond to
uh we'll go immediately sc uh sctp
drafts
uh then joe touch uh for udp
options the nqb draft we just talked
about
and uh anna kastura has one
once once again uh folks in gory's uh
group at uh uh have gone gone and
measured internet again
and we have some interesting interesting
um implications
uh for measurements of use of dscp2
which is one of the key proposed uh
dscps for nqb then the rest of today is
a couple of individual drafts q log
um has been proposed i think initially
the queue i think it may have
initially stood for quick it no doubt
stands for something else now
it's looking like a general logging
mechanism
we want to get some air time here to see
what people think of it
and then we have uh some measurements of
ecn
uh act on an exchange provider um
that uh will talk through through this
representing map
rg we'll talk to some implications here
this is in some ways a setup for
for wednesday which is l for which is l
for s day
um you'll see uh i'm gonna start the
author's operational guidance draft
which we're going to adoption requested
um we
then have the three main uh alfres
drafts
and ingrimar if we have time ingomar
uh will have the uh opportunity to talk
about some of the work
uh doing of racing 5g
gory go ahead um i just wanted to note
that we had
more requests for time than we could
accommodate this time
so um if you're going to make a request
for time
at an agenda in a coming meeting please
do it ahead of the time
so we can get a feel as to how much time
we need and how to allocate it
yeah my initial take is we need to ask
for four hours next time and that we
we could easily have used another hour
that we don't have
for a number of drafts that would like
to
like like some air time and it would be
good to give some of these drafts
airtime but we just
we just don't have the time
okay anybody want to
bash or martin go ahead
uh pass i was just gonna remind you to
do this
do you remind me to do what ask for four
hours next time
no uh that's the agenda okay so now we
need to bash the agenda
and marcus i know you want to bash the
agenda
yeah hi michael speaking author of the
multi-force dsp
draft somehow we had an issue in in our
conversation
um because i intended to request this
time adoption but unfortunately i
haven't got a
slot and my question is do we have
somehow five
minutes to discuss adoption this time
let me go
let's let's let's try to do that fairly
quickly i believe you sent me one slide
let me see if i can fish it out of the
chaos as masquerading as my email inbox
yeah there it is let's put that one
slide up
i think the right thing to do is going
to be to
handle the adoption call on the list
all right now i've got the slide up
now i gotta figure out how to do
stop screen share share screen
hang on um
yeah that one
and if i've done this right your one
slide is showing up
so you want to say a few things about
this slide mark sure i can do
so maybe some of you have seen that we
make some significant
uh progress on the multi-pass dcp so we
updated the draft
what we exactly did you find in the uh
on the tsv wg mailing list so there's a
link
which guides to this email
we have a new contributor to the draft
it's british telecom
and i think most important this time we
have published the multi-past thesis app
open source so
you can get all the informations how to
access the code
how to use it how to maybe set up own
test that you find on the multiple
ccp.org
then we have also seen that uh some
parties
um expressed their interest in multiples
tccp
it was casa systems like telefonica and
so on i can't remember
all of them um yeah that's why my plan
this time is to to request adoption and
happy to discuss this
now with you okay okay
go ahead yeah can i i'm i'm
pretty sure as we've been through this
before that if we're
the ietf is to do work on dccp this is
the right working group
so i think you're in the right place and
dccp isn't a protocol we've seen a lot
of
active development and implementation
activities around
recently so we would be
very interested in people who would like
to implement
this and see a need for an interoperable
standard
so if you're in the area of implementing
this
if you plan to implement it if you plan
to use
a standard if it's produced then these
are the things to speak up with on the
list that will help us
frame this question about adoption
so gary is sorry for for asking again
because
my impression was all right that was
also what we discussed last time last
itf
and my feeling was now with publishing
uh
the multiplex tccp open source as part
of the linux network
stack also uh multiple parties who
expressed already the interest on the
waiting list that this
is or should be enough to request the
adoption
am i wrong here um it's enough to start
asking the question about adoption
and there'll be more questions to follow
these are encouraging answers
i like the answers i'm hearing uh we
will have to discuss this on the list
the other thing is when you say part of
the linux stack is this
core as in is this a part of the
mainstream release that you're planning
or is it no
it's a tree it's a private sheet right
okay so
it's good for experiments it's good for
finding out about interest it's good for
doing doing work with so that's good
um this is something we obviously have
to talk with
with you and we can also talk about
this in a separate catch-up meeting with
you
but please use the list to discuss this
okay yeah thank you
jonathan are you in queue for the same
topic
um just a tiny agenda bashing thing that
i'll be talking about uh pete heist's
draft
is a defeat fair enough
fair enough and uh and as i noted in the
in the chat with you previously um just
prior to this
meeting when pete got cut from his
questions in map rg there simply wasn't
time to really ask questions or go into
the data
so we'd like to open with questions
around the data sets that have been
produced and
and see how that goes i i think it would
be useful to be able to talk about that
data it's useful data
well we're going to feel good with that
okay sounds good all right
what are we on to other new drafts or
liaison statement first
david um yeah let me first turn turn
that off
um and my apology has taken me a little
i will get better at clicking through
meet echo as the meeting goes on
uh but where i think we are now
is we are back to here
okay and we need to quickly talk about
liaison statements so there's two of
them i'll
talk about wba statement the va has sent
us a liaison statement
about uh qos across uh across
uh wi-fi and 5g
the chairs will be working on a response
to that statement and
uh we will deal we we will deal with the
content
of that response on response on the list
gore you want to cover the uh 3gpp
liaison
is a 3gpp liaison in
preparation regarding their need for
using dtls with
larger messages and
this relates to the http draft that
magnus will present so i guess we will
hear more in magnus's talk later
in this meeting which is in 4.2
and we've i think that takes care of the
announcements
and heads up and apologies that we are
in fact
short on time and needed and needed to
to
to constrain uh the mpdccp draft
to that heads up and we're not able to
call these other requests
i have taken a note that we've got to
ask for four hours next time
um okay let me stop screen sharing
and michael you want to start talking
about 4960 best please
i think you offered tom one slide
i'm sorry who's running the slides
dave i'm going to have you run your
slides i think this is this this seems
to work
so i should run this slide so are you
running the scientists today
please michael please please run your
own slides
okay um
david we need to come back to tom's one
slide after
ah i wasn't aware that one slide let's
get okay new screen share is getting
started
yeah yeah yeah give me a i it looks like
i
can't select the window
this is the interesting thing i have to
do the whole
the whole monitor
okay i can share just the window if
you'd like me to if you'd like me to do
that
that would be perfect okay done
hang on now you get to see how fast i
can click through this
um
yeah it's a i hear lots of complaints
from people about
how some of these tools work better on
windows than linux
okay um did that come through michael
perfect
next slide cool we know what it's about
so we got here this time
uh two updates of the documents uh have
happened between the last ietf and this
one
uh the old eight version is about the
transition from xml v2 to v3 so if you
compare both you have lots of white
space changes
um and the appendix a which was about
ecn
has been removed as we discussed last
the last ietf and uh gory sent
comments and they have also been
addressed in the version 08
version 09 um incorporated
basically three reviews um
and um if you go to the next slide
um one quick question um as you go
through accepted
well path mtu is a really common
concept i had three really drafts on
there um
do we have someone in the working group
who's trying to
to write her to all the on all the
various drafts
that are working on path mtu
um i would say how i use this
and what the comments are so like so the
the
the document um so i got lots of
editorial comments but this one was
i would say not not only editorial so
um in a lot of places in the documents
um
um something about the size of the
packet or something like this was
mentioned
and it was vague intentionally vague
and this doesn't seem to be appropriate
anymore so
um there are two contacts
one is a size argument related to the
size of the packet
um like does it fit does it need to be
fragmented and so on and so i changed
um the usage there to pmtu which means
the
maximum size of an sctp packet on
a particular path and the size of the
http pack is
the size of the ip payload um so that's
pmtu
that's consistently used there as pmtu
and um the size was also used in the
context of receive window congestion
window where you increase and
and reduce our numbers and there we
use now pmdcs which is the path maximum
data chunk size
and if you are within the context of
of this document it's just uh the pmtu
minus the size of the
the common header minus uh if you're not
a multiple of four
um if you have auth sap authentication
then you have to
also subtract the size of the
authentication header
but so this is now handled more
precisely
um if you want to change the names i
don't care to change the names
um some of the suggestions which haven't
been accepted was uh
split fast retransmission there was a
suggestion to include this but this is
used for multipath transport
and multipath http is not something the
working
wants to work on so um i
didn't accept that um the other one was
uh that the association fails eventually
if the peer does stop reading date user
data
and this is not how transports work so
if they
if the connection stays alive in the
sense of you can reach your peer
the peer just is not reading anymore
that's an application layer problem but
not a transport layer problem
uh the next one was that um out of the
blue packets should only be so a packet
should only be out of the blue
if it's um um if it's uh
if it's for a particular endpoint so if
a host
running a kernel stack um gets a packet
and there is no open port for it it
shouldn't be considered out of the blue
so this
in my sense not what out of the blue
means um
there was a suggestion to change that
receiver may send it about in response
to an out of the blue
packet currently the text says should
and um this is a protection mechanism
for
for nodes not running http and it should
stay there
and the last one was to provide a
parameter set which is more appropriate
for signaling networks but
we have been through this discussion i
think in 1999 or 2000
um where the ietf does things for the
internet and not for signaling networks
so
uh the parameter sets are for signal uh
for for the internet
not for signaling networks um i listed
the people who
provided feedback thank you very much um
i
pinged three additional person people i
haven't got
feedback from but i picked them again so
from my perspective if you go to the
next slide
um the documents
to me screen too many windows yeah
next time there we go yeah so uh
i i got one comment from magnus that he
wants a
definition of control chunk which is now
in for the next version
but um except for addressing new
comments
there's nothing on it to do with so
please read it or stop the writing
okay corey wants to say something so
gory go ahead and then we need to figure
out what to do here
okay um michael are you familiar with
the implementations are they following
this this update is this new stuff to
them or is this stuff that's already
done and needs to be documented i'm not
familiar with the solaris implementation
but linux and previously should be more
or less
should be more or less compliant
excellent if people want to comment on
that on the list that's fine
okay um so let's let's
let's try something innovative here we
need some working group last call
reviewers
if you're willing to review and comment
on this virtual ass call assume working
glass call happens uh either later this
month
or in april please click on the raise
your hand
join q icon
and to clarify david if you've already
reviewed and will be happy to confirm
your reviews please also click
i see magnus and gory okay and
we may round ups try to round up some
other reviewers some of the folks who
provided comments
michael has reached out for comments on
the important thing is we do need to
have
a number of people read the draft at
uh what new glass call and a fresh pair
of eyes would almost certainly help as
michael's working on this
uh for quite some time suspect he knows
a lot of the text by heart
yeah i guess timo will reread it
i can place an extra caveat if we don't
get people to review it then of course
the working group last call walk
complete
there's my little threat but i don't see
the reason
avoiding having a working group last
call after people have already given
review comments
yeah and i think the thing to do will be
we and i think that means gory
principally will work with michael to
make sure we round up some committed
uh last call some committed last call
reviewers so we so
we we we get uh sufficient reviews
when will you have your revision ready
michael for progressing this
well online is submitted so that's ready
and for this control chunk stuff it's
it's a one sentence i mean i can submit
it if you want
and then so it's ready yeah
go ahead and make all the changes
michael and we'll try and then progress
it
okay so that so dash chance coming is
coming soon and that's the version you
want
that that's ready for working with last
call
so version 10 has one sentence more than
version nine i can submit it today
okay excellent and and that is the very
mischief that is is that the version
that
that that ought to be sent to a group
last call in your opinion
yes okay cool
all right what can i ask for another
comment from michael while he's still
here
michael could you comment on sctp not
it's received some ad review and i
believe this
conversation about progressing it do you
want to give in one sentence
a current status or
something like this either way yeah
maybe i can start
so provide the context there because
actually working group hasn't seen this
uh i did a review just
finished friday i'm sorry for the very
long delay here uh
and my plan here is now after getting
some response i will update my ad review
based on some feedback from michael and
publish
and submit that publicly so everyone can
see it
i talked to um martin about doing that
too
so that's my plan going forward so
everyone can see my feedback here
and then we can have a public discussion
i think on the main list about
dealing with some of these issues etc
but uh
and and and target but yeah
yeah maybe maybe one thing i
would say is that the nut document is
very old it started i think
15 years ago um with the main
um use case uh clients behind a
consumer nut and talking to public web
servers
public servers um and magnus brought up
a use case
in which is with the virtualization
stuff where you have
multi-homing is more important and so we
we didn't
focus on that use case basically so
that's
something we might need to look at
or not okay martin and then we have to
go back to magnus because you've got the
slides the next session martin go ahead
yeah i just want to briefly say that uh
obviously the clock is going to run
out on on um magnus's
uh uh a.d time and so unfortunately
well i'm gonna have to read this thing
and unfortunately you're essentially
gonna get a double id review
and i apologize for the to the authors
for that um but that's how it's getting
working out i'm gonna
i'm gonna it's on my list to relatively
soon i hope you get those comments out
shortly after this meeting
okay as shepherd i i think we're happy
with reviews
the document has been proved vastly over
the time it's existed
and please pay attention on the list to
what's going on so you can contribute
also okay all right with that
magnus you're up you want can you share
your own slides
i can try uh let's see
i need to click that then i guess
yes
bingo level i see yeah i'll try to get
it to
full screen so yes
uh this is dtls over http uh
enough proposed update to rfc 6083
draft is uh titles there uh
it's been worked on by me and my
co-authors
uh claudio polly ferry from ericsson
john matson and
michael jackson from university
flight science so uh so
the background for this update our
proposal update is that
3dpp in the
in 5g networks uses the lsrtp
in other words rc 683 for securing
several radio network application
protocols
and it's it's load update
okay uh
why isn't it updating
has people seen update seen me flipping
let me try magnus
magnus your slides are not in
presentation mode at least what i see
no and i was i went into let's see if it
works better if ah
it seems to doesn't pick up updated yeah
i will do it from this
if you let me just i can do it like
this
so um yes so in gdp
there's at least four different uh
radio network interface related
protocols that uses
that has the theoretical potential to
send
messages over 16k which is the limit
to rfc 6083 for user message sizes
this hasn't been to my knowledge any
real message
yet but as discussion evolution goes
forward in 3dpp
this was realized as they started
discussing larger
sets etc in some cases so they need to
deal with this
and 3dpp
asking tsbw to address the issues
there's an action in that
to respond if we can deal with it etc uh
so that's gonna need
a response in some form 3dpp and
basically people would really prefer
this a general solution to address this
issue
than having to try to address it in
their individual protocols for each and
every
of them so um and that's why
they want us to look into if you can
update
rc63 and it really is the issue here is
that
683 maps produce a message to a single
detailers record
which then becomes too small because
it's only 16k
uh we also have the issues of rfc 6083
security requirements i mean this rfc is
i think 10 years old and it shows its
detail is 1.0
and it's sha one in stp oauth not that
it's
super sense problematic for a moment but
at least it's it's a little bit low
uh on security properties so
so the proposal here really is to
replace our c63 with updated
specification
define a secure fragmentation mechanism
and basically it's a very simple
diff message so looking at the right
side of screen
we have the uh plain text user message
then use fragment that into
units that fits in a detailer's records
as many as you need then you run on each
fragment
you protect that with it to create the
details record and then you concatenate
together as a protected user message
then you transmit it over http
on a particular stream as an individual
user message
and you basically rely on the sctp
authentication to ensure that the
fragments
arrive at the receiver in the correct
order and that no one can
interfere with it as these aspects of
the data being
so you have the stp authentication as a
protection for the order of the
fragments and then
each details record is individually
encrypted and integrity protected
no i should go back sorry
we also have the security requirements
fixing that
we also looked into some signaling of
supported message sizes from the
by the end point uh and
this is now also defined as a sctp
adaptation layer
and with a handshake indication and it
allows us to do
something which uh
avoid some of the uncertainty so when
you're doing this in the handshake you
already know that you're gonna run
details
on all the messages so you have no
question or not if
this should be protected or not um
you also do like some housekeeping or
saying oh eye data for this
large message is really useful because
otherwise you're gonna run
potentially into some bottlenecks and
we're also trying to clarify some of the
details 1.2 renegotiation
so that's the kind of what we're trying
to accomplish here with the updated
proposal
then we have as i said this is still
relying on sctp authentication you can't
use this without it it's
sap authentication is keyed by the dtls
and the details fragmentation mechanism
and
re replay protection of details records
is provided by the ssp stack and
authentication so it's nothing no data
should ever be duplicated up to words
about the http layer if
if any attacker tries to duplicate data
it should be caught and handled by the
stack
so
uh however we do have some open issues
and some work for
front of us still to before this is
ready
one of the issues we actually realized
is that detail is 1.3
and re-keying for long-lived flows is
problematic and the basic here is that
details 1.3 do not support renegotiation
so there's no post handshake
server authentication it
re-authenticates client
it doesn't run re-run the helmet or
export their secret updates
so it can re-key in a certain way but
it's
has a mechanism that's not ideal for
having
long lived sessions and when i talk
about long lead sessions say we're
talking
days weeks months for some of these
usages for example in mobile networks
so it's not really practical to tear
down and it's also not
particularly practical to tear down and
re-establish because
that means that you have to bring maybe
whole cell sites
down etc for doing that so uh it's
really not something we want to do
so we had started some discussion in the
tls working group about these things for
the telus 1.3 so
i'll have to see where this is taking us
but at least there's an issue which i'm
going and therefore
dtls 1.2 support will be crucial
initially
for ensuring that property for long lead
flows
uh and we also
this adaptation layer and being certain
that everything is protected by
detailers
is good but i want to point out that
start tls will
not work under these restrictions and
and therefore it's a question more than
anything to
see if anyone has issues with us taking
this direction
um and
we also want this clarify a bit about
the portrait delivery
or protect user message between the sctp
stack and the upper layer of detail is
here
and what happens when you actually don't
get all the data and what you do
uh we also see in these socket api
changes
maybe have some need for that because if
you're require testing
for example that you should use sha-256
the current socket api for uh sdb auth
it's not clear on which uh handling this
like
uh on the on the algorithm side and set
and put the requirements on those things
so we're gonna see something there
we need to deal with so
so but the main thing here is that we
actually
want to request a working group adoption
of this uh
as we see it it's it's 1683 do you need
an update
uh to resolve this length restriction
it's
a good time to actually update the
security algorithm requirements
and we do have a time frame from 3dpp in
some sense because
they want to fix this i think in the in
in the current release which is
by march 2022 it's this stage free so we
need to have something ready that
by then basically and we think we can do
that we have a year
and so discussion
we're gonna start sending out some of
the open issues on the mailing list
we have some more editorials etc to work
on
and we do have using github for this if
you have source
you can submit all requests or file
issues
on this link so corey
i i i can see the um
suggested need for this i wondered
whether anybody else in the working
group had any comments on the
what you've presented or had interest
in this topic is there anybody
interested in the topic that magnus has
presented
or thinks they would have expertise to
work on this
i knew i knew yeah go ahead
i'm interested in this extension
i'm interested in the work
okay well and this is this is david i
think i'm interested
enough to find the time to read the
draft magnus let me quickly understand
something
um this draft is the
is the anticipated response to the 3gpp
liaison statement that is supposedly
inbound is that correct
it's not supposedly it has arrived so
it's
it's refined but yes so
uh it showed up on friday all right have
you managed to get it posted on friday
it's
just track there so but yes
i would suggest that we take the time to
review that liaison statement
and then launch an adoption call on the
list with reference to that liaison
statement
yep yep i i agree with david on this
and i think this work definitely falls
within the scope of this working group
so please read the draft please look at
the liaison statement and please comment
on list when we make the adoption call
okay thank you any more questions or
some of the people that chat have said
that they they're interested as well
good good okay and i'll stop sharing it
thank you mike all right
next up would be uh udp options
is joe presenting or someone presenting
for joe
yeah guess who's going to volunteer yeah
i'm doing it hi corey
yeah how you get yes you're the usual
suspect on this one
and i don't have joel's shirt to go with
i'm afraid it's a bit too cold up here
but
let's talk about udp options can we get
the slides david
um where would i find said slides
in proceedings oh now i gotta go
go go go over there uh justin
joe's been working and responding to
comments on udp options for a while
this current draft zero nine is
very much a update that includes
responses to nearly all the issues which
have been raised previously on the list
so joe has a set of sites that reviews
each of these in turn
and we'll briefly tour over those with
the last couple of issues at the end
where he wants help from the working
group
so when we get joel's slides just a
minute on the slides on my screen now i
got to get him on yours
hang on a minute here um
[Music]
that looks good
i believe that's the one okay that looks
good
bingo so this is
joel's set of updates he's made changes
since zero nine
um he added the unsafe
option which is specifically for use
with fragmentation
um it tries to overcome the issues which
we talked about in length
two in person ietf so a little while ago
now
and it's produced a simpler
fragmentation method
he's also integrated fragmentation light
so they're no longer separate things
and he's revised the ocs pseudocode with
more input from
rafael zulu and to
fix the zeroing issue he's clarified the
acs is not dropped by default
related the acs and the crc32
also talked about acs and ae to say that
they cover the payload only
so a number of things all being talked
about on the list all in joe's latest
post to the list so we can go quickly
through them next please
um unsafe is basically there to deal
with
a specific option that
follows another option and
we need to judge the safety so this is
the one place
where the results of the
receiving a udp option datagram
doesn't result in the application
receiving the datagram
so there it's an important case and
joel's written text to look at this and
it's in the latest draft so
that's that's around and just email
documents next one
most of that is related to fragment and
the idea of fragments are to provide
some rdma-like avoidance of copying user
data but providing fragmentation
the main reason for highlighting this
here is the expected use case by
joe includes pns
and dns needs to send large records and
this would be the mechanism that would
be used if udp options were used with
dns
so it's important that people who have
dns clue look at the fragmentation part
next slide acs and ae have been
um revised mainly revised in the text so
not a lot of surprises here next one
option process principles have been
clarified
and joe has strong opinions on this and
he's expressed
those consistently on the list and
they're reflected in the draft
um i think i think it's clear there's a
new issue
and the new issue is one relation to
path mtu discovery again
it's a very small thing but joe's
looking for clarification
when we talk about the larger segment
size for a udp datagram
do we mean the largest size of fragment
or do we mean the larger
size of fragmented data unit
which one of these two numbers should
appear in the mss
options the maximum fragment size or the
maximum fragment
set of fragments that can be reassembled
so there are two different parameters
and they could be used in
two different parts of the algorithm
which one of these is most useful
which one of these should be in the spec
i ask the questions because they are
things
that joel's going to have to ask on the
list to finish
this this is the main um issue that's
remaining
next slide there's also a few pending
changes but these are not
um thought by joe to be significant
he admitted that he misunderstood the
way in which rock
309.5 was specified it's complicated
uh and the text has been updated with
help from carsten boorman
to get the text right so the text
currently
in the draft should be correct with
respect to rock
this isn't really a change in udp
options it's a change in text
the second one is how to address the mss
issue
what should be in an mss option what
number goes there
and if these two things are fixed
then this document is
complete in the respect of all the
issues that were raised by the working
group when we did the review
so is there anything else that needs to
be covered by this document before it
goes for a working group last call
that's my brief summary of joe's slides
i'll happily take questions if there are
any
it sounds like we need to resolve the
mss issue
and working group last call can follow
assuming there's no surprises in the
others and
glasgow might be just a real good idea
simply to turn up whether
whether whether all the details are
right
yeah and if you picked up on my
representation of joe
if you're from the dns area or an area
that really would like to use
a feature for sending fragments across
the network or some other part of
udp options please look at this now
because
we want users in the room should we lob
an early review request over to ant
areas i think that's where dns lives
yeah we should do that when we do
version 10.
yeah okay
let me make a note myself
i can't write this morning
okay now with a little any any other
comments on this
before i go and switch to nqb i think we
should go frankie b
all righty here we go um it takes a few
clicks here
i'm getting better at this though um
should be that one yeah it's that one
greg go ahead thank you
um be able to hear me
yes yes okay good i'm getting a pop-up
saying it can't
detect my audio all right so um uh
there have been a couple of updates to
the nqb draft since the last
ietf meeting draft04
which i uploaded at the deadline
for the meeting it covered most of the
changes that had been discussed at the
last meeting and afterward
and then while i was working on putting
my slides together for this talk i
realized
uh there was one
one of the to-do items i had not
actually gotten around to doing
and so i did that into draft205 which
was published
just as the servers opened again
for this week so um and in the process
um
did a little bit of wordsmithing as well
on draft 05. so the
draft 4 the main changes are um
first align the terminology with rfc
um and cleaning all that up where it
talks about
standardizing phps and recommending
dsdps and not the other way around
or some other permutation of those terms
um i think that's good now in the draft
there's also a mention that um you just
served
uh was not intended for n10 usage and
that's that's been reworked with some
help from
brian carpenter on that um and then
um additional requirements um so
this was discussed at the last ietf
around the um
implied behavior in earlier drafts that
a network node or network that doesn't
support
the php should be aggregating nqb
traffic with default traffic
um and so now that's explicitly stated
in the draft now
um it's a little bit uh odd to be
saying in a uh standards document what
uh non-compliant uh nodes should should
be doing
we're adding requirements for for those
that don't support the php
but nonetheless i think it's valuable to
do so i mean it is really the intention
of
the nqb um code point
and traffic uh marking that
if it's not being queued separately
along the lines of what the draft
uh discusses then it really should be
aggregated with default traffic and then
second piece was preserving the nqb
marking
um and that's good that that's going to
be word smith but like i
understand why you want it it's uh uh
grim reality has a second opinion
right it's just assured um yeah i
understand
uh it might not even even make it to
that level uh i'll work that off list
with you
okay well appreciate that um
and then um there there's around that
uh discussion of aggregating with
default uh in the requirement or
destroyed around that
there is a discussion around uh where
that is probably fine um particular
talks about
shallow buffered switches and
core network routers and switches that
uh
are not typically points of congestion
and points of
cueing delay in in networks
next bullet removing a mention of
aggregating network control
traffic with nqb this is in the
discussion of what traffic
could be aggregated potentially uh in a
node that supports the nqb
php what other traffic might you want to
potentially aggregate with nqb marks
traffic
network control was initially listed
there uh
and i was asked um to either
put a lot of uh guard rails around that
in the text
or not mention that and so i
took the easy path of not mentioning it
the last bullet in that first lasso
bullet i guess in the first
section there underlined uh this is the
new piece
that i'd like to spend some time
discussing today and this came out of
reviews from a number of folks in the
working group
and suggestions on what would make
lives easier for people to
comply with some of these requirements
and it amounts to
asking for two code points
to be assigned by ayanna and we'll go
into the detail on that
on the next slide um
uh and then for the draft five with the
new updates
um uh the one piece i'd missed in the
draft four was
uh adding some uh something more clear
in the wi-fi section that
rather than just talking about uh
interaction or
or interoperability with existing wi-fi
networks
really talk about the goal is that wi-fi
networks in the future
actually support the php and so that
should really should be the
recommendation
and then um dealing with the
interoperability with existing networks
as a secondary aspect so that that's now
in the graph five
along with a bit of word smithing um in
the new text that went into draft form
let me quick check where you think the
status is it looks like um
most of the issues been closed uh
there's one major issue on the next
level two dscps and once that's resolved
plus a little more text cleanup this is
ready for
your glass call correct that is correct
all right so here we go all right so
two dscps um so
we're we're trying to work within the
realities of the world as it is
um maybe not as we wish it um
were to be and so there are some
constraints
on the selection of
the the code point to be used for nqb
in order to make it useful in the near
term as well as the long term
and the two main constraints
conflict with one another the first one
is uh that there are hundreds of
millions of wi-fi networks
deployed around the world that map dscp
into access categories the the wmm
access categories um which provide
separate cues as well as priority but
not quite separate cues
and and that mapping is by and large
using what's called the default mapping
and there is an interest in ensuring
that the nqb code point can be handled
in these
existing wi-fi networks and that npb
traffic can get a separate queue
from the best effort default traffic
and so in order to do that
we have since the beginning proposed
that
the code point uh allocated for nqbb
value 42 which has the bit pattern
1 0 and then
1 0 1 0 which would by default map into
the video access category actually any
code point with the value the binary
value 1 0
x x x x would map into the video access
category
on my file so that's one constraint um a
related constraint that
that works well with um this assignment
of
value 42 is that there's a lot of
existing access network gear
that can uh configure
uh classifiers to to put traffic into
different hues
and has a bit masking capability
in doing that that um dscp
matching and so selecting a code point
that um is maskable
and and matches a a set of other
code points that are already assigned by
ana that are
that carry traffic or indicate traffic
that is compatible with nqb
is a distinct advantage um there are a
number of applications today that
already mark their traffic but with some
existing code points
um in particular cs7 cs5 and ef
that um is traffic that is compatible
with
nqb and um selects
either the voice or video access
category and wi-fi um
and the belief is that um
uh uh continuing to support
those or supporting those applications
um in
networks that want to implement the
uh npb code point would be facilitated
by selecting
a code point for nqb that can be
easily grouped with some subset of those
three code points minor note here
um use cs5 and ef is one of the examples
applications should not be marking cs7
because
um most uh diffserv uh boundaries
have to bleach cs7 or to protect the
routing protocols
yeah and the context for for that list
really is
in uh end user networks home networks
and and there cs7
actually is used because the default
wi-fi mapping
map cs7 to the voice access category
things like ef and voice admit
go to the video access category by
default so
so dealing with the reality of um yeah
uh usage in in home networks
uh but point taken um
the the next rationale there that
conflicts with the first one is
that um across interconnections
um it was pointed out that um
particularly for network networks that
run mpls
cores that traffic has to be aggregated
or dhcps have to be aggregated in order
to
fit into the available mpls traffic
categories and that
uh nqb traffic could very easily be
treated
the same as default which would be the
the intention in a core network in a lot
of cases
if the code point were something that
matched the pattern zero zero
zero xxx in binary
so um uh and
um if it were if such a code point were
selected
then those mpls core networks and
transit networks could
very easily carry the nqb code point
through unbleached and so that both of
those are
desirable properties that would enable
end-to-end usage of nqb in the near firm
so that leaves us with these two
conflicting
constraints around the assignment again
one
being that uh the code point is binary
one zero xxx
the other one that it's a binary zero
zero zero xxx
um uh in some off list discussion
um uh uh we came to the
agreement that uh it would be a
potentially
uh useful set or a pair to choose uh
would be 42 and two
42 matching what we've been proposing
all along for the
wi-fi coexistence and access network
coexistence
aspects um and then the value two is
simply
um bleaching the top three bits of the
code point
that is actually already a pathology
that's in place in some
parts of the internet and so naturally
uh
dhcp 42 mark traffic would become the
cp2 in some cases
um and in our case that's an easy
effects
or easy easy um change to make in the in
the dhcp
um and so the way that's kind of
structured in the
draft is that end hosts
applications um essentially mark traffic
is 42.
as they send you the the host is the
um the entity that understands its
ending behavior and understands whether
it's complying with the intention of the
mqb code point
um and the php and so it marks at 42
and then that then traverses
home networks and wi-fi links and gets
the appropriate treatment there
it's um this benefit on access networks
of
having the value 42 and then somewhere
uh prior to interconnection the isp is
responsible for
remapping 42 into the value 2
and using two across the interconnection
and then at the far side before traffic
is
delivered into an end user network
there is another remapping back to 42.
and diagram shows
a client and server case it could also
be
client to client um you know a
peer-to-peer kind of communication as
well but
um that is the the gist of it um and
that's i think the main discussion point
today is
your concerns or
thoughts about the concept of having two
dscps
to deal with this
these two constraints um and then the
specific values of the code points i
think
um you know 42 and two is maybe a second
theory topic that we should uh
touch on as well so
um
i guess if anyone has feedback on this
two dscp concept any concerns with that
okay um do you want to get do you want
to do the discussion now we're going to
get through the rest of your slides
we're a little tight on time as usual
okay well i can the rest of the slides
are kind of wrap up so i can go ahead
and do that then we can have open
discussion
that's okay okay next slide and just the
other thing is we need to figure out
where to put in
uh the uh honest presentation on dscp2
measurements
okay so that's one remaining slides
so this is just to say everything that
we identified the last ihf
to do is either done or this we decided
not to do it uh
checklist checked next um
and then discussion so uh okay with two
dscps and then which ones
and so see anna's talk which has some
interesting
insight into that topic and then
where do we go from here on the draft
all right so something we're going to do
is get anna up to talk about
uh dscp2 and then come back to this for
some more general discussion
and try to watch try try to watch the
clock while we're doing that
um okay hang on where are ah
all these windows
okay hang on a minute here
ah there it is anna go ahead
uh hello can you hear me yes
great um yeah so uh hi uh i'm
anna i work with gory fairhurst at the
university of aberdeen
um i will talk to you today about some
measurement data new measurement data
that we have around the code points for
t2 and 2
that are proposed in the in the mqb
draft that greg just presented
so if we could go on to the next slide
please
um the data is is is new as it addresses
some gaps
um there is there already is some
literature about the traversability of
code points
including 42 and 2 uh but only in the
core of the internet
and all of that is based on uh on active
measurements so you generate traffic
with some dhcp
and then you set it out in the internet
and you look at what comes out of the
other side and what changes you see
at every hop in the path um but today
what we are going to be looking at
is passive data in the core of the
internet i mean
actual traffic uh in the wild and this
is uh this is a data set that is
provided by
keda um we're also going to be briefly
looking at a set of edge measurements
uh that are done from ripe atlas probes
uh in the past we've not had that much
information on edge networks
um and finally we've i've looked at a
few sets of code points
um primarily dhcp's 40 2 but then a
couple of other pairs that
would fulfill the criteria that that
grid just talked about that is
also specified in the aqb draft
so if you could go on to the next slide
i will try to keep this
as short as i can um so the passive data
this is provided by keda it comes from a
monitor that sits somewhere
in a data center it collects all the
traffic on a bad bull link
backbone link rather where a tier one
isp
peers the traffic is anonymized
all of the payload is removed and what
we are left with
with is ip headers and transport headers
as well
so we can look at the dscp markings
in total we analyzed around 18 billion
packets
they were all collected in two hours in
two different years
at the same location if we move on to
the next slide
and yes here is a table that analyzes
what the scps
were seen on all of these packets we
looked at and
i pay particular attention to those that
are proposed in the nqb draft
so as you can see in the table i've
split the traffic per year
per direction the the traffic is
bidirectional
and also per protocol as in ipv4 versus
ipv6 i've not split it per
transport um so first observation that
you can make is that
uh the most traffic uh just carries the
scp-0
so um only zeros are carried in the dhcp
field and this is the case for around 80
to 90 percent of the traffic regardless
of how you split it
um we expect this and this corresponds
to
uh to be the best effort
the second thing that you can notice
which is a bit more unexpected
is that in all of the cases regardless
of how you split the traffic
you can see traffic marked with the
scp-2
which is proposed in the nqb draft
in fact this can be as much as 90
percent of all
traffic carries this particular mark
this is not a trivial amount of traffic
and we'll explore why this happens in a
later slide
uh but something else to notice here is
that all of the other codes don't appear
code points rather don't appear nearly
as much as
codepoint2 and this includes chord point
42 which is uh proposed in the nqb draft
that's a good thing
it means nothing uses it uh but also in
all of for all of the other sets of
chord points that we used as
uh we we looked at like um 44 and 4 and
and 6 they don't appear they only appear
for a fraction of the traffic
so the key takeaway from here from the
slide is that um
on this particular link a lot of the
traffic ends up carrying the same
code point uh that is proposed um
for nqb traffic and because we see it in
both directions and from
different prefixes uh we we believe it
to be the result of uh several different
networks so not just one network but
several
that remark in this way so if we could
go on to the next slide
uh which talks about uh the tests that
we did at the edge
um so we did this test on the ripe atlas
platform which has um geographically
distributed probes
and in fact in the picture that you can
see on your screen right now
these are all the the probes that
participated in the measurement
and from all of these we sent tcp
traffic
marked with dscp42 towards our own
server
at the university of aberdeen and the
goal here was to understand
what remarking happens along a path note
that this is a trace route measurement
so
we can actually see what happens at each
hop
and what we find out is that not much
remarking happened uh
happens at at the first stop so in the
edge network where the probe is
uh with only about five percent of all
of the dhcps are zeroed
uh there but by the time the packets
make it to our server to the end of the
path
um the scp-42 survives only on about
in about 20 percent of traffic so on
around 20
percent of the path percent of the paths
rather
um we also see that about seven percent
of packets have the first three bits of
the field zeroed out
so this is basically toss bleaching so
they arrive at the destination is the
cp2
which is uh the other proposed code
point for nqb
um and interestingly you see about three
percent of them that have the last three
bits as opposed the first three bits
zeroed out which results in code point
uh or cs5 uh i mean
uh greg mentioned that cs5 is ngb
compatible
uh traffic but also in this case uh
it might result from a wi-fi network
pathology
however on the majority of paths this is
not the case on about 60 percent of the
past
packets have the entire field zeroed out
so by the time they
they reach the destination um uh
they carry the sap zero and this
corresponds to best effort
so uh if we move on
to the next slide um what do we learn
from all of this data
well i just uh mentioned that where edge
and edges
edge networks are concerned you see a
lot of bleaching
and resulting in code.0 um but
the keta data results were surprising
because now we've
we know of at least one backbone link
we're using
a code point where codepoint2 is used
and appears on
a lot of the traffic and this is most
likely due to the toss precedence
bleaching
on many packets that maybe have arrived
from various
edge networks carrying the sap such as
af-11 or f21 or
31 or 41 that toss bleach to the value
2.
so what i'm trying to say is that you
have these popular chord points like af
11 and 21 that have established
semantics
which end up at the other edge
uh s2 because because of how popular
they are and because there's a lot of uh
because the practice of toss bleaching
is still quite widespread
um i'm guessing this this might mean
that you have you could have potentially
a lot of
q building traffic that may be remarked
as nqb
and that's the only implication here but
we also saw that
codepoint42 is not used
which brings me to my last point and if
you go to the next slide
so my last point is that there are a lot
of interactions
and different types of remarking that
can happen on many different paths in
many different types of network
when it comes to div surf code points so
all of these kind of should be kept in
mind when you assign new ones
and me and gory and another one of our
colleagues from the university of
aberdeen wrote
an internet graph that attempts to
provide some input on what pathology
remarking pathologies exist
and what other semantics exists with
regards to code points
and we're at the stage where we'd love
any input on this
thank you very much if you've already
commented
and provided feedback on the draft we
will be uploading a new version soon
but if you haven't and you think you can
do so and are interested please do it
um yes this concludes my presentation
thank you for listening
are there any questions let's leave
that hang on where am i
let's leave that slide up for questions
um
great go ahead okay um
thanks anna um this is definitely really
good
useful work for helping help me select
code points here
for nqb it
looks like a potential candidate
pair of code points could be uh
45 and 5. going back to your
data it looks like
5 is not uh used
not it was not seen heavily um
there were a couple of instances i guess
the direction
b both uh 2018 and 2019 where
there was a fair amount of code 0.5
but in other cases much less
and the value 45 is available in the
um assignment
pool as well those other values
4 and 6 the corresponding value
in the upper part of the space uh 44 and
46 i
think those are already assigned 46 is
ef
44 is voice admit um
so if you if we want to have a pair
for which the the low three bits are the
same which i think
there's value in doing that um 45 and
five might be one
that we look at interjecting as a
chair before going congratulating the
next person
in line um voice admit is definitely out
of the question
however ef is intriguing
it might be plausible since nqb traffic
doesn't build cues if you have high
assurance of that
it is not out of the question to carry
it as
ef in the edge networks
and i don't know how to reach conclusion
on that i'm just raising that as an
interest
interesting one to dig into
yes interesting document
responding to that um the uh
you in existing wi-fi networks um
ef and 45 and 42 and
all those which we've been talking about
and that upper range
would go into the same access category
and so from that perspective it would be
equivalent um and then if in a
further network hop ef gets aggregated
with nqb traffic either because they're
in different code points and they get
classified together or because they
share the same code point
that would be fine too the
concern i think i would have is that um
recommendations around future wi-fi
support
for nqb versus ef um
and ef is generally
considered traffic that should be
prioritized in networks
whereas nqb is explicitly not supposed
to be prioritized
and so the recommendation for future
wi-fi uh
nodes is to provide a separate queue
in the best effort access category for
nqb
and is that what we would want
to recommend for ef traffic as well
okay just want to raise possibility uh
vd go ahead
hurry
hello can you hear me yes yes okay
cool a question for greg so for
in the nqb draft i haven't read the
draft i just
saw the slides right now uh is there is
a recommendation
um to for the
edge to use to bleach any of these 42 44
or 46 to
2 instead of zero so that
it can be utilized for the nqb
traffic on the downstream is that the
recommendation
because most of the traffic gets
bleached to zero
um yeah the intention is
here um the intention is
test one two
all right there we go
okay good thank you um yes the intention
is that
we enable the pass-through of this code
point
um end to end and we do whatever we can
to
ensure that that's possible um yesterday
the vast majority if not all isps
particular residential customers bleach
the code point
to zero or to some other you know fixed
value
um most often zero and
so the recommendation in the draft is
that
it'd be carried all the way through and
as the diagram shows
uh you know is 42
in the home network
segment yeah for traffic both upstream
and downstream
to the user um there is one kind of
caveat there that
um you since the wi-fi links don't
support the full
php uh requirements that
there could be some uh
non-ideal behaviors that might happen if
if
traffic is not being policed and
monitored and
your random traffic comes into the isp
network
uh marked uh with this low value say two
or five and if that's the last that's
chosen
and so it recommends that um unless the
operator has
implemented some safeguards to prevent
that from happening that they leave the
code point at the low value
so that uh the traffic stays in the best
effort access category on wi-fi but
the extent that the the isp is
supporting the php and
supporting uh those safeguards then yeah
yeah the intention is that
it is 42 both for upstream traffic and
downstream traffic in
the uh customer's home network right now
there is a risk there in uh on this data
which is that there is existing use of
code 0.2 traffic on the
uh observed on the backbone and that
will get up marked to 42 even though it
didn't start out as 42.
yeah exactly gloria
thinking here that there might be two
outcomes
the first one might be that after
thinking through anna's presentation
and the discussion on this topic that
greg might
finalize on 42 and 2 and that'll have to
propose to the working group so that's
one option
the other option might be that after
thinking through this that
greg wants to try and propose a
different pair of dscps
and then i'm wondering perhaps if we
could have a little interim or something
before the next ietf to discuss
the different option if one emerges so
we weren't kind of clocked by ietf
meetings on
assigning a diff serve called point yeah
if it if if it gets confusing enough an
interim would make up
would make a whole lot of sense um
but i think it's definitely
possibilities anna you want to take the
last word on this
and then we need to move on
uh say that again please did you you're
marcus salon did you want to say
anything more
um no i just i just had a thought um
because i think whichever route you go
whichever pair of code points you have
will you
do you not need to have some sort of
protection just in case
that q building traffic actually ends up
in the nqbq
regardless of what of what code points
are used so if you have such a box and
this box is
is in the isp network perhaps you don't
actually need to choose a different
pair of code points from 40 to 12
if i understand this correctly
okay
because rudiger might want to make a
quick comment on this yes let's look
we're gonna go ahead
go ahead
we'll have a hard time to distinguish it
from it's coming through now
hello yes you're there well
i have a hard time to distinguish it
from real nqb
traffic at the bng
so i'd prefer a different dhcp than two
thanks okay so this is a great
conversation
to have on the list but i would
encourage people to get in there
and try and make some decisions so we
can move forward
okay all right and we are five minutes
behind schedule
unfortunately gorgeous i'm gonna try to
stuff the satellite slides in here very
quickly
yeah as we start the individual drafts
let's do a
heads-up display of the satellite one
and then move through
um robin and then finally back to the
um the final sites okay so tom
um please press your mic and talk for
two minutes
this
and we're not getting audio now you're
getting audio go for it okay next slide
please
uh so nicholas gory emil and john
had um a draft that was targeting quick
where they looked at satellite
considerations for the quick protocol
and part of that was giving something
that was um testable by implementation
so that satellite wasn't left out of the
story
gauri asked me to to look at this draft
to try and align the text with
um rfc 2488 and instead
uh we as a group of authors decided that
the document would be
better suited just approaching transport
protocols generally
and what they need to get from from
satellite and what satellite deployment
does
there are two documents in the rc series
that really cover
satellite use cases 2488 and 2760
they both came from the tcp sap working
group which concluded in 2000
and since 2000 uh geo satellite services
become
massively faster there's just a lot more
capacity available and
the considerations in these documents
were sort of superseded by
split tcp implementing the things they
discussed and so the split tcps are
implemented with peps
uh and and this works great for tcp um
most tcp connections don't actually
realize they're going over satellite
because they have the protocol split
down
and satellite actually works quite well
uh apart from for
latency critical tasks the problem we
have is that peps are a deployment
barrier for new features for tcp
and they are impractical to deploy for
for quick or
or with vpns and we're starting now to
see um
new satellite systems that are actually
getting prominent so we're seeing a lot
of leo stuff come up
and we're seeing neo and there's a big
case with hybrid operations
with uh 5g and so we want to create an
update to 2488 and the advice of 2760
and document the relevant transport
character characteristics of these
satellite networks
so that we can um give advice for
implementers and so we can design and
test and verify that code will work well
and work well
in these different cases and what we
want from the working group is input on
what we need to talk about
and so we have experience with
geoproviders because the
authors group typically work in
geosystems
but what we really want is input in leo
and mio
and then input from satellite network
operators application platform
operators and protocol implementers so
that we're giving the best advice so
that the satellite use cases are
understood
so i just like to ask everyone the
working group to read the document
and provide feedback we'll take feedback
on the mailing list uh individually
and we also have a github and i'll post
a link to the github in the chat and
that is
all i want so please please please
please read and comment
on the draft to the list and or to and
or to the authors
okay next up is once i
let me go find it uh is q log
and i would ask uh both of the next uh
main two presenters uh to try to do it
in about 10 minutes each
sorry we're squeezed on time robin go
for it
yeah if i can have slides uh hang on
just a minute i need to go ah
yes you do need you do need to
go find it um
bingo that should be it there we go
excellent so thanks for giving me a
little bit of time to talk about q
log um again which has been discussed in
in tsv area
before and also throughout the week
so next slide please q log started as as
the quick login project intended to make
it easier to
to analyze and debug quicken http 3.
next slide this is because what you
would normally do for something like
tcps you would take a packet capture
somewhere and
use something like wireshark to analyze
that you can still do that with quick
but it's a bit more difficult
next slide because quickl of course
almost entirely encrypts also its
transport level
uh metadata so to do that you would have
to store the entire packet capture which
gets quite large
and you would also need to store the
decryption secrets
which is of course terrible for privacy
and there's a second important aspect to
this next slide indeed
is that not everything about the
protocol is of course sent on the wire
especially things like just control
parameters are typically not
analyzable in that way so for quick
reproposed
next slide a new approach instead of
doing a network capture we would
capture at the end points directly from
the implementations
and qlog there is the idea that we can
have a single format a single schema
that is used across the different
implementations so everyone logs in the
exact same way
this enables us to create reusable
tooling in a much more
straightforward fashion so next slide
so keylog is far from rocket science we
currently just serialize this to json
getting for example a definition of what
a received packet should look like
or indeed you can just control metrics
update on the right side
next so using qlog as an input format we
also created
quite a bit of tooling for that for
example this type of sequence diagram or
next
tcp trace alike tool to help debug
congestion
and flow control issues in the protocols
next slide
um bishop pros has worked quite well
within quick with the majority of the
implementations actually output in this
single format and for example facebook
actually using it in
production at scale as well to to
monitor their actual quick
deployments next slide
up until now q log has been two
individual drafts
and so because of this this
i would say proof that it can work in
practice we will probably adopt it in a
quick working group
um within the next couple of months as
part of their recharter
so a main goal of that is of course
flashing this out for quick and hp3
but the main reason that i'm here today
and other working groups this week
um is because we also envision qlogs to
be useful for many other protocols as
well
this basic concept of just using a
structured standard format
at the endpoints can be useful in many
different
situations and we actually have pilot
projects running for
for the ones that we that have listed
there below for example tcp is an
obvious target there where we are
extracting some events using
for example evpf from the kernel there
are also
many people interested in doing this
from multibots tcp
and quick of course because these can
get quite difficult to
to debug and fine-tune in practice
next slide um this this goal of making q
log usable for more protocols is
actually already visible in the current
drafts we have the
event definitions for quick and industry
are separate from what we're calling the
main schema
which kind of has the protocol agnostic
stuff of the format
and the hope is that this can grow to a
framework or a set of guidelines that
people can use to define new
types of schemas for different protocols
next slide if you want to do this we're
of course going to have quite a few
challenges
um ahead of us which is one of the
reasons again i'm here today in the
hopes that some people might have
thoughts or
feedback on these i'm going to highlight
just three of them just just to give you
an idea of what we might be talking
about
next slide so one of the things is that
a simple thing to do would be to map the
wire image that you would get
101 to the format for example here you
have a selective acknowledgement missing
the packet number 16.
but this doesn't necessarily reflect
what the implementation is actually
doing
um it might perfectly be that packet
number 16 isn't immediately declared as
lost
and so we need a second type of of
events which you can see on the right
side
to actually reflect that separately
if we start defining both of these types
of events you get a
huge amount of events first of all and
it also becomes more difficult to build
tooling for this because
which event should you be looking for
and which takes precedence over the
other
and so on and this is just within quick
let's see if we
extend this to tcp with the next slide
which of course also has selective
acknowledgements but in a different way
because here they're in the packet
header in the options field and so
it's the exact same information but
reflected in a different civilization
and so we really want them to find a way
to
hopefully make this easier or we need to
see if we really do need to reflect the
wire image completely
the second main challenge next slide is
on the serialization format here
we're currently using json mainly
because it's flexible
but it's also not the most performant
option
uh even though it is kind of usable uh
for example used by facebook but so also
in the drafts we kind of
acknowledge that we might want to use
different things in jsons we have our
own
data type definition language there to
describe the events which is what you
can see on the right side
but we would like to really move to
something more officially supported by
the ietf
with the goal of automatically
generating uh serializers or dc
realizers for different
programming line which is based on this
to make deploying this easier
um we would also like to get some
insight into if people would use this
what type of
processing or collection pipelines they
would typically want to use
which will help guide the correct use of
the format
the final main challenge the next slide
is of course the privacy aspects as i
said in theory it's perfectly possible
that
you you only log the perfectly sanitized
data from the endpoints directly
but in practice you will have use cases
where you do need the ip addresses you
do need
the urls and that kind of stuff so what
we envision now is to have like a
set of standardization levels uh defined
with concrete guidelines on how to hash
or
obfuscate certain fields that people can
then map to individual things
our hope is that if this works quite
well and we can scrub this for most
privacy sensitive information
we can also start to think about
actually actively sharing
um full qlik data sets or individual cue
logs
for additional troubleshooting which of
course
leads to a whole bunch of new issues
that might be interesting to discuss
so a final slide to summarize
we hope that eventually maybe qlor can
grow into
a separate working group if it shows
that it can be done
if it can be done in a protocol agnostic
fashion which at this point isn't even
clear yet
and that that new working group will
help their protocols to adopt
for now we're starting this in the quick
working group mainly because
practical and historical considerations
so if you have any interest in this
please come and join us there
in the next couple of months or join us
on the separate github and the separate
mailing lists
and of course i would like to listen to
your questions and your feedback now as
well
so thanks and i see an ad in the queue
martin go ahead
yes thanks robin uh just to just be
crystal clear about the
the action items i think come out of
this as you know this court group is
basically a community of components for
a bunch of protocols
um i would first of all encourage all of
you to think about the applicability of
this your protocol particularly if it
runs over some sort of crypto like scp
over dtls or what have you
uh secondly um if you think about how to
apply this to your protocols
you may have some input into the main
schema and
um number one you'll probably have to
come to quick to participate in that
discussion
but if if we see a lot of immediate
interest in applying this to more
protocols
we might take that and bring it to
another venue
for the core schema not the quick
specific events but but the core schema
so um that would be very useful input
quickly if there's a lot of
of immediate interest in this but we're
not going to wait forever because we
want to move this forward
and quick as a venue where there's
obviously is an interest of course that
is a follow-on um
you could do your own draft in whatever
working group is appropriate
uh this one for a bunch of protocols
obviously
using the base schema and then applying
the events relative to your protocol so
i encourage
um really a lot of people here to start
thinking about this
and and seeing if there's seeing
if they're if they can start thinking
about how to reply and where
and what they need to do in relatively
short order thanks
okay phil go ahead and then we're going
to close we're going to close the mic
lines move on
yeah i was just going to quickly say
that i think that keeping it in quick
for the time being
is a good thing and if we spin it out to
a working group
we might want to look a bit further and
look into
how you actually manage the
quick server not just the
output but how you apply feedback so i
think it probably
is bestest place in part in a different
context but not one that we should be
looking at now
okay and with that thank you very much
and uh we're gonna move on to
uh last uh one of the session let me
make sure
oh boy make sure i click in the right
place and we'll get the right material
up
jonathan how do you want to handle this
do you want to go through the slides or
do you want to pick up where map rg left
off
um i think
we just pick up where we left off if
anyone has questions
we should um try to answer those
and then go on to a particular slide
is it pick a slide i want to put up uh
to do that
well it's a question of what people have
questions about
i have a different slide deck for for my
talk
so so jonathan peter i wondered
how much of the data you've gathered
is for would be
applicable to other networks how
transferable are the results you have
here
to other network deployments do we need
more data have we got enough
how big are the data sets really
well the um
obviously this is only one vantage point
more data
would be nice from other vantage points
and so we have a script
that can probably be adapted to other
vantage points to collect the same sort
of data
peace knows better more more about the
script
is the script available is it something
we can just use
by the way so data is wonderful and it's
really good to see data
peter yes it is there is a there is a
link to the repo
and it's just a script that can run on
any any linux router we used it up to a
slash 16
subnet but there's 800 some odd ips i'm
not sure
how far it can scale but certainly
beyond this
um but yeah we need to collect more data
this this was collected over
a fairly long time three weeks but 800
some ips isn't
you know it is a relatively small
installation
and probably the unique thing here is
that we have
um a distinction between parts where we
know there's an aqm
and a larger number of parts where we
know that there isn't an aqm within the
isp
okay if there aren't any more questions
perhaps i should go on
to my talk okay
i don't think those slot ah all right
we'll let you share the screen you saw
the guidance i sent you
on uh what to try to cover
okay um oh hang on i have to stop
sharing my screen in order to get your
allow you to share there we go
okay and then i will
switch this over to to some extent this
is a warm-up for the fun we're going to
have on wednesday
oh i'm sure here it is
okay so i'm jonathan morton and i'm here
to talk about the implications
of some measurements that my colleague
pete heist talked about in the map rg
session
a little while ago first i think i need
to lay out some background principles
as engineers we must be aware of the
risks associated with anything we create
and aerospace engineers must take this
extra seriously as they deal in
safety of life risks and they have
developed a model
for this the internet engineers have it
relatively easy
as the internet offers a best effort
service which is not intended for
applications where safety of life is at
stake
the worst effects are therefore mostly
economic in nature
we quantify a particular risk as the
product of the likelihood or frequency
that it occurs
by the severity of the expected
consequences
this means that equivalent risks might
have different availabilities
balanced by inversely differing
likelihoods
the question of how much risk is
acceptable depends on who incurs the
consequences
in the lab we can deliberately induce a
particular failure mode and observe the
consequences
and thereby establish the severity of a
risk
but determine the likelihood we must
look at the real world we'll see how
often these circumstances
likely to trigger that failure mode will
arise
now i'm not going to apply the aerospace
risk model to the internet
that would be absurd but if for example
a systemic congestion collapse event
occurred
or the root dns surface or went down at
once that would be a catastrophic level
event in internet terms and that's why
those servers are managed by a decidedly
paranoid and very international group of
trustees
at the opposite end of the scale a
single packet loss is something that
internet protocols can usually recover
from very quickly
so would be classed as trivial it's
still desirable to minimize
such things but they can be tolerated
pretty well up to a point
haven't had a systemic congestion
collapse since the 1980s
because effective congestion control is
required by current internet standards
as published in rfcs
serious radio events do occur
occasionally and we hear about them in
the news
sometimes there's a tech best but
sometimes the mainstream first picks it
up as well
for the most part we are concerned with
avoiding major category events by design
and reducing the prevalence of minor
events
the tolerable level of risk is strongly
influenced by exactly who it is that
incurs the risk
if you're actually involved in the
activity generating the risk then you
know what to expect
and you have an easy way to stop the
activity or to direct it away from
yourself
perhaps even subconsciously avoiding
other activities
which you expect will interact badly
with it
an interested observer might not know so
much of the details of what's going on
but is at least paying attention
you might guess there's a novel
disruption event that you experience
might be linked to this particular
activity and be able to inquire into
whether that is true
and indirectly cause the activity to
stop if necessary
but an innocent bystander might be
affected by the risk
but have no idea of its existence they
would have
no way to troubleshoot it no contact
point
to have the activities shut down
so clearly the level of risk that
innocent bystanders may incur
is much less than for the other two
categories
in short we must avoid externalizing the
risk
in previous sessions we have documented
lab tests
that mostly exercise one easily
predictable failure mode
of l4s namely that it routinely squashes
conventional tcp
traffic that competes with it whether
easy and capable or not
in the same conventional aqm instance at
a bottleneck
this is a serious impairment of an
entire
rather widespread class of traffic
so it falls into a major category event
there has been some disputes from the
l4s team over how
likely or frequent such conditions are
at first the focus was on single queue
aqms with ecn enabled
which appear to be uncommon compared to
fluidware aqms
but then we realize that flow aware
mechanisms
are defeated by encrypted tunnels and
that l4s and conventional traffic can
share the tunnel
and thus be indistinguishable by a flow
aware aqm
in particular the ubiquitous fq codel
just as a reminder of how much calm is
caused
a single l4s flow represented by tcp
prague forces a competing cubic flow to
collapse
to less than a tenth of the fair share
rate
of our standard link that's for long
running flows
but even on short flows such as a crude
simulation of web traffic
flow completion time is quadrupled with
tcp plug background
relative to an equivalent cubic
background
we'll be happy to discuss the specifics
of this test offline or
in the questions afterwards
using the new hum metric introduced at
the last
ietf meeting we see upwards of
0.85 harm inflicted by prague on cubic
where cubic inflicts only about 0.5 harm
on itself
0.85 is a nasty figure
now if this never almost never occurred
in practice then
perhaps it could be overlooked
the only way to find that out is to look
so we collected some anonymized data
from a small isp
and looked carefully for firm evidence
of acn and aqm
activity we were able to distinguish
activity
on tcp flows that negotiated ecn support
from those who did not and look for ce
marks and ece flags
which are usually a pretty clear sign of
a neg aqm
on the path only a small proportion of
tcp flows negotiated ecn support
but they were spread over a large
fraction of the isps subscribers
this seems consistent with many
subscribers having both apple
and non-apple devices in the same
household and
mostly using the non-apple ones for
internet traffic
we can only easily observe aqms on ect
flows
that drive an aqm bottleneck to
saturation
so this small proportion of ect flows
was less than ideal but we were able to
observe aqm activity
on sixty percent of parts it had a known
aqm
internal to the isp and on ten percent
of parts that did not
this latter proportion is clearly higher
than the
five percent threshold i recall was
suggested on the list some time ago
it's also clearly higher than the rate
of ecn negotiation by client endpoints
so here is a serious question fating
facing this working group
given a major severity risk that could
show up on 10 percent of powers
at least several times a month
is that acceptable to inflict on
innocent bystanders in particular
i would say not but i'm only one voice
and let me be clear existing networks
and their users
are innocent bystanders they do not know
anything whatsoever about l4s
and most of them would not care even if
explained
this isp in particular has a very long
equipment replacement cycle
some of it dates from 15 years ago when
they first set up
and that is one reason why only some of
the internal powers have fq coda
but even if other isps upgrade more
quickly their cast offs will often go to
the less prosperous parts of the world
for a second probably much longer life
if we started eliminating them today
rsc3168 aqms
would still be around for decades
what's more a user who notices a problem
can't evade it merely by disabling ecn
on his own traffic not ect traffic is
just as affected only the aqm
needs to support ecn to trigger the
effect
the alpha west traffic could involve a
completely different device
such as a game's console or set-top box
which the user cannot reconfigure
let's see okay well there's gonna be a
link to the point first i'll just leave
this slide up as a summary
and ask for questions and we are
basically at time so i think this is a
good place to stop
we could take a very brief question now
definitely should let bob
in since i think he's got some comments
but i think a lot of this is for people
think about the next session
bob go ahead
hi there can you hear me yes yes
yep um i
i appreciate jonathan that you know
you're trying to
prove a point here um
what seems fairly
sort of um incongruous to me is that
this this risk analysis that you talk
about here
was never done um when fq is deployed
up
let me refer back to an earlier slide
so a major level a major severity
harm is where the service quality is
seriously impaired for
for example a class of traffic
whereas a minor level severity
would be a moderate sustained localized
impact
on service quality
wouldn't it be reasonable to supply
suppose
that the impact of
um a max min
fairness enforcement would be limited to
minor
no because that you can have any number
of flows in a vpn
that fq puts all into one queue and so
the the no limit how much damage f
does and then
not looking at all and instead
i think what we need to do is call time
on this and take further take further
discussion
of the list and it'll be an opportunity
to dig into this further on wednesday
okay i can get behind that
i think that and maybe bob can
troubleshoot his audio on in the process
yeah yeah yeah bob's audience is better
than wednesday we're gonna have we're
gonna have serious problems so i hope
you figure out what's going on there
um yeah um
do i repeat it all i i don't know i i
was just i was just saying i'd like to
see
i mean the analysis of how much of the
of the problem
was originally there or it is originally
because therefore
um your audio is going downhill again
i think you're asked for how much of the
problem is exists
out completely absent l4s and i think on
that note we probably ought to wind up
the meaning
all right i believe we're done
thank you all very much uh we'll see you
all on wednesday
all right see you then