the video
was awesome
um
you can go ahead sorry
okay we are yes sir we want to use the
microwave closer
with the largest museum
foreign
[Music]
zero and Trust the cloud uh when you
think about the Enterprise users uh
Fortune 500 or 40 percent of the Fortune
500 user they are trying to have to
z-scale Cloud every day 250 billion
transactions going through z-scan
account uh if you think about what what
does that mean right how many Google
searches a day
that's roughly eight eight point five
bit instruments um searches a day and a
Google search to us is one transaction
so if you think about the scale Google
has 8.5 searches a day and then we have
more than 250 billion transactions a day
so the level of the scale is probably
Way Beyond your imagination if you
didn't study the z-scale
so with that I wanted to
um talk a little bit about why we are
discussing this right so I actually have
been in the security industry on and off
for almost 25 years actually it was one
of the original president who wrote
ipsec code for FreeBSD 2.0 back uh more
than 25 years ago and I joined a company
called NFR I don't know how many of you
ever heard about nnpr but you know
that's the I couldn't even find a clear
image online this morning but that was
back in the days one of the pioneers of
intrusion detection uh in the 90s and uh
a few years ago I started a company
during AI machine learning uh it's
called a trust path it was acquired by
z-scale that's why I'm part of the
z-skeleton now now why AI machine
learning because there is something that
I learned many many years ago I felt
like wow that's a huge pain Point uh
jacking you know over there I listened
to your Zoom talk about for 10 minutes
my three takeaways from your talk the
word is we are screwed because the
hackers are winning second that we are
finally together and the third we need
more women so that's why we we I have a
co-speaker but I'm going to talk about
the first two things a little bit we are
screwed so back in 1998 I was reading
this paper uh
I don't know how many of you uh read it
in Social Invasion and the amount of
service including their work uh
intruding the connection there was this
was early in 1998 I read this paper I
truly truly believe we were screwed
because the way I read a paper I don't
know there's a solution for that we can
do intrusion Perfection all day long but
bad guys can just uh you know get ahead
of us whatever the security solution you
are going to be half a step if not 10
steps behind four practical purposes as
a computer science guy no matter how you
look at it it's just uh you cannot argue
against that people so that's why you
know part of the reason I actually sort
of left the security industry a little
bit I went on to do VMware I was I found
that a vmware's networking team and I
went on to do virtual networking laid
out but that was part of the reason I
was a little bit disappointed because
you know we really didn't have a way to
deal with security because you know no
matter what we do how fast we can come
up with signatures we are always always
have a step because the bad guys and the
problem is even worse in the last 20
years uh if you think about the solar
Wings right so when I thought about it
you know again using first principle how
to solve that problem well there are
billions of billing signals and then
data points we can potentially we could
have potentially gathered process it and
then make sense out of it and then got
ahead of that guys but you know it's
actually pretty difficult I think that
Jackie made a simple right you know
where's the data you know is the data
clean do you have the power to even
process the data it's just a lot of work
right when you think about it that is
the motivation for our top we actually
wanted to talk about how Zeta my team
right uh think about uh solving this
problem this is a part of the reason why
I founded a trust path a few years ago I
was thinking wow finally there's some
technology it's not a symbol for it but
it is a technology that has the
potential to deal with this you know
paper that was published back in 1998
and I I really argue the entire
networking industry secured industry
never had a solution for that paper
never ever and then but AI machine
learning if you uh give you a hope that
we can complement not a replace but
complement the existing conventional
technology to solve that problem so when
you look at it right you know we you
know security industry is a little bit
uh reactive we want it to be more
proactive you know we have very limited
Security operation guys we want 10x
ideally if you ask any sea Source they
want to appear Next Step 100x people to
deal with it right that's in practice
but we don't have that so that's why we
need AI machine learning now
we have been talking about using AI
machine learning for security for many
years almost 10 years I mean I'm talking
about even in the mainstream conference
like I say right I'm not even talking
about uh papers we've been talking about
malware detection URL categorization
this is an almost I want to say it's a
solving a problem but this is a well
understood uh we are as a company
z-scaler we have put that into
production for the last few years too
but it's a zero trust leader in the
industry we are kind of getting you know
solving uh newer categories of the
problem there are really two categories
that probably are solving one is you
know either with the threats every more
invasive threats right so that's just
you know wanted to uh easy to get ahead
of us right that's what the second thing
is really the policy that's actually
less understood and less the other ways
in the last 20 years if you think about
zero trust right it's about you know
which user can connect to which
applications it's not a problem until
you deal with ten thousand hundred
thousand users and 10 100 000
applications how can you do that in the
accurate way uh personal way the
contextual and the dynamic way uh how to
do that it's it's actually you need some
potential AI this is not a focus of this
topic I want to talk is more about
evasive threats uh dear friend is going
to talk more about it
um we actually you know got in once we
got into this scale of trespassing you
know here when is a our first hire into
the into the company she came from you
know the
um the Amazon kind of the Alexa kind of
background right you know knowing a lot
about the the data science and as a
company we know a lot of the security
the skin that you're right you know we
just celebrated 15 years of being
um the the anniversary and we have a lot
of data I showed you in the first slide
250 billion transactions that's like um
almost 30X of the Google searches a day
think about it right and how do we deal
with that but one thing I want to say is
in order to deal with that it's it's not
just the knowing AI machine with any
model they are actually when a very long
way in the last almost four years three
and a half years to actually came closer
to the security uh merging right you
know the the two disciplines Ai and the
Machine learning and the data science so
with that background I wanted her to
discuss more of the you know uh more
technology and also some useful some
case studies
so here as you see on this graph where D
scale AI machine learning is filled on
how about three pillars
model domain large and the data and here
I want to elaborate a little bit more
about the data part so these skills that
actually have 240 billion transactions
per day
um what does that mean Google search
transaction today anyone you know the
current number for the Google search
CPS for the
appreciation
um
um okay so with that
has enormous amount of data and most of
the traffic there are actually benign
only tiny bit is malicious and finding
those malicious one is like finding the
needle in his side
and what makes even worse is it basic
attacks um actor usually disguise their
traffic as normal as possible
so the key for find solving a solution
is how to find a way to separate the
signal from the noise
so now I'm going to introduce you our
special recipe to do so
so the most incredible ingredient for
this is a multi-dimensional data so the
First Dimension is about the Deep
hacking instruction
so that means we do the essence of
depression for HR transactions so that
we can get the information that the user
agent
and the second dimension is about
putting the transaction in the context
of time see what happens before and what
happened afterwards
so this allows you to really see what
was going on
imagine if each transaction is either
leave and this protein that put it in
the context allow you to see the tree
now the third dimension about the cloud
effect is really helping to see the
whole Forest
as Holly mentioned G together is a sales
vendor that means we have a data about
all the companies on the clouds
by the way the pi data has been removed
when it comes to the model for analysis
now think about the threat actor they
usually attack multiple companies
now with these scales called impact data
you are able to see the whole landscape
about how the threat actors evolve into
time and how we change from companies to
companies
it's interesting to see that a lot of
the the shares some common
characteristic but at the same time
there's some involvement going on there
so now we've got this precious
multi-dimensional data we still need a
powerful modeling techniques in order to
get the Insight out of this
multi-dimensional data
um so the our approach is innovation
over the existing unknown approach it's
a
typograph based machine learning
approach now I'm going to use a concrete
example to show you what this
multi-dimension data mean and what our
approach is such about
so this is a real Attack that delivers
ransomware at the end it does happen to
a half of the descaler customers but the
good thing is we were able to detach and
block it before dressing wear was
delivered
so there were three invasive tactics in
this attack first it was using the drive
by download to trick the user to
download a zip file which looks like a
normal Chrome update
and then we um if you click uh and then
that's if I actually can get a malware
which contains both blister loader and
the cobal stripe beakening when the
blister loader gets executed the code
was tried
the Mind Control started
um you might be thinking in this attack
even we're able to deter this blister
loader then we will stop the attack
halfway right
but unfortunately at least five the list
loader is very hard to detect
one is that the it was modified from a
legitimate dll and also using the
radical signing so that it can persist
in the system
it was able to bypass the idea of the
news actually so this is from the actual
block where for the customer being
impacted uh the ones highlight in red is
was this particular Network we arrived
in the endpoint and then you see in the
log there's actually some transition to
the India vendor so that shows that this
ER vendor was active when they see the
file but still it didn't manage to stop
the file
afterwards
and on guys total the detention was
um very low at the beginning and you see
a jump that was because uh when the
publisher block and that's why the other
vendor catch up
but in fact this guy was able to detect
one month earlier than the 81 hours
before
and he also want to highlight it even
though now on the BT but I sort of note
about this one I've been delicious but
still no one knows about where this far
downward from the the IP which where the
color file download from still is looks
back deny and there's no information
about how It's associated with this
attack
thank you
okay now this is the exciting part how
we detach it
um
the uh as I mentioned earlier we are
able to put a transaction in the context
so when you look these transaction along
with part at the most you see that user
agent is normal and there's a dno of r
but when you look what happened come to
us 10 minutes afterwards you see there's
a deepening to a particular domain
now the model has a hypothesis putting
connections between these two domains
you might notice we put a deadline
inside the solid line it's because it
could be still coincident at this point
just like I go to yahoo.com I go to
zero.com doesn't mean that they are
they've been correlated
although they might be a transformation
and that's where you might remember the
third dimension about the cloud effect
data
we'll see that this is happening across
two different companies from very two
different sectors
then the chance of being coincidence
lower and then it's more likely to be
correlation
so now the model have higher confidence
there's a correlation between these two
domains
and what we see was just one of the many
connections we are building by the model
and the
um and then you see in this graph some
of them was forming the Clusters there
and we zoom into one of the cluster is
one of which we're looking at earlier
um the this one was the one we're
looking but there's in fact more than
the um
what relations to this
and they are all shared by the same
users who've been attacked by the same
and if you look closer you see that the
um some other share the same ASM
information
so the graph here we see is that it's no
longer on the flat ground level you can
see the compile all the logic there in
terms of the correlation you can see the
whole quality from different dimensions
that's why it's a primograph
so this is a
depression we are able to detect use our
special recipe and this is a quick list
of iocs
this might look familiar to you this is
what you typically get from the
threatened Health it gives you a
blacklist
but earlier you see what we are able to
do uh by our approach not just give you
touch some more detection early
but also we help on the model
explanation how we digest what's this
right it could be about
as we see earlier it's not a planet we
give you a visualization you see how
they are connected
and also that we if you democrate on one
of these domains we give you a
explanation card for each individual
host
um so some of these Sometimes some send
our pictures and the feature value and
the future importance saying which one
is playing the largest role in detecting
the particular Force as liking
suspicious
we also have the data about the progress
so many of you been working on the soft
team you might remember look at the data
in your own environment right you see
where was this host was around
but now with these guys probably by data
you actually seen it across the multiple
companies see what earliest point he
actually arrived and then uh how it was
evolving so you get a better picture
about
um whether it's likely to be something
new or old not just from your own
environment but across different
environment
um
this my example of my thinking this
ground looks familiar rice photo does
give us some relational group right
should last word is very helpful in this
particular case this particular part was
totally for us is correlated to two
domains and one domain is this excess at
the same account I still looks like
benign the other one is icomize the
light again deny one so mean that at
this point
um again what I saw to know about this
part being malicious it doesn't know how
it's related to other C2 domains are way
downward from and what is total is very
useful but the uh as you can see in this
particular case it was not comprehensive
enough for some of the invasive type and
what we're doing here is able to
complement my story and give you more
early detection and more importantly the
insight into what's really happening
yeah
so we may have the reason we're able to
do so is because we are able to put a
transaction in the context and also we
have the cloud effect
this is something we can do manually
right like how you said it's on model
scale
um I want to call you out in the case of
scale a lot of us might be thinking oh
it's just polarization right if I had
enough machine to paralyze it it might
solve the problem and when we call it
out of the challenge there is more than
that because think about this so each
transaction going through these together
across it right
um decide whether it's malicious or not
it is one translation is easy just like
people going to the airport scanning a
security scanning each forecasting by
check only this person that's easy
but if we ask about the contacts meaning
that each person needs to bring them a
Blog about what they did before
afterwards
as a as a
um as additional information was to
check
think about the memory required for that
it really only have one transaction but
if you ask this person to bring past one
week even one month later that's almost
right so how do we handle this memory
and then the um and be able to digest
those information even though they are
able to bring you and you're going to
see these 30 days fast enough so that's
where the challenge in terms of our
early approach give you the hypograph
that based on very efficient computation
not just on memory but also in
computational complexity and most
importantly give you the Insight that
you need
so this is not dimensional data is very
powerful I give you two examples but I
don't mean that that's the only the
signal there are no single killer
features it's all about the connection
among them so that's why we need AIML to
come in to learn how to combine these
different signals in case somebody
wondering what models we're using it's
not just one model they're actually more
than firing models even more models
under this so the um there are some of
them are deep learning model for example
to deter whether it's a DGA or not and
some of them are unsupervised learning
model to detect enormous and some of the
layers at the end was the supervised
learning model which should learn from
the path training data how to correlate
the data to get the signal together to
make the final verdict so it's really a
suite of the different models working
together to solve this problem
so finally on my session I wanted to
close with about the emphasize the
comprehensive
comprehensiveness of our model as we
mentioned inside that we generated from
our model is the most important one
right so we're not just happy with oh we
did have this early that's all we also
wanted to make it possible for you to
digest
um this is what is important
um I want to share with you this is an
article on nature published actually 16
years ago
salad is already called out daddy we
success of the Big Data it's actually
coming with the dangers of the trade-off
decrease in comprehensibility
with that the um
some of you working with AI machine
learning you might have this experience
about the black boss models from ml
where it gives you predictions about why
so that's definitely something we are
well aware in terms of one is probably
but also help the model to improve
further because if we don't know why
model made a mistake it would be again
you'll be almost gambling to try which
approach to to improve the model to the
next uh to take it to the next stage so
that's where the comprehensiveness is
critical for the customers who producing
these intelligence and also for
developers who build a model to really
understand why and then take it to the
next stage and this is actually article
return by my PhD advisor and this is
also research I have been doing for my
PhD making the model interpretable just
by how human beings would do and I'm
very happy to see that we are able to
make this really happening in the
industry not just a common and warning
that this could be a problem
thank you
[Music]
so
um at the beginning I mentioned that you
know the uh if you think about the
security problem a lot of that has to do
with you know leveraging the data
leverage that we are in and uh till when
I hopefully we give you a story that the
scale is what we wanted to overcome I
remember when you know I came to z-scale
I have to transact position our human
resource came to me and I said hey can
you actually explain to me why we need
Ai and machine learning because we have
been doing I'm sorry security for one
last 15 plus years and I it took me a
long time to even figure out how to
explain to someone who didn't know the
technology and I thought about it for
months and then later on I have had this
aha moment and I thought well there is
only one word I should have explained to
you which is the skill right the skill
of the data right the skill of the you
know all sorts of the behavior how do
you correlate them together the cloud
effects the scale is really the
challenge that's why we need to combine
the conventional technology and then the
rule-based or domain knowledge reverse
engineering together with the AI machine
learning data hopefully we will give you
that story give you a copy examples and
as I mentioned earlier like you know
Cloud native security is about invasive
threat detection it's also about
granular policy and in the future we see
that it's actually more than that
hopefully we will get to the world that
Ai and then data native security meaning
that you know the data is going to drive
the policy data is going to drive the uh
the the detection we are not there we
are we're still very far I mean today we
are still you know
um probably just like helping or
assisting uh the domain experts but we
hopefully make it a bigger and bigger
role and at some point right you know
the self-healing but that's going to be
the Nirvana I think the bad guys are
going to advance and then taking
advantage of the AI and a machine
learning as well so it's going to be
interesting battle but I do agree with
Jackie in the keynote opening
um speech in that the only way for us to
tackle was problems and combat the bad
guys is here together by here together
leveraging the data together by you know
hopefully we give you share the
intelligence and this is one of those
things that you know this is the end of
our presentation however if any of you
have any feedback we would have loved to
hear from you there's a survey form you
can just uh you know
put it out I'll make three questions and
uh the other thing is if you're like hey
this is kind of intelligence this is
kind of the uh approach that's a very
much interesting to you uh we would love
to follow up with you offline in terms
of the you know Advanced the technology
and or uh maybe sharing the data
figuring out some ways to sharing the
data with the community uh and then so
that a combat the bad guys together so
that's our talk
questions
[Music]
but we do have the QR code and we have
the semi phone and uh you know for you
to reach out to us you can take a
picture of our contact information too
thank you