so the last meal and I'm not sure how
many are still awake and this is not a
reflection of the presentations that the
previous business clearly but I'm sure
circulation of the luncheon had but I'll
try to not put you see completely and
I'm here to talk to you this afternoon
about what we've done at Qwest regarding
fast throughout my co-presenters here
cyril ahmud and Richard southern from
deliver and let's jump in the agenda
here so what we'll do here is first talk
about what fast year out is what is what
are we trying to do with this particular
technology and next we'll talk about why
questions to do and figure out why not
something else and then cover and a few
real-world scenarios of what we've seen
there with this deployment and share
with you some of the operation lessons
that we learned as we deployed this
particular technology over an 18-month
period and wrap up with conclusions so
to get us in to understand more fast
without this at a high level and
telephone technology words rich
hi my name is Richard southern I'm one
of the tech support engineers at juniper
Networks and I'm here to talk today
about what fast reroute is I'm not going
to try to convince anybody to use MPLS
that's a decision that each ISPs got to
make by themselves so we need to apply a
network there's several things you have
to consider basically have to plan for a
failure
because those are inevitable from the
tech support perspective which I feel
qualified to talk from I would tend to
see two different types of failure modes
these forms are categories of a control
plane filler and a data plane trailer
now these can be addressed with
different types of technologies for
example if the control plane failures
can be addressed with someone like Chris
will restart implemented per protocol
the data from failures can be addressed
with various layer 2 solutions like APs
link bundling aggregated links and so
forth if that network is also running an
MPLS cloud you can then take advantage
of second aerospace and fast reroute
when you're looking at it and networks
and trying to grow some resilience into
the recovery speed is pretty important
how fast is that now we're going to
recover from an event in the case of
using an MPLS based network with
secondary LSP s if you only have a
secondary LSP that's going to place the
burden of recovering the network on the
ingress router you English rider
Escalade for a path message to be sent
back upstream indicating that there has
been a failure downstream the English
rather is also going to be running some
high GPAs likely and there will be some
inherent delay in the change for the
next type for that IGP that's kind of
been an implementation detail that's
unique to each vendor if your LSP is if
your secondary LSP is running in stamp
and the you are at least going to save a
CSP F computational run now the some of
these delays
switching to the to a secondary LSP is
going to be in the hundreds of
milliseconds to one second range and
during that time you are going to
experience in data loss now for people
who've got the the web presentation up I
realized there's no animations possible
with with the PowerPoint conversion so
what I've done on the screen here is
tried to illustrate the process that
happens for these different types of
recovery modes indication of secondary
LSP when there is detected on the link
and this is just sent back upstream as I
mentioned to the English writer and
let's do the lines already there and
then the English writer will reroute the
traffic around the problem using the
secondary path comparing that now it's a
faster route where each node along the
path is capable of making an independent
decision to reroute the traffic these
decisions are made by the inclusion of
additional objects in the setup messages
at the detour and fast reroute objects
are the ones I'm referring to and I want
to point out that fast reroute can be
used in conjunction with other
protection methods so it's not exclusive
to faster route you can have secondaries
you can have
ApS you can have aggregated links it
doesn't matter what the underlying layer
two layer one protection method is again
talking more about the recovery time for
faster when you have a delay in
switching to the faster area that's
going to be primarily the the detection
of the failure typically that detection
will also have to include an update into
the flooring table because this is all
going to be label based you have to
property you have to propagate new
labels out into the forwarding table in
order to use that detour generally this
is in the tens to hundreds of
milliseconds window for the delay
however if you're using something like
fast fast reroute where
the Liberals are pre-loaded into the
flirting plane you can cut that number
down dramatically he's tested in the lab
and consistently seen 50 millisecond and
less numbers and for those people who
are deploying boy networks 50
milliseconds is kind of a key number in
order to be able to meet to keep your
voice traffic flowing properly now again
the general disclaimer here is vendor
specific implementation details can vary
this number then packet loss is going to
be minimized just to the packets that
were knocked out on the link when it
went down
so within fast reroute there's a couple
of different mechanisms that are
available and Israel defined by the
various drafts
there's no RFC at this point the authors
are working towards something where they
all agree on it but for the time being
there's primarily two different widely
deployed accessory up mechanisms the
first of which is something called the
detour and this is currently implemented
by both juniper and VT networks and this
is a one to one method backing up your
your protected LSP this means in essence
that each protected ISP has its own
dedicated detour to use detours also
happen to use a combination of link and
node protection and again the animation
is not there on the web but it is up
here so the blue line that is coming on
the screen represents the protected LSP
that's the path that is signaled and
because this path included the fast
reroute object rather be and all other
routers but for simplicity I'm just
Illustrated router B has created a
detour LSP going through EMF you can see
the labels that are being exchanged if
the fonts are too small and when the
link is when the link failure actually
occurs wherever B is going to reroute
the traffic using the detour that it has
however it's going to be swapping those
labels so instead of floating with the
existing labels it's going to select an
entirely new labels the key difference
here between this method and method
let's talk about is this only uses a
single label stack the other mechanism
professoriate as opposed to detours is
someone has facility backup which is an
end to one or many to one kind of backup
mechanism this means that each protected
ISP will be sharing a bypass LSP in
order to protect the traffic this means
that there will be one or more protected
Ellis Keys transiting that protection
that that bypass LSP when a failure
actually occurs within facility backup
first to sort of broad categories
there's link protection and note
protection link protection sometimes
referred to as next stop which is
implemented by Juniper Cisco VT and
others and then there's the other option
no protection which is next next top
link protection is the one that so far a
lot of ISPs has demanded there has there
has there is an immediate need at this
point to protect the critical links on
the network so that's where most of the
development time has taken place I just
want to mention that with no protection
currently Jennifer doesn't do that cisco
does and it may turn out later on that
this is a this is a good way to do it
however graceful restarts may alleviate
some of the need to have no protection
in your network this is an illustration
that shows how link protection works
across the network again very similar to
the detour mechanism the blue line
represents the protected LSP the dotted
line represents the bypass SP that's
being selected by router B you can see
the labels is a single label stacked
across the primary path now when a link
actually goes down the traffic is rear a
blur across the bypass
however in in the case of bypass LSPs
what happens is you're pushing an
additional label so rather be will push
on to the stack an additional label in
this case I've just used the value of
100,000 as the label
it can be just about anything it's then
your specific implementation detail
again as to what batteries are used for
bypass LSPs whenever he receives that to
stack packet it will pop off the other
label and forward it to rather see and
Roberson will receive the inner level of
200 in this case this was the originally
signaled labrum and it won't know that
there was a failure that had occurred
along the LSP and it will for a bit as
if nothing had happened
this illustrates another example just
using note protection in this case it's
very simple very similar to the loom
protection example I just mentioned
again router C fails here alas the
traffic through node s and a two-level
stack is created and be F pops the other
label he receives the inner label things
that came from the upstream driver which
is actually offline or non-existent now
and everything proceeds as normal now
when we compare secondaries and faster
rats is perhaps not fair to compare them
because they're really complementing
technologies but if you've chosen
network and just just chose to use
second there there's going to be some
things to consider
secondaries again it's similar than
handled by the ingress router so you
have to wait for the ingress router to
slip some traffic to the alternate path
however the good thing about secondaries
is a second here's just another LSP so
it can have its own set of constraints
applied to it generally secondaries will
also try to stay away from the existing
path and nodes so you've got a built-in
food sharing mechanism with secondaries
however secondary student could an
additional management and planning cost
and again like I said switching is done
only at the English writer so you do
experience a longer delay Safiya both
the detours and the facility back up
their varieties are both there to
protect the links however you tend to
have somewhat less control over the path
constraint and those of course Ana - you
don't have to actually configure
anything so the rsps will choose there
the bypass cells peace will choose their
own path through the network take that
as you will it can be accessed because
there's no management required is a -
because you don't know where they're
going to go so a secondary makes all the
same bandwidth requirements and requests
as the primary recipe it can make the
same class of service requirements and
will remain up after the primary LSP has
recovered this is something that differs
significantly from a fast hurry up LSP
so when the primary path fails the
secondary takes a traffic and you might
have multiple secondaries when that
primary path recovers the link flaps for
whatever reasons and the node crashed
and came back up the traffic is going to
continue the flow or the secondary until
some sort of optimization timer kicks it
back over onto a primary fast rate on
fast reroute on the other hand is
generally considered a short-term fix
you only want to wrap around the problem
for as long as it's really happening
in the meantime you want to let the
ingress router know that a problem has
happened so you want to have the English
router handle it either by switching it
maybe to the secondary or by perhaps
signaling a new primary path so at this
point I'll turn it over and learn about
actual implementation in a production
Network a fast reroute thank you it so
all we've cited the really complicated I
think
so it was next a few sort of slides I'm
trying to I'll try to see if I can get
the message across so why we chose to do
this in the quest network so that's a
picture of the network and not time to
prove that they actually do have a
network so this letter still talks
basically with the recovery requirements
that were placed upon us than we had
when we designed our IP no c-119 network
we initially had the set of forcing for
the X on a date yes protected circuits
or sauna protection was billed as you
know over the 50 millisecond recovery
time and then we might go to and also
what I do network which is wearable
unprotected valence and we need to
protect we look at the protection that
sonic piously provided but at a higher
layer and we wanted to hire a production
to be of the same order of magnitude as
Sonic was and what 18 months or so back
we had our folk summer as a voice
portion or business come to us and ask
us that they could use the IP network
for transporting the Royal traffic and
of course their requirements are pretty
stringent as far as the recovery times
and things like that girl at the third
layer part in time we were able to meet
most of their chalets like latency and
packet delivery and all those kinds of
things but the network recovery which we
primary relied on IGP which in our case
is eius eius was in the order of
multiple second so he did not meet the
requirement of less than hundred
milliseconds and we also needed to
protect the sub second level both
against link and node failures so what
were options when we looked at this
about 18 months back as we want to do
provide the sub second recovery times
you could also go back and Twitter is
our s timers in fact there's a demand of
this year in February I think
generous from party design president
presented history on the ice is the
beauty and the quest backbone they can
go back and look at that but basically
the summary of what
presentation was that the intro was
pretty stable but the convergence was in
the order of multiple seconds at the
point where we've done the tweeting we
could this was sometime last year I
could get it down to that the order of a
few seconds now it is possible to
restore to improve this with certain
enhancements Elias a specification and
the parity presentation covers that and
certainly won't have any implementations
that take into account all those
proposed enhancements the second option
we had was we still do is look at the
gross and restart mechanisms this offers
protection against the diff control
plate failures when the routing agent
was done but if a link slab with severe
Italian and then there some vendors are
working on something called stateful
follower by the the roughing engines
actually maintain state and such that
the if there are any outages the routing
card it is transparent to external
viewers that is the pores don't drop now
I'm not seeing a whole lot of wide scale
deployment in the production environment
here so we have to see how that works
and then you have disruption of looking
at flash throughout and the military
initially espousing force to obtain
sub-second convergence times however we
were stuck with their proprietary
implementations initially and we had to
think about the fact that was a new
technology and we had to go back into
interrupts people orders on this new
thing and the National hasn't talked a
little bit about operational
considerations like rip said earlier the
wave even or faster on a network before
if a link phrase the traffic is here
over over the back of the primaries you
optimize and all this happens
transparently so in theory you don't
really need to be monitoring anything
for fast reroute because we already
monitoring your links on the network so
saline goes down your you get alarm so
uniquely the protocol link has gone down
and you can
to those links and let's faster boots
job transferred Lee as possible now this
can be a good thing or a bad thing
depending on how we look at it
however if we do have problems with a
control plane now those ones are much
harder to detect if there's a new
control protocol so people are learning
this and but specially for us we haven't
had a whole lot of problems so far with
that particular issue we had little bugs
like the first implementation but things
haven't really you know gone gone gone
south completely in the worst case the
phosphoryl completely fails to work
IG PSI was available to resolve arise so
the restoration area isn't that were
slimmer because we have here as we
talked about a few things that we had a
consumer from an Operations standpoint
we have a simpler monitoring tools that
the SNMP functionality that is available
today as can do with more work traffic
management we will really do a lot of
traffic engineering so that isn't a real
issue for us and we had educator
operations folks and the changes that
have occurred to the control plane
protocol and also the bigger plane parts
and we wanted to make sure that we don't
really introduce this new protocol and
make things worse for ourselves so
really make sure that the IDP backup or
the beautified to be rather can always
call back to eius eius actually works
and initially to the extent possible we
want to keep those changes transferred
to the map so like it was explained
earlier all these things happen
transparently so the mapping they don't
have to react the changes and amending
the ferryboat apology they just need to
react to changing the physical topology
easily when the physical topology chair
make rooms that's when you're fast or
destroyed they can go back and fix the
link and let faster to do a blue lever
was going and I'm going to hand it out
to a circle as we'll talk about that if
you realize now have you seen our
network then give
a better sense of how this is working my
name is oh hell I'm the lead engineer
from testing integration glue from quest
actually I'm Sir Richard who might cover
all the critical portion of the factory
Robin I'm going to we're going to
explain like four different examples
that I have and this premise real world
scenarios and what we experienced after
the point of us we are my first examples
is pretty straightforward
link failure scenario where I have a
detailed link where our primary links
configuration looks like is between
Chicago called
3 to JFK Kiwanis a single hub LSP and
for this primary LSP I have a detour LSP
which is going to get along Chicago for
three to Chicago to to just go through
the desk
Co one I'm not going to go for every
single stream of the URLs but my family
lives here to this border this other
scenario set the path examples when I
have my jitter of failure and two
different spheres the Chicago for true
which friend a papal message to English
rather Chicago co3 and sugar broken even
one CSPs reduces their calculation and
going to recalculate a new detour for
the primary LSP and the midget roll
going to establish when survival code 3
2 4 1 3 double-crochet TWA 1 - Jessica -
TF equal 1 then 1920 fear that when is
builded the earth detour LSP
a wedding book used and know where the
parallel SP has been built on on the
second example when we experience the
family LSP or the primary means a family
goes down and in this case the traffic
would immediately shift to the digital
taking the effect of fun with
milliseconds of convergence on here that
we're going to lose very minimal and
packet in this case and then this after
the English over again gonna have his
own cstf calculation and going to build
a new primary and in this case the new
family will be the existing dicho so
build upon the existing detour and so
that new primary is going to be a new
detail and I'm not going to go in
details because there were no details
around the path but my lady which we
have a good picture over here so and the
third example that I have here where I
have both primary and detour LSP the
writing on the same cyber path and if we
lose there is any fiber cap cut along
the fiber out we may lose even amid both
primary and detour LSP and in this case
them until espacio fails and we've seen
that in this particular cases the
routing falls back to traditional IDP
and there's other features that we are
looking into it and such we are
featuring one of them and it may have a
solution to this type of other scenario
and now
and my throat examples were is a very
typical which we have some sort of node
unstable in the network and if the links
are constantly flapping and PS comes to
rescue here because Nestle web traffic
that transiting over the unstable router
or reading taking the detour path and we
also you can you can configure the
optimization timer and if this allow
operation to have ample time to make
sure that they are doing real good
troubleshooting and when they're Auto
become stable everything's fall back to
the regular path so I have some very
common troubleshooting tips I'm not
going to go over that and much as
self-explanatory and I think we all use
this troubleshooting and take so I'm
gonna hand it over to Shankar again
thank you so to conclude this
presentation I'm going to talk about
what we learned in experiences and what
I think you might also possibly learn
from our lessons from our experiences so
subsequent production for both control
and data plane traders are necessary in
our network simply because we are
carrying voice traffic faster or
provides a sub second record from data
painful years today the SS convergence
can be improved but to mine awareness
the best time that we can do is fill in
the order of multiple seconds faster
what works but it comes at a cost you
have in limited new technology and
training operations people
it lacks a lot of widely profitable
deployments so this is working with our
vendors to make interoperability a
reality and it's not perfect it's only a
lot of enhancements things like
detecting the data plane liveness when
you set up an LST you don't really know
if you can send packets through things
like srl GUI
we want to take into account that some
of the listings are actually translating
fiber conduits are shared and other
things like quality of service and
traffic engineering which we really do
not widely use in our network but for
those of you who wish to use that that
there are things that missiny to be work
done and it certainly can do with more
manageable improvements what we're
hearing a lot of traffic management the
other ancient mechanisms that we talked
about such as Grace and restart and
Satan soleus all over are interesting to
look at for control playing the
protection and the thing that we wanted
to do as much as possible as efficiently
as we can we provide only on IGP metrics
build our listings and therefore we
don't really explicitly route traffic in
different ways and the IGP would
normally have so we're not doing a lot
of traffic management and if you do wish
to discuss engineering the only scenario
where we see we are using that entire
network will be to protect against
single outage scenarios where you have
multiple stores and you soon have
real-time traffic that you must
absolutely protect the IGP converge
instruments also need to be improved
that you also some that we're working
with with our vendors and our
implementation the fashion world is
deployed only across the core so we
should leave the protection to happen at
subsections across the edge lengths and
the reality of the deployment today is
really wonder how Caleb with the control
protocol is we've done a lot of testing
in our lab we have this deployed in the
network but we don't really know the
limits of how far we can take this so
that is something that's work in
progress and that's all I had for my
presentation and I'm more than happy to
take questions
not everyone
all right thank you