Kaine I'm currently at Cisco Systems
technical leader for ipv6 in my past
life I was program manager at Microsoft
for ipv6 and before that I was the
associate manager at the energy
scientist Network for the US Department
of Energy so I've been on your side of
the thing in terms of operations then
probably the bane of some of your
existence you know building stacks at
Microsoft and now I'm trying to help
life so anyway today we'll get in and
talk about v6 and coverages fundamentals
how many of you have spent any time
thinking about v6 at all okay how many
of you have actually read some
substantial documentation and think you
have a good clue as to what's going on
the image in your hand has to be higher
than that how many of you actually
written some of the documentation that
everybody else is reading
don't say that I'm just trying to gauge
you know how bad the questions are going
to be feel free to throw any questions
out I want to be interactive I don't
want this to be me preaching to you guys
I want you to understand what's going on
when we get done here so you know jump
in and I'm not going to worry too much
about hard questions because there were
only two or three people right so Anita
Jen doesn't get to ask anything so and
my machines asleep this is not a good
time for this
goodness attending a couple weeks ago
waits until you're standing in the
middle of a presentation in an in-wall
page Oh we'll give it a second to wake
up it's probably swapping somewhere
I've got VMware running with the three
BSD VM in the background and that's just
enough memory that's between PowerPoint
and VMware it pushes it over the edge
sometimes anyway so you know v6 is more
than just a different way to spell IP
excuse me for those who had spent some
time thinking about it how long a time
frame are you thinking about before you
actually we're getting ready to deploy
this six months a year two years five
years and the customers needed okay I
really don't know why that's doing that
so you can get its attention by calling
the network out yeah the answer so when
you're going to need to do it is
partially going to be when your
customers demand it you know clearly
that's what most people are going to be
looking at is customer demand before
they start doing something this is one
of those funny technologies where if you
wait until the customer demands it you
may not be able to move fast enough
right you know you may need to have just
a little bit of a running head start
before your customer demands it because
you may get run over this you aren't
quite ready this was working fine right
before we started here
can you switch slide Knicks let me get
it open
until they were supposed to be able to
put that cable in here right yeah so
those who want to actually follow along
there are slides on the website but we
had some logistical problems between
male and me not knowing what was
supposed to happen so they're only in
PowerPoint at the moment we'll get the
other formats available as soon as it
can but for right now they're only in
PowerPoint
we're thinking that we may switch
presentation format so that people would
give us slides and PowerPoint but the
other thing that would be on the web
would be PDF get into some detail about
where the differences are just cut right
here I'm not going to need it get into
you know the technical differences
between v4 and v6 I was describing this
to some novice managers a couple weeks
ago and I said you know if you really
think you know what's going on with
before you're going to be really
confused with v6 right
it's just close enough you think you
know what's going on but it really isn't
the same there are some enhanced
capabilities we'll talk about which ones
of those are real which ones of them are
just publicity there's quite a bit of
inaccuracy and speculation floating
around particularly on the Nanog mail
list you know I pulled some comments
directly often in our mail lists and try
to answer those so that's mine we'll
just get it out of the way
and then spend a little bit of time
towards the end on transition
technologies more as an introduction to
do this course justice and get through
enough detail that's actually useful
we ended up splitting it because you
know it's like three hours worth of
stuff so we'll do an hour and a half at
this manag and then I'll do the other
hour and a half of the next where we'll
go further into detail and the
transition technologies how they get
deployed what combinations make sense or
don't but we'll do a quick introduction
to them here so why a new IP at all you
know we've got ipv4 life is wonderful
why should we be moving on in 91 we
started looking at the runway for v4
address queues and trying to project
when we would run out you know wasn't a
question if it was just a question of
when so several different projections
were done and you can go back and look
through the archives and you'll see they
span from late 90s through 2025 or
something like that when they're all
over the map there aren't any good you
know hard data projections I'm confused
here
you have a different spirit meal and I
was female I said no this one goes in
there thank you okay thank you for your
laptop I appreciate that
anyway so you know the consensus was
2008 ish was the best we could come up
with so several different proposals
we'll put together trying to figure out
what's a reasonable technology to go
forward with we had a bake-off in 94 and
what we know of as ipv6 to rough
approximation was the winner at the
bake-off so those who actually wonder
what you know happened ipv5 that
question comes up from time to time
here's the actual assignments over time
you know six through nine were the
evaluation versions for the possible
choices for the next version of IP and
version 5 is in use in a few buildings
that nobody knows you know they're great
buildings with locked doors you can't
see what's inside but it was built is
being used a little bit certainly not by
anybody in a production network that we
see excuse me
at this point seven through nine could
be recaptured but hasn't been done
so that we really need more address
space is another question if you step
back and you think about how many people
are on the Internet today and use it all
the time you know certain number of
people have the address space they need
in particularly in North America
those that don't most of the
applications they're using works fine
behind a net so functionally they have
the address space they need so we really
need more well there's a whole series of
stuff coming the mobile phone community
in particular has been pushing they want
to deploy a billion nodes at a crack
right you know take a quarter of the v4
space every time we go out and do this
they think you know there are a billion
phones out there now and they want to
grow that number and they want the most
always on the network right so that's a
lot of addresses you can't use DHCP and
reclaim them because they're always on
and then you know consumer devices in
2001 Sony put out a press release every
month and you know this some of all of
those press releases was every consumer
device that Sony ships with electrons in
it will be on the network you think
about how many devices Sony ships with
electrons in it and put it you know IP
address on every one of those always on
that's going to queue up a lot of
address space so you know the only way
they could foresee doing that was to put
v6 in the box so they're going to be
putting a lot of v6 nodes out there in
consumer land when ask Sony I don't know
but that's certainly you know the
direction they were announcing last year
with a press release every month so it's
coming to a neighborhood near you and
it'll be disguised as a refrigerator or
know who knows but the stuff is coming
and in all kinds of forms oh actually
while I was on that page page up risk
the page up
nothing on this laptop I pray there is
the lower right hand corner and put this
up one day and the guy said yeah we were
getting ready to put our fuel pumps on
the internet right so you know that's
not just marketing there was actually a
guy that was getting ready to do that
this slide could be a level and I don't
want a rat hole here you can talk to
Aaron some more later this week about
details on this I just went off to the
air into the I Ana website the other day
and pulled down the what isn't allocated
from the airing pool or from the IANA
pool the root pool and put that as the
end point on the graph the detail of the
graph comes from RFC's historical data
and then his name escapes me gentleman
from Genuity actually sat down with the
registries last year Scott yes
sat down with the registries and got
some more granular data so everything up
to the last data point is based on
either our FCS or Scott's data and then
the last data point is just off the free
pool on the inner eye in a website
anyway the reason I wanted to put this
up was not so much to show projections
late August I was in Shanghai talking to
the Education Network manager there and
you know during his talk he said he
could use 72 /h as he could get him you
know I thought that's a nice big number
wonder where that came from so over
dinner we were talking and he said
this is such a fun talk today later go
away anyway he said he's got 320 million
students right that number just kind of
slept there
okay fine then I got sort of thinking
320 million that's actually larger than
the population in North America know
exactly what the number is that is under
300 million somewhere so how many /
eights this Aaron managed for North
America no one actually looked through
and my backer napkin calculation of the
legacy / 16s and say now okay about this
percentage of them this probably Aaron
comes out to about 75 thanks you throw
away a few odd ones like MIT and Apple
and you know guys that are obvious
consumers of a lot of space you still
are in the ballpark and 300 million
takes about 70 ish / eights to support
it
there's only 90 left I set of Lee you
know the party's over
yes just the education network in China
could get the space they need
there's no v4 space left and that
doesn't count the other three quarters
of China that's just the education
network so yes we need a lot of space
and v4 is it going to work
so also while I was on that page so
anybody else who would wonders about it
there's not a sea that Christian we'd
Emma has been working on for a while
three 194 talks about address allocation
in efficiency when you've got hierarchy
right so you can only use certain amount
of the space even if so you can't use
all four billion addresses in the matter
what
so what were the goals of a new design
as we started looking forward excuse me
excited there's you know we had to be
able to support always on technologies
you can see that coming
in the early 90s always-on was pretty
much a common case mid-90s dial-up
started DHCP came in and started reusing
the address space on a fairly aggressive
basis so we're sharing space but as we
move back towards DSL in Tokyo I've been
hearing a lot of reports that for less
than $100 a month you can get Giggy to
the home on fiber all right so you know
this stuff is coming in various parts of
the world it is always on and it does
chew up a lot of address space as it
does it so we decided you know 10 to 15
endpoints is probably a reasonable goal
and 10 to the 12 sites to support those
endpoints was a you know reasonable
number so taking all that doing the
appropriate math 64-bit addresses are
sufficient to support those two design
points and that was actually the
proposal that was the v6 proposal in the
bake-off
I was on the pragmatic side the OSI
address format was actually being
deployed in real time at that point and
so I was saying you know we should just
take ownership and go with it
right it's already there we've already
got it implemented in routers let's just
use it you know the primary reason that
that battle lost was because it was a
flexible number of bits and therefore
routers would have a hard time deal with
dealing with it but you know some of the
arguments about growth and scaling and
ease about address assignments stuck and
so we ended up doubling the v6 proposal
and picking a hundred 28 bit address
that was fixed format so you end up
getting some of the best of both worlds
you've got plenty of address capacity to
handle ten to the twelfth networks
you've got easy automation and a fixed
format so the routers can can move the
bits in a hurry and so anybody that you
know wants to memorize this number at
the bottom of the screen that's a good
party number so now all right you know
every molecule known to mankind can have
its own address again apply Christian
Way daemons discussion about address
hierarchy and you'll find that you'll
never actually get all those addresses
but this is the new number that replaces
four billion
it concerns an entire slide at the
endpoint
that's more challenging because I've got
a different way of discussing that who
think whether this is the best place or
not okay this is probably the best place
one of the challenges was v6 is because
we have locked in on provider aggregates
as the primary allocation mechanism
melting home sites cause the table to
grow just same problems v4 not nothing
new there so what I was trying to do is
come up with another mechanism for
handling the multi homesites
so I put together an address format that
is based on flat lung parameters so you
know in 22 bits I could allocate 64,000
subnets per 10 meter square so that's
like 128 subnets per vertical meter for
any you know reasonably tall building so
you know 128 subnets per vertical meters
half the size of this one everywhere
including the oceans yeah that's a much
easier number to deal with than whatever
it was planted there right and that's
only sixteenth of the space and so it's
a much bigger number than that okay
we'll come back to that when we get to
be address warm out here a little bit
Japan has been pushing pretty hard as I
said you can get Giggy fiber-to-the-home
in Tokyo now the Japanese government has
had a tax incentive plan in place for a
year and a half now or so and a
promotion council trying to get v6 out
there how many of you went to the IETF
meeting in Yokohama you see the taxis
that were running around Yokohama with
v6 enabled you know one of the things
they were doing was the weather station
would like to be able to get much more
fine-grained weather reporting than they
can with their radar systems
so they outfitted the windshield wiper
controls in the taxicabs and we're
repeating reporting back speed data on
the windshield wiper controls and so you
could get very small pockets as all of
the taxis in an area would have their
windshield wipers on faster than other
areas so you know you not only did you
know it was raining in Yokohama you knew
which streets were actually getting
pounded as opposed to just reasonable
rain right but you know that's the kind
of new application thinking that can
happen when you don't have to worry
about you know addressing every taxi cab
windshield wiper control in the city
right addresses are free at this point
if you were trying to do that would be
for probably you could make it work but
that would chew up a big chunk of
address space and you'd have to go
justify and that it you know why would
you bother so there's you know some
things that are going to come out of the
promotion council in terms of new
applications that I think are going to
be really innovative they've been
showing off the v6 refrigerator if a
couple of shows lately not quite sure
what it does because I've never been
able to see one but I've seen pictures
of it Korea is also pushing hard ones in
Seoul in July and they were saying the
65% of the homes have broadband access
now most of its DSO but there are
already past the point of just trying to
get broadband pushed they got 65% of the
population already behind the broadband
connection always on the song company
was actually considering switching from
traditional telephony to sip based voice
over IP that's how much they're moving
into this and how aggressive they're
trying to be China is trying to work on
collaboration with Japan in several
fronts as I said the education network
can't get the address space they need
the rest of the country is trying to
push into this space as well so it's not
just educational excuse me
Europe it's not as pressing in Europe
there are pockets where addresses have
been more difficult to come by so
there's more of an interest in Europe
than there in say in North America but
certainly not as urgent as it is in Asia
did you want to comment anything okay
one of the things we're trying to do is
get back to the point where we've got an
indian to architecture again if you want
to have your phone called there's a
destination end point on the network it
has to be addressable on the network
right and you don't want five people
sitting behind an app to have to go
manually configure the net so they can
receive phone calls this just has to
work gaming is going to be a big push
for v6 deployments and you could appear
games where the current Linksys
documentation is a 10 page book on how
to configure the games that have already
shipped but every time you get a new
game you have to go download another
couple of pages for how to configure for
that game and it's just you know on and
on your on you configure your mat for v6
support once and when the games just
work right so peer-to-peer games there's
a lot of interest and a very low barrier
to entry in that space
so what's different you got a high level
you know the addresses are four times as
big we'll talk a little bit more about
it but they also have scope with some v6
you get DHCP as an options but you also
have an option for serverless
configuration this is a mode where the
router is in charge of telling the nodes
what address space to use this avoids
any potential for conflict between the
routing infrastructure and the DHCP
servers right you can't possibly get out
of sync with the routers if the routers
are the ones in charge so that's one of
the new capabilities IPSec is built for
v4 and and for v6 as well primary reason
it shows up is because it's mandated for
v6 support v4 it's an option and if
you're actually deploying in an
app-based infrastructure you have to go
to extraordinary lengths to make IPSec
work typically it just doesn't
so it's quotes a v6 feature that you get
IPSec because with v4 so much of the
network as an added already you can't
reliably get IPSec to run just anywhere
you want to go mobility there's another
feature that's been described mobile v4
exists Mobile v6 is slightly different
it the primary difference is that it has
the ability to get rid of the triangle
routing right so with v4 Mobility you're
forced into routing through a home agent
when you're away from home with the six
mobility you route through the home
agent to establish the connection but
then once that's established you can
tell the correspondent oh by the way I'm
over here now stop sending in through
the home and direct shot to me
you know a lightweight tunnel is
effectively what it is so that that
capabilities in there we'll get into
that a little bit more as we go down the
road here quality of service if you look
at the press about all the wonderful
things that v6 is going to bring you it
looks like one of these service reality
is it's exactly the same this service
this service disserve there's no
difference
the one thing that v6 does have that
before doesn't have is a set aside set
of bits for the flow label there's 20
bits set aside and we're calling it a
flow label at this point we're in the
process of trying to define it but until
that thing is defined and routers know
what to do with it you get no difference
right so there's a hope that v6 will
eventually be able to do something that
v4 can't but in the short term quality
of service is identical between the two
so what else have we got
IP multicast now everybody's aware of IP
multicast I assume the primary
difference with these six multicast is
there are now four billion groups per
subnet right so you don't have any of
this managing groups based problem
anymore because you got four billion of
them on every subnet
it's the inverse problem there's so many
you can't figure out which ones or what
and the scoping for the range that the
most those addresses are used over is to
find architectural and v4 it's just kind
of an administrative agreement what the
scopes are going to be little v6 it's
actually architectural a defined what
the scopes are going to be so you know
so when you get to the bottom line v6
expands the address space to a very
large number
and we've got a lot of hierarchy and
structure expecting you know to grow the
routing table in a manageable way we've
moved into the space where notes can be
more easily configured than they came
with these for DHCP you know this is
important if you're going to have a very
large number of nodes beyond what you
currently think of as a large number of
notes today you know you can manage
ability only scale so far with the
server we've streamlined the header
format which I'll show you in a minute
and then fixed extensions and options
there any questions before I move on
from this kind of marketing stuff so ok
there's some advanced features will come
to those later and then you know you
don't want to spend too much time here
ok for just a general question how many
of you already have v6 allocation whew
how many of you are thinking about you
know you're going to do it few more ok
this page has the census that you go to
to find out what the current policy is
it changed in June so hopefully you know
the current policy is something that you
can live with when anybody goes at this
point and you know signs up to get some
v6 address space you'll get a slash 32
unless you need it like now and then you
get a 35 but logically everybody gets a
32 the expectation is that all sites get
slash 48 I'll show this again in a
minute
you know that is unless you know you're
doing a single subnet in which case you
know five six before is okay to go ahead
and allocate you know / 128 there's a
lot of debate back and forth as to
whether you use those on point-to-point
links on routers you can but it's kind
of like a lot of pain to go through so
we're not very much game so I'll show
that here in a minute too and if you
were in Asia you know and I asked that
question there wouldn't be six hands it
would be you know eighty hands right
there's a very large number of networks
that have already gotten address space
from AP NIC Europe there's actually a
bigger number this was trailing behind
until the last three months and then
they shot ahead for some reason and so
you know as it's September there are 90
something allocated out of Europe and
then North America right it's like you
know nobody in this community is really
considering v6 seriously because they
haven't gone off to get address space
right this is a very obvious statistic
that you can look at and figure out
where the interest is in various parts
of the world and why there's a lot more
customer demand in other places than
there are here
so we have a new header we did this
drawing and the graphics artist got
ahold of it and screwed it up and I
tried to fix it and it doesn't look
right anyway the addresses are four
times as big but the head is only twice
as big so that's what I'm trying to show
here several of the fields those in red
are gone they're either in extension
headers or things like to check
somewhere nobody actually used it
anymore right it's just extra bits so
those are just taken out the base v6
header its whole function in life is to
get the packets across the routing
fabric as quickly as possible if there's
a function that doesn't have to do with
getting the packet across the routing
fabric it's in an extension header
primarily those are in system kinds of
things to worry about one exception is
the extension header for hop-by-hop
options but yeah for the normal case you
want to get those packages you know
across the routing fabric it's a fixed
format minimum number of fields to worry
about just getting it out there and go
right everything else has been moved
into extension headers so you know we
streamlined it and we move some fields
out
checksum is gone if you really want to
check some you can use the
authentication header it provides a much
better integrity check of the header
than just a checksum anyway the links
field now excludes the v6 header the
alignment has changed from 32-bit to
64-bit s-- you know things to make it
easier for you to process while you're
at all of these changes
interesting translation between my
PowerPoint years the time to live the
name has changed to protect the guilty
it's now hop limit which is what
everybody always treats it as anyway you
know long long ago it actually did have
to do with time because packets took
more than a second to leave the box but
protocol solo was now called the next
header field part of that is just you
know recognition that what maybe there
is not just a new protocol but an
extension header or you know who knows
what but it's just the next header
whatever the header may be redefined
precedence and TOS into traffic class
which it kind of was anyway that for v6
there's nothing except traffic class and
then you know we added the floor label
field and if we can ever agree on what
that thing means you might be able to
make some use of it somewhere the
segment header you know I put this one
in here in particular routers do not
fragment packets like these or you end
up with all kinds of weird cases because
the rotors might fragment and then you
have to keep track of all the fragments
and put them all back together in
various places in v6 the routers don't
do that path into you must work either
that or the host must send minimum size
packets right so one of the things that
network managers has to do is go back
and figure out you know am i filtering
ICMP messages that are blocking path
into you if so that's got to get fixed
right what's these six there was a
little bit of help because it was given
its own packet type right so it's got
its own ICMP type just for path into you
so it makes it easier you don't you know
just don't block all ICMP block these
things you care about blocking and
leaves path into you open because you
need need that one to work
right if a link can't support the 1280
bite minimum in m2 you for v6 it's
alright for the router to fragment and
reassemble the defragmentation
reassembly across that you know like ATM
kinds of links right you're doing
chopping this thing up and you put it
back together on the other end but it
doesn't leave those two endpoints
sorry minute right so those packets are
moving through the network from any
point along the way fragmentation is
done by the in systems only not by the
network itself and said we get back to
address allocations the registries had
been allocated slash 23 the old policy
was networks and get flash 35 but that's
changed to 32 s so if you've got a 35 my
understanding is you can go ask and
they'll change it to a 32 so you don't
have to go through the whole process
again there's only one semi-hard
boundary in v6 and if it's not like
really hard but for most formats of the
address the low order 64 bits are the
interface identifier the upper 64 bits
are the subnet identifiers you know
essentially what the routing fabric uses
to get the bits to the last wire
as I said earlier there's this
expectation that sites will get flat 48
speed Goering did a study last year
because there was some concern about
possibly running out of last 48 and the
2001 format identifier we're allocating
out of right now is one-eighth of the
total v6 pace and accordingly the
calculations he did for the population
of the earth in 2050 so 48 years from
now projected population there are
enough / 48 in this one prefix for
everybody to have a half a dozen
personally right so we're not going to
run out of these anytime soon and you
know with your size 48 you now have 16
bits of subnet space anybody quick know
what a correlation between 16 bits of
subnet spaces and a v4 allocation
more sixteen bits of subnet space all
right
most people with a slash eight have
functionally sixteen bits of subnet
space right you know you can play that
but it's you know on that order right so
you're talking about every site gets you
know plenty of space to work with you're
not going to run out any time soon and
what you're managing at that point is
subnets the interface identifier didn't
actually put any slides in on that
that's bad most off talking you know I
guess I did
we'll come back to the interface
identifier and then I'm also spawn here
okay this one's out order format for how
you actually type them in textually
everybody who's used to got a decimal
you're gonna have to relearn right it's
colon delimited hex very long strings
yes there are long strings of zeros like
you've got here in this section they can
be compressed out with a double colon
you can do that once right so you can
compress out and say some number bits
colon colon some number other number of
bits and because you can only do that
once you can back calculate how many
zeros there must have been it's a
complete set of zeros so if this was
actually ended as F 0 0 F F 0 0 it
wouldn't be the two zeros with the FS
it's everything between the colons
because you have to be able to count you
integer number of 16-bit zeros there is
some dotted decimal left just to confuse
things
there's a set of addresses that were
used for coexistence with v4 and
transition and so they've got v4
embedded in them and therefore to
represent those and make it easier for
you to figure out what's going on we
actually put the v4 part of the address
in by the decimal format so you can say
ok with this v6 prefix I've got this v4
address that I'm used to and you know
this is being for Maps purposes this is
something that an origin node would look
at and say that guy only speaks before
right that's what that particular
address means you know I've got a v6
address that I got back and so I'm a v6
node and I'm aware of what's going on
but the guy I'm trying to talk to is a
v4 only node that's what the map
addresses are for
there's another format called compatible
which is intended for automatic
tunneling looks very much the same
except there's no less in the middle
there it was a great idea allows Indian
tunneling because you've got the v4
address is better varied in there but
the only way you can make it scale is to
inject the entire v4 BGP table into the
v6 BGP table so we're going no let's not
do that case it's probably a bad idea I
mean so we're trying to discourage the
use of compatible addresses they're
still in the documentation but it's one
of those we're trying hard not them get
people a reason to use them as I said
you know addresses have scope so what
does that mean to you how many of you
have seen a host Auto configure to
169.254 something links co-linear
routers are passing those packets right
those are after the fact allocated for
link use 1918 addresses everybody's very
familiar with those are for use within
the site you guys don't route them
between sites right
so architectural a we looked at what was
going on and said we've got fundamental
use for link scope things we've got
fundamental use for site scope things we
should just architectural II define some
space for those uses right so there are
two chunks of address space set aside
for Lincoln site and then the rest of it
set aside for global the primary
difference that you'll see between v4
and v6 in this space is that in v4 it's
possible for you to actually go
configure and know to have multiple
addresses but you really have to work at
it almost always they have a single
address and v6 they will have multiple
addresses like the only time you end up
with a single address is if you're on an
isolated wire with one other node and
you're both using link-local otherwise
you will have at least site local or
link local and some other format maybe a
site or maybe global that you will
simultaneously have multiple addresses
and they will probably be simultaneous
addresses from multiple scopes this is
where it's going to be a little more
challenging in terms of figuring out
exactly what's going on right so those
two those are on the same wire and
they're talking to each other
according to sending rules they use a
link local scope to talk to each other
because that's it's a logical thing to
do if the router goes down they don't
care they're talking to each other on
the same wire right any rate there are
multiple scopes they are used
simultaneously which is a big difference
and addresses have lifetime right and
these for pretty much everything was
there you might have some lifetimes in
DHCP but that's really for you to come
back to DHCP to give you allocation
that's not any indication about the
validity of using that address it's more
of you know I'm supposed to go back to
the server with v6 the routers will
announce on the wire these prefixes are
valid for this length of time
right the design for this is set up so
that you can move a site from one
provider to another in a graceful manner
and so you've got a week long dialogue
prefix lifetime for the old provider and
getting to bring in the new provider
fine you start announcing the new
provider prefix you can have multiples
it's not a problem and so we're going to
allow all nodes to have multiples but I
shortened the lifetime on the older
prefix to six days and start shortening
it every day right
well the nodes that are aware of that
prefix can continue to use it because
it's still valid but when they go to
establish a new connection they're going
to use the longest available lifetime
right so the new providers prefixes are
going to have a longer lifetime you're
going to start new connections on the
new providers address space any existing
connections can persist on the old one
until your lifetime expires yeah and if
you've given it enough time a few days
is usually reasonable the number of
connections that you actually tear down
at the end of that window is going to be
close to zero because they will all
naturally die offs and new connections
are all naturally open on the new
service so you don't do this hard cut
over from one service provider to
another issue has to do in v4 so you
know lifetime is there there's preferred
lifetime and valid lifetimes just to
make it more challenging give you enough
knobs that you can actually do what you
want to do from this so I said and they
will have multiple addresses here's the
set right you start off every node has a
loopback address and they have more than
one
it's doing weird things every no we'll
have every interface will have a link
local address you may have site local
addresses for use and a little bit more
than about those a minute
for you some within the site we've got
some transition mechanisms 6to4 we'll
talk about later but that's an order
configured type of address there's Auto
configured v4 compatible
we've got solicited node multicast as I
was saying earlier if you think you know
what's going on you're going to be
completely confused with c4 there is a
distinct address resolution type for
every media you've got right so there's
art for Ethernet and there are other
flavors of art for whatever variety of
media you might be attaching to with v6
there's one thing it's called neighbor
discovery it's an IP multicast function
so every node will come up and subscribe
to what's called a solicited node
multicast address which is a derivative
of its address space but it in the
multicast space and there may be
collisions but the number of collisions
is low and so the number of nodes it
could possibly respond to this as you
know can be countered on one hand and
they're aware of what's going on so you
know you don't end up with massive
problems here there's an all nodes
multicast address we'll talk some more
about anonymous that there's global
anonymous addresses and then there's
global published addresses as I said you
could have multiple providers need to do
this transition well you don't have to
do a transition you can actually have
nodes with multiple fighters permanently
on so like the Cisco campus in San Jose
has for service providers connected
full-time if we use this mechanism
you've got for prefixes in the global
published and for in the global
anonymous for every note right so I've
gotten up to order 15 addresses per note
in a hurry right so you know the visa oh
you had an address v6 you might have
handful of addresses or a boatload of
addresses depending on your service
rudder characteristics thank and there
are rules for how you sort through these
because you get a boatload of addresses
figuring out which one you're supposed
to use is another challenge I'm not
gonna spend a lot of time on these rules
but you know basically there are
preferences given and there are certain
cases where it is actually smarter to
use the v4 address the most obvious is
just the two nodes have global v4
addresses but they have mismatch scopes
and v6 v6 addresses so you pick this
thing you know is going to work in the
global v4 addresses right so follow
through the rules
you pick your source address and your
destination address right because you've
gone off the dns and you've got back
this lists or the other guy all right so
you've got a list for him and a list for
you and you got to go there which said
of this right
it's longest match you know that's the
default tiebreaker here all right so the
intent of that was maybe if you you're
sharing a service provider once we're
doing service provider based allocations
if you're sharing a service provider you
probably want to pick the address pair
that actually uses that shared service
provider because the service will
probably be better and if you're going
through some number of exchange points
somewhere or caring points right so you
know the goal is to make things work as
well as possible without a lot of manual
effort and you know if you don't don't
like the rules you can always override
them with local policy right since this
is an in system function local policy on
the box can say I don't care what those
rules are you're going to use this set
of addresses period
and so you can override this so the
various formats for link or folders tend
to set aside that identifies ok this is
going to be a link-local the next 54
bits must be 0 and then the Lord or bits
or the interface identifier and to make
the configuration easy we're saying take
your MAC address and jam it in there
there's an algorithm for how you take a
48-bit MAC and jam it in there when I
Triple E starts allocating 64-bit Macs
they just go straight in right for use
on the wire that's the simple thing to
do you don't end up with any collisions
you can double check and make sure
you're not gonna have collisions but
that's what that's all about
foresight local we've got another tended
identifier set aside for that the
original specification tried to align
the subnet administration with the
global space so that if you're
administering the set of subnets for use
within a site you want that particular
set of bits probably to match the
service provider things that are coming
in right so we said you know 16 bits and
then when there were enough people
complaining that they actually wanted to
be able to use this mechanism between
sites for their internal private network
we're going ahead and opened it up so
all 64 bits are for local administration
but the smart thing to do is keep that
16 bits in the middle the same between
your global space in your private space
and make it much easier for you to find
the sudden that you're looking for right
right now you know the number of sudden
that you manage is a fairly small number
in most cases unless your MIT or HP or
somebody that's got a big chunk address
space
the interface identifier can be Mac
derived again it can also be
administered through DHCP or manual
static configuration whatever you want
there's not a lot of structure to that
other than these are jiaming in the max
so the global one registries are
allocating to the service provider
service providers are allocating / 48
sites so then you've got 16 bits of
subnets for local administration within
the site the interface identify there
can be the Mac again can be locally
administered and it can also be a random
value and I said we could have these
privacy addresses I don't think that's
where I call them at any rate what
they're for is to avoid the problem of
being trackable in the KC aware I'm
using mac addresses if I wander from
service providers to service provider
you know I'm at Starbucks in San Jose
I'm the Starbucks in LA and I'm at
Starbucks in Seattle bang-bang-bang and
they know I do this track every week I
you know when I start showing up there
will be an ad on my laptop telling me
about some things that place next door
because it knows I'm going to be there
right
I'm trackable if I'm using my MAC
address doesn't matter which service
provider I'm on that MAC address
constantly shows up so with the problems
that Intel was having CPU serial numbers
and Microsoft was having with goods it's
like no you don't do anything that's
trackable for that granularity so we put
random numbers in here for services that
you expect for somebody to call you like
you're you're pretending to be a server
your phone you're a game host whatever
you're going to register something in
DNS therefore you're not anonymous in
any case so you might as well register
your MAC address no you're not you're
trackable through DNS therefore you're
trackable therefore it doesn't matter
what you use so we're recommending you
use the Mac based addresses for DNS but
for anything where you connect out and
spend with anew connection you want to
use the anonymous values that way you're
not trackable right current policy of
all the implementations I've seen is
they roll this number once a day
so you use it for a day and then you use
some new ones for the next day the truly
paranoid will roll this once a
connection right I don't want any
connection tracks period and so you know
every new connection gets a new random
value think about what that does to your
neighbor cash your functional equivalent
of the arc cash right
if somebody's rolling one of those every
connection they could blow out your cash
in a hurry so you want to discourage the
paranoid but you know the service is
there
there are several tunneling formats
compatible address we just get the load
of 32 bits with the v4 address so you
can find it in tunnel again that doesn't
scale too well so what we did is it took
and put the v4 address up in the pre six
space as if it were a service provider
allocating this I think so now I get all
of the same capabilities that I have
with a v4 or with a v6 global address
format because I've got a slash 48
allocated to a site but it's derived
from a single v4 address all right so
any global v4 address I can jam one of
those in there and now I have an entire
80 bits for use by the local site I
don't need to do neighbor discovery
across with v4 clouds because I already
know the destination address so the next
lower down layer it's it's embedded I
said I just unique out the v4 address
slappa v4 header on ship it there guy on
the other end takes the d4 header off
and those were to deliver v6 does the
same thing coming back so that's what
fairly straightforward one isatap is a
new thing that hasn't actually gotten
all the way to RFC yet but it's
architectural II the same thing but
putting the v4 address back down in the
lower 32 bits again while allowing for
the upper part to be actual prefixes
instead of all zeros right so
you can use 6to4 and isatap together
where you tunnel within the site so you
don't have to actually upgrade all the
routers within the site to v6 you get to
the edge of the network and then you can
tunnel again using 64 across the service
rider network until they all get to
where they can support it did you want
to just we're going to change tapes it's
going to take a second in this
particular case where you take the Noah
please explain the 64-bit prefix for
this subnet even better than here as
well so I can now have several routes
per subnet right and administer them
with or within the subnet
so I don't have to worry about all those
sharing and other nonsense is going on
there's a lot of work to be done in this
place the address space is satisfied
then and certainly can handle growth so
as long as we're going to have to worry
about it
writing something universe that we all
care about exactly the same like just a
bit where I distinct things that tell
you exactly what's going on
the changes were made but the biggest
issue so we need any more SPF is you
know SPS looking tears of loose varanasi
left ocean 356 and so you're going to
have a little bit of a very includes
challenge to run them both
simultaneously for a while to something
else happens I am in billions running
iOS backs and everything already
we enjoyed and designed to handle Reggie
I understand myself and fairly
straightforward drop in right so is is
site
networks don't seem too much change okay
security our implementations are
required to support I do check this is
required in quotes no it's not in quotes
should be in claiming the non-healing
implementation I'm aware of supports all
of IPSec yet right so there are still in
the process of catching up with this
particular requirement but yeah in the
grand scheme of things in a year or two
all right
I love the recipe IPSec key distribution
is not any better and I did some v4
right so that's still going to be the
blocker the nodes can support it but
unless you've got a key distribution
infrastructure under you it doesn't
really help quarterly a service as I
said earlier the exactly the thing that
services in service in serve they work
the same way and just moving better
bigger headers around
I don't think there's anything really to
say here and
okay the 20 bit flow label it's possible
that we can figure out some mechanism
for RSVP to signal what's going to
happen in land in the floor level it's
also possible that the in nodes just use
some heuristics or how they allocate
these based on local site policy and the
slower the spec is written there is no
structure or clear mechanism for how
that 20 bits gets defined and so even if
we get to the point of agreeing that it
gets delivered in the end without being
modified in the network there's still no
clear definition of what that pattern
means and what you're supposed to do
with it so that's work in progress
signal disks wave is a nice compromise
between the two mobility I said we'd get
to that
whether house can have you know yet
another address and I said you've got
all of these wonderful addresses core
interface yeah if you're mobile you've
got a home address you know the thing
that you're known by when you're home is
actually a set of addresses but we won't
go there we'll just say you've got one
for the moment so you know you get this
home address somebody tries to contact
you the home agent router says oh that
guy's not actually here right now
because I remember he told me he was
over there and we'll funnel the packets
to you right so the packets come
directly to where you're at right now
because you've told the home agent when
you show up somewhere else
when you receive those packets then you
tell the course I'm at node I'm over
here and what it does is wraps the home
agent the home address is an option and
the outer address is your current care
of address so it still goes across the
network as fast as possible because it's
just an address that gets you to an
endpoint right when you receive it you
recognize it as it's got an option for a
home address so you rip that often and
that's what you're actually using to
maintain the application connection
since the home address with that you've
been wandering networks and the
application doesn't perceive that the
address is changing out from under it so
icmp we talked a little bit about it's
basically the same there are primitive
messages that are distinct there are
back to big I said was an explicit
message type you know that was to allow
us to be able to get it past filters or
dip filters we built so that it can be
allowed through without having to worry
about some of these other choices there
are some neighbor discovery functions in
particular you want to know who your
routers are on this link the routers
will come up and announce their presence
and say yeah I'm a router and here are
the prefixes for use on this wire that's
an ICMP message the in modes can be can
take those messages and auto configure
themselves if they do that and they
choose to register those back in DNS you
have to think about how you're going to
do a dynamic update for DNS right if the
node is wanting to do that and it's the
only one that knows the address because
it just generated it right so there's a
tie here between the mechanism for Auto
configuring hosts and an infrastructure
that supports dynamic updates you don't
have to go down that path but that's you
know well the consequences of doing it
if you don't you end up with the same
mechanisms you have today with DHCP
allocating the address and managing the
dns updates excuse me
hey you know I've gone a little bit
quick here because we're running longer
than I expected
okay when the rabbit talks about you
know sometimes it's announcements it'll
send out the I'm a router what the
lifetime's in the prefixes are it'll
tell them those whether or not they're
supposed to use DHCP right and whether
that DHCP is just for addresses or for
things other than addresses so you can
tell the nodes through a router
advertisement here's a set of prefixes
and we manage the address space from the
routers where we're managing all this
other stuff or to set local policy kinds
of things through DHCP
you can tell with you know nodes with
the Lincoln to you is it's assumed to be
1280 unless otherwise specified larger
fella lady is the minimum Lincoln to you
thank so it's considerably larger than
it was for 4v4 we made it twelve eighty
to allow for the fact that if you had
IPSec and mobility running at the same
time when you got all those extra
headers and had a V for transition
mechanism so you've got all these
headers chains you might not be able to
sit it in 1500 bytes right so we backed
it down to where you could put all these
extra headers on it and still sit in
1600 bytes okay so those can find each
other through multicast you know send
solicitations and advertisements back
and forth and you know there's a flag in
there so you can tell whether the node
is a router or not and first question is
going to be here these things secured
and the answer is no right it has the
same security as art it's just there
alright so there's a little bit of a
hole that's being looked at right now
for how secure doesn't clear this
because anybody can come up and claim to
be a router you probably don't want that
Oh in the general case has expected to
use this that our advertisement to
configure their addresses it's expected
you know as we were putting this
together and looking at the number of
nodes you know DHCP management becomes a
real problem when you start to grow it
right so the only way to scale the
number of nodes up that we're talking
about is to get past the ACP so we're
trying to make this the normal case that
nodes self configure and they're also
expected because of this privacy issue
to be using these temporary addresses
for outbound connections if you really
really want explicit control you can do
that one of the things that we're in the
process of trying to figure out right
now is what happens in the case where I
noticed self-configuring off the router
advertisement but there's no you know
DHCP option that says oh by the way DNS
is over here right and see having the
find DNS if you're doing self
configuration we've got a couple of
mechanisms written up there's some
arguments going back and forth as to
which to pick right now my personal
preference is a link-local multicast
what that doesn't seem to be winning the
day there's a strong preference for a
defined anycast which is a routing
advertisement post route functionally
into this space so you've got some
well-known addresses that you go to edit
whichever that comes out there will be a
mechanism for notes to find dns you know
address and dns are the two fundamental
things once you've got that you can
pretty well go from there but if you
don't have dns you're kind of stuck
we're going to talk about how to do the
renumber and on the fly there is a
router lee numbering protocol that has
been defined so you can sit at one point
in your network and propagate prefixes
out to all of the rest of the routers so
you don't have to go touch every router
to tell about a new set of prefixes to
use
I haven't seen a lot of people really
excited about that yet but it is defined
in there if you care
again MTU is 1280 and you know routers
are not going to be fragmentation as you
can see we seriously grew the number of
bytes from 68 to 1280 it would have gone
larger in fact the guys that are working
in the 10-gig protocol space say 64
kilobyte frames is not big enough
because if you get any latency that just
can't keep it full right so yeah it's
coming it's going to be bigger soon if
path MTU is not working and for whatever
reason nodes cans and 1280 by packets
and expect them to be delivered
thank you all links must be able to
support that quickly to get into some of
the speculation exactly I just saw mail
last night you know we're not running
out of v4 addresses because we're not
handing them out right yeah you can't
get one we must be out right the only
people asking about v6 or the people you
know we've heard something about it and
therefore they just want to know well in
North America that's probably true but
in Asia it's definitely not right
they're pushing hard in that space
because they have a real need you know
yeah Japanese government didn't put out
in tax incentives to get people to move
because they thought this is a cool idea
they want their economy to move into a
new space they want to be able to do new
things that they just can't do without
address space and they can't get it so
they're looking at this as strategic
economic you know push
ipv6 adds no functionality or V over V
for with net well yes I'm running mail
or web services where I'm a client this
is true right if I want to put up a web
server this is not true right
so another classic example my son just
wanted to put up NSF's between these two
Linux machines
he's got Tim Linux machines in his room
but they're on opposite sides of the net
that was feeding the house and of course
NFS won't run through that and RPC won't
go so you know I said we can put it on
v6 well that's fine we got v6 running
between these two nodes through the 64
router and the net but there's no NFS
for v6 on Linux yet I tried to convince
him to switch to FreeBSD but he wouldn't
do it
take the saucepan this directory doesn't
work it doesn't work in the cart routing
the mixing of routing the mayor only
which the single grabbing domain in its
current implementation I don't know that
it's going to work in multiple routing
domains but I know it yeah it's also
true that they're pushing very hard in
this space right it's
and very large on me as people was
working on workarounds for naps right
and so the question is do you pay
there's army of people to work around
naturally do you pay them to fix it so
that people don't have to work around
maps you know there's some motivation
that is just business self-interest in
that space okay clear two P replications
now I like I said games it just doesn't
work right it's always the participants
are not in the same address space they
can't share information with each other
directly you know can do it through a
central server that's on the public
space but they can't do direct
peer-to-peer and and get it to come out
right that was short I've got another
couple of slides I don't know why
they're not showing up here these six
deployments will come from the edge as
we said earlier you know people are
going to wait till they hear their
customers demand it's okay well assign
customers are at the edge so until they
start demanding it you're not going to
do a lot of work in the middle right
what you need to be looking for or
protocol type 41 packets right if you
see a lot of protocol type 41 packets
lying in your network that means your
customers are quotes demanding v6
they're not actually telling you they're
just using it right and you know they're
using v6 whether you're ready or not and
they're just tunneling over your v4 so
that's what's going on there
you never you know comment was a visa
true outing which changed drastically
not really you know wedding is the same
there are some concerns and issues about
the potential for growth and multihoming
but outside of that there's not anything
that's really different one of the
things that I keep trying to bring back
to the table is that there are only 11
thousand AES is injecting routes into
the v4 table you can go to this space
and you do a dynamic reclamation of all
of the prefixes that people are
announcing so you give them all
everybody but HP has at most 1/8 right
so they all get one 538 there's only 11
thousand entries in the entire system
right and so you've got some service
providers doing traffic engineering EE I
don't care it's not going to be that big
a deal and that's even if you just
inject all those prefixes in there it's
it it can be a lot better so we're
adding is not as big a problem as people
make it out to be multitask has its own
set of problems to get worked out but
whenever it gets webcast was before
we've got more than enough extra things
for v6 to make it better
interface items have privacy issues this
one comes up from time to time as I said
the original definition you take the MAC
address and jam it in there that does
have privacy issues right but by using
these random values we get around that
you can use DHCP you can manually
configure there's all kinds of options
privacy addresses or the interface IDs
are not this privacy issue
well if it can be if you choose to let
them be but they are not by definition
there's been a complaint with the
privacy addresses actually cause an
infrastructure impact on DNS and yes if
I chose to register the privacy address
in DNS I could turn DNS especially if
I'm doing it once a connection that
really be silly and every time I open a
new connection I go turn DNS wood it
makes more sense to do that right I
shouldn't be using something's designed
for privacy which something is
explicitly not private right DNS is not
private by definition so why am I using
a privacy function so you could but
nobody's going to actually do that let's
put together this timeline that tries to
put this in perspective there was a lot
of Cleef in the press especially little
last year saying our research hasn't
happened already therefore it must be
dead
right well it's a project that takes a
long time and in fact there's a sequence
of things that has to happen before it
can really be deployed you know you've
gotta have applications so you don't
have any applications what's the point
you know we can have the best network in
the world we can have the best
insistence tax in the world but if the
application is still calling the veto
API you know it's going to ship v4 bits
until the applications get ported and
start calling the v6 api's you know
you're not going to go anywhere service
providers to a large degree you know
they're going to wait until they see
applications come in the market right
you know they see that there's going to
be demand some of them or wait around
until they actually hear the customer
called that someone will be looking and
they say all this application somebody's
gonna call I'll step in front of it
right but either way that that isn't
going to happen until after applications
get on the move consumers if we've
exposed which version of the protocol
that is running to the consumer we've
really screwed up right consumers type
on you know type names they click on
links magic happens if they know that it
was v4 v6 it's just screwed out all
right so some holiday purchase they make
somewhere along the way here they're
going to get these accepts in that test
station or there
whatever right and it's just going to go
now the early adopt the kind of guys
that have to go reconfigure the net
maybe a rare but you know the general
consumer shouldn't no enterprises on the
other hand think they have people that
know what's going on I think that this
entire staff of people that's trained in
V for an entire network management
structured keep this minute more network
learning after we train everybody they
have to retool a management system so
even if they start at the same time as a
consumer they're going to be you know
six months a year later just to go
through the process and to get
everything dealt with then we take an
overlay that with the address allocation
pressures in various parts of the world
and you get this thing scaring all over
the place right so you know they're
you're on the moving part of this curve
and applications are coming out now
service providers are coming out now
consumers probably this holiday season
will get a lot of food capable things
enterprises sometime next year it's
really matters you know your way out
here right because you've got money for
address space why are you were pressured
to meet you know VP Nick has been
telling people to two-and-a-half merged
are they what's been telling them for
two years go away and it's just now
starting to tell people to go away right
so you know the pressure has been
definitely in other parts of the world
to get moved over at the same time
remember back to that graph I put it
before somewhere along the right-hand in
with this there's a feedback loop this
thing turns out because it takes a long
time you know people that people buy
today it's going to be four or five
years before they get rid of it and buy
something new and they're not going to
upgrade it all right so v4 only things
that sell right now are going to stay
there for any of their for five years
but towards the end of this you know
before it's sectionally over you can't
get any v4 address space therefore it's
useless so you've got to be moving into
v6
so you know there's a lot of school and
you know if your illusion you're moving
quicker if you're in the Americans
you're going to get there someday
but you can't wait forever because
you're going to run out of v4 address
space somewhere along the way here and
then they have a better rejection to
that later in week yes okay the question
cuz the addresses are 128 notes instead
of 32 bits
so after well make me okay the question
just to repeat since you didn't have the
mic it was you know the router
manufacturers seem to be driving a lot
to support v6 and therefore what is it
realistically required to make v6 work
in a router as opposed to before and
there are several parts for that
question right the simple straight
solenoids ask look up answer is I got
four more four times as many bits to
look at in the fast path so yeah that's
going to be more expensive okay
another part of your question was how
many Meg's in the router well that gets
back to the routing table size right and
do I really hundred twenty thousand
entry table for the prefixes in v6 and
my guess is no right it really depends
on how people end up announcing and how
much quotes traffic engineering they're
doing by putting holes but you know if
we ruined up with more than fifteen
thousand entries in this table in the
next three years I'll be really amazed
right so how many Meg's does that take
yeah
you know I don't get close enough to the
hardware to be able to figure that out
but ask the router manufacturer what
that would look like in terms of if they
get used a realistic number instead of a
hundred and fifty thousand entries you
know so there's there's multiple parts
to that question and you know clearly
handling four times as many goods in a
hurry is more expensive yes inside Cisco
our hardware guys come to me and
complain about that I said you know
that's like get over it right yeah you
know the way we're moving on so your
choice is to handle that many bits or
not it's not a matter of well it's more
expensive than meets or so we should
stay home v4 engines no you can't stay
on v4 that's not a choice right now does
that translate back into more expense to
you unfortunately yes but no it
shouldn't be an outrageous expense I
think you know that's me with none my
ATF had on to be very clear okay look at
the transition techniques we'll talk
more about these next time the primary
technique is do a stack so special I
usually get some people when they
started thinking about v6 as well
whether I need to put the translators
right because I got to speak between
these four and v6 and my answer is you
don't do that unless you really really
really really really really have to
write the only time you need to have a
translator is if you've got a v6 earlier
device that needs to talk to Abby for
only device right and there aren't any
v6 only devices yet in fact there aren't
any on the bottom boards there were a
few the 3G community was going to build
v6 only handsets they realized what a
big mess this was and they backed off
right so address translators shouldn't
be required so we bet them to find we
have pretty much everybody hasn't built
but you shouldn't be deploying them as
sustaining mechanism dual stack is the
basic mechanism you should be looking at
and titling in the places where you
it's the boy b6 in a hurry yes yes
looking at some work on me together and
never try to network the users
application level experience effectively
a translation testing team but so that
the changes that might be on board or
well it's like you can take it a step
further because you only have to change
that application gateway and the EndNote
because you can tunnel across the v4
private network to that application
gateway and then it can do whatever it's
going to do and come out on the other
side as either before or v6 whatever
happens so yeah there are multiple sides
to this and depending on where you are
you know we we got complaints I was the
chair of the v6 on transition tools ng
trans in the IETF
and we got a lot of complaints we had
too many tools well it's because there
are scenarios like this so there's a
tool to solve that scenario but you know
there's 42 tools which one applies to
you I'm trying to bucket them and say
there's really three classes of tools
and if you stay within the first two
classes you're much better off if you
end up in the third class where you've
got these application gateways or at you
know Hitler translators we've got bumps
on the API we've got all kinds of
choices for translation if you end up in
that space it's because you have a
unique need and you need to do that and
it's ok we've got the tool but you
shouldn't go there unless you have to
and we should have made the rest of this
simple enough magic picture basically
just says you know these six is going to
be everywhere you know in particular in
Asia real soon now it's already being
deployed over cable into the homes over
you know Giggy into homes so I mean it's
it's there it's coming to a neighborhood
near you one of the things I was trying
to do with ng trans was to decide the
space yeah so we get service provider
class networks which have a particular
characteristic enterprises and unmanaged
networks and they share some depending
on which way you draw this you know
unmanaged networks had some
characteristics of service provider or
of enterprise and enterprise also has
some characteristics of service provider
so I couldn't draw it very easily
we're spend a lot more time on this next
time but again your stack is a primary
tool yes a node can't be reached over v6
they can continue to use before I
feeling caveat is it it's just like
before today so that the application
doesn't work for that it's not going to
work any better right
tunneling can be between the in systems
it can be between the routers in between
the instance them in a router there's
all kinds of choices there and there's
also different mechanisms based on
whether you're doing this between sites
or within a sight translation exists we
can do an application gateways and good
and routers you NAT PT is very similar
to what you're used to in v4 nap but
instead of just changing addresses or
also change the protocol types so you
know you're taking a key header on the
fly and just rewrapping it and going has
it all the same scaling properties isn't
that right so you definitely don't want
to go here unless you really need to one
of the things if we've got all of this
wonderful wonderful stuff going and the
service provider wants to provide a site
with v6 service but doesn't
mess with the core of the network how
you can actually route that stuff right
so we've got a bgp tunneling mechanism
so you can move the BGP information for
z6 between the edges that need to know
it without having to corrupt the core
infrastructure right so there's lots and
lots of pieces and you can do them all
together in various ways to come up with
a network that that does what you want
to do just in case that's not
complicated enough if you've got an MPLS
Network you can use the v4 MPLS
infrastructure to move the labels around
and do v6 over MPLS directly right so
you know this specs will look more like
an a native v6 service but you're not
using v6 I'm not touching your MPLS core
you're just adding v6 around the edges
as you need it so in that I probably
killed over time and then some any
questions yes
dynamic just the current status of
dynamic DNS where that's at dynamic
updating Thomas because that's I
understand it's going to be a pretty big
yeah publicly was just outside the door
right before we started and I wish he'd
stepped in here there are people here
that can answer that question but I
can't fall down yeah you know there two
or three other people here that would
probably be able to answer the question
as well but you know I'm sorry I'd like
to know you know in the abstract sense I
don't know in case of you know the
Microsoft's things if I happen to have
come from there at one point in my life
that is definitely on the drawing boards
and in fact the Microsoft IT guys are a
little annoyed because when I was a
program manager for v6 and Windows I
didn't give them a knob so since they're
a homogeneous shop all nodes come up and
register in DNS because that's part of
what they do right and it's a nice
ubiquitous
Active Directory thing you just register
yourself well with sending rules as soon
as I see that the other end does v6 I'm
going v6 right so their traffic goes
from v4 to b6 right what do they move
the routers or not it'll tunnel so
they're a homogeneous shop they're you
know they've got this problem the rest
of the world has a little bit more
graceful you know migration you know as
you manage DNS you manage that rollout
but yes we have the other mic cut off
from you I was trying to think of how
many times during the day I actually
type in I was going to say an IP address
but an ipv4 address do you just do a lot
more cutting and pasting in your world
or what's it what's the reality of
working with this no I mean you're
trying to debug sex is your friend
actually until DNS gets up to date most
of what I do with v6 is in post text
files right because that's the only
reasonable way yeah I would be doing
cutting and pasting but that's the
argument that I use for Y PlayStation is
going to be fine right because the guys
who do peer-to-peer games on
Playstations they've already got Instant
Messenger windows open to each other cut
and paste they're done they don't need
DNS
see mine come no mine's not back yet oh
yes it did come back it's it's not no I
mean it's a the education is the hurdle
right and so once you've gotten used to
it then it's not as big a deal
I knew I'd wake up sooner or later
so I can't make that any bigger but
that's just showing you some of the you
know the Windows version those if config
here so that's what v6 address on this
node right now on the wireless network
right that happens to be the privacy
based one so let's go random number that
it generated to the Lord or 64 bits the
one book right below that is based on
the MAC address of the NIC like so the
top one that I highlighted is the one
that we use for any outbound connections
and the bottom one is the one it would
register with DNS if there happen to be
a Active Directory server here too
didn't register with yes percent
notation is the scope in particular if
you've got a node with multiple links on
it and you've got a link scope addresses
you have to know which link it goes out
so you know this is telling you that
that happens to be interface 14 so you
know you can keep track of which
interface it actually is supposed to go
out on the ones down here further with
the percent two's on them those are the
tunnel interfaces since there are
configured those they come up first and
that's like I've got low numbers on the
vs
balance is healthy ipv4 is similar if
you introduce the right local for y'all
anyhow does define localhost respect is
a incident current around nothing is the
easy part
so actually I'm glad you asked it that
way I was afraid you're getting
somewhere else I'll go there anyway site
local in routing is just another prefix
right as far as all of the routers
within the site it's just another prefix
like okay
what is a site and the question is where
do you administrative when we want to
draw the boundary if you're running 1918
it addresses today where do you stop
using those and start using global
publicly public addresses you've done
that it is administrative boundaries for
some reason it's a same decision that
goes into this I can't tell you it's the
same place but it's the same decision
process you know I may now choose to
have all of a campus be one site as
opposed to a building or I may choose to
have my entire company be a site it
really depends on how big it is you know
for Cisco a single site for the entire
company doesn't make any sense but say
San Jose and everything on the west
coast probably does and then you know
everything on the East Coast as another
site everything in Europe is another
site this is first order cut right and
then we can senesce it from there but
it's really site boundary is the
administrative decision of where you're
going to propagate that route the
distinction is your neighbors are not
going to listen
today to do what you cannot officially
private means to address whatever the
policy defines the Honda DDP doesn't
appreciate those as a hospice the global
internet you can do the same thing
eyesight so there's something special
about the whole the thing that's special
about it is we've architectural a
defined it so everybody knows there is a
space they can use for this and they
don't have to go carving up and have you
know if you used your existing public
space but you only advertise part of it
somebody might miss consider an ounce
out things you didn't want ounce
announced out right and your neighbor
might listen because they don't know not
to with the site local prefix we're
saying you know your neighbor shouldn't
be thinking sending you these usually
just heard filter them at the border now
whether you choose to subdivide that or
not that's administrative function
locally so the finding the edge of a
site is really a local decision but what
we're saying is you know it's not yours
you shouldn't hear it you should have a
hard filter on any inbound announcement
of the site local prefix yes right when
you start getting back into the
interface that I came in on and which
interface because as in Venice ice can
only be in one site a router may be in
multiple sites but an interface can only
be in one so then you have to be much
more granular about keeping track of
which interface things came in on and
not just the fact you've got it in a
table somewhere so um well I thought you
were going to go was how does this play
with DNS in fact multi-faced DNS is
going to have to become the norm
if slight local is used right you know
you got to face at least four site local
and global what you may want to even
consider adding links scope addresses in
there that's why I say multi-site
straight you may have or multiple sites
or
so there's a variety of things so VMs
may have some evolution to go through in
the current implementations you're going
to be somewhat restricted into what you
can do with your site local addresses
just because DNS is going to restrict
you one of the things that I found is
that people think that names refer to
boxes indeed no and after day and that's
a fundamental problem if you think that
a name refers to a box then you've got a
real problem in this situation if you
understand that the name refers to a
network service access point then it's
much simpler to handle and you just give
a different access point a different
name you may have to cheat by using the
box and the suffix or something to sort
of work to transition you can manage it
through names you can also manage it
through clever address selection rules
right but there's definitely some work
there you would ask about routing before
and all I showed you was the interface
configuration it occurred to me that was
all I did so this is you know netstat
and things that are actually bound right
so there's some v4 stuff bound and then
we get down here ways and then there's a
little bit of v6 bound because I don't
have too many of these six applications
enabled right now right so you get this
colon colon designation for the what
would have been zero zero before
ditching Aaron quickly put in your
vanity request now not only do I want an
allocation I want an allocation with a
lot of zeros so any other