morning
the stock's going to be on visiting
basics or how brake software little bit
about me I'm Scott or created as the
case may be
whichever allen's almost anything really
first and foremost our future husband my
fiance's here thanks for putting up with
me by the way I'm an avid scuba diver so
if you know any good dive spots around
hit me up
sim e mail sorter professional hacker I
guess but my main I guess work is I'm
lead software developer and do some
security on the side and company X my
employer asked me not to divulge her I
work so I guess for two reasons one kind
of a disclaimer for them and to I can
speak more freely because I work
hopefully so engender why first facing
methods are going through some of those
types of causing some flooding software
that I use and have had some success we
have several examples and samples and
they're posted on get her but the link
there I'll have that link in the
questions and comments slide at the very
end so you can I get that some tips and
tricks that I've learned and were
helpful for me and get some time for
questions and comments if you have any
so first of all I guess wife as well you
don't want to be this guy where you test
your code in production but it's
personally I think it's kind of fun to
break software but one of the main
reasons why I guess we folks who are
attending this conference is as hackers
is to find exploitable plugs which now
really are really fun I personally only
written a couple of simple exploits so
far but definitely want to do more
in terms of raising it really provides
you I feel with more thorough testing
with input their users and often
programmers really don't consider a lot
of times you know you may have asked you
a person that goes through a series of
test cases but they may not consider
stuff like okay well what happens if we
put in a bunch of spaces are a bunch of
special characters or even throw nose
into a field so like I said it provides
more thorough testing which helps
increase your quality of your software
if you're a software vendor if you work
for a place that sells software I think
fuzzy personally is of crucial
importance but for those of us who use
software working I T departments it
really helps hold your vendors
accountable for poorly written and
poorly tested code I've embarrassed a
couple of vendors pretty badly which
honestly was kind of fun but that did
help bring equality their software out
so it can handle cases a little better
sizing methods really I think there's
you could argue that there's more but I
basically kind of broken down into three
categories manual fuzzing where you just
put stuff in yourself whether it's a
Windows Forms program web application I
work mostly in the.net realm so that's
where most of my fucking experiences
from but basically these three methods I
think are the ones that I see that are
more general sense manually inputting
stuff yourself as I said automated using
some posing software writing your own
father and I'll be going through some of
the funding software that I've used here
in a bit and wireless fussing MDK three
in Cali Linux can be kind of fun
if anybody's ever messed with it it will
do all sorts of things in terms of
broadcasting packets so you can really
throw your access points into a tizzy
with it but I have found it useful in
some occasions although I haven't done a
whole lot of wireless forcing types of
furthering local and remote really are
the ones that I deal with local being
where you got the first thing software
and your target installed on the same
machine which as far as I can tell and
in my experience you have to do this
pretty much for exploit development
because you've got to be able to debug
and stuff to see what's going on behind
the scenes when you do get a crash and
it gives you full control over your
environment you can reboot when you want
to you can restart whatever remote being
fighting something that's installed
elsewhere like a web application MPP
piece of software or something that is
going to give and receive packets it's a
bit more restricted in terms of control
but that's kinda mood if you can get to
the server because you can restart stuff
if you need to restart crash services or
whatever the one caveat that I've found
in doing remote fussing specifically
with web applications and hopefully I
won't drop too hard over a top that's
going to be going on later today with
hacking web applications is that network
hardware and software routers switches
firewalls and such
sitting between you and the target can
be problematic I run into a couple of
instances where somebody has a web
application firewall or whatever and you
might start out sending TCP traffic
that's got your first drink it by the
time it gets to the target it's either
garbled or dropped altogether and that's
because there was some
system sitting in between that monkey
with your traffic so that's something
that you gotta kinda keep in mind when
doing closing of remote applications in
terms of buzzing software really
anything that allows interaction with a
target could be considered a Pfizer I
primarily work on the Windows platform
in terms of development and security
related stuff of a non-windows I've used
only birds sweet a little bit I usually
use it through Cali Linux but peach
pfizer anybody use peach Bowser joanne's
peach pfizer is a cross-platform
application I'll be gone into a little
bit more of it in a bit but it's it runs
on both Windows Linux and I think it
runs on Mac OS two have never tried to
run on Mac myself but it's a pretty good
little too in terms of Cali Linux that's
what I used primarily for sizing and the
tools here burp suite all of that all of
those with the exception of peach Pfizer
they're all bundled into Cali Linux oh
that's nice because you don't have to do
a whole lot of extra extra work to get
the tools they're already there
the peach fuzz Iran windows like I said
I've done most of most of my work with
peach Pfizer on the Windows platform the
top link that you see there is the main
site where you can grab it and started
it got really good directions on
installing it the peach pit which is
what the peach faster refers to as the
first definitions are done in XML so
having a good XML editor is helpful
you can do it in notepad and I
have for simpler peach pits but for more
complex stuff like if you were writing a
peach pit to fly as a web application
for instance in Europe defining the HTTP
GET or the HTTP POST having a good XML
editor will save you some time and
headaches
there are some free peach pits available
on the internet and at the peach fuzz ur
site I think it's forums . peach fuzz I
dot com there's a specific area of the
forums that folks will contribute peach
pits to have dropped a few out there so
you can check those out if you like I'm
also that the samples here and on I get
her but the one good thing about peach
Bowser it gives you a really good
feedback for reproducing crashes and
login info useful for exploit
development and like something Kelly
Lenox tools where it's more helpful
around a packet capture on when you're
doing focusing on peach fuzz are you
really don't have to do that it will log
all the stuff for you whenever a crash
occurs and I've got some examples of
that sort of thing coming up but it's
really good for that I definitely
recommend that you go through the
tutorials at the link that you see there
on the screen
those will really help you understand
the ins and outs of peach Pfizer and
that Bottomley a very generous soul
posted some posing for newbies which I
found extremely helpful just to kind of
get my brain juices flowing on ok this I
didn't think about using this sort of
thing it's as this post specifically as
a series of links both off site
and on the peach father site on China
getting your arms raun buzzing in
general there's some off-site links to
tutorials so it's it's really good link
I definitely recommend you check it out
there are some gotchas with peach
further I found a couple of small bugs
near the end of August and about a month
later the peach buzzer developer Mike
Arrington that's his name said ok well
these are no big deal we're working on a
commercial product pitch pfizer has kind
of two flavors there's a Community
Edition which is the free one the one I
use and then there's the think they call
it
peach professional that they're working
on trying to keep it maintained and
up-to-date so the response that I got
from him said well okay we'll get to it
but it's not really that big a deal they
didn't feel so and it's honestly just
two misspelling some one of the
programmers I'm sure just left out and I
in to the commuters the size they have
various mutator in the size of variance
mutator he just left an eye out so if
you want to exclude those then you'll
have to misspell them as I've listed
there on the screen so they will exclude
properly and I'll have some peach
example definitions here and like I said
there on my github area to show you that
not all the samples in the peach fuzz ur
samples directory when you install it
work out of the box you've got the tweak
it a little bit and
that's we're going through the tutorials
on the peach Bowser website can help
because they're XML and I'll be honest
I'm not an XML guru
peach pits can be difficult to write and
debug but there are some ways that you
can tricks with the peach Pfizer that
you can use to help kind of ease that
burden there some validation and stuff
that it will do that will ease your pain
a bit
the one thing and you'll see this if you
go through any funding of WAV files this
specific mutator array numerical edge
cases every time I've tried to run it on
Windows when I've tried to buzz WAV
files it just causes windows to just
crapped out and go crazy the hard drive
light will just stick on and whenever I
can get task manager up its just paying
100% so it just really craps windows out
despite the fact that it really doesn't
crash the wav file player that I was
testing it just totally wax windows so
that when you might want to exclude in
some instances but some tips for running
peach fuzz or that I have found when you
just run peach at the command line of
the song windows with no parameters
it'll give you a list of options that it
supports peach my honesty will validate
your Peachpit not only for well-formed
XML but also if you are missing
something that Pete requires like part
of a data model or state model which
also you in a minute
peach minus one will sample run your
Peachpit it won't apply any of what Pete
refers to as mutator
different ways of twisting your input
data to cause crashes but it'll just run
your target funds program as normal so
if you've got something that develops a
outputs a text file for instance if you
run peach minus one can you repeat with
Paula by your peach pit against it then
it will just run to target program is
normal so you can validate that you hate
speech ran my program I got the output
that I would expect if I were running my
program is normal
a peach minus see with your XML file
will give you a count of the test
iterations before starting and if you
especially if you don't do any mutator
exclusions this can produce a whole
bunch of tests iterations which is what
you want but you may want to be prepared
like to kick it off and just go get a
coffee or 10 or what have you
generally when you run peach fuzz er it
will generate with no exclusions it will
generate several thousand sometimes tens
of thousands or even a couple hundred
thousand test cases so it's gonna run
for a while now that kind of brings me
to an interesting thing that peach fuzz
will do the peach minus P command with
you can split the funding run-up if you
have multiple machines with the peach
browser software installed it's not
particularly fancy but it will do the
job that doesn't only networking as I
said there but it just simply divide the
number of tests iterations by the number
of machines so if you've got thirty
thousand test iterations running on
three machines then it will break down
the iterations as you see there with the
first machine running the first 10,000
the second machine running the middle
chunk and then the last machine running
the final chance so it will it will
definitely let you complete your fucking
run faster
and it went missing test cases but there
may be instances where running in
parallel won't give you full coverage
I'm kind of getting it that I haven't
done a whole lot of parallel fuzzing
running with peach but I have seen some
crashes that were not reproducible on a
parallel fussing run that were if I ran
all of the tests iterations on the same
machine so you can kind of play around
with that here's a peach pit from the
online tutorial at the peach fuzz our
website and basically what it's broken
into chunks the data models chance
they're basically describes the data
that you're going to funds in this
instance this was buzzing a what was it
a picture file so I defined the data
model is defined as a blob the state
model re-creates the logic that peach
needs to know in order to funds properly
so the state name just initial hey this
is our only state this is the only one
we're gonna ride we're going to ride out
the third PNG file and the folder we're
gonna read our sample files from this
area so they'll be ready in from P&G
test files everything in there with a
PNG extension they'll be twisted and
turned by the father and then output as
a I think I call will you see it in a
minute I was dotted PNG the phone that
that is what will be stayed in too
in this case the MS Paint program so
this is what the process of doing that
is controlled here in the state model
agent basically as a process that tells
peach the platform that is running on as
well as platform-specific monitors which
a monitor is some action that peach
takes an agent wraps up monitors so this
guy named as monitor glass windows
debugger and these parameters here are
specific speech commands that can be run
for instance there's the command line
that I'm calling in order to do the
following the path for the windows
debugger peach does not come with the
windows debugging tools you have to get
those but there is a link on the beach
father dot com website that has links to
Microsoft's website in order to download
the debugging tools start on call and
CPU kill those are optional parameters
but the way in going through the
tutorial they used the start on call and
CPU kill command switch start on call
basically says okay don't start a
debugging session until I actually call
in this case the MS Paint program and
CPU kill I believe that stops the
phasing run if the CPU hits 100 percent
for a certain amount of time and not
only am i why I'm also watching the heat
here watching the heap specifically for
this executable and I've got my win
debug path here I don't know if it's a
bug and peach father but you're not
supposed to need to specify the path to
the windows debugger but unless I put it
in there I've never had it work when I
try to validate the Peach Pit it says
peach comes back when they're saying hey
we can't find the windows debugging tool
so I have at least on Windows I've
always specify the debug path and then
the last part of this peach pit is the
test which basically the test node wraps
everything up until speech what to do
based on the info that you provided in
the earlier sections the publisher here
in this case is saying okay I want to
I'm out I'm working with a file so I
have to specify the specific file that
in this case that I'm using the funds so
called funds . PNG that's generated as I
said earlier when the peach takes the
raw file from the directory that I told
to look at it with its mutator and then
it writes it to the buzz . PNG file and
then opens it up in MS Paint and that's
how an iteration of buzzing this works
the strategy class you don't have to
specify there
I was playing around with it decided to
just tell it random random meaning it's
gonna jump around in the various mutate
errs that peaches going to try that may
give you more crashes or better crashes
and just running sequentially from top
to bottom and the larger class there at
the bottom tells peach ok when I get
crash or I'm updating the status to let
the user know in this case what
iteration mi on its writing that to the
logs directory which a log if it doesn't
exist the logs directory will be created
as a subdirectory from wherever you're
running P so if you've installed peach
in the peach fuzz ur directory then
there'll be a logs created under that
with all of the information in there
about the fucking run have a peach pit
here to further command line program
which takes one argument and this one I
created based on my need for there was a
US space program that ran as an
automated job at my work and I decided
well let me see how this thing holds up
under peach Bowser so with some help
from
some of the folks on the pitch visor
forums I created this and I go through
this a little more quickly but basically
the data model in this case has two
parts to it the program the name of the
program
extract that exceed imposing and the
parameter which in this case the sex
tractor pulls some stuff out of a
database and then write it to a
directory
no i didnt want two funds the extract
program itself I just wanted to give it
a malformed directory parameter so
that's the reason the program itself
this extract daddy XE has a once you
specify the program in need the space
for the women are in the parameters so
it may be a little hard to see but there
is a space right after the doc exe year
so like I said I'm trying to follow as
the parameter itself not the extract
program directly so if you wanted to put
these block of comments in here if you
wanted to find a command-line program
which has more than one parameter you
just need to specify additional data
model nodes with the parameters that you
need there
in this case and I commented this
honestly as much for my benefit as
anyone who might want this speech bit so
I can keep in mind I remember it
the state model model writes a batch
file which peach then calls and you'll
see it in the next screen but the first
run whether you're running a test a test
with a 2-1 or not will always be the
program space and then the parameter so
it will run as normal
the subsequent Ryans will have the
program and then whatever the size of
data is so and just like with the data
model the state model will have if you
wanted to add additional parameters if
you had a command-line program that took
two three four parameters you would just
add them as different nodes action nodes
under the under the state no second
parameter third parameter and so on
disclosed here specifically says OK
after you've written a batch file stop
make the fussing run before you blow the
batch file away and recreated with your
next extract that exe buzzed ring so
that in this case that gives me a clean
run only got 15 string at a time when
the batch file
agent is fairly similar to the previous
1 I'm running this on Windows so I
called it the windows debugger I'm
specifying the command line to the batch
file that peaches creating which I refer
which I called it just call program done
that you keep doing that the there's the
windy bike paths and passed to the
windows debugger the start on call in
this case as saying hey I wanna do the
run I want to run the program which is
specified in the state model earlier the
these two parameters I kind of played
around with because the extract exe
program can be long running so you may
need the wait for eggs and on call and
wait for eggs a timeout parameters
basically the first one says hey don't
stop until the program's finished excuse
me I got that backwards the way for
exile call says okay I wanna hold on
before I close and stop the creation of
the call
program dot bad which holds by call and
the way for exit on timeouts is ok peach
don't cut this program off let it run to
completion and see if it crashes said
you might need those for a long running
programs I've not done enough with peach
father yet to know if that's necessary
in all cases but I left him in their
town of his memory job for myself as
before I'm watching the heat to see if
there are any crashes there pete has
this interesting little feature called a
pop-up watcher so in this case when the
extract program if it crashes and it's
not a fatal crash rather than sit there
and having to click the close on those
windows has encountered an error and the
program's closing speech will close
those automatically if you can get the
name of what's in the title bar on the
window so when I ran this and it's going
along is turning and then it crashes but
it's not a fatal crash or it's not an
exploitable crash or for the crash that
peach can't reproduce rather than just
having like 50 60 or more of those
windows there the pop up watching will
close them as they come up so you don't
have a whole lot of clutter on your
screen and the test just like before it
wraps up all of the other notes that you
have created the extract
excuse me exclude expert here
specifically says hey I don't want to
mess with the extract that exe name lead
out alone so that's the reason for this
note here the in this case I was doing a
strategy of sequential I wanted to run
through all the test cases from top to
bottom
my publisher in this case calls the car
program dot map that created one batch
program that peace will create I decided
to be a little different
and lock it specifically to a different
directory I was running the peach
command out of a different install
location in this case and here's the
exclude note for the mutator these are
the mutator that I specifically didn't
want to ride this makes for a shorter
fuzzing run but maybe not as complete a
fussing around so you can if you don't
use this exclude this mutator is mowed
exclude by default peach will run every
one of them you taters so you may want
to you may want to exclude certain
mediators in some circumstances and here
at the bottom note the misspellings here
size data violence mutator and size of
Arts mutator if I'd say that's the bugs
that I mentioned earlier if I had left
those spelled correctly then Pete would
have excluded them in terms of logging
and jump out to
when peach logs items it creates a
creative director under the logs
directory with the pit named the test if
you have multiple testifying in appear
and then a date timestamp I put the
arrows on here just to have they have an
easier way to find what I was looking
for but if you were to get a
reproducible crash you would say
something like this the status that text
file is always there and it tells you
how far you're into opposing run so in
this case speech found a fall at this
iteration so it tried to rerun it to see
if it was reproducible and it was so
within that directory where there's a
faults and then it says hey it ran it I
did exploitable so it gave me a couple
of memory addresses and this was the
inspiration that the reproducible crash
happened on initial holds the the same
information that you see here but the
first pass of it the first iteration
caused the crash the second and the one
that peach deemed exploitable is here so
I was facing the extract program so
action one output is the non-visible
part of the buzzing run that I wanted to
do which means hey don't mess with the
extract DAC I wanna leave that alone the
action to is more interesting because it
tells you the specific strain that
caused the crash so you can reproduce it
if you want a ride up some Python or
parole what a view to reproduce a crash
and then we've got a stack trace hear
that
windows debugging tools logged I think
it's at the bottom that the info here
the user mode right access violations
that are not mere Maula mere naal are
exploitable I haven't tried to write an
exploit for this particular program
honestly I ran this on a 64 bit machine
so this one may be beyond my current
level of skill but the information here
needed to reproduce the crash as well as
to write up and exploit should be all
that you need in order to get started
this is the excuse me the star floor by
the windows debugger and you can see
here at the bottom it says the same
thing in a stack trace that user mode
right access violations that are not
there no llore exploitable so that's
what a peach consider this what you'll
see when you see a reproducible crash
that peach teams exploitable if it's a
false positive or something that peach
could not run through twice it will say
hey I couldn't reproduce it and you'll
see something like a status which has
only one crash in it and within the nine
reproducible it may say unknown it may
say something else but within that
directory
you'll see the iteration where the crash
happened the action one in this case the
extract program that was facing action
to the specific parameter that caused
the crash and then
just a debugger description that said
hey this was the first time I had this
happen but I couldn't get it to happen
again so I'm gonna assume it's not
reproducible it's not exploitable and
I'm just going to go to the next
iteration so it's kind of a run-through
of what you could see in terms of
logging by peach fuzz or is it pretty
decent as far as as far as i'm concern
birth sweet it's not really a father per
se is sweet but I like the repeater for
manual fuzzing I do a lot of work with
web application testing so sweet for
manual testing of web applications but
the decoder and compare seeing windows
in perhaps we are pretty handy as well
and this is a goal that came out
terrible a screenshot of the sweet
repeater function I've got the areas and
red rectangle which specify where
specifically I was wanting to funds in
this case in this case I was wanting to
fuzz the parameter passes that image
handler died I S H X
and the I was wanting to further cookie
value instead rescues me the cookie
value also I just put five day in there
to kind of give myself a little reminder
hey this is where I wanna change
something so Kelly Lenox gone to the
dark side a little bit there's a number
of tools they're bad I think it stands
for brute force exploit detector but I'm
honestly not sure it's a network
protocol father handles those you see it
on the screen as well as a few others I
use it mostly for HTTP but I've used it
for FTP as well use a set list of
strange proposing so it doesn't do
mutation but it's written in Perl so you
can add your own strings by just
changing the code is not that big a deal
it's a good general use funds are you
kind of fired forget it but as with a
lot of tools in Cali Linux I'll start a
packet capture before running it so I
can see the specific value that caused
the crash if one occurs this is a copy
and paste from the bad code with the
specific strains in it you can see they
have their authors broken down into
overflow strings format strings and so
forth so bad water cycle through all of
these test cases when you kick it off
dunno it's basically version too bad
uses a little better list of preset
strings it's also written in Perl so you
can hack it up pretty easy another fire
and forget buzzer and these are the
strings that it uses you can see there
are a few more in there like I said you
know you can
it's perot code so you can add your own
with no big deal that pawn it's good for
finance directory traversal stuff but
when I've used it I had to hand it to
the traversal engine to look for
specific target files that I was seeking
also parole so it's pretty
understandable and easy to modify I
found out that poem most useful after
I've done a decent amount of
reconnaissance to learn the machine well
because the more specific you can tell
dot dot pollen hey this is a Windows
boxes UNIX box it will do a better job
and then run a little quicker because it
won't have to make assumptions on the
target that it's running on and that's
why I mentioned there if you're running
it used the minus even minus X
parameters to really get you get you a
good run through to see if there is a
directory traversal problem on the boxer
testing don't forget the minus in a
switch HTTP methods between get posed if
you're doing it on a web server because
sometimes the get parameters or the post
parameters may not be sanitized as early
as they should be
this is a screenshot of the dot dot
poland colored with D specific files
that it looks for by default in Windows
and Unix and then it was the extra files
section that I edited giving the
specific path where I thought the file
was located the target file is located
in there and then I use them I C
parameter so it would look for that
specifically some other modules
with anybody used any of the other
modules and Metasploit ok there there's
several of them there you can see there
I've got the path to the specific folder
if you're not sure of it or you can just
do a search further within myself
console
SMB and HTTP fathers I found to be
pretty good at crashing things not all
the modules support the threats
parameter but if it does bump it up
it'll help your fucking run finish a
little faster the Metasploit modules
give you pretty good feedback on what
caused the crash it'll give you the
strain that caused the crash
specifically but just to be safe I still
run a packet capture 1 I'm using those
the buzzer . barbie is full give you the
details on how the fuzz strings are
created and I'm no Ruby expert by any
means I've only seen a few lines of ruby
colored but it was good for me in how to
learn how to customize my own father's
because there were some not only some
good five strings in there but also some
good ideas on working strings that would
cause interesting behavior of crashes
definitely check out that father Darby
rebbie code if you find yourself kind of
stuck and i cant get a crash but I just
feel like this thing will crash the
there's some good stuff there that may
be kind of get your brain juices flowing
tears login corrupt and tedious login
username are good for opposing sequel
sorry I haven't done a whole lot of
fussing sequel server but when I was
looking at the ruby colored
it's a smidge another day I think it the
packets that these two fathers create
are well a lot of it it specifically
written for single server 2000 so after
a bit of thumbing through the internet I
found a couple links on Microsoft's
website that defined the TES protocol
and that second link has the TDS
versions used in single server so you
can tweak the ruby color bid to target
more specifically more modern versions
of sequel Sarwar the those HTTP fathers
that I have mentioned they're they're
good I've had gotten some crashes with
those along with the assembly to
negotiate corrupt Pfizer so
Metasploit has some good pricing models
in it
their fathers in in map and i actually
didn't find out until I was just knows
in through the Internet scripts
directions like crap there's followers
there so maybe are attacking the DNA as
far as I haven't used that one year the
pH HTTP PHP self-doubt excess
I think that's fairly new I don't
remember that shown up before the last
maybe next to last update the calendar
skies did a TV for my father has been
there for a while and I found it helpful
it's not quite as good as producing
crashes as the Metasploit modules but
it's pretty decent spike is another
father I found it kind of tough to use
because I'm not a big guy even though
I've written C sharp for a while
SIA still arcane to me but there's a
really good and I mean really good
tutorial on Spike at that link Stephen
Bradshaw think I think is the guys name
and he really breaks down these
difficult to you are difficult for me to
get spy concepts into understandable
language so if you're interested in
learning spike definitely check that
tutorial our ically comes with a number
of pre-built spikes but I've always had
a crown on a little bit there spike
basically as two commands a generics and
TCP and generic UDP which sends packets
respectively
the documentation on Spike well I mean
let's just be honest it stinks but the
tutorial really helped me more than
anything else the tutorial at in four
seconds to resource really helped me
more than anything else to get a handle
on Spike to find the five strings it's
not necessarily easily I did do a fair
amount of grabbing to get it but the
spike dot C code in the area then you
look for fun strange you'll see the
first rings that spike uses but and
somebody correct me if I'm wrong but as
far as I've been able to find the
default Cali Linux installed doesn't
come with the spike source you have to
find it and after a lot of hunting I
found this causing dot org website with
a link that had spiked file it at the
spikes or Senate so I grabbed it and
stuck it on my calendar Linux box so I
can referred to it like i said im no
expert but having the sources been
helpful to see what does drink spiked
uses so I've got some sample spikes here
proposing an HTTP GET basically and I've
got it well commented here they are used
sweet intercept the HTTP GET and
got a spike built from it
a string basically is a constant string
variable is the specific thing that you
want to buzz so for the first past the
HTTP GET will have the variable variable
that you see here which is just a
regular user agent string the subsequent
passes will have the funds strings and
started by Spike so when you kick off a
buzzing around with spike it probably
gonna run for a while so with a lot of
the other Cali links to as you want to
start a packet capture before that so
you can see the specific buzz training
that caused your crash got another spike
here for phasing HTV get and this case I
was causing a variable to the image
handler
ashtec's page so there's my this will be
passed as normal a constant and then the
first time through it'll pass with this
variable and then subsequent times it
will insert the first ring the got a
carriage return line feed here about
four lines down that make sure that the
GET request is properly formed and
another spike for causing an HTTP here
in this case I was browsing the web
resource died accidentally
my guests the best word to describe it
is the it's an internal Microsoft thing
if you're running a web application see
spike revising HTTP posed it's pretty
similar to the gets the difference is
near the bottom and Stephen Bradshaw's
primarily on Spike at the link earlier I
don't think goes into real good detail
on the US so I had to kind of figure
this out these this block size string
block starting block and are there so
that the content links of the post will
be calculated correctly it's not your in
this case I was facing get something
running on IIS is just gonna drop the
POST request so you need to have that
content linked properly calculated and
that's what the block size strength in
the block started blocking and so when
you've got a block started on blocking
and it will calculate everything that's
wrapped within that and then throw it
into the content link so I'm defining in
this case a five digit long content link
there on the block size training and
then the block starting block in like I
said will spike will calculate that
properly and throw it in before it jumps
the HTTP POST request on the wire peach
fuzz Iran Cali Linux I'm only running a
little bit like I said I mostly running
on Windows I don't have as much
familiarity with it but it's basically
the same as on Windows the only
difference is it needs the model
packages the I guess it's open source
version of the.net framework if you're
on a you buy into a Debian distro you
can just do an apt-get install model
complete the directions on the peach
fuzz I dot com website will walk you
through that as well I some general tips
and tricks mess around with your target
program first before doesn't it you
don't have to note inside and out but
the better you understand how it works
properly you can then Taylor you're
going to break it so you can kind of
when you know how it works or get an
understanding of how it works correctly
then you can ask yourself the question
what are the best or worst inputs I can
pass to it that will cause damage a lot
of programmers and I'm including myself
in this category code for certain types
of bad input but it's almost impossible
to catch all instances programmers like
to blacklist stuff rather than white
list but try mixing up special
characters and spaces I carriage returns
online feed stuff I just threw an
example up there they first ring that
have actually gotten some programs to
crash just with that specific text you
see there on the screen like I said
spaces special characters format strings
there some dotnet platform examples
those are specific to see sharp but if
you're using a BB dot net web
application you can do a little looking
on Microsoft's website to see the format
strings that they used opinion seems to
be varied on whether format string
attacks are possible with the.net
platform I
going under the assumption that they are
I just haven't found the right one yet
so I always insert some stuff format
string like when I'm using virtual
machine KVM virtual machine software is
really good at lower your total cost of
doing fighting Oracle VirtualBox VMware
is good whichever you prefer that goes
for spare hardware wireless access
points
dozens disruptive by nature so you got
to be prepared to reboot your target and
if you're doing it live of course make
sure you let folks know about your
network admins programmers and stuff
because especially if you've got some
security people who were on the ball
like they should be watching the logs
then they start seeing a weird traffic
they should get a little nervous the
death of that modern that I have some
free time limited virtual machines that
are good for funding targets
dot com has some challenges via
downloadable virtual machines not
buzzing specific but you can use them to
focus on and exploit gmail.com has some
good writeup on on fighting there i read
through those papers a couple times just
kind of refresh my memory
start with a short fuzzing run at first
to make sure everything's good I guess
it if you're using it on a Windows
platform peach will do just a test run
or just run for a few iterations to make
sure everything is good just checkin on
the uneven with automated posing for
Windows you wanna see me like your
production environment as closely as
possible
antivirus antimalware software
including Microsoft email they may give
you problems depending on how paranoid
they are they may crash or throw up a
message saying it as an attack or
whatever you may want that you may not
depends on you know your specific
circumstances with peach it will run
your target out of memory after a while
the your target will just really start
to bog down and slow down so as to be
prepared for that
Control Alt Delete is your friend the
girl three finger salute on Windows that
we all know and love for Cali Linux I
usually start with more general use
fathers like bad and do not and then go
down the list . up owner whatever but it
really depends on what I'm buzzing but I
guess this really the next one really
applies to both Windows and Cali check
the closing source to make sure that it
sent in the strings that you expect you
might need to customize them based on
what you're saying is you're doing a
white box test for instance where you
know the platform then you can if you
know you're running a PHP application on
UNIX then you can add in specific PHP
format strings for instance if you know
you're running IIS and its csharp web
application you may want to throw in
some csharp specific stuff like reserved
words or nulls or things like that but
definitely on Cali I always start a
packet capture before beginning of
buzzing rod because not all the tools
really give you good feedback with a
packet capture you know you can see
exactly where the exactly what you say
that caused the crash either Wireshark
RTC they don't whichever you prefer
so like I said in the beginning my
samples are on that get home as you see
there grab them fool around with them
but really you want to make buzzing
buzzing excuse me part of your
development of QA process it does help
but like I said there was a smiley face
it might drive your programmers nights
which you know that's good for him it
doesn't hurt him to get a little
stressed every now and then but I'll be
around stop introduce yourself I mean
just walk upto you start talking so be
prepared for that and my email address
is there at the bottom so hit me up if
you have questions any questions
comments
yeah
done it all that much but generally when
peach tells me that something's
exploitable the first thing I'm gonna
try to do is get the stack trace the
original stack trace on one screen and
then I'll code up something in Perl or
Python or something I can just blow out
really quick with that exact posturing
and then I'll see if I get a crash in
exactly that same spot if it does happen
then I'll probably run through I would
suggest running through that same proof
of concept once twice three times even
after rebooting the machine to make sure
that crashed in exactly that same spot
if that happens then you're well on your
way to writing an exploit because at
that point if you can at that point if
you getting a crash at the same spot
with the same string and you see the
same registers being overwritten then
you're about halfway there at that point
is just about you know make in making
some shellcode and finally getting an
obsolete or something so you can see on
Sunday
yes if like i said im no expert exploit
developer only written a couple and none
of them I felt confident enough to try
to send into the exploit these guys but
yeah Depp will give you heartburn if
you're trying to write exploits and I
see somebody out there so I guess you
run into that problem and ASLR address
space layout randomization yeah that'll
that'll give you if it's too but what
you can do is get a you can get one of
the older GM's off the death . modern .
ie they got XP the M's out there where
you can turn off I don't think XP has a
SLR on it but you can turn off down
there and then run yer run your program
so you can have something that will give
you a little cleaner path toward
exploitation I've never tried to bypass
SLR like i said im very much a newbie on
writing exploits but I know it's
possible I just don't have the skills
yet to do it any other questions
comments that's all for me thank you for
listening