was actors
good afternoon when is Paul Burbage
ex-lax on the twitters the Twittersphere
first of which ones as scout.com thanks
for having already becoming one of my
favorite conferences thanks for coming
out even after lunch it was kind of
tired so little bit about myself on our
researcher fish me and one of my
passions dealing with malware is setting
those Mauer families that utilize some
sort of PHP control panel and then you
know researching the vulnerabilities
within those one of my hobbies is
playing the drums and listen to music
course really like truman base trance
gold nineties grounds of course so feel
free to hit me up on this waters are the
email their cover I Jennifer this
presentation about what the frak is an
exploit kit will dive into
under the hood of hundred exploit kit
itself there's a recent campaign that
you may have heard of it was in the news
recently brought to life by proof points
all go over that the drop now we're from
that campaign and then starting to
getting to the vulnerabilities
themselves of the administrative panel
also have some proof of concept code
that I can share with you all really
just wrote it for the demo but I put it
up on again and you'll be able to play
with that as well
and finally as the end user you know
utilizing Windows what they can do to
mitigate some of these issues with
exploit kids are so little disclaimer
though since the proof of concept is
considered 0 day as far as I know has
been passed in awhile so definitely
don't wanna play with that at home
unless you want to be visited by people
with suits so show of hands here who
knows what exploit kit is
a few people ok for those that don't
let's go ahead and ask Eleni and exploit
kit also known as exploit pack is a tool
that automates the exploitation of
client-side vulnerabilities usually
targeting browsers in programs that a
website can invoke through the browser
such as Adobe Flash Adobe Reader or Java
Runtime Environment they can mister
seltzer taking you through the typical
exploitation of victims utilizing a web
browser initially they might receive a
link within a matter of hours man
campaign that redirect them to an
exploit kit but sometimes I might be no
user interaction all just solely through
typical web browsing there might be some
type of mouth advertising on the web
site that they're visiting or
compromised website that then redirect
them silently to that exploit kit and
fix their PC and dropped them out where
the victim's computer so the sole
purpose in life of an excellent kate is
mainly to install malware without any
user intervention so as you can imagine
some of his mouth where actors they're
utilizing you know massive now we're
spam campaigns that requires some sort
of social engineering attacks initially
to get that power installed but with an
exploit kid you know as long as there is
a horrible browser session that's able
to drop that matter where there's not
too many social engineering attacks that
wouldn't you know need to fill that
space in order to get that malware
installed
picture up the left the guys from Friday
pretty scared about drug busts down at
the bottom there there's a screenshot of
the actual generation or where the
administrative user of hundred exploit
kit would upload their malware to the
panel in order to facilitate that
exploitation of a little bit under the
hood of her exploit kit itself so the
panel itself is are there explicate
itself is actually rebranded heroes
exploit kit I'm so not really sure about
the the ties between the author of these
kits it could be that it's the same you
know exploit kit offer that just
rebranded it or it could be that erodes
leaked and then it was just rebranded by
different individual sure so someone has
a copy that our news how to get a copy
I'd really like to see that code myself
hundred explica was actually first thing
in August 2015 and it can be rented $300
a week or $800 a month which is very
inexpensive compared to some of the more
well-known exploit kits that are out
there so she's neutrino or engler those
can go into the tens if not hundreds of
thousands of dollars a month just to
read those
so one thing about this particular
exploit kid there's very light plugin
checks to see if there's a particular
plugin available in the client session
and the way I like to think this is you
know a spray and pray shotgun other
people call it a carpet bomb method for
exploitation where regardless of the
session and pretty much every exploit
known to a browser session that's
available within the kit itself so the
panel claims about 20 exploits but in
reality only about nine or usable mostly
targeting Adobe Flash screenshot here
within the administrative panel itself
of the exploits that it claims to be
capable of targeting the two red stars
over the top and it might be kinda hard
to see the seat numbers there on screen
but these were actually released or
found from within the the hacking team
data dump earlier this year
here's a forum advertisement underground
form of Louisville's exploit diane was
advertising this particular exploit kids
for its use and although the the Twitter
account down there at the bottom has
been suspended by Twitter doing a little
on that particular job XMPP account came
across two other Twitter accounts are
still active and it was in August of
this year the first Twitter account here
as you can see the the dates are so
pretty freshest still active
although the proof point article day
mainly found about this exploit kids
from Assam hours then campaign that all
share with you here in a bit
they sense that campaign is kinda
wrapped up they have not seen any active
threats from Hunter explicate although
it still being advertised so the idea
that this is still being utilized in the
wall is another screenshot here the
second account that I found utilizing
that same XMPP address and very recent
advertisements blowing up that first
advertisement you can see the date
stamped on there at the bottom just a
couple days ago and seems like every
couple days he pushes out this
advertisement for the UK that was pretty
funny included in the hashtag of
cyberwar when I first saw that I imagine
norad utilizing this exploit kit to
launch nukes so I mentioned earlier that
a proof point is pretty much the one
that publicly disclosed this particular
exploit kit and reached out to them
their research teams but also about you
know given me more data than what they
could publicly share and they had a very
large fish campaign for this particular
case back in August it utilized to send
them our or the spam campaign that
contain links to utilize PHP mailers on
compromised host to send those e-mails
these purported to be some type of fake
billing or traffic ticket and also even
coupon games mainly targeting the the
Brazilian ecosystem down there and being
the the language within the amount was
Portuguese and the type of malware that
was dropped called bankers banking
Trojan was solely targeting Brazilian
financial institutions not sure if too
many people are familiar with his family
but essentially it's an auto writes his
scripts that initially drops from
exploitation of the UK itself and then
from there this auto I T script
downloads the main payload of bankers
banking Trojan this particular family of
ours designed to capture user names and
passwords credentials solely for
Brazilian financial institutions so I
mentioned earlier when I recent up to
prove a point when I first started to
put some data together for this
presentation good body mind over there
by the name of Brian burns so some are
redacted headers and one on that initial
spectrum spam campaign what I found
within the headers had a X PHP script
tag with I am both 30 . PHP so luckily
was actually able to find this PHP
source code on pace pin and from there
dropped it onto a lab computer and
render day here in browser in this looks
like a very simple but again that's also
in Portuguese so fairly fairly safe to
say this was contained solely within the
country Brazil targeting Brazilian users
screenshot of one of the initial hours
pam's I'm sorry the redirected actual
exploit kit so the underlined text on
there was the dot zip on the bottom of
the screen there was a link to exploit
itself this one purporting to be some
sort of judicial or court notice to the
individual as a lower second one year
claiming to be some sort of ticket
bolado I believe in Portuguese the down
at the bottom of this little bit cut off
but this was a fake image source tag
that tried to trick the user into
thinking that it was a PDF file that
they need to click on but in reality
again it just redirected to exploit it
finally the third one targeting
Brazilian chocolate lovers I guess this
is a coupon for collectible chocolates
so sorry to dive down into the actual
vulnerabilities of this exploit kit one
of the huge problems with in most
studies P panels from hours the lack of
user input validation so this the kit
source code itself actually leaked
September 2015 from a researcher
compromising the actual exploit kit
itself he made a copy of that leaked it
on or in underground forms so I was able
to grab a copy of that and screwed up to
lab whenever I initially look at PHP
code for vulnerability analysis they
utilize it open source program called
trips down there at the the get help
link and rips comes back and give you a
pretty good idea whether or not you know
there's some vulnerable pass you know
with any type of vulnerability
assessment you have to start weeding out
this false positives
so started to mainly just concentrated
on the the PHP upload formalities for
this presentation but also initial some
of the initial results also included
command execution as well as a sequence
action as well
diving into today I'm just as causing
one of the first PHP upload
vulnerability is for the panel itself
within the file he kid hyphen
dutasteride PHP there's series of checks
that it goes through this
the main purpose of this particular file
within the panel itself so the screen
shot earlier this is where the user of
exploit kid would upload his mouth into
the panel and then thats reference on
this so study in this particular block
of code 1 and figure out if there's a
way for me to upload PHP back door to
kind of masquerade as executable by
uploading my own back door then pretty
much have full access to that panel one
of the first checks that this block of
code performed is it would die if it was
not an ajax request so this being a
client header very easily to forge not
only from the curl command line but also
within lip curled giving any programming
language Perl PHP or Python even second
one being blacklisted extensions and
whenever i'm taking a look at PHP code
for portability is a love scene
blacklist because they're very easily
bypassed
more well-known our families use some of
its earlier panels that were released
into the wild also utilized a blacklist
which if you're able to grab that
cryptic code of the particular malware
sample you can upload PHP back door
because they utilized a blacklist for
extensions
some one of the main issues with doing a
black list is regardless of how you
might be able to think of all the ways
that might have PHP execution with the
particular ones one of the biggest
problems is not taking into account
patchy considers as PHP executed
extensions so so this could block it
didn't take into account that you can
have an uppercase extension for PHP
still get a communication error code
execution rather finally a little bit of
obfuscation that was implemented step 3
it uploads to hardcoded directory which
is that long and a five string which
happens to be there in 25 of uploads so
trying to trying to fool or maybe any
type of like directory fuzzing that a
particular princess you're my performing
in CSE 20 pretty interesting and finally
it remains a file to a bunch of random
digits the extension driving through the
coat pocket self for the Ajax check go
too much into this but again just a
simple girl parameters bypasses check
here's the actual code block for the
black list itself so whenever I
initially you know get that PHP source
code tossing her reps and wallets turn
in burning that you know do a series of
grabs maybe for password or blacklist
definitely being one of them so I love
seeing that pop up and my about but and
as you can see here is very simple
within the program itself although were
uploading shelled out PHP is actually a
file that resides on disk that's my back
door cell there is a filename perimeter
as you can utilize for that extends
finally putting that all together the
fall
girl proof of concept for shell upload
400 explica so take a look to folks in
the back and see that my lab environment
I installed it at the path of Hunter UK
da local / UK and then you can see that
MDN 5 string sorts with 512 of the
directory that it drops in and then the
code block renamed the file to a bunch
of random to just start PHP
and if anyone's interested put together
just a quick PHP code block script for
this only for the demo someone as you
though that I came across is that
whenever it's dropped into that Andy 5
directory there unfortunately is no
directory browsing because they do have
the index file automatically so you not
gonna know the name of the shell that it
renames that rain and didja to see what
you can do within the PHP script itself
to set up a for loop that pretty much
tries the combination decoded this the
randomized function utilizing PHP brand
function and although he he specified
the max integer value as nine trillion
code itself does not support a maximum
of nine trillion so thats machine
dependent so bear that in mind suzhou I
think my coat dole you know try to go
all the way up to nine trillion but it's
definitely not a multithreaded by any
means so if you're not doing this in a
while but if you do better than mine
it's gonna take awhile to find it and
it's any questions so far
yes the question is how did they how did
it go without a training
exploited itself and as far as I
understand it the actual author of this
exploit kid he would give you full
access to the admin interface panel and
then from there you know you could
upload whatever malware that you wanted
to do with an actual leak of the of the
exploit kid there was over twenty
samples of our list of all the drivers
for bankers banking charging within that
uploads directory here
so it just takes two parameters the the
full path of the URL to exploit kit and
then the PHP she'll back door that you
want to upload
this is just a pretty typical WSO
backdoor PHP show that I've loaded your
couple things within the panel itself so
take a look at the code know during my
vulnerability analysis ok so well as the
pen tester you know just broke into this
website by uploading the file how can I
you know fully take over that panel how
do I get access at the panel itself I
could you know about the entire
directory and dump the data base in
locally or a kid you know browser
configuration file see where the sequel
credits are and take a look at the
sequel studies in most of the exploit
kits in PHP panels that I analyze the
admin username passwords are stored
within the data base but with this one
was actually stored in login PHP here
so this one was although he he
MDN 5 he is checking them 25 the
particular values here and i five is
pretty insecure main reason being is
that most of the houses have been
cracked I really liked the website has
killer Dakota UK so awesome D five
houses in there and they came out to be
an admin for the username and Hunter for
the password so pretty simple to to get
into kid backing up here so we did once
you attach to the sequel data base
that's running back in on this panel
the sequel credit themselves or are
there are also in plain text within the
panel was even with you know WordPress
or Joomla
tax credits for the Google database
itself so by exporting you know
utilizing this arbitrary upload exploit
finding out the credentials for the
sequel we pretty much on this entire
panel now even within this shell it has
a sequel client here you can see that I
could attach that a single database even
if it was limiting localhost access to
that data base any questions that I have
a little bit about again and user
Windows users mitigation patch restart
and try to apply when it updates again
or 81 pretty cold so cold that I came
across was secure Nia correctly security
at psi what this application does it
will check all of the apps that you have
on your computer such as Adobe Java make
sure that it's up to date so it's a
pretty new one I think there's probably
a couple more different applications
that a check for this third-party
plug-ins to make sure they're fully
patched
limit the the JavaScript execution
within your your browser to so within
chrome you can install script safe and
also within Firefox there's a plugin
called no script also might want to
consider disabling flash it is not
needed within your environment and other
several you know within your work
environment you might have some
particularly I don't know a jar software
that you might have to run Flash on Jul
had to try to only you as a p.m. for
that type of scenario and you can also
disable finds itself in chrome about
plugins for Firefox Tools out on the
plugins
by the fault now in Firefox thats cool
just wanted to give special thanks to as
well
Brian burns over a proof point again
reached out to him after the published
article is very interested in the book
itself and he's been very helpful in
getting a bunch of data that they
weren't able to share publicly although
redacted to say but sharing unless and
big shout out to to Pinterest fallacy
shaking his head but appreciate his help
you know getting here and everything
great conference so far and finally the
the research team at fishman thanks for
giving me the time off to be here have
any questions or concerns
not most summer more targeted will try
to do some sort of a client pre
filtering to figure out you know there's
there's no reason for me as his exploits
as soon you gonna bility or an exploit
if you're not running flash not running
Joba right and the main reason for that
is within the corporate environment you
have ideas or you have posted base ideas
within most antivirus signatures so you
wouldn't wanna do the shotgun effect
because that would give away here the
presence of an exploit kit but question
so this since this exploit kit is
definitely no low-end compared to some
of the more widely used and highly
developed ones that's the approach that
this particular one uses it also thanks
for having me