[Music]
and thanks for blue hat for having bring
me here to Tel Aviv it's a beautiful
venue and a really bang-up job you guys
did on the all the decorations out there
my computer went to sleep so just go
ahead and wake it up oh good there we go
so the top the topic of the talk is
going to be about supply chain security
with the subtext if if I were a
nation-state and so some people have
asked me is this in response to the big
bloomberg article that came out actually
the topic was picked about a month
before the article came out I was
invited to give the talk and I said hey
guys would you want me to talk about out
here and like I would be cool if he gave
a talk about supply chain security he's
like sure and then like about a month
later that article comes I'm like okay
well that's that's pretty topical what
guy have to make a couple adjustments to
the talk but overall the idea is
essentially if you had a large amount of
resources more than I have what are the
sorts of things that we should actually
be worrying about in terms of supply
chain security so first a little about
my background I'm a hardware guy that
means that when everyone was doing the
dot-com thing I was wasting a lot of
time building stuff like this all the
wires all the sorts of things
time passes a lot of my friends go off
and do more software stuff people
probably the soldering irons people
start outsourcing their supply chains
and eventually this comes to the point
where people start putting using
hardware as security roots in his
enclaves and so if I'm to be believed
that phrase their base roughly
translates to in the land of the blind
the one-eyed man is a king so in the
world where you know everyone had
forgotten how to solder and how to build
circuit boards this is a actually a
picture of a board I put inside the
original Microsoft Xbox to extract the
security keys there were being passed on
a high-speed bus between the South
Bridge and the CPU and back then it was
relatively easy to go ahead and build
one of these things that took up just a
couple weeks and you can pull up the
keys now we have to do much more heroic
to go ahead and pull keys out of the the
trusted roots after that sort of little
stint you know playing around with the
the xbox I decided I want to do
something a little different so I spent
a few years designing silicon this is a
nano photonic integrated chip that I
worked on at a company called Lux Terra
and they really interesting part about
this is that I got exposed to the roots
and the nitty-gritty of how to actually
design transistors on silica and how
they'll do layer stacks how to manage
fab how to build packages these sorts of
things and they'll become relevant that
experience will actually comes into
relevance later in the talk nowadays I
mostly spend my time building systems so
here's a few of the things I've sort of
played around with in recent years which
means basically I spend a lot of time
dealing with supply chains and supply
chains are inherently not a friendly
territory so this is an example of a
chip that was actually sent to me by a
friend this is a st as it purports to be
a service secure microcontroller he
bought a bunch of them they weren't
behaving he sent them to me took the top
off the chip put in a microscope and
found out that on the inside it was not
actually a mic that microcontrollers
labeled on the inside it was actually an
LC X 244 which is like an 8-bit TTL
buffer not a very interesting chip but
but it but it but it tells you about
sort of already there's a bit of subtext
about people playing shenanigans in the
supply chain another problem I had was I
had to source SD cards by them I had
some SD cards from a vendor called
Kingston they weren't behaving correctly
they weren't according to spec and so I
went to the grain markets bought a whole
bunch of them digested off the top with
acid took pictures all of all the chips
on the inside learn more about the
structure of their cards and found some
really interesting sort of correlations
between what was purporting to be a real
chip and what were some patent fakes for
example so there's there's there's a lot
the level of sophistication people are
going to build these sort of fake memory
cards is quite high they're stacking
chip on chip doing wire bonding and
capsulation packaging and marking
another example of a problem that I had
was I built a little board it's open
source that has an FPGA
it and I had a problem we're in
production about 3% of the boards we're
feeling a particular part of the test we
put them aside later on they were sent
to me and one thing I finally noticed
about them is that all of the FPGAs I
were feeling had this little square here
if you look over here here's a bigger
picture of this square this square here
is a someone had put it in a laser after
and just blast it off what was
underneath to hear the letters es for
engineering sample so someone had gone
and recovered engineering sample FPGAs
or they're meant to be ground up have
blast off the letters and put them back
into the supply chain of course we had a
check to check the part number before it
goes in but the worker just saw square
this it's not you know it didn't say
don't not accept the square so the Bart
name was valid that got put on to the
boards so um I brought the issue to the
contract manufacturer was working with
that time make us CEO was sitting there
and then like all the managers and that
sort of stuff and it's really into his
first reaction was he looked on the
Thema says okay if anyone this room is a
response for this you have one chance
now to fess up to it and I and you know
well the punishment will be less severe
right so the first thing he knew was
that inside his own company there could
be people playing the cheating game and
you want to clear himself for that first
right so no of course no one fast up to
it and then so then we started looking
down the supply chain you know who are
the distributors we've all been going
all the way back to Xilinx where the
places the injection could have happened
and people like when we called up
distributors they're like oh it must
have been the courier the courier
intercepted the packages and took the
chips out and swapped them oh it must
have been in your spear warehouse
someone broke in your warehouse and
stole the chips the line workers swapped
it out at the at the line or something
like this so just the blame game was
going back and forth back and forth it
turned out at the other day we had a
couple of distributors for the FPGA one
of them was this Chinese company and and
most likely it came from that one and
not having it we tried to report the
issue to Xilinx unfortunately this
Chinese distributor had so much leverage
on that supply chain scientists couldn't
afford to disqualify them so they
continued to sell through those guys and
we ended up at a settlement where they
just sent us replacements for the chips
that were bad so why would they do it
for just 3% of the chips you know why
would they like blend them in seems like
a lot of effort in LA
risk for what seems like now a reward
except if you consider the fact that
distributor margins only about three or
five percent to start with if you blend
them in at a rate of about three or
three to five percent
you've doubled their margin right so
it's actually a huge amount of money for
those people who are involved in supply
chain to pull off an attack like this
and also when you blend it at a rate of
a few percent it sort of kind of mixes
in with the other noise of manufacturing
like like I said when the issue happened
on the line we just set them aside we
didn't I didn't set up any red flags
like three percent could be a soldering
error could be something else
so was a lot took us a long time to even
catch the problem so that's sort of a
little bit of background about how
supply chains can be hostile even if
Security's not involved now if we want
to think about sort of a security basis
for supply chain attacks let's talk a
little about sort of like the whys the
what's and the where's of supply chain
attacks like why would you want to do it
what might you do and where might it
happen and that's this is going to be
the bulk of the talk so why do you want
to you know attack the supply chain well
there's obviously people want help
getting in so you want you know you want
to have back doors inside hardware to
assist with getting your root kits and
exploits in sometimes I want to get
things out maybe difficult exhale trade
data or you want a more subtle way to
exfiltrate your data or you just want to
sabotage equipment through some sort of
selective defeat or destruction of
equipment in the case of cyber wire for
warfare or ransom way or something like
this there's probably other reasons as
well but we'll just pick these three as
a sort of a basis to talk about supply
chains so getting in a back door can
serve as a beachhead for a rootkit
remote system access or persistence I
mean as the previous talk has
demonstrated some vendors already build
backdoors into the systems and sell them
to you so your work the work is already
done but in some cases people want to go
ahead and for example tamper with the
management engine adds some implants
inside of the inside of the management
interfaces to go ahead and assist with
getting backdoors into the into the end
of the hardware exfiltration is also
another reason so this is a people I'm
pretty sure are familiar with the ant
catalog from the NSA from
Snowden leaks this is an example of an
implant you can put inside a video cable
that will go ahead and radiate what's
going on the screen and so the an
attacker nearby can go ahead and
exfiltrate what's the constant your
screen with the radio receiver there's
also other ways for example if you if
your harddrive reports X amount of
gigabytes and you do a secure wipe but
actually there's a little cache of data
on the side that's unlikable it can be
used for exfiltration of data as well
mobile has a unique opportunity for
acceleration of data and particular
mobile devices are very helpful for
leaking the information on targets and
there's also an enhanced opportunities
in a mobile scenario for direct access
to the hardware so evil made style
attacks and near field access to the
hardware and in terms of sabotage it of
course you know you can imagine
scenarios where if you could have a
selective defeat of hardware based and
remote command that could be extremely
useful particularly to nation-states
interested in engaging in cyber warfare
or ransomware so now let's talk a bit
about the what this is a bit of a big
diagram we're gonna go through each of
these blobs one at a time the idea is
what might you do to attack a supply
chain in this diagram it has two axes
the vertical axis is call this here is
the detection difficulty right so I sort
of have it in a in a ranked it from easy
to hard so easiest is visual you just
look at it and you're like huh there's
something there that shouldn't be there
a harder is so if you need some
equipment specialized equipment to
either an x-ray or you have to use a
meter to detect the presence and on the
bottom the most difficulty would be if
you had to pull off the chip put in a
scanning electron microscope and look
for the implants the on the other sort
of axis is sort of the execution
difficulty so you know on the right hand
side the easiest sort of attacks takes
seconds to execute and cost less than a
buck and the hardest ones can cost
millions of dollars and take months to
plan and perhaps pull off and these sort
of dashed lines here I sort of I want to
sort of if you were to spin customize
these to make these attacks a little
more
effective it gets bit more expensive but
on a log scale it's you know sort of
just pushes out a little bit further
into that region so let's um let's start
with the first sort of easiest stuff
component substitutions right these are
just taking components out and swapping
them for other components super easy to
execute you would think that they're
relatively easy to detect
so they ought to be on the easy side but
they can actually someone can be very
hard to detect so if you ever looked at
a circuit board you'll see plenty of
resistors and capacitors these resistors
have no labels they all look the same
they could be zero ohms they could be
hundreds of mega ohms you have no idea
capacitors look all the same basically
there's no way for you to really tell
what they are unless you pull them off
in fact if you just put a meter on the
board and try to measure it other
circuits around these can mask the
actual value of those of those parts as
well so it can be difficult to tell if
component has been swapped and this is
actually you know in manufacturing is a
classic problem in itself Iowa sweat
bullets that not someone's attacking my
supply chain someone just put the wrong
reel in the Machine now I've got the
wrong resistor in the wrong spot so the
mechanisms that can be in play when you
do a bomb swap is that you can modify
for example bootstrap options chips will
determine perhaps which interface to
read the code from initially based upon
a strapping resistor changing that
resistor from zero ohms to very large
value or vice versa can can change the
boot behavior it can also help with
things like if you want to do remote
side channel attacks if you reduce the
amount of capacitance on a particular
device it makes the supply noise much
larger and you can go ahead and assist
with those styles of attacks for also
Rho Hamming a lot of people here I think
are familiar with real hammering it's
very dependent upon the structure of the
DRAM chip itself this is a micrograph of
the DRAM chip and essentially you're
swinging the neat the jacent wires
around to try and induce a fault inside
a memory cell so the solution to you
know hardening its ro family hammering
part of it as well why don't we just
make sure we accept only extent except
that are like proving to be hardened
against ro Hamming so this is a
wonderful you know memory it's by
Kingston it's got a sight to see label
it's got the labeling all the sort of
stuff except you know you have to look a
little bit deeper in that fun for
Kingston doesn't have a fab they don't
make memory chip so how is it they have
chips with their name on it if you go to
a site like dear Amex exchange they
actually should post the spot price of
DRAM you can get you check in on it it's
like a stock market kind of thing and
you'll notice that one of the memory
chips is like much much cheaper than the
others and it has this term ett after it
what is ET t stand for well ET t is
actually for ram that is effectively
untested or unaffectedly tested or
untested it turns out that Ram
manufacturers can oftentimes produce
memory at a rate faster than they can
test them so they come off the wafer fab
and there's a backup at the testing
machines so for them to go ahead and try
to monetize their fabs faster they'll go
ahead and sell chips that are not tested
or if effectively test this is your spot
tested there are blank and unmarked and
then other manufacturers pick them up
and are supposed to Scouts on or test
them mark them as their own brand and
then sell them out guess what this is a
you know a perfect opportunity for
people to go ahead and swap around chips
inside the supply chain even though they
may be marked as one thing they could
have another chip on the inside another
sort of attack that can happen through
the simple bomb swap is a mobile device
identification so if you were to take a
radio signal from a mobile phone put in
a spectrum analyzer and look at it
you'll see a particular shape to the
spectrum coming out this shape is
actually almost required by law you
can't transmit in the sidebands and this
you know this actual shape on the top is
way is very consistent from device to
device and part of what allows you to
achieve this is there's actually a
passive filter on the back end of your
power amplifier of your mobile phone to
create that shape if you were to go
ahead and tamper with that filter you'll
actually see side bands start appearing
on the edge in this in this band here
where it shouldn't be and sort of like
in that matrix where they have that red
woman who walks through this see of like
you know black suits since everyone's
phones here passes verification the one
person who has a tampered radio that has
doesn't have the filter sight it's going
to stick out you'll know that that
person is new you can sort of identify a
particular target through a modified RF
filter so that's come
substitution let's talk about adding
components so let's just put another
component inside the device that
shouldn't be there and this is the one
that a lot of people think about this is
this took you know the headlines that
the Bloomberg Business Week is for this
little component on the inside if we
make it really small maybe normal notice
or you know NSA had created implants
that go inside of the Ethernet jack or
inside USB Jack's to go ahead and and
exfiltrate data or do something else to
the Machine and so adding components is
relatively easy to detect you can either
see it in there or you can see it in an
x-ray so let's talk about actually is a
little bit so this is a a novena
motherboard a circuit board they made
once upon a time I had a friend with a
CT x-ray machine we stuck in there
decided to look around poke around see
what it looks like this is what the
motherboard looks like on an x-ray so
there's some things are really obvious
you look inside like the Ethernet ports
and you see that the transport is
perfectly normal
these are the trims the Transformers on
the inside they're the hybrid that are
required by spec but then if you look at
for example these are the chips right
you say okay well what I'm looking at
here like what what's going on is this
thing here the silicon actually it turns
out this is not the silicon this is
actually a large solder pad underneath
the chip and the solder itself is very
dense it blocks to x-rays so I actually
masked the presence of the silicon you
it's very hard to tell where the chip is
inside and x-rays which brings me to the
next interesting sort of exploit space
which is adding a chip inside of a
package right so chips multiple chips
and site packages is a sort of
well-established technology as I had
sort of alluded to in the at micro SD
card example there's chips on top of
memory chips to control them in fact
today you can get sort of sixteen
seventeen chips inside a single package
when you have your little micro
high-density micro SD cards there's a
very mature technology and so the thing
that they use to do this is a technology
called wire bonding if you were to take
a standard for example dip chip pick off
the top you would see the silk on the
inside and you would see these little
wires coming off the edge of the chip
those are the wire bonds
if you were to look inside of a USB key
for example they're made by taking chips
sticking directly onto a circuit board
and while you're bonding them down the
circuit board and encapsulating them
with plastic this is what the wire bonds
look like in sort of a microscope view
this is the chip and you can see these
little thin wire bonds coming off the
chip down onto the circuit board once
the wire bond is done the chip is
usually encapsulated so in the case of
chip on board you get the little black
you know blob on it and in case of
actual chips it goes into overmolding
machine so it looks a little bit nicer
wire bonding process itself so you can
get this video to start is actually very
fast so this is actually a water mummy
binding machine it's not in the
cleanroom
I'm sitting it's me with the camera
standing next to them in regular street
clothes happens very quickly the
operator just swaps and boards it finds
the chips goes and puts a wire bond it's
down this machine here you can buy it on
the second-hand market for tens of
thousands of dollars it's not super
expensive if you want to do a custom
wire bond you go this guy here programs
machine he does it he sees basically has
like an image he sees through the
microscope he doesn't H wear the wire
bond goes and he hits a button and it
remembers those positions as you can see
here the actual specification is a PNG
they made that I mailed email to the guy
he's looking on his phone
counting where the wire bond should go
he's gonna go back to the screen and
sort of identify where those bonds go
and then once he designates all the
points the Machine remembers where all
those wire bonds should go has a little
bit of vision recognition to make sure
it's aligned up and it just replays and
replays and replays the replays to go
ahead and do it so why we're binding is
very accessible it's very versatile you
can do chip on chip and so now when you
want to go ahead and look inside of
chips and sort of look for implants
there's a bit of a challenge because
actually some chips intentionally have
multiple chips on the inside this is an
example of a mobile phone mobile phone
chipset from MediaTek I put it in an
x-ray just those curious to see I
actually just want to know how big the
die was and I was surprised to see if
you know how to read these things you
can you'll see there's about six or
seven separate silicon pieces inside of
here each of them
are from different manufacturers and I
was like okay why do they do this if you
look at their skew matrix it turns out
they offer the same like part as a
single package with multiple memory
options different power amplifier
options different radio bands and so
instead of spinning a bunch of different
masks for different SKUs they just put
them on a single substrate wire bond
them together and then sell them to you
on the outside as a single chip so if I
were to try and take this and I say okay
I'll put in the x-ray and trying to
figure out someone's got an implant on
the inside it could just be the
manufacturing changing vendors for the
memory chip for example and nothing
malicious at all and then if you want to
go ahead and zoom in say okay what's the
best I can do to look at the silicon so
I'm playing with the contrast destroy it
try to image the silicon you can see
kind of the outline of the silicon here
but the first thing I notice is any cop
or any sort of metal underneath it
immediately masked it out so the moment
these so this is this chip it's not
mount a circuit board the moment that
thing goes on a circuit board you're
gonna have more and more layers of
copper and and solder masking out the
presence of the chip so let's take a
little closer look at what a wire bond
looks like this is in the 3d view is a
little rendering that I made this is a
chip then what you know the wire comes
down and put on the chip it's pulled off
to the side and then bond it on the
circuit board they just do this over and
over again and if you were to go in an
x-ray you would see sort of like this
outline and then the wires coming off of
the chip now let's imagine that we want
to go ahead and put an implant inside of
a chip on the unmodified version the
wire bonds comes straight from the
original bond pads down to the PCB for
the implant version I've gone ahead and
just placed a die on top of the die I
wore a bond from the pads to the
existing pads and then stitch it back
down to the to the circuit board double
bonding on two passes a well-established
technology they do it all the time if
you want to sort of get a
man-in-the-middle effect you can wire
bond from the target pad and then wire
bond back over it onto the board that's
also a technique that is perfectly fine
and wire bonding if you're to imagine
what it looks like in an x-ray view you
would have a second chip on the inside
which remember is very hard to see and
the only Delta you'll see is that some
wire bonds are just a little bit longer
inside the x-ray view so it's a you know
it's detectable but difficult this is
when actual piggyback looks like an
x-ray if this is the cross-section of
the chip you know eight layers or so and
you can see the stitching of the wire
bond going down to the circuit board if
you were able to actually get the edge
of the chip and look at an x-ray edge on
you can see the stitching the thing is
normally it's mounted on the circuit
board so other components would be in
the way you won't be able get the x-rays
through to it so you have to pull a chip
off to get this view from the top view
all you see are straight wires it's
there's nothing in the top view that
really gives away the fact that this has
so many chips inside the stack in an
x-ray view so why are bond implants
leveraged mature commodity technology
cost a few thousand dollars and maybe a
couple weeks to develop and you can do
this with all sort of you know either
outsource equipment or if you're
paranoid you don't want someone know
about your operations you can source it
for a couple hundred thousand bucks and
buy the molding line outright and you
can also you don't have to develop
custom chips for these exploits you can
use commodity MCS or FPGA so you buy in
bare die form put them inside of a chip
and go ahead and have your implant
deployed the problem is it's it is
detectable in x-rays so there is another
technology that's come out call it a
through silicon via so as the name
implies this is a piece of silicon and
there's no avea that goes from the front
coming out the back side of the silicon
this height here is about point one to
point two millimeters this is a
cross-section of a through silver via if
this may be about five or six years ago
this was exotic today you can if you buy
any graphics card they have advertises
HBM the high bandwidth memory they're
using through-silicon vias it's a mass
produced but a production process you
can just sort of order it from the fabs
so now if you're to have a through
silicon via chip and you were to execute
the same implant you just bonded on top
of the existing pads and you wire bond
on top of those right there's no
extension of the wire bonds so if you
were to go ahead and take a
cross-section of this implant you know
this is the implant I see and this is
the wire bonds I'm just going to just
cut right through those wire bonds here
this is what it looked like
you have your package substrate your
target silicon chip this is your man in
the middle I see through this through
silicon vias with bumps going down the
chip and then your wire bonds coming off
the top
if you were to look at this in the x-ray
view the unmodified version versus the
modified version you wouldn't see any
difference in terms of bond my links you
just have to sort of rely on the hope
that you can see this ghostly bit of
silicon rim the silicon itself is rather
transparent to x-rays so wire bond with
to cut through silicon via implants does
require a bespoke man-in-the-middle chip
because it has to match the the bond
pattern and through so than v is sort of
a newish technology so you can't just
buy commodity parts so it's a bit more
expensive and difficult to pull off but
it's harder to tech with x-rays so what
about this other packaging technology
called wafer level of chip scale
packages WL csps this is like this is
just a random one I had on my desk took
a picture of it you can see it's the
silicon die and then little solder bumps
put on the silicon die this is actually
becoming a super popular packaging
format if you look at so I have an
iPhone motherboard like 80% of the chips
by count use this packaging technology
the cool thing about this is that
essentially they've done a lot of the
hard work for you in terms of getting an
implant in there you've got the bare die
so you don't have to source the bare die
you've got the but you've got the things
already balled out into large pads and
so if you were to look at the
cross-section of a normal device you can
see you've got your starter balls your
target silicon and then some backside
passivation to protect the IC you go
ahead and you throw in your implant you
just go ahead and you just stack it
right on top of the bumps and then you
have the solder balls on top of your
implant and now you have basically an
addictive implant on the inside of your
chip using through silicon via
technology so if you want to try and
detect this through an x-ray it's going
to be difficult detect because the
solder balls as mentioned before will
mask a bit of what's going behind it
inside the x-ray machine so you mean if
you can tilt the chip a bit it's a
little bit difficult to tell that you
have another chip on top of a chip and
if you optically inspect actually a lot
of these chips already have a seam on
the edge because as I mentioned before
there's a backside passivation coating
so it's easy to confuse that seam with
for example what might be another layer
of silicon that's been put in between
your chip and and and the chip that's
the sorry the man-in-the-middle chip
between the chip that you want to have
on your board so wait for level of chip
scale implants the pro zone is there
logistically much easier actually than
wire band where I'm on implants because
for a wire bonding thing you have to
source the target chips in Barre chip
form that can be a little bit of a trick
you have to bribe someone you have to
work with some inside the company to get
the bare die out
there's no package to reverse engineer
you don't have to redo a package it's
it's just the chip and the SU silicon
vias and the wafer level chip scale
package are both commodity technologies
there's not
new tech I'm proposing here this is
off-the-shelf stuff
the con is that requires you to
fabricate a custom template for every
single chip you're trying to exploit so
you have to make a piece of silicon that
has a through Segovia's at the right
locations for every single chip you want
to attack I would probably cost in the
mid hundred thousand dollars to set what
these up you don't have to do in a
cutting-edge fab you can do it in sort
of a you know 130 nanometer 180
nanometer fab to go ahead and build
those chips so it's not as expensive to
fab the chip but the real pro of this is
extremely hard to detect there's almost
no x-ray footprint almost no visual
footprint so that's adding an IC in the
package let's talk about substituting
very briefly substituting ICS in a
package this is where instead of putting
another chip on top of a chip or using
the existing chip you just get rid of
the chip put your own chip in so you
know system controllers are oftentimes a
little embedded ICS you can go ahead and
just swap it out with another one
another objective you could have is for
example on every DRAM dim you have a
little sort of SPD little I squared CW
prom that tells you what the character
except that dim is it's supposed to be a
certain amount of bytes large if you put
another chip inside that I squared C
package it has a much larger capacity as
long as you don't try to read or write
past the end the system will never know
you won't detect that issue and so in
and this is a relatively trivial thing
to do to go ahead and take an existing
SPD memory market as sort of a lower
capacity than it is put it inside your
your dim and now you have a convenient
little cache we can go ahead and store
keys you want to exfiltrate or code you
want to use later on something like that
so this is a this is also another sort
of attack menu that is feasible
and useful in certain situations and
very hard to detect because when you
look at in the x-ray there's one chip
that looks legit it's inside of a
package finally there's the subject of
modifying the chips themselves right so
I kind of consider this the ultimate
attack backdoors inside the IC of course
as the previous talk it indicates some
manufacturers backdoor their ICS for you
by putting management engines in with
all kinds of fun flaws in it but if if
someone is trying to harden their chips
against you if you can get backdoor
inside the IC they're very hard to
detect there they can be difficult to
attribute and they're of course very
persistent so how would this happen
there's actually multiple insertion
opportunities during the process flow of
making a chip so when you start with
your high level chip design at the very
top here you start with a piece of RTL
piece of code and then either you're the
type of shop that owns the set of the
tools internally to build that into a
mass set or you don't and if you don't
own those then you're actually just
sending off a mat a netlist to a third
party service and that third party
service can tamper with the netlist so
it's a relatively easy way to get a
backdoor into the chip even if you do
own the back end flow you know there's
opportunities such as tampering with the
hard IP and also mask tampering to go
ahead and get implants and so talk a
little bit more about each of these
so netlist tampering so there's kind of
two if you were to split the flows into
two major categories if you're at a
spinning on chip there's one called the
ASIC application-specific integrated
circuit path here on the left and the
right hand side is called khat
customer-owned tooling the big
difference between the two is on this
one you've you've got several extra head
count and spent several million dollars
extra to buy those tools that you need
to go ahead and turn RTL into a math set
and typically it's used only for like
high-performance applications where you
can justify the investment of Co t4 sort
of like cheaper support ships things
like server bmc's disk controllers
set-top boxes the controllers inside of
your memory chips whatever it is these
jellybean ICS you it doesn't pay off
to buy the whole flow so a lot of times
people just hand off RTL to third-party
service to go ahead and implement those
chips here's an example of one vendor
that advertises service called Sakai own
X they did about a 1.3 billion revenue
in 2016 estimated and then from their
own page they have like you know here
the here the stages we can hand off a
design to us you could just hand a
specification we'll do the whole thing
for you you can hand off RTL or you can
just hand off a netlist of course on
this whole back-end site here from
physical design all the way to testing
to the shipment there's opportunities to
put stuff inside in fact what you often
find is that these ASIC vendors will put
backdoors in for you not under any
malicious guys but just to help them
with testing it's their responsibility
to yield to you a working chip and so
they are going to go ahead and put sort
of effectively test access ports in the
inside which are not going to be within
you know the you know the RTL that
you've hardened and and can go ahead and
serve as a backdoor so okay if you care
about security you're going to ducat
right so I'm safe with caught the
problem is is that even if you're doing
you have all the tooling yourself you
have these blocks they're called hard IP
blocks this is a view of what you might
look at at on the back end of your place
and route you have these small little
boxes here which is all your standard
cells there are being placed down your
your Nan's your flip-flops whatever it
is and then literally you just have this
block called this blob of SRAM right and
the foundry will not share with you the
actual layout of the SRAM they insert it
to you after you hand back to them your
mask pattern so when you ship a mask pan
to the foundry it's got these big holes
in it for things like RF an analog PLL's
ADCs DACs and band gaps things like Ram
things like ROM things like effuse so
you know the reason why the manufacturer
doesn't share these with you is that ram
density is one of the metrics that
really drive the cost of a chip chips
have a lot of RAM on the inside they
spend a lot of money and effort
optimizing those layouts they're not
going to let that layout leak to another
foundry so you can get that edge in
terms of cost so they're so they're just
not going to share with you what those
blocks look like you just have to trust
them that those blocks perform to spec
if use is another thing that's very hard
to get from the manufactures review I
have accounts from people who work
very large companies that are very
security-conscious and they want to get
the beef use blocks to audit and the
best they can do is they can get test
ships back and they have to send them to
a third-party service to delay and
reverse-engineer to make sure that
they're working correctly the
manufacturer will just not share with
you the effuse IP pad rings also as well
for various reasons manufacturers don't
want to share those with you so
basically even if you do a cop tooling
flow everything you need to back door
your RTL is going to be a hard IP block
and you're just trusting a manufacturer
a fab not to do anything wrong with it
even if you were able to convince a FAP
to give you all of those blocks and you
can review the GDS to mass before it
goes out the masks themselves go through
a lot of processing so if you were to
draw just let's think about the problem
in the first place
if you you know people heard like okay
we're at 14 nanometer or something like
this and it's a number of people bad
around how big are the photons they use
to image that 193 nanometers okay using
photons they're this big
to make transistors this big this
something doesn't work out there but
some magic has to happen so when you
have your mashed pattern that looks like
an L like this it gets turned into this
green outline which then turns into this
read printed outline this is not even at
14 nanometer to do the 49er stuff they
actually take your mask and fracture it
into multiple sub masks and use a whole
bunch of other techniques to do this and
this is all done after you hand your
masks to them the main the fab runs a
whole bunch of algorithms to to just
tamper with your data essentially and
turn it into something they can
manufacture and then also the mass
themselves have to be perfect right
masts aren't born perfect so there's a
whole industry around editing masks
after they're made so this is a guy this
is a manufacturer they're advertising
how they can go ahead and take masts to
have broken lines and fill in the lines
are broken they have excess material and
remove the excess material and they can
go and printed well guess what mask
editing is the perfect opportunity to go
ahead and if you can control that mask
editing process even if you've vetted
everything all the way down and you
don't control that mask editor someone
can go ahead and tamper with your layout
what can they do for example dopant
tampering there's a there's a paper you
can check out where essentially you can
instead of theirs and this one's a very
difficult one to tech because there's no
morphological change to the poly silicon
changed the metal layers all that's
happened is the trace amounts of atoms
to control whether you have an N or P
type transistor have been modified right
so this is a very difficult one to
detect and this one can be done entirely
at a mask level edit spare cell rewiring
so you know Asics are expensive you
don't tape them out without any sort of
sort of silver bullets in your pocket to
save you in case of a bug so when you
have your final layout this is an
example of all the little standard cells
they'll look for empty slots the tool
automatically inserts pairs things that
aren't connected to anything else but I
already have essentially all the logic
wired in so later on if you folks like
you know I screwed up my logic you don't
have to spend a whole set of masks you
just have to make a couple mask layer
changes to go ahead and and and fix your
design and so this is often time done as
a mask edit guess what the thing that's
good for the designer is also good for
the attacker and you can do just simple
subtle things like signal bypasses if
you look at the design of a flip-flop
standard cell it turns out every
standard cell gives you both the true
and the inverse of the signal this is
just a feature that every cell has built
into it whether you want it or not so if
you want to take a signal or invert it
you don't have to add anything you're
just changing the contact point from the
true output to the not true output right
so that's a pretty useful primitive to
have or if you have a multiplexer you
want to just go ahead and say instead of
you know if the you know if the hash
checks out go from signal a or if not go
through signal B you want to always go
through signal B it's just a matter of
changing our contact from being here the
Select pin just wiring it to power or
ground they're both the next feature
there's a tiny little change of the mask
and remember this masks have billions
and billions of features is looking
you're looking for like you know a
literal needle needle in a haystack so
that's sort of the the what you might
find people doing to attack on a supply
chain so the question now is like where
can these sorts of things happen so
let's first start with you write your
wherever you are and you want to order
something that comes from a distributor
via a courier there are documented
attacks where people intercept packages
on route via FedEx open
up put an implant on the inside and then
ship them on to you so that's that's a
well-known issue there's also the issue
that particularly ordering from Amazon
you have returns that go back to the
Depot so you can have a hacker inside
the customer base buying stuff and if
they don't want to be very specific
about it or they're something specific
within this distribution region they can
go ahead and tamper with the product say
it's broke send it back and Amazon will
happily sell it to someone else without
checking it again and so even if you
have tamper stickers for example they
can remove this actually a really great
talk by Dmitriy net house and a bunch of
other guys at 35 c3 I encourage people
to check it off you can learn more about
sort of the tax they can do at this
level called Walt fail and they
demonstrate they can move remove the
tamper evidence seal and sort of the
chaos that these tamper evident seals in
the attempt to try and secure this can
happen in the salon in the supply chain
so that's sort of at the distributor and
courier level so now let's think a
little bit deeper into spying how big
does that attack surface go well where
does this Juba get this stuff from it
comes from any manufacturer that goes
overseas it goes through customs there's
certain single points of entry right and
so this is where we sort of now enter
these like sensational stories about
like the big hack right from from
Bloomberg Businessweek
because it's actually just a huge attack
surface places where people can go ahead
and inject implants so not only do you
have customs and the factory that does
the Box build the bet the box built
Factory has to buy their components from
other factories there's distributors
there interacting with the gray market
and then you have that test and IC
packaging houses which are separate from
the chip fab houses we just separate
from the mask prep houses which is
separate from the actual house that does
your design so all these different
actors are opportunities for someone to
go ahead and and put an implant so the
question now becomes how well can we
target that implant how far away can we
get from a particular target and say I
just want it on that one not everybody
but just that guy right and so there's a
trend in supply chain Liz this is called
built to order mass customization or
custom turnkey or some of the terms for
it so if you order something on the
Apple web store at they'll send you a
tracking number and it comes from
Shenzhen China and you can track it all
the way to your doorstep right the world
is great because now the world is very
small the world is also very targeted so
essentially I've visited some of these
flavoring facilities inside China
there's a facility called CTS that I
went to once and for example when you
order a laptop you say I want to have
like you know the secure hard drive and
the hardened OS I want to have the
secure Enclave and I all these are the
features guess guess where that gets
built there's some guy inside this
Factory who's just you know going ahead
and putting all these things into the
laptop for you next to all the other
ones and you know I can walk into those
factories and just sort of take a look
around right so and the other thing is
for example during the fulfillment
process they use a system called pic
delights
so the blue bins in the back are the
inventory and then the the packages in
front or the box is going to customers
what happens is the worker just gets a
printed order there's a bunch of words
on it but basically barcodes you scan
the barcode a light turns on they pick
out the band they put in the box they
steal it they ship it right so the the
neat thing about this from a supply
chain attack standpoint is that you
don't need to buy off any of these
workers to go ahead and get them to put
something into a very targeted box for a
particular customer you just need to be
able to go ahead and install another bin
at the end install another code for the
software that has your special inventory
in it those workers continue with their
daily operations and then when a
particular zip code comes up took a
customer name whatever it is they get
the special version versus the regular
version and so and so it's not like you
have to go in the facility and bribe
every single person from top to bottom
and get this to happen just a couple
weak points need to be knocked over to
go ahead and get a very targeted implant
towards a customer and the other thing I
want to know is that
swapping chips is actually easy I mean
if you haven't done it before it feels
hard but you know there's people whose
day job essentially is swapping chips
off and putting them on there's an
example here our YouTube video you can
go and see someone basically pulls off
the man flash from an iPhone
weatherboard and replaces it within 30
minutes right with a with what looks
like pretty simple equipment and the
equipment's not that expensive to do so
so from this from the perspective of
like do we have to worry about inventory
sitting on a shelf post manufacturing
that has a chip swapped on it yes that's
a real possibility that's not something
that's hard to do
so people have oftentimes ask me it's
like hey you know what do you think is
this is this thing real or not I mean so
the problem is is that everything that
leaked seems feasible technically right
but for me the actual scheme as reported
doesn't pass Occam's razor they put a
lot of effort in to develop a really
really tiny implant that you can detect
by just looking at it right and this is
a country where they have all the
manufacturing capability in the world it
can do anything right and so if I were
to actually probably what my guess is
what happened is that something did
happen but the details were changed for
operational reasons to not leak the
actual thing that's happening but if I
were if I had those kinds of resources I
would develop sort of a set of through
skills through silicon via WLC SP
implants they can go ahead and put
between chips there's Sencha lien
detectable and I have multiple options
for putting them into the supply chain
if I have to be on one side of the ocean
I can go ahead and put them all the way
from the icy tests and packaging to the
box build site and then if I need to
have a very targeted operations in the
target country a mobile rework station
cost not a lot of money the actual tools
you need to remove a chip and put them
on cost about a couple hundred bucks on
the market and within five minutes to an
hour depending on the complexity of the
box and the amount of you know the you
know serve other things they use like
goo to hold down the chip and whatnot
you can typically pull off the chip and
replace it within about an hour
and so there's multiple opportunities
from the courier to customs to
distributor to to returns and exchanges
to go ahead and put a very directed
implant towards particular customers so
the key takeaways from this talk that if
I were to sort of put them out there
supply chains are hard even when
security is not a concern right I have
to deal with all kinds of shenanigans
fakes and you know people trying to sell
me stuff that isn't real even when it's
not a security issue and in this case
the red team isn't caring about my
secrets
they just want to make some money right
so and the interesting thing is that
this this ecosystem essentially has
developed a large amount of commodity
technology that can be readily adapted
to the manufacture of sort of implants
at the other day so now you can do a
wire blind implant for you load tens of
thousands of dollars and if you want to
do this wait for level chip scale
implant it's probably a few hundred
thousand dollars and also it's got a
very large attack surface so you have
everything from workers and couriers
it's a very porous transient community
with olive loyalty to their employers
you have distributors and factories who
have misaligned interest to yours they
you know these are supers and factories
they they have a profit motive they're
not necessary caring about your security
and then finally the bill to order
practices that we all sort of love and
take advantage of these days really
extends act acts surface with great
specificity over borders and across
multiple companies and so that's it
[Applause]
[Music]