[Music]
thank you very much for coming to my
talk which is called attacking edge from
the JavaScript compiler so just a quick
words about me I got started security
three years ago now by paying CTF HD
upon repeat team and I quit my job last
year to do VR full-time I've mostly been
doing JavaScript engines focusing on JIT
compilers for all the engines chakra was
my main target up to a few months now
and this is my twitter handle if you
want to are intend to risk everything
like the slides and the exploit code
within a week or so so i'll probably
publish it on twitter so the agenda for
today I try to make the talk accessible
to anyone those that do not have any
kind of experience with JavaScript
engines and those would you so we'll do
a quick intro of what chakra call some
primary about javascript engines and
some of the internals basics and then
we'll go into just-in-time compilation
and the problematic of you know just an
incorporation for JavaScript and then
I'll talk specifically about the JIT
compiler that's inside chakra and we'll
finish by working through unexploited I
submitted to a masazi last year so
quickly what's chakra Co so you probably
know edge is the default browser on
Windows 10 now chakra is the name of the
JavaScript engine that powers Microsoft
edge and basically chakra Co is the open
source version of chakra which as far as
I know is basically 95% of the thing - a
few things such as chrome API edge
bindings and chakra Co is available in
github so you can just like look at the
code is written mainly in C++ and
yeah that's about it there's to say
about so a quick primer about JavaScript
engines so that everyone can be on the
same page so these days what makes up a
JavaScript engine you have kind of this
five main components that you will see
in the four major engines or Chrome
Safari Firefox and edge so the first
thing you have is basically the parser
it's the entry part of the engine you
basically fitted the source code it
passes the thing produce an abstract
syntax tree
and produces custom byte code that
custom byte code which is specific to
each engine is then fed to the
interpreter which is basically a virtual
machine that will execute that byte code
that relies on what I call the runtime
which basically provides all the basic
data structures implements the built in
functions of JavaScript etc you of
course have a garbage collector because
you don't have to free memory and do
memory management in JavaScript and you
might have one or many JIT compilers so
this varies for each engines but at
least you you have one these days so so
now quickly some internals of chakra
code that we'll need throughout the talk
so in all JavaScript engine these days
basically everything that that you that
you have in your JavaScript code is
internally represented as something
called a JS value in chakra every value
basically has the same type which is
just like a void pointer which is called
the vow chakra uses a trick that you
find also in other engines which is
basically none boxing it's a trick where
you basically in 8 bytes you can encode
some type some kind of type information
as well as the as the value itself so
how that looks like is basically in
chakra if you take the integer X 4 1 4 1
4 & 4 1 it basically it is represented
internally as the thing you have on the
right which is 4 1 4 1 4 1 which the 48
bits set and if you take a double which
has the same hex at the small
representation you have you find the
same thing for 1 4 1 4 1 but exhort with
the fffc so basically they use the fact
that on X 64 the other 17 bits are
cleared for user space addresses to to
encode some kind of type information
there and what that means is that if
none of those bits are set you're
basically dealing with a valid pointer
and dereference
dereferencing that pointer will
basically lead you to the actual object
which will contain more information so
those objects
commonly refer to as J subjects in all
the major engines
talk about them now so javascript
objects are basically a dictionary so
it's a collision of collection of
key-value pairs that are called
properties the interesting to note is
that each object does not maintain its
own map of property names to property
values and this is something that all
J's engines do these days the object
will only maintain the property values
and as basically a pointer to an object
which will basically describe that
object layout so in chakra is called the
type and it will ask for two nice things
the first one is you save space because
every object of the same type basically
you know you're only allocated up
allocate the type once and you have all
the objects pointing to the same type
and he also allows for optimization such
as inline caching and we'll talk more on
that later
so object layouts and chakra so you have
two two objects a arts basically this is
the most default one I realized this
morning that the code might be a bit
small for the ones at the back so I hope
you'll be able to follow along so
basically here I declare an empty object
and set two property on it x and y those
are integers X 4 1 4 1 4 1 and X 4 2 4 2
4 2 and if you look in memory this is
the layout that you'll have you
basically have the v table pointer the
type pointer which is what i talked
about previously and you basically have
this ox Lutz pointer and if you
dereference that pointer is basically
where you will find your property values
in memory so it's basically a pointer to
a contiguous memory region where you
will only have the property values and
not the property names so if like here
you can see right like it points to to
our properties we also have a another
layout that's used throughout chakra and
it's also a common optimization so here
I declare an object but I declare the
properties directly in it so it's a
scalar object and here they use a layout
that they call object header inlined
and basically what that means is they
don't choose the extra pointer to store
the property values the story directly
inline into the object itself so how
property access basically works well as
I said all the chakra objects will
basically have something called the type
and when the runtime has to deal with a
code that
certain property so here I'm setting
property X on an object and just
printing it
well the runtime will basically call a
class method on the type saying get me
that property for that certain property
name so internally it's called the
property ID if you want to look in the
code and that type is basically able to
say a property ID is that this certain
index and we all return the thing so
here if we query the type it will return
ox lots zero because that's where a dot
X will be so that's about it for the
intervals that we'll need there's a lot
more there's more to talk about of
course but I don't have time to spend
too much but that's all we'll need going
forward so now we'll go into the core of
the subject which is a Java Script JIT
compilation and especially like the
problem associated with it for
JavaScript so basically what is the goal
of JIT compilation is it's basically to
generate highly optimized machine code
the upside of it of course is that your
code runs like way faster than when it
runs in the interpreter but you have two
problems that you have to deal with the
first one is higher start of time
because you don't want your webpage to
take like you know 10 seconds to load
and you also have no type information
javascript doesn't have type into
operation so we have to deal with that
somehow and I'll try to shed some light
on that later on so in practice what you
have is basically your JavaScript code
will start running in the interpreter
and if something gets called repeatedly
it will then be scheduled to be compiled
and be compared to machine code and then
your run actual machine code so I try to
be to have a lot of examples so this is
the first one we'll look at which is
edition so I have a function that
basically takes two parameter X and Y
and returned the addition of the two and
you've probably all seen some of the
memes about JavaScript edition being
quite obscure and behaving weirdly and
if you look at the standard that defines
the JavaScript edition this is basically
what you have so you don't have to read
everything but like something as simple
as the addition like as all these steps
that you have to take if you want to
implement it so now the question is do
we really want to generate machine code
that does that well the answer is no
because this is
basically what you already have in the
interpreter so if you were to have any
kind of performance gain it would be
pretty marginal so so we need to be
smarter than that
so the truth is if if you have a
function called addition like that
realistically like modern likely you're
going to only call it with like integers
like the and that's kind of what the JIT
compiler will rely on so here assuming I
only called the function addition with
integers I probably want something
that's as close as the assembly code
that I have here which is basically two
instructions just like you know add the
two registers that hold the parameter
values and just written but we don't
have type information right we don't
know that those things are going to be
integer which is like the main problem
of JavaScript come just-in-time
compilation so the way we the JIT
compilers basically deal with that is
that while we are running in the
interpreter we will collect profile
information on the type of parameters
and we will generate optimized code
based on that and so more on that later
I have another oh yes sorry so so here I
I called the function repeatedly no loop
I is going to be an integer one thousand
three three seven is also an integer and
every time we call that function with
the interpreter collects type
information saying or X is an integer Y
is an integer and every time we run the
loop we call that up to the point where
we'll actually say oh this thing has
been called a lot let's let's JIT
compile it so the JIT compiler will
basically make the assumption that we've
only seen integer parameter for that
function so more than likely the
parameters will continue to be of the
same type and the idea is that the JIT
compiler will check the type of the
parameters at the beginning to make sure
that it's what we assume there will be
and the code will be generated based on
that assumption which is why it's called
speculative compilation because we
speculate on the type of the parameters
so I have another example here I have a
function called get X
pretty simple it takes one parameter and
returns property X on the thing so more
than likely if you have this function
you expect to only give it
objects and here I call it in a loop
repeatedly with a scanner object which
only has property X and the key is I
only call it with the same scanner
object every time so the thing will add
the same layout in memory but object
look object lookup is a bit complex
right you have to go through the types
you have to create the type to know
where the property lies and you don't
want to compile down that whole logic
because then you don't gain anything
it's basically code that's already
implemented in the interpreter so here
same thing we will basically speculate
on the type of the parameter assume that
if we've only seen one particular type
then we will generate code for that
particular type and then we'll be able
to use direct memory access and this is
what's called inline caching I haven't
like will see that in details later on
and if if this if the code gets an
object of a different type when it's jet
compiled then we'll basically have to
fall back to the interpreter because the
code won't be valid for all the types of
objects so that takes us to two key
concepts that I use in read compilation
the first one is so-called slow path so
basically as I said speculative
compilation will make assumptions those
assumptions needs to be checked in the
code and if something does not hold you
might have to go back into the
interpreter so that's true for addition
right like you know if we generate JIT
code for addition of two integers and
then we have like two strings then we
need to do something completely
different so we have to fall back into
the interpreter via a slow path the bad
news for that is you get a performance
hit because you you you exit the JIT
code the good news is that it was
actually intended so for that particular
operation you you will go back to an
interpreter which is much slower but you
will still return to a JIT function the
second key concept is is called bailout
and basically sometimes if your
assumption does not hold while the slow
path is not going to cut it because your
code is complete garbage so for example
for my function get X an object is a
pointer what if I give it an integer
well integer are tagged it's never going
to be a right pointer so if we don't
bail out we'll just most likely end up
crashing at some point in the JIT code
so you don't want that and then in that
case like the old execution of the
function has to basically resume into
the interpreter the the downside of that
is now it's a big performance hit
because bailing out is a non-trivial
process and the only upside I can find
is basically you probably like if you're
not familiar probably never realized
that your engine was actually doing that
which is a good thing so it actually
works which is like it's pretty insane
to me
so to summarize JIT compilation of
JavaScript you you're relying on the
profile information that you collect
while you're running into the intern in
the interpreter the the optimized code
is generated based on basically that
information and the key takeaway is that
your JIT code has to be responsible for
checking that the assumptions that
you're going to make actually all true
otherwise you will have bad surprises
and so basically problems whether it's
security issues or just X random crush
crush will basically arise when do gene
assume something that that is not true
and that's the old gamer security
researchers looking for for back in
those jet engines so now we'll be will
get to talk about chakras JIT compiler
specifically so so the chakra cheat
pipeline now it looks like roughly so
nothing crazy you have an interpreter it
keeps track of how many times function
has been called and passed a certain
threshold it will just schedule the
thing for JIT compilation so what that
means is that each function object has
an entry point it will swap that entry
point for to a func that basically will
schedule JIT compilation the interesting
note is that compilation happens out of
process in edge basically they move the
old JIT compiler to its own process so
that the content process can have
arbitrary code guard which prevents
mapping read write execute memory and
basically when code generation is done
the JIT server will basically like
notify the content process and you will
change the entry point to the native
code address so the next time the
function is called you will be actually
running the cheat code chakras only what
one JIT compiler which is two-tiered so
the two names are simple JIT and forge
it for the purpose of this talk will
only focus on forge it because like
simple JIT is not super interesting from
a security researcher point of view it's
pretty standard it operates on a control
flow graph and crystal maya which is
right infront functions by code the
interesting bit here is that the byte
code is basically as a format that's
optimized for the interpreter use case
which might not be the best the best
thing for the JIT compiler so it like
you will find in other engines that you
might have a basically or transpiling
face from like the interpreter bytecode
to an IR that's most suited for a JIT
compiler and the made steps of
computation are roughly so I have the
list here you basically build the IATA
sees ir build the face then you do the
inline phase it always happens quite
early in the process because inlining
allows for further optimization so if
you look at other jet engines you
probably see that happens super early in
the process then the build phase which
basically builds the control flow graph
and then we have the global face so it's
short for global optimizer it's where
most of the magic happens and what we'll
be focusing on and then you have other
faces and other phases and which
basically start to be machine dependent
up until the lower phase everything is
done independently of the architecture
we're dealing with to some extent and
yeah as I said like the global team ISO
is what interests us the most if you're
going to look for bug I've looked for
work more than likely that's what you
that's what you've looked at because
that's where most of the bugs are Sri
lying so I have some example once again
I'm I do apologise for the back for the
back of the room I hope she'll be able
to foul so here basically we'll see two
examples on the left I have two
JavaScript code here I have a simple
addition function that we talked about
just returns the sum of the addition of
the two parameters you give it x and y
and the function is called with integer
parameter and on the right we have
basically what is generated by the JIT
compiler with some kind of high-level
assembly and I'll walk through what is
generated so that you know I can
highlight some of the concepts I talked
about so here highlighted in red you
have the intermediate representation of
the of the instruction that we are
looking at if you can if you cannot see
on the right the instructions basically
called add a which is basically you know
add those two things s2 and s3 which are
symbols which basically represents the
parameters x and y
and the addition of that is put into s0
which is the special symbol for the
return value and I don't know if you can
see but like the symbol of an annotation
between brackets which is likely can be
tagged value integer and this is what
comes from the profiling phase you know
this is the profiling information that
we got from the interpreter saying the
thing can be a tag value and some kind
of hints that says like it should be an
integer so the first thing that code
does in terms of assembly it actually
checks that x and y actually integers
the way it does that is that as I said
integers are represented with the 48 bit
set so it will just shift the value to
the right with a certain constant do a
binary or on the two and compare that to
a constant so it it's a cute
optimization to basically check the the
two in one with one one snippet of
assembly and basically that fails we can
see that we have some jumps to that
label for f---ing and on that table for
we basically see that does a call
operation at full and this is the slow
path I was talking about you know in
case where nothing which tagged integer
the code we generated is basically
garbage and not going to be it's
basically either going to be faulty in
terms of semantics or you know 14th also
if it will crash the process so here we
have to go back into the interpreter and
this is exactly what we're looking at
now calling up at full we'll actually go
back to the interpreter for that
particular thing but we see that we
written afterwards right like you know
so this is what I was talking about you
know slow path it's not ideal by still
still okay and here highlighted I had to
code in case the assumption like the
assumption actually was true which is
that the two things were actually
integer and then we can see that it's
pretty straightforward just does like an
add operation in X 64 put that into the
return register and we're basically done
so the interesting thing just here is
basically if the check is successful
then we basically only have like seven
to eight or seven years structures that
are that are being run so you know from
the addition thing which is like you
know ten high-level operations in the
standard we actually have something
which is like seven to eight assembly
instructions so so that's why it gets
super fast
now I have the same thing but this time
with an object to illustrate other
concepts I talked about the function is
also an addition function but this time
instead of having two parameters you
only give it
which is an object and dad's property
X&Y and I call it repeatedly with an
object that has those two properties x
and y but the same layout this is the
important thing so the interpreter will
basically profile will have profile
information that those the function was
called with only one type of object and
will optimize based on that so we'll
look once again at what was generated to
illustrate some of the concepts so the
first thing we do is check if we are
dealing with with a pointer so once
again it's pretty simple as I said a
pointer will have the the upper
seventeen bits cleared so the first
thing it does it's it shifts the value
right by 48 checks that the thing is
actually zero and if it's not then we
see that we have a call to something
called save all registers and bailout
and that basically means like I'm not
able to end all that type of parameter
like this has to go back into the
interpreter and this is like the really
really costly thing that you want to
avoid if you like trying to write
performant JavaScript code then
basically like another interesting thing
to see if you're looking at chakra
specifically is that the annotation was
the thing likely can be a tag value with
hint object but since we actually now
check that the thing was actually not a
tag value we can see that the annotation
has changed and now it's marked as being
likely object so this illustrates the
concept I will talk a bit more later on
where basically based on what we've run
so far we have updated type information
which is more refined here we know we
are dealing with pointer which is most
likely a regular javascript object and
here basically we basically we have to
check for the type we basically fetch
the type of the object of the javascript
object and we check that its value is
equal to the one we profile here we have
another slow path as I said which is if
the type is not the same maybe for some
reason it still it still is equivalent
in terms of where the properties are
stored so we might have two different
type objects but property X's are top
set 0 pop two eyes that upset one in
which case we can use the jet code so we
basically try to salvage things instead
of painting out if we cannot reach as VR
and here we get to the real interesting
part which is if the checks were
actually successful then we we know
precisely
property excess Todd so here we have a
direct memory access to fetch property X
so we fetch from offset 16 which is
where the property X will be and now
when we fetch all that Y we see that we
only have one assembly instruction which
is this time fetch from up set 24 of the
object which is where property y will be
so the interesting thing here is that
once again if all the assumptions
actually held true then you don't
execute a lot of assembly instruction to
actually check that the thing is correct
and then you have two memory direct
memory access to fetch the object
property itself and also we can also
note that for the second property access
we don't run the checks again which is
pretty smart right because we know that
in between the two instructions the type
shouldn't have changed so we don't have
to recheck again the other thing is
actually a pointer and that this is of
the type repo file and I'll try to
explain a bit how basically chakra still
does it so most of the magic magic
happens in the global optimizer it's a
free pass process on the CFG one
backward pass one forward path and
another backward pass which is called
the desktop as the backward pass
algorithm is in a backward pass dot CPP
if you want to look at it it's about
nine thousand lines of code and the
forward pass is in a bunch of files that
are prefixed with glob opt and this is
about 30,000 lines of code so as you can
guess this is what we really care about
and the entry point is in globs
optimized if you want to to look at it
yourself so the backward pass is not the
most interesting for us the algorithm in
essence is pretty simple you go over
each block backwards which for each
block you go with over inch instructions
backward information is gathered for
each block and every time you start
processing a new block you merge the
information of all the success of block
that show that you've already processed
and it can perform some like simple
optimization like instruction rewriting
and that sort of stuff is not like from
from security standpoint it's not
important for us and the forward pass so
I will spend some time on that because
what we this is what we really care
about the algorithm is the reverse so
you go the each block of the CFG forward
and for each block you go over each
instruction forward and same thing
data is gathered for each block and
every time you start processing a new
block you basically merge the
information that you have
from all the success of luck so
sometimes you have one one block but
sometimes you have multiples who have to
you have to merge information and this
is what basically will perform most of
the magic that will lead to really
optimized code and here I have an
example that I want to walk you through
it's really minimalist based kind of to
give you a feel of you know how things
are performed in the forward pass if you
want to look at the code yourself and
this is also basically what you will see
in other engines to some extent as well
so here I have the same function edition
with an object and on the right we have
the intermediate representation of that
function which is basically three
intermediate instructions to load fields
so load property X load property Y and
add the two together and this is the
output right before we do the forward
pass and after the forward pass we have
this thing on the right that's totally
unreadable like took me like four months
to be able to decipher it and it's
redacted like it's actually even more
obscure than not in reality the thing
here I want to show you is that
basically for some reason like the thing
has been completely transformed and we
have a lot more of annotations going on
and stuff right so like you know a lot
of things actually took place in the
forward pass and the question is what
actually happened here so I can't afford
to try to highlight what happens so as I
said you know the forward pass will go
over each instruction each instruction
will basically go through that function
which is called opt instruction and opt
instruction will basically call a whole
bunch of function like 30 to 40 faculty
passing that instruction and all the
methods in the forward pass are only
going to deal with like a subset or for
the ir instruction that exists so you
have switch statements everywhere and
one of those function is called
optimized tag checks and if we look at
the code then we'll see that we
basically have a switch statement and we
actually have a case for when the opcode
is a load field which is what we're
dealing with now so like that function
actually we'll be able to do some things
on that on that particular instruction
so if we look further at the code
there's a bunch of things happening
first of it retrieves all the type
information it has for that particular
value at the block we're dealing with
and then we can see that highlighted on
on the right we have a check an if
statement if value type can be tagged
value and if this is true then we
execute new code and the first time we
run through that thing it will actually
be true because we we profiled that the
thing can you know
it's most likely an object by still can
be a type value because we we don't have
any certainty at this stage so the check
is true and basically execute do two
things which is the first one will
insert a new instruction which is Baylon
not object this is what we've seen
before the first check that you saw at
the beginning where you know it checks
that the thing is an object and if not
just completely bails out and then we
update the value type because now since
we inserted a check to check that the
thing is actually an object we know that
going forward the thing is most likely
like it's definitely a pointer so we
updating the thing it cannot be a tag
value anymore and now the cool thing is
that when you process the second load
filled instruction you end up following
the same code path but this time the
check will actually return false and
this is to highlight the fact that the
forward pass basically every time it
deals with an instruction all the
methods will be either able to refine
the type information which will lead to
more optimization or in some cases they
will have to loosen type information
because you know things can your jaw
receives the complex language you have
callbacks and everything so you have to
be mindful of that so there's of course
a lot more happening my hope is that
this example kind of gives you gives you
a rough idea of you know like how things
are done you have to keep in mind that
it's like 30,000 lines of code so you
know like there's a lot of methods that
deal with only certain instruction the
load field one i alighted is probably
one of the simplest operation and yeah
it's to give a rough idea basically and
I'll introduce two key concept that I
use throughout the chakra JIT compiler
to basically perform the optimization
right now so the first one is called
symbol liveness if you've done like some
data flow analysis and surprised you you
probably know that term
it's what the chakra team uses as lingo
as well so you will find those words in
the code and we take the same example
like you know we we add to object
properties together and here property X
will be in in my oak slots array at
offset zero property I will be in my
Oaks
sorry out of that one and if what you
expect from your compiler is that the
compiler will be smart and you will see
that it will dereference the same array
twice at two different offsets so you
expect that the compiler will only load
the array once the array pointer once
and then just the reference that two
times so you probably expect assembly
code that's as close as what I have here
so how does the forward pass is able to
do that is basically using symbol
lightness when it's well optimized the
first property access or dot X it will
basically set the symbol associated with
the odds lots point of oh as life going
forward and what that means is that with
that information when we are when we
deal with the second instruction we are
now able to see oh this thing is live so
when we generate the code this thing is
live I don't have to actually read it I
can just reuse the value that was there
already and this is how the JIT compiler
is able to you know come up with this
kind of optimization when you're when
you access the same memory over over and
over again
now the counterpart to that is that if
we change the example slightly and in
between the time we fetch property X and
we fetch property Y we have some
operations and those operations might
cause you know the the property value
array to be reallocated what do we have
to do in that case well you don't want
to use a previously fetched value
because you would then read from free in
memory on maybe you do if you're looking
for box but the chakra developers
probably don't want that and so you have
to use the counterpart mechanism which
is called the QL mechanism once again
this is chakra lingo that's what they
use in the code which basically in
essence is if you deal with an
instruction that might you know for
example cause that particular object to
be reallocated then the JIT compiler has
to kill the symbol associated with to
basically say going forward this thing
might have been completely you know
changed so you cannot reuse what you
previously had so that's basically you
know when you lose refined information
and that's basically when you when you
when you have those situations you will
basically miss some of optimization
opportunities and this is basically like
those two mechanisms like this is a real
basic instruction but this is what
you'll see throughout
God everywhere and if you foul closely
some of the bugs reported by Loki art or
sorry my bad mostly with her raise those
basics did they have to do with that
particular mechanism of you know type
information and not being killed
properly under certain conditions so
maybe if you look at those bugs again it
won't make no sense so far what does
sounds simple enough
right well the truth is all the examples
I showed you are reefs imple because
there's only one block in reality g-code
has to deal with complex construct in
terms of CFG so such as loops because
loops have information that that is true
only the first time you run it so before
you run the loop body and then you have
information that is also true all the
subsequent iterations of that loop
because you've run the body once you
have conditional statements which
introduce multiple blocks where only one
is taken and you have a lot of different
tricks to keep track of track you know
which viable elias's another viable in
case of bailout what do you restore for
the interpreter this is really
non-trivial the JIT also asks you model
perfectly what will happen in case of in
situations where wait you know it might
fall back into the interpreter because
you don't want the G to assume that
nothing is going to change when the slow
path might actually change some internal
data structures it also does some range
analysis for bounce check removal which
sounds really scary and a lot more
things happening so there's a lot of
things that can go wrong and now quick
start about the desktop pass which is
the last bus that's run by the global
team Iser once again not really
interesting cross is the same algorithm
as the first backward pass and it's
mostly there to read to remove what's
redundant such as like you know type
checks which might be redundant because
you know the thing is checked
higher up in the CFG and it's not super
interesting if you're looking for bugs
because most of the bad decisions that
will be taken in the backward in the
desktop ass will be as consequence of
you know bad things happening in forward
us so yeah so finally we get we get to
to a bug we'll walk through with you
it's a bug I reported to msse last year
it's a JIT bug of course I found it with
fuzzing which like I'm not going to
discuss the approach
at all because like it's uh it's it's
took it's too complicated I will talk
about that that's infiltrate if you want
to check it out it was fixed last over
say basically relies on what I talked
about legit not basically accounting for
certain internal things that can change
in jail with JavaScript operations so
here on the Left I have a have some
JavaScript code I hope so quite able to
see at the back and will basically walk
through walk through that together but
the thing is if you if you took that
code run it on a rebuild of chakra core
which is vulnerable well you're well
basically observe the following crash
well it's basically trying to move
whatever is in RB p inside you know what
looks to be an array access with like
our ax holding the base of the buffer so
if we look at the value of the two
registers it's trying to move one so the
tagged integer one which is probably
what we have on the left or dots equals
one so that's what the one comes from
and the RX two based on the the base of
the buffer is X 4 1 4 & 4 1 the with the
tag bit set and we basically see as well
in the JavaScript code that we actually
set a property to X 4 1 4 1 4 M so it
seems to be correlated somehow and
basically what you gain as information
from that crash if you're familiar with
chakra it's basically that somehow the
pointer that holds that points to the
property values has been overwritten by
X 4 1 4 1
so just a quick refresher that's one of
the slides that we saw right at the
beginning they have this layer that's
called the object header in line where
basically the property values are
stopped directly inside the object
itself and we'll need that because the
debug is actually related to that so
here we'll walk through basically what
happens in the JavaScript code so first
off we see that ridiculous function opt
and we basically have a loop where we
call the function repeatedly with the
same kind of scalar object which has
three properties ABC and we why we do
that is basically we want to optimize
the code for that particular type of
object now what happens is that in the
code we access some properties to set
the symbol as live this is not super
important just because you want the
optimization to take place so you need
it but it's not really relevant to the
to the exploit itself and then we add a
new property property on the object that
we set to 1 in the code and we
repeatedly you know property II set is
in a nonnamous function I call
repeatedly inside inside the loop and we
call that function and we set property a
all the time to X for one for one so
what I want you to take away from that
is basically like it's not meaningful
JavaScript code I doubt that you would
ever write that if you write JavaScript
for living but it's not ludicrous code
like it does not rely on any of the
crazy things that you can have in
JavaScript like proxies and suffered so
why do we have a bug basically why do we
are crash well the key is in how these
two objects basically differ and how
they will behave when you add property
II to it so to highlight that I have
here an object which is similar to the
one I pass to the function we optimize
it which is an object with like three
properties a scalar object and if you
look in memory how it looks like you
basically see that you have the property
stored directly in the object so you can
find the value in blue and now I had a
fourth property property data I said two
four four four four and if with the
reference memory then we can see that
two things are changed first off we have
the property four four four four which
is which appears where we expect it to
appear and then we have the second point
of the change so this is the type
pointer and of course it has changed
because since we added the property the
type of the object has changed but
nothing crazy like the key takeaway here
is that
a property - it actually doesn't change
the layout of the object now what
happens with this object which is a
scanner object but this time has four
properties so if we look in memory here
we have the same thing we see our four
properties appearing directly inside the
object as you would expect and now we
add the fifth property to it so property
EDA is set to four five four five and
now if we can if we look in memory how
it looks like we see that everything has
moved the second pointer has been
updated as before and now we have a
pointer where x4 one-for-one was we have
a null pointer where x4 - photo was then
we have X 4 1 4 1 X 4 2 4 2 so those
have been like moved by by 16 bytes and
if we dereference the pointer that we
saw up here we basically find the rest
of the property values so this is the ox
lost pointer we're looking at the finger
points or property values and the
takeaway here is that we still reuse
some of the in life space that we had
allocated because let's not waste it but
the thing has completely changed instead
of having all the property stored in
line into the object we now rely on that
external storage through the oxfords
pointer to store the property values so
maybe you you kind of guessed like the
the problem already so here when I set
property II on my object which has
fourth property which is just what we
saw that will actually change the layout
now what happens if the JIT compiler for
some reason failed to say oh this might
actually change the layout I better you
know redo the type check or actually you
account for that so what happens is that
chakra just like in under this
particular situation just like what okay
this is fine nothing is going to happen
well when we come back from the function
after we change the layout of the object
this will just like right at the direct
offset in memory as we've seen in your
example and that will write well
although it dot a previously was which
was which is where the observed pattern
now is so so this is basically the bug
in the nature and why we observe the
crash so the primitive we have is we are
basically able to corrupt the observes
pointer of an object with a JavaScript
value we have a couple of problems
associated with that first off we cannot
set it to a raw pointer directly because
every integer or double that we produce
from JavaScript will be stopped tagged
so that's not going to be valid address
we have the same thing than to write
arbitrary values
so we basically need to further craft
other objects and if you've looked at
any kind of JavaScript destroyed your
produce in Arriba firs and typed arrays
which which is the best gift that could
could have happened for us so now I walk
through basically the full exploit to
get to full read/write primitive from
that I will raise the exploit code so
like you if you want to check it out for
yourself later on so here I am an object
it's a global object I declare it right
before I even declare the function I
said to certain bunch of property to it
and I also declare a global array buffer
so nothing crazy so far and now I used
the trigger that I highlighted before so
I just changed to thing instead of
setting oh that's a 2x4 one for one for
one I set it to my global object
so basically when when we trigger the
corruption the bug this is basically the
memory layout that we achieve and right
we have object oh that basically points
to the to the global object itself but
doughty inside it and now when I run
auto T equals target I'm not able to
further crow up the global object and
make it so close point a point inside
the array buffer itself so all in all
basically like right after we triggered
the bug this is the memory layout we
have on the Left we have our two global
objects and my global object points
directly inside the array buffer object
and the array buffer object is very
interesting because it has a certain
field which is like the the buffer
pointer which points directly to memory
where you read and write from when you
declare typed array on it but we still
have the same problem which is even
though I could corrupt everything that's
inside the array buffer so I can
overwrite the length field to get an out
of one we cannot completely control the
pointer and we want to read and write
from memory arbitrarily not relative to
to the buffer its to the buffer itself
so we need again another corruption and
this is really simple it's only tonight
two lines of JavaScript I just declare
another array buffer and since I have
the ability to overwrite whatever is
inside the target
array buffer by just executing op dot H
equals hacks which is the new Arbor file
I created where basically achieved this
memory layout which is we have an an
array buffer of which the buffer pointer
points to the inside of another
and what that gives us as primitive now
is that we can create typed array on the
target or a buffer to completely corrupt
the hack sorry buffer and type Tories
are really good because we've typed to
race you're not dealing with tag value
like the integers or the doubles or the
floats show you're generating will be
stalled completely unboxed so that
basically gives us to read and write
function so these are really simple like
four lines four five lines of JavaScript
so if you want to read and write from
that point on basically the first thing
you do is you you write you declare with
you on the target array buffer so you
declare typed array on it the first
thing you do is you have a right out of
set 14 and 15 this is where the buffer
pointer will be doing that will
basically control the buffer point of
hacks and now you just have to declare
type torreón hacks and you can read and
write from memory anywhere so that
that's basically a full read/write
primitive you're not quite done if
you're looking to do a full chain but
this is not to talk about exploitation
on windows if you want to check that out
sock gave an amazing talk at ccc that
you should check it out which will have
much more information i still like
getting for real right it's pretty good
but it's what you want basically so yeah
you
[Music]