[Music]
you everybody for being here this is
super exciting blue Ezreal is awesome
I'm glad that you all made the time to
come out and see some really amazing
presentations that we've had from
everybody so far so so thank you so as
the intro said my name is Matt Miller
I've had the pleasure of getting to be
kind of on the front lines of how we
think about responding to
vulnerabilities particularly as they
have to do with Microsoft in our
products the team that I work on in the
Microsoft Security Response Center we
get to see all the vulnerabilities that
come in through our front door and we
get to think about smart ways to try to
actually rather than just fixing one bug
at a time try to find ways to really
change the landscape change the game
make things better for our customers and
everybody out there that's are using our
products and services so I've been at
Microsoft for about 10 years now and
I've been kind of in this role of trying
to think about how do we change this
landscape and so this talk is really an
opportunity to take you all on a sort of
journey through what are we seeing today
what how has the landscape evolved what
type of trends are we actually seeing
going from the era of trivial to exploit
stack-based buffer overruns to really
complicated multi-chain exploits that
are now the norm and what we see in the
ecosystem so we'll kind of talk about
some of those trends we'll go then from
there to shift about well what are some
of the challenges that we're actually
facing today and how we think about
approaching the problem space of
vulnerability role in relative
mitigation and from there we'll shift
gears and talk about how those
challenges are shaping our thinking for
what do we want to shift and focus more
on in the future to try to tackle this
problem space so let's go so for those
of you who may not be deep into the
vulnerability mitigation space I think
it's probably helpful to frame a little
bit of how we think about this problem
space and when you think about a
vulnerability ultimately what an
attacker is trying to do is they're
trying to take a vulnerability in some
software component and use that as a
vector for delivering some type of
payload to the target device they want
to run some code they want to do
something using this vulnerability and
so you want to go from A to B and so how
does this actually work in practice well
first of all there's lots of different
types of software vulnerabilities stack
buffer overruns heap buffer overruns so
on and so forth and what attackers have
done over time is they've really studied
those classes of vulnerabilities and
they come up with techniques to take
those vulnerabilities
hibbett them into other types of
primitives eventually as bruno talked
about in the talk previously they get to
this point where they get an arbitrary
read right and this is kind of the Swiss
Army knife of the exploit and from there
they go on to their generic exploitation
primitives to be able to run arbitrary
code data only corruption things like
that and this is kind of the final stage
that ultimately enables them to deliver
their payload so when you think about
trying to mitigate this space there's
sort of a few phases you can think about
it one you can try to think about
eliminating vulnerabilities just kind of
at the root cause
two you can think about trying to break
those techniques those primitives that
attackers use to actually try to go from
A to B from that vulnerability and three
there's containment so actually limit
what the payload can do when it's
running on the target device so these
are kind of how you can think about this
now it turns out today one vulnerability
typically isn't enough and that's
because we've entered this era where we
have sandboxing and so what this means
is that an attacker is gonna need to
have another vulnerability to actually
elevate privileges on the device and
this means that when we think from a
defense perspective we've got to apply
those same defenses to that privileged
attack surface and this kind of
continues you might have multiple layers
of containment
but at the end of the day you eventually
reach a point where you lose containment
and this really means from a defense
perspective either got to kill the bugs
or you got to break the techniques so
this is just at a very high level how
you can think about this problem space
now Microsoft's been at this for a while
we've been thinking about how can we go
about mitigating vulnerabilities and
we've been pursuing a common strategy in
this space for over 10 years now and
really the strategy boils down to how
are we going to make it as difficult and
costly to find exploit and leverage of
vulnerability and the tactics that we
think about here go back to what I just
talked about in the previous slide well
on the one hand we can look for ways to
eliminate vulnerabilities as much as
possible but you know we know they're
gonna be vulnerabilities so how are we
going to break those exploitation
techniques that attackers can rely on
and we know we probably are going to be
able to break all of the exploitation
techniques so how can we contain damage
limit persistence and prevent for
assistance and so on and finally if all
else fails how are we going to limit the
window of opportunity for an attacker to
actually leverage a vulnerability and an
exploit and there are a bunch of
different things that we pursued to date
in the
kind of different tactics so as I
mentioned on the introduction you know
we've been at this for a while how is
the landscape evolved in response to
these things so let's start talking
about trends so I am gonna throw a lot
of data and I'm gonna try to explain it
as we go through but this will give you
a flavor of how you know we look at the
landscape and how we actually try to
measure how the landscape is changing to
inform our thinking of how we approach a
vulnerability mitigation and defense so
first it's important to define our scope
what are we gonna be looking at in terms
of trends and when you think about how
Microsoft deals with response to
vulnerabilities we typically address
vulnerabilities in one of two ways so as
a researcher thank you for all the
researchers who have reported
vulnerabilities to us through our bounty
programs you send a vulnerability report
over to secure at Microsoft comm we say
okay yep interesting we're gonna open
nsrc case for that lots and lots of
magic happens behind the scenes and
either we ship a fix through an online
service update or we ship a fix through
a software update typically on update
Tuesday of every month to the endpoint
device now when you look at a very macro
level in 2018 about 54% of the reported
vulnerabilities that we addressed were
addressed through a security update that
we shipped to an endpoint and about 85%
of those were classified in terms of
severity and an impact of what we call
remote code execution elevation of
privilege and information disclosure
this is kind of the security impact of
those issues so for our talk today we're
gonna focus on those remote code
execution elevation of privilege and
information disclosure issues that
actually were addressed through a fix
that we shipped to an endpoint through a
product now what that's kind of setting
our scope now let's start to dive into
some of the data so at a very very macro
level what we're seeing today is that
more vulnerabilities are being fixed but
fewer vulnerabilities are being
exploited and so if you look at the
chart right here what this is showing
you is the number of CVEs that were
addressed by the year that there were or
addressed through a security update and
if you just look at this
it appears that on the surface risk is
going up you know there's more
vulnerabilities being reported there's
more vulnerabilities being fixed but
when you juxtapose that with the chart
on the right we're showing you the
percentage and the number of those
vulnerabilities that we actually have
evidence of known
have been exploited within 30 days of a
security update the trend actually
appears to be decreasing so risk appears
to be going up but actualized risk
appears to be going down so let's try to
probe this a little bit more so of those
vulnerabilities that are or that we have
evidence of being exploited it's
interesting to start to look into when
and how are they exploited so what this
chart showing you is here is the percent
of the sea bees by when they were first
exploited and they're kind of two phases
that we're looking at here there's the
phase of vulnerabilities that might have
been exploited as a zero-day before
security updates available or those that
were exploited after a security update
was available but within 30 kind of a
30-day window and what we see
increasingly is that if a vulnerability
is exploited it is most likely going to
be exploited as zero day and you can see
that trends been going up up up even
through 2018 and it's gotten to the
point where it's now uncommon for us to
see a vulnerability exploited after the
security update but within that 30-day
window so what this tells you is at the
other day it's most likely going to be a
zero day if an exploit is is found in
the wild now if we look at another view
we can look at the percent of the
Seavey's by the first scenario in which
they were attacked like in which they
were first used and what this is showing
you here is a few different scenarios
targeted attack a proof of concept that
a researcher may have released of an
exploit for vulnerability something
getting pulled into a public exploit
framework like Metasploit and criminal
exploit it's being used in the wild and
what we see here is that far and away if
a vulnerability is going to be exploited
the first scenario that it's going to be
exploited in is in a targeted attack
scenario by an adversary and more to the
point is when we actually dig into this
data what's interesting is that those
exploits actually typically target older
versions of the software they don't
typically target the latest versions of
the software so I'm sure from these
couple of slides a thoughts probably
popped in your head about well what
about all those zero days that you don't
know about and that's a great question
and it turns out that it is challenging
for us to actually effectively estimate
the number of 0 days that we don't know
about right but there's a few hypotheses
and kind of assertions that we can make
here
and so the first is that as exploit cost
has increased we believe this is driven
a cycle and to the point that right now
where this drives selective use and so
simply put you can think of this as the
number of times that an adversary or an
attacker wants to use an exploit
increases the probability or likelihood
of there being a detection at that and
so what this means is that attackers are
incentivized to minimize use and at the
end of the day if a target does actually
detect that they've been exploited by
this odds are they're gonna report that
to the vendor so they can be addressed
and as a consequence of this what's
happened is that this is the selective
use behavior has reduced downstream
supply because a lot of the actors out
there might not have the capability or
the means to actually go and acquire
these exploits themselves now the
assertion here is that over time what's
happened is that the economy around the
zero day market has actually shifted so
fast-forward to today where we have
Windows 10 which has a very mature kind
of update lifecycle you end up having
pretty poor return on investment for
trying to exploit a vulnerability that's
going to be rapidly remediated within
the ecosystem and furthermore if you
look at something like Windows 10
there's a fast evolution cycle of major
releases that are bringing new defenses
not just security updates and what we've
observed in the market is that if you
look at sort of the mass-market exploit
kit world it appears to have become the
case that they now struggle to maintain
supply and they've there's no longer
this pool of reusable exploits typically
or public exploits for them to use and
what's happened is that the costs for
them to acquire now exceeds their return
on investment and as a consequence of
that we've seen the market shift more
towards the social engineering type
vectors so macros fishing tech support
scans password spraying all these other
less sophisticated but in some cases
equally effective means that don't
require somebody to resort to an actual
exploit another trend that we see here
is that widespread attacks are now the
exception and not the norm and so if you
go back into the early 2000s we went
through a period of time where
server-side exploits for is sequel decom
so on and so forth we're the norm and
those have essentially gone away
similarly productivity apps and
weights for those that we went through
an arrow we're a widespread exploitation
was common for those and that's not such
the case anymore and same for browsers
we went through a period where
widespread exploitation was more common
for browsers and we just we don't see
that anymore and there are some
milestones in defense that correlate
with some of these changes in the
landscape so flashback to Windows XP
service pack 2 shipped with a firewall
on by default with depth some of these
other mitigation is enabled and that
sort of was kind of the beginning of the
end of the server side exploit era in
terms of widespread attacks Windows
Vista shipping with ASL our office 2010
shipping with Deb ASL are protected view
turned on and finally fast forward to
2015 with the edge browser shipping with
the sandbox ASLR Det CFG and so forth so
all these things have kind of added up
to a point where if we just typically
don't see widespread exploitation and
this is you know due to many factors one
being pervasive sandboxing stronger
mitigations reliable update channels and
just a you know the ecosystem has
changed as well it's not just Windows
there's phone there's mobile devices
there's other things out there for
people to try to target that influenced
this as well but there are exceptions
so for example in 2017 I'm sure many of
you are familiar with the wanna cry
incident this is an example of where a
you know weaponized exploit ready made
ready to go became public and this was
immediately something that folks could
jump on and try to go and attack folks
with at a broader scale but even there
that exploit didn't work against some of
the latest versions of Windows at the
time due to various factors such as
additional mitigations so another
interesting trend that I mentioned here
is that we now are kind of at this point
where many of the applications that need
the care and defend and protect
customers now enable sandboxes and
what's noteworthy about this is we can
probe and try to see whether or not we
see echoes of the effects of pervasive
sandboxing and some of our data so what
this chart showing you here is the
security impact of vulnerabilities that
had evidence of being exploited within
30 days of a security update by their
impact remote code execution elevation
and privilege information disclosure and
what the chart on the right is showing
you is that this is the sort of
execution domain of those
vulnerabilities was it at corner
vulnerability or was it a user motive
vulnerability and in both charts what
you can actually see here is that we see
an increase proportionately in terms of
elevation of privileged vulnerabilities
and also kernel vulnerabilities with
respect to user mode and so what this is
a hinting at here is that we see more
evidence of attackers needing to resort
and find elevation or privilege exploits
typically focusing on the kernel mode
attack surface now one of the things
that we really try to do is deeply study
the types of vulnerabilities that people
are finding in our software our services
so that we can actually look for
patterns and think about ways to make
things better and what's noteworthy here
is that at a macro scale going all the
way back to 2006 memory safety issues
remain the most common kind of in this
category of vulnerabilities that we're
looking at about 70% of the
vulnerabilities that are addressed
through a security update each year are
related to a memory safety issue and
it's worth actually drilling down a bit
more into that because memory safety is
a big category so what this chart
showing you here is some of the
high-level root cause trends within this
bucketing so stack corruptions heap
corruptions use after freetype confusion
so on and so forth and there are a few
things that are interesting to call out
here so one of these is that if you look
at the dark blue at the bottom of this
chart
these are stack corruption
vulnerabilities and if you go all the
way back to 2006 these accounted for
non-trivial proportion of the
vulnerabilities that we were actually
addressing each year but now in 2018 and
they're essentially a blip like they
essentially aren't there so this is kind
of an example of a bug class that has
largely gone away similarly you might
notice that there's a big spike kind of
around the 2013-2014 time frame abuse
after freeze and what happened here is
that this was an era where attackers and
researchers actually got really good at
finding use after free vulnerabilities
in the web browser and so of course us
monitoring these trends we went looked
for ways to actually kind of
categorically deal with this type of
issue which ultimately resulted in us
shipping a mitigation
called mgc the memory garbage collector
for our Dom engine and you can see that
the effect that that had in the
following years 2015-2016 where we went
back to more of a steady state in terms
of the percentage of use after free
vulnerabilities that we saw
now the other call-out here is that keep
out of bounds Reeves type confusions
uninitialized use these have all sort of
generally accrete increased in recent
years which is something that's
interesting for us to look at and the
last call it is that spatial safety
issues these are bounds violations where
you access memory outside the bounds of
an object these continue to be one of
the more common categories kind of
across the period of time that we're
looking at here so these are heap
out-of-bounds reason rights so if you
want to kind of sum it all up the top
root causes since about 2016 or heap
out-of-bounds issues use after free
issues type confusions and an
uninitialized use in that order
now we've talked a little bit about
exploited vulnerabilities and it's also
interesting for us to look at the root
causes of the vulnerabilities they'd
actually get exploited and the reason
why this is interesting is because this
provides us hints in terms of what are
what are the types of vulnerabilities
that may be easier or more preferred by
attackers in terms of going and trying
to exploit them and so that's what this
chart shows you here is the root cause
of CVS that were exploited within 30
days and the things that I'll call out
here are one use after free and heap
corruption continue to be sort of a
preferably targeted vulnerability class
in terms of exploitation but you'll also
notice that there's quite a large
percentage of what we classify as other
in here so don't fall into the the top
memory safety buckets that we see and
just to give you a flavor of what these
types of issues are they could be things
like cross-site scripting that leads to
a zone elevation if your film familiar
with Internet Explorer
they could be dll planting issues or
file canonicalization and and related
issues like that so those are some of
the non memory safety issues that we
actually see folks trying to go after in
addition to the memory safety now again
it's kind of interesting to drill even
deeper so we started from memory safety
we drilled down a bit more into the the
broad buckets of memory safety issues we
can actually go deeper in terms of our
classification to explore the types of
spatial safety issues that we see in
terms of the trends and what's
noteworthy here in the chart showing you
is this is the sort of distribution of
what we classify as adjacent spatial the
safety issues versus non adjacent
spatial safety issues
what does that
so in simple terms adjacent spacial
safety it's a buffer overrun
it's a mem copy where you control the
length and you write beyond the pounds
and the reason we call it a Jaison is
because the first byte that you go and
corrupt or access is always going to be
immediately adjacent to the buffer that
you're accessing whereas not adjacent as
one where as as an attacker you
controlled the index you control the
displacement and you get a little bit
more freedom in terms of that so the
call-out here and the interesting thing
to observe is that in terms of the
trends that we see here is that non
adjacent spatial safety issues are
increasingly more common with respect to
adjacent spatial lists safety issues so
again this is important from a defense
perspective because the mitigations you
might consider are different depending
on the types of spatial safety issues
you're dealing with so that was a quick
whirlwind tour of some of the trends
that we're seeing in the in the
landscape today from from our
perspective for the vulnerabilities that
we're actually addressing on the
Microsoft side now we're gonna shift
gears and kind of take that background
and use that to frame how we discuss
some of the challenges in the space of
actually trying to mitigate
vulnerabilities you know kind of
following that strategy that I outlined
at the beginning of the talk so we're
going to go through this section by each
of the tactics I mentioned so
eliminating vulnerabilities breaking
exploitation techniques containing
damage and so on and some of the
challenges that we face with each of
those so let's start with eliminating
vulnerabilities so the first challenge
is if you go back to the root cause
slide you'll notice that many of the
root causes of the vulnerabilities that
we saw back in 2006 we still see today
in 2018 and in fact most of the
vulnerability classes that existed 20 30
plus years ago still exists today now we
have had some success at eliminating
vulnerabilities at classes like nolde
references and the kernel have been
fully mitigated at this point but the
fact is that most of them still remain
and we still do see many of the develop
like developers making some of the same
mistakes that were made 10 years ago and
so this is a challenge that we're still
facing in the space another one to call
out is that we have seen that things
like the security development life cycle
the SDL and training can help like they
do raise awareness they help with the
culture and the philosophy around
security but at the end of the day the
developer who's actually
Ryann the code has tons of cognitive
load that they have to keep in their
head they have to remember the thousand
different rules the thousand different
ways that C++ might have undefined
behavior when they're actually going and
trying to write their software and what
this means is that developers are often
expected to self-identify to prevent
vulnerabilities and in many cases they
don't necessarily have the tools at hand
to really help them out as much as we
might hope another challenging that
we're facing here is in the moment
eliminative ulnar abilities is that
increasingly software is being developed
by disjoint parties and like different
folks may own a different component you
might have an open source library that's
written by somebody else another one
that's written by somebody else all of
which are coming together to form your
product or your service and what's
noteworthy here is that each of these
maintained errs for each of these
products have different security
policies different practices different
levels of understanding about the risks
in this space and this creates a
challenge for trying to have a cohesive
response in terms of what bar you're
enforcing around eliminating
vulnerabilities and at the end of the
day you're not necessarily going to be
able to expect that the collection of
all of the individuals involved in this
have gone through training have done SDL
and so on and another point to call and
I think many of the folks in the
audience probably already appreciate
this but it's worth noting is that at
the end of the day you know finding
every vulnerability is not scalable or
practical it is necessary and important
for us to actually go and hunt for
vulnerabilities today and we do and we
appreciate the researchers out there
that help us do this but it's not
sufficient to really kind of change the
landscape and as we saw you know the
number of vulnerabilities that are being
found and fixed continues to increase
despite tons and tons of effort by folks
in this room and folks at Microsoft as
well another challenge and eliminating
vulnerabilities is that every once in a
while pretty rare but every once in a
while we get a new vulnerability class
and one example of this is uh many of
you all saw the specter meltdown the
speculative execution side-channel
issues that popped up at the beginning
of January and in 2018 so this is
noteworthy because when a new
vulnerability class pops up it can have
significant ramifications for how you
think about the security boundaries that
you developed for software and it turns
out that something like Spectre
have implications for pretty much all
the security boundaries that software
has so for processes you know you've got
a process you've got a kernel there's a
security boundary between those there's
a security boundary between processes
that run as different users and forced
by the operating system
you bring a hypervisor into the picture
with virtualization well and now you've
got a security boundary between the
kernel and the hypervisor between the
VMS around the machine oh and on Windows
we actually have a technology called
virtualization based security which has
virtual secure mode where we actually
have kind of subdividing within a VM to
create another security boundary between
these contexts and oh and actually in
some cases a process might also enforce
a language based security boundary with
the software sandbox so think about
Bruno's talk when he was talking about
something like chakra
well chakra is trying to enforce a
language based sandbox for the code that
it's getting or interpreting but with
something like a speculative side
channels this has implications for all
these boundaries so again when you think
about vulnerability mitigation now
you've got to go back and think about
how do we mitigate this new class of
issues in all these different scenarios
so that's some of the challenges and
eliminating vulnerabilities let's talk
about now some of the challenges and
braking exploitation techniques so since
around 2012 we've been pursuing a set of
solutions that we've been trying to
design to mitigate arbitrary native code
execution regardless of the type of
memory safety issue that you have and
there are sort of a few different
pillars of this so two of these pillars
actually deal with trying to prevent
arbitrary code from even being generated
in the process and there are two parts
of this so one is a technology we call
code integrity garden which very simply
it enforces code signing for the process
so only dll's and executable lists that
are properly signed are permitted to be
loaded in the process and then there's
arbitrary code guard an arbitrary code
guard or a cg is designed to prevent new
code from being injected into the
process or existing code that's signed
from being modified and both of these
features are mitigations that we've now
shipped in the operating system now it's
all great and good to have properly
signed code that's immutable in your
process but you also want to try to keep
the code that does exist on the rails
and this is where control flow integrity
comes into play and there are two parts
of this
so one
is a technology called control flow
garden and this is one that tries to
enforce control flow integrity for
indirect calls and whatnot and the
second part of this is a shadow stack
protecting return addresses and whatnot
and this is something that where a CFG
has already been shipped in Windows CET
something that's going to come in the
future that that we plan to leverage for
Windows now at this point CFG ciga CG
they've been enabled for Windows 10 for
edge for the hyper-v view and worker
process and for the Windows kernel when
you turn on HBC ISO we've started to get
fairly pervasive adoption of this so the
question is how have exploits adapted in
light of these things being in place so
most of the exploits since around 2016
maybe even before that have followed the
same general script for how they go
about exploiting vulnerabilities so you
start with your vulnerability you use
your u you set up the address space to
place an array base or link at some
known location or offset within the
address space you use your memory
corruption vulnerability to modify the
array base or length using a memory
corruption and so this is what's going
to give you the ability to read and
write to arbitrary locations in memory
so this is exactly what Bruno talked
about in his talk previously you're
gonna then use that arbitrary read write
to go and discover where things like dll
and code or locating the address space
in some cases you might need to learn
where other things are located like the
stack so you'll go and gobble for that
with this information you'll go and
construct a rot payload you discovered
your gadgets you'll dynamically
construct a rot payload using the code
sequences that you found and now it's
the point where you're gonna actually go
and try to hijack control flow you might
corrupt a return to dress you might
corrupt a function pointer you might
corrupt a virtual table pointer any of
these methods to ultimately get to the
point where now you're executing that
raw payload that you've constructed now
after when you're a payload it's running
typically what's going to happen next is
you're going to try to actually
transition that and to being able to run
arbitrary code because it's kind of
annoying to do something fully and Rob
and now you're done now you're running
arbitrary code so that's kind of the the
typical flow but there are some other
flows that attackers might try to do so
they might take their arbitrary read
write and rather than go through all the
hops of trying to hijack control flow
over an arbitrary native code they'll
actually go and corrupt the state of a
security policy or they might try to
just simply read sensitive content
they're just trying to do an information
disclosure so when you have something
like CFG c IG and a CG in place what
we've actually observed attackers do are
sort of three things
so one simply if the target the you can
want to go after doesn't enable all
these things then that's actually the
most preferred route to go the second
one is that well since we don't have
protection for return addresses yet
corrupting the return address is the
second most preferred way and then third
is just going the route of data only
corruption where you don't actually need
to hijack control flow so you know as I
mentioned we have a ship control full
guard it's been there for a while now
and we've actually learned a lot through
this and one of the challenges that
we've actually faced here is that
delivering robust efficient and
compatible control flow integrity
solution is hard you know we do believe
that something like control CET until
control enforcement technology will
actually address the last major sort of
gap here in terms of return address
protection but even then there are
design limitations of CFG that make it
hard to provide a really comprehensive
solution in the space when you assume
attacker can read and write arbitrary
memory at arbitrary times so there are a
few limitations that are worth calling
out here so one of them is just by
design CFG is implemented as coarse
grained control flow integrity so this
means you can only call valid functions
but you can call any valid function out
of context and so this creates more
permutations for things that attackers
might be able to do given that valid
function set the second is that there
are places in Windows where there's
actually a dynamic construction of
what's equivalent to a CPU context so
when you think about how the DLL loader
work so when you think about how the
exception handler would the unwinder
work these things are actually kind of
modifying the CPU stage and will
continue execution in different ways and
it's possible that you might actually be
able to use your memory corruption to
hijack control flow there rather than
going after a typical function pointer
another one is in many cases CFG
actually relies on certain things being
read-only in memory for example the
import address table is one that we rely
on being read-only and memory and if an
attacker can coerce an application into
being able to make that read-only memory
writable then they can bypass some of
the security guarantees
that CFG tries to enforce another one is
reusing stale code pointers so for
example imagine you can coerce an
application into suspending a thread you
on map a dll you go and map something
new there and then you resume the thread
well whatever instruction pointer that
referred to is now it been invalidated
and now you may be able to execute
something that's useful that again isn't
kind of within the scope of something
that CFG which typically protect against
and then finally there's downgrade
attacks so when you think about trying
to coerce the application to loading a
dll that maybe didn't have wasn't fully
instrumented or it had another
limitation that could now be leveraged
in the context of this so there was a
much more detailed talk about this that
we gave at a defensive con that I
encourage you to check out if you want
to learn more but these are some of the
challenges that we're facing here and so
those are challenges with control flow
integrity but there's also challenges on
the data on the corruption side of the
house and that's that it generally
remains kind of a generally unsolved
problem at this point and when you think
about mitigating data only corruption it
essentially becomes equivalent to
mitigating memory safety all up in many
cases and in most cases it's not going
to be practical to try to isolate the
sensitive data or whatever it is that
you're trying to protect from being
corrupted in this way so I'll give a few
examples very quickly so one is the one
that we talked about previously
corrupting an array base or an array
length
well sure it'd be great if we could
prevent those from being corrupted but
it ends up being pretty hard right at
the end of the day protecting this means
not only do you need to protect all the
Rays but more likely the night you're
gonna have to protect all pointers to
arrays and then you're gonna to protect
all pointers to pointers and this kind
of cascades down into well now you're
trying to solve memory safety another
good example sort of a classic example
is that on Windows the way that we
represent processes in the kernel and
the identity that they run with is the
token field on the e process object and
one of the things that attackers will
typically do is use a data only
corruption to replace that token with
one of a privileged process like system
and they'll go and use this to elevate
privileges and this is another example
where it's challenging to mitigate this
because well a process is a dynamically
allocated mutable and frequently
accessed data structure and so it's not
necessarily practical to make that
read-only
similarly trying to take any process and
it into an isolated context is not
necessarily practical as well because
this is used pervasively across the
kernel and finally on the same subject
as the kernel as the e process token
field you can think about kernel objects
and windows and the access control list
and how we actually enforce access
control to those objects this is another
example of where you can actually go and
try to corrupt that grant you're less
privileged user access to a more
privileged object and use this to
elevate privileges so these are just a
few examples of challenges kind of in
the space of mitigating data only
corruption but you can imagine that
there are many other examples as well
all right so let's talk about challenges
in continued damage and permitting
persistence so one of the challenges
that we face here and there's actually a
fun discussion about this on Twitter
recently it has to do with trying to
limit the kernel attack surface on
windows and in particular one of the
challenges that we face is trying to
limit the kernel system calls that may
be available to an application in a way
that can be configurable and one of the
reasons that this is hard for Windows is
because we intentionally don't want
applications to take dependencies on the
system calls that we use under the hood
we want to be able to change this this
is one of the reasons that Windows has
been so successful is we've had the
ability to change some of the
implementation guts under the hood and
retain application compatibility so
trying to extend that into a space that
allows applications to restrict system
calls is a challenge but we do have some
alternatives so one is virtual
virtualized containers like Windows
Defender application guard actually
provide a pretty good and useful
alternative to trying to do this type of
system call filtering because they
actually just shove the whole kernel
into a virtual machine and now you've
actually restricted that kernel surface
another challenge that we face here is
what we talk all kind of efficient and
finer grained compartmentalization and
one of the reasons this is a challenge
is if you think about something like
control flow guard where we'd really
like to be able to isolate the loader
and the exception handler and the
unwinder well practically speaking it's
harder to isolate something more than a
process today and this is one of the one
of the things that makes it hard for us
to actually go and try to address some
of those limitations and furthermore
when you think about trying to adapt
software to finer grained
compartmentalized environment
most the designs and implementations
that exist today were aren't really
easily portable to kind of this concept
of running in a more fine-grained
compartment and the third challenge here
is that they're increasing tensions
between the desire to have high density
and performance on one hand and having
sort of hostile multi-tenant isolation
on the other hand concrete examples here
are when you think about a web browser
or you think about a container you want
to be as highly dense as possible for
the performance of the system but you
also want to have hostile multi-tenancy
to guarantees for the web browser you
don't want sites on the web to be able
to influence each other and for
containers you don't want tenants
running in different containers to be
able to influence each other and as a
concrete example one of the challenges
here if you think about again
speculative side channels and the
mitigations here these have had an
effect on density with the the need for
side isolation to move sites into their
own processes the need for core
isolation to actually mitigate things
like l1 Terminal fault and the overhead
that's placed on things like context
switching so these are some other
challenges that are being faced in this
space so challenges in terms of limiting
the window of time to exploit so one of
the challenges here is that when you
think about something like long term
support this tends to be at odds and
have issues with the evolving threat
landscape so long term support is great
for customers but at the same token when
you think about how the landscape
evolves it becomes challenging for some
of the older versions of software to
actually be able to to mitigate the
threats of today that weren't there
tomorrow and that's you know in large
part because advancements in defense and
some of the big mitigations that may
come in future versions of a product
aren't necessarily or likely to be
brought back to older versions and yeah
so this is one of the challenges that we
face here another challenge which has
been a theme here at blue hat Israel is
that comes back to supply chain and this
is in particular has to do with software
supply chain so when you think about the
world of open source software and the
many interlinked dependencies and the
actual update lifecycle for these
components this creates a challenge in
terms of how you think about trying to
limit the window of time to exploit a
vulnerability
so we're increasingly in a space where
applications and services have taken a
dependency many folks have taken
dependencies on various open source
projects and when you think about the
scenario where there's a vulnerability
in those and one of those components
coordinating the you know the mitigation
of that issue amongst all the folks that
depend on it is an increasing challenge
for the industry at large so those are a
few of the challenges so let's think
about those trends let's think about
those challenges and now start to think
more about how might we look at this
differently how might we try to change
our thinking and how we want to approach
the space of vulnerability mitigation
going forward so to start this out let's
ask the question what should software
development look like in the future just
what should look like should it still be
easy for developers to make the mistakes
they do today
no I don't think we really want that
should software and service vendors
still be fixing a non-trivial number of
vulnerabilities hopefully not should
consumers and businesses still be
concerned about the risk associated with
software vulnerabilities again you know
I don't think so and so really we kind
of land on this question of what can we
do to actually get to a point where
we're done with vulnerabilities how can
we actually try to realistically
approach this space so that you know
however many years from now we actually
are at a state where these really aren't
major issues for us so what what does
done mean so the sort of concept had
done is something that John Lambert if
you know him from Microsoft actually
challenged us to think about here a few
years ago and when we think about what
done means done is basically equivalent
to software vulnerabilities just aren't
a significant problem anymore doesn't
mean we've gotten to zero
vulnerabilities it means that they're
just not a significant problem and if
you look at this from the lens of say a
customer well from the customers
perspective you know this means there's
you know pretty minimal risk of them
actually being attacked by a
vulnerability and the security updates
that they actually deal with today all
right become uncommon they're not
disruptive you know they aren't really
something that people have to
consciously think about for attackers
what this means is that exploitable
vulnerabilities are uncommon you know
there may still be vulnerabilities but
you know they shouldn't really be
exploitable and furthermore exploit
those vulnerabilities is simply not
economically viable anymore even to some
of the big players that exist today and
for vendors if you think about like
somebody like Microsoft for example the
total cost of secure software and
development should start to become less
and less and more minimal over time and
so as I said you know we don't have to
get to zero vulnerabilities to get to
done and there are other challenges like
for instance we've talked a lot about
memory safety today but there are other
classes of issues like design and logic
clause which are admittedly much more
complex to think about how you're going
to tackle those in terms of a getting to
done State and those will require more
thought but they can sort of fit in with
this philosophy as well and getting to
done doesn't mean everybody's done at
once it doesn't mean we wake up tomorrow
and the entire software industry is done
it could mean that well for this
particular application or this
particular service you've kind of
achieved this state with these
properties and obviously there's tons of
challenges here but you know if we think
about what we need for the software
industry and what we need to achieve
going forward you know I think it's
necessary that we challenge ourselves to
approach this state so how might we
think about moving the needle more
towards getting to done and so the
mitigation tactics that I started out
the presentation with they're still
completely relevant they are absolutely
still useful for how we think about
approaching this problem space but
really more what we want to try to think
about is how do we tune our strategic
objective here and really it comes down
to how can we shift the goalposts from
increasing cost and difficulty which how
do you know when enough is enough
toward that state of actually getting to
done so I'll give a few examples here
just as a high level of how you might
think about tuning some of those tactics
so one example is again we've talked a
lot about eliminating vulnerabilities so
one opportunity here is actually focus
more attention on how do we make unsafe
code safer and we've been doing this for
a while now but there's more that we can
do here and this is again how can we
eliminate common classes and memory
safety vulnerabilities and there are
various ways that we can actually try to
do this we can introduce more rigorous
build time errors that just become de
facto standard both you know thinking
about a Microsoft or more broadly a
niche in the industry and we can also
think about things like run time
prevention where we may not be able to
eliminate it
compile-time but we can deterministic ly
mitigated at runtime the section one
second one is a common theme and this
has come up many times in history but
really this is about thinking about how
do we seriously transition to safer
languages where it's necessary and
warranted and so this means not only
stop it doesn't mean stop using C++ it
means make C++ safer by default and it
also does mean using safer alternative
languages so you think about rust as an
alternative for safer systems
programming you think about something
like c-sharp for example for just
general application development and as I
mentioned you know we can make C++ safer
there's been a lot of work in things
like the C++ core guidelines which
actually do a lot of work to try to
provide developers with the tools to
make smart decisions in the space and we
can also make use of practical memory
safety languages and the third is it's
not all about security so we actually do
want to approach this problem from how
do we make things safer but how do we
also make developers more efficient and
how they do their work and so things
like how can we provide developers with
the tools to automatically fix
vulnerabilities how can we actually
improve the performance when you write
safe code as compared to unsafe code and
when you think about it really the
efforts in the space focus more on how
do we make it durably difficult and hard
for developers to make mistakes in the
first place while allowing them to
maintain good performance and efficiency
so I'll just highlight two examples I'd
love to talk more about this but we
don't have enough time today but I'll
highlight two examples of progress
towards this direction so one example of
sort of this concept of making unsafe
code safer is work that we've been doing
in the space of uninitialized useful nor
abilities so for Microsoft one of the
trends that we observed is we saw lots
of vulnerabilities being reported where
uninitialized memory on the stack was
actually being disclosed to user mode in
various places and the pattern here had
to do with padding bytes of structures
not being initialized because there's no
way to initialize them from the language
so unless you zero memory for the
structure it's never going to be zero
and so what we've actually done is added
support to the compiler and now built
the entire Windows kernel and all the
device drivers with this mitigation that
we called init all that actually well
zero padding bytes in these cases so
this is a great
example where we have now killed this
bug class which was about 50
vulnerabilities over the course of a
couple of years and now we just don't
have to deal with it anymore
another example again on this theme of
transitioning to safer languages this is
a great example of trying to make C++
safer and in particular this has to do
with leveraging again one of the C++
core guidelines technologies which is
GSL span and you can simply think of GSL
span is rather than simply using raw
pointers and array indices you use span
as a tool to provide you with the
ability to have sort of transparent
bounds checking for your code it
basically just turns a pointer into a
pointer and a length and it will do the
bounds checking for you and as a
concrete example of how this has worked
well for us is we've actually taken this
we've gone and applied it pervasively
across hyper-v and we've seen evidence
of after we did this later we discovered
vulnerabilities that had been completely
mitigated in terms of being able to
exploit them because we've moved to GS l
span so again there's a lot of work to
be done in this case
I'll highlight a couple examples of
where we're sort of focusing our R&D and
how we think we're gonna try to move the
needle forward here it's it's
eliminating common classes of
vulnerabilities
it's adopting safer languages where it
matters it's looking into how can we do
efficient and finer grained
compartmentalization and it is still how
can we have stronger and more robust
exploit mitigations because we know
we're not going to reach this kind of
done state overnight and we're gonna
need to continue to to make it as
difficult and costly to exploit
vulnerabilities while we're working
toward that and so we do believe that
and focusing kind of in these areas can
start to help us really address some of
the challenge those that I talked about
previously now it's important to
remember that there are other threats we
spent this whole talk focusing just on
vulnerabilities but there are a lot of
other threats out there and it's worth
actually focusing attention on
mitigating those those two so we can't
just have blinders on and say we're only
going to look at vulnerabilities we got
to look across all the threats and think
about how we want to mitigate those too
we highlighted that as the cost of
exploiting vulnerabilities has gone up
we've seen other vectors increase
related to social engineering password
spraying all these other things those
are really important too and so we've
got to think about those so to close
you know based off of the trends that
we're seeing you know we believe that
our strategy has had a positive impact
on helping to ship the landscape and
we're continue to think about how we
want to refine it there's you know lots
of the challenges that I talked about
today are not just Microsoft challenges
they're actually industry challenges and
so you know Microsoft and the rest of
the folks in the industry need to think
about how we work together to go and
tackle some of these and you know we're
super excited about the progress that
we're gonna make towards this space I I
feel like I have one of the most
exciting jobs in the industry being on
the front lines of some of this and I'm
really excited about what we're gonna be
able to do here and I hope you can help
us so that's it thank you
[Applause]
[Music]