[Music]
hello and thank you all very much for
joining us today for our talk hardening
secure secure boots on embedded devices
for hostile environments so together the
three of us Christophe Rowe Niq and I
have a lot of experience breaking secure
boots analyzing secure boots
evaluating secure boots and also when we
look at the public talks things people
have done in public we see for instance
that bunny who gave the previous talk
talks about hacking the Xbox in 2003 and
two hours ago we had the latest
installment of breaking secure boot from
the CTS Labs guys so after all that time
secure boot is still often vulnerable so
therefore our goal is to try and create
a secure boot guidance for people
designing secure boot so designing the
hardware designing the software of
secure boot people actually creating
this Hardware people actually write in
this code and people who then actually
have to take all that work and put it
into a finished product so over the in
the next couple of months we'll try to
release a white paper which we're still
working on which will hopefully give
quite a bit of guidance there however in
this presentation we will try to take a
little bit of an offensive focus so
we'll show some known attacks and some
new attacks and using those new attacks
we'll try to give some new perspectives
in attacking secure boots but also in
ways to defend it so I will give the
introduction I will talk a little bit
about secure boot and then Cristoforo
and I will talk about some attacks and
some mitigations and then Nick who's
behind me will give a demonstration a
live demonstration which he's still
trying to fix I think followed by a
okay so let's imagine a system an
embedded system without secure boots so
basically there's the system on the chip
inside one package it has a processor it
has some memory it has some code and
attached to this package is a piece of
flash memory containing some code and
there's a DDR chip so this is the state
when the device is turned off and when
it boots when it's released from reset
the ROM code will load the BL 1 into s
Ram and then the B r1 will initialize
DDR and load the BL 2 into it and so on
and so forth
okay so as we already saw this leads us
to some attacks so there are two major
attack of scenarios and that is one a
hardware attacker these solders this
flash chip 3 programs it sort of sit
back on or an attacker with software
control basically reprograms flash so
that's why we need secure boots so what
is secure boot and well luckily today we
already had an explanation from the CTS
labs guys on what's secure boot is but
just to recap it's basically the
authentication of loaded images and it
has a root of trust embedded in hardware
and for us that means that immutable
code and data are stored in ROM and OTP
so one-time programmable memory so now
let's try to explain secure boot so here
is the picture we saw before the ROM has
copied BL 1 into s Ram but now there are
also signatures so the ROM will first
calculate a hash of the BL 1 and then
verify it against the reference
signature so either an RSA signature or
as we saw with the PSP may be just a
hash
stole somewhere and basically if these
signatures match you boots and otherwise
you don't boots okay
so that's an easy explanation but you
know the real world is typically a
little bit more complex so on a better
device a typical secure boot flow can
look something like this on one end of
the spectrum you have hardware and ROM
and at the very other end of the
spectrum you actually have applications
and as you go from one end of the
spectrum to the other end some
properties change so first of all a lot
of privileges are dropped and we don't
mean just you know hypervisor mode
kernel mode user mode also things like
access to cryptographic keys access to
the ROM code itself and maybe access to
engines are drops or change another big
difference is that hardware cannot
really be updated in the field and
neither can ROM code while at the other
end of the spectrum the applications
might actually be updated multiple times
a day and the last big difference is
that there are actually a lot of
manufacturers involved so in this
hardware and ROM stage basically has a
responsibility of one manufacturer but
within that company maybe another group
is actually responsible for writing the
bootloader
then a third party may be responsible
for actually providing te OS and then an
original equipment manufacturer is
actually responsible for basically the
normal world bootloader and maybe
something like a Linux OS so they're
actually a lot of different interests in
the secure boot chain and all of these
parties and all of these interests all
have a slightly different perspective on
secure boots okay so the goal of secure
boot is to mitigate a number of threats
so it's basically to prevent
modification of code and data in flash
it's to allow you to actually have
secure updates and it prevents attackers
from
persistent footholds and it also
prevents access to assets like keys code
and crypto engines and finally it's an
important part of preventing attacks
from escalating for instance from the re
e to the T ok so when we talk about this
attack surface
we believe that basically you either
have a broken design or a broken
implementation and this basically
translates to as well also translates to
maybe actually having broken software or
actually having broken hardware yep so
I'll now give some examples of secure
boots having been publicly broken but
again the CTS Labs guys did an excellent
job this morning of actually giving us
and other examples so please also take
that one in mind okay so our personal
favourites of a secure boot ROM bypass
is the am logic so we believe it to be a
broken software design that is available
because of weak cryptographic options
and the bypass is basically a downgrade
attack from an RSA signature to a char
signature and as this char signature
contains no secrets an attacker can just
modify the code update the hash and
that's it so how could this have been
mitigated well first of all they
probably shouldn't have supported weak
cryptographic options and in general we
suggest that limiting the amount of
options an attacker can choose from is
good for security because an attacker
will always choose the weakest option
our second example is an attender switch
bootrom vulnerability and we believe
this to be a software issue that was
basically due to a broken implementation
and it's basically a classic buffer
overflow attack so in the USB recovery
mode there's this buffer overflow attack
which may actually just be you know
exploited using nor
all software exploitation techniques so
how could they have mitigated this well
they could have just written secure
software so I got complaints sadly
that's not an acceptable answer so they
should have tried to make software
exploitation harder so they could have
used for instance you know typical
mitigations like stack cookies s la CFI
they could have used memory protections
to enforce rights or execute they could
have used you know MP use mm use IOM
amuse so in 2019 I'm standing onstage at
a security conference and I'm talking
about you know implementing stack
cookies aslr and see you fine that
sounds a bit stupid but you have to
remember that most secure implement
secure boot implementations implement
none of these mitigations okay so I said
you could write secure software now even
if you write secure software you might
still have broken hardware so our next
example is fault injection on the
Nintendo switch and basically they
skipped the hash verification stage
using voltage fault injection so what is
fault injection well basically you try
to make glitches using let's say an
electromagnetic pulse a laser playing
with the targets clock or power and you
try to introduce a glitch so you try to
get that glitch to introduce a fault in
that device and typically we can model
these faults as let's say something like
instruction skipping so saying
pretending that this fault will skip an
instruction so for instance in the hash
bypass case perhaps the branch
instruction was skipped we have also
another model called instruction
instruction and data corruption and
basically this means that
perhaps when the instructions are being
fetched from memory one of the bits
falls over and instead of executing the
original instruction you're now
executing an entirely different
instruction Christopher Oh we'll talk a
little bit more about that later so the
key takeaway here is that fault
injection alters the intended behavior
of both hardware and software so you
know how could we keep mitigate this
well
I'll now give some software examples so
perhaps we could add some redundancy so
instead of checking that hash value once
you check it twice and that only if both
checks match you actually boots you
could also add random delays and
basically adding random delays makes it
harder to pinpoint the exact moments in
time when you need to introduce a glitch
and especially when you combine this
with dolt something like double checks
it makes it that much harder to actually
bypass that check you could also add
some countermeasures in hardware for
instance you could again add redundancy
perhaps you could use a lot of check
sums on things perhaps you could add
glitch detectors so actually for
instance adding light sensors to detect
that someone is shining a laser on your
die or perhaps measure the voltage to
ensure no one's playing with it and
finally you can also add non constant
timing for instance using clock
randomization and again this makes it
harder to pinpoint the exact moment in
time the glitch needs to be introduced
okay so this is my final example and
it's basically a fault injection attack
on the PS Vita so we believe that it's
basically a broken implementation on
broken hardware and again using fault
injection so in this case what they did
is they use fault injection to bypass a
length check and that means now more
data is copied in which again gives you
this classic buffer overflow attack
so how could you mitigate this well its
fault injection so you can use all these
fault injection mitigations but on the
other hand it's a software exploits so
you could use all these exploit
mitigations so I think at this point
we've realized that you know designing
secure boots is not simple it's not easy
but you know we also have to take into
account all these other constraints so
you know we need to initialize Hardware
as well we need to be aware of
performance constraints we need to keep
engineering costs low and we may need to
recover devices in the field and you
know additionally sometimes customers
have you know extra requests as well but
we believe it is very important to get
it right because bad security can be
very expensive so for instance if you
need to know the tape outs that can cost
upwards of a million dollars and that's
before you take into consideration the
extra damage you might have from the bad
publicity or the fact that you have
unsold inventory or inventory you'll
have to sell for a lower price on top of
which you'll probably still need to pay
this additional engineering time okay
with that in mind I now discuss some
public attacks and Cristoforo will now
talk about some new attacks
which the world has not seen yet okay
Thank You Albert for this nice overview
on current attacks which are say
up-to-date at the moment but it's
important to realize that the attack
surface here can be much larger than
it's usually discussed that intended so
we try to respond very bit more and to
discuss a few attacks which we think
have not been discussed before or even
presented or even
demonstrated before we're going to share
with you something which i think is
quite new and share for the first time
so the first one that I would like to
discuss is a fault injection on OTP
transfer there is one thing which hold
the attacks that Albert shared that they
do have in common so all the types of
cooler while the code is actually been
executed so there is always the CPU
executing instructions which are
attacked in one way or another either
through software bugs or fault injection
attacks in order to alter the flow in
the execution intend distribution on
secure boot but we are proposing here a
different attack which is attacking the
secure boot before any code is actually
executed at all let's have a look a bit
more in details to this attack so there
is one important chip component which is
heavily used in embedded devices
although not not necessarily in common
PC architecture which is OTP memory
which stands for one time for drama book
which is what is been also commonly
referred to as if users also bunny
mentioned in his talk so the idea is
that OTP is an ideal storage for
configuration data you have to imagine
that for example here you have flags
that might says if your secure boot is
enabled or if the stage needs to be
decrypted before being verified and
things like that
why this is not your storage because
it's one-time programmable meaning that
you can actually change the physical
properties of the cells that represent a
bit you can change at 0 to 1 but you did
not reset that to 0 so that is
permanently set as a module or some say
fib attacks for example that is
permanently set to 1 and this can
happens anytime in the device lifetime
basically even in the field you can
enable secure route and if you do in
this way unless you bypass it then there
is no way that you can disable secure
boot
anymore because that flag has been
enabled in the OTP memory so the main
consumer of this data of this
information is actually the ROM code
that takes decisions according to the
information which is stored you can see
here an example where our number 4
calculate ash and 5a verify image so
that's purification as less calculation
the image verification is only performed
if the bit 17 in the OTP shallow
location is set to 1 so this means that
there is the information which is stored
which allows to perform a signature
verification it is a memory mapped
location otherwise will not be able to
reference that point basically so this
means that there is a register which is
memory mapped at run time which allows
you to query this information and act
upon but it's a register so this means
that when the shop is restarted that
register is typically at 0 value is
cleared so when the CPU is executing
this code summarized as to populate as
already populated that that register
would do the lutheran OTP and it is what
we call OTP transfer it's a mechanism
that populates registers shadow
registers with information from A to B
so this transfer is performed in our
blood it is Hardware logic performing it
before the CPU is actually released from
the set and then any rom code is
executed for example in what order to
realize this as that this harbour stage
happens before the cpu lisman started
there are multiple resets point in time
in an actual system so when the sock the
system on chip or the system stars is
released from reset then the resolver
logic which performs initialization
tasks and only once the proper analysis
tasks are completed then the CPU is
released from reset and start executing
code fetching instruction from the
design location so that part Hardware
OTP transfer happens between a very
large time window when you press Start
reset basically and when the actually
CPU is started so let's have a look at
what happens there basically so we have
a typical occupied chip here which is
dividing in banks which is then
organized in cells and these cells are
the one that you can set from a zero to
one so it is a special OTP a block which
is just data and of course you need
something that transferred this data to
product called location which is an OTP
controller usually connected to the OTP
mainship with a bus which can transfer
between 8 and 16 bits which can be quite
slow so now narrow bandwidth and where a
common response protocol actually query
the logic on queries the logic on the
main chip in order to transfer data so
you have to imagine that our flag that
says secure boot is enabled travels from
the main chip main component from TP on
the bus until rise to the OTP controller
then you have to be controller depending
on the data which has been fetched
basically severely from the from the we
typically Siddeley from the main chip
actually transfer this data to the
intended Harville or including in the
shall register keep in mind that there
may be additional hardware which might
use of the people figuration and got to
be controller as the task of
transferring properly this information
and this information may not be
accessible to the cpu at all and the
CPUs not started yet
here but once the do information is in
the shadow register then the CPU can be
leased from you said I can access the
information over the main bus via the
memory map ad mechanism a question so
let's keep in mind that fault injection
can have the alter the behavior will
ship not only software but also hardware
so with this in mind let's see where we
cleaning we attack in principle while
the bytes are being transferred so to
assume that you have a 1 which is set
for secure enable so you would enable in
the OTP main if you probably time in
your attack you might be able to toggle
that bit from 1 to 0 1 is being
transferred to do TP controller or
change it while it's being processed on
the OTP controller or even while this is
transferred to the shadow register keep
in mind that the types have different
opportunities because the bus have
different speeds the
bandwidth of course and even information
may be transferred yes literally in
initial stage or parallel so it's just a
matter of understanding that even before
the CPU starts it you might have an
option for a change in this
configuration in the end so basically we
can affect the signal verification and
the stage encryption by modifying
bypassing the secure boot also the
encrypts your boot depending if you are
able to toggle only one bit or both with
one or multiple glitches here in mind
what is this important why I'm saying
one glitch because if we the transfer
happens byte level one the information
may be bit level so in that single bytes
you might be able to have both the
information regarding the signal
terrific ation and the encrypted secure
boot so basically this is what we think
is doable in our spins we know it's
doable we are not doing a demonstration
on stage on on this point but we're
going to share another one which we
think is important about the injection
encrypted to your boot without actually
having an encryption key let's see how
this is possible
so this is the silver verification and
verify there is the cornerstone on every
boot you have to relate for example to
the PSP verifying the next stage it
might be an H Mac comparison for example
or it may be an LSA verification but
regardless there is always a
verification point and it is always a
conditional it says you should go here
or yours over there okay one other
important fault models first what is a
fault model a fault model describes the
effects that a fault can have actually
on a system one of the most common fault
model is called instruction skipping it
assumes that you can cause instruction
not to be executed such as if you know
you fall to the right time you might
have the instruction which is being
executed at that point in time is
actually skipped
actually we know this is inaccurate so
from a physics point of view and from
computing system until we win really
know it's natural because it's very
likely that instruction or
modified or corrupted wine for example
they're being fetched from the memory
towards the domain CPU this is not great
but it's efficient because it'd be a it
models the behavior of the ship so he's
actually a behavioral model rather than
an accurate physics model what happens
this is sufficient so to the point has
been wider value adopted both by
academia and Industry so most of the
fault injection attacks that you are
going to describe or to see described in
papers relies on the assumption that you
can change data while it's being stored
for BFA or that you can change skip and
instruction so even if it's inaccurate
this can be useful for affecting the
clone code flow so let's try to see how
this can be used for bypassing secure
boot so the textbook tap is the
following you have your bootloader bill
one when the device is turned off you
just reflash in software or in Apple
sorry by software Tom Binns
and replace that with a malicious image
basically which is your payload okay
which in principle should not be should
not be accepted because the signal is
actually wrong so that verify is going
to bailouts I say I don't want it but
the point is that if you are able to
time that comparison that if you might
be able to at the assembly level you may
be able to skip the call to that
function you might be able to skip the
assignment two flags for example to test
registers you might be able to skip the
decision point and fall through because
that's what you you might be doing so if
you're able to skip that function call
then you will be just going to jump
annex uni the malicious image this might
be for example say a way of bypassing
the also the PSP secure boot by its
orbiting a the DSM a comparison reason
if likely or targeting the comparison of
the hash stored in a signature depending
on the are so again props to the guys
from city s labs so the point is a
glitch at the right moment and profit
there is a big problem here because if
BL one is encrypted then you have an
encrypted see you what do you think this
can be applied well actually there is a
bit problem and we are going to see that
in a moment because this there is first
decrypt of the image in memory and then
the signals it is checked this is a
quite typical approach from device
manufacturer and the reason is that you
are allow your loved to have one single
sign image which can then be encrypted
with device and cryptid specific keys if
you do the other way around you will
need to first encrypt and then sign and
add a signature different for each
device doing this way you first sign the
image then you encrypt it and when you
actually are doing that you first
stripped and then you verify the
signature so there is the additional
state step here level 2 which brings up
become problems a lot of problems for
applying the the previous attack because
you remind remember that we're putting
our malicious image in plain text in the
in the flash the promise that you don't
have a key now that would pass the
decryption stage so whatever you put in
plain text is going to decrypt it to
garbage and if you are going to bypass
the signal verification your code
execution is actually going haywire
because you don't control the code will
just be encrypted because you don't have
a P and that's the reason why usually a
file on the attack so attacks which only
rely on fault injection are considered
infeasible when targeting include does
your boot to the point that it is often
suggest as a countermeasure encrypt your
secure boot and then the attacker will
need first to the truth D and then
perform the fault injection we are going
to show that that is a misconception in
order to do that we are going to
consider a different fault injection
model which is instruction corruption so
before we assume that a fault could only
skip instruction now let's assume that
the fault can actually alter
modify corrupt instruction in a way that
might be useful to run for an attacker
so you know that instruction
as operands where the destination
register are specified okay
so imagine that you are copying some
data from the memory or from flash from
RAM and put that into a register like
load this information is 32 bits into a
register the point that is that if you
might be able to change that register by
injecting a glitch and you see in a
moment how this could be leveraged the
firmly new is a fairly new application
of this kind of fault model it has been
discussed first by in 2016
Nick Albert and Mark Whitman and we are
going to use this for modifying code and
getting runtime control different from
before where we all trade the existing
code flow now we are good really to get
control so let's see a bit the attacks
in detail here again the device turned
off before we place the plaintext image
in bill 1 ok now we are going to play
still the same image to the payload with
a with a tail of pointers or pointers
let a pointer to what well we know that
that code is going to be replaced in
SRAM at some specific address let's
assume that you know that address ok
what you have to do is that that sled of
pointers has to be exactly that address
so if that goes into a strum at address
10 for example is going to be loaded at
address 10 then your pointer should be
just a sled of 10 0 X 10 ok and the
point is that this is copied in sequence
you start from the first and then go to
the up to the end of the image in the if
you glitch during the pointers while the
pointers are being copied something
interesting can happen so if you
blistering that man copy that copies the
image something really nice can happen
because you can assign value that you
are copying so the pointers to a
different register and if you are in an
architecture that allows direct
addressing of the program counter like
our 32 for example which is exactly like
the PSP that we discussed before
at least that's what it looked like from
the assembly then you could have sign
that point which has been copied into a
register directly to do from a counter
and we all know what happens where the
program counter is set to a value
meaning that the execution flow just
immediately goes to that address correct
and what is there at the address it's
the start of the image in SRAM which is
our code so this means that if we glitch
during that copy while the pointers are
being copied the pointers may end up in
PC and basically we start exceeding our
code flow and what about the trypsin
signal verification well they're gone
because the control flow is ejected
during the copy
so whatever soft has been written there
whatever countermeasures been written
there double checks and randomization
and all these things is actually gone so
we are bypassing in one go the
decryption and the verification which
happens after that mint copy so
basically what we're doing here is that
we turn an encrypted secure boot into a
plaintext unprotected boot with a single
glitch and for which we don't need a key
because the image we're placing there is
going to be in plaintiffs we are going
to see these now in a few moments
you might hear some beep perhaps the one
on the front rows pay attention to this
because the system with this attack is
going to be found in a very interesting
way well first the timing is not so
relevant because your sled can be even
quite long so you don't have now to
point pinpoint one signals or
verification you just have to take the
right glitch while multiple pointers are
copied
ok so the timing is not so much a
problem so your figure can be really
precise you get full PC control why
because you are diverting the data that
you have in flash that you control to
the wrong register so you can actually
say to the PC go here go here go here go
there and you don't need a software
vulnerabilities for that so even if your
software is perfect and you harbour is
sensitive to fault injection you can
actually also do that one important
point with a clicker we discussing here
does not depend on how you inject the
glitch or Coast
thought it's irrelevant you can do this
with voltage you can do that with laser
with the M in principle if you are able
to do that also we draw half Merrill -
it's extremely if you do that during
boot but in principle the technique
could be used in the same way but way we
use also this technique last year in
order to escalate our privilege from
users to route and Duker to Colonel -
that Colonel call execution on a fully
patched system without a software
without any softer vulnerability so the
fault model we're discussing it is
extremely powerful powerful because it
bypass any software which happens before
so whatever is implemented is a
countermeasure after was doesn't really
count
well on this I leave the stage - nique
which is going to show how is this
possible if the tap is practical or
viable thankfully Thank You Christopher
so before we start I would like to make
one small disclaimer is that we what we
are targeting here on States is not
actually the world code so there's two
stages that are programmed by us and is
for demonstration purposes but before we
go to the other laptop let's have a look
at what we're having here laying in
front of us so we have the most
important device which is actually
capable of injecting the glitches into
the target and we in this case we use
the RISC er spider which is really a
swiss knife for between fault injection
attacks but nothing prevents you from
using easier to access tooling like
Colin's chip Whisperer for example so we
communicate with these devices in a
laptop where we have a Python framework
that allows us to control the hardware
and this laptop is also used to
communicate with the target - the serial
interface and in this case we're using
an STM 32 chip which is arm 32 and
actually this type of chips are also
used for products like crypto wallets
for example so even though our product
is a switch knife we don't even use too
many things we provide an arbitrary
voltage signal to the target that's
fundamental so what we need to do to the
target is we need to somehow remove the
original power supply and the power
supply I don't know don't mean the power
provided to the board would actually the
power that's
holding the arm core so there's
typically a VCC signal in this case for
this particular target is roughly 3
volts that we use but also because we
are targeting secure boot we need to
reset the device every time in order to
trigger the secure boot so we're also
using a system reset in order to reset
the device every time with a GPIO pin
but everybody knows that does some
hardware hacking that even when you have
a simple setup that the cables will grow
everywhere but this is exactly what we
have laying in front of us I do not have
the time to explain what all the cables
are doing but please come to us after
the presentation and I think we will
build on the setup during one of the
breaks that we can talk about it in more
detail so what we did in order to make
this attack is that we first programmed
a secure boot implementation and
basically what is happening here is the
device gets reset some hardware gets
initialized then po1 is executed and bo1
is actually loading decrypting and then
authenticating bill - so the the binary
data that you see there is actually a
copy of the bill - so as you can see
it's completely encrypted due to the
high entropy so what we did is we
modified the vo - in a similar fashion
as Christopher explained so on the right
side you see the bill - again and
whenever it starts up it will be loaded
by bill 1 it will still be decrypted but
it will be decrypted into garbage
because we do not have the key and then
the other indication of bill - oh
actually fill but what you can see is
that we loaded a few things in there so
first some knobs these are not too
relevant and then actually our payload
and as you can see on the right side
there is a string and that's already a
giveaway of what's going to happen and
after this code is actually the pointers
that Christopher mentioned and this
pointers don't point to the flash but
actually point to the buffer in Ezra
where these image will be copied so
whenever the boot device with a valid
image there will be some strings printed
on the serial interface so you see it
started via one that it's loading bill
to decrypting bill to authenticating
bill - and then it jumps to build - and
then bill - happily says I also started
but for the malicious image
bo1 still starts it still loads bo2 it
decrypts bo2 but you'll see that
afterwards it stops because like I said
the authentication of bo1 will actually
fill and this is exactly what we will
try to bypass use a fault injection in a
similar fashion as Christopher already
explained so we can switch to the other
laptop can I have the other feet thank
you very much
so here on the left side let's focus on
that first we see actually a signal and
this is the signal measured by the
oscilloscope and this is actually the
system reset that we use to get the
board out of reset so every time the
signal goes up the system is actually
released and the hardware starts
initializing so I can open another
signal this other signal is actually the
photos provided to the target and as you
can see I lied it is not around 3 volt
is actually I have 2 volts but it's
enough for the chip to operate and
roughly in the middle you see sometimes
this red dip in the signal and that's
exactly the glitch we are injecting and
of course we know roughly where to
inject this glitch because in principle
when you start doing phone injection the
attack window starts from the moment the
chip cards out of reset until the moment
you can detect something goes wrong but
we already roughly know this location so
let's look at the right side with your
interface to control the hardware I will
just briefly stop the updating so what
you can see is that we roughly performs
in the start of this presentation 9000
experiments we randomized declared delay
a little bit so we go from : from left
to right and then the glitz voltage is
the amplitude of the dip and the glaze
length is the width of that dip and then
on the right side you see that the
expected data is being returned by the
target is finalized with stopping so the
target detects that it actually cannot
attend to gate the image now when I
started again you will see that there's
different stuff going on
for example this purple one it's a bit
hard to read but what's happening here
is that actually a CPU exception is
is strong so somehow the CPU got a
hiccup and it printed some information
about the current state of some of the
registers but for the people that
actually heard the beep
every time you ready beep something else
happened and we ever looked at this hat
experiment and we see still that bo1 is
success we started but then directly
afterwards it does not print he expect
these links anymore we directly jump to
our payload so somehow we take the CPU
into executing a different instruction
that resulted into loading one of the
pointers that was in our flash into the
PC so I can show you that since the
beginning of the presentation we
bypassed this reboot implementation
roughly 260 times in roughly an hour so
it's pretty pretty stable for this
particular implementation can I go back
to the other screen again
so we shoot multiple ways of bypassing
secure boot whether it was done doing
software exploitation or a hardware
attack like fault injection of a company
or a combination of well our talk was
hardening secure boot for hostile
environments and so far we only
explained the offensive part but the
defensive part will really be explained
in more detail in our paper that will be
hopefully released early this year but
to give you an idea of the things that
are being discussed some of these things
are open doors but very important for
example you want to make sure that your
implementation is real design is simple
the more complexity you add the more
opportunity or the more opportunity
there's for mistakes to slip in or more
opportunities for attackers in a similar
fashion you want to make sure that you
minimize the attackers choices for
example we already seen this morning
that for some implementations the amount
of options you have in order to control
small parts of the scribbled
implementation can lead to particular
threats that can be materialized also
already mentioned you want to make sure
that you authenticate everything and it
does not only mean you want to attempt
dedicate the code that's being executed
but also the data that the secure boot
implementation relies on because
otherwise you might trigger
vulnerabilities which you could not
trigger if it was properly authenticated
and please remember you need to
authenticate it before you use it and
not after otherwise it's kind of useless
so like we've seen even don't want to
use weak crypto you want to make so for
exploitation hard the clicker is not
always working you wanna drop privileges
when possible because often an attacker
is after a particular asset and if this
assert reaching this asset requires
particular privileges by inspecting the
amount of stages that can access this
asset you decrease the size of the
attack surface also what we've seen
already in the field but also the
example that we shown that fault
injection is a real threat on secure
boot implementations and you see it
already happening in the field and
moreover it's always possible that
mistakes slip in but you want to make
sure you can fix these mistakes
if they're in silver and when you do you
want to make sure that attackers cannot
go back to a more renewable version in
order to exploit the vulnerability that
was identified in an older version so
what else you can think of well a mature
product has a secure system software
development lifecycle and this is
exactly what's important in order to
verify the hardness of a secure boot
implementation so you want to think of
continuous software review and testing
but more importantly for the hardware
you want to make sure that you test your
hardware because it's very difficult to
do an analysis of your hardware so what
the impact of a fault injection attack
would be on your hardware from just a
paper study where she can review code by
sitting behind your computer in order to
verify the robustness of your hardware
you really need to get your hands dirty
and start testing so to wrap up in
together with the presentation have
already seen this morning but also the
examples we gave secure boot is nowadays
often not obsolete hardened and
especially if you compare to the the
system when it's fully initialized the
typical software exploitation
mitigations and other features that are
used to make it more difficult to the
attack and device are actually not
implemented during boot attack surface
of secure boot is much larger than often
expected so one of the examples we've
shown that the attack service actually
starts before any code is being executed
and also during this presentation we
gave a few new perspectives on attacking
secure boot and by that I would like to
finalise the presentation we are very
happy to be here and if there's any time
left we are happy to answer some
questions and otherwise please approach
us we will be here for the remainder of
the event thank you very much
you
[Applause]
[Music]