[Music]
yeah thanks everyone
um
great introduction yeah thanks uh
welcome to our talk a brief history of
imessage exploitation
i'm sam
uh unfortunately ian couldn't make it
short notice so i'll be covering his
part as well
now for those of you who don't know
imessage is apple's messaging service
that they use on their platforms you
know when you send a message from your
iphone to your friends
macbook or ipad
this is
going over imessage
um
and yeah so
this this history or this story of
imessage security
i'm going to tell it in in three
chapters
um
i i only have 40 minutes so i kind of
can't go into much detail
but every chapter there's a blog post
for it you can find the link on the
slide and those slides end up on twitter
also
and there you can find many more details
okay so why is imessage interesting for
security researchers
well
if you as an attacker if you are able to
find and exploit a bug in imessage
then you can basically remotely
compromise kind of every pretty much
every apple device
without the user doing anything and
without the user noticing so it's really
kind of scary
and i think it's very
uh very interesting to look into these
attacks
but okay so let's start with the first
chapter
uh this starts in 2019
when
my team at project zero when we
developed one of these exploits against
imessage
so i go walk you through how this worked
now
before we can exploit anything
well we need a bug right
but even before we have a bug we need an
attack service so
some kind of of software
that we can supply input to that's going
to process that input and where we can
then look for bugs
right so this is going to be the first
step
finding an attack surface
how would you go about it i think the
straight straightforward way is
you look at how imessage works uh like
how the
how an imessage looks on the wire right
so when you like take one of these
phones you send a message
um
this here is what actually goes over the
wire
it's called it's it's a property list
it's like the
the name of this like format it's apple
specific but you can think of it like a
json
dictionary
i guess some of these fields they will
make immediate sense like p
that's the participants in this case
it's a two two person chat um
t that's the
uh the plain text message like hello
bluehead
there's some what looks like it's html
in there in the x key but it's not
really html it's
parse this xml is kind of weird
some uu ids to identify this message
but what's really standing out
at least when we looked at this
is this ati key
where it has some
what's called an ns keyed archiver
payload in it so it's like raw bytes
that they then go into some
some other decoder
so what is the ns keyed archiver if you
look into the documentation
it says nskt archiver provides a way to
encode objects and scalar values into an
architecture independent format suitable
for storage in a file
or you know in this case suitable for
sending it over the wire
now this is a pretty powerful
serialization format
it even supports cycles
so json for example it doesn't support
circles but this one does so for here in
this bottom
image you see
like an ns area ns is just the prefix
they use for these objects so you have
like an array contains a number and
dictionary and now the dictionary links
back to the array
so you have a circle and this you can
serialize just fine with this format so
it's really quite complex
it has a lot of
a lot of features
and so we immediately like went into
this as our attack surface this looks
complex
there could be bugs here
and now to make it even more uh even
nicer
we realized that one of these so there
were multiple payloads in these
imessages but one of them was actually
being decoded in springboard and
springboard is the main ui process and
it's unsandboxed so what that means is
if you find a bug in this format and you
trigger
and you can exploit it over imessage
you immediately get code execution
outside the sandbox like it's done
so this looks really good let's go into
that
so here's where we are this is kind of
i'm going to like draw a picture of how
these attacks work they look like this
the colors are a bit ad hoc so orange is
something that's required
red is the the exploit flow
so we now have the attack surface that's
the ns keyed unarchiver stuff we have a
bug i didn't mention the bug it doesn't
really matter we found a bug there
and we also have seen that if we can
exploit it we have unsandboxed code
execution
so now we're in the exploitation part
um and the first thing with these memory
corruption bugs the first thing we need
to deal with is aslr
what is aslr so it's address-based
layout randomization
here is like a schematic of a process
address space it can address everything
from zero to address hex seven
fff and so on
and
we now need to find a certain mapping
like a certain object in the address
space it's called the dyld shared cache
it's not really important what's in
there it's basically all the code
libraries linked together all the code
is in there
and we need to find it to then continue
the exploit because we don't know where
anything is in the process
so this is our next task
now why is this hard
so if you think about how a
kind of on an abstract level
how a typical memory corruption exploit
works it's these three steps that you
have at the bottom
so the first step is
you have to leak a valid address from
the target process right you don't know
where addresses are you have to leak an
address of something
and then you can figure out where some
library is for example
and so what you then do with that is you
have your what i call abstract payload
here
for example you might have a rob chain
that is just offsets
so that is your abstract payload just
that rob chain with offsets into some
library
then you take that abstract payload and
you instantiate a concrete one if you
will
right and so
you do that by adding those offsets onto
that address you leak and now you have a
real payload that is valid in the target
process
and has like the correct addresses and
then you deliver that
this is kind of what you need to do but
for this to work you need a
communication channel
between the target process
and the exploit logic
now in some cases this is not a problem
at all if you think about typical web
browser exploits
there the exploit logic is implemented
in javascript
and so it runs in the process that's
being exploited so of course you have a
communication channel you just read
memory it's the same process
but for us in imessage this is much more
of a problem because there is of course
no message that sends back addresses to
to like the attacker so we have to
figure out how to like communicate in a
way that
lets us uh infer aslr addresses
so how we're going to do this um
we will use something called delivery
receipts
if you've ever sent an imessage probably
have seen something like this image here
on the left
so a message it can basically have three
different states it can be sent
delivered red
red meaning the user looked at it
delivered meaning it got to the device
the way this is implemented
is that when the service the daemon that
processes imessages when it gets the
message it sends back
another message to the sender saying yep
this message i got it and then the
sender marks it as delivered
now this gives us an interesting oracle
because if
during the processing of our imessage if
the service crashes
then it never sends the delivery receipt
and so we have this like one bit
channel that says did it crash or did it
not crash
and this is enough to break aslr so
here's how
what we do is we construct the payload
from the memory corruption bug
that just like reads from some address
that we tell it to
right
and we send this payload over imessage
to the target device and then we check
did we get a delivery receipt or did we
not
and if not
then the address was not valid otherwise
it's valid
and so we then like we started some some
low address
maybe this one here and it crashes we
don't get a receipt that's why it's red
we check another one
aha and now we get a delivery received
so this address must be valid right
and at this point we just kind of do a
binary search to find the base address
in reality it's a little more complex
but the idea is exactly this
so in this case we you know try the
middle
that doesn't work it crashes okay so we
take the upper half again go to the
middle
this doesn't crash okay lower half right
and so on and so on um and if you do
this a couple of times then
you end up leaking the the correct base
address
takes like 20 to 30 messages
so i think this exploit took maybe three
to five minutes total it's i think
acceptable
okay so here's where we are
right we have the attack surface and the
bug
and we've broken aslr and what we needed
are all of these four things here so we
needed what i didn't mention at all we
need this shared cache to be at a
constant address across crashes which
was the case like the process restarts
but this thing is at the same address
we need the crash oracle
we do need some heat spraying which i
also didn't mention
and we need to be able to make repeated
attempts
so back then you could just send a
message get the service to crash 10
seconds later it would come back you try
again right so
you have a lot of attempts
so this is where we are final step is we
need a pack bypass
what is pack
pointer authentication
it's a
new wish hardware security feature on
apple's platforms
the idea is that you can
cryptographically sign
pointers and then verify that they are
legitimate right
and so this effectively breaks rob and
job and these kinds of
standard expert tricks
because they all rely on
you faking or
creating your own pointers into code
yeah
so at the bottom you can kind of see
how pack works very briefly like you
take a normal pointer the top bits are
all unused
you run it through one of these pack
sign instructions and that puts the
signature and the top bits
and then if you want to use this pointer
you
first run it through one of these
authentication
instructions
if that succeeds if the signature is
valid then the top bits are cleared to
zero the address is valid if the
authentication fails the top bits become
some garbage and if you then try to use
it you crash
yeah so this breaks rob
but if you think about it really
arbitrary code execution isn't necessary
for you
right like whatever you would want to do
after your first stage payload all the
functionality is there like the all the
syscall
functions also all the objective-c
methods it's all there so really all you
need to do is figure out how to just
call existing methods
and
this is not too hard with objective c
objective c is kind of very dynamic
and and the runtime around it
and so one of the objects that was very
convenient back then is ns invocation
which essentially represents like a
bound function call or bound method call
so it looks like this uh maybe a bit
weird if you've never seen objective c
uh but this makes an ns invocation then
sets the target object to foo then sets
the selector which is the method to bar
and then if you call invoke on the
invocation
this calls foo dot bar
right and so if you control one of these
objects
you can call whatever you want so
you win
and so this is the full exploit um this
is how it looked like in 2019
um
and uh yeah
so first chapter is over
let's go to the next one so what
happened afterwards we did this 2019
mid-2019
we sent all of this to apple
and they got very busy fixing stuff
right and so this is the next chapter
all the things that apple did in
afterwards
so
one of the very first things and this
happened i think
the only days after we
sent them this stuff
well they fixed the bug of course
but they also did a lot of attack
surface reduction and this is really
powerful because not only does this
like make this bug unexploitable it
makes all other bugs that are like in
the same area
unreachable and so they yeah they
basically blocked a whole bunch of this
ns archiver attack surface in imessage
so that's really nice
let's look at what they what else they
did
one of the
biggest changes is they did some
re-architecturing
for imessage and they introduced
something called blastoir
or messages blast or service
which is essentially a super tightly
sandboxed process that sits in between
the imessage processing and does all the
parsing so i am agent here that's the
demon that
gets the incoming imessage
and this
pretty much directly forwards everything
to blast or
blast or does all the parsing all the
p-list parting the xml parsing the
ns keyed archiver parsing whatever is in
there and then sends the result back to
i am agent
it also has
high level logic implemented in swift
it's kind of nice it's a
bit more of a safe language
but also this
also like besides sandboxing stuff this
also breaks the crash oracle
because um no longer is like the the
sending of the delivery received is
decoupled from the
from the it's not no longer happening in
the process that crashes right so if you
send a crashing payload blast or crashes
but i am agent is the thing sending the
receipt so
this no longer works right
and so they fixed this box here
and this already breaks the
aslr bypass
but that's not all
so the next thing they did is
the constant address of the shared cache
that's gone
they implemented some shared cache
re-sliding it's actually quite
interesting it seems to specifically
look for this attack where you kind of
probe memory around the shared cache to
figure out where it is
and when they detect you doing that they
just re-randomized the shared cache
so this technique is also broken
and also they stopped you
they
try to stop you from
subsequent like crashing a service and
then having it restart
quickly by introducing something called
exponential throttling
um the idea being well if the service
crashes once it restarts 10 seconds
later
crashes again
20 seconds delay crashes again 40
seconds delay this goes up to 20 minutes
and so very quickly you only get one
attempt every 20 minutes and so this
exploit from 2019
wouldn't have taken three to five
minutes it probably would have taken a
few hours
so still not terrible but yeah
okay so this already looks pretty solid
but then they also
try to to fix all of these techniques so
the 2019 exploit it would just
fake uh these ns invocations objects in
memory
uh but they fixed that by by assigning
them with pack so there's a pack
signature in these classes now you can
no longer
just create these things from scratch
they also did some hardening of these ns
invocations so
that also doesn't use doesn't work sorry
right um so this
this looks pretty solid right like kind
of every every aspect of this exploit
with the exception of heap spraying
which i think still works um all of the
other stuff is fixed
and so
you you would expect a new exploit like
it would have to be quite fundamentally
different right all of this is gone
and yeah it was quite fundamentally
different
so last year citizen lab
found
an expert
titled forest entry
which was actually used in the wild an
imessage exploit and they
found traces of it they found
a file containing the exploit basically
and they gave it to us and we looked at
it so we didn't write this exploit but
we analyzed it
again i'll walk you through how it works
again we have to start with the text
surface because the previous one is gone
okay
so
i showed you this image before right
where like blasto came in and how the
parsing works
it's not like it was obviously a
simplification uh one of the other
things that happens is there is another
process called i am transcoder agent
which
does some image transcoding for example
so this one is important
now
what imessage wanted to do is when you
send a gif file so like an animated
picture
what they wanted to make sure is that it
effectively
looped forever
right so it wouldn't stop like repeating
itself so here you just saw the left
image just like repeated once and the
right image keeps spinning and so on um
now in the in the gif file format the
way you say this this is supposed to
loop forever
is to set some loop counter to zero
right so you see kind of a hex dump of
these two files the only difference is
one of them has a zero which means
infinite repeats and one has a one which
means one repeat
so that's what they wanted to implement
on the receiver side so you get a gif
incoming they would try to set this loop
count to zero
the way they did it is um
there's a helper function that would be
called by im agent when when it like
downloaded those attachments or those
images it would call a function called
copy jiff from pass to destination
and this actually
ended up
running in this im transcoder agent
and this transcoder agent it would call
a method like something read file
properties blah blah blah
with updated loop count
and then gave it a loop count of zero
right and so
this kind of seems simple like i mean
just you know read the file set the loop
count to zero write it back
but funnily or maybe not so funny
this is an actual stack trace from the
exploit crashing so from it failing
and
well you see it starts in imessage it
starts exactly in this copy gif from
from file and so on goes to the read
file properties it then goes into image
i o
which is their image parsing library
and then it goes into core graphics
right and you kind of see it's like
starting to do pdf stuff
why is it doing pdf stuff
and then it's going into something
called jbig2 which is a compression
format used in pdf so what you see here
is that this
seemingly harmless
call of like just you know take this gif
make the loop count infinite this ended
up doing pdf parsing
um so it's kind of like
iceberg um attack surface right like you
see the top just this top bit of like ah
this is just a bit of a you know file
copying no no
pdf parsing all kinds of stuff is
happening under the surface um
how much stuff is happening under the
surface so here's a list of all the
supported file formats
that image io will will parse for you
right and so the the trick here is that
i mean the the reason this happens is
because image i o it tries to auto
detect the file format so even though
you send something ending with dot gif
image io will look at the header and
determine ah no this is a pdf i know how
to
work with this right um
so yeah this list may be a bit
surprising right i mean you see the
i guess typical image formats jpeg png
and stuff um
but but just for for fun
raise your hands if you know what dot
psd is the top top right okay it's
pretty good so it's a photoshop file
um
raise your hands if you know what astc
is
okay there's like one person
adaptive scalable texture compression
i don't even know um
anyone know what mpo is
no okay so i mean i didn't either it
apparently it's some kind of image
format used on nintendo 3ds where you
could like because it has two cameras
you can take like some kind of
stereoscopic image and
yeah
i don't know
so it's it's pretty crazy um
but the point i want to make here is
this
this is not a like apple specific
problem right like this is how we
develop software in a way right like if
you are
writing a library you want that library
to be as useful as possible and so if
you're writing an image library that
means you want to support as many
formats as possible for your users to be
really useful
but then this just ends up
being this gigantic attack surface of
like these dozens of
of file formats right
okay
so um
anyway back to jbc2 right so that's the
compression
code in in pdf um this is the bug that
was ultimately exploited it's not really
that interesting it's kind of a standard
heap buffer overflow coming from an
integer overflow so
you have this num num symbols integer
you want to allocate some buffer to hold
all the i don't know symbol dictionaries
also
so you first figure out how many are
there so you add up all the
dictionaries
this thing ends up overflowing from like
4 billion to 10 or whatever
you allocate a buffer for 10
simple dictionaries
and then you copy 4 billion into it
right so that
of course corrupts memory
so we are here again
looks kind of familiar right we have a
new attack surface we have a different
bug
we know what we're going to end up with
or we're going to end up in an im
transcoder agent
if we can exploit this
and again we have to bypass aslr
and this time we have to do different
thing because the last
approach was completely fixed
so the first thing we're going to do is
we will
what we just call unbounding here will
make more memory available to jbc2
so jbc2 it operates on bitmaps
you can supply operations to perform on
bitmaps we'll see that in a second
and in memory a bitmap looks like this
v table
so on so on and then there's a width and
a height right and so if you just
overflow
corrupt one of these bitmap objects with
this heat buffer overflow you end up
corrupting the width
now the bitmap looks really large and
you can perform your operations on kind
of all of memory
this is a fairly standard exploitation
trick
just make some buffer look really big
and then use it
so the next thing is we need to
understand a bit more about what jbc2 is
so it's a compression algorithm designed
originally for i believe
kind of black and white scans of
documents
and one thing it can do it it can figure
out similar looking pixel patterns like
it might identify all of these e's
as being similar in this document
and it can group them together and what
it can then do
is just take one representative
like the one one e
and replace all of the other e's in the
document with this one
right and so now you no longer need to
store six e's you just need to store one
that's kind of neat
except that this can go horribly wrong
if it like replaces one character with
another that looks a bit similar and i
think this happens what happened
and so the way you can fix that problem
is by uh just kind of computing the
difference
between the
reference or the substituted e and the
original e right so here
left e that that's the reference one
that's going to substitute the others
the middle one is the
real e so you compute the difference you
store the difference which has a less
entropy so it can be encoded more
efficiently and then when you decode or
decompress the stream
you apply the difference again to the
substituted
one
so in this case this just needs an x or
operation
xor is not the only one
j big two supports these four kind of
fundamental
um logic operations and or x or x nor
um
and uh well
if you have these four gates you can
build other gates right like if you for
example combine an and
with an x or with a constant of one that
gives gives you a non-gate right the the
xor is a negation so this makes a
non-gate and now will the non-gate
that lets you build all kinds of stuff
like you can kind of build every circuit
from none there's a website where you
can go to
where they teach you uh how to
how to build like full full-scale
computer just from non-gates and then
write tetris for it
what they what they don't tell you in
this course but what i can tell you is
you can also
take non-gates and like build an im
transcoder sandbox uh escape from it
yeah
so nand is really powerful um
this here is an actual gate that was
used in the exploit so this is um
an adder
built
right from these basic circuits um and
so what this now lets you do is
because we have unbounded the jbc2
stream right we can now add
arbitrary stuff in memory together and
like perform logical operations on other
parts of the process memory
so how does this help us with aslr
let's go back to this slide
remember from before
before we needed this communication
channel right because
the exploit logic was running
on the server on the attacker's machine
and
the target process was on the device but
now with this um jbig2 like virtual
machine thing
really what we're doing is we're now
running the export logic also inside the
target process right it's really quite
similar to the browser exploit
where you would write all of the expert
logic in javascript and run it in the
attack process and here we're
you know we're not using javascript
we're using jpeg 2 virtual machine
something something but it's effectively
the same thing right and so this means
we no longer need this communication
channel
yeah so here here's where we're at
we have the attack server and the bug
and we break aslr
essentially by you know implementing a
mini cpu from j big two compression
operators
yeah it's definitely not like a weekend
ctf project building this thing so
that's quite
i think it's quite a lot of effort
so what's left is the pack bypass i'm
just going to show this slide
i mentioned it before like objective c
is really quite dynamic and this runtime
it
like really lets you do a lot of things
like you can add methods to existing
classes at runtime
stuff like this
and here's another class that you have
available called ns expression and if
you just kind of scroll down in the
documentation it literally says
you know since mac os whatever function
expressions also support arbitrary
method invocations right i mean
that's all we've been looking for um so
this is a kind of
yeah easy substitute for the ns
invocation stuff this is again how you
can call
arbitrary stuff
this is how the final thing looks like
so yeah we're creating these ns
expressions
remember we we can't fake them we can't
just create our own ns expressions in
memory anymore because apple added the
signature to objects you can make your
own
what you can still do and what this
exploit does is it just deserializes
them so remember the ns archive it can
decode arbitrary objects
so if you can
put pass input to one of these decoders
you can just create every object you
want right you can like
deserialize ns expressions it's it's
going to work so that's how this
expert got this object
right and yeah here's the
kind of end of end of chapter three
the final exploit flow um
so i think the the story continues
i i did took take a brief look yesterday
and from what i can tell apple has
already again done some attack surface
reduction and removed a lot of this like
this copied gif stuff seemed to be
completely gone
so i expect there to be more changes
will be interesting to see
right so let's go to the conclusion
i think there are kind of two main
points that i want to make um the first
point is yeah if you do make the right
hardenings right mitigations they can
make a big difference right here we saw
that the old 2019 exploited was
kind of fundamentally broken
um the new exploit had to be written
from scratch go a completely different
route
if you compare that with typical browser
exploits they kind of all look the same
right they will all pretty much do the
same thing and they have been doing that
for the last couple of years
this one here is like completely
different completely different thing
on the other hand right
the fact that this
second export was possible at all um
it's
good to keep in mind i think
we should assume that if you have memory
corruption
it's probably still exploitable in some
way i mean when we did this research
back in 2019 i think many people were
saying that these kinds of bugs in
imessage they can't be exploitable
but yeah now we've seen it at least two
times so
it's really like memory corruption is
really still very powerful
maybe two smaller points here so i think
sometimes can be quite hard to reason
about
where a specific piece of code runs so
we've seen this here we we had this
blast or process
but somehow this parsing still ended up
being an im transcoder agent
because of yeah whatever the gif gif
transformation stuff um
it was also similar in 2019 where one of
these payloads was decoded in
springboard which seemed really weird
um because it's on sandbox this is maybe
one interesting thing and the other is
like look out for this hidden attack
surface right like this it looks very
you know not not dangerous like just
this copy gif thing but then it throws
you into this huge sea of
of like image formats that it will
suddenly parse
so yeah
yeah and that's the end of my
presentation
thank you all for for listening
i guess
i guess we do have four minutes if there
are any questions but otherwise i'll be
around
feel free to find me ask me whatever's
on your mind
thanks
[Music]
you