thank you very much for being here and
coming to see my talk about a program
that I calm analyzed so it's a static
analyzer 4p executables so first I'd
like to say a few words about Who I am
so I work for Paris based company called
a CMS to national and I'm really not
going to go on too long about what we do
basically just run up the mail security
stuff services etc we are two two-man
team I work with attic doors which you
probably already follow on Twitter since
we're a very small company we do get a
lot of lead weights you work on some
open source projects and we releases a
lot of code on github so other projects
that worked on our apk track which is an
Android app to trap to track your
updates for Android software for people
who don't have the Play Store do not
want to use any Google services like I
do
there is also maybe something that's
going to be more relevant to your
interests which is called which is what
I call freedom fighting it's a
representative for pentesting scripts it
contains something like a stealthy lot
cleaner reverse encrypted Python shell
that also supports TTY so stuff geared
towards a red teaming apart from that I
do I do operate a tour exit node it's
located in France and I've learned
yesterday that a French exit not
operator has just been not arrested but
she's been questioned by the police
because he his note had been used to
access some kind of child pornography
case I don't know so this might be my
last talk ever before I go to jail as
well hopefully not
and finally I'm not CISSP which is a
thoroughly or some kind of running joke
on Twitter so I thought I'd just mention
it so a few words about the project
origin so manualized stands for malware
and analyze I learned at later date
that's in English it has also a whole
different meaning which I didn't know
about but the project was always named
this way so I didn't want to change it
again I started working on this in
February 2014 when I was working at a
Security Operations Center there were
mainly two reasons for my starting this
project first was my personal annoyance
raishin @a antivirus software Oh packet
decisions what I mean by that is that I
used to have hard drives full with
malware samples that I downloaded here
and there the whole wide web and
regularly that every time I would plug
the disk I would be very fearful that
the antivirus software would try to
delete everything on it and I was very
annoying at the same time every time I
would download the program from the
internet sometime it would it would get
deleted and I wouldn't have any
explanation as to why the program was
flagged as being suspicious and it was
kind of frustrating so imagine you're
downloading a keychain for something
four dollar application that region that
you've tracked for maybe an hour of your
life that you're never getting back and
as soon as you've gotten your hands on
it it's just get deleted with no form of
explanation I just wanted to know what
were the reasons behind my antivirus
software decisions so there was also
another concern that I had in my job was
that a lot of the tasks that I had to do
were increasingly growing repetitive so
every time I would receive a malware
sample I would first drag the sample
into PID to see if there was a unknown
Packer I would then upload the file to
virustotal
etc etc so I was wondering why can't
there be a single tool that does all
this and as I couldn't find any I just
decided to write one so just to give you
a quick overview of the project it's a
free open source software so it's reason
that the terms of the GPL v3 it's a tool
that was written in C++ and it's
available on both Windows Linux and I
think it probably works on Mac OS as
well even though I've never tested it
what it's used for is to perform initial
assessment of PE files so the objective
is to be able to quickly figure out
whether one sample is worth
investigating closer or whether it's
like a known quantity that you can
discard it almost immediately so the way
it works is it's going to generate a
report containing weak signals that hint
at the final behavior and I would like
to point out immediately that's the way
it works is
it's not a drop in av replacement it's
definitely not some program that you're
going to be able to give to your end
users and expect them to be able to take
decisions based on what the program
outputs it's developed for InfoSec
professionals and it's not a replacement
for human intelligence right
intelligence either it so what it does
is it gathers as much information as it
can on a particular file and presents
that information to you and it expects
the user the experts user to be able to
understand this information and be able
to take a decision based on whatever was
collected so it shows you a lot of
information and you figure out whether
you want to open the find an Ida or drag
it into the queue sandbox etc this
morning we've had a very interesting
talk from IDI about dynamic analysis I
don't want to go into too much detail
details about the differences between
static and dynamic analysis I'm sure
most of you have already used some
experience in the field so the only
thing I'm going to say is that static
and Isis has its shortcomings but it
also yields very quick wins from time to
time so I think it would be a shame not
to take 20 seconds to look at the
outside correct characteristics of a
program and see if we can already infer
its behavior just from there so the tool
only performs setting and Isis and does
not do any sort of dynamic execution or
not even symbolic in the execution it's
just looking at the way the file
structure and trying to guess what it
does from there but the architecture of
the program so the idea is simple you
get a lot of input files maybe thousands
or hundreds of thousands of different
files that you know nothing about and
you feed them into a parser the P parser
is going to dissect the file and offer
all the information about the file to a
whole set of plugins now I'd like to go
into much more details later and each of
the this plugins going to generate some
individual output that populates a
report in the end I also embedded the
yarra engine which I think most of you
know as well that can be used by the
plugins to perform additional tasks and
finally after the report has been
generated it goes
you know outside in an output form a
line which is going to format the text
into either plain text or human readable
output or JSON for other tools if you
need to use them so the way this talk is
structured is I'm going to go over each
different parts of the this architecture
to talk about the different reasons and
technical technological choices that
made developing this tool so the first
and core part of this program is the PD
parser so I before before starting to
work on this project I looked at the
different parts that were already
developed and that I could reuse so I
looked particularly into a PE file in
Python and there were also a couple of
C++ libraries but all of those were
ultimately rejected PD file was I
thought a bit too slow and I wanted to
be able to scale a lot and handle
thousands of files in a matter of
minutes so this is why I didn't want to
go to the Python way and the C++ level I
found looked like they were very and
safely written and I didn't want to risk
using them so I decided to write my own
which might be a bad idea you let me
know
the problem is that PE files are
extremely complex so there is an
official specifications for PE files you
can download it from Microsoft's website
but the thing is this specification is
sometimes quite cryptic it's not very
clear and moreover the windows as loader
that actually parses the PE files for
the OS is quite liked so it's going to
accept a lot of files that are not that
did not adhere strictly to the
specification and writing a parser
that's that's that performs tricks
parsing is going to reject a lot of
malware that would actually be able to
execute on a normal system so there also
there's another difficulty is that since
we are going to be handling malware
which is by definition very interested
in put we know that there is a
significant chance that the input that
we're going to use is going to try to
actively attack the parser so there have
been a couple of bugs in either Pro in
the past and other analysis tools that
were
attacked by the malware in order to
prevent analysts for from reversing the
programs and looking into it so there is
a very nice presentation from the black
hat us 2011 where people from reversing
labs discussed all the different
pitfalls that they had identified while
looking at the P specification and the
way they could maybe crash an Isis tools
so yeah the idea is that I wrote my own
P parser I did in C++ as well so you're
probably thinking that is this is a very
stupid idea because never a C++ is a
memory and safe language all I can say
is that C++ is fast and I did my best to
program very defensively I also tried
fuzzing the programs for maybe something
like to mount with AFL and well-known
fuzzing tool from Google didn't find any
crashes
I used gel West Indies handcrafted PE
file so you wrote minimize take PE
samples that are that do work on Windows
but not exactly valid as well all I can
say is I couldn't find a lot of crashes
well I couldn't find the questions that
are in the program I open the bug bounty
so if anyone can you find a PE
executable that triggers a crash in my
parser feel free to send it to me and
there's a bug bounty on it it's not a
lot but just come out of my personal
pocket money so please be understanding
oh nice there's a PowerPoint crash I'll
have to investigate that later probably
or the VM is shutting off that's nice
ok please bear with me for a second
yeah and of course that windows updates
as well it's just been triggered okay
I'll do my best to continue with other
slides while everything is rebooting so
there has been a Chinese researcher
who's been posing the application as
well he's found two crashes in the past
so it's definitely not a foolproof but
yeah please please try to find the blogs
in the application maybe you'll get a
the rewards well hopefully it won't be
too easy I'm so sorry about this
yeah so we're back
yeah so finally I talked about the speed
I was able to go through a whole virus
share release with the tool and was able
to go through it in about 10 minutes
so parsing about sixty eight gigs of
eatables in a few minutes I think it's
quite nice the keys is that a lot of the
files in the virus share archives are
and actually not be executables so they
just get rejected as soon as the
analysis starts another thing is that
all the analysis plugins were turned off
so obviously this speeds up analysis a
bit so a few words about Yarra which is
a parent searching tool written by
Victor Alvarez from virus tool you all
know about Jaros oh I'm going to say is
it's I use a slightly modified version
in man lies the reason I do this is that
they had their own PE parts for to do
stuff like looking for patterns at the
entry point or looking for patterns at
the specific section and it felt really
bad having two different beauty parlors
in the same project even having one is
already quite shaky to me so I removed
the the processor entirely and put mine
in that place I I did C++ wrappers as
well and removed all the non library
code now I'm going to talk a bit about
all the different plugins that are
implemented inside this tool so the
first one is the tranny this what I do
is I simply apply Clannad e-signatures
clan ID doesn't need to be installed on
the machine all you have to do is
download signature files run a Python
script that converts them into yarra
rules and then apply those rules
automatically with the program so the
signatures are not distributed with the
with manual eyes because obviously they
change every day but there's a Python
script that just allows you to download
them and use them immediately they also
have the family uses other kinds of
databases that are HDTV and NDB files
are just no big list of hashes of known
executables and sections that I don't
use but maybe I will at some point I
also have a resource nicest plugin which
looks at all resources our mechanisms
that I used to buy PD files to embark
arbitrary contents so looking at those
those resources usually leads useful
information its magazine mechanisms that
malware is liable to use to drop other
executables or files that they might be
needing to use like your configuration
files etc so just by looking at the
resources of a PE file like are they
impossibly encrypted or compressed is
the P file composed of more than 75%
resources etc in which case we might
infer that this is maybe a dropper we
can get some interesting information
about what the P might be doing on the
machine so of course if you use the
program called a resource hacker that
works only on Windows as far as I know
you can use my eyes to extract resources
on any OS I also have a PE plug-in which
just applies PID signatures yeah I've
decided to spread them into two
different plugins one that's dedicated
to compiler detection and the other one
to Packer detection but accurate
detection plugins also looks for
well-known section names so if it's a if
there is a section called dot VN pro
tect we know that the Packer is possibly
the unprotected cetera so it's useful
information the ID hasn't been
maintained for I think a few years so
I'm not sure how relevant this there are
signatures still are but maybe I'll just
remove them at some points so far I
haven't had any complaints I have a
strings plug-in which does a very
straightforward thing of looking for
well-known strings that indicates and
possible malicious behavior like
reference to system tools like Reggie
did
task manager etc etc debugger process
names references to address icky
registry keys the WMI
there are also a lot of virtual machine
detection techniques that rely on
looking for specific strings in the OS
so if you look for those strings in the
malware as well if the strings are not
obfuscated you're going to know
immediately that it's trying to be
something fishy basically every time
there is a new apt report that comes out
I'd brush through it look for
groundbreaking new invasion techniques
and add a few lines to
- this plugin to possibly detects and
you know newer implementations I also
have a cryptography detection plug-in
that is directly inspired from the
either Pro plug-in of fine crypt I think
so what it does is it looks for the
particular cryptographic constants you
used in particular algorithms I also
look for the oids that I used to
reference other algorithms in
third-party IP is the way I did this was
simply to download you know some random
crypto library on the Internet
I looked for all arrays of integral
integers like this I'm not sure you can
if you can read it properly from where
you stand but the idea is I built some
big error rules that look for all those
constants and now I'm able to detect md4
md5 sha-1 cetera et cetera
AES inside binary so knowing that a
binary is using cryptography is always
something interesting because it can
either mean that there is some of
obfuscation going on or even that the
programs are run somewhere we'll see
some examples they also have a backward
detection plug-in which I mentioned a
bit earlier there is a whitelist of
section names I look for possibly
encrypted or write alone executable
sections I look that the number of
imports is reasonable so PE files that
have less than 10 imports are usually a
little bit suspicious and require
further inspection apart from that there
are also funny in custom senses that are
caused by some Packer so this is a funny
one that I discovered a while ago was
there was this Packer that would
compress every resource in the program
but it wouldn't update the size of the
resources inside the PE headers so if
you were to sum up to sum all the sizes
of all the different resources you would
end up with a size bigger than the size
of the PE itself so you would
immediately know that the file has
impact something not groundbreaking but
it's always nice to have is important
Isis plugin so I'm going to look for
combinations of imports that would hint
at the program's behavior so for
instance everyone knows about the
virtual log by process memory and
craveable thread that's used to inject
code
processes I look for networking
functions process service and registry
manipulation api's and also cutting
process imports that can be used for
code injection in particular process
Halloween power loader and item bonding
which are well known techniques to
perform code injection but all rely on
very specific assets of api's there is a
small example given here at the end of
this slide again I'm not sure if you can
read but basically this is a program
that imports crate process shall execute
and also create a trade file and get ten
paths so it doesn't require a lot of
thinking to figure out that this is a
program that probably creates a file in
the temp folder and tries to execute it
so most likely dropper behavior one of
the future works I'd like to work on is
be able being able to resolve imports
that are loaded dynamically with get
proc get truck address and load library
with the capstone engine and I don't
know if that's possible but I'd like to
try one of the most recent additions is
a Bitcoin plugin so it just looks for
Bitcoin addresses in a binary so what it
does is go through all the possible
addresses and then tries to validate the
Bitcoin addresses have a very specific
structure the first four bytes I think
from memory the sha-256 of the rest of
the address so it's quite easy to figure
out whether the address is actually a
very Bitcoin address or not so this is
the output of the tool for the wanna cry
ransomware so you can see immediately
that even though it pretends to come
from my crystal corporation it contains
three different Bitcoin addresses and if
you were to google those Bitcoin
addresses you would find reports for a
link to the wanna cry attacks in
anything so this is a quite this is a
way to you to to gain time and perform
the analysis very very quickly
finally I have this authentical plug-in
that checks whether the digital
signatures of the PE is valid if I ever
find a binary that's claiming to come
from Adobe or Oracle or Google and if
it's not signed then immediately I can
raise an alert and say that okay wait
second this is supposed to come from a
well-known publisher but there was no
digital snake sir signature what's up
with that
so far the the plug-in is mostly only
available in Windows I have a UNIX
version that works but it relies on open
SSL which is a you know and horrible to
work with on Linux so I can look at I
can display the certificate issue but I
cannot check the digital signature at
the moment so there are other problems
so how do we check the digital the
digital signature of program on Linux
when you don't have Windows at rest so
there is another issue which is
Microsoft executive hours often known by
hash in the security catalog of the OS
and they are not even signed themselves
so is there a way I can export that and
into the tool I have no idea finally
there's a virustotal plugin that just
submits the hash to virustotal and
returns the new result so all I can say
is only the file hashes submitted if
some of you are very privacy conscious
and you do need to register on
virustotal account if you want to use
this plugin because they won't let you
use their api without a key by the way
each plug-in that I present it is
absolutely optional so you don't have to
use one of them if you don't like it
especially if you don't want to send
queries to virus although you really
don't have to
finally I created a portal which is a an
online portal for people who want to try
out the tool so you can just submit
executables online or either the P file
directly or a link to it and you will
get the report immediately the samples
are not shared with anyone and the only
one with access to the server but
basically you we don't have to trust me
if you don't want to you can just
download the source code from github and
run it locally so I'm just going to give
you a quick look at how this looks like
so here you've got a summary the pony
output this is I still wanna cry or rent
somewhere so there are strings related
to yes just 32 Bitcoin addresses in is a
few imports there are quite suspicious
etc it's a trial also you know the virus
total score which is a 58 out of 62
which is a lot there's a tab for
discussions if you
share your findings and then the hopi
structure but I'm not going to go over
that because it's more specialized
one thing that I'm quite proud of with
this tool is that it's quite easy to use
and reuse there's one thing I hate more
than anything is when I try to use an
open-source tool and see that it's it's
a mess to compile I can't get it to work
that dependencies are missing so I
really did my best to make Menai very
easy to install in just apt-get install
the dependencies git clone the code from
github see make make and that's it it
works you don't have if you want extend
the tool you don't need to understand
the core you can just use the API which
is I think quite well documented and
just interact with the people without
having to understand the structure being
beneath it you can also use the pea
parser and take it out of the project
and use it in your own one of the
examples I made available online is
using this P parser to write your own
process hollowing code so you can find
all the resources on my blog a few words
about the future works so one the most
the most the things I would like to do
most is getting that authentical plug-in
to work on Linux I would like to work on
icon recognition for so if for instance
in executable files has a PDF document
icon I think this is something we can
detect automatically and raise alerts
for very quickly I mentioned wanting to
use capstone engine to resolve imports
and for as for the web portal I would
love to be able to work a bit on some
more bigger data capabilities like
having a search engine within people of
search for malware based on section
names or any characteristics you want
and finally possibly Python bindings in
the future I've started working on this
but it's far from ready yet
then I'm just going to do a short
demonstration of the tool to illustrate
how it can help people during their
analyzes so this is a sample coming from
the apt one CSI campaign from 2014 it's
quite all but I really like this example
because it just works perfectly it's not
always the case
to be honest about this but when it
works it's really really nice so let me
launch just colonize this of this
program
and I'm just going to launch all the
plugins
I hope yeah then we go so I have to go
up a bit so here we see the compilation
days which was when we received the file
in the Sun I worked at it was somewhere
around January 17th so we knew it was a
very fresh train there was reference
system Chinese language inside the PE
file at the time there were there
weren't any clan Meili signatures but
there is now so we see here that it's
creating processes and creating files in
the temporary folder yeah this is
possibly a dropper because when you look
at the resources then one of the
resources is a PDF document which is
weird why would the P file and embark in
a PDF file who knows there is also
another P executable embarked inside the
file and all you know the resource is a
month for 93% of the executive also
mostly this is a file whose only role is
to drop all the files yeah constants
related to this as well so there was a
strange obfuscation being performed and
now there are lots of lots of different
signatures for an entire software so
what we can do from there is extract all
the resources so you look at them very
closer you I create a folder called out
I'm going to go to the bracele folder
and look at what's inside it
absolutely there's alcohol or so what's
in there is a PDF documents the icon of
the of the pin file which is a PDF icon
this PDF was simply decoy document that
would be opened when the user clicked on
the file didn't make them believe that
it had you know open the an actual PDF
document I didn't work and here there
was a second executive which was dropped
on the system and we seemed executed so
I'm going to perform the analysis on
this section in the second program
now go
see here we see so they're the refers to
the Chinese language are not present
anymore
there are still constants related to
this and now the interesting import of
this program or create process
Internet's open Internet open URL etc so
we can easily infer that the first part
was the dropper and the second part is
actually the implant is going to perform
a download and execute
we're going to be looking for commands
on a remote server and just executing
them and going and also a lot of
signature so that's it for the example
one last thing I would like to mention
is if you want to look at the pea
structure in more details you can just
dump any any part of the structure you
want so there you go you have all the
imports the different sections etc etc
and if there is any part of this that
you want to reuse in another tool you
can just use the JSON output formats
and there and you can feed it to another
to like so I think that's it and be
happy to answer any questions otherwise
the project is available on github and
feel free to download it tweak it and
send me back reports thank you very much
[Applause]
I haven't counted them I think it's
something like two or three gigs files
that's not much but I only keep
executables I rejected everything else I
think most people are not very
interested in using the portal for
anything else that just testing the tool
so people will upload one or two files
to see how it works and whether it's
interesting and then if they are
satisfied with it I assume that you
download the code and run it locally
because they don't have to send me
anything which is perfectly okay
as far as I'm concerned anyone else yep
yeah it's quite easy in the sense that
I've written a lot of documentation
there are lots well maybe not a lot of
sample plugins that all the code of the
other plugins is I think mostly clear
I've had there is one example and then
you can use the other plug-in as a
reference so you hopefully it should be
quite easy for you but if you ever
encounter any problems then it means I
have done my job
wrong and the documentation is not good
enough so be sure to let me know is you
have to subclass a class and then
implement a single method and then you
can interact with the people through the
API but that's it you just have to
implement a single method well maybe two
or three methods because you have to
provide the plug-in name apart from this
you just drop in your plugin inside the
default program folder just drop the
Esso or the other file inside the same
folder as memorize and it's just going
to be detected in automatically okay
well thank you very much for your
attention