I'm a managing security consultant at
NCC group X software developer I used to
develop all kinds of software from
desktop software to web so games and
even some factoring machines and I think
myself as a as a hacker breaker I like
to I like to bake stuff bad stuff to
break stuff so problems outside of work
and technology and I was kind of stuff
I'm a hiker and what grandma and I mixed
to be be on the Internet Twitter and
what-have-you
so first thing thumbs up if you would
know what to do if you saw this packet
during a pen test
that's right welcome
cool so you start off with a story I
went to a customer site to assess a web
application except when I got there they
told me I needed a specific old version
of Java that's a bit strange is a web
app sure I would buy the only but so I
thought maybe it's a job a client
application that communicates over HTTP
so I started to build a VM and asset to
poke around with this application and I
know it's the application eventually
responded so just our test logging
request with something saying that the
account was locked out there are strange
because I haven't seen any requests go
through web suite
so fried up wireshark see what was going
on and and it turns out that it was just
a job application
served by HTTP page so it was it was a
Java Web Start application so it was
actually just that okay I think client
application and with Wireshark running I
generate some logging requests and I saw
a packet like freeze drug login request
a packet like the one that I just showed
you so it was a a login pocket like I
say not let's see the discovery of a
vulnerability that survived multiple
previous pen tests every time the new
version in this application was rolled
out and on the network they had it been
tested
a fold on a server that had a hard
exterior but there was something inside
but on that server and from I was able
to jump around the entire environment
and from pre-production to production I
was in at least three different data
centers
so I would have missed up one ability as
well as all of the previous pen testers
but I've done a lot of research into
that and Java D civilization stuff so as
soon as I saw a packet I recognized that
I knew what to do
I've been talking about it today
everyone in this industry needs to be
learning constantly so the private
starkest so look at these kind of look
how we can identify these kind of
vulnerabilities or potential entry
points and how we can then attack them
using existing tools
so the first thing to point out is that
that score doesn't mean point-and-click
generally these kind of attacks are a
bit more involved but I would put that I
would put that in line with of many or
SQL injection about to poke around a bit
more to it equerry a bit more dry and
bypass and fillers
but they are rewarding these kind of
vulnerabilities generally get you
command execution on a box so it's worth
doing
so we need to understand how serious a
ssin works and how these kind of
volleyball is can be can be identified
and attacked in order to sudhir it
effectively so start with some
background the serialization the process
is the process of converting one-time
variables and program objects that are
in memory in so form that can be stored
on the desk or in a database or
transferred over the network
the best process be civilization takes
that data and turns it back into
one-time objects and variables
the more complex the one-time data
structures are so object oriented
programming languages have objects
embedded within objects the more complex
a civilization than format and process
has to be and the more complex that but
family is not processes the more scope
the risk for vulnerabilities there is no
fixed format for serialized data can be
a custom format it can be a built-in
farm up that this provided is part of
the programming language our API is
standard API use Jason XML and
similarly built informants are easier to
use you don't have to do anything to use
them so focusing on Java for the stock
but so high level concepts they apply it
said so other languages in technologies
for example PHP and let's say the built
in civilization is easy to use so in
Java we have in order to make Java cross
serializable we just implement the
interface Java dot IO dot serializable
once we've done that we can pass an
instance of that object in time object
to an object output stream and we can
write it to a file to a network can over
a network connection so on to read that
back we use an object input stream and
we can move that there a buck is that's
all there is to it
really easy to use
and the actual dates of Roma can be
described as a simple stream farmer
so each stream starts with I see by
magic number
let's fill it by a teapot version number
I've only ever seen version 5 draw this
there's older versions that exist and in
future newer versions could exist
and that header is followed by at least
one concern element
the reason it's a stream format is a
there can be multiple concert elements
and you just read and read and read
until the end of the stream so there's
no more data so that content element
will begin with by in the range X 7 0 X
and so for example
Zarek's 7-0 is no an object is 73 arrays
7 5 and so on
the actual specification can be found
online on the Oracle website and it's a
bet on clearing places so some examples
just to show you what civilization data
looks like I'll see guys date it looked
like so a minimal stream I could say
you've got the to base a CED the header
magic number the version number zero
zero zero five and then seven zero which
is a null element string for A's again
you've got the header you've got seven
four which is a string zero zero zero
four is it's a by length field which
cells as hold on the string is and then
we've got the actual bytes of the string
and then this is a basic objects a
better caliber should actually implement
so as a robot that's a simple object so
we've got seven three
but I've set for is the sellers this is
an object 7c this is across description
and then we've got the rest of the data
for that class so the length of the
class name the actual class name and so
on
the serialization in Java is done using
the objects input stream but
parsa's data sequentially so it reads
free stream tries to instantiate some
element from constant element gets the
next one after la and so on but didn't
sake and they're a go with thoughts the
first byte of a Content element that
tells us a type whether it's no string
so on but also tells us the format of
the data that follows for our elements
or like I said in a string you've got a
length field and then you've got the
actual string then you can have
additional content elements
data is instantiated as it is read it's
instantly sunshade so this I'm not I'm
not an object in the stream
data for objects is red insert memory
send it to an object and then Java or
carry on reading from the stream I've
requested
there isn't much validation performed if
any really so for example here we're
reading recalling objects input stream
that read objects to read an object from
a serialization stream we then cast it
to a string
and assign that string to the available
s
the validation kind of happens there if
the object that we read from the stream
isn't compatible type compatible with
string then an exception will be thrown
and that's kind of you your validation
so you a program should handle that
exception you're right that there's not
how we expected it to be and took it
away whatever
while the several Ice Age civilizations
happening look at the destabilization
say Java doesn't care I was going to
read an object from the stream
instantiate and then return it about
brain it's too late and we'll get to
that
so in a class implements civilized world
interface it can also implement a read
object method
the method can be used in place of or in
conjunction with Javas d4 Reid objects
javis different method of reading
objects so you can read custom date so
it can have shared version and bring the
stream so that you can parable weave you
can have a newer version you software
compatible with older versions of data
but we can also use that read object
methods to sort of handle the event that
an object is loaded
so a deft example of that there's
neither across the manager database
connection when you see realize that
glass in my write the database
connection parameters to a file using
solarization and then when you read
those back
it might automatically reconnect to a
database so that's how we might handle
and this object loaded event
so this civilization vulnerability
these occur when we as an attacker have
control of the data that's being
deserialized
by controlling that data we control the
properties of objects but are being
instantiated in memory including the
type of the objects so our example where
we custom pincer a string we don't have
to have a string in the stream there an
exception will perform but by that point
and objects has already been
instantiated by controlling bait so we
can control code flow that depends on
that data and that includes any code
that's in a serializable classes read
object method that handles they object
loaded event and any interaction with an
object that's been loaded I've been read
from a serialization stream so if cold
calls read objects and then interacts
with the result
again we can manipulate the code using
the properties of the objects
[Music]
solicit co-op the or it's a programming
we control properties of objects to
implements the flow of current execution
payload like safe controls so code that
we control through controlling
properties and objects is it's got a
cadet we can think about as high level
rock gadget accepts a rock gadget mat
just push a value on to a stack a pop
gadget my rights and dates or fail for
example so it is much much higher level
and generally exploitation relies on
exploitation relies on knowledge and
source code so we need to know what code
is executing when our object is
instantiated in order to be able to
manipulate it this seems to be a point
of confusion when it comes to this kind
of stuff a memory corruption expert you
kind of it sounds be sending some kind
of code city application and it's going
to eventually execute that code
the civilization expert where it's
sending properties and were manipulating
code that already exists
it's not always possible to acquire an
application source code so how do we
attack an application without source
code
now anyone that's done any this kind of
stuff before already anything about this
kind of stuff should have heard of white
sauce area and so I saw cereal it's
actually these that various researchers
when looks at all of these libraries and
some more and basically said write what
code is there that we can manipulate to
do something useful to an attacker
[Music]
but a lot of pop gadget chains and
publish them in a tall glass of cereal
which regenerates these chains and
generates these payloads
most of these payloads enable us to
execute months blindly so we don't get
anything back from those commands unless
the command addition so like we can
pinch ourselves but we'll get output
from the ping command
so how do we suck Java deserialization
there's three key parts to a
civilization attack first part is an
entry point
sex Empire is some gadgets so right so
surreal
and then actual commands to execute
against the target environment and I'll
get through today's
so
an inch brain is any part of the
application that
DC arises data so if we're looking at
network traffic or we're looking at
files that an application reads you can
identify civilise data by the magic
number in the version number you want
ideally you want five bytes so
identified a sterilized stream excuse me
let's say the header on a bright in the
range 7 0 to 70 because that's a valid
say realizations dream so
got some paella that's corley not plain
text in burp suite we click on the hex
view and you can see that a CED zero
zeros in five seven three
again the same thing Wireshark startup
packet
basics for recoded serialization data so
in for example a web application where
we're working with a text-based broad
scope and binary data is no it's not
it's not very nice to use nobody isn't
really comparable with a text-based
bolts code so we might basics for encode
the data which produces a recognizable
pattern and so if you see if you see a
cookie or an HTTP header that starts off
with lowercase R capital o 0 and own
capital ABX then that's the civilization
hello
so when we're looking at some sales data
a Java centralized data and there were
another a handful of other indicators
that I was that this is definitely
civilized data first thing is Java class
names you'll see this stuff here the
dates are so soon that reflects that
annotation but annotation invocation
handler comes up for you to a so on
there's also not a net format format for
that and that's don't see the
serialization and data format it's just
I don't know the exact reason for it but
these certain places the class name will
be in a slightly different format so
it'll begin with a capital L end with a
semicolon and then instead of dots in
between and the parcel names based in
the actual class name it's false lashes
and then
know about that
stands out again from the format of the
but from the screen format you'll see
strings like SiO and XP throw it throw
it
so si are tells us this is an object and
this is across different description 7 X
7 3x 72 XP is seen as the end of a cross
description it sells as that this is the
end of the class annotations unless this
cross has no has
your parent class and so that's CC and
what dates last as the content type is
and what data and then constants I know
flows and so looking back at that login
pocket
we could say all these indicators
so we've got si
Java class names XP
but there's no a CED zero zero zero five
and the reason for that is so this is
this was the first of the login packets
that I actually saw in Wireshark when I
was testing an application
and the reason for there being no a ced
0:05 is that that's a stream header that
only appears right there they start of a
sterilization stream so what this
application did was it when you started
up connected to a server and use the
objects input stream object output
stream so to read and write over that
connection a batplane
the serialization had a goes in each
direction and then subsequent packets
can say don't contain the header because
we've already open the stream have
already started the stream an
interesting point here this client had
and IDs in place which had rules to
decide these kinds of attacks but it
looks for
those boats and some additional bytes in
the packet in the same packet because my
payload went over the network layer pone
my attacks went completely on it
undetected
so don't rely on seeing the header
it should be there it's not over the
stream but if you see data that's bit
over into the stream then you're not
going to see it straight away
so once we've we've identified an entry
point we needs to work out where to
actually inject our payload
so the simple case is that we will see
the serialization stream header and it
will be followed by a bright any very
these three ranges so seven zeros to
seventy six or seven basis of any each
of those all of the breaks in those two
ranges
constant elements civilization stream
constant elements that can be read as an
object so if you call objects input
stream dot read objects you can read any
of those content types the ones that I'm
in those ranges they won't read them so
there is some validation going on so we
see that pattern in a solarization
stream then we can replace
the fifth by an woods with a payload an
arbitrary object when that stream gets
passed to the target it will read the
header and it will start to instantiate
an object which is the object we put in
the stream once our objects instantiated
and returned from objects in equestrian
but read objects there might be an
exception from something there might be
an error somewhere where that point our
objects aside have been associated in
memory and we potentially already to
control some code and exploit the
application just too late
becoming alternatives that is the stream
might start with a block data about data
long element the so again we'll up the
stream header and then we'll have either
7 7 or 7 8
7/7 is followed by a single bite which
is the lymph excuse me
followed by that many bites which to the
actual blood data
7a has four bytes for the lung field and
I'm not many boats after that if we see
about in that range if it all C ranges
then we can replace that by and then
words with a payload and we can inject
there so got an example where we've got
the header we've got the version number
at the magic number the version number
seven seven so we've got blog data 0 8 8
bytes long 8 bytes and block beta and
I'm at 7 3 is in those one of those two
ranges so we can actually replace that
something 3 onwards with any object we
want and plus the states it's in the
target application and it
instantiate our object or something
so more complex situations cases then
those and all tool for this because I've
spent ridiculous amounts of time
manually decoding sterilized streams of
data and working out what all the
different things are where exactly I can
inject a payload so sterilization didn't
put that gotcha we win it and just press
about Bible civilization scream
or we can import a file
and it will attempt to pass that in
Xalapa human human readable form
and what we're looking for in air is
again those those two bright rage back
ranges so seven zero two seven six I
think and then seven beats they're 70
and as we can see in the contents the
first one is a string element seven four
so we can actually replace from the
start within objects of our twos and it
will be instantiated but all is on
github
I've got details of that bit later on
essentially we're looking for a Content
element that's got that the type seven
zero two seven six or seven be 270 we
can replace that with any object we want
them so we've got an entry point we need
to find some pop gadgets that we can use
I could say we need source go where to
find pop gadgets you're looking for read
object methods and you're looking for
the code in those methods how you can
manipulate that based on the day there's
been read from the stream the properties
of the objects that going across and
we're looking for objects input stream
got read objects' and code that
instructs with the return value any of
that code we can manipulate using the
properties of that object well that's
not very practical we don't always have
source code and I'm talking about
practical attacks so
like I said Russell cereal if if there
were these little common libraries that
are used by lots of applications Commons
collections is is one of the most
commonly known and loads of applications
are still using it still I would say the
most common vulnerable library for this
kind of stuff so ideally we'll have some
background information on the
application or we'll have an information
disclosure that will give us some idea
of what libraries are in use and we can
just go right that's a little Burleigh
berry rather that correct payload on it
and we went hopefully and
if we don't have that information
we can kitchen sink it which is throw
everything but the kitchen sink area so
we've got my sauce cereal it generates
all these different bowls for all these
different libraries brought them all
so
like Russell sales got load of pillows
for different libraries us just an
example if we know that any of these
libraries are in use they the jar files
on the left then we can use the payload
on the right somebody's over up so I
think this accumbens be initials payload
that we relies on Commons collections
being present and so
that might not be so so useful but
so access that kitchen sink in any way
there I've got a Python script which
I've used quite a few times it's a pop
this kind of stuff just got a list of
Wessel sailor payload types loop through
them and we record by source or to
generate a payload that generates the
serialized object that will execute a
given command using one of these pop
gadget chains so the Commons collections
one for example we don't call fire
payload we pass all spikes see that
method fire payload will be whatever it
needs to do to deliver that payload said
application so not sir Freyja a certain
sequence and packets over the network
and then inject the payload into the
stream insert over the network
that's potentially risky
where
Ferenc a lot of random data and objects
an application we could crush it
I've never seen this happen
the application would likely fall over
if you just am upset if it was going to
fall over because of this so it's
probably not that bad because any any
strange data going over the network hit
in this boat were probably because it's
a crutch of its if it's not it was hand
or less
it's definitely noisy doing that
because we're going to generate
move buckets different payloads from all
over the network
the issue is that it's we're doing brand
command execution when these payloads we
don't know that the pop gadget chains
and the libraries are present which ones
if we're going to just fire all the
different payloads so we might fire 10
different payloads at an application and
we might see that replicate that the
server starts opinions or something
about the payload that we use in which
one actually cause that to happen
and another thing is we might find
nothing's happening nothing seems to be
happening is the pelo command that we're
trying to use actually available on
server is a server
is there actually actually some good
firewall and in places step in traffic
from reaching us when we've we've
executed a command we don't know so
ideally we want some feedback from the
application
I said you might pin yourself farewell
Matt stop that if you do try that make
sure that you limit the pink um
when I did this I got a bit excited and
I forgot to do that so I made some
processes constantly pinging my box and
so I managed to get on the sovereign and
kill them off but actually a better
option is to try an invalid command
generally when you when you
sucking these kind of issues you'll at
least get exceptions back over there
network I don't think I've seen a saga
yet that didn't some an exception back
now reuse an invalid command
and
[Music]
then we'll get an exception IO exception
says cannot one program so everyone X Y
Z X Y Zed and that's not present on the
server will get that so we can confirm
that the payload chain the pop gadget
chain that actually triggered that is is
available to the server if the pop
gadget chain isn't available
[Music]
across not found exception because we've
sent our objects of a cross sort of
server the Soviets attempted to
instantiate an object of that grass and
it doesn't know what the cross is so
it's gone
I don't know cosmic farm there you go
and so we can fire a single payload with
anybody command and we can find out
whether the pop graduate chain is usable
and also well we using the sense that
now we can find out the commanders
available sorry
so that's saying pelo commands there's a
few quirks with this
like I said we've got blanked command
execution if we've got an entrant and
we've got some pub gadgets at work
usually we want the sunlight so shall we
want more actresses so we want a nicer
way to interrupt with server and then
pivot sir to other systems
so
lesson that we might do is try and
enumerate Commons available a target
environment
same technique that I just mentioned if
we get a IO exception saying cannot run
program then we know that the pop gadget
chain is available but we also know
there that command isn't available
and there are some limitations to
the payload commands that we can use and
so
these these pop gadget chains in my
source aerial use Java dot lined up one
time to exec with a single string
parameter and well that does is it takes
up string splits it on the space
character and then the first is the the
first item in that array and the result
is the command to execute and the rest
of the parameters to that command that
means that we can't use whitespace in
parameters through that command
so for example we can run this command
you can see that parameters like Amanda
different colors and we can't use this
command because we've got spaces in
between meant that the parameters get
split up as shown there with the
different colors we also can't use shell
operators so piping and output
redirection and now I'm going to skip
over these some examples of payload
commands that we can use and windows as
well but came across this after the
first summer deliver this talk payload
command X encoder a type in arbitrary
brush commands PowerShell - perl and
encode source commands so that you can
use them with one time book Jack so we
just take out the button and we can
execute whatever commands one
hopefully windows where powershell is
obviously a bit more difficult but we we
can probably Dave thought so we've got
all these things now for a sock
couple of case studies
so the first one
and Spring Framework
and as if has a feature called hayseeds
people will take what remoting generally
but this is HTTP version razorba
versions of it and what this allows us
to do is expose a bunch of Java classes
over HTTP
that's facilitated by the spring remote
invocation class
so essentially
that we do is we we do some
configuration stuff with Spring
Framework and we say right this class is
going to be exposed over-hasty to people
moving on the client side we can learn
we do a similar configuration we say
right I want an object I want this
object and sprinkle some logic in the
background then it goes it recall the
method on the object spring will further
off over-hasty to page to the server way
or decode or you know invocation objects
and column method got the result and
send it back
that's done and in a body ever hasty to
be post request
and it looks like this
this
so that's our entry point
literally just the body of a post
request before any civilized objects in
there and the server spring Hasty's be
remote and will be sterilized it
and so this is an extension to the
script I showed earlier where we're
looping through different payload types
fire payload just does a post request
using the piping request library it also
checks for the cross not phone
exceptional tells us if that pop gadget
chain is supported on up
yeah so using that you could pop Spring
Framework spring hayseeds be mine
doesn't happen though and the problem
here is that
I'm sending a
hushed set objects to spoon framework in
the body is post request
the spring framework is deserializing a
hush sled but it wanted a remote
invocation I should have sent a remote
invocation objects but just Ysera rise
to anyway the hash set object that I
sent isn't compatible with the remote
invocation it's not compatible and so an
exception gets thrown
and the object that I send to the server
never reaches the application that's
using spring Hastie to be remoting and
because Spring Framework itself can't
cast it's a remote invocation
but card it's pivotal who make Spring
Framework that's not an issue with
Spring Framework
go figure
the Garland's been secured the pivotal
security team that reported this issue -
has a CV number for report on a very
similar issue and I think J boss and he
still thinks that this is an issue with
Spring Framework as an application
developer you can't you won't ever see
that payload
second case study Acme money obviously
that's not what it's called can't reveal
the name in a minute
but it's where that band login packet
was
so exploitation was a little bit more
involved this time still easily done and
but scripts can still do it quite easily
so that's probably civilisation day or
in the stream can say that quite clearly
though so like I said I didn't see a CEB
zero zero zero five so we started
application fright up wireshark I know
that sorry closed application down
alfredo by shot restarted application
and I captured the full
communication and actually it was quite
simple that was just an initial pocket
went out to the server response came
back another response came back and then
like sled before you're looking for a
bite in what do you see ranges so seven
three and that second out brown packet
that's the injection point
oh sorry soap yeah
highlight the stuff
so
some prints point out here this very
first packet the following bytes there
is static every single time I did this
so I knew that I could just send that
same packet replay that same packet to
the server so as we can see we've got
fire payload method from that same
Python script are similar you know a
copy of it we connected a target we
send that first pocket the static every
single time we received see packets from
the server don't care what they are just
trucking away and then we send the
payload and the reason for the square
brackets for : is the stream header was
already sent there a CED so on so that
payload contains the stream header so we
just trim that off and we summon the
rest of it the objects the payload
objects so through this script together
based on the packet capture I fried it
at a server found out that it was
running it was using Commons collections
3 t1 and got command execution got quite
a lot of command executions actually
so this point I've proved that I'm
executing commands on the server and you
could say that's you one and well then
this is a good example of what you can
do with this kind of issue and this
there's it's there's loads of big
enterprise applications that have this
kind of issue so I've got to carry on
obviously I wanted a show so I used
technique that I've talked about
so find valid commands on the server I
tried net cut to beget curl getting the
command didn't exist
I found that pearl was on the server at
the time I wasn't aware of the payload
encoder I mentioned so this Brian ever
I can't easily write a file because I
can't Ocoee direct outputs or file for
example every one of they were purl
she'll one-liner I've got to use socket
so I need a space and the parameter to
purl
so it's I could probably use it some
help and we'll see what else there is
solve it around eventually found that
the server had the TFTP command
available quick Python script so it set
up a directory as a TFTP server and our
books I had access to the file system
then I could download stuff from my box
I could have all sorts a bit to the
server so that she'll on server and well
as well firstly this is the first the
first every time I found I come across
an air box
I do mostly application testing and code
review first sampling across one of
these and that's probably what was a bit
of fun kid with commands but it was also
outdated because obviously operating
system patches don't know and
and so from the privileged escalation
expert
I thought awesome I'm done I've got me
on this box but the
exploit was read in C and I didn't have
build tools available on the box brooded
up peril
so I rewrote my exploit in Perth it was
painful but it was worth it because I
got root on that box and I'm like I said
from there I jumps around the entire
network I had units up millions running
out from when they got alerts that's
what I logged onto the production
servers like it wasn't me
so
like I said this I'm talking about
practical civilization attack sees I'm
as practical as although attacks other
than as easy to do but I want some tools
that hopefully make it a bit more
practical so the first one serial brute
this is basically what scripts and Sarah
blue top I will replay HTTP HTTP request
r/a
a TCP conversation and we'll then jet to
payload at some prime
and it will bring folks through the
payloads analog it will stop at each one
site was it successful because ideally
you don't want to be spamming all these
different payloads they'll also try and
detect the exceptions coming back and
I'll tell ya this payloads no good this
one's no good that one might be useful
and it's not meant to be a robust
attacks all
it works for most cases if you have to
do something like get such an ID from
the server and then replay that info in
a packet
it's not going to do it but for that
there's another version srl BRT that by
which you basically implement you
dispatch payload method do whatever you
want to do that I so like it's look at
it before replay the first pocket me two
pockets back and play the replay payload
or send up a Lord
civilization dump it up Jarrah released
that as well so if we've got some
theorize date set we can just pass it
through this it would empower in a more
human readable form and we can find a
point in that stream where we can inject
a payload and yeah
decel up whatever you wanna call it
however you want to pronounce it it's
it's just a demo application client and
server it does something similar to this
application this me money application
but you can use up to actually just try
the tools out and see how it works and
see if we can exploit something nice and
so I was going to do a demo but I think
I'm out of time so I also didn't
sacrifice to go any conclusion and any
questions
it's built into Java it's just easy to
use you don't have to do you don't have
to have an extra library and there's no
you know no dependencies you just
implement this interface and you go so
that's it's easy that's that's it
basically
possible to build a gadget ideally from
with glasses from the JJ
yes weather glasses rather than the
classical home
and so I know that there are ngenikis
JDK 7 and JDK 8 pure Java gadgets but
for very very old versions of the JDK
it's you have to really think in silico
this medical research is the loads of
work in this area and it could be quite
time-consuming some people built tools
that help to find gadgets and the Hat
being gadgets that work just purely
using jelly cake jelly
you