Ellis and Tucker rules to our group they
have massive levels we put you over to
me I'm sorry for second with a
professional dancer at the customer
service time killed a group that's not
matter so is Russell the incomparable
global attention and the separable as
design algorithms Europe but you
remember fast whistles as the work of
every day at robert morris and others
and mathematics and cambridge
massachusetts so whether suppressor
whatever left with at least that your
local ever made giggles through the
another culture will turn left at
traffic to link but we're going to be
unless were also attacked the parent
servers with some very high a very
attractive ever got plans and purposes
the second section goes during that we
have the opportunity to waive superior
ability and a bourbon distributive
monorail faculty structural so fast that
he declared effective intimately so I
children it was rather surreal a person
responding to a certificate or where
that is to talk today about it and
oppose i meant official
there was actual factual issues but a
bachelor of course everything after that
sequestration address can be so trying
to censor their official government to
local wrong decisions at the same time
do the most know who the staff members
have sponsors pockets with many victims
I don't want to send a person to get
their servers max Rebecca very simply
really is without the past so finally
over the shoulder want the nearest until
it's true system is positioned those
circle left a note for the record that
the metropolitan official term federal
family education material and support so
listen to the potential problem with
faster ones and auditory rhythms have a
retrospective of traffic analysis with
rigorous as network devotees some ways
to ensure and particularly with networks
the burial violence or diocese chose
reference so efficient Western
photographer the fact that access list
of the room with aperture hybrid that
bad and the favor really I think through
a mismatch respective with the dream
that was before though Nazareth and this
ones who can be reserved in very small
fears of traffic since other issues go
to a maximum area center Evans at that
track of the middle of the platter
advantage that through
providence that we should let room so
going back to resemble answer refer
special though we have had the network
lips and that we want to prove there's
some dynamic signature some information
about the attack traffic from which we
might possibly be able to build a filter
somehow staff is this flood that's what
I was talking about is how rhythms and
heuristics that we've developed and
actually implemented at mizzou and
describe how they work like a loop so
the general category of the general name
that begins our approach is historical
aggregate analysis of the term aggregate
I've borrowed from Steve velvet or
others from there agri congestion
control work earlier this year so I
think it refers to a set of packets that
share some properties difference all dns
back as well back to a certain source
and the original focus of the aggregate
work was focused on the station
addresses and rate limit effectively
traffic's going to high volume
destination addresses so this is a great
idea if you're trying to protect the
network that will work fine but of
course the only increases the analysis
back in the victim and furthermore
doesn't work well if you try to compute
aggregates on parameters that can be
ranging these hoops authentic source
addresses so our approach is of a
variation that is p formal is two
branches for work the first to use
multiple parameters simultaneously
compute a gift so look at things like a
cat lands pcl distributions even hash
the packet payload and the second is to
look at distribution of these parameters
over time an attempt to decrease
collateral damage so the question won't
you ask me at this point is how can
history be useful you know what we get
from looking at historical data and the
intuitive insight which will also
confirmed from collecting data from
order of a dozen network so
the last year eventually is in fact many
parameter distributions tend to be well
to be stable they don't change very much
overtime so an example actually
unfortunately I see that the plots or
software loans on the projector but i'll
describe them the two plots that you see
are addressed distributions so the
x-axis is IP address space from all
zeros with left hand sides to all one
when the right hand side and the y-axis
pack accounts and what being counted is
source addresses of incoming packets and
the station rest without going packets
for a particular t1 line and the data
you see is over period of two months
from the top draft and over a period of
one essentially a day for the bottom
Arab and what you'll notice is that in
fact that the graphs are very similar
and the traffic that isn't seen during a
day typical even seen engine a longer
period and conversely reasons that have
traffic during a long period and to also
see traffic during a shorter period and
this data holds across many networks
locations where we had the opportunity
to observe traffic and it seems to hold
across multiple parameters so for
instance source addresses ptl's many
other things tend to be clumped and they
have to be consistent in a given
location for scales time scales that RL
belongs to longer than about a minute or
so and so the intuition of this might
lead you to is that in the worst case if
you're looking at some parameter and
you're trying to minimize collateral
damage we're trying to minimize the
filtering or negative reinforcement that
you do on traffic that actually is not
part of the arc attack then one way of
trying to limit that to that collateral
damage is to actually look at the
long-term past distributions for
guidance and therefore you know then
first apply filters to biggest outliers
that we see in our current traffic or
maybe to value the up the regions of the
parameter space that are starkly load so
here's an example what you see on the
top in both cases both images the axes
are the same as in the previous slide
don't you see the topic is
source address distribution for incoming
traffic for a large website simply at
speeds on the order of half a million
packets per second sustained during the
day collected over a period of a few
days and the bottom is what you
typically expect to see during some sort
of randomized flood in this case it was
a sense that we were measuring where
source addresses have been screwed
friend uniformly and so go back to our
previous intuition what we might do here
is you know being able to take no source
based aggregate on which the filter
would have simply try to utterly shape
the traffic that we're seeing incoming a
relative to past distribution that was
obtained over a long term past series so
the previous slide had a soothing
example and techniques pooling of
interesting for a couple reasons are
certainly a just an
information-gathering or a forensic
aspect to it but it's also it can be
easily guidelines to help us determine
whether in fact it's useful to smooth
this is a filter or try to track attacks
based on high volume aggregates in the
silence of development for instance or
whether a history based approach is more
appropriate so one way to try to
determine this is for instance to look
at the variance or standard deviations
of the histogram buckets for parameter
histograms that we collect so going back
you're looking just for a second backup
at the previous plot you'll notice that
in the top figure there are some
particular some groups of addresses that
see a lot of traffic others see almost
none so you'd expect no deviation to be
relatively high if we look at San
deviation of the actual bucket values
within values in histogram and
conversely for the bottom plot there's
not a lot of splits and deviation
intuitively is low we can divide by the
mean of the tracks that you see during
the period of data collection in order
to normalize for different traffic
volumes so person so you can compare
traffic see at night when they're little
data to collect that night when there
isn't much traffic the data interval of
the day when there's more traffic and
then intuitively obtained as a metric
where lower values
imply more randomness high degree of
spoofing and this is even though again
the bottom plot doesn't show up very
well on the projector this is it comes
through it in these plots so for
instance that what you need to look at
is the y-axis of these its parameter
values the x-axis again it's time so
this parameter computed over a period of
a day for the large website you see
values are approximately in the range of
ten to fifteen whereas for completely
random uniform spoofing the value drops
the bar below 12 and show you another
parameter of an example of the
illustrator our approach let's take a
look at ttls so different IP
implementations will set their initial
ptl's the different values to three
thousand two so if you look at incoming
traffic this plot was the top cloth is
TTL values on the x-axis for incoming
traffic and the y-axis is a pack account
into a large data center and you see
there are your spikes at all powers of
two and the width of the spike if you
will indicates of the diameter of the
internet if you will at that particular
data center and this plot is extremely
stable across different time periods and
it sort of indicates a certain approach
for detecting whether we're seeing
smooth traffic or not or in general
attack traffic's but if an attacker is
actually not very truthful and decides
to completely randomized entire package
at the destination address and therefore
also including the ppl then we'll see
all sorts of packets in the big empty
regions where we know that it's very
unlikely especially legitimate traffic
by contrast if for instance having
reflect to attack we're whole bunch of
machines at one particular data center
that's a given number of hops away from
the victim if someone on to the fact is
effective from that they are sending
them it'll be a big spike presumably
from the TTL corresponding that data
center and again we can detect that
spike either by direct inspection
histogram or by looking at metrics like
the ratio standard deviation to mean as
evidenced in the bottom flaw
and use that to filter out the traffic
it seems improbable hopefully incurring
minimum collateral damage and process
and another example is packet length
I'll skip over it an interest of time
since he seems to be falling over when
scheduled but again the intuition is the
same to look at historical distribution
notice that there are patterns that
remain stable at given locations over
time for different time scales and then
to use that help us select the
aggregates are set to packets in which
to it that we suspect should be part of
the artifact okay so at this point I'm
going to switch over to the second part
of the path where the second question in
the agenda if you remember so let's
assume that we can identify with a good
degree of probability so distinguished a
traffic behind card without fat versus
fact that's how a legitimate on a
particular link so now of course where
the goal is to try to identify for
instance where that traffic centering
our network and possibly even move as
close as possible to source so the roads
of the plate an infrastructure that can
perform this task and awareness through
practice with incremental given time
constraints so then to remind you of
constraints that I listed earlier you
know a limited rival computation budget
certainty one operational bias against
Network change and in fact that attacked
racing might involve multiple
administrative domains and therefore
encourages potential policy or you know
human collaboration issues so our
approach is to minimize the change that
needs to happen to existing
infrastructure in particular the goal is
to not poke devices that are on the
network at all and to try to minimize
communication between different
administrative domain so first in
different ISPs and this
this piece of slide we're here which
I'll use to give an example of how the
protocol that we've implemented actually
operates is sort of the earth the
infrastructure plan to the floor but the
idea is at the bottom level there's
already deployed infrastructure routers
switches and so forth the goal is to
passively monitor links that are major
US or English links the particular
networks paramotoring infrastructure
communicating on each other and then to
define a well specified set of machines
and call knock servers to allow
communication between different
administrative domains so give you a
quick example before I move into some
details and some motivations for design
students that we've made lets us human
in some historical number one then
attack is happening on a link to assume
that a passive monitor is looking at
traffic on this link using some set of
heuristics effects of religion attack
and comes up with some signature
congestion shaken attack signature that
describes the traffic that's probably
causing the attacks that information is
then communicated in step 3 to what we
call out an op server which effectively
take this information generates a set of
queries that foreign things might be is
anyone seeing practice of this
particular time say UDP traffic with the
use of these particular ports or has
such and such payload hash and take this
query and propagates it to both other
domains so other peer knock servers and
two other monitors as in this
information is that the data collection
happened a complete distributed manner
and this information can then be
returned to the clearing master server
which can provide essential information
about English and egress points of the
suspect traffic to an operator these
this is just text of what I said and
really what I what I want to move to is
motivations for this design which as I
said we've for large degree implemented
so there's really three categories of
design criteria the design criteria for
the individual monitoring technology
that has obtained information about
attacks on a link the second is blank
right here for how the devices
communicate and third is really design
criteria for filtering how do you
influence filtering so the first thing
that we believe very strongly and I
guess this is in contrast to rather them
in the previous talk is that tapping
links is actually operationally the
least intrusive way of doing things we
we've tried again both approaches and I
guess both Rob and I have contrasting
anecdotal evidence but certainly many
operators of large high heavily loaded
routers don't like it when one has to
obtain information from those routers so
it appears that tapping the network at
the link level with the vector is fiber
splitters is the least intrusive we're
doing so this also provides increased
visibility and traffic to the different
since the data collection method like
net flow or see floaty that we use to
get data from router doesn't return say
TTL information we can do that through
direct packet inspection so things like
it more general approach it's the second
decision rated for monitoring devices
that really they should be storing state
of first because this enables historical
analysis which as I earlier can help to
decrease false positives and collateral
damage in general so the second is that
that can help to minimize into monitor
communications so some schemes have been
proposed where edge routers actually
send a traffic relating to be suspicious
across versus IP tunnels to some central
collecting agency which then tries to
determine whether traffickers process
call is the cause of us back or not and
that that seems to actually potentially
cause basket back on the monitoring
network itself and the idea in the
height of type of storage and monitors
is to enable each mine from phone
announced and in and simply
reply with your short yes no type
answers to the central information
gathering location so talking about
communication I believe that hierarchy
is key because providing a hierarchical
network can simplify into the main
administration it's much easier for each
ice P or a s to have you know one or two
machines that talk to other ISPs or a s
is about of the potential potentially
harmful cast when they're seeing that
they're seeing in trying to create a
vast authentication infrastructure that
would allow your monitors or edge
routers at arbitrary you know i'ma show
you deploy your ISP to talk to all other
such devices and other ISPs and even
though it's not really designed this
isn't something that I think you know we
very much advocate is an open standard
for communication because all these
devices were there embedded in router
whether standalone monitors in the end
if they if they don't communicate if
they don't have some open standard with
the snake and communicate of risk
becoming useless and really not being
deployed very widely and final bit of
religion with that our claim today is
filtering policy and weirder Suki things
there the first is the needs of separate
filtering from monitoring it's much
easier for me as a high-speed operator
to ask my peer is be whether they're
seeing a certain kind of traffic and
you'll help me track the traffic across
their network there it is to try to
impose a filtering strategy as part of
that tracking mechanism so the to
rethink kind of missed rated we need to
be separated and then the second filter
and design criteria is that there should
be really a human in the loop during
filtering but that this has not the case
then we were opening ourselves up to
people who especially smarter than the
designers of the monitoring system or
the filtration system to create das
packs implemented
the boss local system itself and so
those are two proposals that have been
your most influential design were were
traced back in push back in both of
these at some level are very elegant
because they make monitoring part of the
network itself but the thing that really
wanted to minimize that that's not
minimizing both of those honors its
changes to infrastructure that is ready
to Floyd today so forth of software
changes to routers and then read the
other important thing was to try to
separate a very cleanly filtering policy
from monetary policy of course
distributed monitoring as we call it has
its own challenges the first of course
is that it requires deployment of new
monitoring devices and really we see
this is a trade off either you change
infrastructure there that works and that
most people don't want to change or you
need to effectively deploy new devices
that are you know perform a specific
monitoring task as far as posting is
concerned it really seems to be no free
and easy solution if you try to filter
by our routers right by creating a CLS
for instance that might be used or you
know committed access rate type things
that can be used to filter traffic and
routers and we listen we risk decreasing
router performance and furthermore were
limited by the expressiveness of the ACO
language itself and if the weather
allows the filter by ppl and you know
there's no use to using pto basic
statistics using a dedicated device the
filter can solve both of these issues
both the speed and expressiveness and of
course introduces a new network element
so nothing things to come for free these
days and the final challenge really for
any scheme that attempts to do
distributed data analysis is to
generally
lament American should have open
standard for communication between these
devices just a quick word on our own
sort of implementation status if you
will the heuristics that I described
today as well as several others are
implemented devices that run them can
monitor up to eight gig e links at about
a million packets per second per link
and we had a fair degree of success
deploying on a number of commercial
networks where we've actually been able
to identify and help users the bug
denial of service attacks first version
of the monitoring protocol that I so
roughly described earlier is actually
implemented and we the focus that we're
that we are the area that we're focusing
on most is improving the detection of
heuristics and also building filtering
functionality so in conclusion I think
that combining aggregates to inspire
development with historical information
using multiple exits to try to
categorize and traffic is a promising
method of identifying an officer escape
while minimizing collateral damage and
their scheme like student monitoring
that actually imposes love the little
change to existing infrastructure and
minimizes inter-domain communication is
probably a reasonable way to go to try
to address Geoff's in our distributed
fashion and finally was the last thing
I'd like to leave you today leave with
you today is really that
interoperability between devices that
perform distributed de las analysis is
the key to their success and with that
if you have questions are you happy to
feel them
pleasure
one quick question before you leave as
we saw the the ambient level of attacks
on the network seems to be at a fairly
high level just on a day-to-day basis
and most of these systems seemed to be
extremely good at detecting the attacks
and telling me I'm being attacked almost
constantly which is not a very useful
piece of information um how well do
these systems are at prioritizing
attacks and telling me what are the big
attacks or how well can I tell them tell
me when this important thing is being
attacked as opposed to just picking up
every single d dose on my network well
can you hear me yes so it's really a
question of at some level threshold
setting so you know that the kind of
things of it so for instance if you one
possible things to look at Cynthia link
capacity and a one possible way to
define a DDoS attack or for that matter
a flash crowd is to look for instance at
congestion or router or high utilization
or link at that point you know you could
have a small icy or a home table user
could obviously have a different notion
of the professional for what of suspects
levels of traffic are relative to you
know what a big backbone might have
inertia that answers your question i
mean the as if there's two separate
problems the problem of detecting am i
under d left at the second one is you
know assuming that i am under ddos
attack then let me look at my traffic
and try to figure out which packets the
suspect in which don't
and the point that I mainly addressed in
this path was the latter so assuming
that we are assuming that the link is
congested are the things that I can look
at in the traffic sort of just observing
that link that helped me you know give
me some indication as to what might be
unusual and definitely bad and what /
isn't in use there's a question about
the unrealistic or not is really a
function of your if you're worried about
diamonds attacks and it's what your
suggested or not and if you're worried
about things like server attacks like
running out of TCP control blocks or
whatever surf Lud's then you re need
effectively information about server
state how do you think d dose or dos
attacks are in correlation with flash
crowds flash pass so the question is how
do dealers have to correlate with flash
files like what is how can they be how
they different or the same i guess my so
again going back to previous theme
detecting whether you're under a dart
attack or and then the second question
is you know what are the dots packets so
it seems to be quite difficult in
general to distinguish you know when you
see a traffic spikes to distinguish
immediately without the flash drive is
asked that except to the extent that you
can predict the flash crowd because it
might be related to marketing efforts or
publicity or whatever now as far as once
you've once you enter the suspicious
space and you decide to look at traffic
to see whether it's it might be a flash
browser announcer stack in the limit a
very very smart attacker that knows you
know what your or the TTL distribution
is your site looks like what those
addresses you see and so forth might be
able to engineer a gossip at that
actually looks indistinguishable for a
flash for them
but chances are that your most tools at
least for a while will generate the
packs that are distinguishable at least
in a few subtle parameters amount of
course if you perform one thing I guess
I'm the limit the worst kind of da stack
with the one that you want to least
allows of people you know all listen to
another world the BBC you know a
shortcut way radio and when it's noon in
London everyone picks wrote on their
browser right then there's really not
much you can do aside from you know up
some sort of read or you know other
kinds of fair queuing or routers and if
I understand correctly you're saying
that ACL and routers is not a very
successful solution yeah and but on the
other hand if you have to add a device
this means now I have to put this all
around my guess is that correct if you
and it has to be on the way of the main
routers for filter I talking about the
filtering problem I mean yes that's a
cell phone tablet or difficult phone and
and yes I mean that yeah either you can
do it may different ways you can well
today the simple place install an apple
on your router it probably won't work
for many kinds of tasks or at least
probably won't work in in the ways you'd
like us to for instance by one thing to
do is filter of course by destination
address and that would just completely
Spanish the let the victim another thing
is a deserve actual router hardware
changes so for instance some sort of a
high-speed filtering blade but I'm not
sure how far away that is and then of
course there's deployment of devices on
every rank and yes certainly it's it's a
logistical issue thank you
in your last answer you mentioned active
to management briefly not only a little
house in your last answer you mentioned
active queue management briefly I was
wondering if you're aware of any
research in using your normality filters
as you were discussing earlier as a way
of weighing an active queue management
algorithm in the case of a band with
consuming attack towards the edge where
an edge site could choose to drop
packets on a congested link that don't
fit the normality filter thereby
reducing the negative impact of an
attack although it wouldn't stop the
attack and I haven't seen any any
research towards actually doing that
that would be something that could be
deployed more towards the target of the
attack without many network
infrastructure changes so I'm actually
together some not completely I didn't I
haven't I don't I'm not familiar with
such research I don't know that anything
done I'm not completely sure I
understand your point you might want to
talk about it offline certainly
certainly a few management's based on
historical information might be might be
useful again with the same fear that I
have there is that if you try to
automatically drop packets based on
history then you can get into well
possibly very uh yeah that's how
problematic well if you're talking about
doing like a CL based on historical data
I can definitely see the room for
problems there but if you're looking at
a congested link a packet has to be
dropped there might be an advantage to
weighing that drop based on the normalcy
of the packet rather than just first-in
first-out or another probability metric
yeah well again you know I think unless
in that case things like red I think you
know things that are completely random
or you know what probability changes
based on the queue length seem like
they're the least likely to introduce
sort of vicious side effects that might
be exploited for the purposes i think if
we if you reach I to be smart about
filtering and these things like history
or whatever then that can be very useful
and I mean that's really what I'm
advocating I think that's something
where a human is to be involved or else
we're in trouble okay thank you yep