before Messi caps deployment a couple of
housekeeping things first of all glad
you're here second thing which people
try to move forward they've asked me to
ask you to try to move forward if you
can that would be that way I can see you
better there's these lights in my eyes
and all that good stuff second thing is
as I'm talking please whether the mic
opponent interrupts me don't wait for me
to see you
that probably won't so do interrupt me
I'll be glad to take your questions as
we go along and one should have some
time afterwards to talk about some
questions as well so my name is Bill
Nicholas I'm from the Argonne National
Laboratory just outside of Chicago
the access grid in the upper left-hand
corner of my slides is the project I've
been working on for the past year and a
half it's essentially a video
teleconferencing system that's a
architectural statement rather than a
furniture statement you know it's also
integrated with big computers and their
applications and so forth the thing
about the access grid is we've
intentionally designed it for a number
of reasons to require IP multicast
across the wide area so I got involved
because I'm pushing multicast out there
my colleagues sometimes call me the
multicast bullying because they'll take
a place that needs multicast and they'll
point me at them I'll call them up and
say hey your multicast is broken I can
help you so first of all we should talk
about what is multicast well multicast
is an IP delivery mechanism we're all
familiar with unicast we've got a sender
a source and a destination address on a
multicast packet in the multicast world
instead of sending to one destination
you send to a multicast group and the
intervening routers between your sender
and all the receivers who are interested
they all conspire you know this is Steve
Deering's word I really like it they all
conspire to get the data from the sender
to anybody who's interested the sender
doesn't know nor care necessarily if or
who those
Seavers are it's just the responsibility
of the network to get it there
again the destination IP address is
within the old Class D range to 24.0
slash four within that range you don't
actually have hosts listening that's the
group address it's you can think of it
as a place where you can get traffic
from will get any more of that in a
little bit little bit of notation you'll
see this in the literature this comes
from all the names blanking me I'll
remember it later specific source
addresses are referred to as s the group
addresses are referred to as G if you're
talking about a specific set of packets
or forwarding state having to do with
packets coming from a particular source
to a particular group that's referred to
as s comma G and you can see how it's
written if they're talking about all the
packets going to a group or forwarding
stated in router or whatever that's
referred to as star comma G I may slip
these into my talk later if I do it's
jargon I'm sorry and RP is the pin
sparkswood rendezvous point that's just
basically what just some notation so if
I flip them in my slides you'll know
what I'm talking about
there's two kinds of multicast to find
one is referred to be called just
multicast now then it was called the
internet standard multicast and then in
Minneapolis with the IETF they decided
it should be called any source multicast
in any source multicast the sender's
simply send multicast group address
packets they put them on the wire
whether it's an Ethernet or or whatever
and the network takes them from there
the senator just puts the packets on the
wire a receiver takes most learns about
the group somehow and that's we'll get
into that later and they register their
interest in the group they tell the
network hey I'm interested in all the
packets that might come in to the
network that have this group address
that is the packets that were given to
the network by a source with the
destination address of the
in the multicast group range the
receiver is used the IGMP version 2
protocol
I call them joins I think in the
standard they're called
igmp host membership reports or
something like that
I call them joins it's easy to remember
I know there's some people in the back
who could heckled me if they wanted to
the network this is important the in any
source multicast paradigm the network's
job is to keep track of all the senders
for the group and deliver packets from
all the senders to each interested
receiver for that group emphasize this
last left left bullet because this is in
contrast to the next slide I'm going to
talk about which is so specific
multicast this is in contrast with any
source multicast in this paradigm again
the sender's just send multicast group
address packets to the network there's
no difference on the sender side however
in this case receivers register their
interest in specific sources that are
sending to specific groups they do this
typically by way of the internet group
management protocol IGMP version 3 and
one way of militating this is the IgM
tv3
does s comma G joins that is group
membership reports the network does not
need to know where all the sources are
because the receiver is telling the
network hey I want the traffic from this
source that's addressed to this group
the receivers are responsible for
specifying which senders traffic they
want to receive this is the crucial
difference in any source multicast it's
the network's job to keep track of where
all the sources are for a group in
source-specific multicast it's the job
of the application to keep track of
where all the sources are or any sources
that the receiver is interested in
listening to one of the piece of
housekeeping can you read this anybody
not able to read this okay the buttons
I've been given out are referring to
reach ability if you look at one of the
buttons I've been given out it says
reach ability on it what I'm going to be
doing for the next few minutes just
talking about this this phrase reach
ability
and I'm emphasizing something here in
earlier time I gave a talk like this I
offered somebody 20 bucks if they could
show me in the internet standards where
it was well
somebody came awfully close so close I'm
not going to offer any money but that's
for unicast for multicast I'm pretty
sure reach ability in the unicast world
this is what we all do every day here
what reach ability means in the unicast
world is the its interpreted that is
it's not necessarily clearly defined
it's hard to go wrong from the
definitions that are there but I I still
don't think it's really well defined
what it means when you get a bgp reach
ability advertisement what that means is
pretty much 7 e IP packets with
destination addresses that match this
advertisement and I'll get them closer
to their results in sort or their
address that's that's kind of a social
contract between the autonomous systems
if I give you reachability information
you can send me packets and I'll try to
get them closer to where they belong
and if you're on a Cisco router or you
pretty much everybody here knows how to
run a Cisco router but when you look at
reachability information for a specific
destination is you type show IP route
and then you give it the address and the
router tells you what it's going to do
with packets that are addressed with
destination addresses ok this is in
contrast to the concept of reach ability
in the multicast in the context of
multiple of a multicast
this one I know for darn sure is not
defined by internet standards yet it's
still in flux again you can make
arguments based on inferences and the
standards to get a pretty good idea but
it's not well defined what multicast
reachability has interpreted by
implementation in practice that is if
you go by a Juniper or you go get gate D
from next top or Cisco what you'll get
is this interpretation and that is a
reach ability advertisement with a
prefix is where to get the IP packets
from sources that match that
advertisement notice the difference in
the unicast world
you're talking about where to send the
packet in the multicast world we're
talking about where to receive those
packets from whether you ask for them or
whether you just receive them that's a
little bit more detailed
the point is it's inverted from what you
might normally expect now in a Cisco
router again because it's most common
the way you can find out where you
really get packets from from a given
source is through this command the show
IP RPF this is equivalent to the earlier
command I talked about for unicast show
IP route there's another command we used
in Cisco's to talk about multicast but
this is not this is the command you use
to see reach ability the other command
you may have heard about is something
else entirely and we'll get into what
that is in a few minutes so here's an
example
seriously I hope you can read this what
I did is I took the machine that I if I
run my screen session on back at the lab
and I'm wearing it stat - RN this is a
pretty typical Linux box you can see on
the first line well you got headers and
so forth the first line talks about the
reach ability for the interface in this
case the interface has an IP address of
114 at 221 dot 11.1 o3 there's no
gateway that doesn't make any sense in
the context of an interface it's netmask
is a slash 32 because again this is an
interface that has a single host route
or is a single route and you can see
which interface is associated with its
eth0 Ethernet 0 yo whose multihomed host
would have different options but anyway
now the second piece of really
flexibility information this this
particular host has is the subnet to
which it's directly connected as it
happens this machine is connected to a
network that has a net MacOS net mask
2/22
because of the number of hosts on it as
you can see the base address for this
prefix is 1:40 that to 21.8 again
there's no gateway involved this is the
local network it's net mask if I said as
a slash 22 the flag is you for it to the
network and again if you want to get if
it wants to get packets to 148 up to 28
0 / 22 destiny
it's going to go to eth0 the next line
is pretty standard on pretty much any
UNIX boxer or what in any IP host really
if you want to get to the 127 Network
you'd said what are the loopback device
it's always internal nothing nothing
strange here and skipping one line you
look at the last one 0 dot 0 dot 0 with
the net mask of 0 dot 0 dot 0 that's the
default route here the Gateway makes
sense because that's the default route
to the outside world 140 or 221 dot 11
up to 53 you know that's an H SRP
address for a couple of routers you
don't know the drill
again this is but this time we have a
gateway address a gateway flag and an
interface it says if you're going to go
to that gateway you use that interface
this sounds for dancing but I'm setting
the stage to explain the next to the
bottom line here the next in the bottom
line is the multicast line ok where we
have the reachability information for
multicast we reasonably know it's
multicast is because where it says
destination it's 220 4.0 0.0 and the net
mask is the slash 4 well just telling
the kernel is if you're interested in
multicast traffic where you go to get
that traffic is that Ethernet interface
this has nothing to do with where the
traffic is sent it has well may have
something to do with it but the point is
it's more important to remember the
business where the multicast traffic is
going to come from in fact this is one
thing that was not in the standard Linux
distributions that we had we have to put
this static route in there to tell the
colonel if you're going to get multicast
traffic for your clients that are
running on your on your platform you
have to get that traffic from the
Ethernet interface that's where you talk
IGMP version version 2 in this case out
of this is reach ability on the host
side again we have the duality here we
have the where does the traffic come
from and where does the traffic go to
depending on whether you're talking
multicast or unicast here's an example
of reach ability for you know on the
Cisco box ok this is my brother router
Kiwi as its name
here the river louder is a couple hops
away from the host I was talking about
but I'm going to talk about reach
ability in terms of unicast right now so
I do the show IP route and I put the IP
address in for the host and we get the
sort of standard stuff we're used to see
it happens that I'm running OS PF you
can see the distance the metric and all
that good stuff it's got a Gigabit
Ethernet interface it heard it you know
three hours ago or whatever and when it
wants to send a packet somewhere it's
going to send it by way of Gigabit
Ethernet 5/0 and it's going to send it
to the next hop which is 140 up to 20
1.20 dot 124 that happens to be the IP
address of the intervening router again
no rocket science here this is what
we're used to doing on a day-by-day
basis on the other hand if my router
says you know I need to get traffic from
148 at 221 dot 11.1 o 3 this is how I
find out where this router is going to
get that traffic from it's a different
command show IP RPF in this case it
tells me that it's going to get the
traffic from interface Gigabit Ethernet
5/0 no surprise the same sort of thing
the RPF neighbor is this router we
referred to earlier the route and mask
it tells me where I got that information
from in some cases you may have
divergent unicast and multicast paths in
this case we don't and some other
information emphasized here the unicast
and multicast paths may diverge and use
different commands to look them up
unique asking your show IP route
multicast you to show IP RPF to look
find out what that topology is okay some
of us may have heard of the old mbone
some of us may still be on the old mbone
the I the slide here used to be why the
EM vote should go away and somebody
yelled at me and they were right the old
mbone is an excellent first
approximation this is not that hadn't
been done before and so it's really hard
to fault the people who started the
unknown architecture used tunnels to get
multicast traffic across the unicast
only Network the old internet the
routing was done again this was an
experiment it was done by user space
demons run on general-purpose UNIX boxes
ethically some threes the IGMP protocol
internet group management protocol was
developed in this context this is one
piece of the old mbone architecture that
hasn't changed until we get to SSN IGMP
is it turns out to be a very good
interface and we've held that up held
that over another thing about the old M
book people sometimes get confused
between the M bone and an application
used on the N bone called SDR notice
that the M bone predates the World Wide
Web the reason that the M bone has this
session directory application so tightly
associated with it is because you had to
have a directory system to find sources
or sessions that you were interested in
and you didn't have the infrastructure
we have today for the World Wide Web so
that's why you'll see SDR sessions refer
to a lot of the time in fact if this
particular conference there's two ways
to get the information about the
multicast group you can get it off the
SDR or you can get it off an an on web
pages either way will work some lessons
we learn from the in Bowen yes sir the
use of SBI there one nice aspect of
using multicast to distribute the
program information is it then scoping
rules allow it to go to exactly the same
places as the program information can go
and so there can be problems when using
the web as the mechanism for making
program listings that you can find a
listing for something that you can't
actually get access to all the way
that's a little further I will in Prak
in in theory I agree with you completely
there's some practical problems with
that however I'll get into that a little
later some lessons we learn from the
mbone from first thing that the first
lesson that's come out of this is that
the mbone routing protocol dvmrp simply
doesn't scale okay it's essentially the
multicast equivalent of rip I doubt that
there are many Internet service
providers today who will give their
clients a full feed of unicast routes
using rip if there are
I'm sorry customers I don't know but
that's what dvmrp did is it flooded the
reach ability information for sources on
a regular basis just like rip does
because of this and because of some
other things about it it was easy to
create IP multicast amplifiers this is
where you get reach ability it's like a
it's like a routing loop but instead of
just being a routing loop at every hop
you sprint you're spewing off additional
packets from every hop because it's a
tree fan-out thing and so you'd end up
melting the place down if you had a
routing loop not just the links involved
another problem with dvmrp in the mbone
implementation is it involves separate
routing infrastructure that wasn't
aligned with what became bgp so this was
an application testbed as opposed to
something that could be managed as a
service with all the the policies that
are involved another thing that they
learn from the mbone is that a technique
for multicast routing called flood and
croon doesn't scale flood and prune is
where i let's say i'm sending traffic i
send you all the traffic that i've got
until you tell me to stop I refer to
this as hurt me until I tell you to stop
okay the reason this doesn't scale there
are several reasons but two of the big
ones here it's not sensitive to the
available bandwidth okay I will keep
sending you traffic regardless of
whether you have receivers that care
whether or not it over subscribes your
links it doesn't matter I just send you
the traffic until you tell me to stop on
a regular basis and the second reason is
that in this situation the failure modes
are horrible if your router can't handle
this kind of traffic if it can't keep up
with this kind of traffic if it can't
send you the prunes because it's
overwhelmed or crashed or something
you're just going to keep getting the
traffic and you're going to be stuck in
this in this in this stable state of
being down this is not a good thing
so it requires downstream routers that
are that are powerful and smart enough
to be able to send all the prune message
is necessary this is this is a feature
of
Apryl a flood and prune protocol
examples of flood improvement protocol
ARP in dense mode and again the original
implementation of multicast routing
dvmrp need the MRP did both the reach
ability in the forwarding and it had
these these problems with it so some of
the lessons that have been applied to
this the multicast border gateway
protocol and I got the wrong slides oh
no I didn't this is not the multicast
quarter gateway protocol this is the
multi protocol border gateway protocol I
forgot to update this look the
multi-protocol border gateway protocol
it provides reach ability and policy
control for multicast routing just as it
does for unicast routing you have all
the knobs ranging from you know length
comparisons to a s path length
comparisons to local prep to metrics all
those things are available to you with
the multi protocol border gateway
protocol second thing you need is a
forwarding scheme that is actually how
you move packets from one economist
system or one router to another and the
protocol that has ended up sort of
winning the Darwinian evolution battle
here is the protocol independent
multicast sparse mode or pin sparse mode
where protocol independent multicast the
protocol independent refers to the fact
that it's independent of the underlying
reachability protocols so you can run
him over a network that uses any other
reachability protocol underneath this is
again in contrast to dvmrp or dvmrp have
a combined reach ability and forwarding
protocol features of pin sparse mode
include listeners receive traffic only
when they want it they have to do
something affirmative to get traffic and
they have to continue to do something
affirmative to get traffic second thing
is the pin does again likes or liked
dvmrp it forms a multicast distribution
tree that is you start with a sender and
you go from the sender to the local
designated router and as necessary you
get a branching structure tree that
distributes traffic from the sender to
all the receivers
a feature of this tree
is that no more than one copy of the
packet needs to reverse any any edge on
that tree which makes for very efficient
distribution and packet replication in
terms of link bandwidth requirements M
BGP is good him sparse mode is good
the thing with PIM sparse mode is it
only scales so far typically within a an
autonomous system so what you need is
another protocol to distribute the
knowledge of all the available sources
in the Internet and so a protocol called
MSBP or the multicast source discovery
protocol was developed multicast source
discovery protocol is a way for pin
sparse mode rendezvous points to talk to
each other to tell each other where the
active sources are so they can form
these trees between pin domains a pim
domain is a set of routers that share a
pin rendezvous point we'll get into this
little more detail so drilling down a
little bit further into each of these
protocols Multi multi protocol BGP comes
from RFC 28:58 where it adds the MP
reach NLR I attribute to BGP what this
does is it advocate it identifies a
reach ability advertisement as whether
it's unicast whether it's multicast or
for efficiency whether it's both there's
there's two bits and 0 0 is undefined so
that's going to year 3
as I said earlier when implemented a
router you get all the standard BGP
machinery for choosing reach ability
with that you're going to use and
forwarding it to your peers and all that
good stuff it's just just exactly the
right thing you need for scalability of
reach ability information and it's in an
internetwork
of autonomous systems another thing to
be aware of is that multi-protocol BGP
routes can be independent of that is the
topology of reach ability can be
different between unicast and multicast
so you may decide that some set of here
peer autonomous systems you'll only
exchange multicast with or the chill
only exchange unique amps to it
this is actually pretty common some of
the research networks have considerably
more open peering policies for multicast
traffic than they do for unicast traffic
I'm not going to try to figure out why
but that's just the way it is and this
supports that model where you have
differences between your multicast
community has to copy rings it allows
that topology to be generated and used
in in two separate two separate ways
so to configure multi-protocol bgp i'll
go through these slides reasonably
quickly but I've got configuration
information here francisco for the next
top technology gate d as well as for
juniper so you can get a flavor for what
do you have to do to bring up reach
ability multi-protocol bgp reach ability
communication so differences here the
second line you had the NLRA unicast
multicast which tells the router hey
this prefix that I'm putting into vgp
will be used for both unicast and
multicast you tell it the name your
neighbor statement that you're going to
be exchanging unicast and multicast
routes whether that's a standard stuff
description vbn as soft configuration
and they have a route map and if we're
inbound and outbound when you go to see
what the route map looks like what I'm
showing here is that you could treat the
inbound and outbound prefixes
differently you can set them to
different values if you wish you can
filter out prefixes from unicast and not
from multicast or vice-versa
you can set different LEDs or local
weights or local prefs whatever you want
to do cxs plus 50 is the list of
prefixes I used that in the earlier
config or the alert and here's a prefix
list again that I used in the route map
these are these slides are in the in the
talks also just get by them for gate D
it's a similar sort of situation you're
basically telling it you're going to be
speaking in BGP and you know there it is
one thing in vgp in India is it
specifically calls out the fact that
there are two routing information basis
here you've got a unicast routing
information base a rib and a multicast
one and it talks about how your than the
importing and outputting for that and
again this is talking about where you're
going to be sending these networks to
autonomy system 145 again in juniper
juniper has to several routing
information basis I net zero is your
unicast forwarding table
iein 8.2 is your multicast reach ability
table I think I net dot one I don't want
to guess I know that I net dot 2 is your
multi cast for each ability table you
can look into in the Juniper
documentation those people from Juniper
here you can tell you all about it what
they're doing here is they're putting in
some static reach ability information
into the ina to routing information base
just basically these are the multicast
equivalent of static routes again
multicast world you're telling it you
know if I get if I want traffic from
these places this is where I'm going to
get it from in the case of multi
protocol BGP you're talking about you
have to tell the various protocols which
sets of reach ability written id's
you're going to be using this is some
examples again UCI net 0 and I knit to
you see for the multicast routing group
its I net two for the interfaces that
are capable those are ina and I to know
this you can get into more detail about
this what you need to take home from
this is that there are two tables of
reach ability information here's where
you set up a peer if you have a juniper
in protocol BGP this is a appearing
between one of my peers in Oregon where
I work we've got the policy who you're
going to accept what prefixes you're
going to accept from them what prefixes
you're going to announce to them what
they're appear autonomous system is what
their IP address is again this is very
similar to a unicast peering you just
have a couple extra
a couple extra statements to make sure
that multi-campus reach ability
information is being turned on when you
when you want to look at this Cisco also
has two sets of reach ability
informations that you can look at in in
in in Cisco if you want to look at the
multicast reach ability from BGP you do
a use show IP em BGP commands as opposed
to show IP BGP show IP BGP is unicast
show IP m BGP as multicast so here's an
example of running show IP m v GP some
i've taken out you know all but one of
them you can see the typical stuff the
neighbor the version the autonomous
system yada yada yada and the number of
prefixes you've received these prefixes
again are multicast reachable prefixes
if you do it without the M in BGP you
know in the case of at the time there
was a lot more I'm not sure what the
differential is anymore I looked you
want to look at a specific prefix again
this is sort of standard stuff you do
show IP m BGP to look at a specific
address to see what reach ability
information you have for it as you can
see here we've picked number two where
it's coming from
from VV NS - I think that socks but I
could be wrong 104 90 and we've picked
that protect that reach ability
information over the longer autonomous
system path information from es 24 the
NASA the NASA network there you know for
obvious reasons it's a shorter I asked
on a Juniper you want to do the same
sorts of things you do a show I show bgp
neighbor and you give it the IP address
of a neighbor you get a bunch of
information but the key thing you want
to look for in this is the event is the
NL RI is advertised for inet unicast
tonight at multicast for the session if
I met unicast and multicast and that you
are for table I met zero which is your
unicast and I know to you are receiving
prefixes from your neighbor that go into
both ribs that's you know the peat what
you do to look at it here here's another
example
just like the Cisco one
this isn't my router so I was able to
use my host address you can see that
they have quite a few paths multicast
reachable paths to get to me the one
they're choosing is the direct path a s
path 683 they could go by way of Abilene
one one five through seven just to me
they could go by way of e vns to me they
can go by way of their campus network to
me or they could go by way of Vario to
me you know that's the reach ability
information they have and again in
situations like this where your
multi-home you need BGP to make the
decision for you in terms of reach
ability I don't have a gate key
monitoring this I'm sorry move on to pin
spar smoke multi-cap rota call BGP gives
you the reach ability information this
is a relatively static topology if you
will now when you want to talk about
actually moving packets around the
protocol you use for this is well that
it's typically used for this is pin
sparse mode somebody want to ask
somebody a couple of you weeks ago asked
me if PIM is a Cisco thing the answer is
very much no it's an RFC it's a standard
it's implemented by a bunch of people
you can get it from a lot of different
vendors RFC 2362 defined sparse mode one
of the nice things about PIM sparse mode
is there's no activity in pin sparse
mode until either a host starts
transmitting traffic at which point you
have to do sometimes stuff or if a host
subscribes to a group if neither of
those things happen to your network you
don't get any pins far support activity
that means a few things one of which is
that you can't do bug it if you don't
have sources and receivers in PIM sparse
mode you define a rendezvous point in
order to distribute the knowledge of the
active sources you have to have a
rendezvous point that gets the
information from all about all the
sources and redistributes it down a
shared tree for each for so that's what
PIM sparse mode does is creates a shared
tree rooted at the rendezvous point
which is defined typically by
configuration there's some automatic
ways to define where the rendezvous
point is I prefer configuration for
reasons we'll get into given enough
traffic being sent to the rendezvous
point well what happens is that the
traffic gets from the source to the
designated router on the local network
it's encapsulated to the rendezvous
point then down the shared tree if you
get enough traffic the rendezvous point
says hey everybody look don't get the
traffic for me get it from him he's the
one sending it and so everybody then
does source-specific joins towards that
source this is called a source based
distribution tree and typically enough
traffic to trigger the creation of these
is typically anything greater than zero
it just works better that way
another thing to be aware of is that
anytime you've got traffic moving
between pim domains those distribution
trees are always but always source based
those are source based there are is no
such thing as a shared tree in current
practice between autonomous systems or
between PIM rendezvous points I see
somebody can give you the microphone no
ok here's a diagram that I would use
I've already walked you through most of
it
if you're using a shared tree what that
means is the source sources package is
grabbed by the router a in this case
sources of the top receivers at the
bottom right away grabs that packet
encapsulate sit in the unicast packet
sends it to the rendezvous point the
rendezvous point then sends it out to
anybody who's interested in that group
in that case it's router C ok there's
enough traffic that announcement that
that that traffic to get set out the
shared tree has a bit set that says you
know you really ought to create your own
source-based tree so router C will send
a message hey I know you've got this
source there
I want traffic from it and router a
whilst on the traffic directly from
router a to routers C and then to the
receiver which obviously is more
efficient rather than running into the
rendezvous point that could become a
bottleneck ok that's great in within an
autonomous system if you've got a bunch
of autonomous systems you want the
inaudible points in those autonomous
systems to be able to communicate the
knowledge of active sources in order to
do that we use a protocol called MSBP
this one isn't yet an RFC
it's real close last I saw we were
either entering her in the last call
stage and they have gone actually out of
my last call stage I haven't been
following
it's being done out of the MSTP working
group of the ITF and there's the draft
if you want to go read it clearly it
only covers ipv4 there's some talk that
ipv6 should be done a different way
that's still under discussion again the
rendezvous points communicate amongst
themselves to find the active sources
and then once I have the active sources
and they have interest within their
domain for those sources they send pins
parsable joins toward each other there's
a sports-specific
sparse more joined towards each active
source and then they that that's how
they graft on to the internet wide
distribution tree for that source in
that group in the internet I should also
say a couple things about MSTP that
aren't on my slides one of them is that
the MS DP connections between autonomous
systems are between PIM rendezvous
points are TCP they're not UDP like like
other things and they MSD fee also
follows the reach ability information
typically from multi-protocol BGP like
PIM sparse mode does so the if you'd say
it's not a it's a flooding protocol but
the flooding is extremely constrained
should not flood the knowledge of a
given source more than once a minute
and currently scalability doesn't seem
to be a problem I think last time I
looked we got enough like 3900 sources
in the internet kata does a good job of
tracking that over time okay
leachability again I've got a whole
bunch of these pins and now you can
understand what I mean by these pins
reach ability there's two things to
dealing with reach ability you have the
where to of reach ability for unicast
and you have the lengths of reach
ability for multicast it's a duality
these pins say both of them i've got
pins on both ends of these tables if you
want to come pick them up whatever in
bgp nli multicast router is a statement
of reach ability
this case reach ability means the
ability get traffic from a given source
you know domain PIN sparse mode joins
follow that reach ability the traffic
coming back is the inverse of that
topology reach ability is a directed
graph you can think of it that way and
the traffic follows the reverse of each
edge of that directed graph again MSBP
forwarding between rendezvous points
follows the BGP reach ability to apology
that's rule number one in the MSTP
giraffe pretty much is you know if
you've got the next hop and it's that
direction that's where you get your
that's we accept things from this means
something and that is if you're if
you're announcing something with n BGP
this is not this goes back to my earlier
thing where m bgp or multi-protocol bgp
multicast semantics reach ability
semantics are defined in practice if
you're doing multi-protocol bgp even if
you're doing PIM sparse mode if you're
not doing M SDP what you've just formed
is an MSD P black hole we ran into this
earlier this year in the in the December
January February time frame where there
were some MSBP storms and some transit
networks just turned off MSD P this was
not good because the sources behind them
their customer sources the knowledge of
those sources were not made available to
the rest of the Internet and we couldn't
get their traffic because our routers
had no idea that those sources even
existed so turning off MSD P if you've
got multi-protocol BGP turned on is a
bad thing and Here I am standing in
front of an are saying please don't do
this
it hurts that's one of the reasons I'm
here they pay me to come up and say
these things ok configuration for a gate
key and I'm sorry for PIM sparse and
MSBP I'll run through these real quick
last I didn't get any miss TP
configuration for gate D I understand
it's coming
soon Finn sparse is released he can
figure on gate D you say I'm gonna do
IGMP on this interface and I'm gonna do
thin sparse you know that's that's
pretty straightforward in Sisko
configuration you do some a combination
of interface commands for PIN sparse
mode configuration and you do some
global bone commands for EM SDP on the
interface side the two things you add to
on appearing between you and somebody
else is you or four things you first of
all you say pin sparse mode between you
and another another autonomous system
you say you're a pin boarder that way
well you see a pin border and you put a
boundary with an access control list
there are some automatic discovery
mechanisms implemented Auto RP + RP
discovery that allow a networks up
automatically self discover where the
rendezvous point is intent for reasons
having to do with debugging I don't like
that that's it's that sort of an
engineering decision but that's sort of
where I come down on the engineering
decisions one thing that's important
though to do is to make sure that you
don't advertise your rendezvous point to
somebody else or you don't accept
advertisement for somebody else's
rendezvous point that would not be a
good thing things are very confusing in
that situation so you put in a border
statement which does one of them and
then there's a IP multicast boundary
with an access control list number you
use to to do the other one I don't
remember whether it's anyway another
thing you say between autonomous systems
is you put in two threshold so that
packets that don't have a TTL this much
or more they don't transit this this
appearing this is useful so you can do a
scoping of where this multicast traffic
is going to go based on TTL let's say me
yeah so the access list ten here it's
just the fiscal RP announced you don't
want this traffic either leaving or
entering your network and you also
probably don't want traffic in the
administrative leave scope range to
enter or leave your
and so that's why that's the access list
that is associated with that interface
daily MSBP peering is again it's just
it's just a peering configuration got an
IP address description you decide what
to filter incoming and outgoing we'll
look at that ACL in a minute sa request
and TTL threshold sa request that says
you know when I bring up the peering
send me all these source advertisements
you've got otherwise you'd have to wait
for up to a minute and a half for all of
them to populate your cache it's just
bootstraps quicker and the last line is
now obsolete because as of the latest
draft for MSTP sa caching is mandatory
access most 111 this is partial this is
partially what's out there I'm working
on the draft that will try to codify
this in the anymore you want to stop
some things like for example you don't
want
let's see Sun RPC you probably don't
care to do an R who - a and get
everybody in the internet just maybe you
do I don't want you to be able to okay
another one down there is the old SGI
dog fight you know I really enjoy that
game unfortunately the tradition of
filtering this happened when that was
just too much traffic for the internet
nowadays you know the people who put SGI
dog that would probably be filtering all
the do you know that there's there's no
an implementation of quake that uses
multicast so you can watch players in a
tournament you know that would probably
get put on there because it's at the
same level some other things you want to
deny you want to deny the administrative
with scoped areas assuming you want to
control the administrative with scoped
areas within your autonomous system
that's an assumption you want to filter
the martians and then after that you
want to accept any you might if you're a
if you're not a transit network also
only permit outgoing addresses that you
own as sort of a belt-and-suspenders
approach okay I don't have all the
details on juniper MSD P and let's you
do the same things but
go through the pin and MSTP now for pin
you have to tell pin which routing
information based group you're going to
use you tell pin in juniper and I don't
have the Cisco stuff but we should do
the same thing that Cisco you say the
rendezvous point is going to be local
and it's address is going to be in this
case on the border router and you say
all the interfaces should run Tim
version 2 sparse mode you know again
pretty straightforward on for MSBP again
use the multicast routing group rib
group in this case and this shows
appearing between this router and in my
network you have appeared you have a
local address the local address in this
case is the rendezvous point address
from this you can probably figure out
where this router is oh mfdp also in the
in juniper lets you apply import and
export policies here which is highly
recommended it's just I don't have that
example here yet ok again how do we
monitor each of them how do we look at
them and see which ones are on my dream
to them how do we look and see how
things are going first thing you want to
do with ms is is make sure that MSBP has
actually come up on on cisco you can do
this with a show IP MSD piece um and you
can see the peer addresses there in this
case this was my hearing with vbn SAS
145 peer address stayed up this is good
it's been up for a day in 12 hours it's
been reset 11 times since I set up
appearing and you'll do the DNS lookup
on the name in juniper it's a very
similar command it's you want to look
and see if the peering is up is to show
MSBP peer give it the address and you
get back again the peer address the
local address you're using its
established and it's been up for two
weeks five days 18 now or something like
that yeah it's up this is a good thing
you can get in more detail on both of
these
next thing you want to do if in fact you
you've got a mess DP up you want to make
sure that you're getting active sources
that is you've got reach ability
information is being properly
interpreted on Cisco you do a show IP
MSD PSA cache in this case I'm looking
up a particular multicast group I get
lots of entries there the entries here
we need to go and talk about just a
little bit we see these two these two
addresses and parenthesis that's the s
comma G I was talking about the source
in the group MSD P tells you the source
and the group of an active source it
also tells you the rendezvous point that
generated this source announcement so
that's the third address one thing
that's commonly not understood of MSD P
is that the reach ability information
that MSTP uses is not the source
it's the rendezvous point that generated
the advertisement this is important if
you're setting up MSD P so you make sure
that your rendezvous point address is
actually advertised by you for multicast
purposes
otherwise your MSTP peers are going to
drop all your stuff on the floor and
that's not a good thing
again we only need GPA s 145 that's just
a lookup in the reach ability table and
from this it looks like that source has
been active for three hours and 40
minutes and that source will expire in
five minutes and three seconds unless we
hear another another announcement of it
and in this case if you do this right
now you'll get a bunch of these in
juniper you can do the same or you the
equivalent command is show MSD P source
active and then for group and this is a
different group again you get the group
address you get the source address you
get the peer from which this was heard
and the originator is the rendezvous
point that originated this in the first
place so as you can see this router is
getting this announcement from four of
its peers but they're all coming from
the same rendezvous point
now if you if you're going to be
assuming your router knows about the
source and you've got interested
listeners you want to do a show IPM
route count that's actually not right
that's that's wrong I think that's show
IPM route anyway it's a command very
much like this I may have count in the
wrong place should be at the end
probably what this tells you is that in
this group but on the very bottom in
this group to 24 2007 t 7.1 55 source
128 on 163 dot 3.2 14 it has forward and
7089 packets it's getting zero packets
per second this is not a good thing the
packets that it used to get were about
forward maybe basis and kilobits a
second is zero this is how you tell to
see if packets are actually coming into
your network properly from the outside
now assuming they were one thing you
want to know is from which peer am I
actually asking for traffic and which my
interfaces am I am i sending traffic
towards this is where you use the show.i
p.m. route command notice that this has
nothing to do with reach ability this
has to do with actual packet forwarding
state
don't confuse show IP route with show IP
Emerald they've they're they're
orthogonal and function in this case
looking Genesis at this source the
source is 128 X 160 3.3 to 14 in the
group to 24.2 that 177 dot 155
this state has been there for three
hours fifty-five minutes it's going to
go away in three minutes if there's no
traffic flag m-meaning was created by
MSD PT is it's it's a source-based tree
which is sort of the way they've all
gotta be because it's an MSD painting
the incoming interface this tells me
that the traffic should be coming in on
ATM 3/0 to 145 I happen to know this is
my peering with Abilene autonomous
145 the RPF neighbor is one 92.5 out 179
130 that's the address of my peering
with with BB NS and it shows me that
this router has received requests for
traffic from that source on two of its
interfaces ATM 0 to 16 and 18 0 to 100
so this router is receiving if it were
to receive a packet it would come in on
the ATM 3 0 145 sub-interface it would
replicate that packet and send one copy
out each of ATM 0 to 16 and 18 0 200
juniper has a very similar command of
course shell multicast route group 233
to 170 1.1 source prefix again a source
address and then I use the word
extensive to make sure I get all the
same information here you've got the
group address you've got the source
prefix it's a slash 32 because it's a
source specific thing you can see the
number of packets that have come in on
this it is the upstream interface is ATM
100.6 283 that's their sub interface to
get the packets for my source and again
I missed it but you can also find out I
don't have the command here
unfortunately what the downstream
interfaces are with juniper I'm sure the
Juniper people know I just forgot to put
it on the slide the important thing to
remember here again is this is not reach
ability information this is actual
packet forwarding information based on
active sources and active receivers oh
this is the downstream so if you want to
see who has essentially joins for four
sources use the show pin join command
and it tells you the upstream interface
is and the downstream interfaces are
going back to this one the useful thing
is I've run the same command twice you
can see the packets are coming because
packet count is higher in the upper one
in the Laurel one so you just use the up
arrow return up or a return to make sure
the packet
or incrementing here you can see where
they're going to and where they came
from
Shope enjoin etc okay some tips somebody
said that an expert as somebody who's
made all the mistakes in a very narrow
field here's some tips from somebody
who's made a lot of mistakes on an ATM
hearings is this best done with
point-to-point sub interfaces as opposed
to points multi-point one way to sort of
think about this is in a
point-to-multipoint inter sub interface
what you're doing is you're emulating a
multi access network in a multi access
network depends sparse mode protocol
requires you to elect a designated
router what this really is is a bunch of
point-to-point interfaces a designated
router needs to be able to see all the
traffic in the multi access network so
I'm not even sure what a designated
router in the context of an ATM exchange
point is there are some extensions of
him sparse mode that allow you to use I
think it's called
NBN a mode or something like that my
experience this is my experience talking
here is that it's better to do this with
point-to-point sub interfaces and my
experience is you don't have to you
don't have to interact with your peers
in order to make all of your unicast
connections point-to-point it's a little
longer in the configuration but when you
go to turn on multicast it's very much
simpler to debug and operate another
thing to be aware of MSD P source active
messages are essentially just pin
register messages somebody may complain
to you that your autonomous system isn't
sending them MSTP source active messages
this problem may not become your border
router chances are this problem isn't
your designated router right next to
your source there are some unfortunately
there's there are some bugs in
designated router implementations where
they stop sending Tim registers which
means that order router stops
source actives which means the rest of
the world doesn't know to start sending
joins towards you what you know this has
happening is because some people who've
been listening to your source for a
while continue to get the traffic but
somebody else who gets interested in
your source can't get your traffic
because there's no knowledge of that
source out in the Internet if you want I
can tell you the bug numbers and all
that good stuff but this is something to
keep in mind MSBP encapsulates data and
its source active messages just like
they were capsulated in the pin sparse
mode this is going back to the earlier
question from what i can tell this was
done primarily to support bursty sources
they call them or sources that don't
transmit enough to have a source
specific tree or are not judged worthy
to have a source specific tree and i
believe because of the low frequency of
advertisements of SDR this was one of
the driver applications another one
people have talked about is ntp what
worries me about sorry what worries me
about ntp is that ntp really truly does
want to know what the round trip is like
and I'm not sure what round trip means
in the context of multicast so what this
ends up saying what I've observed what's
going to scar I have is that it's
possible for M SDP to be operating
correctly the pin sparse mode is not
again this goes back to one of the big
reasons often is because they're using
point-to-multipoint interfaces it look
like PIM is working you've got the reach
ability information from from
multi-protocol BGP but you can't
actually do any joints the problem is if
the debugging tool you're using is SDR
you're not you're getting a bad view
because this data is encapsulated in
your M SDP source actives it gets sent
down the shared tree within your pin
sparse mode domain it shows up on your
on your display as you've got sources
but if you try to click on them you
don't get any source you don't get any
actual traffic because things are broken
and it's really hard to tell unless you
have active sources and active
destinations and FDR doesn't count
because of its low frequency and the
fact that it's data is encapsulated in
MSTP so these are some of the tips will
lead into a little bit about debugging
here and okay we don't tell you that
let's talk about debugging multicast as
I've said two or three times already in
order to debug multicast
you must have at least one constantly
active source when the internet was
small enough you could coordinate the
people who are going to do the debugging
today you file trouble tickets and you
coordinate trouble tickets between knobs
you can't assume that you're going to
get in to end people on the knocks for a
non-emergency situation like a multicast
debugging so what you must have is one
at least one constantly active source
and you've got to have at least one
constantly active receiver otherwise the
MSTP state doesn't matter or doesn't get
created the PIM sparse mode state
doesn't get created and you can't you
cannot debug this without an active
source and an active receiver once
you've got that requirement but that
pair of requirements met you can start
near the receiver the first thing you
need to do assume using pin sparse more
than all those good things is look at
your router attached to that network the
receiver has you need to identify the
pins sparse mode designated router now
you may say duh it's this router I know
it's this router consists of a one I
control well I spent three days because
I made that assumption you really need
to go into the router and say hey are
you the designated router maybe that
Ethernet switch over there that doesn't
have layer three forwarding turned on
its app in sparse mode designated router
and it got elected okay you really need
to go look at the designated router to
make sure it really is the designated
router then you verified the IGMP stayed
in the designated router to make sure
that it has gotten the host membership
report that is the IGMP joins
and that it has it's not appropriate
state in the designated router if it's
God only group state then you know that
it's not getting source information down
the shared tree and so forth but that's
that's where you start from the
designated router you follow the reverse
path forwarding from the designated
router back towards the source on each
hop you verify the pin sparse wood has
been configured for each interface along
the RPF tim spahr smoke has no clue if
Finn's parcel it hasn't been configured
upstream it follows the underlying
reachability information so you need to
verify steps along the way you also
might think just for a few minutes you
know all the setup multicast on this
subset of my network well if you do that
it's dangerous because with outages or
who knows why your reach ability may
change with a dynamic routing protocol
and that reach ability information may
be going away you didn't expect for all
of the RPF based on the reach ability at
each Eddings router at each point check
the s comma g state make sure that the
appropriate upstream and downstream
interfaces have been in that state has
been created and check the s comma G
packet counters on each router there are
situations where routers will have pins
sparse mode state but the layer to
infrastructure between them isn't
working properly and the packets are
getting dropped on the floor
so check both the state and the counters
at each hop and you'll eventually find
where the packets aren't being forwarded
going into the into the sort of the
larger case if the source is external to
your pin domain that is a pin domain is
a set of routers that share a rendezvous
point meaning that they the rendezvous
points have to talk to each other with
MSBP
if the source is external to your pin
domain first of all the first thing you
do is you go to your rendezvous point
and you verify that you have an MSBP
source active for that source if you
don't that's your problem you got to get
more
you have to verify the multi-protocol
bgp next-hop in your reach ability
information is both app in sparse mode
neighbor and that the mspb here is good
it simplifies things but that the next
hop is on the path towards your MSBP
peer read the MSTP drive a lot simpler
if your pairings are MSTP speakers also
verify verify that you're actually
choosing the NLRA equals multicast
routes with reach ability as you
preferred RPF path there are ways to
screw this up in configuration bgp
distance if you're in a cisco picking
the wrong rim if you're in a Juniper be
sure verify this ok outgoing let's say
you're you're transmitting if somebody
wants to hear you what if nobody can
hear you scream verify that the s comma
G shows up at your honorable point
that's the first place to look verify
that if it's not you've got problems go
back to the designated router make sure
it sees the traffic and so forth and
it's properly encapsulating to the
rendezvous point etcetera etc verify
that your honor the point is MSBP
announcing the source and that it shows
up in your peers MST PSA cache when
somebody calls your NOC and says yo I'm
not getting the source your question to
them is are you seeing the MSTP source
active from me that should be your first
question in return verify that you've
got a pince parcel an adjacency with
your peer and that the modes match you
know again what if those adjacency look
like is the question to ask they're
looking glass or or they're not person
if everything looks good and they should
be getting your traffic verify that you
have a Pierce interface and the outgoing
list for the s comma G if not that means
the join hasn't gotten to you or you
haven't accepted that join for some
reason and finally verify that the
packet counters show the traffic going
out again look at the counters don't
just look at the s hamaji state also
look at the counters
to make sure that the packets are really
moving okay I've been talking about this
a drink I've been talking about the need
for active senders and active receivers
when I first got involved with the
access grid the kind of questions I got
from my network users were I can't hear
somebody over there there I can't see
their video and they were and then they
would go to lunch and expect me to fix
it while they were at lunch you know I
can't do that because they turn
everything off what we needed was the
ability to have a static source and a
static receiver that we could query and
know what the reach ability you know the
actual packet reach ability look like
reach ability I'm using in one sense
here so the good posted at best created
this for us they think we collaborated
with them innate and they've generated
this for us you can get this it's a it's
written in Java at that URL I highly
recommend it it's in Java so it runs
anywhere what you end up doing is this
goes to a web page rather the server
there puts out HTTP and HTML what you
end up with is a matrix each beacon does
three things it transmits continuously
on a multicast group
he puts packets on the wire ten francs
ten packets a second the other thing it
does is it receives packets from that
group it's an active receiver the third
thing it does is it sends information
about who it's receiving back via
unicast to a central repository that you
can query with a web browser
this lets you tell somebody for example
when I first got involved in debugging
access grid I called the networking
people at a site and I said you know
your people aren't seeing the traffic
from the outside and they said well
they're just not sending we've got
multicast setup and it's working great
and it was kind of hard to argue with
them because how can I give them real
data to tell them there's nothing there
well what I can do here is if you look
at the at number three here in that
situation I would go to them and it
wasn't by the way it wasn't a RS see
that I've had this discussion with but
in the case of a RS see what you can see
is a horizontal line that's gray what
that means is that they aren't hearing
incoming traffic from anybody but
themselves they're not hearing traffic
from the zero from number one from
number two from number four number five
or number six a consistent role like
that is pretty good evidence that the
problem is with the site that can't hear
anybody and you can use this you can
point to another knot or or to another
application people and say look you're
not receiving anything you've got a
problem to work on okay again a RFC this
was before they got there their
multicast working they're not being
heard by anybody either you can look at
the vertical column for number three in
this case sender three which is the same
as receiver 3 F 3 nobody can hear you
know R 0 can't hear number three our one
can't hear number three our two can't
hear number three they can hear
themselves but numbers four five and six
can't hear number three either this is
again pretty good evidence that that
site is isolated the problem isn't with
the outside world the problems with that
site and their pairings with their up
streams and their peers this tells you
that information if you've got two sites
where's a good example on this page
there our site there are sometimes
situations where which one is this
number two there are situations where
you can get out better than you can come
in these are two problems that you need
to work separately incoming versus
outgoing traffic for a given for a given
group you look at number two everybody
with the exception of number number
three of course everybody can hear
number two
on this vertical plank that's what that
means but incoming traffic is either
congested or not working properly
because there are three sources that
they can't hear at all and the other two
have lost in them 25 and 40 and 19
percent loss and so that tells me that
if I was going to be working helping
that site get multicast enabled I would
first look at reception because it looks
like looks like they're not hearing some
sources there anyway
what I've got here I couldn't put this
on my slide
this is today's beacon or this was
Saturday night's beacon page it's an 80
by 80 matrix but just started enough
pixels to put this up on the slide so I
would recommend you know afterwards when
you come to pick up your buttons and
come take a look at this you can also go
to the to the beacon page there and get
the hyperlink to the actual server that
generated this you can see right away
where the reach ability is even from
back there you can see how much green
there is that's the good news
variance is actually connectivity that
exists also you're seeing blocks of
green which means you've got whole
groups that can see each other and can
be can be seen without traffic dropping
down we've got some problems with a
beacon for one thing it only shows the
current state so if you print out it
that's if you print it out that's about
the only way to keep track of how things
were if you're nice we get archive of
state over time so we can see when
problems occurred we're working on that
you don't know how quite how to
visualize evolving state this is a two
dimensional problem it really requires
you to to to manage a matrix of reach
ability from all sources to all
receivers because of the inherent
branching nature of the problem I don't
know how to keep an ad by eating in my
head so I need a picture inherently four
three two so if you want to see how this
evolves over time it's a three
dimensional problem and I'm not quite
sure how to how to represent that in
some sort of irrational
I'm sure some other people will have a
great idea and I really hope I hear
about it so it can be done but I don't
know what that is yet we had some
problems when we hit 40 beacons we've
pretty much resolved those we're up
around this picture here shows an 80 by
80 matrix we continue to grow this is a
good thing please please feel free to
download the software from from the n
ladder site that I mentioned and and
start a beacon just leave it running and
that way you can tell and everybody else
can get a better feel for what the
internet multi cast reach ability looks
like so let us worry about the
scalability of the servers that is what
I'm saying about this bullet another
thing about the multicast beacon is it
assumes the any source multicast model
we don't have an implementation of this
alexis debug things in the source
specific model there's several reasons
for this one reason is that it's written
in Java and we're concerned that the SM
support in Java isn't there yet
I very much like somebody to tell me oh
yes it is but you know we don't see it
yet okay some of the building blocks
I've talked about em bgp the
multi-protocol bgp this is the older
this is the older RFC use the one in the
earlier slide this is implement
implemented by juniper and cisco in
their major releases especially the
service provider releases for Cisco and
in the in the 12 dato and 12 though
these are the later 12 ATO and it is in
the 12.1 base release I know this the
access grid community has used unifor in
cisco the most so those are the ones I
know the most about there may be others
MSBP
is implemented by juniper cisco foundry
and so forth the only it's meets the
multiple interoperating implementations
test of an RFC it's just a matter of
time before it gets codified as an RFC
codified Tim sparse mode is implemented
by a whole raft of vendors cisco juniper
foundry extreme Marconi
next top technologies has it for your
UNIX boxes etc etc so in other words you
can put this in your network so you
don't have to do a forklift upgrade to
Cisco in order to get them sparse mode
anymore you used to be you had to you
don't have to anymore edge multicast
building blocks
IGMP v2 is widely available in layer 2
you know IGP snooping switches and layer
3 devices like like routers and host and
AIGFP v2 is widely available most host
operating systems that's in Ward where
from Windows 95 on it's in all the BS DS
of course it's in Linux you know name
your operating system Solaris iris
whatever IG mtv2 is there it's been
there for a long time it just works
IGMP v3 is coming soon it's not quite
there yet it's a matter of getting it
implemented and in the appropriate
places
it's available in layer 3 devices that
is routers now Cisco and juniper the
latest release from juniper has IGMP v3
support I think it's in the 12.1 t train
on Cisco IGF ev3 it's not there yet in
the in the layer 2 devices I don't think
I GMT v2 v3 snooping works yet so I
can't really deploy it in my in my wide
layer 2 network IGMP v3 will be
available in Windows XP Whistler and
therefore Borg where I wish it was going
to be available as a service back at
some of the earlier windows it's not
there yet
currently it's available as a patch in
Linux and as I last time I looked that
patch was not compatible with more than
one processor which limits its
availability and I don't think it's in
the core Linux kernel yet I GMT v3 is
coming it's not there yet because it's
not there yet there are some ugly hack
workarounds if you don't want to deploy
IGMP v3 there are some ways to emulate
IGMP VIII's and things like the URL
redirect where you make a sudo HTTP
request off for some you are
and the router intercepts this request
magically and says oh you meant to do IG
mtv3 it works but it that it was that's
all I can say North American we are in
North America of course multicast status
I can speak to the research and so our
government networks better because
that's the that's that's where I work
yes net Abilene VB NS plus and n ran are
all running these protocols amongst
themselves and with their customers and
peers this is a good thing we've been
working with typically the problems we
see what we'll get into that yeah the
regional and institutional networks are
currently the most common stumbling
blocks were at multicast applications
when I say regional I mean things it
used to be that some of the Giga pops
weren't multicast enabled that's that's
getting a lot better now I'm finding
that the institutional networks like
within a university or within a national
lab or if in a company just are the most
the most difficult stumbling blocks a
lot of reasons for that one of the best
reasons for that is that they've worked
very hard to find a integrated piece of
routing code that will do all of their
protocols Neil appletalk decnet IPX you
know make your list and they really
don't want to go have to go through the
test process to add another version of
code that may break something else in
their network that's that's a good
reason unless good reason is because
they have they have routing boxes that
can't be upgraded in because they don't
have enough memory or they've been in an
engineered or their vendor doesn't do
can sparse mode right we've seen those
and of course we've seen them that I'm
just overworked I don't have time you
know we we look around that as well
there exists some meeting points one my
colleague Linda Winkler she worked at
our home for me she's one of the
engineers on start app in Chicago come
to start to have if you're an
international and multicast is available
they're just like all the other services
from starts have are the international
and commercial networks are coming on
you'll see some on this reach ability
you'll see some other networks the Vario
is running we've got appearing with very
oh I think I mentioned them earlier with
this other router and big sprint link if
I'm not mistaken anyway there's Marshall
Eubanks and multicast technologies
handles the commercial side of the world
a lot better than I do I can tell you
about the research networks better than
the commercial side good news is we're
seeing more and more penetration of
multicast into the into the provider
networks that's what I had to say I'd be
very interested in hearing your
questions comments feel free to come up
and grab some pins or on both ends here
now that you understand what these pins
are saying I'd be very grateful if you
could wear them around and tell other
people what they what they mean when
they ask is what this sort of opaque
saying is also feel free to come up and
take a look at this reachability graph
glad to take questions Jerry Anderson
level 3 if you were a customer going to
a service provider and you wanted to buy
multicast what questions would you ask
and why as a matter of fact I've been
asked that question and first question I
would ask is how are you providing it or
are you providing multicast the there's
a company that's taking the excess grade
technology is trying to commercialize it
and they're finding that one of the
biggest barriers to commercialization of
the access grade technology is the lack
of multicast from commercial providers I
would just make sure that they're
running the current multicast protocols
if you're doing you know standard bgp
peering with your customer make sure
that your upstream provider will
upstream provider you're evaluating also
does fin sparse and n bgp if your
customer wants dvmrp think that question
equivalent to your customer wants rip
from you ok it's just you know it just
doesn't just
match what the what the real world is
these days
did that help okay anybody else
well we're about 12 minutes early so I
think you all four come