I'm Jen Andre I'm the CEO of a company
called command which is a startup based
out of Cambridge here in Boston my
background is I would say it's an RD and
insecurities products um I'm also an
entrepreneur so before command I was
co-founder of a company called Brett sac
which does cloud-based security
monitoring which is also based out of
here in Boston before that I worked rd
at Mandaeans and for that I did several
roles at symantec that semantics MSSP I
started off working the song and then I
move more to like the product
engineering side so I have for better or
worse a background in security and
security products some of the other
stuff I do is I helped organize a local
Boston security meetup group here called
hack secure we're just getting started
but we're starting to hold monthly
meetups we do things like lightning
toxin so it's basically designed for
practitioners to come and talk about
what they're working on so I'm really
excited about some of the stuff we I'm
coming up we've organized the CTF over
at rapid7 um and we should have some fun
stuff happening there anyway so I
realized when I was writing this talk
not everyone knew what a Hydra was so I
figured I should put some slides here to
explain it and thank you for pointing
that out um so a Hydra for those of you
that don't know is a mythical creature
it's definitely not real but it's a
creature and the story of this creature
is if you cut off one of its heads to
will grow back so there's a whole
there's a whole myth all mythological
story about it but that's the essential
core point of it um and I wanted to talk
about how we security teams ah should
aspire to some of those traits so the
first train I want to talk about is
resiliency so um I like this picture
here because you see me all of you are
familiar with the pirate
a and the many attempts to shut off
while sharing our report sharing their
but I think resiliency is one key point
that we can we can take from this
mythological myth you cut off one of its
heads to girls back and we a security
team should aspire to that short of
resiliency scalability is another thing
obviously having multiple heads is a
useful thing the guy this picture here
looks like he's kind of struggling to
deal with what's going on here and um it
can kind of feel like this as a defender
but if you're if you're an attacker and
you have to avoid all these different
traps you can kind of turn the tables on
an attacker as well and I'm going to
talk about some of those use cases later
on so the key point about this is that
we want these traits across not just
like the systems that we're trying to
secure and the stuff we're trying to
secure but also in our security team as
well we should be resilient and we
should be scalable so as the
organization grows that we are
protecting we should also scale to that
organization we should be resilient to
changes within the environment we're
protecting and for most of us we have to
be just because we don't take a snapshot
of a company or a network at a certain
state and protect that we have to always
be thinking about the next big thing
so ways we fail at both of those things
we own the policy in the process around
things that don't help execute and I'll
talk about more specific use cases but
it's generally the philosophy that we
give out these policies or to find these
processes to these other organizations
several organizations and teams that
were working with and we say you need to
be doing this versus you need to be
doing this and here's a way we can help
you get that done I think another way
where security teams can fail is we
don't scale ourselves so if we are the
gating factor for security decisions if
we put a process in place or a policy in
place that says you know we need to have
some sort of uh you know but a
vulnerability management process but you
guys are you know we'd ever prove
everything or um at for any login that
comes in or any access control we have
to approve the access control we become
the gating factor and it's hard to scale
ourselves and also if we hold all the
knowledge and expertise about security
and every time a decision has to be made
they have to come to us then I think we
also fail
so this concept of the human body net um
how many of you have been or seen a
security at scale conference how about
Facebook cool yeah there's one in Boston
recently and I like these conferences
because you just kind of see some
interesting ways these new technology
companies are solving problems in
security so this term actually came from
yoga Monica who I think he's at daughter
security now but back when he gave this
talk he was at square security and this
is actually a really good talk to watch
because he talks about some of the stuff
they did it square which is obviously a
payment processing company um you know a
technology company that he had to do in
order to protect that business and he
didn't have a huge security team he
didn't have a huge security budget so he
ended up having to do some really
innovative things and one concept he
introduces in this talk is the idea of
being a human botnet so rather than you
know security taking all of the tasks
that's pretty traditionally owns he
decided to introduce some processes and
some tools to start scaling that out to
the rest of the organization and that's
actually kind of the core of this talk
there's going to be some you know talk
of automation and different tools to
accomplish that but really the
philosophy is like how do we as security
team scale ourselves so we can be
resilient and we can be flexible
so the first use case I want to talk
about is around security monitoring so
when you think about how security teams
have traditionally done security
monitoring you have all these different
tools and systems generating alarms
they're looking at a bunch of different
stuff the cool thing is is like there's
there's actually more I think data
collection and more technology today we
have all these new different types of
cool endpoints that you all these
interesting on collection and alerting
of things and it's really great except
that you need someone to actually
monitor these alerts you're gonna you're
going to do some level filtering things
out but um you know this is how I felt
like this is what private why I left the
stock because after you know six months
of doing that wreak havoc I don't want
to do with that triage ever get in my
life I want to work on the systems that
actually detect these threats and try to
improve that so what have I told you
that you didn't have to do this anymore
like this this wasn't the only way to do
security monitoring so I don't know how
many of you saw um I guess three or four
weeks ago Ryan Hoover was a straight
edge here at slac close to this blog
post and I thought was really
interesting and it very much ties into
this whole talking getting but it's all
around how they the team at slac scaled
out their security monitoring they don't
have a huge you know sock with a bunch
of security and us triaging all these
alerts what they did was very
interesting so oh my i failed on
animation but you get the point so the
way the process works is they have
monitoring on various servers and in
points that you security monitoring
right and what happens is that every
time there's an alert that happens the
Lord doesn't immediately go to some
security event manager that queue for
security analyst to triage what they do
instead for certain possible Ertz is
they actually determine who could
potentially triage
alert so on this particular use case if
someone logs into a server right like an
application server and runs a command
that slap being suspicious on what they
do is they look up who's the user that's
actually logged in at the time what's a
slack username and then they triage via
slack so what they'll do is they'll send
a direct message to that person and say
hey did you actually run this command
that we saw was suspicious that person
can reply yes or no they can acknowledge
or not and then the acknowledgement
itself is actually um confirmed to be a
two-factor system they have a kind of an
app on their phone where someone has to
confirm that they actually knowledge
learn and that's cool and the cool thing
about it is like it's not really that
hard to implement when you think about
it so what about some of the pieces that
you need to actually accomplish this you
need the endpoint monitoring the cool
thing is is there's a lot of open source
tools that actually accomplish this
stuff and by the way like in their
particular use case they were doing some
very specific behavioral monitoring this
could also apply to application
wondering well there's no reason why you
couldn't scale those alerts or even
certain classes and network alerts to
you know more sophisticated members of
your operations and engineering teams um
you need a means of determining user
identity ownership so again like if
you're using open source stuff you can
use a configuration management database
if you have some other internal system
you need that as well you can use that
as well um you know
need to determine who read the first
factor notification capability so in
this particular example they're using
slack you could easily use hipchat
jabber IRC anything else to first get in
touch with the user and try to confirm
whether or not that security alarm was
something that needs to be investigated
and then you need that to factor
confirmation so an example they used I
think they had built an app if you
actually go and look about blog it's
like a custom app that they built it
does a post trip edification but again
like you could use twilio or something
else some other you maybe the email as
another two factor authentication
mechanism um so I just talked about that
and then then this is sometimes the
toughest part you need the technology to
glue it all together um to be honest
like this isn't actually that much code
to put together and in order to prove
that to you I'm gonna show you a demo so
pray to the demo gods this works
actually first before I do the demo let
me talk about the architecture that I
came up with to replicate this so you
see here like I have this example server
that I'm to set up using a vagrant
virtual machine I've installed system
dig foul Scott code because it's open
source and it's free you can tell I just
like it didn't take me weeks to write
this because this was released this week
I literally just launched it but like if
you want a more commercial solution like
actually the last copy at co-founded
threat sac has a very nice turnkey
solution and you know for what a support
there's other commercial solutions that
you can use again like it's not the the
actual monitoring system isn't that
important it's more about demonstrating
the process here and then I have a
little agent that I wrote that basically
looks for the alerts on that box and
then what it'll do is every time there's
an alert it will forward it to our
deputy bought server and what's that
server do it actually connects to slack
and it will do well before I even does
that it does certain things like it
looks up who does the user account
belong to so if it's jai andhra and just
logged in it's going to be me and
got a look at my phone number and then
it will try to notify me on slack I have
to confirm that that behavior was me and
if I confirm it it's going to try to
two-factor message me on to Leo so let's
see if I can actually get this demo to
work so some of the tools i'm using here
just to go over it again these are all
free or open source or like open
platforms there's nothing here that's
you know like customer at all ah this
tool here is just a tool that I had to
use to mirror my messages it's super
sketchy so after this talk and probably
gonna delete it because it's like
connected to my android phone at all
these weird ways ah let's see if I can
make sure i'm logged in here cool those
are all my text messages if anyone here
is my phone number please don't text me
cuz it will show up here in the
notifications I'm looking over you
commanders um oh and before i get
started to show us a little bit of some
of the other stuff here um this is
actually the repo with the source code
again this is very much proof of concept
don't deploy this in a production
environment it's going to require a lot
more validation to actually use
um just to show a little bit about what
I'm actually going to learn on I've
deployed the Cystic Falco tool with two
rules one rule which is to detect what I
call privilege escalation and all this
does actually let me just zoom in here
so you can see this is that good so the
privilege escalation rule will just look
for people basically running on sudo so
if you look at a studio user whoops yeah
the user exact binders here corresponds
to a pseudo execution if I can find it
yep exactly so it's looking for anyone
running pseudo or su on this particular
machine and um if it's not the agent
self because I don't want to report on
my own alerts i'll create this endless
loop of stuff that's really annoying to
deal with probably more annoying for
twilio slack than me but annoying and
then I want to look for anything this is
here just the system call exec CDE which
is a process starting off very simple um
right let's go down here
I can't actually zoom in here for some
reason but if you can see this here the
second alert I have is on network
activity and again this I think actually
just shipped with Falco and modified it
just a tiny bit to filter anything from
the agent itself because of that
infinite loop issue and all I'm looking
for is any inbound or outbound FPS
activity from the IP family that's not
the agent and um actually has a process
named sometimes them for some reason
some events come in without a process
name that's it so this is the system
tool if you're interested in it again I
will look at you were looking at other
tools there's other open source OS query
threats that's a very good turnkey
commercial one it doesn't really matter
so for the second factory notification i
am using twilio twilio is just basically
an API for sending text messages and
creating voice messages um they have
like a nice little rest api and it's
very easy to use so i used it because i
have to do this demo very fast um what
I've created here is a slack slack group
i called it security bot demo and once i
start the service you'll see basically a
bot come up called deputy you'll see
here i also created a channel called
security so what happens if i don't
actually confirm the second factor
authentication or I say this whole you
know this thing happened but it wasn't
me is that the security alert will get
escalated by getting posted to the
security channel so the security team
can deal with it now again you probably
want a more robust process for actually
escalating security events alright so
now that that's done let's get started
with the demo again try not to message
me or at least keep it PG if you do so
um the first thing I'm going to do is
actually log into my vagrant server
credit a user J Andre to do so hopefully
this will work cut off um oh so this
tool here is just I'm just running
basically a proxy so that my agent can
connect and post messages to HBS IP like
I just wanted to make it more consistent
for my demo environment that's not
required in a production architecture
and here is my security BOTS and I'm
using docker basically to start it up so
that's what I'm doing right now going to
start up my security BOTS and what it's
going to do it's going to create an ACP
server it's going to listen for two
posts so um alerts is where my agent is
going to be posting alerts to when it
sees them and confirm is where the
twilio call back api is going to post
the confirmation after I've applied via
text message any questions so far now
pray to the devil God's this works so
first of all i'm going to pretend i just
logged in this box you know on the
system admin i'm going to do something
that's going to be triggered by our
security monitoring system and because i
have one of those privilege escalation
lips configured it should this should
work actually let me just um ah so you
can see here that i got a message saying
a suspicious commanders r and so again
what happened here was the agent which
is constantly looking for message from
cystic valco got an alert and posted a
message to my slot channel say hey ah
you logged in and you ran sudo LS on
this particular box now my job here if
this is you know this is me i'm just
going to confirm yes i ran that and then
it says acknowledging and what it's
going to do is confirm via my phone and
because i don't pay for twilio i'm using
the demo or the trial account can be a
little bit slow but hopefully a message
will come through actually confirming in
a second
and if not you can see previous examples
of me testing this service out come on
twilio
oh yeah so it came in on my phone and
then i refreshed right what was coming
in so you didn't see the notification
but you did see the message um sudo LS
was ran on this box at this time now I
can confirm um that I actually ran it
but like just for the sake of this demo
I want to pretend that like hey like
someone had actually stolen my slack
credentials and um tried to basically
confirm the security alert happen for me
so I'm just going to hit no to reject
and then what you see is the escalation
process happening where this where we
see it actually in the security channel
now again like this probably isn't the
most for both rebuff escalation process
you're probably going to want this to go
when total an actual ticketing system or
event queue afford instant handler to
handle but you can see the benefits of
this is like I don't have to deal with
every single potential security alert
that comes in I can actually fan out or
crowdsource some of these security
alerts to more sophisticated members of
the engineering team and off steam and
reduce the burden of alert triage on the
security team any questions give us a
thumbs up again all the source code is
up on github it's very much proof of
concept like some of the things like the
actual looking up my phone number is
just hard coded to environment variables
you don't want to use this you want an
actual system where you're looking at
people's credentials and everything like
that so cool
now back to this talk
so that's just one example of how
through a combination of both technology
process and I think security culture
we'll talk about a little bit later on
we can actually start crowdsourcing some
of the tasks that were previously owned
by security to um you know other members
of the organization second use case and
this actually comes from the top that I
reps in the first part of the slide on
the human body is around authentication
and access control so we have this
problem like everyone you know every
company tries to have some sort of
single sign-on solution but it turns out
like that rarely ever works especially
now that we have all these different
services that you know teams like to
sign up for news and that makes the big
pain in the ass for the security team
when someone reads the company or even
switches teams like who actually has
access to what and if you see this image
on the right is actually from a friend
of mine this was a list of his
credentials that he had to have at his
company and i will say it was a security
company so even though yet even though
even seen it several single sign-on
solutions like the thing i like here is
like some other password that is SSO but
not you have all these different
passwords for things and like someone um
when someone leaves the company whoops
the usual process is you get you get
this checklist right and someone goes
through a disables on this access which
is not super scalable and if the
security team is a gating factor at all
that that's time taken away from you
guys to do other things that you
probably should be doing so let me get
the story again cool so that's
absolutely the wrong solution security
should not gate access control for
things although that is a solution i've
seen some teams actually try because i
want to be able to wear the compliance
auditor comes and say yeah here's who
have access to what you know when
someone leaves the company we have a
process in the sack
gets implemented and also like they
don't want to have potential flying
around in case they get stolen so the
next case study I want to talk about is
again from that talk it's from square
and I thought this is a really cool
solution um so what square did is they
built this portal called doorman and
what doorman is is an app store of
access control so I have all the
differences things that people would
need access to and what they do is if
you want access to like Amazon you go in
and you request access to Amazon and
instead of the notification going the
security who has to approve it it
actually goes to the person's manager
because what they figured it was like
your manager was the best person the
person was best equipped to actually
answer should this person have access to
it or not that said that brings up a
couple questions what happens if your
manager just approves everything like he
doesn't want to deal with a she's like
yes yes yes you know Bob ah who's
basically a administrative assistant has
to have access to everything and what
happens if people just abused the system
and you know get access to all the
things they don't need what happens when
people leave so one cool thing they
actually built in this system was
basically access exploration like
automatic access desperation so if you
they create an account for you on like
an application server or somewhere else
and you never use it what happens to
that account it will actually get
deleted over time so things aged out so
even if you know someone leaves the
company and they go through that
checklist I'm assuming this is Matthew
automates the provisioning but that's
how you still had a checklist and
someone forgot to remove you from an
account eventually it would still lose
access because you're no longer long
that you can't get into the VPN you
can't log into that one
the server so I thought that was a cool
concept again by using by crowdsourcing
the work to on the managers instead of
making the security team to gating
factor they actually are crowdsourcing
the work that to do so again this is all
cool stuff but there are some actual
challenge is to implementing this like
you know not every organization can do
this and I wanted to point some of that
out so it's gonna be challenging
diplomat if you have a highly siloed
culture where people you know a
responsible for their thing they don't
want to take any security task because
you know they're good I'd say that's
securities job you need to have a very
collaborative culture where you all try
to solve problems together to be able to
accomplish this I think if you're
outsourcing your IT and operations it's
also going to be very hard because again
like there's a contact in place and
you're paying this person do this it's
going to be very hard for them to do
additional work outside of the scope of
that contract if you don't have
development skills in your security team
this is also going to be challenging
because again a lot of the system relies
on some level of automation being able
to figure this stuff out and scripting
it and to be honest that's a hard thing
to hire for these days everyone wants to
have a dead on their screen 18 but not
everyone can and again the final
challenges you don't have the technology
in place to do the things you want to
accomplish like security monitoring the
Joe API access to the things you want to
instrument that stuff's that sucks
challenging you can't really get around
that very easily that's there are some
organizations where it can be successful
I think you have a strong operation
engineering shared culture if you're
doing DevOps where people are starting
that you were they take responsibility
for these things and there's a high
level of communication you could you can
probably introduce this concept you
succeed and same sort of thing good
cross functional relationships you have
an assist or some sort of security
leadership that you know crosses
boundaries and it can be a champion for
you etc and your security team already
have some Deb capabilities or the
business is willing to dedicate you know
some programmers to a project like this
in the name of you know
security in conclusion security should
not be monkeys in my opinion we should
be the experts and we should think of
creative ways to reduce you know alert
fatigue for the security by
crowdsourcing these tasks where possible
instead of just providing a policy or
guideline we should provide some level
of automation um to actually make it
easier for the business to adopt our
security policies and whoops we should
bring on experts what experts are needed
and that's what I really think you know
in the future the security team is going
to be we're going to be the experts
we're going to be that the knowledge but
our job is also to educate on the rest
of the organization it and you know
deputize them on specific security task
wherever we can and we should not be the
sole owner of security and the benefits
of this is that you know bring it back
to the hugger thing it's hard to kill
you know if the whole security team goes
on vacation or gets food poisoning
security monitoring and these cash
should not stop and that's what we want
to accomplish here thank you any
questions
so there is a paramount to chat up stuff
in there yes are there other like chat
apps applications that you think are
more relevant to security than just kind
of general like the security monitoring
use case yeah like you could definitely
I saw someone beautiful on post where I
think they integrated with my signal
sciences laughs so you can actually I
think run scams or like few laughs
lobster do something but I'm like oh
I've also seen someone else for someone
else like you could set a command to the
bond and have it run at em up scan or
you know even have it go fetch logs so
based off of a like a security alert
that comes in maybe I need more
information to determine hey that was me
or not maybe I was drinking or something
I mean I needed the other logs just for
contacts so maybe you could have it you
can send a command to the bot and have
it fetch other logs around the same time
so you can actually use the bottom more
than just like a little bit initial
notification you can actually use it as
part of the incident handling and
investigation and even projecting part
of response process
think I'm early