so this is the CSO panel and a lot of
baggage there we go alright so my name's
Patrick clarity on this speaker chair
and decided to moderate the CSO panel
this was actually somebody else's idea
on the committee and then we asked them
do you still want to do it he said nah
so it's okay I'll does oh alright so
what we have today it is going to be six
csos chief security officers chief
information people in charge of security
of companies and the six that we have
here represent tech banking higher
education and a non-profit so we have a
bunch of questions and healthcare
developer and I actually three of those
a partner academic and South province
all right so that's going to make this
next one even more just any sense the
next one to us okay I asked them to
answer questions from their own
individual perspective and not anything
like I would think in other industries
they would do things and that's why we
tried to get a little bit of a diverse
bored here so that way each of them
could kind of answer the questions from
their own industry perspective so what
we are going to start with and probably
not in the same order that they're
actually sitting up there is going to be
some introductions so we have from
akamai technologies and I guess the
wrong will go up there is what I'm
dependable that's less settlers a lot oh
we will fail he's not fire me
you're done what's actually disclaimers
I used to work for Andy but I don't
anymore so so I'm gonna let them
introduce themselves Andy pls i'm the
chief security officer for off my have
been on for 16 years and in addition to
doing security governance across the
entire business also gotten to work on
the product side helping launch a lot of
our new products before i was at optima
i was in the Air Force doing information
warfare nice next in him which is also
curious we have Josh I love from rapid7
who now can fire we also have displayed
on that I work for josh Josh when
introduced yourself then introductions
great I can't actually fired him that's
not you can ask somebody to keep the
hominy back in the Corellian on this
Jeff I'm the security rapid7 four out of
seven I spent time and I bro healthcare
companies and working in various telecom
companies and law enforcement agencies
and you know rinse and repeat federal
agency said you know spell out of time
gate different perspectives and found
out my home was in high-growth high-tech
companies and I just happen to also land
the security company which a is allowed
me to build a different type of team and
experiment a little bit more and B is
starting to give me an opportunity to
delve more into product and building a
stronger community and helping our
customers be successful but just as a
function of what's expected of my job
instead of you know going on
way having people look at me saying why
are you why are you here secure it
doesn't make sense all right and next to
him from century bank we have Adam Blake
I can say they don't work for Adam I've
actually working with him I'll give us
am also a campfire hello I am out of it
as mentioned I'm screwed officer for
century bank a lot of you made mairone
I've seen our logo we're a
five-million-dollar bank right here in
medford now kennedy bank relatively
small in that sense but I responsible
security and all those big jargon and
buzzwords that are associated with it
thank you great and from Northeastern
University with Martin our dome so I'm
Martin are don't different racial
security officer for northeastern I been
in information security since the mid
two thousand and two boys about a year
after northeastern and starting to have
an information security question so I
got to evolve as the piranha
no I run it so somebody's bigger and the
end from cyber discovery group John
Creek Park alright thanks Patrick my
name's John Barrymore our chief security
officer for the solder discover group
it's a 501c3 and research and
development education in cyber security
so personally about me everything i say
is my opinion miss Carson my employer
and one contractor this additionally at
this time I've got about closest 13
years when pretty much consulting pro
bono as well support work for a lot of
nonprofits in theory that scrimmage
would work predominant liveth the
supporting people through security at
Brewster nonprofits and we like working
in the trenches of those people because
he was several audible things was it and
what last night I was creating these
names hence that India's so nicely
recreated for himself and one of things
that I was noticing was that we didn't
have a whole lot of diversity with them
yeah very good to that watering the
targa give the power now I was reading
the tents and noticed we did not have a
lot of diversity and today josh came up
to me and said we would like to add
another person here CSO panel do you
mind this ll be awesome so from Tufts
University we have some yourself I have
the diversity in the panel
so pleased to be here I managed that
information security for tufts medical
center and the floating Hospital for
Children been there about 10 years but
always in the healthcare space so it's
more for Harvard Pilgrim and they open
health plan before that and before that
i did a management consulting work out
texas dell services and rosboroughs
management consulting group so there's a
lot of blog verticals in there in terms
of clients but really specifically
focused in health care and love working
in the hospital spaces thank you alright
so basically refers to ask them
questions and hear some of their answer
so we can start with some really easy
ones for them how about what's the CSO
do with your typical day look like and
take us through some of the typical
things that happen in a CSO say let's
see who has a microphone wants to start
he's good what ya know oh wow that works
everyone working with with cool things
would be very security officer high res
I never really know what men do day to
day I try to apply my days as best I can
but they don't always targeted way that
I plan certainly what I had what I do is
evolving as the maturity of our program
the university is evolving as
universities profile is evolving the
challenges continue to increase I do a
lot of meetings with Jim caso risk and
compliance talking about strategies for
implementation for new things that
northeastern want to do like good name
brand new CMS systems or LMS strategy
seems to be a big part of my job note
and probably how the university
positions itself for all the things that
it wants to do and still protect the
infrastructure and protect the data that
we have on a daily basis and then it's
also an annual base right handle is
Darren anuran crisis mode in your
incident response so the key point that
I heard there to agree with that your
day is totally not predictable from a
long-term perspective and that's an
executive function that's not a security
thing right did you the higher you go in
an organization the less you're doing
routine things because that's what you
have grown the team is to take care of
the things that are somewhat predictable
and much of your day is handled
escalations right talk about the things
that are off tracking how do you get
them back on track karen feeding of your
staff becomes a much larger and larger
portion of your job Larry's over there
going man little better but it's
ensuring that people have the challenges
that are one of them is that they're
suited for right so they can grow and
develop you don't take a junior
contributor and say oh look I think
someday you can be a senior architects
let me put that job in front of you
today it's how do you ensure this at
work is being put in front of them in a
way that's consumable that they can grow
that your managers are doing the same
that your directors are doing the same
so a lot of it really has to do is sort
of watching this machine and making sure
that it's on track within your
organization and that it's fitting
within the larger organization
you know I think the simplest way to
explain it is frequently herding cats
which is a lot of what and you just said
it's not exaggeration I think one of the
really fun things about security
security teams in essentially places of
rapid growth or high technology places
you have the opportunity to understand
the business both from a strategic level
and a tactical level in a way that
doesn't exist it they'd almost any other
component of that business and so I
think that one of the one of the things
that I've always enjoyed the most about
it is that you can really get in and
gain and both gained in perspective and
get the business back a perspective that
they're not used to and I think that
aligns directly with being both a
tactical and strategic contributor and
so I don't want an echo I mean obviously
the same things that all these guys said
what I think that there is very very fun
perspective if we get to others go don't
I think in addition to that the only
thing that I would really add to my role
day-to-day as being a constant
evangelist and lobbyist for security and
why security is important to the various
individuals you know working in the
organization so I talked daily with
physicians and understand how they using
technology and remind them that security
is a big component of the patient
experience and patient trust as it
relates to the help you know the
hospital environment but that constant
kind of lobbying for the program to
mature within the organization I feel is
my largest role
yeah so did Oh to the previous four
panelists very much along with Andy's
sentiment is that it is much beyond
knows what I would walk into every day
we are a financial institution so I'd be
lying if I didn't say that a large
portion of my time is taken up by
auditors we're audited five or six times
a year so I am and with Deloitte KPMG
the Federal Reserve FDIC whoever might
be flavor the week at that point is is a
good portion of my time but yeah you
know the day-to-day you come in and
you're unknown you got to handle the
reports there were changes yesterday
what happened what was it very much
responsive in nature unfortunately it's
a gag album 25 people so coming from the
background we're a non-profit cnc
mountain system budget so there's a lot
of all TT Gorillaz and managing security
projects nonprofit has been rather
interesting because the audit quality
standards and things that we enable
those people with I do think though that
they've all been on as a sentence
success factor actually is personnel
management as well as communication and
your team as a CSO you're actually
working rather hard to be that
communication Virgil a lot between your
neighbors and the people making
decisions in the business so are not
suited for multiple industries at this
point a lot of rules down to being a
communicator and being able to get
employer yup John I'm gonna come right
back
okay so let's say all right listen
number one thing as you struggle with
each day at wish you could get a better
handle on or what's the one takeaway you
would like to see each of us leave here
today that will make the security
environment better we have some tackle
in the first one on that one a new
circle with every other nonprofits can
anyone guess how the most work really
hard for little Knights know by now
right so obviously financial constraints
of accomplishing the objectives of the
organization is always going to be the
systemic nonprofits so that that is
absolutely the one things innovating
alternative methods to accomplishing
their goals so he mentioned earlier
being a tactical strategic you have to
be able to have a team that can have the
agility to go through the decision
process where you go from being tactical
to strategic a rapid notice is one right
back and then one of the ones eight ways
actually probably would be that is too
long if you do anything especially
nonprofits you have to work a lot of
people come to you wanting to help with
the mission
ization maximize the potential other
people have so this personal management
strategies again but also one thing I
don't think a lot of people see with
nonprofits often it's stakeholder ship
so making every single person to like
everything that goes detrimental the
success of the organization they
absolutely keep or give you anything CT
meter mark about from the University
perspective take away I mean I it's
really getting people to understand that
there is much are the solution as they
are sometimes are the phone and making
evil our information security us of
commissioning baked into their daily job
they realize that thing that's one of
the things that you push really hard for
when we do our information security
awareness training is ok it's not just
European to buy job that you should you
think
is also excited so really kind of
driving those things
as a super important I mean worked I
dated a struggle for me right now it's
its value and resources to continue to
grow the program we have one that the
university needs of the growth it's
tough because your university and we are
a non-profit so full of money is small
if anybody's from around this area area
you know that kind of meteoric rise in
northeastern over the last 15 years 15
years ago we were right there three
hundreds and never in the top 50
universities in the country and that has
brought some very many challenges not a
list of with is the fact that people
never do our name which means people in
China and money I think you really
surprised that red increase profile and
attack vectors or comment is there
because we're on NPR or there's a news
article in The New York Times it's aight
surname and finding the resources not
only keep keep universe and safe but
also to continue to move forward
strategically position as bad or Caminos
challenges that's that's the next
struggle is trying to find most all
Sonia you described a couple three
different industries I think that you
kind of cover in your position do you
think there is one thing that you
struggle with or is it because you would
worry about so many different things
that there are not one thing yes so I
see my organization through the lens of
if we look at research you look at the
you know nonprofit academia obviously
large consumer component with providing
health care to the masses and in the mom
for-profit component of the organization
so you know I think I have to view the
organization there's three different
spaces and I've really leveraged
leadership in those spaces and gotten
them ramped up within security you know
knowledge so that I have some visibility
that's spread because even if my team
were seven people I still wouldn't be
able to look at security through the
lens of what they're with their facing
day to day I think the biggest struggle
for me that really is getting on top of
the technology that's coming into my
organization so if you think about how
help you know we're in the middle Boston
epicenter of great development from a
software perspective a lot of big
healthcare companies and small you know
incubators developing software
applications to use on your phone that
will transmit health data to your
physician and all of your friends on
facebook if you
and and so that's kind of one component
of it there's an influx of telemedicine
based medical devices that are now going
to have random operating systems that
are not haven't been a part of the
program historically so that's a big
challenge for me out of you and from
academia to banking sure how do you see
is these questions being I'd opening for
you when you went to the banking sector
yeah so it's a obviously I don't need to
tell you it's a world of difference
between talking about the financial
sector from the higher end hi red sector
pirate is very much in open environment
it's you know how can we communicate
freely how can we enable this technology
and then its kind about the earth day by
the way you should we add us at some of
that or maybe should we add some sort of
security to it whereas the financial
sector is very much the other way around
so the financial sector is okay is it
secure is it a you know button down do
we have all configuration corner correct
okay maybe we should think about having
a user in and see if they can use a
technology so it's kind of this you know
what end of the tunnel you're really
looking at but as far as you related to
the question one thing I struggle with
my big shoulder right now he has the
Swift network if anyone familiar
explains my executives yes we have more
than ten dollar routers and we do have
something called the firewall on our
network it's difficult to say yeah I've
got it and also said try to explain to
them what it is but it goes back to the
initial question of you know every day
is different I did not know I was gonna
have to come in and answer a bunch of
Swift questions one day and now I find
myself doing it but I struggle with that
I struggle with user awareness getting
my users to understand and be a part of
the culture I find that to be extremely
valuable from a security standpoint I
want people to take centuries security
as part of something that they are part
of and by doing so they are secure in
the professional environment and they're
secure in their personal environment we
work really hard at that and i
understand i'm getting you guys from
bear song about watching um take away
from this i think a you know a bit of a
paradigm shift from the security world I
try to be an enabler the most positive
sense of that if someone says though we
can't do that I want to find out how we
can't do that no that servers isn't
allowed well let's find something that
is allowed will find a secure way of
doing it lets you know let's not be that
that breaking point let's be the
enabling point of that that's gonna take
away Josh your indigent yeah good you
know one thing that I was that just
president here was I'd say my biggest
struggle before I I myself and we the
team is prioritization we're figuring
out what I want to get what I want
personally what I want the team to get
an a-plus on and will be what's okay to
get a C on I mean a lot of times it just
feels like you're rolling the dice
especially when you're dealing with you
know a smaller organization but you know
sometimes it just it feels like you're
guessing it really comes down to
intuition and ultimately instinct and I
don't know it commission if you should
have a larger larger organization and
I'd say the takeaway is that I think
that the industry in many respects is
become very pessimistic and I actually
am optimistic i think that they're
really
problems that we can solve if we get
curious highly apt and excited people
that are going to solving problems and
so when you're going out and hiring
cause something I learned from this guy
actually is don't you don't need to go
find that security engineer with the
five years of experience you can get
creative and try and find find a
creative creative and energetic people
that are really smart and they're going
to help you be very successful with your
building your program yeah that's a new
tangent for India the left one maybe
talk about what Joshua is describing the
kinds of people that you look for ya so
the struggles but I'm having here it is
easy everything a good staff yeah good
time I'm kanya so often that was the
state Larry because we weren't here in
the previous talk Larry's that I who
broke CBE and failed to find 1300
WordPress vulnerabilities wants down 30
instead but like we hired Larry and
larry was it officially security person
right his resume was been assisted men
for god I don't even know how many years
like since before there were computers
right great security researcher yeah we
hire from places and sometimes you make
mistakes when you do that right you
don't always find it the best fit and so
one of your struggles is how do you take
somebody because everybody has value
that they bring into your organization
and put them in a position where they'll
thrive because when somebody is in
thriving more than half the time it's
not their fault it's the fault of the
organization of how you supported them
of how you train them or didn't bother
to and we've done you know almost every
mistake imaginable all I'm sure we'll
discover some more next year I have very
defensive managers
way to fail and you blew off food but
for the second one the one thing I want
ever been to take away with is you know
in your career at some point probably on
a regular basis you or one of your
co-workers will engage with the business
in a dynamic in which the security
person is holding themselves up as
protecting the business and trying to
stop this stupid or evil person from
doing a thing cut it out it's not
helpful right we have security personnel
do not make money for the business our
job is not to keep them from taking
risks it's to help them make better risk
choices and any dynamic in which you say
that they're the villain which obviously
means you're the hero is exactly the
opposite we are sidekicks we're in the
industry where the best we get to be is
Robin you're not Batman we are not
Superman we're not even Aquaman Wonder
Woman like that I'd killed 31 woman I'm
Robin I'm running around and maybe I
help Batman remember to put on his
utility belt that's what our industry is
there is there something that Andy said
on several years ago that I actually
whenever I stayed out business number oh
my god what is what is happening he said
something very similar which is known as
the villain in a nobody and so whatever
i'm going to crush created or or is then
tell it to the same thing to every every
professional
point is when somebody is coming back
and saying something that you think is
the most ludicrous thing you've ever
heard like you step back and try and
make sure you don't try make sure you
understand that respect in why they rely
y all right I got this next one probably
a little bit more for Indian Josh since
they actually do have staff here humping
your staff and other people have your
company better serve you it's all right
give us one tapas and executives don't
want problems brought to the mother
staff they want solutions offered ideas
suggested it takes problem set it so I
have said that to people and I
increasingly feel like that's an untruth
when I want to tell that to post I do
want to know what the problems aren't
even if you don't have a solution now
that doesn't mean that fact you found a
problem that you think is crazy
existential doesn't mean I'm going to do
anything about it because guess what
gotta register some crazy existential
problems that I can't do anything about
anyway and this might just go on it so
some of it is that level of tolerance to
understand that when you find the thing
then you're traumatized by that might
actually be reasonable within the scope
to order within the organization so
accept it it's going to go up and it's
not going to bounce which is not going
to move the organization but also expect
that if you bring me a problem without a
solution and it's a problem that i think
i know what a solution is I'm just going
to tell you what's good too like if you
walk into hey I got a problem like this
and you stop I'm going to say ok go to
this this this and this like I'm not a
psychiatrist if you want somebody just
to be able to talk to for a minute you
got to start by saying like hey I'm
frustrated about this day I want to tell
you about it and I don't want any action
from but if you walk in and say I'm
having a problem with my data
are my great let me solve it I'm a
troubleshooter that's what I do for a
living so that that's the one thing that
I think and I most of my folks were
pretty good about learning that one but
that's big piece I would say that I I
encourage as much open dialogue as
possible and so it's never a if you
don't have a solution don't don't come
what I don't like they don't like people
to complain a ton and never try and
offer you know a valuable approach to
the things that are bothering them it's
just constant complaining i think that's
different than coming with a real
problem and and working through it as a
team but what I what I don't like I
don't like when people in the security
industry in general go to business
without a solution right you think we
can't just be people and point out
problems right so the most important
thing is that when we see a problem
there's something that we're
uncomfortable with that we're not just
going in saying no it's hey how about
this or if you can't do it this way
maybe we can help you do it that way if
you don't have the resources to which
isn't always practical with all security
organizations a you know froggy staffing
reasons but it's a really important
focus oh you just not the team of no I
know you guys have started to hear that
but if that's if that's what your team
is doing your time to be successful as a
team Sonia I think you said you had
seven people and even if you had more
that wouldn't be enough oh no I don't
have seven people oh man that I said
even if I had seven people it one thing
I guess
okay one thing that I guess I DISA tag
off of that you know it's I think we get
tagged as a team of know and so one of
the things I implore people to do is
invite me to the meeting because I'd
rather see that wreck ahead right or if
a new technologies coming down the pipe
or they are planning on you know doing
something strategic that involves an
application that is fraught with
security holes like Swiss cheese in the
code I want to know about it and make
other you know mitigating decisions on
it John how does this work with your
office oh man every one of my scenes is
you are a security on profit internally
is probably better than I am to be
honest with you I'm the guy that's the
extrovert the ncj is they fall in the
psychology world apparently but I know
that after that and just trust very much
everything that they do for me the
better served me they can stop bringing
solutions for our clients basically
because they don't sound like it's just
hey we did this business and nine times
out of ten as a matter of okay with what
resource in time but no it's really
honestly about communication and they
never talked about it be very
transparent routine on at times I would
like to be more involved as she said
with things that may seem mind you to
someone or they may seem so they don't
have a solution to that problem
cross-pollinating across little work you
actually did a lot of things like the
CFO make know something I've got CEOs or
in preventable star
I mean that person hell that you see SEO
in one ear CEO other than okay good
that's all so many more of those right
so actually asking something back on the
top side you can also help out I think
not just people that serve you see the
people you work for long okay remark
doing a tease me a good yeah I have to
say I trust your team for a reason said
smart I knew but what do you make sure
that they understand that it's okay to
get a problem sometimes penalize them
for that look at an opportunity to get
it right and x yeah in the tomorrow in
Sonja's and Johnson also i really
appreciate open communication so you
know it's going to upset me more you
know they come to me on a friday and say
hey with banging our heads against the
wall since monday on this and we've made
no progress and we're still dealing with
it i wish it came here earlier you know
we've gone to these points and we're
being paid to be solution providers i
think at this level in our job so open
dialogue is extremely helpful talking
through it whatever the case may be but
bring us a little every right here party
this next one we're going to ask you to
look into your crystal balls and
hopefully with the different industries
we get different answers what do you see
is the next big thing that security
practitioners who have to face and deal
with over the next few years who wants
to jump in on
first I was open security vendor I want
to say ironically that I think that
would you like we fear like a huge
monolithic more than security vendor
early very important but you do a lot
other really cool things I would say
that the fact security tech cooling is
failing us I mean lately if you were a
security practitioner and all you do is
install security tools you're not a
security practitioners their tools
practitioner security practitioners are
innovative their intuitive they've
learned how to automate problems and
solutions they don't sit there and click
the same button every day over and over
because they go hey that's not effective
like that's something I should be able
to make happen automatically and so I
think what if I had first of all its
what what a practitioner is and how we
start addressing problems to be much
more oriented around as much more word
interest interest is building it into
solutions that kind of bindings in both
indoor environment first of all got a
protest on security vendor 250 million
in revenue broken out our revenue for
anything is for security so excited
been waiting to drop exclusive security
vendor that's much better secret of
boxes I think that it's the there's an
approach on complexity apocalypse and
you learning what everybody my father
and here's a simple anecdote for you how
many people here automotive engineers
great no hands went up so I've got no
readers in the room people remember the
story the Ford Pinto put a gas tank
right at the very back when you got
rear-ended at least yeah how many of you
think that's a good idea again none of
you you're all lame people and you can
all understand how the Ford Pinto is
badly designed the jeep cherokee that
was taken over at top speed by a number
of your researchers were always supposed
to credit and i don't want to like blank
on new haberdasher Charlie Miller's name
so it's do I love their twitter name now
what did they do wrong anybody here know
what is the simple design failure of a
Jeep Cherokee there's like 18 things
that go wrong right it's not once I go
into one simple we can the aunt about
but the lane versity can look at that
and say here is the one bad design
failure that went into that systems are
now so inherently complex then we can no
longer look at them and go this is safe
or this is not safe and that means doing
risk evaluations really hard because
here's the other dirty little secret our
industry quantitative risk assessment
doesn't work outside of the actuarial
industries like if you're doing fraud or
insurance on large populations great
other than that all risk management is
done from the gut we're papering it over
with the beautiful reports that say what
we should do but it isn't it's a gut
check we think we need more security
short go to risk assessment so I track
which things i'll go do but it's only
started because somebody believed that
there was a problem we're losing the
ability for lay people and by laypeople
that includes three
Gio's in the room and all of us if
you're not a systems architect you're
looking at some complex system that
you're building and trying to judge its
risk and we no longer have the tools to
understand how these systems operate and
that's something that really worries me
is will security increasingly become a
cargo cult where we just tell people
will go rotate your password every 90
days because that's what we've always
done even while that's no longer
interesting problem or solution sorry so
far yep oh so I think we're going to
continue to see that cyber application
of traditional crying models I think
that's the big emotional ladder 15 years
you know you had vandalism with people
just defacing websites and then we had
that the sole credit cards and their
data and there we have you know
kidnapping and ransom warrior which is
the next thing and even its evolving
because they start their your
fingers off and send them back to you is
it delete your files when you don't pay
I think that's it's not gonna where they
at
I think everybody knows the FBI said
that ransomware is going to be a
billion-dollar business this year and
it's just never-ending and I think
adding to the complexity of the Internet
of Things that's just going to open more
opportunities for these you know
traditional crying models to move into
the cyberspace and and we all have bank
accounts so this should be interesting
to see what you're worried about
management I like marc bullard and cyber
advised the cyber cyber minus I thought
of a good summer vacations like this one
too like the bank at pointa know i wish
i had a nice metaphor that like Andy had
but um I'm with mark on kind of that
that what we've seen in the past or
regular crime taking on that digital
life and I think one of the you know
again if I knew what was gonna be the
next big thing I'd be talking to my
broker's right now and not talking
anyone else here but I don't know what
it is so I think kind of that I OT that
mark kind of led onto is as we start
putting on more and more things to the
internet without truly understanding the
proper ramifications of you know how to
secure you know a simple bus within you
know jeep cherokee like that you know so
someone can't tap into your car and turn
it off while you're driving on the
highway we're missing that full
understanding of the implications of
when we add these things and I'm sure
Sony can talk more about from a health
care standpoint of you know having a
heart rate monitor things like that to
the Internet the personal devices all
the wearables all that stuff are
becoming more and more relevant and I'm
just cautious that no one is watching
the watchtower
yeah this morning when Mudge was talking
about how one of the car companies send
out a USB to create their own where do
so I'm I'm really glad that that I'm
hoping the health care industry doesn't
do that for pacemakers or something like
that Jam this into your nipples likely
taking all of y'all laughter yeah the
market what would you have them do
instead like think through the
alternative of how else would i think it
was our update we can send it over to
the internet and you can download it to
your pacemaker does that no damn in I've
idea like we have somebody hand side of
it all that really makes me scared like
so we don't give them place solutions to
really children it's going every day
when I was on drug dealer but there's
real Duke solutions it was easy for us
especially make fun of the ones they
choose but at the end of the day the
larger IT industry has failed yes to
create means that will work for
businesses so businesses ignore us
because we haven't helped them solve
their problems yes are to actually
answer your question path from a
financial sector what we're seeing is is
the sagra fication of money so the big
boys editing of that manner in the
blockchain looking at kind of how are we
going to handle the credit default
default swaps and things like that from
a financial standpoint with this digital
currency it's really unprecedented I
haven't seen much regulation revolves
around it it's gonna be an interesting
world as it becomes
morrell into the layperson health care
so within healthcare the compliance the
regulatory space is changing rapidly and
it's been very difficult to understand
and the standards and controls that are
going to be used across the industry so
everybody's sort of using their best
effort right now but the technologies
that we know around you know encryptions
in more secure protocols but since
there's really not a definitive guide
line and now you know changing with a
political landscape that kind of in
government is trying to you know
regulate the standard that's even a
little bit scarier and more challenging
because we do have potentially solutions
in the private sector they're going to
be overlooked because government
political officials feel like their
standard is going to be better may not
may be may not be but it's an effective
rapidly evolving the space challenging
and earlier one of you referred to us is
how many the group of know which is
often said that the security team is no
you can't do that but enough negativity
in worrying what are some of the things
that you think the security field does
really well I'll go John yeah sure
actually one of the last one answered
Polly a directive if you really come on
oh ok my selfish alert moment on the
last thing of his challenge to my
subjective opinion is that we are not as
practitioners in our community mentoring
and controlling and guiding
industrialization of our workforce we
have people with security buzz that have
I made an industry experience working in
drugs on those people and these children
these projects innovations in their
pocket of every of the block we don't
have the best mentors for ethel
barrymore references or them to meet the
demand our policymakers i created in the
cyber nashville challenge over the
summer I was probably not a person there
that ever actually worked on the video
network which is really good to see how
these kids and remember universities
talking about policy I actually went
there as a social project the CBD to do
a white paper is coming out soon to talk
about the socialization of cyber
security and to see the difference in
the definition of what some of my age
that's working on PhD a political
science has to meet us in kc i'm working
on is so in 10 years it's good for me to
sit down and actually see what their
thing is coming and it's totally
different so I talked about policymaker
definition if people like much DTI
workings advocates for years and no
one's could see to have much more
drastic impact
if they had listened to them whether you
do now so investing into your cheer one
person now is absolutely been opposed to
your success in the future I'm sorry
about that that's just what I'm saying
any part b 1 vectors welcome back on
that social but negativity and wearing
yeah absolutely or anything optimistic
and it's like the is starting on
the guys it's like it's cool we got this
don't worry about it sometime i three
gigs of data would be probably that back
it was good though is that your bank
card works you'll right I don't know
it's all century um they probably just
be want to know telling me how's it
going um Gator but know some of these
materials / well so we're actually going
to go back into their coin there I've
seen the hackerspace situation right
people while it sounds to people that
arguing better things on their off-duty
time than they're not if I working as a
security practitioner and we've only
driving that later but I really think is
what we're doing well we are working as
a middle piece better now I think that
we honestly ever have an industry yet
cso's that are going out of their lanes
and doing things like going to the
Masters developing with the CEO because
they know that might be what it needs to
take it are keen to victory you next
year and its back in the day that would
then never even heard the security guy
and I didn't even have an you know a
full seat of the board so I think we're
doing really well today or bringing
ourselves out of her comfort zone that's
it all Andy what are we doing well I
don't know dorm conferences
yeah so it's a hard one yep sort of step
back and say what is our job right
fundamentally our job is to enable
better risk voices and so are we doing
that or is our the industries that were
protecting thriving and are we helping
contribute to that the automatics it
like naming vulnerabilities might
actually be the thing we did most well
over the last three and look I know a
lot of people are opposed it right they
talked about you the jeep cherokee being
stunt hacking and why do we have have a
logo for heartbleed and image tragic and
all this other stuff but let's put it
this way how many people besides Larry
can name Seabees by number right and
sure times on the e guy and I can't
there we go right we can you know
continue to think of our industries
being this arcane thing we have to be
part of and which means we have to
market ourselves and I think we are
doing better marketing ourselves and
everybody interested that they had to do
something because of Hartley like
everybody across every business rather
than I talked with somebody the reason
we're hiring and he came in he said yeah
you know heartbleed was a boon for me in
my previous job I'm like why said well
because for the first time I could say
we have to do this thing and pass
servers and nobody argued with all right
that's fantastic then we're actually
able to communicate up to the layperson
even as our systems are getting
complicated
yeah oh I agree I don't want to go too
much on the same similar rent but the
socializing of security you know the
longest time the security guy was
someone in a dark room in dark corner
doing you know whatever security people
did you know even if they had a security
guy or girl and I think the ability to
now you know understand that there is a
human aspect to it and being out there
and talking to people and I work very
hard to be the social face of security I
walk around I put my ear to the ground i
know people see me kind of water in the
halls and that's how i get good
information i learn about it you know
what are you working out when you see
how this where possible we don't just
becomes very well yeah right thank you
but I'm serious becoming that social
aspect and I think we're doing a better
job of it I think that we have a face we
have a name you know security besides I
don't know how long you guys been doing
this six or seven years six or seven
years but I think we're making that
progress you know six or seven years ago
this wasn't here so get out there put a
face to it it's funny I occasionally
somebody will poke fun at me for not a
ping pong I play but I'd like the best
source of information that is
have be being social is so critically
important to the role in here if you're
not going to walk around and again talk
about a little really come from the top
of the stack you're seeing you all the
way down to junior developer help desk
person they it's probably not a great
role role for you so you get
disconnected on the organization I would
say as far as the optimism i think that
the security community yeah I've talked
about it a different way a few different
tops but it will really a young industry
right people have saw me in source on
Wednesday long as I said is that you
legitimately in the late eighties
through the 90s were a bunch of you know
teens or young adult or in some cases
kids breaking into shin and then we woke
up in this I really do now epileptic
crap this is like an industry to have
Caroline and so we're really young and a
function of that maturation so which has
been good or someone obviously has been
bad one of the fantastic things that
we've seen is we've seen our community
become more open and accepting so I mean
you know Andy Lucas earlier with holding
conferences it was not that long ago
when you roll up to DEFCON people in OB
were like you were going to be bored you
weren't welcome like it was just a
different experience than that you have
now a lot of adventure and I'm add one
more thing on a jump onto the third rail
yo that'd be really careful up as a
white male to talk about diversity but
if I was in a conference like this five
years ago it would not have been
twenty-five percent female or this
outwardly female in case anybody's
presented differently in the inner room
right that was not our industry our
industry was pretty much white male if
you weren't white male you we felt like
the outsider is nobody knew
work I'm sure so I did quite has some
stories of those days but that's a
fantastic change we are not a community
that is installer and we'll need one
demographic so I think that's the thing
we're doing well at but that's well by
comparison of we were horrible several
years ago Chomp well by comparison oh he
should just be done don't sounds bad
yeah we don't suck as bad as we used to
yeah that's going to all take that
that's that's always the first step
acceptance and markup I didn't pirate ah
hi right in general I think one of the
things we're doing well is we
communicated with each other we share an
information in ways that we have done
previously on hell even the government's
stop to get better on and that's that's
unique and not only are they shared
information better with themselves but
they're sharing information with other
it is important organ we're sharing it
back with that and I think that helps us
all higher end is always being
relatively good at that is Adam will
probably a test when it was back in his
days of high rent or longer we share
information a lot we talked about how
good vendors are badly their tax on
quarter and thirty or anything else is
whether the by-product or not we share
indicators are compromised very quickly
amongst ourselves and never I'm seeing
more initiatives where high red is
pardoned with the business is partnered
with the government that collaborated
shows
of information and this is really help
and not eat any job to get that pay no
fees I think that's one of the things
that while I'm looking better did you
want to add anything Simon yeah I would
just say the collaboration I mean you
would think that security professionals
would not be a very open bunch but I
don't know if it's the therapeutic value
that comes from getting around the table
with fewer stories I hear would you know
we cross hair yeah and it but that's
refreshing to me because it kind of
keeps me aligned with what I feel like
my strategy and my priorities are going
to be for the next year it's sort of a
sort of you know throwing things on the
wall making you know having them stick
just kind of reiterating the value of
what I'm doing day to day so I think
collaboration is what we're doing well
and that we need to do more of it and I
think it needs to be you know security
is not security across every industry
and I constantly seek out people in my
vertical to understand what their
particular problems are because programs
are going to look very different I mean
you have baseline you know firewall
architecture discussions at its you know
security forum like this but when you
get into healthcare you get into banking
things become very different very
quickly and with the amount of monies
that we get in the nonprofit sector we
will really have to be very careful
about where we invest annually invest
with
I just have one more question when I
want to hit you sony just said something
that I think it gave me an anecdote
humble years ago to drive some pretty
much a good chunk away just hurt I was
standing at the recon two years ago
there are different kinds of levels in
September each year I think they're
having their sixth one this year and
every year separately they've broken the
record of the including Kentucky Derby
weekend of the hyatt in Louisville is
about alcohol sold Institute and so they
always have fleets on site we have large
event and like it was like three o'clock
for 45 min Mourinho's competing in CTF
and I was just kind of taking a walk and
talk to one of the cops and he's like I
usually I've never seen anything like
this before like you like that sweetly
obliterated people playing with complex
variants of chess like some guys are
talking about like Heidi headers and
every excuse this is not something you
just vacation other and it's only on
vacation is just cool alright so we're
drinking will yeah it really nice out
drinking every what bunch of alcohol
that was the takeaway
about a functional social out foundation
is that they excel in etiquette so
before we can go all sit around the
table and have a beer i7 laptop question
afro so how would you say that your team
is or your team can impacts the
community both local and abroad John do
you want to start without yeah so uh
we're dying here and here is that I
don't not even explain Anaheim I see
chapter president I think we were
workers labor laws we have no chapter I
mean we just don't stop it's pretty much
the mission is in size every day two of
us are finishing up at HT is Peavy who
can't great long ago started loudly
about 90 people here medical offices in
there every heavy literally just don't
stop every single day being advocated we
get on the barnes and noble some votes
on the group and basically just work to
teach people like how the 3d
internationally understands what's doing
for programming is security but
advocating my god dinner with the mayor
and next week to talk about the economy
development direction cybersecurity and
two weeks obviously one of the person
who we volunteered via community courts
council to help children with shua
congregation initiative and sin as well
as disabilities so nonprofit work
belarus abilities so to summarize it
don't hack the world and have a good
time for you each other I guess along
the way inception is where you're going
my CEO is a roast and I even have a
party response people everybody that
just you have anything about how you're
impacting the local scrutiny because
everybody is it because it's because we
had a 144 divided people speak like it's
exactly except I think that you a always
push the envelope and then talk about it
but one of the problems is industry guys
they got caught in this run its end
because people that aren't new to the
industry or are new to the industry want
to get out and they want to do best
practice problem is best practices are
broken and so do best practices don't
happen and put people experiment and
then talk about it talk about what's
worked and what hasn't borin computer a
doll that Nia better so the only weight
will get better is if all of us
experiment push the envelope and come
together and talk about what worked and
what didn't work
it was when we can't work in this like a
state local municipality but that's my
charity work our municipalities
department where we do a lot of the
banking for countin town is whatever
light power things like that you would
be surprised a lot of security so I have
built this 10 page they called my
security Bible whenever we bring on a
new client and when I got here I went
through all of our existing clients I
sit down with them in their security
department and I go over a when you're
sending our you know ACH transfer you
really shouldn't use pork 21 for that
and we go over a lot of times I think so
I try to make as most I can too they
expand our security and our posture
internally to our customers and we work
a lot with Miss apologies in a sense of
trying to bring them up to the year 2016
just want to say thank you to Andy Josh
Adam mark John Sonia thank you for doing
this friend thank all of you for making
this another successful d sighs