you know
yes let's see if you feel about like
that after we're done they found the
topic in they gave it to me they said
just whatever you're uncomfortable with
give it to the Puerto Rican he'll take
care of it that's my job I'm the Puerto
Rican that just cleans up after
everybody else so I do forensics I do
governance I take care of bad behaviors
so why are a lot of people uncomfortable
with this topic the conversation starts
really really nicely you know there is
great post things there is great
research being done and then the trolls
come in so there is this really good
things to be said there's real numbers
there's all of these things out there
and then the conversation just very
quickly degrades so whenever you get
into these conversations don't read the
comments don't listen to the comet just
bypass this thing to focus on what is at
hand so yeah questions oh okay good yeah
feel free to agree and disagree too for
that matter let's just not go too far
into that so definition what are we
going to talk about today we're not
going to talk about equality or
liberation or justice or anything any of
those things we need to get into a
position to staff some of the positions
that we have open and that's actually
where we're going to go another thing
that we're not going to talk about today
is we're not going to talk about how
this is so great and how having one of
everything is it's a good thing and it
do it this is not true it's not true
there's just no way that you're going to
put a whole bunch of personalities
particularly infosec personalities in
one room and they're going to get along
so what is diversity so when you look at
me a lot of people i have had Iranians
Iraqis Venezuelan so let's let's come
back to this continent Venezuelans every
every nationality of brown person so to
speak clean me right it's like II one of
ours sec nom tiny little island a lot of
people don't know that it's actually a
turret
one of the last colonies if you actually
want to get political and it's a mess
it's a mess right now but putting that
aside it's what we perceive with the
five senses sometimes you know the
person next to you is cooking really
funky food they're not from here and you
know what do they look like and that's
how we tend to judge people okay fair
enough but if you actually start looking
underneath the surface and your
presentation happens to just go away for
some reason because you press the wrong
button you'll see that it's way more
than that right the conversation
nowadays it's in the gender right where
we're discussing a lot of gender issues
and bathroom conversations it's it's the
big thing that is part of the
conversation right but it's also where
does the person come from their politics
there the way they think their values
their beliefs is way more than just what
they look like or what they eat or
anything like that this picture is
floating around and it's we have
everything that we can see as the tip of
the iceberg and then the depth of the
person is actually way underneath that
there's a stereotype that I'm still
trying to look for it there is a there
is a little Mexican guy with a big
sombrero taking a siesta I gotta tell
you I've been to Mexico a few times have
friends that are Mexican I never seen a
mexican take a siesta now they're
fiestas though that their parties are
wild but I never seen somebody take work
so seriously down to religious status as
I've seen a lot of immigrants they just
they come here to work they work really
hard and again it's like I'm still
looking for that little sleepy town
where I can actually take a rest and I
haven't found it so where this
conversation is going where I want to
take it where the people that write
these great postings want to take it
it's in a little bit more complex of a
direction this woman does anybody know
where she's from okay for the weekend
race to New York Sonia Sotomayor even
she's complaining about the fact that
the
words in our home state are a little bit
too uniform all of the judges are
familiar with white grant crime and
they're not really well versed in the
situations that they're going to be
faced as judges and what she's looking
to do is to bring a diverse perspective
into the cases that the courts are seen
by the way this conversation is going to
be in stop doing that oh did they ok now
the entertainment portion I'm going to
teach you how to dance salsa in the
meantime but so I talked kind of quickly
is one of the traits that you don't
particularly see until you actually
start talking to and engaging me in
things that i really like like infosec
and politics so long as you know bring
them into the right we keep them at the
right level and so anyway let's see so
the issues whether we have security
security right now it's kind of like
diet and health we're spending a ton of
money we're getting success as we move
forward we improve a lot and then cake
happens or insecurity we get breached so
we get pulled in different directions I
in the late 80s Early 90s it was all
your hacker you you Sakura thing you
break things can you prevent people from
breaking in can you change my mortgage
for my grades it's like well yeah but I
don't want to go to jail so in diets
most a lot of the diets fail there's
there's no commitment in diversity kind
of the same thing happens there is yeah
we're going to create a diversity
program we have these great successes in
infosec kind of the same thing we're
actually going to secure all these
things we're going to implement the
million dollars worth of new hardware
and then it fails we're back to the
drawing board well how about we get a
new risk management framework how about
we get some new tools let's do some new
scanning let's get a new perspective and
it just is kind of like we keep going up
and down up and down and we don't get
anywhere so let's just jump on a new fad
let's see what happens then in the
meantime we're going along with a whole
bunch of positions that are still open
so the conversation it scoops the
conversation needs to be about people
the life where later aight the the
problem that exists between the keyboard
and the chair it needs to be mu it needs
to be moved towards why can the human do
to actually secure the enterprise and
where do we get more of these humans
it's been about what the blue team needs
to secure to secure the flag from the
red team what can your employees do to
defend themselves from attackers and
again there is no matter how many tools
you put out there no matter how much
money you put out their tools money
resources you throw this problem there's
just not gonna be enough so not bad I'm
having a lot of problems doing
presentations nowadays because it's I
want to hit the most people and when I
present the a-team I said should be
people think of Oh Liam Neeson no this
is the 18 there is no other 18 there's
no more there's no other so as you can't
these the group does anybody recognize
the top picture NASA specifically which
team up Apollo 1 2 3 4 5 6 the moon 11
yes so one thing that these teams have
in common is a door diverse there was a
lot of issues in the 80s about
objectification of women in the 18 but
she was there
to me there was a woman that was mostly
part of the team but these are the guys
that that were the face of that group
then we get SNL saturday night live one
of the most successful runs that they
had was with this team of crazy people
and there we have it again ladies and
gentlemen so if this keeps going we're
going to switch to salsa lessons okay
which in the end may or may not be more
productive but definitely will be more
fun so what was that go ahead so
question your team at home at work
whatever you work at does it do you have
within your team all of these skills or
somebody in your corporation that
provides them Who am I missing here
something that you have in your work
team okay I was gonna ask you a chart
but then you switch excellent who else
who do you work with that it's missing
here business okay yeah do like customer
care or for technical response it's
often like if something is broken
customers will complain about it to like
help people and making sure that
intermission is tasked out to equal
incident response is really important
okay in very large companies this is
these are broken down and you know it's
us versus them and all of those things
but let me give you a lesson a very
quick lesson everybody know what SSL is
good everybody incident which any
incident responders in the room present
or past
and now our salsa intervention I like it
see diverse thinking right there so
insulin responders in the room as
present future excellent imagine this Oh
Tracy una llamada le dicen que van a
pagar Su Su corporación que hace no
hablo exactly so with all of these
people in the room not a single one
speak Spanish okay that for today my
friends is not your swinging salsa
lesson it's your Spanish as a second
language lesson okay so no matter how
the verse you think you are there's
always the attackers are going to throw
something at you that you may not be
ready for and what you think with that
and what you think you need it before
the attack it just gets thrown out of
the window somebody had a source this
week said everybody has a plan until
they actually get punched in the face
Mike Tyson yes somebody used that I at
source and what ends up happening is
sure you actually have all of these
plans you have all of these people you
have this awesome team and then you get
a curve that my friends was a phone call
from a hacktivist in South America that
called the corporation and all he cares
about is the politics of the corporation
and he just said I'm going to attack
your corporation this is what I'm gonna
do go out defend against it good luck so
if you actually had somebody that spoke
Spanish and that actually looked this
good then you could actually
couldn't say that with a straight face
you would actually be in a better
position to defend your corporation and
again it may or may not happen that
easily but by the time you get the phone
call who knows what's going to happen so
what we have right now is we actually
have a lot of external factors
controlling what we do as incident
responders even as product managers we
have a lot of people that are getting
packed because of social engineering the
counts of fishing that it's that is
coming in for CEOs it's just it is
incredibly high as to how successful
they are last night we were sitting at a
table discussing InfoSec in politics and
what then this election happens one of
the people at the table got an alert
that somebody was trying to hack into
his account relatively high level
individual inner product corporation and
of course he doesn't respond very well
to Authority he doesn't respond very
well to getting you know click this to
actually change your you know it just
doesn't go then on the other side you
actually have a lot of people that are
very angry as to what corporations and
and particularly in this country are
doing so you get an activism and then
the worst thing seven thousand dollars
for example to just to pick a number
it's a lot of money in in other
countries it's what somewhat some
families make together in a year so for
a relatively amount for a relatively
small amount of money you have somebody
that is going to dedicate their life to
trying to get into your corporation to
get your secret's out or just to cause
mayhem if they shorted your stock so HR
I eat how do you know 022 yeah they just
click yeah its first of all right if you
actually if you're hacktivists right if
you're actually trying to break into a
corporation and you can get through what
are you gonna do if you fall short
technically you go recruit someone that
is already angry and there we have it
ladies and gentlemen non-malicious
accidental you know I opened up the zip
file and I got a shipping notification I
got a bill and then you go ask him were
you expecting a bill no I never gotten
one in my life so why do you open that
they're just you know sometimes curious
well-meaning they just want to do well
by your corporation and they just they
do silly things I'm the one giving this
dog by the way my partner that is
Romanian he will tell you they're stupid
and then you'll leave it at that so now
you know why I'm here instead of him IRA
week work is brought this up but a lot
of people do not want to security
awareness we talk about individuals who
either intentionally or unintentionally
it it's ugly there was a talk this week
at source about insiders and the nation
states that love them if you can
actually watch the recording it was
great it's scary the amount of money
that it takes to recruit someone that is
disgruntled most of the successful
attacks exfiltration data that happen in
corporations it's the range of money
that they get is between a thousand and
ten thousand dollars which in this
country is pocket change in other places
is a lot of money but these are people
in corporations with white collar jobs
that are just
getting paid peanuts to to just do
damage genuinely not only am I not being
wounded are they not malicious but they
don't realize what to do it for doing
this problem a former employer might had
a ton of fraud situation where attackers
collect socially engineered collected
pieces of information from different
employees of the organization and once
they had enough pieces were able to
submit fraudulent orders to our vendors
and then made mom make off with more
dollar amounts what hardware and you
know print paper printer Schneider and
that's like none of the targets inside
our organization malicious none of them
knew they were helping owners that were
paid off and then we're bad people ah
but things people can do wrong type of
the causing problems without because
they believe that you called ask
questions or call them what help they
should help people oh yeah I do physical
pen tests i did a phishing attack not
too long ago a paid don't let the color
of my head fool you paid and at a tech
company where i submitted 900 request to
for password tests 90 ten percent of the
people sent it back within the day I'd
ended a test of a financial of their
financial department I asked for a
million-dollar million dollars and I
didn't get it but I did ask for 25,000
and before I came back from lunch the
money was transferred so it's just it's
amazing yes people want to help that's
our nature but there's control in place
yeah there's control and it was email it
wasn't a lot of work and I made the
email ugly everything was well spell but
it was it we try to make it silly on
purpose and it just it worked it worked
you were okay
so then we have HR and recruiters and
they make our teams look like this very
capable very energetic energetic they
had their is experience I saw anybody
not caught up with this is it right um
but she said it yeah so there's former
dead people here to make it even more
diverse so it's it's you know great team
great team but you know they actually
have really predictable tactics right
this is what we're gonna do we're going
to move together as a unit we're gonna
go left we're gonna go right everybody's
going to be honorable and let's fight in
line and let's get this done and then
the attackers come in and they throw
everything they can at you right old
ladies frozen dead people Giants
red-haired people actually that was one
of the one of the memes that was going
around at redheads heart no soul but I'm
glad that one this over I happen to like
redheads a lot and so they throw
anything they can they want and then
then you're left with you know the
Spanish phone code that you don't know
what to do with so the worst thing that
happens is you get a phone call saying I
have a great opportunity for you right
and it happens to be a resume that you
posted about 10 years ago that somebody
sucked out of a database and you're
getting cold to do tech support and you
haven't done tech support in the last 15
years or your career so yes I am a
senior recruiter my name is John I have
a very thick accent from nowhere in this
country and I'm here to offer you
something and it's for your corporation
and there we have it so you get this
phone call and then you get this if
you're actually the the hiring manager
you get this great
eat resumes from people that don't
really want to talk to you I was just
talking to someone at source Mike Taylor
that said he got a resume from an
individual that I wanted to do
metasploit as part of their job and
metasploit is a great product and if you
use that for pen testing or just to
cover the bases you know that is pretty
much a wizard you just you can put in a
wizard mode and you walk through it so
this individual asked for a hundred and
eighty thousand dollar salary to click
through a security tool and there was
nothing else he knew how to do by the
way so if you happen to be in this room
I want to hire you but I'm gonna put
your my sales team okay because if you
got that kind of money for that level of
job I mean hats off yeah yeah I mean 180
kick to run a wizard it's like the
clippy that Microsoft used to have in
the corner hey do you need help yeah
called their metasploit guy he's
clipping so we actually have regardless
how many bad resumes we get what we have
right now is we have a huge gap in
resources particularly impede on the
people side we have great tools awesome
budgets city that got hacked last year
was in the tens of millions just
insecurities I don't know about any of
you but if I had a 10 million dollar
budget for security I wouldn't be here
giving this talk I'll be in Mexico
sitting down looking for that mystical
village will the Mexican sit down and
just take siestas the rest of the day
but depending on who you ask right now
there's an awesome black screen that I
was just going to point that there is a
million jobs out there just in infosec
and that are open that are unfilled
there's a million jobs open out there
I'm going to this guy by 2020 there's
going to be a million and a half right
however the good old US government says
there are
in 2014 there was 80 2900 security
professionals out there and to make
90,000 you need a bachelor's degree in
less than five years of experience okay
these are the numbers that are a lot of
corporations use to pick your salaries
right good luck getting somebody with
that level of experience here in
Cambridge for example where they're just
people just go across the street and
they get a 30-percent salary increase so
by the way there's two categories that
if you actually do the search for
information security that come up you're
either an information security analyst
any of those in the room ha one yeah so
you are the person that they're counting
here none of these are the good people
and then database administrators their
response they're responsible for setting
permissions on databases and keep any
user is limited to the data I think
these are the guys that are skipping
their jobs signal injection and all
those tanks anyway no hating on the
database admins so however they're
saying that we're gonna experience an
18-percent a full eighteen percent
growth and yes so you start with the
left and then yes and then you step back
yes and then you step back with the
right and then you bring it to the
middle that salsa okay so if you want to
look really really good in a in a cruise
anybody going on vacation on a cruise
this this summer so this is see I can
move my hips too and that's it that's
your lesson for this information we're
going to go back to our schedule
presentation in three so there's going
to be a full eighteen percent increase
if you actually if you if you do numbers
you know that if twenty percent of
positions and your company are open or
in your department
anybody have 10 people in their
Department security in 10 don't be shy
20 more than 50 people Wow one you're
the sole security person yes okay you
got a person on a hell yeah so you know
that if you actually have eighteen
percent vacancies in your in your in
your department you're in trouble so the
good ol bureau of labor statistics is
saying that we're actually going to have
14,000 positions open in the next eight
years so i decided to figure out where
were the security people and I just pick
one of the amine regardless of how you
feel about certifications this is not
the cissp is not easy to get it's a
hassle you need five years of experience
you need a boring test and really thick
books unless you have the experience but
you can pass it it within a year you'll
be ready to pass it from zero to
certified and there are 77,000 again
82,000 jobs open or filled with 14,000
positions that are going to be open by
20 22 24 coming praying for there's
77,000 cissp s that's not counting the
rest of the ISC square certifications
let alone g act or anything else the
biggest wrong and i was for coming to
try to do this what boy and what we were
trying to do is actually have real time
yeah really distinguish Princeton I
at least eight times at the edge off
doesn't change you call information
security office you could call a lead
principal security engineer he could be
call the principal security analyst and
it's very hard to compare these no cause
it's very very different how do you try
to do that I took four offices what
certifications what experience how do
you move people of the land large people
jobs posted they're all using job
descriptions as I must be is the speed
of VSM please no idea is I'm experience
Isis Joe wants one to two years
experience NSE is fit the debt they are
out but it's almost like people copy and
it is for every single job now realize
it was great diversity oh yeah and and
all of the jobs that you mentioned
happen to have some sort of security
responsibility which you would think
will make it easy to search but again I
try to account for that looking for the
all the security jobs there's two
descriptions that actually include that
I'm there we have it right now
engineering type but also involve a
security risk management correct and GF
which are the hardcore you know Cee age
and whether you like certification or
not I just used it as the guideline just
to figure out who self-identifies versus
what our government thinks and it just
it was ridiculous in 32 you've had it
almost end excellent so facts regardless
how you feel about certifications as to
what your team composition is we're not
expecting a problem we have a problem
right it's we're lacking the human
resources that we need to move some of
their programs forward and to keep the
corporation secure even at eighteen
percent that the government says we're
actually going to have these vacancies
we're heading towards a chaos we're
going to have to start hiring people and
bringing them along
and ask good security professionals we
all know we can't solve the problem but
we can mitigate it we can make things a
little bit better I'm about to switch
into Puerto Rican mode because this
dance with with the computer has made us
lose a lot of time so let's take women
for example in IT not security specific
that that became very hard to find 51
percent of the population it's it's
female fifty-nine percent is actually
make up the general labor force however
once you start getting down into IT you
start seeing thirty percent thirty-five
percent and lower once they actually you
know good good for the women once they
get hired a lot of them gravitates
towards management depending on how you
feel about this it's a fact women
communicate better if not better more
but the reality is they're they're
better communicators in general that's
not so I thought to some of the research
endeavors on so the women's that women
including the problem is missing to
determine communicate better Pablo is
starting in about fourth grade and
continuing all the way through c-level
executives in women ditch technology and
ditch computing faster than that whoo
from middle school to high school more
women say yeah I'm going in liberal arts
to hell with this than men from high
school to college for women stay on top
of this and it's not because when they
are better communicators or women are
nurturers the women are dumb a lot of
the evidence suggests you ask them and
why do you need why did you bail it has
to do with hostility and culture yep
women don't leave because they want to
communicate women leave because people
are jerks and they're done with it yeah
so
yeah so I'm gonna be around all day
let's let's start getting start getting
closer to to the end because this is
this is the facts right these are the
numbers that we need to bring back and
present this study came out this week
from how the Massachusetts tech
ecosystem is creating new growth
opportunities from mass TLC go check it
out they their main claim is that we
have now surpassed Silicon Valley as the
place to work in technology again
arguable but hey let's go let's go with
that what it does show is that women are
definitely underrepresented they have a
claim of thirty five thirty five percent
in tech in Massachusetts yeah check the
study whoever wants this presentation
I'll give it to them nothing here that
is secret so diversity to me if I was
looking for a candidate today I'm
looking for an open mind somebody that
is curious self driven and that brings
that and manifest that into innovation
give me a new solution to an old problem
you know sim by itself and aggregating
logs is not solving our issue we need to
figure out how we're going to embrace
this that this future that that where we
going to be underpowered and then outgun
in defending our enterprises so the new
tyler ward looks something like this i
wanted to actually interact a little bit
more but even holy wood had this right
Angelina Jolie does he bring anybody
know where that her grandparents are
from their slow backs so Hollywood had
diversity right right mr. robot yeah
well hey hey hacker teams these are
hacker teams okay this two guys mr.
robot pretty cool show where you believe
it or not it's it's fun
he was at RSA this year uh if you guys
don't know where who he is hes from
egypt right and the guy that got crushed
in the elevator and mission impossible
mr. Stevens does anybody know where he's
from Irish in Spanish so again there in
the pursuit of beauty they have come up
with these individuals that happened to
be relatively diverse the two women on
the top are not from Hollywood there are
actually real hackers and I wish I could
tell you more about it but we're running
out of time so look around this room you
know we're relatively diverse but who's
missing right we need all guys for one I
don't know people I'm sorry people with
experience now you guys look too young
way too young Oh older make this air we
got a relative mix so to me age this
experience I know that once in
technology pretty much once you hit 30
your unhireable once you hit your 40s
it's they want you out if you're there
by 55 and you know and you don't get
laid off more power to you just an
interesting and disturbing factor in
Silicon Valley at a lot of plastic
surgeons are seeing more and more young
men who are going to get are getting
surgery so there we go also gave the
derrick with that so also maybe two yeah
is she better government over hey so to
me H is its I came to experience racing
different cultures they bring a
different perspective I was doing this
presentation and I dare say that women
communicate better so I just leave in
the blanks my wife that she definitely
only when we
I was doing this presentation I decided
to leave my perspective of what women
bring to the job out of this I like to
fill in the blank and different
backgrounds in education mean different
solutions so I wanted to bring an
exercise if you were building the
perfect security person what are the
skills and what are the qualities that
you would bring that you will want them
to have to me certification is less
important but curiosity and passion are
definitely critical I don't advocate
that you go out to the to the HR
supermarket and you get yourself one of
everything get yourself capable people
that exhibit these straits and if you
can try to bring in different
perspectives when two candidates are
equal and one of them can actually bring
a different perspective think about that
when you're building your team when does
the next presenter start okay so I'm
gonna steal a steal you for a couple
more minutes because I'm gonna ask you
for your help very potent MI osita a
survey of members their experiences
security and one of the things that
stood out to me was a turn to the things
that work for them and their security
leaders okay one is technical acumen to
is business acumen free was
communication so there we have it so
what can you do mentor people sponsor
more people go out and recruit if you
actually look at your company's HR
materials and you wouldn't go to work
there today just have a talk with them
show them the cool projects that you're
working on every time I start speaking
security to somebody that is an outsider
normal as somebody called them this week
they get really really excited what we
do is pretty cool and there's so many
things that we can do here code
debugging the gender gap I'm trying to
put together a screening of this movie
to keep the conversation going this was
the one change that I made to my
presentation today this showdown
check it out code documentary calm if we
if we can actually if you have some
extra energy and want to contribute to
this let's let's say we can bring this
to Boston well I want to see if because
I don't I can't do it by myself I have a
day job too I don't know yet but see
this is what I need other other offers
other ideas so um what's happening out
there ah let's see these two guys
they're doing security and promoting the
curriculum in the in bars for free so
this happened last year talk to these
people about talking about bringing
better curriculums to the schools Nick
ciao Roy thank you oh no that's that's
what's happening that's what's happening
corporations for example NASA sit-in in
the University of Puerto Rico magic ways
and they just take all the engineers out
of Puerto Rico and then they do the same
thing with pharmacy not NASA but CVS
Walgreens and all of that they go to
Puerto Rico recruit them these people
are bilingual they'd like diversity and
things I will comment on my volunteer at
a collegiate cyber security competition
every year and we have to go before the
college level and start educating yes
even in grade school and middle school
or high school because even to today I
was at competition in March and the
students are still there education and
college at bachelor's and master's level
is still focusing on network and
perimeter stop they're not hearing about
applications yeah you're about to get
these two starting
so women in cybersecurity nicks there's
a free environment where word veterans
can actually test their cybersecurity
skills there's grants there's a whole
bunch of things out there get the people
you know together Demi I really wanna
get some people out of here in Boston
this is what the population looked like
this is what your security team will
look like and remember 51-percent female
if you don't have this this is an idea
but let's see what does again what does
it mean what should it mean to you be
aware of your gaps look for passion not
certifications and look for aptitude not
necessarily technical skills and that's
on purpose so whoever wants to stay and
talk let me know excellent pun intended
that's nice there's also a relatively
new organization called the
international consortium of minority
Secretary of Nationals they have the
reverse side kick on conference months
ago ICM CP excellent um can you email me
yeah please thank you enjoy