and he's going to talk to you today
about breaking out of application
sandbox environments carcase fun yeah
okay we even lose stuff a little bit so
I'm excited to be here today
Dave graver gave a great talk and I
think there's a lot of great talks on
tap today hope you guys are excited for
this one I know I am I'm excited to be
here and mainly because I can finally
tell my family friends I went to Harvard
thank you for laughing at my lame jokes
yeah so I'm going to talk about escaping
Alcatraz today and we'll just jump right
in this is a little bit about Who I am
Patrick I already talked about me so
we'll just move right on so we're going
to look at a lot of different things
today specifically we're going to look
at the history of Alcatraz
you'll notice that Alcatraz is in
quotations there's a reason for that
we're going to look at the island the
prison of Alcatraz but we're also going
to I'm going to define what I mean by
Alcatraz for the purpose of this
presentation we're then going to move
into some escapes and how we break out
of these and we're going to do it at
different levels I'm using the
Wolfenstein three levels because as kid
I love playing Wolfenstein 3 anybody's
played that when they were growing up
awesome so you'll know how these
different levels got gradually harder
and harder until you got I am death
incarnate and I never could get through
that so but we will through this one to
these escapes we'll talk about the
mitigation techniques how can we stop or
at least figure out that somebody's
trying to escape and then we'll wrap up
with a little conclusion here so a
couple years ago I would do some work
out in the San Francisco area and I'm a
big history guy so when I go places on
vacation or for work I like to go visit
historical sites on
it just gives the history kind of
instead of it's just in the book when
you learn in school really being able to
touch and see things needs a lot for me
so when we were out there of course I
had to go to Alcatraz and was a ton of
fun so how many anybody had been to
Alcatraz a number of you okay great so
some of this you'll know
Alcatraz opened in 1934 it's this island
in the middle of the San Francisco Bay
San Francisco Bay if you don't know is
not warm water it's cold it gets up to
about sixty degrees Fahrenheit at the
warmest so that's that since late August
September at sixty degrees hypothermia
kicks in
within an hour to two you'll pass out
from the cold so it's a mile and a half
to the closest shore how long do you
think that it would take to swim a mile
and a half anybody have a guess twenty
minutes No
about an hour and a half
my sister-in-law does triathlons and a
lot of these things and so she'll swim
this type of distance in warmer water
but in the ocean and it takes her about
an hour and 20 minutes hour-and-a-half
and she trains for this so a mile and a
half hour and have to take approximately
hypothermia is kicking in within an hour
to two it's very unlikely that somebody
if they try to escape yep they get past
the guards they get past the walls they
get past everything and they try to swim
it's very unlikely they're going to
survive so the government kind of
thought this is a great place for this
president looking house ability most
notorious prisoners here and they'll be
safe well in the 29 years of operation
there were 14 escape attempts this was
by 36 prisoners two of them tried twice
23 were caught six were shot and killed
two drowned but the scary part is their
spy
unaccounted for and they don't know what
happened to these there's been reports
that they've been seen afterwards but we
don't know for sure if they survived if
we think about that with our computing
environment that can be kind of scary if
you set up your network and you try to
secure it but if there's five
unaccounted for English's actors in your
environment that can be kind of scary so
we've got to be careful with that now I
don't want to just talk about the island
we want to talk about what we're really
here for which is these applications
sandbox environments and some of the
technologies we use are the Microsoft
Remote Desktop you can use this and do
web applications publish these
applications to the web login access
them just like they're on your computer
I don't recommend it I've used it just
as a proof of concept it was terribly
slow when I tried doing this but it's
great for for management and trying
things up we also have VMware View
they're thin app which is what I used
when I was a sysadmin works great allows
you to just publish these apps and it's
very easy to manage and then if you ask
anybody Citrix everybody knows what
Citrix is it's probably one of the BEA
leader in this space with application
virtualization but we can apply these
same concepts that we'll learn today -
kiosk PCs so you go to the library and
you want to look up some books and you
have the the browser window that's lost
there for you to look it up
what can you escape that can you get out
of that to get access to the underlying
operating system it's it's possible
right so we'll look at that as well so
what's the purpose of these applications
well simplified management we're
responsible we're expected to do less
with
or more with less now we don't want to
hire more people and all that companies
so if we can simplify this management's
going to make it easier for us we want
to be able to provide remote access to
our our resources easily for our users
we want to deliver these applications to
any device so if my sales team or my
executives want to use their iPad to
access some Windows 98
application that can only run Windows 98
we want to be able to do that and so
this allows us to do and then we can
centralize that control of those
applications so I can provide an
application that's all set up ready to
go for that user and specify who's has
access to it what they can access and
really control that application and so
from from a administration standpoint
these things are great and we want to do
this but as the malicious actor or as a
pen tester myself I want to be able to
break out because having access to an
application is cool having actions to
that data is okay but I want more right
I want to I'm going to start moving
around the environment more so I want to
escape out of that if I can and then
keep moving but to escape we need a good
escape plan so this map is shows the
locations that those 14 escape attempts
were made from and by who and the dates
all that stuff but each of these
attempts they had to have a plan they
couldn't just wing it they're not going
to do well if they did that so they have
to get everything ready maybe they have
a scape rafts that they have to build
maybe they have to get a job and it's
certainly part of the prison so that
they can gather the materials they want
they have to know where they want to
escape from the one kind of at the top
escape attempt 13 those three of those
there's three guys in that one and those
three of those were part of the five
that are on account of
for they needed to know where they
wanted to escape from because of the way
that the current was running in the
water and everything that would help
them be successful so we want to do the
same thing so I've created a little
escape plan here for us so the first
thing we want to do is of course obtain
access to our Alcatraz so what's that
mean do we want to get arrested no we're
not going to prison we have to gain
access to that computing environment so
if it's Citrix if it's VMware whatever
it is we need to gain access how do we
do that a number of ways we kiosk pcs we
can get physical access these
virtualized maybe we do password
guessing that's usually the easiest way
people are very choose weak passwords
that we can just guess and often that's
how we get in the second thing we want
to do of course is figure out how secure
this application is and so we do this by
just poking around the application
usually normal usually if you use is use
it the way it's designed we can start
seeing flaws in it based on what we've
done in the past this is where the
prisoners are getting that job in that
certain area they're doing the
reconnaissance of where the guards are
when and figuring out what the best time
is for their escape then we want to set
up our tap infrastructure and that's
where we set up our command control
channels we set up our media Metasploit
or Empire listener of some sort and so
we get that all set up and ready to go
this is where of course our prisoners
are creating their escape raft again
they're probably not going to make that
swim so let's create a raft so that's
maybe we can make it and then we escape
the application this is where we
actually get code execution we can get
access to the underlying operating
system and out of that sandbox
environment and this is where the
prisoners have escaped and they've made
that attempt
and finally we profit we gain access to
other resources other data and that's
what we want this is where the prisoners
get their freedom but the prisoners now
have to do something they can't just
live life normal they have to keep their
I over their shoulder at all times and
as a attacker we need to do the same
thing I need to make sure I'm careful
what I'm doing to cover my tracks and to
be quiet so that way I'm not detected
and the prisoners would be sent back to
jail we would be kicked out and possibly
the loopholes that we found will be
blocked so we need to be careful there
so we're going to get into some escapes
then and so we're going to have some fun
with this we're gonna start on the easy
level if you played Wolfenstein this
level was so easy just blow right
through it and and so that's what we're
going to hit here keep in mind some of
these demos are heavily blurred and
that's just because the data that's in
them and to protect the systems that are
being recorded so so this first one this
first one is a the remote desktop web
access we've gained access and for all
of our attempts here we're going to
assume that you have access we're not
going to cover that part we're going to
kind of go the other steps and in this
case the application is Internet
Explorer's is very common we see this
all the time and it's most applications
or most companies when they do this they
want to be able to provide access to
their internal resources the internal
websites so they give access to Internet
Explorer to do that so Internet Explorer
is a lot like another Explorer that's in
Windows called Windows Explorer right a
lot of the code is similar that they do
the same functionality I can access
files from Internet Explorer so why not
so I'm going to type in the path to the
command prompt because that's one good
place to start with for this so type it
in we run it and we have a command
prompt right very easy there's no
difficulty here at all and we can run
basic commands and so I'll run through
you know what's the hostname of the
Machine maybe what are what's the user
I'm running as what our users on the
system are in the domain we can type all
these commands we can start running
executable too long we can whatever we
want to do at this point we have access
in this case we're going to also look at
who's the domain admins and on the
domain we notice that da3 who's the user
we're running at is a domain admin again
this is easy level right this is not
likely to happen in the real world but
we need that tutorial kind of to get
started to see where we can start from
the second demo here again is pretty
easy and same Internet Explorer but
we're going to right click and go to
view source we're going to save the
source as and gives us kind of a pseudo
Windows Explorer we can just right click
on computer open now we have access to
the file structure and then we'll go
gate to see windows system32 and this
time we're going to use Windows
PowerShell because usually that's a lot
easier we can do a lot more with it and
the same kinds of commands that we had
as before we can run our hostname and
all that so very easy not very hard
usually when I play a game I skip that
easy level when I go right to the next
level or even harder but we need to kind
of understand how we start so that gave
us that so we'll bump up the difficulty
a little bit and what they don't hurt me
and I like to think of this as
more of a amaze and so this maze you
know you can look at it and you probably
can figure out what the best path is
without even trying
my three-year-old did this maze and you
can see she she traced the whole way
without getting stuck once which is
pretty good and then she proceeded to
correct make it more pretty
so she colored it and now you can't
really see the path but that's okay but
it was even easy for her she's three so
again there's multiple ways as well so
maybe there's multiple ways to escape we
got a look at so in this demo we have an
old version of wind Microsoft Word and
so we're going to try to open a file
we're right-clicking things aren't
working that way we can't right click
and open because of the version of it so
we're going to look at some different
things here we don't even have a C Drive
so we can't go with navigate the drive
again we try using it somewhat normal
and we poke at it we try to see where we
can escape from and so nothing is
working there so let's look at some
other areas we'll look at the print
dialog I like to use the print dialog
because it's not usually thought of a
good place to escape but it's easy to
escape from from that so maybe we could
try I tried looking for a printer in the
directory the directory wasn't working
had some issues there maybe look at the
options there's nothing really there
look at the properties of that printer
sometimes you'll see files pass in there
that we can mess with it's important to
always change that printer to different
printers because the different
properties in this case we have a
default folder so we can browse and look
at it again it's an older version of
Windows of word so it might not be as
easy as some of the newer stuff so we're
just going to get out of that
so we'll try some other things maybe in
the help menu and we notice that
Microsoft Office online so let's click
that and we get access to our Internet
Explorer browser which we had fun with
before so we're moving we're making a
little bit more progress here we have no
file many of those so we can't do file
save as or open or any of that maybe we
can try navigating to a web site here so
we'll try going to Google nothing's
loading they may have some kind of web
application proxeny that's stopping us
so or a little proxy for the web that
doesn't allow us outbound access maybe
we can go to the internet options and so
going to the temporary internet files
areas is a lot of fun too because they
have links to where those are stored
where those files are and so if you
files doesn't work maybe view objects
well and now we have access to Windows
Explorer so we can try typing in the
path and doing that but this is going to
be unsuccessful they have some
protections in place for this again this
is that maze where we're butting up
against dead ends okay let's move
another way let's try something else and
so in this we're going to create a new
folder just as an example there was
nothing on there but likely you'll find
folders within my documents and stuff
for that user and in this case when we
double-click it it moves us to a
different Windows Explorer Explorer too
which is a little more powerful it's
kind of like the power shell of Windows
Explorer it gives us a little more and
now we can start to play and and get
more access here so we're going to try
modifying the path here to just the C
Drive which we didn't have access to
through word remember and now we do so
now again we'll go system32 and we're
going to try to run the command prompt
again
now we get a message that software
restriction policy is in effect and
that's blocking so now what do we do so
maybe we can copy this file off and move
it to our My Documents folder so create
a new folder just throw it in well paste
it in there and we can now try to run it
now this ran because the software
restriction policy was based on the path
but like David says maybe renaming the
file would work here different different
options so now we can start enumerate
this application what was a little more
difficult you'll notice kind of up in in
this area there's Excel icons and so we
as we poked around here and we're
usually normal we we see what does it
what are those dude so we find that it
allows us to save the data as an Excel
so let's save it and once we save it it
actually opens it in Excel which gives
us access to another application and if
we go to the Excel options we can go to
the the ribbon and to enable the
Developer tab which isn't enabled by
default but gives us a lot of control so
now if we go to that Developer tab we
can now run a macro which is a lot of
fun so let's let's create a macro and in
this case I like to use unicorn to do
this Dave and them over it just a sec
made this and it's great tool to to
really easily make those the macro so
we'll just generate a macro here we'll
copy it will paste it in usually this is
used in session attacks and things like
that but hey I have control over a
remote Excel why not try it
so we'll paste that in but now we need
to get our attack infrastructure set up
and again unicorn makes it nice and easy
by giving us an RC file that we can just
load into through Metasploit and not
have to type everything out so we'll
load that in and this is going to
establish our listener so now we're our
attack infrastructure setup we figured
out where we're going to attack escape
from and so then we can once we listen
there's up we can actually do the escape
and we got the cows a so it's likely to
succeed whenever you see that
so our listeners up we'll run the macro
we'll get an error which is in the macro
itself so I don't care I don't care
about saving it but then we'll switch
back to our listener and we found out we
have a session open so now we can
interact with that machine we could
pivot into the internal network we could
do what we want at this point so again
it's gotten a little harder it's not too
hard though so let's let's get a little
harder here again we've got the maze
it's a little harder of a maze though
you probably can't look at this and
figure out the path like that right it
takes a little more you have to kind of
play with it my six-year-old son tried
doing this you can tell that he hit a
lot of roadblocks on the way but he was
able to finally do it and so we may do
the same thing we may find a lot of a
blocks but if we keep trying we'll get
there so we're back to our remote
desktop here and our internet explorer
so we'll run that this is the problem
that I have with remote desktop is it's
just slow so even on the local network
that's why I never used it so we'll just
run this this time where I is a
different user hopefully when you're
doing your password guessing and you're
starting these processes you have
multiple accounts that you can have
compromised that you can use
usually if one is burned you're okay you
can move on so in this case we have the
file menu and we're going to go open
we're going to look around to see what
we can do here often I'll find that a
lot of things are locked down on it on
the system but interactively so I go to
the command prompt or PowerShell so
we'll go to the command prompt here and
I'll right-click and open and I'll find
this message but it's been disabled by
the administrator happens a lot so I
can't interactively use this command
prompt now I could try moving it I could
try renaming it in those cases maybe it
all fails but let's let's try some other
things and so we'll do all file and
we're going to actually create a file
sometimes you could download a file if
you have access to your own servers but
in this case I'll just create one we're
going to just give it a generic name
whatever PowerShell and I'm going to
open that now I have notepad so now I
have a little bit more access here and
so we're just going to try calling the
command prompt from it and I like to
throw in the pause in there when you do
not interactive because just in case it
just closes you can pause it and see
what's on the screen in this case I
can't go to the properties to rename it
so I'm gonna have to reopen it and save
as so I have a batch file this could be
done with VB script - or any other
scripting language that you might want
to use we'll give it the bat extension
and then we'll try right clicking open
and we'll see what happens and we see
we've hit another dead end here we can't
do that it's not allowing us it's been
blocked by the administrator so let's
let's change this let's use PowerShell
instead often when you see command
prompted block power self not so let's
try it so again we're going to
right-click and open and this time we
have PowerShell but it was PowerShell
through a back script which uses command
prompt so we have some kind of execution
there so even if you don't have access
to PowerShell you can't run those things
and nothing interactive is happening for
you you can at least run command so I do
this often when when I'm trying to
enumerate the system and figure out
users and from the domain and everything
else I could run it throw that pause in
there and now I have the data I want and
just go from there so let's move to the
hard level I like to think of this as
this kind of mace right now we have the
Minotaur in there we have fire we have
maybe the walls are changing on us as
we're walking through this labyrinth so
it's it's actually extremely hard when I
played Wolfenstein I stayed away from
these levels is I just got killed
so again we have another app and this
time we're going to hit the shift key
five times to get our sticky key prompt
and even if we don't get that command
prompt we didn't still do things and we
can open up the preferences for the
sticky keys and that gives us control
panel windows explorer so let's try some
things let's try running these files and
we're trying PowerShell we're trying
PowerShell ISE we're trying command
prompt and these things are all failing
on us and so you're going to hit this
you're going to these systems are more
locked out so maybe we can
try running an actual command through
command prompt it's not working either
try open your notepad or something
nuttin things are just not working for
us so we'll see we're blocked at all
these different places and so I can't
even right-click they've disabled that
so sometimes we can go to the settings
and get a internet explorer window which
is back to where we like to escape from
it's a good place to escape from so we
have no file menu this time we can get
to the internet so I can get to a server
that I control I have a batch file
waiting for me I want to download that
but it's not letting me so maybe I can
go to the internet options and allow it
but they blocked that too so again we're
a lot harder here no file menu I can't
right click and save as to do this or
view source and or any of that stuff so
that's not the best way so let's break
out of here go back to the application
remember it we want to use this as
normal so let's see what we can do so we
start clicking around and we find export
to excel and so we'll see what happened
well we get an Excel document right in
this case that Excel options were locked
down
I couldn't enable that Developer tab but
why not use the cell to put in macros
that we want or other commands we want
so here I'm going to try with PowerShell
and I missed the quote so we'll run that
it yes let's run it and nothing happens
ok so let's try with our command prompt
this is likely to fail as well and
that's ok
it happens run that nothing happens as
well but when PowerShell is blocked a
lot of times Power Cells interactive
scripting environments not and so we'll
run PowerShell ISE and run that and Loan
hold we now powershell interactive
scripting environment which is great now
I can do whatever I want from that load
load in my own custom modules run
commands everything autocompletes for me
so it's nice and easy so here i'm going
to dump all the users in the domain so
then i can use those in other attacks if
i wanted to i could use in a corner or
another empire or something to get a
shell if i wanted whatever you want to
do at this point and then for our last
demo this one is extremely tough
I don't know why that's not let's just
open it up here
ah
so the export didn't work on that one
for some reason so we'll just skip that
one in that one sometimes you'll get a
system that you can't get command
execution you can't get anything to load
but what can you do with it and in in
that example that was not playing I
could steal data right I can I was able
to finally get to be using the printer
menu I was able to escape out and get
access to the file system and I could
mount my drives on that system so now
when I do that I can then start moving
data back and forth between them and I
was able to steal all their data which
is great especially their custom
proprietary software which then I can
pull off decompile find you know
different flaws in and then without even
trying then exploit their system a
different way their proprietary software
so so what can we do we need to be able
to mitigate things and and I don't like
to just show hey this is how we own
things we want to be able to also
mitigate these things so first thing we
want to do is of course those login
portals if I can stop me from logging in
that's going to go a long way so use
multi-factor authentication train your
users to use those strong passphrase is
going to make my job a lot harder and
it's going to make it harder for me to
get through you want to secure your
operating systems these issues you saw
are not issues with vmware they're not
issues with citrix or remote desktop
there are issues at the operating system
level we have to secure our operating
system in our applications that are on
those so prevent access to your command
prompt your powershell PowerShell ISE a
lot of these different things that Dave
had talked about as well restrict the
use of those macros I shouldn't have to
be able to just load any macro I want
you should be able to limit that and
restrictive the internet access really I
mean why should I connect to my company
and then get out to the internet through
Citrix the purpose of that should be to
access internal websites so limit that
access and then monitor everything you
you have to be able to know where this
is happening I've been hit I hit a lot
of walls while I was trying things you
should be able to see that when you're
monitoring so in conclusion you know
securing your systems it's not a game we
had some fun with the Wolfenstein and
the mazes and all that stuff but it's
hard work and so we have to be diligent
and do that using multi-factor
authentication again it's your friend
lock down those shared systems no matter
what architectures you select and of
course it can't catch what you don't see
escaping is a lot of fun it for me it's
it's one of my favorite things to do is
get access to these systems and then
escape them in some sort so it's a lot
of fun as well and so that's it thank
you and so my contact information some
of the tools I've written and stuff if
you want to if anybody has questions of
course would be great so thank you
[Applause]
who have I been stopped by a
general-purpose kiosk where multiple
applications are available I don't see
those a lot personally when I'm when I'm
doing testing a lot of it most of it is
all through the virtual application so
you're Citrix or VMware you're that kind
of thing but what I'm saying here is
just the same things can apply to those
systems as well yeah I again those
locking down those those management
tools is probably the biggest thing
there and monitoring those those systems
would be the biggest help
I have not no