okay so let's get started good so my
name is Gordon Makai and I work for
digital defense and we're going to I'm
going to share an info sec talk in the
form of a murder mystery okay
anyone here play clue before okay
excellent
so let me just introduce myself first so
yeah I'm Gordon I grew up in Montreal
Canada so not far from here I know that
Boston and Montreal are very you know
head-to-head in terms of hockey just by
the way I saw the Montreal Canadiens
beat the Rangers yesterday was
incredible game just want to brag about
that this is a great weekend and was on
the plane so I live in San Antonio I was
on the plane coming here I guess it was
Friday and so many runners were on and
I'm gonna runner lots of runners were
you know on the plane I'm like what is
going on is it really the Boston
Marathon
of course I googled and there was so
great weekend I'm not going to be
running in it because I'm going to be
drinking later on so come join me anyway
yes I'm from Montreal Canada I grew up
there I went to McGill University so
kind of friends with Harvard sort of and
I started working in sama I graduated in
Computer Engineering I started working
started my career at Bell north and
research Nortel doing software
engineering software development for
switching telephone and telephony and it
was great and I thought hey if I'm going
to do this where's all the action and
all the telecom action at the time was
happening in Dallas Texas in the telecom
corridor so I moved my family in myself
of course to to Texas to Dallas Texas in
very very late 1995 just after Christmas
started working I think it was like
January second or third I can't quite
remember in 1996 and I you know did some
call processing call processing software
platform type software and stayed there
about seven years then telecom started
going downhill at the time sort of
gradually and I started looking for a
job I was being laid
I was given the heads-up and so anyway I
looked around and I found this
cybersecurity Internet company called
digital defense and that's where I still
work I started there in November of 2002
I didn't know much about Internet
security at the time I knew a little bit
but they brought me on board made me for
my software architecture skills and I
learned off through osmosis you know
security my work with a bunch of pen
testers who drink redbull and hack into
banks and stuff and get paid to do that
I don't know what they do on their off
time but anyway so they brought me on
board to help reaaargh attacked a
vulnerability management system so
digital defense we offer vulnerability
management system much like you know
Jack was talking about you know some of
the three like tenable rapid7 you know
Qualis tripwire digital defense we offer
a vulnerability management system we
architected it ourselves we have three
patents on it already so we're one of
the best-kept secrets in that area and
so when I came on board way back in 2002
I remember I started working you know it
started really Viktor me right into it
right away and I started working on the
existing system which was very immature
if you will was not in tiered it was
like you know essentially you had you
had database code right in the web and
you know it's kind of like two-tiered I
guess and there was an issue that I
started learning about and that's the
basis of this talk and so we came up
with a solution for this when we
reaaargh affected it approximately 2004
was the second incarnation now we're in
our sixth incarnation of this
vulnerability management system and the
solution that I'm going to talk about
here or the problem that I'm going to
talk about is solved in that incarnation
so anyway let's move on and let's get to
this so as far as an overview I'm going
to go over a little bit about clue right
because this talk models clue right so
this problem that I'm referring to I'm
not going to tell you about it up front
I'm going to step-by-step walk you
through it and I'm going to encourage
you and invite you to you know if you
figure out what this issue
you is that I'm referring to you can
raise your hand and say hey mordenite I
think I know what it is you can shout it
out and I don't have a price to give you
if you win but you recognition right so
recognition is almost as good so meager
mission we're going to talk about clue a
little bit we're going to go over a
crime scene we're going to talk about
what I call detective tools moment we're
going to talk about vulnerability
management background because there's a
specific scanning methodology that this
problem is related to and we're going to
talk about circumstantial evidence I
will then reveal whodunit so so that's
maybe 3/4 way through the presentation
talk about the victims the consequences
and avoiding future crimes okay great
this is the clue board does this look
familiar
great so clue is a game where you have
nine rooms so the ballroom conservatory
etc study room you have a set of cards
actually you kind of see them in the
corner up there I guess that's what
these are right here that's kind of cool
these are rooms right so these are the
rooms you also have six weapons the
knife the lead pipe the candlestick etc
and you have six suspects which are
represented by the little playing toque
is the little colored player in tokens
that you see here that's mrs. peacock
here she is okay missus garnet one of my
favorite characters here she is right
and so what happens is each player rolls
a dice up to six players can play you
move around the squares and you enter a
room right let me take a step back first
prior to prior to all that the very
beginning of the game one of the players
turns turns this set of weapons around
shuffles them up right and then pulls
out one that's the weapon that the
suspect use it uses to commit the crime
right so there's a crime that happen in
clue and you had to deduce who had
committed it with what weapon and in
what room so with the suspects you know
the person shuffles them up takes one Oh
places the cards
there similarly with with the rooms take
one out and place the rest in there now
the person then shuffles up the
remainder of the cards and distributes
them to the players okay so now you have
a set of cards in your hand and you're
rolling a dice and you're going around
you enter a room each player when they
enter a room can make a suggestion and
the suggestion is I suggest as an
example I suggest that mrs. peacock
committed the murder with the rope in
the billiard room so you have to suggest
the room that you enter in right now
what happens is the player to year I
believe it's left if they have one of
these cards in their hands the path if
they have one of these cards if they
have the billiard room or the rope or
mrs. peacock then they can choose to
show you whichever one that is okay so
it's mrs. peacock so mrs. peacock of
course didn't do it one of the things I
forgot to mention is at the very
beginning of the game when you shuffle
up the actual crime scene a player puts
it in the sort of envelope and that's
what that envelope is that you see there
top right here right so just blowing it
up a little bit there it is it's placed
in the middle okay so that's so your
goal is to guess what that is and that's
what we're going to do as we walk
through this presentation so we're going
to talk about information crime scene
what is this scene that we're going to
talk about okay well you know in the
olden days or quite some time ago when
security was a lot younger and I was a
little younger as well than you were as
well the different security technologies
mainly operated within their own
security silo maybe with the with the
exception of sin but essentially
vulnerability management you know had
technology and processes and it didn't
share that information with other
technologies
similarly DLP etc right and then we
started to get smarter and we started to
say hey if we want to solve sort of more
advanced and maybe not even that
advanced use cases we need to we need to
talk to each other
we need to take this information from
the various systems from the various
systems or going to go back and share it
and so what I did is I map these various
technologies like I am is mr. green
miss Carter this vulnerability
management etc one of these one of these
technologies is actually sharing
poisonous data this is the crime scene
is actually sharing poisonous data into
your security ecosystem and not only is
it polluting its own silo but it's
polluting you know these security
technologies that it shares information
with so that in the middle is your sis
Oh drinking poison as a result of it
that's sort of a side effect
unfortunately so let's take a step back
and talk about a security use case it's
a hypothetical use case but it actually
could be very real so sort of set the
stage so now please don't go over here
out of this room and say hey Gordon just
revealed a zero-day because that's not
the case it's a hypothetical use case
right but imagine imagine that we had
just been you know just today has been
revealed the fact that the apache web
server for specific versions right so
for versions two point four point zero
to two point four point two four there
is a serious vulnerability but it's not
impacting the most recent release of two
point four point two five it's fixed in
that one magically okay what would you
do as a security professional to sort of
gauge your risk across your network well
you'd probably want to consult your
vulnerability assessments right
hopefully you have a vulnerability
assessment program vulnerability
management program you consult those or
even better you would launch a more
recent scan right maybe even today
across your entire network to determine
ok which of my which of my network
elements actually is running Apache at
the vulnerable versions so I'm showing
this network diagram here right a very
small one where the red dot represents
a vulnerable instance of Apache so
there's only one here today and you'd be
you know a lot of security professionals
would say that's enough to know that
I'll now just you know prioritize this
amongst all my other vulnerabilities and
throw it into my vulnerability
management program and off to the races
I go and I'm happy but if you know if
you think about it a little bit more
it's very possible that although today
we know about this zero day
hypothetically the bad guys and bad
girls
for example the hackers might have known
about this for quite some time and they
perhaps might have even compromised this
without even knowing it maybe they got
past their incident response program if
that makes sense so what you do in
addition to you know looking at the
present is you'd look in the past you'd
say hey where perhaps was I vulnerable
in the past where today I'm not how
could that happen well maybe maybe you
know maybe you used to have an Apache
that system that was vulnerable it was
installed here in the past but you'd be
installed that you didn't need it on
that server anymore or perhaps you
upgraded to the two point four point two
five and you're not vulnerable so it's
possible that you were vulnerable in the
past but not necessary today so this
diagram is showing one instance of
vulnerable which is there in the past
but two that were in the past that is
not in the present if that makes sense
you can take that what I call
vulnerability intelligence feed an into
your incident response program as
candidates for nodes that are perhaps
already compromised not to say that they
are but they might be okay it's just
extra information so that's pretty cool
so here's where I'm showing
vulnerability management and this is at
the stage now you're playing clue and
you discovered through the process of
elimination going through the board and
you look at your cards Wow
I know that Miss Scarlet is the actual
the actual murderer if that makes sense
you may not know what room it's in you
don't know what weapon but you know it's
Miss Scarlet
so you're proceeding on so this is the
situation where vulnerability management
is feeding poisonous information
to incident response something's gone
wrong okay so in other words in the
previous diagram where I showed three
candidates three candidates are being
shared
perhaps there's actually more than the
three candidates but but we didn't feed
the right information pins in response
so there's some challenge within
vulnerability management where the data
that we're sharing isn't perfect if that
makes sense okay so let's explore more
so this is where we take a step back I
put this on the board because on my next
diagram I talked about time and every
time I think about that I think about
you know pretty Marty right so we're
Doc's on the board and in Back to the
Future - this is back to the future - by
the way if you've seen it so I used
these sort of I guess diagrams I you
know kind of fantasized about myself on
the board just like Doc and so to share
a little bit more about this issue this
challenge that vulnerability management
vulnerability scanning has is the bottom
part of the diagram that I'm showing
here represents the real-world assets
right the computers that you can touch
even if they're virtual you know they're
there right whereas the top part of the
diagram illustrates two different point
in time scans these are right so within
vulnerability management you're not just
doing one scan at one point in time and
finding the vulnerabilities and saying
I'm done let me go patch never again
look at it it's a process where you're
doing this at regular intervals to
understand all new vulnerabilities came
out or what did I fix did I really fix
it let me verify that so you're actually
doing vulnerability scans at multiple
points in time well one of the
challenges is how does the vulnerability
management system not necessarily the
scanners but the vulnerability
management system how does it know that
a given asset that's been scanned at one
point in time is the same as its correct
counterpart as scanned at a different
point in time so that's important in
order to satisfy our use case in many
other use cases it needs to be able to
do this okay if that makes sense
question is how does it do this right so
to
understand that let's look a little more
into vulnerability management
vulnerability scanning technologies I
mapped the different weapons of clue to
these and I'll explain that in a second
but first let me explain these different
technologies so there are different
scanning technologies and vulnerability
scanning land that we all use
there's agent-based which is up here
there's passive scanning not all vendors
do that but some do it's not up here but
it falls into one of these categories
there's what I call remote
unauthenticated based scanning or
network scanning and then credential
base or privilege based so when
asian-based
represented by the Rope because it's
tied to it so there's sort of a relation
this is where essentially you'll have
your your vulnerability management
system which perhaps is not necessarily
on you know on your computer and you'll
have agents that are on the computers
they're actually programs that are on
the computers that you want to scan so
you have to deploy them somehow
sometimes that's not hard but sometimes
it's not that easy right and so when you
run a scan the centralized vulnerability
management system interfaces with that
program and says go launch your scan and
the scan is actually running on the
computer if that makes sense it's right
on it so it's very accurate because it's
present on it you can get all the files
all the registry Keys lots more so
that's the engine based remote
unauthenticated in this case the scanner
has no presence at all on the host that
it's scanning its remote and it will
send internet messages to those nodes
that it's scanning and based upon the
responses it'll determine well first of
all is there even a computer there at
the IP address space that I may be
scanning what ports are open what
services are there what applications are
present for example Apache what what
vulnerabilities exist
finally right so that's remote
unauthenticated based scanning or
network based credential based scanning
is sort of a mixture of the two the
scanning intelligence is remote but
essentially what you do is you
go into your your IT system you set up a
set of credentials for your various
nodes that you want to use privilege
scanning with you enter the
vulnerability management system and you
provision those credentials and then the
vulnerability scanner will authenticate
to the various nodes and then it can get
information such as registry keys files
etc and draw conclusions it may even be
able to or can depending upon the
credentials drop what we call a
dissolvable agent or which is a program
on the computer so in that sense it's
very very similar to agent based
scanning okay so it's very you know very
deep but there are challenges or
overhead challenges IP overhead
challenges to actually perform it in
other words you have to create
credentials you have to maintain those
credentials you don't want them to have
too much power you may not want them to
live forever maybe you just want to
manage it and you know sort of in such a
way that okay I'm just about to launch a
scan let's let's enable it so there's
some overhead involved if you want to do
it right okay so let's take a step back
now most organizations enders first of
all most vulnerability management
vendors will offer their certainly
offers the remote an authenticated one
they may or may not offer agent-based
and they typically will offer credential
based so they're going to offer two two
things maybe three maybe even four
passive is in there as well and
essentially the way that clients will
use use the technology is because
unauthenticated or network based
scanning is so it has such low overhead
and it's quite accurate even though it's
not necessarily on the node they'll set
up recurring scans may be monthly may be
weekly maybe even continuously to scan
these the entire network they'll cast
the wide net to get you know to kind of
get the risk and the information across
the entire network and then they'll use
agent based or credential base for
certain situations we can talk a little
bit about more for example laptops where
you know you know you're actually doing
browsing and you have Adobe and you know
flash and those types of things there
are certain vulnerabilities that
authentic
it cannot detect because they actually
don't open ports to do so but yet
they're still remotely exploitable so if
I send you for example a word doc that
has a you know malicious payload
even though word isn't an application
that listens on the Internet you you may
still be compromised right so you'll use
credential based scanning to detect that
or for example if you know where your
credit card information is you have
nodes that or parts of the network which
have more risk you'll want to perhaps
get more information so you'll be
willing to spend more money to set up
credential based scanning or agent based
gaming if that makes sense now I tied
the candlestick to remote
unauthenticated based scanning because
the candlestick if you look at the
various weapons include the candlestick
is the only one that actually sheds
light or can shed light I didn't have a
flashlight so if I did I would have used
it but so the candlestick sheds light
right so it's kind of like the scanner
sheds light on the nose that it's
scanning and based upon what it sees
remotely with that light it draws
conclusions okay so that makes sense so
great no it's at this point in time I
didn't tell you but the candlestick is
actually the weapon if you haven't
guessed it yet since I spend so much
time on it the candlestick is actually
the weapon that's being used here in
other words it's because of remote
network based unauthenticated scanning
that vulnerability management vendors
experienced this challenge that I'm
sharing with you today
which is the subject of our murder and
you may wonder a great specifically how
do Valle 'nor ability management vendors
the solution providers how do they
actually track the various endpoints
that remember that diagram that I shared
where you had two different scans how do
they track the assets I've seen at one
point to the correct counterparts as
seen as the other at the other point
especially when we're talking about
remote unauthenticated scanning agent
base scanning credentialed a scanning
don't have that challenge and we can
talk about why but let's leave that to
the side for now
remote unauthenticated does have that
channel
and the reason is because if you look at
network characteristics for the various
elements that are on the internet
there's really nothing I mean there's
certain characteristics that you would
think are quite static but in reality
they may all change okay a lot of people
talk when when I present this or talk
about it they will say well what about
MAC address and I'm like yeah it's
pretty stable but the problem is unless
you're deploying scanners on every
single network segment or unless you're
talking about Windows you're not always
going to get the MAC address and so in
fact one of the largest vendors out
there doesn't use MAC address at all to
track and so you may wonder how do they
do it
what do they use well they use various
characteristics such as IP address
various host names MAC address they do
use host types other things to actually
correctly match those things but most of
the vendors out there used only one or
two perhaps three so they're very
limited in those algorithms if that
makes sense actually this is this is one
of the very you know one of the top
mentors out there I'm not going to name
who this is what they they actually I'm
so I'm sharing with you one one of the
prevalent algorithms out there that
actually is used to solve this problem
and I call the algorithm and they call
it for example they call this this
problem host tracking so if you googled
host tracking you know what I really
meant event host tracking you'll figure
out who it is because I'm not banging on
anybody here I'm just saying this this
is you know this is real this is a real
problem and so they use what I call
single host tracking key admin user
specifies one of it's a very long name
I'm a software developer and I use very
long names in my variables as well and
everyone tells me what are you doing but
anyway I digress so they use one of I P
address DNS host name or NetBIOS hosting
in other words they will allow you to go
into the vulnerability management system
as you as the administrator and
provision this system in such a way that
you indicate how do you want
how do you want the vulnerability
management system to track hosts across
time from you know different scans and
you can specify well you know I know
that I had this this ranger this IP
address range in this range I know I
have laptops and it's using the HCP so
I'm not going to use IP address that
would be done I need something else let
me use NetBIOS oh but this this is a set
of servers and this different IP address
so you can do it by different ranges and
you can go in and say oh I want this
technique for this range this technique
for that range etc and so that's how
they do it now is that good enough and
the question and that's the question and
to answer whether or not that's good
enough we really have to ask another
question and the other question is how
often do these characteristics change in
different IT environments so my team and
I actually did this study about a year
and a half ago that's why we entered the
study room did this study to find out
and understand well how often do these
things change and the reason we were
wondering about this is because we know
that we spent you know we have we have
an algorithm which I'll share you know
in a little while to solve this problem
and you know it uses pattern recognition
and things like that I kind of studied
that you know my final Europe Gill and
so we're spending a lot of money a lot
of money meaning it's special software
it's not like simple okay I'll just use
this characteristic or that
characteristic it's it's a lot more
complex than that and when you have
software that's semi complex you're
going to have maintenance as time goes
on more maintenance that if it's simple
meaning you're going to have some bugs
so you're going to have updates you're
going to have to make babysit it you're
going to have to you know you're going
to have to it's not it's it be great if
you have an algorithm let's just perhaps
possible it's hands off and it's very
intelligent and uses analytics etc but
that's that's not necessarily you know
how this works
and so we want to understand well
whatever what are our competitors doing
and is it worth it is it worth it for us
to actually spend this extra time if in
fact IT environments are very static
because if they're very sad
we don't have to spend all that money if
that makes sense so we did a study and
what we did is we looked across time and
we subdivided this study into different
types of devices firewalls servers
laptops and desktops you know because
they're going to have different rates of
change if that makes sense based upon
different characteristics okay
and so I'm showing you just a
cross-section I'm showing you server
types host these are findings and client
type post clients meeting laptops and
desktops by the way here is a reference
I'm sure you could all read that I'll
make the slides available so that it's
more easier we can go to my website
digital defense comm and just search on
resources and you'll find it anyway so
for server type host database servers
web servers etc application servers
where you would think that you know
there's they're not going to change that
much and it's true there's very low rate
of change but you know IP address which
is default actually on the previous
algorithm that I showed you for that
large vendor IP address actually changes
at four percent across three months so
if you look at a three month time period
if you have one server or let's say you
have a hundred thousand servers four
thousand of them are going to actually
experience at least one change so we
counted one if we saw a change across
that three month and it compounds itself
so after another three months you're
going to see more more churn right so if
your algorithms are simplistic you're
going to get things wrong if that makes
sense
so you're probably getting a little
understanding of the crime here so
here's where I have a diagram actually
showing and a map so what I did is I map
the rooms to the different IP addresses
and so in this vulnerability management
game that we're playing which is more
than just vulnerability management
because we're taking the information
we're feeding it into our security
ecosystems in the form of integrations
right to solve different use cases this
game is actually more complex than clue
because include the murders the murder
happens or what's committed in one room
but in this game
the rooms change
right so it's actually multiple rooms
that make sense so that's that one
so whodunit reveal this is the point in
time where I reveal the whole story
probably guessed it by now but a it's
the candlestick which is the weapon Miss
Scarlet is the culprit and any room you
would have picked is cool because it
happens in many different rooms so the
reason is most widely used scanning
technology in environments not to say
that the other ones are not used but I
mean if you're using if you're doing
scanning and you're doing all
agent-based than the Bravo to you that's
great similarly with credential based
but most most if not all of our clients
actually are having troubles doing that
because it costs money and so they they
often use remote network unauthenticated
scanning but that comes with the
challenge and that challenge is solved
in different ways by different vendors
in fact that challenge isn't is it's not
at the forefront of your minds often
when I give this talk by the end of it
people people come up to me and they say
wow I didn't even realize that that was
a problem and you know it's kind of like
you just don't think about it you just
assume that it's there just matching
perfectly but that's not the case and in
fact most vendors use very simplistic
algorithms and I was a little surprised
at this and so that's the second point
and thirdly all remotely discoverable
characteristics derp subject to change
so IP address is subject to change
you know IT personnel they're not just
sitting around doing nothing they're you
know things things draw up printers drop
it I said I'll just change the IP
address and I'll inform the people you
know so they kind of get around that
problem but they're not thinking oh I
better I better not change these things
because the vulnerability management
system is using this tracking mechanism
to track it and all things are going to
break so that's not good
no they don't think that right you have
these different teams and so anyway
that's that's a big problem
so the real crime here is that
vulnerability management systems lacks
efficient what I call scan to scan
endpoint correlation and the result is
often they mistake a scanned asset at
one in one point in time to a different
one or they assume a
it must be a new asset I've never seen
this before so this is the sort of crime
revealed so I open up the envelope well
I almost forgot I have it here open it
up and I've got the candlestick
I got Miss Scarlet here obviously you
know that I shuffled them up sort of non
randomly so right and you got the roof
anyway for the purpose of the
presentation very good let's move on
consequences time check
we're doing good okay consequences
there's actually two different I mean
there's a lot of sub consequences wasted
money etc but the root cause or
consequences of this issue are that the
vulnerability management system that
you're using will often declare an asset
duplication in other words and we'll
talk within the second or an asset
mismatch let's talk about asset mismatch
okay so here's an example there's this
diagram again this back to the future
diagram okay here's your assets and over
here I scan in week one and I you know I
see three different hosts with various
different network characteristics this
is what the scanner is seeing at that
point in time time progresses now let's
assume that your IT operations team is
doing some work and something happened
and they made a change to these two
assets and for whatever reason they flip
the IP addresses okay this is sort of a
very simplified example but in this
situation what happens is the
vulnerability management system if it's
using IP address for example that larger
vendor that I was talking about if if
you didn't know about this problem you
can go into the system it specify
anything it's going to be using the
default which is IP address and even if
it were servers maybe you'd want it to
be that way so anyway the system the
vulnerability management system will
believe that this asset is the same as
this one because they have the same IP
address well what's going to happen is
let's so for example take a step back
let's assume that this red asset has you
know a set of vulnerabilities
and the yellow asset has a completely
different you know it's orthogonal
nothing in common yeah sure they may
that may both have high-level
vulnerabilities etc but they have
nothing in common for the sake of
argument right so what happens is after
this scan the vulnerability management
system will declare wow you fix all the
vulnerabilities that were there before
for that red asset oh you got new ones
now but that's okay you're always going
to have new ones here and there but that
good job you fix those but that's not
true the only reason it's declaring that
is because it it encountered a mismatch
I don't know if you've experienced this
but we've talked to you know lots of
people not not necessarily our clients
but prospects that have come to us and
you know or people come up to me after a
presentation early oh that's exactly the
issue I'm experiencing thank you for
highlighting that so that's that's
mismatch duplication which I don't have
a diagram for you but sort of
simplistically is a case where imagine
that at this point in time or later you
know so for example let's say here you
you you actually detected this issue you
like wow wait a sec why is the
vulnerability management system telling
me that these things are fixed I know
they're still there and then you and
then you discover oh it's because okay
let me go into the system and actually
change this so that it no longer matches
an IP address but instead matches on
let's say oh I don't know well I guess
it's kind of hard because there isn't
anything in this situation but let's use
this one so the red one
DNS hostname I think that's correct it
looks right yeah we're going to use that
and if it's not let's assume that it is
right so I'll use that right but then
later let's say that's changed and so
now you're in a situation where you have
nothing that's common and the
vulnerability management system will
detect it at a certain IP address and it
would declare well I've never seen this
host before because it doesn't match
anything so it must be a new one let me
add it to the asset list so that's
duplication now you have two hosts which
actually had the same information and
you may actually take this and take this
host prioritize the vulnerabilities and
send it out for remediation well
need to discover you know after work you
know in research Wow
I don't I don't even know where that
host is or oh hey wait a sec this house
belongs to this other team it's not mine
and so there's actually what I call a
lot of chasing ghosts right so victims
and impacts I talked a little bit about
this one of the largest well there's a
lot of different issues here but one of
them one of the sort of high level ends
is you have in your you know in most
organizations security generals right
and they're looking at this information
and they're making decisions based upon
the risk you know so if you look at what
what vulnerability management brings us
brings us a lot of things but it also
brings us sort of a gauge of what our
risk is across our entire network
talking about our actual you know
network security risk that's opposed to
other types of risk right well that
information they want they're making us
making decisions based upon it and often
that decision-making although perhaps is
correct based you know it's correct from
an algorithm perspective it's incorrect
because the actual data is not correct
right so if so in other words the the
vulnerability management system is is a
gauge for risk and that gauge is off
because of this issue right so that's
that mismatch scanned endpoints right so
I had a prospect that comes to us and
told us told me a story where they were
actually like just as the example before
they were assigning out vulnerabilities
so so essentially this is a large
organization they have they were using a
different solution at the time they have
a centralized vulnerability management
team or centralized security team that
is responsible for vulnerability
management and they had different IT
teams that owned these assets right and
so they had a lot of duplication in
their asset because of this problem and
they were signing up Valle 'nor
abilities to teams that didn't even know
where the assets were because they
weren't owned by them they were owned by
a different team so that's wasting time
right so lots of other issues there so
how do you solve it
well this is what we did at digital
defense we unlike other vendors where
they're just taking a few different
characteristics simultaneously in the
case of that large vendor that I
referred to they were actually using one
simultaneously you had a choice of which
one out of three but really you're
looking at you could imagine like or
sort of you know
yeah the analogy I use is imagine your
fingerprint where you have all these
different ridges etc well wouldn't it be
great if you could fingerprint match
based upon everything you see but what a
lot of vendors are doing is they're
actually just taking one one little
Ridge one that you could one a three
that you can choose or maybe they have
two maybe you don't have a choice maybe
there's two or three so it's very
limiting why not use everything that you
can see and that's what we do right so
it's not simple because you have
different characteristics that have
different weights and there's a lot of
sort of dependencies etc but if you
could use everything that's a philosophy
if you could use everything you see then
even though you know one thing or two
things may change across time at certain
rates by and large if you're looking at
everything you kind of have a semi
static thing that you can use to match
these hosts right so that's what we do
so the ideal solution so going back to
our mismatch even though this red host
had perhaps changed its IP address the
system should actually of course realize
that and this is a simplistic case but
it should match it together so simple
diagram murder mystery solved thank you
very much for helping me with this so
security ecosystems the use case for
example at the very beginning which is
kind of you know it's a cool use case
inner others in order to satisfy that
you have to understand or the the
vulnerability management system has to
correctly map the given assets as it
sees them at different points in time
and those things change right that's the
second point Network
and points change problem is most
vulnerability management solutions use
one or two characteristics or three but
they don't use all of them unfortunately
so they're very limiting how do you
solve this well ask your vendor hey well
how do you how do you solve this problem
now that you're sort of more enlightened
on it or hey use their API pull out so
for every scan you pull out all the data
put it in you know some place not
necessarily a sim although perhaps you
could and you correlate this on your own
now not easy but it's doable and that's
what we do but we do it within the
context of the actual bowels of our
vulnerability management system so
wonderful it might be a little bit early
but hey thank you and any questions