a little bit about my background I've
done about everything in security i
started i graduated out of the Media Lab
the MIT Media Lab focused on how humans
perceive technology I was doing some
crazy things with head-mounted displays
a friend of my friend and I actually
developed our own head mounted display
crazy enough it looked just like the
Apple glass or the google glass that
came out so I'm trying to figure out
where my friend is who worked with me on
that but I I mean that was a small-time
you know kind of kitty hacker at a c64
at home poor family so what else am I
going to do but do BBS hacking in my
spare time I learned some basic did some
coding that sort of thing and then
decided yeah I suck at this so if I
could figure something else to do and so
I went into cognitive psychology start
focusing on how humans interact with
technology which made it great to become
a social engineer so that was fun and so
from there I did usability engineering
for the government doing user interface
design but then I moved into security
because I was already kind of doing
security so I figured I might as well
move into security I've been doing
security for about 20 years started on
the consulting side I actually call
myself recovering consultant anybody a
consultant in the room anybody who wants
to be a consultant in the room they so
but i did some interesting things i work
with some big companies work with some
big agency start working on really
really large risky security oriented
projects i'm sure everyone's heard about
DHS at one point in time DHS was a bunch
of different little bureaus that all
came together at a net by an act of
congress and didn't want to communicate
with each other I was the guy who was
trying to convince all those CIA SOS to
do so so I did some of that and then I
jumped out of consulting became a CISO
started listening to vendors try and
sell me twenty-thousand-dollar
appliances why do security appliances
always cost twenty thousand dollars I
don't get it to this day somehow that's
the magic price point I guess somebody
paid twenty thousand dollars like oh I
got an idea so so I did that and then I
ran my own consider curity consulting
company with a friend of mine moved from
DC thank goodness i don't know if
anybody lives in DC ors ever lived in
DC I would never wish that on my worst
enemy came up here to Boston I started
focusing on advanced research and one of
the things about advanced research you
know we have a problem with security
right in all of those pads that you know
all the path that I've taken all the
little touch points I've taken as far as
security is concerned there's one thing
that has been consistent we users
administrators investors businesspeople
executives etc etc board members we are
the weakest link right why have we been
saying this for 20 some odd years at
least right I say 20 some odd years
because of course we didn't have really
the web before then so we didn't have a
lot of cause to have to talk a lot about
security but for the past 20 years we've
been talking about we are the weakest
like and the thing is is through my
entire career I've been trying to figure
out what does that mean not what does
the statement mean but what does it mean
that we keep saying the same thing over
and over and over for two decades at
least and so you started taking a look
at the problem of course cognitive
psychologist I always have to see okay
how am I things up right what am
I just doing wrong I'm doing something
wrong everyone's doing something wrong
I've been saying for years everyone's
doing something wrong and I started
thinking about it and I'm like there's a
different problem here if we if we keep
saying the same thing it's kind of the
definition of madness right we keep
expecting a different result and all
that's happened over the past 20 years
is there's more of us saying it right
but you start thinking about it and you
start realizing that what is going on is
we're trying to convince ourselves that
we know what the problem is but if we
can't haven't been able to solve the
problem then can we really say that and
so I started looking at the psychology
of it I came to bsides last year was my
first b-sides I really had a great time
and Melanie Anson last year she was she
was talking about how security
professionals market themselves how they
market their capabilities and how they
communicate to executives and all that
and she said consistently blaming people
reinforces the perception of being part
of a negative subculture and generates
hostility well we all know that because
we're kind of a hostile community right
when in part we want to generate
hostility because we think that by
generating hostility we are going to
affect change right but I'll go back to
we keep saying the same thing over and
over and you can extend that to just
about everything else that the community
does vendors are saying the same things
over and over they're selling the same
things over and over we put new names on
them we do some incremental enhancements
we add about five more pages of
configuration and say now you're good to
go right so if we keep saying the same
thing over and over and we're developing
a negative subculture so we're being
less listen to less and less then what
does that actually mean about us as a
community now I piss people off by
talking about this in the way that I
talk about this i'm not saying it in
order to be adversarial even though as a
security professional i suppose it is
part of my job right but i think that
we're living with the shared delusion of
superiority right it's a delusion that
is consistently reinforced right these
headlines this is from this week because
of course i wrote the presentation this
week it didn't really have time to do it
otherwise and so um we every time we see
a data breach every time we see a hack
every time something happens that's bad
in security it reinforces our rightness
our correctness right we are basically
living high on the fact that all these
years everything that happens we are
right and this is proof that we're right
hmm yeah America that's right so the
question at the bottom there if we're so
smart then why isn't anything getting
better I ask people all the time I ask
the people I work with I I work with a
lot of non security researchers right
and I also work with I'm working with
the ciso of my organization right now
as he and I have good sit-downs me
having Tennessee is oh he being a CISO
for a nominally a defense contractor and
I sit down I say here are the ways that
I'm breaking your policy right now you
know I'm breaking your policy you know
my team's breaking the policy and I can
tell you all the good reasons why we're
breaking that policy the thing is is
that it's because something's not
working we're not being enabled we can't
do this but I understand that I try and
serve as a bridge right but if we're
always consistently right and why isn't
anything getting fixed so I want to
change things up a little bit and say at
some point we need to stop being so good
about pointing the finger around
everything that surrounds us and we need
to turn the finger back on ourselves as
a community if things aren't getting
better okay fine at some point we just
need to come to acceptance we're living
in the state of denial right now we are
the weakest link the security community
has not fixed what we set out to fix so
then the question becomes okay after
half the room wants to lynch me or you
know then we go into typical security
mode cynicism I haven't seen anyone
leave yet so i guess i'm doing ok but
the obvious statement the next statement
that we too rarely move towards is what
do we do about it right what can we do
about it so what i would say from a
cycle from a psychology perspective i'm
going back to my social psychology
education where of course the professor
asked why are you in this class and the
best response came from a football
player and yes MIT does have football
players the best response came from a
football player who said I want to learn
how to manipulate people and the
professor says that's the best response
I've ever heard anyone give he also
wanted us to grade ourselves by the end
of the term and halfway into it he was
asking us he had to have an intervention
because we were all giving ourselves ass
so I I presented this theory at is d
squared last year where I said that my
theory is that part of the
if we start going to start looking at
the root causes the problem we have to
take some introspection maybe a little
bit of intervention and we have to say
that where what is the root cause of our
problem and I would I what I'm
theorizing is that the root cause
happened at about the point where the
web was the web started getting used for
e-commerce right where we started
professionalizing the use of the
internet and we started to
professionalize ourselves as a community
right at one point in time hackers and
security professionals were the same
people in different contexts in fact
literally the same person right you're a
hacker by some point of the day you were
a protector at some point at night mit
at the in the 90s the way that the MIT
network was run the MIT network was run
by the hackers why because they were the
ones trying to defend their space right
from the hackers that were trying to
take over that space it was a game you
know it was a game but we all had very
similar skills and we all shared
information we didn't have any sense of
malfeasance vs um what altruism or you
know whatever you want to call it
goodness we were the same people and in
a lot of ways we would make decisions
based on the context that gave us kind
of that gray hat sort of mentality right
depending on the context we might be a
black hat we might be a white hat it's
all a matter of what we're trying to
defend that then there was a divergence
the divergence happened with
professionalizing the use of the
internet okay so what happened is we
started becoming corporate beings we had
to start adhering to certain structures
we had to start you know we had to start
being consistent we had to have
stability in what we were doing we had
to get certifications I've had my cissp
forever I don't know why is just kind of
inertia at this point right I don't even
know what it means anymore to have it
other than the fact that every July I've
got it goes creeping back through all my
you know activities to get my CPEs
together thank you very much besides for
letting me speak I think I've got my cps
for this year um hmm hey yeah so so we
had this divergence but
the whole puzzle thing up there we I
feel like by professionalizing we've
lost our ability to solve the puzzles we
used to solve we used to get really
fascinated by the puzzles by just trying
to tool around and figure out how things
worked and and we didn't figure out
things broke to find out how they broke
we were do we were breaking things
trying to figure out how it worked right
and it was there there was there was
that exploration of it but what happened
is that the security practitioner became
way too formal and way to practice in
routine but the hacker did not and so
there was a divergence and we started
losing cycles we started losing the
ability to to dedicate time to invest
time and resources and doing that stuff
so if you accept that and I won't ask if
anybody accepts that because I like to
live in my own delusion superiority uh
what about security is so hard right and
I asked that question intentionally
because 1i I like my hacker graphic of
being hit over the head with a hammer
but I asked the question because I feel
like we're asking the wrong questions
we're trying to solve the wrong problems
and I think that all the breaches
telling us that we're right that there
are problems it's kind of masking the
fact that we're not willing to actually
explore what those root cause problems
are right and so I feel like in all the
steps in my career I I kept thinking
there's got to be a better way I'm gonna
go try something different I'm going to
go become an executive and see how
operations can be fixed okay well that
didn't work out too well let me let me
go run a consulting company because I
think I I'm better well you know that
didn't work very well actually that
works great my wife relocated us here
and I gave it to my partner because I
wasn't willing to travel at him down to
DC well maybe Advanced Research had the
answer but then what are some of the
things that people say about researchers
and when I say Advanced Research i'm
talking about i'm going to be talking
about DARPA programs right I'm going to
sound a lot like Mudge actually in fact
you'll see a couple of graphics that
look just like Mudge's graphics except
they're better here
but you from from there's gotta be a way
all of our intelligence all of our
smartness and our innate abilities to
solve puzzles we should be able to do a
better job so how do we do that what
about it is so hard let's look at that
problem so I know a lot of people have
seen this t-shirt walking around the
cons um majority said this he was about
as critical of antivirus as I am about
the entire security industry as a whole
security industry is a subscribe and
respond model it's not even about
security what we would consider security
right security companies they come up
and I can say this because they did this
to me come up and they say i want you to
subscribe to my service okay i want you
to subscribe to my service because it's
fantastic everything you're doing well
you got to keep doing it but i want you
to do more you've got capex right you've
got a capital expenditure moaning well I
want you to use it on us because you've
got to use it somewhere and then when
something breaks I want you to call us
again so we can tell you what broke and
then when we tell you what broke I want
you to call us again because then we'll
tell you how to fix it oh you still have
capex right what ended up happening from
a CISO perspective is my capex Dave
level year after year my effects was
going through the roof because I was
kept sliding more and more appliances
into my racks right but so essentially
the question becomes why do most of us
think this is actually correct there's a
point in time where the only way you
learn about data breaches was because
brian krebs figured it out going through
credit records and you know dark web
forum selling credit cards and you know
all the connections that he has all
these organizations you know they had
the tools right they all had tools and
what do we say when target gets hacked
her when Sony gets hacked or whatever we
say oh they just weren't using the ring
target what was the one the first
headlines I saw oh they had something
that could have found the breach but
they weren't using it
it hasn't been actually you know
deployed yet and we keep finding reasons
but if they have the tools what good are
they right the basic premise I'm trying
to get to is an understanding that okay
we're selling lots of tools we're using
lots of tools we're consulting we're
integrating we're doing all this stuff
but they're not working our first
instinct is to blame the administrators
to blame the users to blame how it was
configured how it's being logged but
that's that's going past the point right
what we're doing is we're really
defeating our core mission and that's to
protect what's good protect the users
right how do we protect them if we keep
blaming them so as I delve into this a
little more I kind of came to this idea
that we we sort of i'm sure people could
add to this list but i kind of started
thinking about it from a software
perspective we keep selling tools
generally it's software there there's
not a lot of hardware and I'll time I
talk about a little bit of that but I
kind of cut it down to three assumptions
right these three assumptions we can
write secure code right you think about
the things that we blame people for
right we can write secure code we can
simplify the administration of software
or is it simplify the development and
administration of software we can manage
patches right all of the messages I hear
that blame someone kind of go in some
spectrum of these assumptions right so
if we're blaming them based on these
assumptions then these assumptions must
be correct right well if we take a look
at each of the assumptions maybe maybe
we can get a better understanding of
that root cause problem um we can write
secure code Microsoft are wonderful
hosts here hopefully I don't piss
anybody off from Microsoft if I do I'm
sorry I doubt you want to hire me anyway
um Microsoft is great case study right
the trusted computing initiative great
idea great necessary idea it was a
marketing ploy it lasted for 10 years 12
years something like that
and of course Microsoft will come back
and say well it's still going on all we
did is redistribute those people into
the places where they need to go living
one of the mantras that we use which is
the security people need to be
integrated into the teens right except
what Microsoft doesn't tell you is most
the people who were part of the trusted
computing initiative are no longer with
Microsoft so if that was such a good
idea why right well we still have
patched Tuesday right in fact in trusted
computing initiative I think probably
started Patch Tuesday because otherwise
it was just randomly we're just getting
patches and so in order to help
organizations we we gave them okay
here's what we're going to do just to
make CISO your life easier we're going
to tell you which day of every single
week you need to have your people
working overtime so they can evaluate
whether or not something's going to
break in your environment right then you
can plan around it that's great love it
but the core thing is is that what
Microsoft was experimenting with and was
doing quite a let's call it a beneficial
effort was Microsoft really put a lot
behind and I mean Bill Gates had a great
statement about it I have a lot of
respect for everything that mr. gates is
done and I think this is right in a way
but yet here we are this was what 2002
here we are 14 years later and we're
still getting patches every week right
the only thing that's changed is that
they're shrinking the lifespan of the
operating systems so they don't need to
keep releasing patches for them right my
iPad just went in lock I think Apple
needs to fix that assumption too we can
we can simplify software right this is
going to look really familiar okay
software size continues to grow right
anybody else see this recently you know
why this chart is better than Mudge's
well I'll tell you um I'll tell you
Mudge is one of my jizz bosses who
reported to Regina Dugan at DARPA
and at Google a tap was a gentleman by
the name of Ken Gabriel who's now my
boss he hates this chart too just as
much as general Alexander I best hate
that hates it and so when I showed him
this chart he said I hate this chart and
what I did I took out the years and the
lines of code now it's gorgeous now no
one can argue with me about numbers but
up there we have I changed I've changed
some of the the code bases a little much
talked about operating systems i added
in i think that's a c-class Mercedes
Mercedes Mercedes is great at creating
bloatware I'll tell you what you should
see the number of processors on that
thing it's awesome so anyway the budget
I have some disagreement as far as the
number of bugs per thousand lines of
code i'm pretty sure it's 15 i think
that 125 is a number of security defects
in thousand lines of code but i don't
think we need to argue about that about
numbers i'm actually going to take out
those numbers after you know much
disagrees because i know you know Mudge
has all the credibility I'll just some
dope up here so I've gotten like a
little gallery over here so um so when
you take a look at this and you think we
can simplify software this doesn't even
tell the whole story right think about
the number of packages that we're
reusing as we're building software think
about the number of open source packages
I was just looking at one very commonly
used open source package and it has
somewhere on the order of a hundred
different other packages calling within
them now if you if you've ever been
exposed to open sort of it to software
in general or anything like that you
understand that a package the software
package may have a lot of functions in
it right and you need to you need to
basically use that package in order to
call that one function you want and
suddenly you've you know inherited
hundreds of functions you're never going
to use right and then we're nesting so
much into that software that any given
developer actually does not cannot touch
every part of the saw of the software
that you're actually delivering
then when there's a paps that comes out
no one knows where who's affected by it
right G would see that's a good one
let's have a vulnerability in G let's
see and see how many people you know can
fix that right away um and so we're
talking about all the nesting and
everything that happens and we start to
understand that can we really simplify
code I mean someone l word some people
say that the answer is going to be IOT
because we're gonna have smaller code
bases I laughs of course majority showed
that malware is not going up anywhere
because we only have to attack one
little you know small park right so I
think that assumption it can be blown
away so third assumption let's talk
about managing patches who thinks we can
manage a patch man and we can do patch
management oh they just didn't deploy
the patch yeah how many times have you
heard people say that how many times
have you said that how many times have I
said that we are terrible Apache for
good and bad reasons right okay the
administrator I can't patch that
database because it might break it well
yeah I I remember Oracle deployed a
patch one time this was back in the 90s
Oracle developed a patch for a
vulnerability it was it was some sort of
you know remote oh we've got an open
back door vulnerability we're gonna
close it by not closing vulnerability
but by removing the function that had it
thanks Oracle I appreciate Larry um but
there are good reasons there are bad
reasons there are many reasons there are
people reasons right but please don't
argue with me about the verizon dvir i
intentionally did not fix this to be the
2015 because it seems like nobody likes
the 2015 I don't really like the 2015
either so get past the fact that this
comes from verizon let's just focus on a
little bit about the information in 2014
verizon found its investigations at
seventy-five percent of the
vulnerabilities that were exploited in
2014 came from before 2014 in fact came
from 2011 back I love 1999 I think
verizon they get real kick when they put
that 1999 and
you know what that is that's SNMP it's
it's it's still a problem right it's
still problem but so 75% older than
three years right five percent were
discovered in 2004 to where at least
discos in 2014 right so there's reasons
for this we know that okay now we're
looking at going oh my gosh things are
really bad we can't do anything right
well I think that kind of blows
assumption 3 out of the way right is
this right we could argue over whether
or not this is right but i think it
probably is a pretty good point right is
the assumption valid well i think based
on what I've heard from blame messages
it's a valid assumption that we're
making but is it correct can we fix that
there's a harder problem to evaluate
here and it gets worse let's talk about
IOT again what was it nest or Google had
bought that a hub and they said that I
OT hub that everyone said it was going
to be the next big thing and then they
killed it and said what we're going to
do is we're just going to remove the
capability all together so that we're
not leaving it unmanaged out there I
actually said that was a good idea
because that's not what's going to
happen right right now we're getting
patches right right now it's just a
process problem right a really big one
but what about when we stop getting
patches whose responsibility is it going
to be to maintain those devices that are
on that are in the IOT that are no
longer being managed by companies that
no longer exists who twenty thousand
dollars in appliances that's right so
that is my premise the hypothesis
software will always be inherently
flawed why do we try to fix that then
you know we're going to be we're going
to be trying to write secure code and
what's going to happen is that all the
Sun we read the best code and we need to
write a new function as some kid 22
years old is going to come in some guy
who's 60 is finally going to retire that
22 year old is going
make a mistake that 60 year old maid
when he was 40 right oh but universities
they're the problem they're not teaching
them right I mean it Microsoft oh I'll
pick on our host a little bit i pick on
our hosts a lot um microsoft did a great
thing most brilliant thing they could do
in the 90s and that was to say hey we
know our software kind of doesn't always
work right but it's not our
responsibility to protect it it's yours
I want you to invest all of your
company's money and your employees time
I want you to create a whole industry a
professional industry around protecting
our software I call it defect acceptance
right brilliant business strategy you
can argue whether or not it's merited
but um it really is we've we've become
accustomed to that idea that it's hard
jobs to protect something that's already
defective right but all we can do is
just kind of put containers and wrappers
around it but again I ask what's the
core problem right we don't want to ask
that because now we're starting to get
hard right our imaginations are starting
to run wild about what the problem is
and so what what I'm trying to charge
everyone to do is number one stop the
blame it's not effective it obviously
hasn't worked you know you could just as
easily say stop the madness let's start
focusing on what the users need to
perform well not where they fail right
let's reassess the problems that we're
trying to solve and let's an embrace our
inner hackers again what we're dealing
with is we're dealing with a really
complex puzzle and it's a puzzle I think
most of us have willingly stopped trying
to piece together not saying it's going
to be easy but I'm saying that we need
we's can start forging new paths and
stop whining about the problems we can
be part of the solutions so the question
becomes what are we going to do about it
well I put this up here because I I
really if you haven't noticed I'm trying
to charge I'm trying to charge up the
community I'm trying to change the
narrative CIO phone s from
DHS he said this in 2016 it's online you
can you know it's it's video it's really
great he says there there's no there's a
lot of incremental improvements in cyber
security but there's really no
breakthroughs going on I'm like oh my
gosh here's a Vinick biggest cynic I've
heard in a while right the thing is is
he's wrong but there's a problem there's
a problem they are happening i'm going
to talk about three technologies that
are going on in boston right now that
are being developed in boston right now
the problem is is it's well one nobody
speaks research or talk you know
researchers can't talk to the
practitioners because researchers have
this idealistic vision practitioners
want you know too much blah blah blah
blah blah it's hard to talk to the
researchers I know I'm do it all every
day but the challenges is that they
don't necessarily have the access the
tool or the tools or the relationships
to figure out what about what they're
doing will work well right that's where
we as a community can help we can help
the researchers researchers but it's
going to take a little bit of effort let
me talk about some of the technologies
appropriate disclaimers I'm I related to
this effort one of the things much was
talking about is the stuff that DARPA
funded when Mudge was at DARPA there was
one of those big money programs 100
million dollar program that was focused
on the idea what if we could redo
computer architecture right and so that
effort was um was based on the premise
that computer architecture we use today
is the exact same computer architecture
that van Noy Minh designed in 1948 1947
1948 the same architecture we just made
it bigger faster gave it more memory
connected to network and said go and
that architecture is essentially when a
processor sees something comes in it
goes okay and so what um what the
project was it was part of the crash
program which has some long acronym name
that DARPA likes to use and bae systems
which I was at I wasn't involved in this
research project but bae systems said
they had a project around building
your processor now there are problems
with transitioning a secure processor
right now you're telling everyone
they've got to use a new processor well
at the end of the project the team the
engineering team was able to demonstrate
that they could get most of the same
properties that they were building into
a proprietary processor onto a commodity
processor and so we call it Dover Draper
took over the transition of it Draper's
and not-for-profit research laboratory
and the reason why I came was you know
to do this but the reason why I went
over to Draper's because its board
driven mission oriented and they said we
are going to invest money we have in the
bank to see if we can transition that
that's one of the gap areas DARPA's
going to fund a project from eighty
percent risk say to about maybe let's
say sixty or fifty percent risk a VC is
only going to fund something at sub
twenty percent risk so where's the
thirty percent going to come from that's
what Draper is trying to do they're
giving us the opportunity to do that we
may crash and burn but one of the things
that's really cool is we we stopped
heartbleed we demonstrated that to our
CEO in February we stopped heartbleed on
the working we're working on an FPGA
right now so bare metal FPGA so we
showed heartbleed working gave it gave
his password actually so we know ken
Gabriel's password but then um what we
did is we we put it on our adapted
processor and it stopped it the cool
thing about is it's on a risk five risk
five if anybody's not familiar with risk
five risk five is an open source
instruction set architecture being
developed out of it's essentially out of
Berkeley it's backed by Google's backed
by Oracle it's backed by amazon and
several others the point here isn't to
tout our own technology it's too
it'sit's to talk about this is really
cool if we succeed this is awesome right
nobody uses risk five today but the
thing is is it's open you know how much
arm costs arm cost a million dollars a
year to use for companies to use 20
million dollars to design to the what we
would need to do is we would need to be
doing 20 million dollars to do what we
feel needs to be done at the processor
level
or a year to do it on arm we started
with risk 5 because that's free you know
it's open source but it's an example
it's an example and we we're forming a
not-for-profit collaboration with
industry partners right now to get
access to it to see how is it how could
it work in your environment and we're
going to open source all of the tools
that are necessary to do it so great
example i have a link up here oh yeah
credits randall Munroe XKCD rocks that
link on the slides I'll make the slides
available somehow you can always email
me to that link will take you to the
core paper one of the court papers that
describe the technology from the
research perspective another technology
not affiliated with as well I kind of
one of the projects I manage MIT is a
team member for DARPA they're doing a
competing project on the same so I'm not
talking about my project i'm talking
about mi tease project because it's
really cool and i'm an MIT grad so i try
and pump them up a little bit um the
idea profit is auto correcting code as
your as you're working on it how cool
would that be they're not quite to auto
correcting right now but they are
stewing synthesis for a specific code
class but they've got about two and a
half more years of work to do on the
project but this is really great
technology it's the idea that they can
press office said recently that they can
repair ten times as fast as other as
other techniques they also do different
things than other techniques do but this
is being done right where are we where
it's right there hey you know at the at
the strange Frank gehry-designed status
Center over there that's where this work
is going on they would love they would
love to get real problems from
practitioners that they can focus some
attention on in solving right you can
just contact the researchers I put a
link to the place where they talk about
profit for your information there's a
paper they're also all the contacts are
there and then let me talk about ibr
I came from bae systems when I came over
to Draper a Draper driver um and I've
used ibr I've designed technologies on
top of I BR disclaimers there I think
it's really really cool and it's open
source so it's available right now
online and what I dr what's really cool
about ib our introduction based routing
it's based on this concept that two
endpoints cannot communicate and less
introduced by a third party by a by by
some communal third party that third
party can then be connected to other
third parties in order to create a link
chain of introduction then if one of the
endpoints detects something wrong with
something going on with the other
endpoint the reputation is funneled
through all the introducers and
eventually if your reputation drops to
some level then you would take action on
that it was it's it's a very simple
technology it uses point-to-point VPNs
once the introduction chain goes through
then what happens is it creates a
point-to-point tunnel between the two
endpoints that tunnel is refreshed in
some arbitrary time frame we were
generally doing three minutes there was
we demonstrated how it had no effect on
a video stream for example between two
endpoints as it was refreshing that
session and what it does at that session
refresh it is it asks everyone in the
chain have you heard anything bad have
you heard anything bad have you heard
anything back really really simple
concept the researcher who first came up
with the idea gentleman by the name of
Gregg Fraser he runs his own company
down in Virginia he called it a
peer-to-peer network for devices but we
had done it bae the technology we
actually ended up building a management
layer around it for cyber physical
systems and after i left bae they
continued with it and it seems to have
some some movement in DoD so we'll we'll
see how the technology evolves but like
i said it's open source you can play
around with it now right and um there's
a pay i put a link to up there for the
core introductory paper again one of the
things i was impressed by josh Gorman
said at a recent conference last year he
said at a presentation where somebody
was talking about active research going
on technology research he said there
isn't enough
this going on in security cons so that's
why I'm putting the paper sources this
is stuff you can actually get access to
you can look at you can find the
contacts you can talk to people about
them okay so no breakthroughs going on
each of these technologies solves
lower-level problems than we've been
willing to address up to this point are
they the solutions for those problems
well time's going to tell but to say
that it's not happening that there
aren't people exploring this space is
just flat-out wrong my tagline solutions
not problems we've blamed people enough
but our jobs are to protect the users
may be to protect them from themselves
right but the thing is is that there are
inherent flaws and everything that we
use today and we have been unwilling to
address those flaws thinking that either
the problem is too hard or that they're
impossible to fix I don't believe either
of those are the case but I don't
believe we're trying hard enough but I
think the researchers have the right
ideas I think DARPA too much as point I
think DARPA's doing a great job of
seating this stuff but they need help
the researchers need help so I I said
the definition of madness I when I
pitched this speech I talked about Moby
Dick a hab in Moby Dick right I get the
sense that we as a community are really
turning to Ahab and we're chasing our
white whale it's imaginary the problems
that we're trying to solve right they're
not really the problems they're just the
easy way for us to reinforce our feeling
of superiority so what can we do about
it how do we change every security
practitioner can help in some way if
you're willing number one collaborate
reach out to the researchers find out
about these technologies that are going
that are happening sit down with some of
these researchers
granted some of them are arrogant pricks
I I work with many of them I think in
order to do stuff that they're doing you
kind of have to be but they would love
to hear your insight and I'm sure you
would appreciate understanding how
they're approaching the problem I
mentioned before Draper is starting to
host an industry-wide collaboration
around the concept of inherent security
it's not meant to sell our processor
like I said we're open sourcing you know
most of the tools so there are some
designs that may end up getting
classified yadda yadda but there but
we're having we're hosting this
collaboration in order to bring
organizations together to say okay if we
agree that there's a big problem we
agree we can be part of the solution how
do we build an ecosystem to start
supporting that solution space right so
reach out evaluate one of the things
that I found when I was in my ciso
position is I didn't give any time for
my employees to just tool around right I
didn't give them any sort of New
Directions hey this is a problem area
right can you go explore this I might
say hey this vendor called me and wants
to sell me this tool can you go valuate
it that's not it that's not research
that's not research um reserve time to
take a look at this stuff give your
employees a way to do it I I mentioned
besides asked what do we want to say
what questions do we want to ask at the
CSO panel and one of the questions I
want to ask is what are you willing to
allow your employees to do to help your
organization get more protected right
and I'm not talking just internal bug
bounties or something like that i'm
talking about are you going to give them
time to tool right to kind of reinter
and participate offer researchers time
and resources to help i'll tell you from
my perspective i'm working on a project
right now where if i could get object
code from companies if I could just get
your object code and I could you just
allowed me to store it for example right
so i can use it for my evaluation for
I'm we're doing a machine learning
he had mentioned at machine learning
against to predict bugs and code right
we're going to find something at some
point we can talk to you about it but
we're not looking for any of your time
to do it other than if you give us your
code if you're willing to write um you
can give us old code if you want on
earth just something to help us do it
right in some cases what I've been doing
is I've been reaching out also to other
organizations at commercial
organizations and saying hey do you want
to participate in some DARPA research
are you willing to do that I mean Google
you have lots and lots of money can you
spare you know 100 engineers to help us
out on this project oh thank you but we
don't need necessarily a lot we just
need a starting point and so what I'm
just asking the community to do is give
it a little thought offer something of
yourself kind of get to that hacker
mentality again and start asking well is
there something else that I could be
doing with a little bit of time a little
bit of money a little bit of resource
that could be in Ann's it could be an or
so that's my pitch it is now 247 I'm two
minutes over I apologize for that are
there any questions
from big peanut gallery over here well
part III think I think part of the thing
is they're there needs to be an
educational side you know informational
right because there are lots of
agreements that are preventing that I
work in the Department of Defense space
and I try getting code from defense
projects even though I mean please I've
got asked if available to me I could
keep things classified I you know can we
just and there's that need to know sort
of thing and it's the same problem and I
was talking to one of the the gosh I
forget her name at the moment the person
who runs the bug bounty program for the
the hack the Pentagon right i was
talking to her hmm for well known the
DoD side and i talked to her a week and
a half ago and i asked her a very
similar question and she said part of it
is the educational side the
informational site it's making it
available but part of it is also helping
them understand that just because it's
going out doesn't make it any less it
doesn't make it any more available to
attackers and it already is and so when
you if you have those agreements it's
one thing there are technologies where
the researchers can bring it to your
organization and you could use it there
perhaps you can also of course I think
as far as agreements are concerned if
you go through the chain of people who
are responsible for the restriction that
you can architect some sort of way in
order to do it it's not an easy problem
from a contractual perspective but my
whole thing is I'd much rather go to the
source than to go to some you know
further up the chain interface as
concern so I'm not saying it's it's
certainly easy but it'll get easier if
more people start allowing it
and part of it is a trust thing right i
mean i can't tell you that Draper is
going to hold your code and no one's
going to get access to it right but then
again neither can you so so there's
there's some perception things to go
over and stuff I I think there are
strategies to be able to do it and I've
worked on the contractual side of
getting through some of those strategies
and they're always oh I guess she's in
control we have a question right here
yeah I mean I I suppose I probably
implied a few ways of how you need to
support the users but one of the things
is is that our way of providing features
to users is completely it's way too
complex right we just add configurations
to tools that we're developing and we
expect that as long as the capability is
made available then the user can use it
but we have no attention to usability
you know what is it that users can
actually do I don't think there's enough
user testing about about the tools that
are actually going into place that's
that's one example and of course I'm
biased because I started my career in IT
as a usability engineer another way is
simply by blaming them when something
goes wrong I mean how many times have
you heard people be blamed because they
used a bad password rather than say well
the whole active using passwords is
wrong you know our the way we apply the
way we use passwords is absolutely wrong
we have websites today that won't let
you copy and paste a password into the
input field because they say that's a
security risk but that prevents anyone
using a password vault from being able
to use their secure passwords right um
so I think that there's that secure by
design sort of the sort of perspective
we need to kind of apply that to the
community itself and understands that
secure by design means designing user
interactions in such a way that prevents
them or helps them
not break the security chain we're more
informed than they are about the risks
and yet we put all the tools for them to
protect themselves in their hands okay I
haven't looked at ways in in that regard
of course you know I'm one person
unfocused on some sort of limited
problem spaces right I'm familiar with
some of the work and again I think it's
really really cool work there are
challenges when it comes to the vast
majority of ass number of systems that
we're going to start our devices that
we're going to start talking about and
stuff so I think that it's it's a great
example of approaches that are being
applied to address these problems but
like i said i don't have direct exposure
in it one of the things i think there
aren't enough people looking at things
the way trying to bridge the gaps the
way that a few of us are but i think
that many of us are capable of doing it
so it's great to hear about that and i
think one of the big challenges comes in
disclosure right in talking about this
stuff right an academic researchers I'm
going to come to be sides and talk about
their work right and and well then they
may not be able to in many many regards
academic researchers generally don't
care what they're allowed to do but uh I
think then once you start transitioning
something you end up going into some
sort of stealth mode where you don't
want to talk about it right so so there
there is a disclosure challenge there as
well I think where we don't when we
don't have any issues with
like with these technologies everything
I said up here is all public source
information right there are things I
can't talk about obviously in this
audience but that's all public source
information and I'm willing to you know
I want to do it because i think that
there's a lot going on that we should be
talking about and i'm just trying to put
some more focus on having people talk
about that side of how they're trying to
fix that technology research side
uh I you know it's from my background I
talk about the gap areas when I'm with
my folks we talked about it we did I
generally become the voice I've become
the voice for the user the voice for the
human but funny enough our lab at the
moment is co-located with our human
factors folks in at Draper so we sew and
I kind of take it in a different
direction I've been working with human
factors folks on identifying a new
solution space where we can combine
security and the human factor stuff in
order to do some really interesting
things around I don't want to say too
much around how we can model attacks and
how attacks work right and so I think
there are probably two sides of it
there's the how do we leverage that
information to understand how users are
using the tools that are available to
them and I think we need to do more of
that from a practitioner perspective
then there's the research perspective
how can we leverage the research that
how they how the research they've
already done in behavior analysis and
usage analysis and all that stuff how
can we leverage that to understand
better how systems work for the user and
and how systems work for the attackers
and so I I there there are some really
we've been tossing around some really
interesting ideas and we've been
pitching some of them the dart bone
where we're we're hitting a little bit
of success a little bit of failure and
so I think I always say messaging
usually when i get them when i fail at
doing something it's because i didn't
communicate it well enough and so we're
working on our messaging right now to
help at least communicate our ideas
better thank you thank you everyone
you