all right we got Dave Comstock here with
us Dave currently is with tripwire and
if when you if you want I think it's
very very entertaining
go read Dave's file and put down
particular what I like is he actually he
actually mentions the fact he's going to
admit to it that he had an IBM XT that's
kind of what going back there
but what I really liked about it was he
actually he actually talked about
abusing his equipment now this is the
same guy who's going to talk to us right
now about social engineering right okay
so I think I think he's speaking from
experience that right all right here
Dave all yours okay all right so so
thanks for coming um today we're going
to talk about social engineering let's
just take a real quick mint thanks at
that or this great event so far but that
a lot of good talks up block leaking
villages cool I'm not gonna you guys
went to that you can find me on the
steno deco-style and that's leet speak
so to zero I also on Twitter and
Mastodon the same exact thing so this
presentation is going to be I did a lot
of studying of recent interesting
attacks that I'd seen in social
engineering going from the DEF CON you
know social engineering capture the
flags and general clothes from popular
media Twitter post stuff like that and I
wanted to find a framework for social
engineering because I'm gonna I liked
framework Smith it's just one of those
things that they're nice you know they
help you streamline things and social
anomie --rings very relative it's very
it's very hard to plan it it's not you
can't just have like a set in stone way
of doing things so you know another good
thing about it is I don't like going
microwavable food instruction guides you
know there's not like a oh dude this
abuse this bias and all of a sudden
you'll be under the most bad guy on the
planet
not really so script all the things
right and I tried coming up with this
little acronym for it and everyone will
action in acronyms so we're going to
streamline fishing fishing and physical
gave me physical access personal PvP and
then we're going to do it by tech I see
now the clowns no clown hate here okay
so set up pvp by tagging ivy what the
heck is I see that's bottom plate and
these are the three general areas that
I've found that most social engineers
attacks that seem to be effective take
advantage of so it's personally like
sanity and the identity come down to you
want to assume their role as much as
possible so if you're going to pretend
to be you know a construction worker
you're going to have one clothes
you're not going to have the new clothes
obviously you're going to have no tools
you're gonna have certain tool you're
gonna have calloused hands maybe there's
gonna be all kinds of weird little
details you need to pay attention to
you're going to have certain logos and
insignia so if you work for a circle
company you're going to have a certain
logo on your back on your jacket
stuff like that method acting this is a
famous klasky he was a he was an active
back in the day and he made this was
custom thing and he said you know one of
the best things to do is just people
watch so you just go out watch people
patron some details of the situation and
you can kind of use that to build your
character so culture jargon standard
operating procedure if you're going to
be trying to fish someone you're going
to want to focus on call Hamiltons if
you're going to be trying to trick a
tech-support
baiting they're going to have Reedus
batteries so Dell for instance I I work
with though a lot and one of the ways
I've gotten their customer service reps
to stop giving me crap and I want
something done as I say I've done all of
this I give them all the information
they asked I said all the revisions or
you know the newest all the firmwares
are great blah blah blah because one of
the new things they have isn't already
are read this stature eight and if they
had to send a check out a second time
the person on the phone gets a negative
mark for that so of course that's going
to be one of the main things and then
again psychology cognitive biases and
just out of curiosity how many of you
guys like mr. Rogers a couple of you
okay have you ever seen this Pope I
always look through the helpers okay
well that's a great quote but not quite
for the reason you might first expect
and I really like the Satanic mr. Rogers
in the corner those were pretty pretty
prime so and you know even Charles
finishing here he says you know
my DMX four friend he says people are
primed to help we want to help not even
corporate corporate policy sometimes
it's driven into them from almost every
angle so the most and there was actually
a cool article I'm going to bring it up
a little later but the title of it was a
hackers best friend is a helpful
employee and that's almost always true
so we're gonna start real simple here
and this is a popular social media post
from a little while back just back in
December and it deals with wearing a
high visiting to just three events
concerts you know backstage that's like
that something intense but you know what
it really relies on is two things
there's a psychologist called Ralph
Linton and he has different steps
scribed versus achieved so ascribe
status says well I'm sitting here with
my cute little speaker behead and that
makes me speak that makes me an expert
of some kind I submitted to the CFP I
got accepted obviously I had an idea
what I'm talking about right now but
that's the ascribes dance now the
achieve status is what I achieved if
after you sit here listen to my talk
okay that kid Sally what he knows what
he's talking about maybe I'll do that
and I also uses authority bias and this
is pretty common you guys probably
already know it and what happens is you
automatically trust a respect authority
figures so if you're going to a concert
event you see a guy wearing a security
vest you instantly think that guy
security you're not really going to
think well let's check let's make sure
let's call his manager right not gonna
happen and this one was a presentation
by a so close employee from ipx4 2016
and basically what he did was he took a
letter around
he took a ladder tried to look like a
maintenance worker and they've got led
him to so many places he was all a
surprised and again this is a really
really simple example so imagine having
a little bit more complexity to that
situation and you're going to get into a
lot more places so now again back when I
started here I like the frameworks I
like the framers because they're modular
they're not microwave food sets right so
how many guys apply Legos mmm good Mady
so I came up with this TNT and so
African goes PvP by attacking ICP with
Chanti okay and the TMT I cheated a
little bit and instead of an a types and
tactics right so I'm not going to read
the slides onto you but there's five
general types I came across and the
first one I support staff this one's
pretty broad there's gonna be IT
painters construction workers cleaning
staff you know any kind of support work
at all and then there's four different
sort of sub groups that could fall under
support but they're really their own
kind of thing and then I also want to go
over a couple of different tactics so
abusing self-interest using tools
paperwork things like that using Osen
open source information cliches and
banner to kind of guide the conversation
and maybe misdirecting with they're not
trusting you things like that and
abusing cognitive biases that so the
first part is abusing self interest and
as you can see from Dale Carnegie up
there he says you can make a lot more
friends by being interested in others
and trying to get them interested in you
so it's just one of those things where
it's a pretty universal thing
and there's a quote from a book called
like what we got where it says welcome
like obiga where all the women are
strong all the men are good-looking and
all the children are above average
that kind of describe is how most people
view themselves you're never the outlier
you're never the below average
right you're always at least a little
bit about so tools on paper work and
this is going to be you know you can do
Osen obviously but if you see the badge
there you go on LinkedIn there's a lion
piglet LinkedIn open networking and
people will literally just follow you
back so openly let you to the network
they don't care and then people will
post employee badges on I'll say oh I
finally got my dream job I'm so happy
and it's like a picture of their
employee badge okay that probably
shouldn't be on the internet guys I just
want to say so again tools and you know
they should show wear and tear again and
again the general idea is that you want
to disarm people you want to get
something looking at you and saying that
guy looks like a carpenter he doesn't
look like an IT guy right good that's
how you're going for one of the things
you want to do when you're picking an
identity is you want to pick an identity
that will allow you potentially can show
your near better
so one of the way to do that would be
googling and you can just google for a
company find their logo and call up a
print job get the discards get shirts
just say you're with the company how
many of those places are actually going
to call the company and verify you work
there probably not many if they ask just
say oh well I'm just emailing you from a
personal account because my curtain one
got hacked you know how that feels right
most people will pride you but that
makes sense so construction workers here
you can see they're dirty they are
literally knee-deep in concrete they're
obviously going to have tools the tools
are all gonna be worn blah blah blah
blah and this was an outfit I use and
one of my favorites is IT gut because
I'm an idea so it's very easy for me and
this again when dovo share another
laptop Kali Linux USB and general
business casual Club now these are
pretty cool if you haven't been around
Twitter too much twitter is pretty cool
and this left image here is some guy who
literally turns his dog into a walking
Wi-Fi pineapple I mean clearly talk
about disguising your tools right kay
turning your dog into a walking attack
vector that's pretty cool
there was a similar wheel attached to I
forget the exactly well I think it was
for Wi-Fi networks yeah yep and if you
look on the right there jekhide and
tinker have this thing called hacker
adventures on twitter and it's really
cool if you don't follow them go check
it out but you know you can see there
she has cameras hidden in the sides her
glasses hey do I look truck ready yeah I
mean they look a little thick with the
style thing you know whatever and then
again now we can see here on the left
here some guy took a Raspberry Pi
running Kali Linux and shove it into a
power adapter so he can take this with
them make it look like the power adapter
to his computer use it to hook into
another computer or a network or
whatever and Vaughn Kelly on the right
side if you guys follow mugak he's a
really cool guy couple of people have
mentioned today actually and my company
actually does this everyone so why we do
this for like uh like menu boards and
signings
but stuff like that but really computers
are getting so small now you can stick
them in a back of a TV if you can get
physical access and how even anywhere
just to the cafeteria the cafeteria is
slight publicly open you know literally
3-d dongle kali linux plug it into a TV
there you go so open source information
again the general idea is you want to
look for the corporate information so
you want to look at the culture you want
to look at the structure this is where
the ocean comes into play you might want
to look at the corporate blog my one
check out glass or calm but last door
you're going to take a look grain of
salt because you know when you go to
glass door and you just came away from a
bad company what are you going to write
about them not positive things if you
feel slighted by your prior company what
are you going to write it up not
positive things so not only 100% true
try to correlate it try to build some
baselines figure it out that way and
then the second part their VIP
information again check out the
corporate Facebook check out the blog
check out their social media profiles
the guys might say out going on vacation
in two weeks okay cool well between
night and Glassdoor I just figured out
that you're a bit impatient so when I go
in there I'm gonna say oh hi I'm Dave
the IT guy I'm here to change the you
know Jack out in the wall because it's
in isn't working well you know how he is
you know how he gets very impatient he's
out of the office it's a good time to do
it you know you don't want to call him
in the middle of his vacation had to
bother him etcetera so he's massaging
these things in and then all of a sudden
you build it up and they just kind of go
with a little bit and industry forms
subreddits things like that you can just
do general information gather and get
the jargon so for instance um I did a I
did a little experiment where I went out
to an airport and I was a pilot and one
of the things or pilots is squawking
it's a way of transmitting certain
things that are happening so for
instance here's a whistle blow squats
and if you're going to be a North
American squawk in the bottom there you
can see 1,200 is the standard VFR flight
clip like pleco so if you're a pilot in
anywhere in North America Canada Mexico
where then we go to use all the time
you're gonna have to know that if you
don't know that you're going to be shown
as a fake
so cliches and banter and again this is
the idea is to drive the conversation
away from the things that they might not
necessarily trust about you and push it
off onto Dale
so banner stories excuses misdirection
focus these and make them all about
let's say oh I got a new employee by
scheduler he's not he doesn't he might
not work out you know if you if you go
to the place to play oh you're not
actually scheduled to be coming in for
you know repairing the steps today just
like oh did he not call you that's the
third time this week and then you can
say you know he's a new guy I feel like
he's going to work out but he just need
to step it up and a lot of people will
just come back with you and try to
relate to you and tell you their own
story and say oh I know exactly how that
is I have this one guy I swear I wish I
could fire but I just can't and they'll
just kind of keep going with that and
you can just keep rolling with it and
move it up from there so different
frames to use again corporate policy
sometimes corporate policy is just silly
and you can say well no that's the
policy I don't like it I don't
understand it but at the way that social
norms being a new parent being the fan
of a disappointing sports team right
those things can all help explain away
the things that might not necessarily be
going my way again
overbearing boss porco work or just
being simply too busy you know I'll I
meant to call you but yesterday was just
so awful tell them this you know real
nice short story about some client you
had there was you know really bad view
stuff like that build empathy you know
stuff like that so cognitive biases this
is going to be cool because the idea
here is that you want to take these
biases and you want to chain them
together so the first one there but
we're first we're going to talk about
actually is anchoring and this is that
people usually tend to rely too heavily
on the very first piece of information
they get about so your very first piece
of amazing information is likely your
how you look right I mean that's the
assuming the identity portion right
that's the picking the tools
the making sure your tools are worn
that's the making sure your shoes are
bent they're dirty they have paint
splatters on it's definitely that so you
start off there and then from there you
say okay well I'm from X company here
for y problem at the request of this
person and you can use real people from
your open source information right you
can say okay well this boss probably to
come in I'm from this company I had the
logo on my shirt it's not a real shirt I
print a fake employee badge you don't
know what the heck that badge looks like
right right in next one the kind of talk
about here is ambiguity and so you want
to avoid this one by giving me too much
information
so ambiguity up there if you look at it
says you want to avoid options we're
missing info makes changes unknown so if
you don't know much about me you don't
really have a good baseline of me and
that was actually one of the things I
really liked about the conference so far
Dave Kennedy mentioned it yo yo I think
mentioned it first vet until 1:00 and it
said that you know the basic idea is to
take baselines and that's really you
know even just general defense in your
network find what your networks usually
does find the outlier and then that's
the ideal find baselines so by giving
them just stupid information again just
the banter the social norm is just
stupid stuff oh my boss is an idiot
giving them that little bit of
information tends to help them think
okay well now I know him now I have a
baseline plan right it's not just some
random person who I'd says alway he
works in this company he sounds like an
IT guy he looks like an Ikea he's really
going through it and Arthur Aron is a
psychologist and he mentioned this study
he had where he said that mutual
vulnerability Foster's closeness and
really what it talks about is it really
just a Scott describes the natural
process for friendship you know once I
open up to you you open up to me and
then we kind of snowball that and as it
gets heavier you know a bigger snowball
you Eve eventually will have a really
think you'll have a really aggressive
Who I am right and again that's the
baseline so after that you want to chain
this into the authority and the scribes
dead stuff right
so if all of a sudden you're showing up
you're talking to them you're you know
doing banter and if you've listened to
some of the the social engineering CTS
banter and small talk is huge I mean
that's that's really where they spend
probably what 40% of the conversation
it's in between parts of the face the
fillings it's a void in the ambiguity
the next part is the zero risk one and
this one is it can be used to get you
out of a situation so let's say oh geez
wrong time so let's say that you're
going in to this place and the very
first thing you get in there you realize
that you don't have an ID and the
security guard checks IDs well you can
say hey look yeah I have a young son at
home he wanted to see what I looked like
so he was playing with it he lost it I
haven't found it yet it just happened
this morning here's my employee badge
fake her real who knows is that good
enough and for a lot of people that
might that could get you in pretty
easily and again it's that zero risk it
actually uses that that bias and it says
they prefer small risks over a larger
risk of a larger reduction so you want
to make it seem there's a problem
there's another thing called the hairy
arm technique or talking to the rubber
duck where you say you know there was a
photographer configured out that when
you put a certain frame in a photo of
like a little bit of his hairy arm very
picky clients would say hey get rid of
that and then it's good there were
certain client fee had that always had
to find something wrong so by giving
them just a little bit of something at
the beginning it automatically focuses
on them the one that it's almost like
shortly in a sense you know they'll go
okay sure that doesn't look right let's
investigate that oh okay then you
already had this plan in place to be
able to say oh well no look I'm dressed
like it oh yeah I don't have my my real
legal ID but here's my badge here's my
business card
go to my website create a fake website
you know stuff like that
so just to go over a couple of these
these two pictures here I'm in the
computer man if you google computer man
you'll find these two videos the left
one here is just a small business guy
and they're all going through dancing it
was really cool and the right one you
can see the cool Tron graphics there
right
so these Tron graphics this is from some
80s children's Canadian show or
something the guy doesn't like tight
robot moves to check them out what's up
that exactly and so again going back to
Def Con Chris Silver's from Def Con 24
he used this idea where he said okay I'm
going to send someone a gift card for a
very real thing that their company did
he found through up through ocean that
they were doing this gift card thing and
he said okay I'm going to cinema link
the link isn't going to work and then
when the wing link doesn't work I'm
going to offer to remote in and help
assist assist that person right and
again appealing their interest abusing
self-interest hey you want to gift art
who doesn't want a free gift r3 mine
even if you don't want to spend it at
that place you can you know hock it for
everything you did he's in price made so
you know and then hmm go to the next one
so auditors and new employees there was
a Def Con 20 CTF and the guy's name was
chain and what he did was he pretended
to be a government contractor a new
government contractor for Walmart and
he's working on this big project it was
super-secret and he called it a target
in front of everyone at Def Con
obviously and said you know hey um I'm
here I'm gonna you know we're profiling
your store you want to just get some
information about it to see if you'd be
possible for you to go in this program
with us and you know you'd be like the
flagship store you'd be like a guinea
pig in a sense and gets people excited
obviously you know so they're gonna say
you know okay and he ended up going
through and talking to them and just
going through the general banter with
them and the end up getting all the
flags at once he got their suppliers you
got their vendors you got you know the
information about their their computer
systems yeah all kinds of stupid stuff
out of it just from pretending that he
was some auditing
and again you know you can say you can
do some old sign you can say okay well
I'm calling you on behalf of this real
manager from your company who is a very
big deal and I'm also from a reputable
auditing company so that way you might
not be obviously but if you build that
up you can say oh hey no no really I am
and that's basically what he did and
again tinker the hacker adventures there
was another one where he did an internal
audit and companies will oftentimes have
surprised off especially in the food
industry sometimes health they're not
usually surprising helped them whatever
so he said you know he showed up out of
the blue randomly just knowing the
company name just knowing the boss man
and said okay hi I'm here to do a
surprise about it
show me around and managers all right
just like that went along with now
vendor reps I don't know why anyone
would want to be one little loan to
pretend to be one but it's definitely
some way that you could get in so if you
think about what a vendor rep does they
bring free stuff the free stuff always
has the complete logo on it so if you're
looking for the company logo look up
like EPS files vector files things like
that and then take them to a local print
shop a buddy or you know whatever how
are you going to do it and print out
stuff with that if you're not using
buzzwords then you don't sound like a
vendor rep no symmetry no synergy no
horizontal or vertical integration next
gen AI or cloud right I mean you guys
got a third yeah put those in there if
you're going to pretending to be a
vendor it and so it looks like we're
just about out of time you question
conference
you