welcome to the afternoon of b-sides
quick programming note we're 230 here
right after the talks will be having a
networking event in case you didn't see
it at John Harvard's brew house so it's
pretty much just across Harvard down to
Harvard Square about a five minute walk
which is beautiful up
so hopefully you all can make it yeah
Johnson Street there you go and so
without further adieu we'll get started
here
with Pedro and Vic giving us a great
talk about security in many sizes as one
size does not sell it fit all so let's
give a warm welcome to Pedro today
thanks Josh so as you noticed if you've
never been to B sides before every tone
is a little bit light my name is Pedro
this is Vic we're known as Pedro and Vic
nothing special about that
so the talk today it's funny because you
get on these on the mood of doing the
talk and you hear what you want to talk
about in other people's talk especially
this late in the day it's that there's a
lot of talk about how to do security for
$0 small businesses all the things that
they should do so we're going to talk
about how to do security for small
businesses medium businesses large
businesses but we're gonna put a twist
to that we're going to compare that to
kind of people in fashion alright so
some people have come up to me today and
say hey you got a shirt with ninjas on
well this is Deadpool and other people
for some reason can only see the yellow
spots
those are tacos and then in between we
have swords so my fashion sense is just
not the best but I'm ok I'm ok with that
I'm ok so I'm talking about fashion I
just want to talk about people that go
into stores right there is a
particularly large large stores there's
a lot of mirrors around so you see
people walking through and thirsty on
the wrists of mirrors they just walk
through thanks oh yeah
do I look fat in this
hey of course you do but you're as well
some people some people are very
realistic about what they look like and
then you know there is some of us that
just walk into the store just go this
shirt looks good on me it's like I'm all
pumped up right so what does that have
to do with security better oh Allah
there's a lot of people that are looking
at their security programs and they're
just you know they're very happy they
feel protected they feel nurtured for
some reason and they're happy with with
with the state of security and then you
have consultants come in and say your
baby's ugly you got to throw it up there
is in usually the those are the ones
that are most comfortable with their
security programs right it's like we're
doing everything we have all the
products we have all the labels we got
the gardener's we got the other analysts
and the old come in and the blister
program
well you're less than covered right the
the emperor has no clothes and to stick
with their fashion sense today for those
of you that are here because they saw my
previous talk and some months ago and
you got salsa lessons for free big is
going to be doing most of their talking
and none of the dancing so sorry to
disappoint you you're gonna have to come
to another talk at some other point in
time but with that I'll leave you a big
thank you better so we're going to talk
about small medium large and extra-large
the topic of the talk I'm Vic Solem the
MEI security we do physical and digital
security consulting so as part of every
talk I have to start by saying I'm not
kidding there's an emergency exit here
there's another money exit out the door
to the right and turn right there's a
fire line pull up there asmath our
extinguisher here because we're the
paranoid ones who really take this stuff
seriously it's how we live and work it's
not a lot of fun sometimes
but today we're going to talk about
sizing so forgive me I'm going to try
not to stretch the analogy a little in
some ways we're going to be talking
about acting as a security tailor
getting your program to fit just right
we are going to focus on small and
medium businesses later on but for right
now we're going to talk about small
medium large and extra-large we'll say
what that means in a little bit going to
cover a little bit about points of view
on security and that has to do with what
you're wearing and what you're buying
and why and we're going to talk a little
bit about specifics on what a small
business can do we do cover zero dollar
budget because some of some folks are in
that boat sometimes we talk to you just
don't have budget for security but they
know they need to do something and there
are things that you can do and if you
have budget you may be using some
freeware tools and that's really okay
the other thing I want to say is that
when we talk about security we want to
be sure that we get the size right and
to pay those point when we're going
shopping I may want to be a large but
I'm an extra-large that's the way it is
I haven't beaten this back yet it's
still here I can't put on a large shirt
it's just not going to work right but
for security you've got to get the size
exactly right for instance I'm going
into a hazardous environment I'm gonna
want to look at the chart and I'm gonna
want to know that not only am I not an
extra-large I'm a double extra-large and
if I'm going to put on a hazmat suit I
better get the right thing that doesn't
matter how much I like something at the
store if I need it to fit right if it
absolutely has to fit right like
insecurity you've got to get the size
right and if you think your environment
is a certain size you better be sure
your environment is a certain size be
sure you know your environment we'll
talk about that a lot here and by our
environments come in all shapes and
sizes and people's companies and teddy
bears come in all sizes
I have the cool slides that Jack has I
wish I had talked before Jack you got to
deal with what you got well we'll move
forward so you talk a little lot sizing
when you're buying off the rack you're
getting whatever is happens to be there
and you may be customizing it on your
own right if you're super expensive on
the big end of the scale the vendors are
coming to you and customizing everything
you want so there's sort of the analogy
between I'm small and I can't afford to
tell or I say what they're going to do
or I'm big and I'm going to tell them
this is what you're going to deliver and
you've got to keep this in mind when you
think about what products you're looking
at and what companies are dealing with a
big company is less likely to be
customizable for you than a small one it
also depends a lot on your environment
right what are you wearing you're
wearing Vera Wang or Eddie Bauer you're
making your own clothes are you a
barracuda shop that's your way of doing
things are you a Cisco shop that's it
right that's how you work do you build
fires out of OpenBSD by hand the way God
intended all right I mean whatever
whatever your culture is you've got to
know that you have to fit your security
solutions to that and each of them has
merit but you got to be sure that you
know what your environment is what size
you are so when you're going shopping
you know what you're looking for sorry
my screen didn't scroll correctly so
presentation there a couple of images I
don't have a clue one's jack head I do
have some and I will tell you if you go
looking on the web for images having to
do with size medium large and
extra-large
please turn safesearch on for your own
protection I'm not going to share the
details of everything that I saw when I
was looking at this but my ISP has that
and if you want you can contact them
gonna be happy to sell it to you I'm
sure no problem
it's about being prepared knowing your
environment knowing where you're going
right if you're walking into a boardroom
at a traditional company you've got to
dress the part which like it looked that
good you've got a dressed apart and your
security systems have to fit you the
same way they have to fit you well so
that whatever you're preparing them for
whatever day you're going to have your
systems are ready for it so we're gonna
talk about points of view so we're going
to cover four points of view we're going
to cover in the trenches when you're
working when you're actually using the
clothes you're going to cover shopping
when you're buying clothes or buying the
security systems and a little bit from
the other side with the attacker seized
and why you want them to see a certain
thing or not a little bit about style
and frameworks so from the trenches I
couldn't I couldn't not show those
pictures from the trenches you got to
know which trenches you're talking about
going into right for fashion are you in
World War one
are you walking into the hazmat
environment I mentioned before are you
going after neo in the matrix you have
to know ahead of time what exactly
you're you're trying to do with your
security program you have to be prepared
getting the right size at least as
important is knowing what you where
you're going and what you need to wear
for that and I talked about the
boardroom before and one of the things
to remember is that even if you think
you know what a boardroom should look
like like if I get the chance to get
that pitch to that company in Manila
because I want to go back and live with
some family there and then switch it
back and forth between totnes oh that
would be really cool
I'm going to know that in Manila you
wear belong to dialogue on a boardroom
so it's not as simple as I know what I
have to wear for this situation you have
to be sure you know everything about the
situation what's really about what's
what's your environment what's your
company what your company needs for
security what's what what are the
different environments will your company
needs to function well are you taking
your security program and applying it to
an environment that has a different
culture and has to have a different
style for your security program now if
you have a program it's working really
great in Cambridge or Boston and you all
of a sudden acquire 50 developers
sitting in India you better make sure
that your security program is going to
match the culture the different
environments a lot of other problems in
there as well so what do you want to
wear today depends a lot on where you're
going
boardroom you're racking servers from
racking servers I do actually tuck the
tie in though I don't I still keep the
tie on but I tuck it in it's like what
what do you do
what's your security program have to
react to what's happening today right if
you're here sitting at B sides you're
not patching your Microsoft machines
this weekend right as an example are you
still running the broken Adobe that we
heard about recently what's what's
happening today and what tools you need
to handle that and if you're working in
a small start-up and you've got 20
people in a room and that's your cubicle
farm then patching that there's a
completely different task than if you've
got 200 people spread across different
cities in in the country or if you've
got 2,000 people on different continents
right these are different security
programs completely different orders of
magnitude right in a small shop you can
stand up and say hey our IT guys coming
today is going to patch everything so
everybody just go away from 11:00 to
12:00 and you know it's done right
doesn't work when you've got multiple
cities or multiple continents so you got
to be sure
that the tools that you're using right
for your environment and right for where
your environment is going to go let's
talk a little bit about shopping as I
said I'm I'm a well okay I'll say I'm a
large but I'm going to be an extra-large
although I wish you were going the other
way not many companies are going to tell
you we're really large and we want to
get smaller but that's not what
companies want to do you want to grow so
when you're buying a security solution
you want to buy a little bit extra to be
able to fit where you think you're going
to be in six months down the road too
small is really hard to fix too large
can usually be tucked in sorry
the other point I want to make here is
about how long you're going to own stuff
I don't like to dryclean stuff it's not
that I don't like that particular fabric
it's that I don't want to pay for
dry-cleaning every time I spill
something on my shirt or my jacket it's
just ridiculous because I spill coffee
it happens these things happen
that means general upkeep and dry clean
suit is going to be a lot more than not
if you're talking to a vendor or looking
at a solution and they're telling you
this is great you're going to love it
it's just awesome you want to talk to
people who are using because if you find
out oh by the way this great tool
ArcSight requires an entire FTE just to
keep it running you might want to say
hold on a second I don't have a
full-time person for that or you may be
a great University and say we got three
people we'll throw it that that's great
but you got to be sure that whatever
you're doing fits your environment will
it last for your environment is it is it
the right size for where you want to be
in six months
you don't want to get too big obviously
to want to spend the budget it can also
look a little silly and and the thing
I've been harping on all this time is
one size doesn't fit all in security
there are places
where you just want to be a Cisco shop
and they're places where really you want
to do stuff by hand because you're super
paranoid or whatever each environment is
different in each has its merits but you
want to keep in mind that you're what
you're looking at for your security
solution may not be what the vendor had
mind when they told their marketing
person to give you a call on the phone
and tell you how awesome their tool is
you're the one who's to be on the hook
for making it work the way it's supposed
to not the vendor so the point of view
of an attacker I'm short on time preview
an attacker I'm not talking specific
about a physical attack against clothing
so but that's a physical tax or
different class or not covering that
here but if you think of attacks against
clothing as what is it clothing trying
to defend against your clothing is
trying to keep you warm your clothing is
trying to protect you from the elements
give you a place to put your valuable
stuff and to make you convey the image
that you want to convey right this is
this is how big looks this is just it
this is the image I convey if I'm
walking into a computer room this may
not convey the image that I want to talk
to people who sit at a keyboard all day
because I may look like a sales guy so
you want to be sure that your clothing
convey the image you want and you want
your we're stretching it a little bit
here you want your security tools to
convey the right image to your employees
about the culture of your company as
well as to your potential investors
people who may want to spend money on
your company going to be sure that that
you're conveying the right image for
everyone who's going to be looking at
your security program a lot of the time
its customers we've had a lot of people
who are contacting customers of ours
saying here here's a 10 page
questionnaire or a twenty page query I
see the head nodding tell us a bunch of
security program and you better believe
that there are questions on page two
that are double-checking answers you
give on page nine because they want to
be sure that you're not lying about it
and then you hand that off and you think
you're done and then they send you back
hey you said that you do antivirus it
using this concept and that you keep
your logs show us the logs they want
evidence they want you to tell the truth
and they're going to make you prove it
it's like they really care about
security or something
yeah I don't have a good answer for that
I'm stretching the analogy a little bit
here sometimes you actually want to tell
the attacker things that are not true
you want to change honey pots or you
want to change the banners that you're
advertising on us is a demon or on your
HTTP demon to say a version that they're
not and then watch for the faulty
attacks come in which is kind of fun in
a weird sort of way
but I don't have a way to say that you
don't want you know I'll use it again
arcsight instead of what alienvault
cubed ro sim right I don't have a way to
say that you don't want that so the
attacker to see that it breaks down a
little bit here I'm ripping the analogy
if you'll permit me link but the some of
the things apply you are you are using
your security program to protect you
from adverse outcomes bad whether you
are using it to protect your stuff your
valuables but you're right the analogy
doesn't doesn't hold all the way here
you got me but my next slide is so cool
okay though
no that's okay
the norm in the industries to hide as
much as you can but it kills some tools
are required to put out certain
information here's some things you can't
hide but really eventually on the body
that you're actually projecting some of
it's not necessarily to the attacker
it's to the other folks in your
organization it's making it fit you
organization so for instance if you're a
small one location shop and you're doing
a big giant implementation of I started
so I'll keep going the park site right
that's insane for a tiny little shop
right are sites for like you know thirty
thousand computers right so what you
don't want to secure a program that's
too big for you this is the segue to my
next picture you don't want it too big
for you because then if it's too big you
it'll may protect you in some areas but
you spent money so you don't have
protection in other places and it's hard
to move quickly there we go
so so the the big giant program the big
giant tool can be hard to be agile with
right you're right it's not necessarily
in point of view of the attacker that I
don't want them to think that I'm
running where were alienvault for my sim
but from the point of view of being able
to move around in my organization and
make a difference quickly I don't want
something that's too big because you
couldn't move quickly although they look
pretty happy but move on to the point of
view of style of frameworks and I'm
stretching the analogy again but I'm
saying that a security framework
whatever you're using for organizing
your security program is similar to
your style of your fashion so this is if
I said this is this is how big dresses
this is it
when I'm going to shop I'm not shopping
when Hitler would shop because it looks
cooler than I do I couldn't pull off the
shirt like that this is what I got now
we talked about that that's because I'm
an extra large so the you want to be
sure that your style is fitting your
organization there are there are people
I haven't seen people in particular I'm
thinking about at this conference but
the people who will tell you that you
can't use NIST to develop your security
framework it's not big enough it's not
good enough this won't work and heavens
bid you talk about using the CIA's top
20 because that's just tiny and yet from
talking to a company that has 30 people
that's the whole company and I start
talking about the CIA's top 20 right
they could stay just hand of a top to
write inventory of the devices in your
environment just give me an inventory of
the devices simple everybody knows you
can start with that inventory the
software but they don't have to go even
down to the bottom 20 and they've
already made a huge difference in their
environment right on the other hand if
you're you know GE if you better be
using ISO right you need a real program
that handles it enterprise-wide so
figure out what's appropriate for your
environment and be sure that you're
acting appropriately that you have the
right style for what you want to do so
pulling at you a little bit hard here
but I think you see what I'm getting at
is want to pick the right framework if
you're in the government supply chain we
have customers that manufactured pivot
if you're making chips that go into
circuit boards that go into modules that
go into jet fighters for the military
you're in the government supply chain
and you better be looking at this 171
even if you're only a 20% shop because
you're going to get the questionnaires
from the Raytheon's or though all the
way down all the way down to you to say
tell me about your security program or I
can't buy from you the SEM
20:17 and so you have to figure out
what's right for your environment for
the size of your company based on what
you've got going on in addition to your
to your size and you want to be sure
that that what you fit what you get
doesn't have any unintended consequences
because the vendor may tell you this
looks really great on you really really
though this this appliance will look
really grating it server accent too
pretty color it has blinking lights but
when you put it in and it starts running
is it not right for you is it going to
get caught in that will tell me that's
not going to get caught in that wheel
she's coming off the back of that and
and I want to talk about the guy with
the shredder Italian sorry stop touching
the day so be sure that whatever you're
looking at is right for what you plan to
do in the real world
not just what the vendor says or the
sales person who's trying to sell you
whatever the services happen to be so
now we're to the the part I promise
we're going to talk about medium to
small businesses I've separated them by
size extra small do it yourself
limited to no budget small medium large
extra large there are many different
ways to figure out what you think people
should be spending on IT security what
you think your your company should be
spending the best evidence from Gartner
has to do with industry because IT
spending is dependent on industry and IT
security spending is typically dependent
on that we're technical people here
right you know I had this spreadsheet
with all these dimensions and the
multiple values by industry and the
multiple values by different sizes of
security programming and yeah but it
doesn't work in a presentation so I took
the average of North America which is
three point five percent two point five
percent of revenue is your IT program
and ten percent of that variety security
and that's how these numbers came to be
these are rough numbers for comparison
only I'm not saying that if you have
twenty five million in revenue that you
have seven three hundred to spend I'm
saying
relative to the others they're useful
numbers
and I doubt the ones in gray at the top
I think a lot of small companies don't
even have that but this is the rough
sizing I'm talking about for comparison
and this is just the slide with
different small medium/large because it
had to go into presentation somewhere so
taking those same extra
small-extra-large
and start talking about what what people
can actually do so the dollars per month
is across the top the people that you
have is the second line that should be
less than one person not greater than
one person you if you're a small company
you've got you know 20 people you don't
have a whole person dedicated IP let
alone IT security if you're a small
company you've got an IT person probably
but that person is also going to be
doing IT security so you got part of a
person who's doing the car driven system
right who's doing patching for antivirus
who's doing awareness for security
that's all coming out of your IT person
when you get to be a medium-sized
company you got a whole person that one
FTE to do that security work which is
awesome
large gets a department next large gets
a big department they're not going to be
the focus for the rest of this they're
the other ones with lots of money and
would be nice to be there but a lot of
companies are not in that situation if
you're go ahead I'll get that but thank
you it's coming it's next so this line
is antivirus if you're running a BG and
you're a small company check the License
Agreement because I'm the only person in
the world who reads it and you can find
one that's free better if you don't use
one that might cause you a problem later
but you're doing something but you're
doing a free service if you're small
you've got commercial-off-the-shelf
you're buying semantics or Kaspersky or
McAfee or whatever if you're
medium-sized company you have a console
which is awesome you can track all of
your machines and all your antivirus
right
now it's a little bit we've all seen
this right consoles anyway you're
tracking all of your different machines
and making sure they're up-to-date
you're getting alerts but say hey this
machine has been on the network for a
week and it's antivirus without a date
if you're large you have consoles
because you've got consoles working with
each other you've got a Mac at the
console and you've got your cue radar
console and they've got all these
different consoles that are working
together because when you're meeting you
can only afford one seaboard antivirus
because that vendor got to you first
extra large covers and vulnerability
management programs which are really
cool
but they're out of reach for small to
medium sized companies it's not going to
happen if you're training let me
rephrase that
when you're training your employees
about information security because that
matters because people are the weakest
link right we're training people telling
them don't click on the link it should
be a chant at a small company you're
just talking to people being sure that
they just know right
that's an extra small that's small you
may be gathering together at lunch to
have a single conversation and covered
in a class where you stand there and you
say this is how you're not going to
click on the link the note that says
it's from the director of the FBI is not
to you really people medium you're doing
online online training is ok better if
you can hire a trainer to come in and do
the job right the larger an extra large
company taking people off site for
backups at a small company you've got a
USB Drive preferably not a little USB
stick a real USB Drive and you're taking
it with you home
and bringing it back and you get to be a
small company you've got two USB drives
at home and two USB drives at the office
and you back up to one and then you take
that one with you you still got one at
the office now you put that one here and
you take the other one from home and
bring it back you've always got backups
off-site and up-to-date geographic
distribution at least within wherever
your IT person lives so you can do a
real backup solution for a small company
without actually spending more than the
cost of a USB Drive
right these are the solutions part we
were talking about before
if you medium you do more either real
off-site you work with Iron Mountain
large and extra-large they have other
cool stuff that they're doing but you
get the point so the reason to believe
in all this about small and medium-sized
business is this so this a while ago in
it it made sense based on risk tolerance
for small companies but sixty percent
after they have a cyber attack gone in
six months so if you're talking with
small and medium sized business they've
got real risk now when you start a
company small you take on a lot of risk
right to go a bigger take a little less
risk because you've now got some more
money invested and things are working
well by the time you get to be a
medium-sized company you've got people
depending on you for payroll every day
you may have 3040 people who need that
payroll you can't be taking the same
risks you were taken back here right so
it's understandable that you take on
more risk but small companies should
know that they're taking on this risk
and not just bear the risk without
understanding it right
sixty percent out of business after a
cyber attack not prepared not ready to
handle the aftermath I don't have the
details on that obviously but so that's
a bad number what I'm talking about for
small business is time versus money when
you're running a small company you don't
have a lot of money if you do that would
be awesome and I want you to invest in
my small company but typically you don't
have a lot of money you just can't spend
the money you don't have it so you're
spending time as you grow that will
change and there's a theoretical
crossover point I don't have units on
here for a reason but the idea is you're
spending time to get things done so a
lot of small business security is about
time management if you say I'm going to
periodically check my whisp because I'm
a company in Massachusetts I know that I
have to have a written information
security program and that the law says I
have to check it every year with 1207
visa
every year right then you better put a
tickler on your schedule to say after
year I got a check-in as a security
person because if you're the security
person who's operating as I've been
there I handle whatever I can out of my
Inbox
I can't scroll to the bottom the next
day I handle what I can out of my inbox
and these messages are not getting seen
right there are some networks where if
you lose a packet it's no big deal
and some networks are if you lose a
packet the plane crashes if you're the
IT security and you've got a note in
there that says your website's been
hacked and you need to do something
about this now and you didn't see it
because it was below the fold or below
the scroll line on your email and your
company's in deep trouble so if you're
running an IT security program at a
small company you've got to be very sure
that you're careful with your time
management if you set these things up
and that you're watching all the
information is coming in to you which
can be really really difficult we sue
you budget time to view things
periodically we've been talking about
the typical vendor presentation I'm not
down on vendors I'm ok with vendors they
do good stuff but a lot of times their
slides look like this right if you're
extra small we can't help you if you're
small we can give you something but if
you spend a lot of money boy have we got
a long list for you right you've seen
these but for you this is the diagram if
you're a small company you can find
stuff just not with that vendor right
you can't afford the big giant gorgeous
console if you're at a tiny company so
don't talk to them unless they're going
to buy you lunch just go look for the
solution that fits what you need to do
you can do something no matter your size
so we're talking about these size
companies for now this time we have five
minutes
okay so again we're talking about extra
small companies that have almost no
budget too small to medium-sized
companies have real budget can have a
real person working there it's about
having your mindset that there are
solutions that I can use they have to
pick the right ones that don't break my
budget and don't take too much of my
time you've got to balance what you're
doing and what you're buying to be sure
that it's right for your company and
remember the big picture is your
security program not whether
thoroughness would be a really cool
solution because you can backtrack and
watch what happened on the file system
right that's awesome stuff but if you're
a small company I'm sorry it's not a
scope it's just it's not it's too
expensive it solves only one solution
and you're leaving yourself wide open in
other areas so if you're doing inventory
and you have some specific examples my
example before with the the 20 people in
a room small startup their cubicles 20
people in a room right you can do
inventory on a piece of paper really you
can it's not fun but you can you can
walk around with a black magic marker
and tack the Machine I wrote down the
serial number and go to the next one and
then the next month or the next year
when you have to the inventory again use
a different color magic marker and you
can do inventory for no budget you don't
have to listen to the vendor who wants
to sell you this awesome tool that will
go to automatically inventory your
machines of course if you graduate to
having more time than you can script it
which is even cooler of course a
medium-sized company will buy the tool
and they'll have it automated so that
we've been a real inventory that then
they can get a report item instead they
have to work with Excel or have somebody
else work with Excel because you can't
someone else on a company to do it for
you patching we already talked about
bring your own device
I've heard a lot of people say I'm in a
small company I can't help bring BYOD I
can't be done there's nothing I can do
and I argue that's not true if you want
to handle bring your own device and
you've got a company with almost no
budget you get a guest access point and
you take the password for that access
point because we secure all of our
access points right everybody secure all
of our access points none of them going
secure but take the password you put it
up on the wall I wouldn't write it on
this wall but you put it up on the wall
you put on the whiteboard you let people
know this is the pass for the guest
access point and you leave it alone and
you let it stay that way for a year or
two years however long you want it to go
then you change the password on your
internal access point and you only put
that on machines that you know our
company owned and then a month later you
change it again because somebody's going
to have caught it but you keep you
rotate that every once in a while and
all of a sudden you've got to bring your
own device policy because everyone who
brought in their iPhone or their iPad or
anything else they want to do the stream
their movies is now stuck on the guest
network because you keep changing the
flip and password they get tired of
coming and asking you about it bring
your own device free policy though you
had to buy an Access Point right like
that small company that's too small no
budget of course yes if you've got
budget and you can afford an AK go for
it they're awesome you can kick people
off automatically and there's a middle
ground with scripting where you're
watching your network and you're
watching the the MAC addresses go by and
you're filtering by vendor and your
chain you can you can script this and
you can hire somebody to script it but
it can be done on a sort of a middle
ground when you got more time but for a
quick simple solution just change the
access point and lock people out you'll
find out who's using it you'll see them
at their desk going why doesn't this
work so user education we talk about
antivirus we talked about you can use
komodo it's free free for commercial
entities you don't have to use AVG
got two more of these and then the
clothes so disk encryption yes you can
do disk encryption as a small company
what scares people out is what if they
change the passphrase on me so you have
a rescue phrase you when you when you do
it you use a product or a UNIX tool that
will let you save the underlying
passphrase the typically the way disk
encryption works is you've got an
encrypted disk and you're going to
algorithm from crippling the disk and
you've got a big long key and that's the
key for the desk then you have people
enter their own key and that encrypts
this special key so that's what gets
saved this hash in the middle and then
we get rid of the first two and this is
people have to match and anything that
it's used to generate this that it
decrypts the drive well you can save the
intermediary key when you're installing
it when you're setting it up any product
worth its salt for instance the free one
on linux will give you that key that you
can save you can write it down it's
really long you put it in a safe and if
somebody says haha
I changed the key and I'm leaving the
company you can't have that computer
sure you can you get the key in their
safe so disk encryption free it's a pain
writing stuff on paper and putting it in
a safe is a pain but it will work and if
you're free and all you've got is time
and no money you're small other there's
time enough money there's a solution
that'll work obviously be better to have
a console you can control it or at least
centrally managed for this encryption
that's better if you can afford it but
if you can't afford it and you need this
concretion because you happen to have
social security numbers or driver's
license numbers or credit card numbers
or anything that Massachusetts says is
PII or even the government supply chain
you have to enlist 171 then for crying
out loud you've got to encrypt there's
no we don't want to because we don't
because we can't afford it you've got
two brand alerts this is free for
everybody then you can hire a company to
watch the brand but
I've set these up for multiple customers
where I'm watching for their customer
name just the domain name also the
customer name on free sites like paste
bin right yeah uh-huh yep and you see
some interesting stuff go by and paste
bin but if you're watching for your
customers name there or that was me I'm
sorry if you're a company and you're
watching for your company name there
then you're going to see when someone is
saying hey look I broke into Acme
widgets look at the cool stuff I got or
I'm daxing the CEO isn't as cool and he
works at acne is your Google Alert which
you set up a free we'll kick that to you
right away
you can go get it off pay spam and tell
people to don't click the link in the
email obviously you can do more stuff we
hire companies to monitor your brand and
so forth but but this is free right we
talked about backups DNS web proxy yes
yeah
yep exactly and and and what you're
doing is you're you're looking at what
would an attacker be doing the opponent
pastebin their Pirate Bay and and you're
watching for their activity and you're
doing it for free it's a great example
because in if you're running a software
company you know what you could be
looking for to catch your stuff as it
went out not just your company name
obviously well yeah in my province
that's a that's an attacker they're
inside they've got access but that's an
attacker yeah no you're right you're
looking for you're looking for bad
actors doing stuff and and these ones
happen to be inside you're right but
yeah that's that's a great example we
talk about backups DNS web proxy yeah
good that's like um snack overflow I'm
sure your developers would never do this
but pasting code from your company
asking questions right so you know
periodically checking that seeing if you
know your company comm shows up on Stack
Overflow is a is a good way to see if
you know you have a overanxious
developer that may be leaking some your
source code yeah leaking it yeah oh yeah
I totally buy into it yeah yeah yeah
well cleansing that stuff can be hard I
was in a hurry yeah you can look for
your IP addresses in there as well so
yeah DNS web proxy sometimes people at a
company want to go places on the
internet that would be inappropriate for
work sometimes this happens sometimes
the places that they're going to want to
download malware onto their computer and
having set up alerts in systems like
your radar to say hey look this
she went out then after going out to
this place we don't like then it started
attacking her the machine on the network
so this really does happen web proxies
are great if you can afford a web proxy
to lock things down to just the sites
you want that's awesome but if you can't
you can control the DNS on your network
now you're not going to stop someone who
works in this room who knows that they
can go there have their own DNS or they
can tunnel their DNA you're not going to
stop security people right but you're
going to stop the regular person sitting
at their desk who happens to click on
links hey take a look at this right
you're going to stop them because the
site doesn't resolve now Open DNS had a
solution this is it's still free I think
Open DNS isn't francisco has a free one
ok so the there are three solutions
Cisco my mic sorry yeah it still use it
at my house I yeah they have them shut
me off yet but well yeah so you're not
again it's not a perfect security
solution you're not actually blocking
people from going there if they get the
IP address but you're stopping 90% of
people who would go there because they
can't get the IP address they know the
name of the site which I'm not going to
say that they want to go to and then
stop because they can't they can't
resolve it free solution right it's not
technically a web proxy but you've made
your network a lot safer ransomware
there's at least one company cyber
reason offering a free ransomware tool
you can actively protect your machines
from ransomware now obviously we're
security people we don't trust people
right so having cyber reason land free
software on my end point it's dicey
situation but it's a low risk compared
to if you know you've got users who are
definitely going to click on those links
and definitely going to download the
stuff and run the stuff and encrypt your
sort your hard drive and they've already
done it three times and it went over to
the file share and you you know if this
happens maybe it's time to look at
something like that and extend here your
level of trust a little there are free
solutions obviously a full antivirus or
a full-blown solution is better
but there are three ways to handle that
I'm getting short on time right okay I
got two minutes okay we'll do this one
quickly there's a last one so asset
protection free asset protection prey
project install it on your machine it's
called the prey project it's a script
that will run that will check if your
machine has if you've told the Central
Command that your machine is stolen and
if it is then it's does telling you hey
I'm here obviously if the attacker wipes
the machine doesn't protect that but I
can tell you from actual live experience
that there are attackers I know at least
two examples where they took the machine
and took it to their house and turned it
on and put it on the network yeah smart
one got caught detectives caught him but
so prey project blew there our vendor
solutions you can buy two particular
assets but pre-project works really well
and it's free policy is a dicey one you
can write your own security policy if
your security professional you're better
off letting security positive you know
so what you're looking for it's a little
bit dicey if in a small company in this
room you can pick and choose and write
your own policy and make it happen it'll
be enough for a small company because
again you're looking at the CIS top
three maybe not even the whole twenty
just a tiny company spam prevention ask
your ISP about fixing about making sure
that they're doing as much limiting as
possible on your mail passwords
obviously want a full program but you
can go to the server and say we require
complex passwords you can do it free on
your own and network segmentation start
with subnetting yes network segmentation
with firewalls is really awesome and
it's a really great way to go and I love
the way I feel nice and warm and cozy
behind all my firewalls but if you can't
afford all these firewalls at least
segment the network you'll stop some of
the broadcast traffic that some of the
viruses are using
so skipping through to the end yes so
remember that your company is going to
try to grow the company maybe small
medium or large but you're going to try
to grow be sure that the solutions that
you spend all this time on are going to
be working in six months remember you've
got to handle today but in six months
you've got to be ready a year and so
forth you don't want to be straight face
you want to be like this guy who spent
all this time and effort on his solution
and set out six months later you
couldn't fit into his own suit hey still
pretty cool all right you want you want
to be sure that what you've got will
work for now and will work when it's
finally implemented so think ahead and
we've got four minutes for questions no
questions awesome yes slides will be
online we'll give it a D sides right
yeah what was the other thing you said
oh the product list yeah for the list of
that I went down with all the products
that will be also provided via live link
in the slides those will go up or they
can everyone can attack me yet good they
want to record your voice forever
you mentioned the USB drive swap back
and forth as a low-cost backup option
definitely done that I I think if you
have a small or even a small to medium
size company here you started relatively
recently you don't have much local
infrastructure you don't have much local
data is there is there a comparable
low-cost backup solution for when you're
using Google Apps or you're using office
365 or is that really no it's not there
yet good luck
I have very mixed feelings about a lot
of that stuff because running stuff in
the cloud is great for some stuff but
not for other stuff and and and so I
sort of draw lines there and stuff that
I really care about not getting out I
would never put up there but to answer
your question you can export from there
onto a USB Drive just pull the data down
now I talked with one customer there
quite a bit about this and I finally
explained to them look if something
happens to your license agreement with
Amazon and suddenly you can't get in is
your company out of business if they
decide you haven't paid your bill you're
done is all of your data now there and
you can't get to it oh wait there's a
clause in the contract that says within
like six months you have the right to do
a special download as yeah okay I need
it today I want to get the company going
right so if you've downloaded your data
then you've got a way out it does hit
your bandwidth oh I don't have a way
around that does that answer your
question
okay I'll just stop come on launch codes
I'm going to keep it on an internal
server that I secure with my own
firewalls on my own you know area then
you're running it in the cloud yep yet
mail like mail I put in the cloud mail
is easy I was going by SMTP in the clear
anyway so I'm sending anything valuable
in mail I'm screwed but yeah a lot of
stuff runs in the cloud and then some
stuff is just not local you're right oh
yeah we are