my name is Nick Kalina this is Scot
Goodwin we're from OCD Tech which is the
IT audit and security division of
O'Connor and Dru with regional
accounting firm we're going to talk
about Hastings great thing and the
implications for everyone in this room
and everyone in the greater world
I'll let Scott take it off thank you
thank you so we're going to yeah we're
gonna be talking about a web scraping
platform that we've designed at OCD tech
to monitor and collect data related to
information leaks and security breaches
that have been posted to public sources
like pastebin and other page style
websites so we'll start with in just an
intro to open source intelligence and
some of the sources that we're using the
tools that we've used up to this point
to collect some of that information and
then why we decided to build our own to
collect a subset of information that's
kind of poorly captured by those tools
we'll talk about where that data is
ending up for some smaller and even the
large breaches where that data is ending
up on the Internet and how we can
leverage that to capture that
information take a look at the scraping
platform itself how it's built how we're
using it and finally we'll look at some
examples of the data that we've captured
over the past year so we've been
scraping pastebin and other pastebin
style sites for about a year so we have
a pretty big data set to play with so to
start open source intelligence that's an
umbrella term we give to the tools that
we use to collect the data as well as
the data that comes back I want us for
people who aren't familiar I want to
distinguish open source intelligence
from the open source that you hear with
regards to software where you have
access to that the source code itself in
this case it really means that that data
is being collected from the public
domain from sources that everybody in
the room has access to so in the context
of security research and our team we're
collecting data about a business
sometimes more granularly collecting
information about the employees of that
business trying to get an idea for the
organizational structure while we're
planning a security assessment or a pen
test and then also obviously we're
collecting information about the
technical infrastructure using DNS to
get host names and IP addresses and then
who is you can connect some of those
names that you got in the last step to
the DNS records who owns those websites
and then any internet facing systems
that we have so
your firewalls and routers and load
balancers and anything that sits inside
your DMZ so we'll be you know pinging
and probing those systems trying to get
as much information as possible and we
use a number of tools some most of you
are probably familiar with tools like
recon ng and the harvester discover
scripts and they're really great for a
point in time assessment to bring in as
much information for whatever sources
they're using for those tools you can
get a point in time assessment of the
information that's available on the
Internet and what we found is what you
get back is some personnel information
you can generate employee lists and an
email address lists and stuff like that
but what you get back is mostly
technical data you can get back a lot of
information to start assembling a
picture of their from the outside of
what their network looks like but the
problem is most of that data is known to
be public already sometimes you'll find
you know the easter-egg of something
that somebody didn't know was made
public and one thing that we tried to
use these tools for and realize that
they don't work very well in this
capacity is to identify new data that's
been released for a target so if
something new is released and you
compare that back to the data that you
had before you could identify that some
new information had been made public and
they don't work in that capacity that's
not what they're designed to do so what
we designed was a tool to capture or
subset of data on the internet that's
really not well analyzed by those types
of tools and what we're really going
after is we want to get right to the
password we want to capture any
information to capture email address and
password together and that information
is out there and it's not something that
you can reliably pull back with existing
tools so in order to do that we're
leveraging paste style websites for
those of you aren't familiar with
something like paste bin they get their
name from your ability to copy any text
you want and paste it to the website and
once you click Submit
you're granted a URL dedicated to that
text so you don't have to register a
domain name you don't have to sign up
with paste bin or any of these other
sites really some of them you do but
pastebin allows anonymous pastes and
because of the anonymous aspect of it
they're being
abused by hackers and attackers to
release that information to the public
in cases where they're either trying to
make that data for sale make that data
available on the dark web so they'll
give you a link to where you can go buy
it or releasing that data just to either
take credit for the for the breach that
they committed or to increase the
damages to that target organization so
lots of data is getting posted to
paceman and and others and other sites
as well actually and I want to be clear
that that's not what they're designed
for obviously they were designed
originally for code sharing and
collaboration for developers on opposite
sides of the planet want to share code
for debugging and peer review without
having to use an extra layer like email
or FTP so there's an awful lot of
legitimate traffic on these websites as
well and that's why they're still
available but what we're trying to do is
grab all that illicit material that's
being posted there as well so that's
what we've done we've we're
programmatically extracting data from
pastebin and other web sites to pull
down everything that's there and then
secondarily go through that information
and try to understand pull out the
information that we're interested in
which is obviously not the majority of
the traffic that you see from a web
scraping perspective you're limited by
the the sources that you can scrape so
you have to have access to that site and
a lot of web sites like you can get an
awful lot of information by parsing
social media and stuff like that but
once you need there's an Authenticator
there you need to have a username and
password and once you've authenticated
you still only have access to your
network you can you can't see everything
that's actually there and hackers
wouldn't use that forum to release
information publicly anyways their
intent is to get as many eyes on that
data as possible so pastebin style
site-geist and flexi and pastebin they
really they fit the bill for this type
of information leakage and you're also
limited to a certain extent by you know
acceptable use when your program
programming
requests when you're programmatically
making requests over the Internet it's
really easy to not tune the scraper and
send way too many requests more than
whatever be necessary to that resource
on the Internet
and if that happens in most cases
they'll just shut you off or throttle
the connection so you have to be careful
it comes down to tuning to get
everything that you do need without
making extra requests the tool that we
built is built on our standard lamp
stack so we have a dedicated a boom to
VM Apache web server on the front end
for with PHP myadmin which we don't
generally use that often but we have it
my sequel database in the backend and
the entire platform is written in Python
the actual analysis is happening Python
so we'll go through how it works just
really quickly this is for paste bin but
it applies to any pay style website that
publishes this archive page so we first
will step one is to reach out to the URL
pastebin.com slash archive and by
parsing the raw HTML content on that
page you can extract links to all of the
recently created pastes so so the posted
time over there was zero seconds ago so
this is constantly updated list of paste
that have been created so that Stepan
creates a list of paste that you're
interested in scraping and then
separately we'll take that list and go
through each one of them reach out to
paceman at that URL and pull down that
route text as long as we haven't seen it
already and so now we have a paste
locally on our VM in memory that came
from paestum at that point what we did
originally was take the paste and put it
right into the database that was like
the proof of concept stage we didn't
perform any analysis on it and then as
the dataset grew in the dataset grows
very quickly it became harder and harder
to use that data for anything any pay an
individual pace can have a thousand
lines or more thousands of lines and we
have millions of pastes so by not
performing any analysis on the front end
we were relegated to full-text searches
only which became incredibly exhaustive
from a time and resource perspective so
what we do now
kind of like version two is while we
have that paste in memory we extract
information types that we think we're
interested in now so one example that we
have up here is an email and password
combination so we have an MIT edu
password I mean an email address
with a colon followed by a string and
that string represents a password hash
so we're using regular expressions to
match username and password combinations
that are separated by a delimiter
usually a colon or the pipe character
and we have other one set up for other
types of information as well so now we
extract that information and we store it
in a separate table on the database
which is indexed so we can get to that
data we have a lot more visibility into
the data now because the data set is
growing so quickly at this point these
are rough numbers it's changing all the
time it's running as we speak we have 8
million or so pastes over the last year
with some downtime in there so it hasn't
been a complete year four and a half
million email addresses that we pulled
out of these pastes so if I was a
spammer you know we can stop right here
we have a we have a tool that's
generating email addresses in real time
and then crucially the one and a half
million about of those email emails had
a password associated with them in the
standard format that we see which is
email followed by a colon or a pipe
character and then the password
we're also extracting IP addresses and
finally onion links and I'm sure most of
you're aware that those are links to the
dark the dark web for lack of a better
term and we collect those because it's
hard to find resources on the dark web
if you don't already have URL so we're
scrape that we're collecting those onion
links now and in the future since
there's such a wealth of information
available on the dark web the future
state will be that those onion links are
actually populating their own scraper so
at this point I want to make clear what
we're going to be showing you and why
we're interested in this data and it's
because there is a tendency for users to
do two things one of them is reuse their
corporate or business kernel address on
external services which is something
that has to happen sometimes it's not
necessarily something we you know you
frowned upon using the email address on
an external service sometimes it's
frowned upon but also the reuse of
passwords across multiple services so
we're targeting corporate or business
credentials that have been released to
pastebin and other websites as a result
of a breach that happened on
one else's server so when we have you
know a breach of some random website on
the internet that data doesn't
necessarily have a lot of value you know
it's not like a Dropbox or yahoo breach
where it's millions and millions of
records it affects a smaller user base
and they can't necessarily make any real
money off of that data so they posted to
paceman to make it public and take
credit for what they've done
but in that data there is regularly
corporate email addresses for agencies
and businesses of all types and when
there's a password associated with that
email address there's always a chance
that that's a valid password for the for
the organization itself so that's what
we're targeting and that's what we're
going to be showing you later on with
the examples so how do we use this data
internally well obviously we like to go
through the data for from a research
perspective that's what I spend a lot of
time doing trying to see what's been
released
but also for vulnerability assessments
and pen tests this is you know one of
our first stops we have a year's worth
of paceman data and ideally we would be
entering these environments already
having credentials to the you know to
the environment they don't have to be
admin credentials or anything like that
but we can hopefully we'll be starting
an engagement already having some
credentials to that environment but so
besides those two things what we were
trying to do at the very beginning was
come up with a way to create alerts
based on our own information being
released to pastebin clients partners or
vendors that whole supply chain so if
any of that information makes its way to
pastebin we want to create alert on that
and initially we had sent those via
email just like every other service and
people stopped looking at them as is to
be expected so now we're doing sending
them directly to slack so which is a
chat program they have laptop and mobile
clients so we're getting these letters
right to our cell phone and we've also
set up the ability to search through
that database via slack so we have
pretty much the databases more or less
pretty well integrated from a mobile
device standpoint you don't need to have
VPN access or you don't need to putty
none of that stuff no my sequel syntax
just basic searching can be completed
via slack so let's take a look at some
of the data that we found over the last
year the nasa breach was semi publicized
you might have heard of that that a lot
of that information was released a
pastebin we have FBI credentials you see
that there's a hash up there and I left
the IP address unobscured as well
because it shows that you know we're
using pattern matching to do this we're
not we don't know what that piece of
data is that's after that delimiter in
this case it was an IP address and that
might not be a password but we can still
associate that IP address would be with
the FBI
email address that goes with it so we're
capturing all that information
regardless of what the string is
Department Homeland Security and then
from an infrastructure standpoint the
United States the parts of energy we've
captured credentials for the Federal
Reserve Bank over last year the
Securities and Exchange Commission we
captured one password that's potentially
valid in that environment and then the
FDIC we also captured a number of emails
no passwords though and I left that in
there because I think that most people
would still be interested to understand
the context of how their agencies or
their businesses email addresses even
email by itself is making its way to
paste bin you know you don't this is a
if they are not aware of that
information making its way out then
there's a chance that you know it came
from inside their network I'm pulled out
I tried to take a breath over deft
approach with these examples trying to
show that large companies are affected
by this just as a result of the number
of users that they have so there's the
more users that you have the more email
addresses you have in exchange the more
users are spreading that information out
over the internet and the more
opportunities you have for password
reuse so UnitedHealthcare that's the
larger self care provide in the United
States we have credentials that are
potentially about in that environment
pharmaceutical McKesson the same story
from the defense sector we pulled out
Raytheon got a couple passwords for them
and then in the retail space we pulled
out Walmart a single password for them
as well Ford looks like they might have
had an actual breach it's kind of hard
to tell
that's quite a few passwords Amazon has
a pretty big presence here it's security
beside so we pulled them out for the
furry commerce
and for communication people let AT&T so
it really does spans all industry
sectors medium to large sized businesses
this is more of an eventualities than it
is anything else
in our perspective I mean I have trouble
I'm you're more likely to find it than
not find it for large businesses in our
pay spend database since Harvard is nice
enough to partner with security besides
this year I figured it would be a good
forum to bring up higher education
because we see more dot edu credentials
on pastebin than any other top-level
domain and that's again a function of
that intuitive trend that you have more
users and in this case more users who
aren't necessarily security focused
spreading that information out and we
you know students are probably just as
likely as everyone else to be reusing
those passwords too so this is not a
Harvard University problem by any means
these are student credentials their
student bodies you know constantly
changing are always provisioning new
email addresses and revoking old ones so
you know we're pretty interested to find
out one what percentage of these
credentials are potentially valid for
higher education institutions not just
Harvard but anybody and then to you know
what can we get to with those
credentials not you know we're not going
out and validating that any of these
work but you know is none of these
student portals usually have two-factor
authentication or anything like that
because it's such a burden for the for
the whole environment so you know every
every University has a student portal
and they're all available online so
statistically this is only a subset I
mean we've had we have a hundred in the
last year for Harvard University
distinct email and password combinations
so statistically speaking I think we
should be able to get access to some
financial records web scraping for fun
and profit so I had talked about the fun
part from the profit perspective paceman
is a clearinghouse for stolen data it's
an advertising platform for hackers
you'll it's constantly finding links to
purchase this information in Bitcoin on
external sites usually on the dark web
but we do see credit card numbers very
very
regularly posted to pastebin and and
other paste style websites and we use
regular expressions again for this
pattern matching and what it comes down
to is that we see so many that it's
really highly unlikely that they're all
valid credit card numbers even though
they match that pattern so what we do is
we retain the paste ID in this table so
we can always refer back to the raw
paste so we can get the context of how
that credit credit card or potential
credit card number was released and try
to understand if it really represents a
credit card number because you know
these for instance these ones down here
that have the space right in the middle
it's hard to tell I mean generally their
system logs and tons of code and
encrypted data and binary data people
post all sorts of things to paste them
so we kind of have to take a holistic
approach to pulling out these numbers
and if we were interested in finding out
if they're real or not we'd have to go
back to that original paste and try to
get that context so we're not really
profiting off of this obviously we're
not using those credit card numbers and
we're not trying any of these
credentials that we found for us it's
more about a potential savings so we're
going to try to identify those threats
as soon as they're made public obviously
we have no visibility into what happened
with those credentials before they are
made public or who else has them prior
to that but as soon as that information
is made public and I assure you that
we're not the only people who are doing
this once that data is made public it
becomes a risk to that in that
environment that someone else is going
to try to use those credentials against
you so the faster that we can respond to
these types of things and you know
basically change that password if it
happened to be a legitimate password
we're going to limit the damages we're
going to limit the ability of an
attacker to use public domain data
against us and you know at the bottom
pretty common commonly cited stat is the
cost of a data breach and any single one
of these credentials could instigate a
breach like that even if they're not you
know domain admin or anything like that
once you have access to an email inbox
or something like that you can start
pivoting and gaining trust and you have
a foothold in that environment so for
our for our perspective it's not about
making money as much as it is saving
money
question it was any freedom for a guide
like these others not to limit the many
good reason for they would do that that
would in fact sir their ability to
provide service to customers so the
question is is there any reason for them
not to do it exactly so like they
haven't done it yet I mean I think that
it sounds like like one of the possible
ways to sort of mitigate this as special
risk as you know you guys good good that
you're really doing this to to access
and others may not be so absolutely so
page Benton is absolutely aware of this
problem and they are more or less
profiting off of it to be honest with
you
so previous to have one haffley to
describe a project maybe six months ago
we were doing raw HTML scraping parsing
the raw HTML content on the page and
pulling out the you know the raw text
from the paste and that's what we still
have to do for all other sources that
we're scraping paste bin released an API
for scraping and if you don't if you
don't use their API they're going to
shut you off immediately we've had
issues with other services throttling
drawing the connection and whatnot but
um the real way that they're mitigating
this and paceman is not doing anything
to mitigate this they will remove paste
data that's been made public but it's
not before the data is made public so
the data gets posted to that archive
page that I showed you immediately and
we're scraping all that and we raise on
alert often times by the time the alert
makes it to the cellphone and you try to
click the link to go look at the paste
the pace has already been removed and
paste them but the page is in our paste
bin database and it's in everybody else
is based on database already so other
services and the services that we're not
scraping are ones that have either a an
Authenticator in front of that page so
you have to log in and only see your
network of people that you're allowed to
talk with really or be they don't make
the list of pastes public so you don't
know what you're looking for
they don't make an archive page public
so I can create a list of pace that I
want to go out and scrape
I would have to basically guess paste
IDs until I found them and that's just
not going to work so the real way that
they're mitigating this is by not making
public pastes not making the URL for
public pastes public domain even though
if I navigate it to that URL I would
still be able to access that I just
don't have that data to start with yep
yep that's why we keep the original
information of the original paste so we
always reference back usually what you
find is that they'll either be either
portion of the credit card number or the
whole credit card number with no extra
information and then a link to go
purchase these records on the dark web
it's not we try to create I try to
create a regular expression that would
also parse out the sea snail the CCD
number and everything else and them it
just broke every time so what we have to
do is when we find a credit card that
Mike we haven't really started digging
into the credit card data yet because
there's nothing we can really do with it
I'm gonna borrow credit card data you
know popped up we could go back and
verify whether or not it came out of
some random junk data or fit them and we
do see full credit card we have
absolutely seen full full records
released and that doesn't mean that
they'll work I mean it could be shut
down or whatever but they're absolutely
full records available - sure
and is there another question yeah sure
which is in general are you seeing is
there a sizing or is routine works on
small boss there is a size limit a max
size limit on the page and think it's
500 kilobytes okay people are making you
can make multiple pace write in a row
but there is a limit just based on
bandwidth kind of that they put a
pastebin puts a limit on how big of a
pace that you can create so I'm going to
get out of here and in order to give a
demo I'm going to search right from
slack so you know we could log into the
database and do it that way but I'm
going to pull up our slack client is
anyone brave enough to offer a domain
that they're so yeah but you got yes
it okay I will give you a there's a
disclaimer that's as you can see right
here if there was a plaintext password
associated with that domain it's going
to show up right here okay
so you know I'll show you this to shell
CMD paste bin
we're telling we're going to tell our we
have a robot set up to do this we're
going to tell the robot that we're going
to be executing command and bash which
is called paste bin and that's living on
a VM on our network and then we're going
to do researching for a domain and once
again are you and I didn't put in a
condition that says that there's nothing
say no so that means nothing
so you're clean say big you know it
works really well for for big big
domains yep VA n OB given job required
yeah as long as I thought so yeah
proof it does work what was let yeah
between do Qualcomm which is two M's
right yeah yeah the bigger the domain
the more likely this is to be a you know
problem
it's just statistics really it's not to
say we don't find small businesses
that's an issue as well we certainly do
so now these are somebody posted the
same thing over and over again so we got
no passwords there but hand these are
all from individual pastes negatives
well we have one but there's no password
yep yes but it's locked down entirely to
those words yeah I can't I can't run
whatever I want I've know so we don't
have we this is not an interactive bass
show now this is me calling out to a
server that we've set up to to run a
specific script and it doesn't accept
anything else except for there's a
number of things that we can do with
this robot but it doesn't accept
anything outside of that so you can't
run RM minus RF soon pardon absolutely
not
this I'm not a developer I hope nobody
nobody touch any of the stuff because
I'm sure it's very fragile
but proof of concept it does work that's
the excellent question we've we've been
struggling with how you know what what
controls really need to be in place for
this type of data it's an excellent
question and everybody has their own
opinion and up until now or a little
while ago it was our answer was that
it's public domain data and we're not
the only people that have it but that
doesn't change the fact that it is PII
we have pretty I mean I'm the only one
with access to directly to the database
obviously anybody with access to slack
and search the database but we have
access controls and the virtual disk is
encrypted and that's all we have in
place I mean I'm scraping data from
pastebin that everyone else has as well
so more nefarious people yep you also
the other - it's a what is shown here is
one of these identities where the hash
would be shown here we're not
differentiating between a password and a
hash anything that comes after the
delimiter next to an email address is
what we're calling the password so
sometimes that's hash if the web
application has two passwords sometimes
it's a plaintext password so we're not
free interests appreciating there so are
you collecting other types of logins
though like usernames and are
necessarily addresses we have everything
that's supposed to paceman last year so
the reason we keep everything is because
we can go back and answer questions like
that we can react whatever data we want
by designing a.m. we're running out of
time by designing a new regular
expression go back to that entire
database a year's worth of data a
hundred gigabytes extract every piece of
information are interested in storing
its own table so we're looking to do
that with social security numbers right
now
what's the ratio to hash passwords to
acquaintance we see many more plaintext
passwords and hash passwords and I
believe that's the result of some of
those plaintext passwords being a
complete bump it's hard to say we don't
know if it's really not we're not
validating any of this but when we see a
hash password the people who that
belongs to some project be nervous
because it's generally real or you know
it's real for whatever resources
compromised we think so you know any
other questions you have to come up I'll
search but everyone sign up