hello everyone thank you for coming out
- exploding continuous integration
systems and automated built systems
I'm calling this part two last year at
Freaknik I gave a talk on kind of some
similar stuff but I didn't maybe go into
as much technical detail as I wanted to
and then I over the last year I've
developed exploit framework and I was
able to present that at Def Con and then
I actually found some more stuff since
that talk three months ago and so I'm
gonna present that here as well so
hopefully you'll get something you'll
learn something or we'll have a good
time I'm space box I'll go by Tyler as
well I'm the senior security engineering
software company called link it we are
based here locally in Franklin I do
mostly application and network security
but I also get my hands dirty doing like
policy stuff and pen testing and
sysadmin type things and access control
we're a smaller company so you wear lots
of hats and I like I like to wear lots
of hats I also do security consultancy
on the side
when my children and wife allow attend
the dc-6 one-five group meetings once a
month but that's you know up in the air
sometimes what we're going to do here in
this talk is basically go over a
high-level overview like a flyover of
continuous integration and some of the
concepts and what it is and some of the
tooling around that and then we'll also
go through the typical build chain flow
for software from the time that it code
gets pushed to a repository to the time
that it's deployed to production and
we'll talk about some of the problems
that are inherent with these build
models and then also I'll give a
real-world example of an exploit just a
very basic one it's if you saw the talk
last year it's the one from that and
then some bad practices that contribute
to more exploitation and then I'll get
to real-world examples that are more a
little different kind of unique to the
vendors and then after that I've written
a program called cider and so I'm going
to introduce and just kind of quickly go
over what cider is so we need to talk at
least set some definitions before I
really get any deeper continuous
integration at a high level is the tools
that are in place to quickly and
iteratively release code into production
environments the goal a lot of times for
most especially development type shops
is to have many iterative releases per
day that's kind of the dream or per week
these systems though at least the ones
that I'm going to be talking about are
mostly repository centric meaning the
build process starts from the code that
has pushed two repositories
and this is code built processes in sync
with the automated building systems as
well as the automated deployment systems
and one thing to also know is the
further this kind of evolves it it lends
itself not just to development practices
but also to infrastructure practices as
you're having systems like AWS and Azure
that are being you can deploy
infrastructure components with templates
it just makes sense that these are
repository centric and that these
template deployments get shoved out in
the same way oftentimes starting with
poor requests and things like that so we
have to talk about micro services but I
won't harp too much on this because I've
done so in the past and I it may not be
pertinent to what everyone does but
micro services is the high-level concept
that we're going to take a piece of
software that does acts as a unified
whole the monolith if you will and break
it down into smaller components that do
one or two things by themselves and they
do only those one or two things and they
can be developed autonomously by groups
of developers who say all right you're
going to build this thing it's going to
take X as an input it's going to do Y
and seize the output and if it breaks we
know what broke we have this single
micro service that's going to handle the
left-hand toolbar on this nice app we
have and if the left-hand toolbar you
know gets forked then we probably know
which service that is it's the left-hand
toolbar micro service
so we're gonna do tooling I'm gonna go
briefly over the tools I'm not going to
spend too much time talking about
specific ones until we get to the
exploitation part but these are things
that I feel you can probably look up and
research on your time there a lot of
them are very in-depth and they have a
lot of capabilities we're going to be
focusing on the portions that I've been
able to exploit because that's more fun
to me and it's what I've been focusing
all of my research on the idea of a
built system is to take the code and you
build it conditionally and what that
means is in some cases it doesn't have
to be very much it it could mean you
print hello world and the code doesn't
throw an error and that's that's all
your test is but really what this is is
a way to get a rough preliminary test on
the code it's not a QA framework or
anything like that but a lot of times
these systems are quasi containerized
meaning you shove your code up to a
repository it goes into the build into
the build system and it builds it with
these minor tests and then a lot of
times like in github it'll send a signal
back like a thumbs up and go hey your
code didn't crash and that that lets the
person who's going to be merging that
request go okay it doesn't totally suck
and they don't waste their time and
that's that's not the entire purpose of
the build systems the built systems do a
lot more but in a lot of cases that's
what they love getting used for some
vendors are Travis CI circle CI drone
team city build kite Jenkins falls into
this category as well then there's the
deployment systems and there's a lot of
crossover between the build systems in
the deployment system sometimes but some
of them are segregated and so I decided
in here but the code after it's built
goes to a system that then will find the
servers or find clusters of servers or
find a container or a place to spin up a
docker container with that service in
after it's been built a lot of times a
lot of times the build service actually
will containerize and build an image of
the built service and then shove that up
to the deployment system and now the
deployment system just indiscriminately
it's just programmed to just find a
right amount of space than the allocated
servers and deploy it
so Jenkins would also fall in there
octopus deploy kubernetes Rancher missus
fear a lot of these are going to be
container based that's kind of the
direction that a lot of these are going
so I sort of verbally gone over it my
hair some pictures got developer man he
pushes up to github the build service
has a web hook and it sees hey a PR has
been made a pull request or just a
commit has been made you can they
trigger off various things I'm gonna
pull that code down and I'm gonna do the
build test with it I'm gonna build that
code and then I'm gonna let the
repository know github that it succeeded
so once that succeeded then it might do
something like I was just talking about
like build an image and shove it up to
an image repository different than the
code repository or it doesn't have to do
that and then it will take that and
push it down to a deployment system and
now that the deployment system goes hey
this crowd is built successfully we have
an image and we have a target we can
then use the deployment service and
deploy that out to those little blue
squares at the top or just serve it you
know servers or clusters or resources or
whatever so that's that's it in a
nutshell and so as these systems and
these interactions between these systems
that we're really going to be focusing
on exploiting there are some trends that
are developing in the kind of
development world that maybe aren't the
most secure in the need the need for
speed makes pushes people to focus on
quick releases versus the security of
those releases and so what we find
happening one of the big ones that I
already sort of talked about was that
one of the one of the purposes of the
build service is to let the person who's
going to be merging it and know that
it's successfully built meaning that
before the code is actually proved to be
a part of the code base it's being built
on a service somewhere which means that
anyone who has access to do that bill is
has capability to manipulate that build
service even if they don't have
permission to actually control the code
in the repo that's because they're
triggered from vrz commits the thing is
about these is the repository in most
cases
holds the downstream instructions for
the build service it pulls a dot Travis
yeah mo file or a drone mo file or
something in the repository
that tells the next thing down what to
do which means that someone without
permission who is just trying to do a
pull request can now give instructions
to many built service before it's even
been approved to be merged into the
repository and that's kind of where I do
most of the exploitation is that that
step there and it can have fake
downstream effects vulnerabilities lime
for the most part in the idea that you
have these interdependent systems that
are being linked together with basically
just webhook calls and so you have a
built service that's talking to a
automated deployment service but these
have different user permissions these
have different access to your repository
it's hard to take one like if you're on
a company and you're trying to do a
policy like a user access policy it's
hard to take that policy and apply it
they same to every one of these so it's
not necessarily the individual systems
there will be taking advantage of it's
the Mis configuration in the interaction
of these systems which is where most the
vulnerabilities actually lie in many
cases in most cases it's actually the
service themselves are operating just
exactly as they're intended to function
and I think personally I feel that the
most volatile like threat vector here is
are the external repos particularly
external repos that trigger builds on a
company's internal build servers so you
have something where it's like hey and
we want to share our code base of the
world that's fantastic until you are
allowing the world to trigger builds on
your you know
administrative subnets and then that's
really bad let's see here there are
patterns that are evolving especially in
the build systems where there are
multiple ways to execute code or
manipulate the way those builds work but
the three biggest that I've experimented
with are in most of these files for most
of these systems there's a section
called pre and post commands so before
you test your build and after you test
your build what do you want this thing
to do and in most cases this is where
the you can just eject Linux commands
like raw Linux commands and in most
cases they're actually running as root
so you're allowing in these repost
commands to just run arbitrary code
which is fantastic the other deal and
this is by the way the section of the
file that I kind of exploit the most
because it's the easiest but there are
other ways to do it one is the image
specification some of these systems
allow you to actually specify which
docker image you want to build build
from and it will just blatantly pull
down a docker image to build on so if
you have a malicious docker container
you can just pull that down or and some
of them don't allow you to pull
arbitrary images down but they will
allow you to supply a docker file so you
can just build your own invention that's
even better
and then the last thing is I think the
newest version of drone
actually allows you to say hey I don't
want any changes to the config file for
the build and in the code repository
don't don't build it
that's dangerous which is great of them
the problem is is they don't seem to
forbid you changing the test file that
gets run it's all I got to do is inject
bad code now in the test file and it
will still you'll be able to bypass that
feature so real-world hacking this was
kind of the first time I discovered and
another person discovered to the
problems inherent with this so you can
kind of see here we have the image
specification at the top you have the
environment where you do the environment
variable setup and then you have the
command section here which is includes
the pre post commands that I was talking
about and so that's where you're going
to inject arbitrary code then you have
publish information after that in this
example where it built the image and
shoves it up to a repository and then
some plugins you can have to do alerting
and such in this case the guy came up to
me and was like hey man I think I can
change an environment variable in the
build and I think that's bad I think we
can actively change environment
variables and at this point I wasn't
aware of kind of what these systems did
I was still new to it it's like all
right let's take a look man and sure
enough he was right you could change
environment variables but I was like
what's this command section do and and
so then we just like injected like a
echo statement and I just wanted to see
if it would reflect back and it did and
I couldn't believe it and so I was like
oh man we could do a lot more than
change environment variables you know
it's like he found the treasure chest
and then was like hey it's a really cool
box I only had open up the box so I did
something like this in this command
section
to do a back pipe and then I met Kat
back over it to my little control server
where I'm listening on board and so then
from there you were able to get route
because most of these systems inherently
run with root privileges so that was the
first example but then it just like got
my brain on a torrent of like why isn't
anyone exploited this yet and who's
aware of it you know like I can't be the
only one that's aware of these problems
but they are like relatively new and
when these systems come out everyone
just jumps on them so and then also
what's the attack surface how big are
things how many repos and github are
actually actually have these and are
triggering builds on servers and things
like that so before there is an older
project I think Jonathan claudius I
think he was at Mozilla I'm not sure he
is now or maybe he's at Mozilla now I
don't know but he in his spare time did
this project called rotten apple is
written in ruby and it did kind of what
I tried to do with my exploit framework
to an extent his was more auditing and
it audited Jenkins to look for things
during the build and tell you hey this
is potentially insecure and it was
really really cool and I liked that
framework a lot I felt like I wanted to
do a little bit more with it so I kept
poking around with it but other than his
tool and a few white papers that I found
that were really not very specific I
didn't find a lot of people that were
Jenkins so that's kind of what motivated
in my morbid
let's see there are most of these
systems are cloud-based meaning if you
sign up for a Travis account you get the
Travis instance in the cloud and they
run it and you don't touch it however
you can sign up for enterprise versions
of some of these software's and run them
locally in fact a lot of these actually
there are some vendors that do local
only so you just kind of get a mix and a
lot of times you don't actually know
what you're getting into when you find
one of these you kind of have to figure
out if it's right are they using the
cloud hosted version of Travis are they
using you know the local version
obviously the local version has a lot
more implications as far as taking over
a network but there's still bad things
that can happen I was kind of surprised
that I mean this would be it be
inefficient hard to control because when
you do these builds that go into a built
queue but you could you could use these
to take all public builds that are doing
builds from a config file and do some
sort of like malicious attack on
something because they would all start
building in sequence right you take
every single every single dot Travis
demo file on github and do a PR to it
and just see what happens I say yes
place but I really am not condoning it
at all
but I'm kind of surprised that that
hasn't been an attack vector that Lisa's
been seen yet or I say mine here Ian but
big block change stuff unlike I just
don't see that happening but it would be
funny because there's the ether miners
now that are out in like taking over
docile Reddit servers and stuff or not
reddit servers Redis servers
but like I said the on-prem stuff is
really the biggest concern when you're
running these services and you have an
external facing web webhook going in
into your built servers that's where a
lot of this is going to lie and then
some of the fun stuff is altering
downstream production and this applies
also to cloud-based but there's a lot
more implications of taking over Network
when you can get control than internet
server all right I'll stop talking about
that now there are some development
things that are also need to be known in
operations like DevOps practices one is
it's a common practice now to store
credentials for other micro services in
environment variables so that it's
technically better than storing a
hard-coded cred in a config file in your
repo but since everything's repository
centric the kind of other solution -
then it's like hey let's just shove in
an environment variable the problem is
is when you compromise one of the
server's I have to do is like env and
you dump all of your creds to get to
other services so this if you're
thinking and kind of the typical attack
vector kill chain and it's finally
one thing to another once you can access
em inside it's at least one technique
and the other big thing is that most of
these are implicitly running things
those rooms and so when you take over
you just have root access now a lot of
these are on a stripped down image like
a Alpine image instead of a full of moon
to image but it doesn't really matter if
you can talk out to the web right and
then I can just start pulling stuff down
through apt-get or whatever and or just
start falling down from my own personal
toolset as long as i web access and then
you have controlled the foley argument
that image into whatever kind of even
she wanted to be so the next one the
next example of something that I sort of
found on accident was I was testing as I
sort of got trigger-happy once I kind of
really delved into this and so I was
testing against I was doing bug bounty
stuff which it turns out testing is to
get up repositories is out of scope for
most bug bounties just heads up but I
was testing for a social networking
company and I tried to start messing
around with their Travis stuff and I
just started doing basic recon right
here you have I'm doing nets down
getting computer name and getting what's
my external IP address just basic stuff
about the posts that I was able to
execute code on trying to you know
figure out where I was and what I was
doing I noticed that the external IP
actually went back to a Google like a
Google cloud hosting which I wasn't very
familiar with them but one thing that I
noticed that was really unique was that
I started seeing the Google cloud stuff
and I knew that I was operating in
Travis and so I knew that I must have
been in there cloud-based Travis build
services and I started seeing these
environment variables I'm doing
and variable dump for g-cloud pants are
g-cloud something-something and I
started to get really really curious as
to what that was most of my experiences
in AWS and Azure but I thought I would
do some research so I I researched like
what those were and it turns out some of
those references were to a Jeep cloud
CLI program which is the way that you
control your instance of Google Cloud
and this is something that the customer
should never see right this is something
that them as a company would be using to
control their networks and deploy stuff
and but I got curious and I was like
what if I could just like shove one of
those g-cloud commands into the pre the
pre-built file and see if it worked and
it did so I did this command and it was
pseudo g-cloud compute project input
describe just to see if I could at least
list Google cloud deployment information
from their service and I could and it
dumped out even like a you know like a
public key there and a bunch of stuff so
I was like oh man this could be this
could be really bad so I didn't stop
there I kept going and I did this next
one is Google compute networks create
test network mode auto and what that
does is spin up a virtual network and it
worked and so then you can see halfway
down there underneath the smiley face
where I was really happy that it worked
the other stuff verifies that the
network networks were created not only
was the network created but it was
created in multiple regions across
multiple continents and so I was really
surprised that I ended up actually just
spinning up that virtual network from
you know attend a tune line-to-line pull
request to repository that I didn't have
permission to access so I contacted them
and they were really happy they were
very grateful that I did that here's the
phone here's the full file that I ended
up pushing their way they were grateful
and they fixed it right away
Travis was really awesome about that the
github was not they banned my account
all right
they eventually unflagged it but it
turns out it's against github policy to
do pull requests or do anything to a
repository that you don't own even if
you have permission from the owner say I
don't know how that works but it's
really a problem when testing because
even if you're approved pentester going
in doing this thing it's actually
against your policy to do that and then
the social media company kind of was
like yeah that's probably too intrusive
for for a bug bounty but be warned so
this last one was one I found recently
this was a problem with the service
called drone and the problem really is
that the way these built systems work is
you give them a list of steps and like
let's say you give them a docker file to
build each one of those commands like
expose or you know add or any of the
other docker
commands that go into a doctor file
actually end up getting run in their own
instance of a container so spin up a
small container real quick it'll run
just that step in the container and the
next app moved to the next
so if you know you know 50 commands your
darker violet ends up spending on fifty
things but in the build service
proportion of that bill the build goes
the same way so when you're not building
the invention and you're just doing the
portions of the config file it'll go
through each one of those and run that
in its own container as well it should
only share the kernel of the host that's
still in the building
it shouldn't everything that happens in
those containers should not go out and
have anything to do with any of the
other steps but the problem with this
drone stuff is that a shared file system
stuff too
outside of just sharing the kernel and
they were doing that on purpose and that
one of those shared things was the OAuth
token to get into the github account so
you can pull the code down so what
here's here's basically what it looks
like you can see here I'm doing
different steps
there's the cloning of the repo which is
the only step that actually needs that
go out token none of the other steps
need to talk to there and and it only
needs it only needs read access it
doesn't need write access or anything
else but by default that's not the way
its provision that actually has write
access and it can generate tags and then
these are just the various steps that's
been up in containers so once I got
command over that I actually threw back
a shell to myself just to go exploring
and this is how I found it I just found
it in the in the home directory of the
root user in the.net our C file
it was just it has blatantly the content
the github oh I throw in there that
oughta throw in this provision with
access to commit to
so I'm actually able to take that token
and then write back to the master branch
so you can do commits to repos don't
have any permission beyond and it also
allows you to impersonate users so you
can actually use that auth token to be
any user and do any action against any
repo and most of the time that token is
is at an organizational level so
whatever whatever reposed in that
organization have access to drone you
can now do anything to this repo so this
is only the case however for private
repos if it's a public repo they just do
a git pull so that is one thing to note
but I brought it up with them and they
don't really have a solution at this
time as to how to fix it so just
something to be aware of and I actually
wrote an exploit and put that in my
exploit framework which we'll get to now
that's what I was wondering I was
thinking that I was thinking what you
don't need I can't think of a scenario
in the built service why you would want
to have write access to the repository
like why implicitly that service in
github that when you install the drum
service why it would need to have write
access
maybe maybe needs to like maybe that's
the permission it needs to in order to
talk back and say yeah the build
succeeded I thought yeah right they
didn't say something to the effect of
well you could have you could come up
with a API user specific to that and use
that but then you have to I can't
remember what their solution was but it
was one of those things whereas like
that's not going to work at scale it's
gonna work for a single repository but
they're gonna work for an organization
with 300 repos yes just like my question
it seems like a lot of your attacks are
so Caretti and it appears that a lot of
the things that you're gonna show us so
really focus on the fact that it can
guide your environmental variable she
got you to build commands all that stuff
in the same repo and it's wide open so
are you seeing any customers I've got
companies that are focused on kind of
separating that out and using key value
stores to be able to hold their
environmental variable oh yeah
right and weeds like this is very like
if you do it this way you're here so
back into the owner kind of these are
common practices I see a lot in like in
our place of work we we do we have had
to go out of our way to build key
handling services the one I built was
called key handler it's I'm super
creative the title stuff but it that's
what it does and it speaks on behalf of
the service to go leverage you know a
store key but there's no there's like
vault IO that kind of helps with that so
yes like as far as the environment
variable stuff goes there are different
ways to get around it right right but
even like the micro services themselves
are like you know
fault without seeing it
right the history the best history I
remember yeah absolutely
yeah there's a lot of a lot of problems
here the in the entry into this for the
most part I kind of mentioned they I got
further in once I landed so to speak but
the landing part happens through the
github configuration so no ability just
initializing a build process and
honestly I haven't dealt I haven't
gotten too much past that in weaponizing
you know image repository poisoning or
anything like that because I've just had
a lot to do here just exploiting the
actual built service so the jewel that
I'm about to introduce is called cider
it's the continuous integration and
deployment exploiter and it is a
framework for exploiting CI build chains
it leverages github as a attack service
I haven't really integrated any other I
have an integrated gitlab or bitbucket
or anything like that but it easily
could be done to those I wrote the thing
in notes so it has some api's that lend
themselves well I don't want to get
framework but to github itself for doing
for requests you wrote in in what node
nodejs okay yeah it was an experiment I
could have written it in other languages
I'm glad for the lesson in node okay it
handles callback shells really well
actually has a really cool socket
functions that
that lend itself well to handling lots
of sessions I wanted to take the mess
out of forking and making full requests
to repositories because let's say you
want to test something I have to pork
the repo
I have to pull that repo to make my
change push it back up and to make a
pull request to the target repo from my
report repo and then hopefully it works
and if it failed I have to do all that
over again except for the forking
because I've already done there it was a
pain so to take like you know 30 minutes
to test for different things and then as
part of this was I've laziness and what
it this can also do is take a bunch of
repos takes a list of repos and then you
load an exploit and say exploit and it
will figure out if they're the right
kind of repo third drone or a Travis or
whatever and then it will run the
exploit for those I did it for fun I did
it to make the attacking easy I also
feel like even there's not a lot of
awareness here about the potential for
bad stuff to happen and I still want
people to know and contribute and you
know help make these things more secure
because application code is being
deployed in bulk built off these systems
and is similar any similar patterns and
I also wanted to make it relatively
modular so that it could be easy to
contribute to if you had a nine
or something you can kind of look at one
of the other exploits and kind of figure
out how to write your own so it looks
like this this is the command line
that's very command line e like such a
social engineering Joetta or Metasploit
or something I kind of wanted that vibe
to it as basic help menu with help
commands you can add targets so you
would just say right now it would be
it's it's expecting github so when you
type owner slash repository name it's
assuming github I would like to expand
it like I said to other services but
right now this is just what it's doing
so I add a target you can load set
target so you load the target name you
can get some basic information about
what it does and then you hit exploit
and it will dump you know it'll dump
whatever back at you if if it's a shell
an exploit that's supposed to call back
Michelle I actually have a menu written
in there to dude shell handling
otherwise it'll just you know if it's a
recon exploit it'll just grab the all
the recon info and then just dump it
back on the screen to you one of the
features the way I do the reverse shells
which I actually tried to do this and
I'm hoping this sort of catches on and
be really cool is I use in grok which is
a service for forward port forwarding
public requests down locally for when
you're testing a testing code it's a
service that's free I think they have
some sort of paid version for it but
this is a free thing and so what I'm
doing is I'm actually spinning up an
instance of in grok that's listening on
a port like a TCP port and then I have
my callbacks actually calling back to
that and then I tell
down locally and what this allows me to
do is not worry about port forwarding
anymore I don't have to worry about
being on a public-facing web server
anymore for getting called eggshells I
can think of eggshells like here in the
Wi-Fi behind you know I'm tunneling it
through that service so this is like it
in a nutshell but it does all that
implicitly and it'd be really cool if
more services start leveraging this so
you don't have to get on your pen test
box that has a public IP or yeah this is
my disclaimer that I sort of said before
you must be the owner of a repo but you
must ask them to make you an owner
before you can test without getting
yelled at which is you know probably not
going to happen I'm warning you so let's
see here I can't remember if I link this
video or not it did do we have time we
go down time yeah okay then up I'll play
the video of just an exploit
right
oh there we go okay
so here I'm listing the exploits this is
just some basic functionality just so
you know what the tool does I'm gonna
load one of those exploits in this case
the Travis netcat reverse shell so what
this is going to do is pick from my list
of targets figure out which ones are
Travis repos it's going to fork and pull
them down it's going to poison them and
then make a port request so there you
can see I've already the yellow beans
have already forked it and I've already
pulled it down already cloned it and it
found the two of them were Travis in an
over of them they pushed it back up I
should have just cut this part of the
video but it takes a bit for that to get
queued and for the belt to start and
once the belt starts then it won't
trigger those and hopefully throw a call
back shell to me and it will say it
should say the way I have it now is it
will say the eagle has landed and we'll
just arbitrarily pop on the screen just
so I know like peace of mind hey that
shell actually called back but then
after that it'll jump into the sessions
menu and show hop on the shell so maybe
I can just fast-forward
yeah okay let's go back
there you go they both came in at the
same time that was kind of odd all that
times they're staggered because you're
you're leaving it up to the building
queue of whatever that repo is so now I
can jump into missions menu just by
typing session and then whisk my
sessions and it sees that I have two
active shells to those repositories I
select one of them so just select in the
naming and now I'm in the session and
Who am I I'm Travis are now on taking
over that build server now this one is
in the cloud so it's taking over the
actual Travis build server that's about
it that's kind of what it does it also
have a lot of recon in sort of
information gathering sort of exploits
that do the same thing just with a
throwback shell but also I also added
the drone exploited to steal the OAuth
cookies so that's my newest one there we
go
the limitations like I said before are
the belt queues there's a lot of noise
and github so if you're trying to be
stealthy into this it's not gonna be the
case
you're gonna be just like firing off
pull requests after pull requests and
there it's gonna be very loud I actually
thought about adding some functionality
to clean that up so that you could go in
and just go yeah close pull request
whatever
yeah the thing is is once that triggers
and builds and you execute code on the
build server who cares right I mean your
your one step past it's too late unless
you're testing over and over and over as
they tell it give up and they ban you
but the timeouts are another thing I had
to work around Travis implicitly times
out if he doesn't return after if it
doesn't see anything after ten minutes
it shuts down if it sees standard out it
will go up to sixty amendments or fifty
minutes and so I have a keepalive and
the Travis ones and just keep it alive
it just prints keep alive every 30
seconds to keep that alive so I can get
the full hour of time to do whatever I
want with the callback shells others are
different I think the new version of
drone has you know 60 minutes by default
but you can lower it down and but they
all vary and also API request throttling
I'm leveraging the github API which I
think has something like 500 or 5,000
requests per hour is its max so if you
want to really just spam like more than
5,000 it would be 2500 repos because
it's making multiple requests then
you're gonna you're gonna hit that limit
so all things to consider I'd like to
add more CF frameworks everyone seems to
use Jenkins except for me so I'm gonna
be adding Jenkins support I'm gonna
start tackling more deployment services
as well right now I'm really just
focusing on the build services I'd like
to get into repo poisoning and things
like that and there's a new movement
called chat ops which is kind of
evolving in the DevOps community which
is triggering automation and
infrastructure builds from
and other chat programs so that's a new
entry point versus doing a hoe request
you can now make a trigger some of these
exploits through chats so that's about
it these are my thanks to people that
helped and my information here is you
can find me on github and space box with
this arrow Twitter is the same thing and
I have a blog that's occasionally
updated at untamed theory