so if the working title for this talk
was the bastard talk from hell I spit
ball that off of bin with this and he's
like go with welcome welcome
so Oh this was very calm prep of
beginning of the end
yeah yesterday was much like the cookie
scene oh yeah
type cookie you idiot I might've
actually set that more than once oh this
is how I expect things to look like
after all of this is over and there's
the more tea over there
say hi Morty he even has his own little
bat look at him go alright so the
network in a nutshell I'm gonna talk
while you guys read that if you're not
familiar with this particular xkcd so Oh
last year
oh the we'll call it the onion we'll
call it the naan architecture of the
network Oh switches were daisy chained
and it was just in general awful Oh
so I ended up buying some managed
switches and some other things out of my
own pocket
and I'm thinking of taking my side show
on the road there's some regional cons
I'm not really sure what I want to do
with that just yet but uh if nothing
catches fire or gets destroyed this
weekend then I will consider the network
this current implementation of the
network battle-tested
oh so if you find any issues let me know
Oh
changes from last year we moved Ben's
pixie set up to like an actual rackmount
server he was running everything off of
a single laptop
oh it worked but I just didn't feel
comfortable with that oh I already
talked about the switches of bed there's
a mind test server been upgraded from
unreal 99 to 2004 oh there's vehicles
that's about all I know I'm going to
force Ben to come up here and talk about
some stuff regarding you teen 99 the
pekoms later I also spun up some
services like DNS ntp for basically so
the switches know what time it is and I
brought the IRC server that no one
actually used back because I just needed
to scratch that itch
oh this next slide if you guys are gonna
like take pictures with phones this you
need this one
uh because I didn't get around to
printing stuff out so uh dot inkay is
not a real ccTLD I made that up
dot PN is already in use by a little
island nation with like two hundred
people so it's like yeah we're going
thud in cave in Kate by the ways for
Netcom Oh should DNS not work because
let's face it when there's issues it's
always DNS oh those are what you need oh
I didn't have time to put anything about
FTP m'kay in here so I'll elaborate on
that now oh that's essentially kind of
like a pirate box it's a it's a random
router I bought off the eBay with a USB
stick in it feel free to upload download
whatever I seeded it with a copy of
pulgasari and I forget what else I don't
think the Democratic People's Republic
of North Korea it's going to file any
sort of intellectual property claim over
pulgasari
so I'm good just as long as I don't get
assassinated uh so once scored on inkay
I found out about a propane it's kind of
a facelift for the net cough scoring
code or total rewrite whatever
oh I really like it I have to start that
up after this talk actually but uh that
should be going fairly soon
Oh net call for those of you don't know
to CTF for lazy bastards you pop the
boxes put the your name in the team tags
on the index page start scoring points
the attack range is up there don't stray
outside Ben no oh so alright so there is
a Wi-Fi network oh well there's two
SSIDs freak net and Freaknik 5g password
for that is freak net it's just all
lower because laziness oh they can also
sit at any of though the bin tops and
pull that up uh but there's no access
from the hotels like no-man's land into
here we're properly mad at off I believe
but feel free to prove me wrong
Oh welcome in so I'm not covering like
how the Hat time or any of that nonsense
there's probably some workshops or talks
here covering that to be honest I
haven't looked at the schedule I've been
laser focused on making the network
great again and yeah yeah so that said
it really does still level doesn't
matter
feel free to participate leave your
insecurities at the door um so as far as
net cough last year I tried to focus on
fun backdoors weak passwords and in
general hi cbss scores I make things a
little easier after feedback from
brimstone and
and uh we'll see we'll see how that goes
I'm hoping it goes well we'll just again
we'll just have to see what happens
rules are essentially only attack the
IPS in scope don't mess with the network
I can change the rules whenever I feel
like I decide what lives and dies I
think this slide speaks for itself
yo and I don't have any sharp objects
but if I get to that point
paper or plastic so uh this is still
sitting in no false place but uh this
year's prize is the poker gtfo Bible I'm
not doing prizes per day it's just
whoever has the highest score at the end
which I think a little cut it off at
dinner Saturday night this year at what
time because last year it was like a
photo finish
yeah two minutes right yeah that was Oh
so last year we had two guys who tied up
when the cutoff happened so I had a
one-hour sudden-death round with five
copies of Metasploit able to and it was
decided in the last two minutes
the guy who won probably went in his
hotel and got drunk to the point you
didn't know his own name Oh partly
because in the middle of it towards the
end I are in I counselled into one of
the DMT at honed and our end the root
filesystem I like to have fun kids
so the IRC server that probably none of
you will actually use Oh nobody used as
IRC anymore guys are heathens so found
that cards
talking about the CTF I might drop hints
there there might even be some
vulnerable clients connected and sitting
in that channel
hint hint Oh Palin mind test I actually
set up a gateway between mind the mind
test server and the IRC server so if the
chats get passed back and forth oh I'm
not a moderator
I'm not censoring anything oh I'm also
not interested in introducing
vulnerabilities stone as of services on
IRC network so there's none of that it's
it's basically almost EF net this is not
actually the protection reduction of
mind test server oh this is where I was
playing at home I added the globe locks
mod went a little crazy with playing
okay so mind test is basically a GPL
wannabe minecraft oh it's not really
first survival mode it's more for
creative and they have this kind of
strange attitude with oh here's the base
game people can build on it if they want
whatever it works it's spun up have fun
with it oh and by the way some people
have already started building stuff I
did not tamper with the actual world
I built sand blocks up and then let's
just say 8-bit aliens may or may not
have made pixelated crop circles in the
air
okay Ben you might want to start walking
up this way
Oh slap her neck beards yeah you could
just yeah microphone not yet
I'll give you permission to talk I got
three of them so anyways oh yeah been
migrated from UT 99 to 2004 we had a lot
of back and forth I felt like we were
talking in completely different
languages at some points um I actually
told him I wanted to purge the Unreal
Network come like just know Unreal
Tournament what's doing perfectly fair
oh I got to a point where I I untangled
thins Gordian knot serve it so that III
could purge unreal for good and I still
kind of want to but Ben stopped living
up to his full handle and asserted
himself just a little bit I was like
it he can have it
so uh this is Ben still at
[Laughter]
if indeed documentation is you had the
floor okay
so originally years ago how many ever
had land parties at their house you know
it used to it took like 45 minutes or
two hours or three hours you're one of
fixing the computers and try to get me
think right here so six years ago in
Freaknik I decided hey I want to just
have a portable land party where we
could just start it up and it'll work
and that started this process I'm all
self-taught and so I just solved the
problems as they come up and not
necessarily the best way and originally
when I didn't even real 99 does any of
you know what smart step technology is
on Intel processors so Unreal Tournament
1999 this is the part that he wants me
to share is Unreal Tournament up 1999
ran on like a Pentium 3 and we're trying
to run it run it on modern systems which
you would start the game everything
would fly it'd be too fast to move and
it was crazy
so I found this weird script online and
put it in the launcher where I would
flood the CPU with instructions for 4
seconds to get the processor going
really fast and then I would launch the
game and once I launched the game that
way everything was fine
well then sound so then I found this
other script but if you launch the game
in this wrapper it'll start up with
sound and then and it just kind of built
from there so what he's talking about is
I have a script calling a script calling
his room call you script launching
unreal and that was a mess he hated it
so but it worked and it's worked for 5 5
years anyways years yeah and so in and
all that if you're not interested
none of those laptops back there they
don't have hard drives they're all pixie
booted from Linux they all run from one
server it was a laptop last year and now
it runs off a nice HP server and we've
got I think 30 of them up so as many of
you on playing real mind test does
anybody played minecraft in here
does everybody know what minecraft is
yeah so there's a free version I wanted
to explain that there's a free version
of minecraft if you've never played it
sit down try it he's got a server up
it's all built and it's got cool Mario
figures on it and I think that's
infinitely right any more abuse okay
quick show of hands who understands my
pain dismissed
so the breaks this year in work it
worked but that was about it
try trying to do anything to it at all
is you talk about that I told no fault
more than once
we need been the beak voodoo dolls to
give out this year I still want to bend
the meat community doll so every time I
stumble across some weird bit of
previously unknown technical that I can
stand oh so there's two images this year
there's been a special snowflake heart
of maintain a 2000 the abuse is
never-ending
one of us has to die for um so his
special snowflake ut2004 image oh that
is almost impossible ooh it's really
hard to add stuff to oh and then there's
my colleague image which is mostly stock
except I added some IRC clients I've got
chrome working by the way but I let the
USB stick at home so that's tomorrow and
I found a project called refractive so
essentially the workflow is you spin up
a desktop via you install up the
refractive snapshot you get everything
the way you want and then you pull up a
terminal run the refractive snapshot hit
enter a few time
after like 15 minutes it barfs out an
ISO that can then be added to the pixie
box I did it that way partly to get Ben
a means of doing his thing in a way
that's easy to maintain in the future we
still have to have that class session it
might have to get a little percussive
I'm not really sure we'll play that one
by ear so one thing who is here for my
overly caffeinated talk last year okay
so last year I had a freebsd box running
dump cap for capturing CTF traffic this
year I actually bought a couple of
network tabs have all of that fed into a
Dell server all the protocols are
plaintext on purpose mostly because I'm
gonna get the intern the captures and be
like start learning I will publish the
CTF captures though sometime after the
con after I've had some sleep and have
time to sort things out that's pretty
much it oh here's some credits and I
think other than no fault all of the
people in the credits are in here he was
that guy two years ago for those of you
who remember oh there are multiple
pictures of him passed out on the floor
with this he's the intern okay okay yeah
yeah after Ben and after Ben is taken
enough abuse I'm just gonna keep the
abuse on it wasn't me that's the that's
the game plan I am thinking ahead on
something he has drinking and burping
and yeah no okay
you can take you can take bin we can
latch this Basin pretend he's 14 years
old okay that's it
[Applause]