hi my name is mateo campanelli and i'm
going to talk about eclipse uh eclipse
is a better computer for snark with the
universal srs it's actually a family of
community-approved snarks
and this is a joint work with
other researchers from oahu's university
concordium and the indian institute of
science
our setting can be split in three parts
so we care about succinct interactive
zero knowledge snarks i'll tell more
about that we want coming to improve
clearly i'll tell more about that too
and we care about the setting where we
have a universal trusted setup of linear
size
now succinct and interactive their
knowledge
of the following setting imagine you
have a relation r with a public input x
and a witness w for example w could be a
signature or which you want to prove
knowledge with respect to a certain
certain public statement x
then
approver can provide the very succinct
certificate pi
they can be verified by verifier using x
as a
simple using the following syntax we
call this as an arc if it's of knowledge
now
this setting we care about snarks that
are zero knowledge
is the standard zero logic setting so in
the interactive case p
and v are two parties they interrupt and
at the end v is convinced that
some w satisfying certain property is
known
now we're going to care about
a more specific setting well then
calling community proof or cp their
knowledge which is when we trust data
we trust that ps
knowledge of some data that can be
pointed to
in particular what p is going to do is
going to commit here represented with an
envelope
to a witness w it's gonna be out there
and we can
have some guarantees about
what uh will properties
holds for w in
and so now this in particular that we
were proving is both that a certain
property holds so these are but also
that uh
the envelope opens to sweetness w
so we prove the relation in this comment
now why do we care about this setting
there's uh many main different scenarios
anywhere we care about compression and
fingerprinting imagine you have a
hospital holding sensitive health
data
and we want to train
public machine learning model
so what's going to happen
what could happen possibly is that
the data could be committed in a very
sustained way this commitment is public
it's authenticated by the government and
such
and then
we can publicly prove that a certain
training
procedure was executed on them
other settings involve commit ahead of
time which here
uh with this name i'm calling any
setting where we commit to a bunch of
data for example my credentials some
data about me uh my credit history my
passport and so on and then later even
when
after i've committed this i can prove
things about it
and then we also know that cp commit
improve can be useful to obtain very
efficient
composition of proofs
when we have
proof system with different instruments
okay so these settings
settings translate to
clear applications or anonymous
credentials blockchains with privacy
properties
and then in general anywhere we need
data to be referenced in a certain
manner in particular privately instances
so just going back to the syntax of
snarks versus cp's narcs to understand
the difference there's not really any
difference here in this dark setting
we're probably relation r
and
in the cps in arcade we're proving
relation r
and the consistency between w and
certain
public commitments here we have l
commitments and i'm representing with
this dotted sorry dashed lines the
opening relation so i say there's really
no difference but what do we care about
this setting
well
the reason is that
there are
there are some efficiency advantages in
doing that efficiency advantage is the
interoperability properties want to
strive for
in particular we want this augmented
relation this r plus opening to be
efficiently provable and verifiable and
they want these commitments to be
interoperable and as standard as
possible we want them to be
interoperable among proof systems and
standard
is in
they should be parasite commitment with
classic curves or merkle trees and so on
there are unsatisfactory solutions for
example that
can one can straightforwardly come up
with for example use merkle tree or
patterson
inside the relation r and then open that
in the circuit
this issue standard the standard
property but it can be expensive you
need to do all this
in the encoding of the relation there
are lots of tricks that
the community came up with and one of
the most famous one is the one you
played in c cash for the jab jab curve
there's coco backstab for bullet proofs
and these tend to be more efficient but
they're also curve dependent or they're
dependent on different settings so we
care about having this efficiency but
also in generality of sort
now before the last component of our
setting is trust models
real quick
we know that we always have some type of
setup
to achieve
interacting zero knowledge now
in the best possible case this is
transparent we can sample uniform string
and this can work
for that it's basically no trusted setup
and then we have setting when we this
string is structured and it's dependent
on the relation
and then we have settings where
this string depends only on some type of
bound
on the size of the relation
and then can be usually specialized
in um deterministically depending on the
relation and this is the setting we're
going to care about often this property
is also
paired with
updatability
which is very useful
we are now ready to set our results
so
in eclipse we provide new ways to
construct the efficient ship is not with
the universal srs
and our results are generic as possible
and we'll see a little bit more about
them in particular breaking them down we
have a general compiler into cp snarks
with universal srs of linear size so
take your favorite snark
and start with the srs and you can
compile it into a cp snark
and now here i'm saying take your
favorite snarky composite but really
what i mean is take a snarking
information throughout the form of sort
we're going to talk about that later and
you can convert it into c business
then we show how to
concretely
uh apply this compiler
to
three
very efficient and
popular systems up there marlin plunk
and sonic
um and in particular the type of
commitment
that we managed to obtain and they
managed to support is a comparison of
commitment and we managed to do that
importantly because we care about
efficiency in practice
we managed to do that with small
overhead concretely
the overhead is this
so
the first here i'm comparing eclipse to
other works from generic supersnarks
with universal srs
in eclipse in the first row
other results other
words we can compare the two naturally
are the lunar
and the legos in our paper which has
this lego usc
you can see how eclipse obtains
sub-linear proof size here l
is
the number of commitments
we're committing to in the the size of
the opening of each of the commitments
and when i say subliner size
these are these rows refer to the
applications of
this persistent to
constant of the eclipse compiling
another compiler to constant size proof
systems
and you can also see how
we improve on lunar improve size and we
obtain
a trade-off in verification time
in particular
for example lunarchives
better proven to more verification time
in case
they can be a
burden for the very fire
now i'm going to give a little bit more
background about our techniques
and before that i'm going to give more
background about how we construct we
construct
snarks with a universal srs in general
and the way we construct the mutual is
from basically every recipe already
mentioned
we use a compiler from an idealized
information theoretic object so
so we take this information theoretic
object if you're familiar with that pcps
each piece observer holography
holographic processing we take a
cryptograph a cryptographic object say
vector commitment polynomial between
others collision resistance
and we compile them
into an object we can actually use a
snark
so we obtain usually what examples of
what we can obtain with these compilers
are
these constructions already mentioned
sonic mark and planck here i'm just
showing a table to show a little bit
what type of efficiency they achieve
it's not super important right now just
to give
an idea you can see
proof is constant here and the columns i
um
[Music]
i blocked they're they're not for
censorship but they're just because
they're not real
so we can achieve these proof systems
through these compilers and we're going
to tweak this recipe the recipe by which
we shoot them a little bit
in the recipe
is as follows
we take an algebraic holographic proof
which is
it doesn't matter what it is exactly i'm
going to give some information about it
but it's our idealized protocol
and
you can think of it as an interactive
atlas protocol where the prover holds
polynomial encodings to the witness so
it takes the witness it encodes that in
a bunch of polynomials
and then the
it gives oracle access to the verifier
to the evaluations of these polynomials
and the verifier can query
the prover
on
this
proverbs polynomials provided by
approver in different points
more pictorially you have your prover on
the left for right here it says php but
php is a different
idealized protocol that generalizes hp
but you can think of that as
algebraically graphic proof
and the prover puts in the sky these
polynomials
and the verifier sends challenges
sets there are a few details i mentoring
here but this
this is the main idea and q is a set of
queries dot q system queries the very
first mask
and each query is going to look like
that so
each query can be for example p1 x star
equals t star
prove it to me
in in this idealized protocol the
verifier just receives an answer to this
and can check it
but in the real world this doesn't
happen
also one thing i ignore here
uh this is gonna come up later this is
an interactive world but then it's going
to be
the interactive eyes it's going to be
made new interactive through the facial
mirror heuristic
okay so if you have an ahp how do you
compile that to an srs it's not your new
srsnark
and what you need here
is
polynomial commitment this is the main
tool in some other
compilers such as the modeling dark
lunar clone compilers
and
by polynomial commitment we mean a
machinery get that takes a polynomial
and compresses it into
a very short digest and allows to prove
efficiently assessingly into your
knowledge
and evaluation of the polynomial
basically the queries i mentioned about
earlier
but also there are some other caveats so
for example they should the loft and
um
they should allow to prove some current
uh want to prove some guarantees about
the degree of the polynomial we can
ignore these details for this
presentation
the one
popular polynomial commitment we use in
practice is the kcg
commitment which looks roughly like that
now i'm going to introduce some notation
so
i'm going to talk
about
commitments of different types with
different geometric shapes
earlier in the relation i use these
little squares but now i'm going to
introduce
a circle notation to
to denote commitments to
these encodings we're using in the
idealized object
so the squares are the ones that are
input to the relation and the circles
are the one we use new protocol
okay so i mentioned a protocol what is
this protocol what is this recipe we
have our ideological idealized object
and want to convert it into
we take our polynomial commitment and we
use it to make each of these encodings
p1pn of the witness
then the verifier
the hp verifier is going to make some
queries
and we can use the polynomial machinery
to prove these queries are satisfied
nothing super surprising at the high
level there's a lot of important details
to take care of which i'm going to
ignore here
now this is the recipe for stocks in
general we care about cp snarks let's
see what we should do for
so one more thing to mention is shamir
and why is this rs universal before we
move to cp's nerves
and the reason why the structural
reference string ends up being universal
so it's valid for any for any relation
or a certain bond
is because the snark setup itself is the
polynomial commitment setup
which itself just depends on the degree
of the
uh of the phone number
and the polynomial degree is related to
the size of the relation
so next let's look at the actual recipe
for cp snarks
of course we need to change our syntax a
little bit here so i'm
i'm introducing here
the commit the commitment uh c1 to
correlation about and it's opening oc
i'm gonna assume just for for the time
being that there's only one commitment
or the general case there are l
so we know by the earlier recipe that
we can prove
this dash part of the relation
on the top left
so the actual relation but what's left
is to prove the connection between
whatever the program knows
and these commitments that are also the
the public inputs very far so we need we
need some additional pieces
and
remember this
these uh
c1cn over here in the circle in circles
they represent commitments to some
encoding of the polynomial
of the witness so what we can do is we
can show that they're linked
to
the witness whatever string the square
commitments are committed to
so intuitively we can add a proof this
pylink over here an additional
object
that can link
um the commit the committed encodings
circle c1 circle cn
to whatever is in the square c
and so this linking proof this is
basically a specialized narc
proves linking or knowledge of a certain
w such that
the square c opens to some parts of w
is not going to be the whole witness
ci the ci is opens to the polynomials
and calling this witness and everything
is consistent and nice
so this is the object we need but of
course it's not that simple i mean sure
this is what we need but a few
challenges to to solve and this is what
we do in eclipse
um
the challenge one challenge one is we
don't want to depend on the whole
witness when we do this
so the commitment square c
may only be part of the whole witness we
are using in our relation are we paying
for all of it when we are doing this
proof
hopefully not so
in order not to pay for it we showed
that
we can decompose each of these encodings
in an additive manner
in marlin plunksonic the constructions
we care about
and we define an appropriate abstraction
that helps us
um
[Music]
helps us doing this generically
and there's a an important sub challenge
here which is proving
that
whatever um
decomposing doesn't overlap because a
dishonest proverb may
mean doing this decomposition
as we expect
and then the second challenge we saw
is
that um
we want to have actually
a concrete
a concrete proof system for this linking
so it's a little bit like a chicken neck
problem what process are we gonna use
for this this is now we're trying to
build this on cp snark we need the cpu
is not for doing this but
we need the cpu start that's simpler
and what we use
um is intuitively sigma protocols to
prove this relation because everything
you need in each of these
construction it reduces to proving that
a certain commitment c
the
uppercase on the left here that commits
to the whole witness
is basically equal to
the concatenation of the openings or all
these
um seahawk eyes
which are commitments to your parts of
the witness one way to do this is
through sigma particles but then
this requires naively
all of size of the weakness
um
size of each of these weaknesses times
number of commitments and then we can
compress that through
compressed sigma protocol techniques
from mataman grammar 2020 to
logarithmic side
okay and
the
i want to spend a couple words on
the uh
the work that's very close in nature to
eclipse which is lunar they both follow
a similar blueprint of recipe
but lunar is a quite different
pairing-based protocol for linking they
do share some intuitions at some point
but there are some technical differences
in lunar for example doesn't
doesn't use any of the compressed sigma
protocol tricks we use here
and indeed it ends up requires to pay in
communication complexity a communication
complexity that's linear in the number
of components
and there they show different tradeoffs
in efficiency especially verifier time
as i said before and i'm going to
show in the next slide
also lunar uses a more general
formalization this php i
end up mentioning polynomial
or graphic proofs
i believe
but our work can be easily from
formalizing the same word
okay that
leads us to the last slide of this
presentation
with a couple open questions so
so far you can see how
eclipse
and lunar have
these trade-offs in them in efficiency
but what's left
is another problem entertaining
something that's not just sub linear or
logarithmic less actually or constant
size
we get it
an intuitive
avenue to explore there is some type of
recursion but to do that efficiently
maybe we need more specialized tricks of
that it'd be nice to see a
a cp snark with a
general modular cp start with such
such features
and then it'd be interesting to explore
different techniques for this linking
module we have
and or finding other applications for
the ones we have
thank you so much this is my
presentation and if you have any
questions feel free to write to me or
any of my collaborators thanks