of pkc 2022
uh let me introduce uh first embedded
speaker dr dustin murray
uh dr dustin molly is a mathematician in
the mixed computer science uh as a
computer security division or he
received his phd from the university
university of washington in 2009
uh his area of research deals always
repeat curves and all the applications
in cryptography uh dr murray is the post
quantum cryptography project and nist
and today he'll
talk about the latest stages of missed
pqc standardization oh let's welcome dr
dustin
thank you very much for the introduction
hopefully you can see and hear the
slides let me know if not
um yeah thankful to be able to speak on
behalf of nist and our post quantum
cryptography team
it would be nice if we could all be
there together for pkc in in japan it
was
six years ago in japan when
um i went to give a talk that kicked off
the nest post quantum cryptography
standardization process
um it's been a long six years and i
did not know what was in store for me
when we uh started this off
so i titled this talk the beginning of
the end
um sounds a little bit ominous i've been
told
i called it that because we're nearing
the end of the third round of our
process
and at the end of the third round we
will of course name some algorithms that
we will be standardizing so the
competition
is uh getting close to
reaching some kind of a stopping point
of course it's not completely the end
i'll talk about
more work that will continue to go on
um
i will so the outline for my talk i will
talk about what is our pqc
standardization process
what's happened during the last six
years
when will nist announce the results
i'm sure some of you were hoping that
today would be the day and i was hoping
so as well
when i was invited to give this talk at
pkc
it was a goal to try and get our
announcement ready that hasn't quite
happened yet it'll probably be a couple
more weeks
and so we hope by the end of the month
to be able to announce the algorithms
that we will select
so i'll talk a little bit about that and
what the future holds as well
so is motivation i'm sure many of you
are probably aware of this but back in
the 90s there were some very influential
and foundational
research that was being done
that helped spur research into a new
field
of course this refers to peter shore's
algorithm in 1994
they gave a exponential speed up when
using a quantum computer
to solve some problems that we care
about for cryptography particularly for
public key cryptography
shorts algorithm if you have a large
enough computer to implement it
efficiently
could solve two different problems first
it would be able to factor large
integers
and second it could solve the discrete
log problem
of course we know both of those are the
basis for various public key
cryptosystems that we use in practice
another algorithm which is important is
grover's algorithm
it was not
an exponential speed up but it was also
a quantum algorithm that gave a
polynomial speed up an unstructured
search
so both of these algorithms they impact
some of the cryptography that we have at
nist
in particular nist has various public
key cryptography standards
we've standardized
a key establishment that includes
encryption as well as key exchange like
the diffie-hellman
and we also have various digital
signatures standardized
and with schwarz algorithm every single
one of those algorithms in our standards
would be vulnerable to attacks from a
large-scale quantum computer
so we would need to completely replace
those cryptosystems it would not be
enough to simply
increase parameters because you'd have
to increase them so much it would be
just
so inefficient to use them
some of our symmetric key primitives
would also be impacted by grover's
algorithm or
other quantum algorithms
but the impact is less dramatic
we would need to use longer key sizes
use longer outputs from
hash functions
which is doable we don't have to
completely replace the algorithm
so the focus of our project was geared
towards
the public key side first
we needed to standardize new algorithms
to replace the ones that would be broken
and this field has come to be known as
post quantum cryptography or sometimes
quantum safe quantum resistant
cryptography
and the big question is uh well when do
we need to worry about this
obviously we have to worry about it
before quantum computers arrive if we
wait till after they arrive
it'll be too late
um that's the trivial answer
the
other answer that we always give is well
we need these
new cryptosystems long before then
in every presentation i referred to dr
mosca's theorem here
that helps you understand that
you could be at risk from a
threat of a quantum computer long before
a quantum computer is ever built
and the way you imagine that is to just
think about the the case where your
adversary
is able to get a hold of your data and
he copies it and encrypts it or he
copies your encrypted data
so the adversary cannot read it yet but
he simply holds on to it
and then
after a quantum computer comes out they
will get access to your data
so the only way to prevent that
is if before a quantum computer comes
around
we need time to discover new quantum
resistant algorithms to standardize them
get them implemented in products and get
them widely adopted
so you need all that to happen first so
you can use quantum resistant algorithms
and then if you're wanting to keep your
information safe for a number of years
in this case it's x in this little
theorem
you need the number of years to keep
your information safe
plus the number of years for
standardization and getting things
adopted
to be less than a the time it takes to
get a quantum computer
if not then you have a problem
so from our experience at nist with
standardization we've seen some past
crypto transitions
and we know that they are never as as
quick as we would like them to be
there are steps you can take to try and
speed them up a little bit
but getting organizations to switch from
one crypto algorithm to another
it just takes time and it takes time to
standardize and evaluate new algorithms
so that's why it's very important to
begin this work and get it accomplished
well before we have a quantum computer
out there
what is the status of quantum computers
i'm not going to speak much about it
you can see that there are headlines
that give you all sorts of information
different organizations that
are building quantum computers trying to
make them larger
have less errors in them
and
we try and track their progress
i also like to turn to uh some other
experts who have quantified
the probability that we would have such
a computer
so at the global risk institute dr
molska and dr piani and some of their
colleagues
have put out a survey every year where
they've they've asked several experts
what their opinion is about when would
we have a quantum computer that would be
large enough to break
rsa 2048 and 24 year hours
this is their
latest results that they have these were
posted just a month or two ago
and this gives you uh some kind of
estimates maybe there's some
knowledgeable estimates by some people
who
who seem to know a little bit of course
nobody knows for certain
what we can take from this this is a
chart that kind of summarizes their
their main findings
but if you look at that bottom row so
what are the odds in five years uh the
the experts surveyed put it at pretty
low odds most of them were below one
percent
five percent
if you look at the next few rows up if
you go to 10 years and then 15 years
you start to see
more of these people who were surveyed
think that there's a higher chance that
we could have a big enough quantum
computer to threaten cryptography
so maybe all you can take from this is
that you know it's it's certainly a
possibility to have a big enough quantum
computer
in 10 years 15 years 20 years
we don't really know but there's there's
a chance that that could happen
and we need to be prepared with new
crypto crypto algorithms
uh before that happens
so at nist uh we've had our project
going for a number of years um it
started before 2016
which is the first date on this slide
but that was the date we kind of began
some
bigger actions that were more visible
it was in 2016 that we went to pq crypto
and announced the
the pqc
competition-like process
where we would be soliciting crypto
systems from design teams around the
world
to find these new algorithms
since then it's been six years and we've
gone through three rounds of evaluation
we've held workshops throughout that
process
we've issued reports to explain uh the
choices we've made at nist
and where we are currently is the third
round is about to end and then we will
very shortly begin writing
the draft standards that we will uh
put out for comment and publish
so i'll talk a little bit more in detail
about some of these events during these
past six years
back in the beginning
this was a slide that was on my my first
presentation in
fukuoka about the pqc
process that we would be doing
we were calling for quantum resistant
crypto algorithms for new public key
crypto standards
we wanted two different functionalities
because we needed to focus first on the
basic primitives before trying to do
anything more advanced
and we wanted to replace the algorithms
that we had in our nist standards
so that was again digital signatures
and
also encryption or key establishment
we saw our role at nist as managing a
process of achieving community consensus
in a transparent and in a timely manner
nist has done a few of these crypto
competitions over the past few decades
and we think they have worked out pretty
well in harnessing the tremendous talent
that the cryptographic community around
the world has and focusing it on a
certain problem
we knew in many ways that this would be
different than the past competitions we
also anticipated that it would be a lot
more complicated than the aes and the
sha-3 competitions
we're dealing with more primitives uh
post-quantum crypto is a very active
field of research so we knew that there
would be results that would be ongoing
throughout the process
we knew we would be picking more than
one algorithm at the end of this not
just a single one
some of these algorithms come from a
variety of different mathematical
families and backgrounds
we also have to worry about classical
computers and quantum computers
so we knew that this was going to be a
very complicated and tricky thing to to
do our hope was that at the end we would
be able to select some algorithms
that most people would agree were good
choices and would work for the majority
of applications
our evaluation criteria
first we wanted to ensure that the
algorithms selected would be secure
both against classical attacks and
against quantum attacks
for some of the algorithms
that were submitted some of the best
known attacks are classical attacks for
others the best known attacks are
quantum attacks so we need to provide
protection against both
the second criteria
involved performance which is a pretty
big criteria because you can measure
that in a variety of different ways
you can look at
benchmarks in software and hardware on
low end platforms
you can look at what are your key and
ciphertext sizes what are your your
signature sizes
and so all those different ways that you
can measure performance
we wanted to to look at and make sure
that applications and protocols
would be able to use any algorithms that
were selected
besides those two main criteria there
were a number of other properties that
we were hoping to get
as much as possible we want these
algorithms to be able to be dropped in
to existing protocols and networks
without requiring a lot of changes
we know that might not be possible most
of these algorithms have larger key
sizes
but uh we we think that it should work
pretty well
we also wanted things like perfect
forward secrecy resistance to side
channel attacks that's an area that's
getting a lot more focus
and so on and so forth
in looking at security
we needed to define some security levels
or security categories so that we could
compare the different crypto systems to
each other
we knew we would get some based on
lattices some based on codes some based
on other ideas
and as kind of a first way to
to be able to compare them we needed to
try and measure in a rough way how much
security they were providing when they
gave us a concrete parameter set
there's no consensus is the best way to
do this back when we were defining these
i still don't think there's probably
consensus even today as the best way to
measure security um in regards to both
classical and quantum attacks
how we define these categories in a way
that leaves open the relative cost of
the various computational resources
including things like quantum gates
classical gates
quantum memory classical memory hardware
energy
time etc
the idea was that in order to meet for
example say category 1
the best attack
that would be violating the security
definition for a particular parameter
set
should cost more than a brute force key
search attack on a single instance of
aes 128
according to any plausible assumption
regarding the relative cost of the
various computational resources involved
in a real world attack
of course there are different opinions
that can arise this is
subjective in many ways regarding what
constitutes a plausible assumption
regarding the relative cost of
computational resources
and nonetheless this was the the best
definition our team could
come together with and so that's what we
used
and
it's been a little bit easier i think
submitters tended to focus on levels one
three and five because those were easier
to provide arguments for
and if you wanted to argue a little bit
more about providing more security
against quantum attacks you could look
at levels two and four
in relation to
sha-256 and 384
so the
competition
essentially began in december 7 december
2017 we'd given submitters about a year
to design their crypto systems
and
overall we received 82 submissions 69
met our criteria for acceptance
we had almost 300 submitters that were
part of the design teams for these
algorithms um they were from all around
the world that was pretty cool to see
that
and the first round lasted about a year
we held a workshop
and all the teams came and presented at
the workshop
and explained how their algorithms
worked and their their advantages that
they saw
even in the first round we saw a lot of
cryptanalysis right away
from research that was done there was
probably around 25 schemes that
were attacked or broken in some way
we set up the pqc forum which is an
online mailing list where you could
discuss research you could ask questions
we use it for announcements
and just basically all sorts of topics
and discussion related to pqc
standardization
and at the end of one year we selected
the 26 algorithms we thought were most
promising to advance into the second
round
there were some hard decisions to be
made here
there were some good schemes that didn't
make it because we needed to focus the
number down to smaller
in large part our goal was to just keep
the algorithm algorithmic diversity of
the different types of uh
cryptosystems that were submitted
going into the second round
so in the first round we'd seen a lot of
lattice-based and code-based submissions
and so in the second round again the
majority of the algorithms were both
lattice-based and
or or code-based
of course there were also some
multivariate signatures we had two
signatures based on symmetric primitives
and then we had a scheme based on
esogenies of elliptic curves
during that second round it ended up
lasting about a year and a half
similar again
we had a workshop where the teams could
come and present any updates and we saw
new research that was done
there was more cryptanalysis done
even though some of these schemes we
picked to be the more promising ones
there were several of them that were
attacked or broken during the second
round as well
we started to see more benchmarking as
well more performance numbers
we started to see some mergers
there were some schemes that were very
similar to each other and we encouraged
those teams to merge
i think in fact two of the
schemes that are still in round three
are mergers that happened earlier on
so at the conclusion of the second round
we focused
on a smaller number again
we did something different than we've
done in the past where we made kind of
two different categories of algorithms
that would be moving on
uh the first category were finalists
these were the algorithms we thought
would be ready to be standardized at the
end of the third round
and that they would be uh
general purpose type algorithms that
could be used for the majority of
applications
we also selected some other algorithms
that we called alternates that we were
still interested in we still wanted
study to continue on them but we thought
that they might take a little bit longer
in order for standardization or there
was a little bit less urgency
so they could continue being
studied and evaluated but that they
might need a fourth round of evaluation
so we we put it this way so that we
could have attention focused on the
finalists and get a lot of
dedicated research into them before that
they would potentially be
standardized so we had four chem
finalists
uh kyber entry saber classic mcleese and
then we had three signature finalists
dilithium falcon and rainbow
then we had five chem alternates and
three signature alternates
and again the table shows that we
maintain the algorithmic diversity
uh
going into the third round as well
we still had lattices codes multivariate
and so on and so forth represented
so i'll talk a little bit more about
these schemes that are in the third
round
i'm not going to get into great detail
or technical details about them
the three finalists kyber entry and
sabre are all based on what are called
structured lattices
two of them are a little bit more
similar kyber and saber are both based
on module
learning with errors for kyber and for
saber learning with rounding
entry was based on a different problem
that's um it's been around a little bit
longer since entry was proposed in the
in the 90s what's called the entrue
problem
all three of these algorithms have
pretty good performance i'll show later
on that they they're
pretty similar in performance as well
it's likely any of these three would be
able to be used by most applications and
they do all right
because they are quite similar nist
expects to select at most one for
standardization
there were two other lattice chems that
were based on
or that were based on lattices uh there
were alternates we had n true prime
so entry prime also use structured
lattices and they had as a design
consideration
trying to prevent a number of potential
attack surfaces
so that was part of the way that they
looked at their their design
and then frodo chem instead of all these
other schemes using structured lattices
they made the choice to use unstructured
lattices
in case there's any potential attack
that would exploit the structure
frodocam might possibly still be
unaffected by that so there's a security
performance trade-off
their performance their key and
ciphertex sizes are a little bit bigger
and their performance is a little bit
slower than these other structured
lattice themes
um
the other finalist was based on codes
classic lease it's been around for
over 40 years it's seen a lot of
cryptanalysis
without any uh
a lot of significant concrete attacks
that have shaved off any bits of
security
it has an interesting performance
profile very large public keys
um i think they're
they might be the the largest out of the
chems they're in the third round
but they have the very smallest cipher
texts so for some applications that
might be a
potentially useful thing if you can find
a way to work around the large public
keys
we had two other chems that were
alternates that were based on codes as
well
the design teams introduce some
algebraic structure into the codes in
order to try and reduce the key sizes
down
and so they do both have much smaller
key sizes than classic mclease in terms
of the public keys they're both pretty
efficient they're not quite as efficient
as the structured lattice space
finalists but they're not too far behind
either
and nist is interested in them as good
general purpose
algorithms that would complement our
chem portfolio
so we
want to
continue research on them as well
the final alternate chem styke is based
on isogens of elliptic curves
that's a little bit newer idea um it's
been probably only in the last decade
that there's been more attention focused
on the cryptographic applications of
isogenes where we're starting to see a
lot of research being put into that
psych has a
performance profile that has very small
public keys very small cipher text
but as a disadvantage it is slower in
implementations by almost an order of
magnitude in comparison to most of its
uh competitors
so we still have a variety of different
mathematical
problems and security assumptions which
these chems are all based on
if we look at the signatures there's a
smaller number of them
we selected dilithium and falcon both
were finalists both are based on
structured lattices
um
lithium and falcon
again
they're similar but they have some
differences i'll go into them uh later
on both have very good all-around
performance
and so nist is looking at them to see
which would make good algorithms um
to be selected for standardization
there was also two alternate signatures
that were based on symmetric primitives
so picnic is based on a zero knowledge
proof and a block cipher low mc
it has a very interesting design that
was kind of different than anything else
in the in the process
its design has also evolved probably
more than any other algorithm over the
three rounds
as there's been a lot of research into
kind of
how picnic could be improved and improve
its efficiency in particular
sphinx plus of course is based on a
security of hash functions it's a
stateless scheme
security is very well understood it's
been a
we'd say it's a mature scheme and is
been pretty stable throughout the
process
it's a little bit bigger and not quite
as efficient as the lattice based themes
um picnic is the same has kind of
similar performance characteristics
and then finally we have the two
multivariate-based schemes um the
finalists rainbow which we thought was a
little bit better than the alternate
gems
they both have very large public keys
very small signature sizes
and then talking about rainbow and gems
early on in the third round
there were some crypt analytic results
that led to attacks on both rainbow and
gems
and
the designers you know responded to
those in rainbow's case they said well
if you look at the amount of memory
that's required
you know that might come into play
so it raised some doubts about having
confidence in either of their security
of course very recently in the past few
weeks we've seen uh
ward bullions posted a new attack on
rainbow
that
breaks the category one parameters as
titled in the paper uh in a weekend on a
laptop
and that's got a
lot of attention because i think people
know we're close to the end of the third
round and so seeing a finalist get
broken
um
catches their attention
of course during all three rounds we
have seen algorithms
um get attacked or broken
and that's because uh we have a lot of
dedicated research going on and that's
what we expect to see throughout the
process
i'm rainbow had shown some earlier signs
of being um
potentially having some attacks where
earlier on in the third round there had
been some attacks
so this wasn't completely unexpected and
out of blue and out of the blue but it
was still a nice result
to see this come out
and i think it serves as a reminder that
until an algorithm has been completely
evaluated and selected and standardized
you want to be careful not to put it
into products until the standard is done
as a result of some of this
these attacks on these signatures
we only had six signatures in the third
round
and both gems and rainbow had suffered
attacks
about a year ago we asked for feedback
on two things that nist might do to
address
some of these issues
the first thing we put forward is that
we would consider or we wanted feedback
on the idea of standardizing sphinx plus
after the third round even though it was
an alternate and not a finalist
in our report we mentioned it was a very
conservative scheme it had been stable
and was was ready for standardization
we also discussed the idea of
introducing
a new mechanism that nist would start a
process to consider new signature
schemes
after our current process was over
so we asked for feedback on both of
those and i would say we got positive
feedback
if nist wanted to take actions on both
of those different things
so the past few months nist has been our
team has been meeting
very frequently a couple of times a week
to evaluate which of the schemes we
would select
as we were nearing the end of the third
round
we have dedicated presentations on each
and every candidate
looking at the evaluation criteria
specifically
looking at the security looking at the
different uh parameter sets that they
had their security proofs the best known
classical and quantum attacks
we looked at all the performance numbers
that we could we could find
it's easier to measure their the size of
the parameters the p sizes and so on but
we were also looking at efficiency of
key gen
encryption decryption signing verifying
both in software and hardware on on many
different platforms how much memory they
used that kind of thing
and then we looked at particular
algorithm and implementation
characteristics you know were there ip
issues do they have decryption failures
has there been side channel work done on
them
how good is the documentation that the
team turned in
what papers were published in dealing
with them what was the discussion on the
pqc forum about them
and so we've had a lot of
good uh discussion
um as well as on the pqc forum we've
seen there have been a lot of external
discussion as well
we also had various presentations
comparing some of these algorithms
against each other each other so we
could make uh some of these tough
decisions that we'd have to make
for lattice chems our main decision that
we're focusing on
was selecting between kyber and true and
saber
as i said they're they're quite similar
and we expected to
only need one of them
to
be our primary go-to algorithm
that would work for most applications
similarly for lattice signatures
our main decision that we were focused
on was looking at dilithium and falcon
for all of the other algorithms
when we were deciding
it kind of came down that each one was
kind of its own competitor
and we were looking to see would it
advance or would it be selected for
standardization
based on its own merits um so there was
a lot of kind of individual decisions
there of course they're in somewhat in
competition with each other in various
ways but the particular algorithm
the decisions were a little bit
different than those two main decisions
that i talked about up there
so giving a little bit more info on
kyber and true and saber
again this isn't super detailed but just
a little bit more
as i said kyber and sabre are based on
similar
security assumptions both are based on
module learning with errors
in saber's case learning with grounding
while entry was based on a different
problem
all three were constructed from public
key encryption schemes and then using
some type of fujisak akamoto transform
to convert it into a chem and then they
were able to have
security proofs
dealing with industry
indistinguishability against chosen
ciphertext attacks
kyber and sabre both had decryption
failures and true does not
um there's different choices that these
algorithms made in their design
so kyber and sabre use modules with a
cycloatomic ring that's a power of two
whereas entro uses a sickle atomic ring
with a prime power
there are other further differences of
course when you dig into the
specifications
but you can see that there's a lot of
similarities as well as some differences
i put two charts up here just to give
you some idea about the performance
again these are not intended to be
you know we made our decision based only
on these two charts kind of thing but
just to kind of show you how do they
compare relative to each other
on the left the chart shows
the bandwidth the public key size plus
the ciphertext size
and it's grouped into category one
category three and category five
you can see a category one they're all
pretty close together uh similarly for
category three
i mean category five entries key sizes
look to be a little bit higher but they
they're
still relatively comparable
on the right i put a chart that looks at
their performance in software on an
avx-2 processor
and this takes into account their
bandwidth as well as their efficiency in
terms of cycle counts for key gen
encapsulation and decapsulation
since performance
in the real world would probably take
both metrics into account
um again you see all three if you were
to look at the numbers they're very
comparable and would would probably do
quite well compared to current crypto
algorithms that we use today
and saber tend to be a little bit more
efficient based in this graph than and
true
but again all three would probably work
just fine for most applications
if we look at a similar type of chart
for dilithium and falcon
again they're both lattice-based but
there are some different design
differences
dilithium is based more on module lwe
while falcon was based on module sis
over entry type lattices
that lithium uses the idea of fiat
shimmer with the boards
it uses the simpler uniform sampling
falcon's a little bit more complicated
it uses hash than sine with a gaussian
sampling algorithm that it's a little
bit more delicate
in particular their key gen and just
overall implementation
is more complex
and uh
potentially in some you know low
resource environment
a falcon uses floating point arithmetic
with high precision and some complicated
data structures
and that might be a challenge in some
cases
on the other hand we'll see that falcon
has some performance advantages down
below
they both use rings of the same type
against stick atomic extensions or with
powers of two
they both had security proofs against uh
existential unforgiability
and comparing them you can see uh falcon
on the left our our chart that measures
the public key plus the signature size
falcon is noticeably smaller than
dilithium it's it's got just a lot
smaller
key sizes and signature sizes
on the right if we include
the performance
on again a software and avx2 machine
largely because of the
bandwidth
you know falcon again comes out ahead so
there are some trade-offs to each one
as we had to consider our decision we
had to carefully consider those
and then a factor which
has played a part in a lot of our
discussion both internally and we've
seen on the pqc form as well is the
issue of patents and ipr
um this played a larger role than i ever
anticipated when we began the process
um at the beginning we we had this
ip statements that each team had to
submit in where their submission team
let us know of any patents that they
held or that they were aware of
our call for proposal said we didn't
object in principle to algorithms that
have patents where technical reasons
justify the approach
but nist would strongly consider any
factors which would hinder adoption in
our evaluation process
we know that when there are ipr issues
people are less likely to adopt those
algorithms
and one of our goals is to get these
post-quantum algorithms widely adopted
to help protect against uh you know
future attacks from quantum computers
so this was a
obviously a big consideration
it's also very complicated area i'm not
a lawyer no one on my you know our pqc
team at nist is a lawyer
um
and
is
something we've had to learn a little
bit about we've counseled with our
artist lawyers that we have who have
helped us on this but they are not
crypto experts so we have we've had to
kind of work together
we are actively engaging to try and
resolve known ipr issues of course there
were some we knew about it initially
because the submitters had patents on
their own algorithms
we also became aware of third-party
patents where outside
parties and organizations held patents
that were potentially relevant to some
of the algorithms that we were
considering standardizing
so we've been in talks with these
parties to try and resolve them
happy to say we've had some
positive steps in the right direction
i'd say
i don't have any concrete details that i
can give out at that at this point yet
but um
i'm happier than i was several months
ago that we've been able to
get things going in the right direction
it may not be possible for nist to
resolve all ip concerns because we can't
control you know what what other parties
do
so this was
something during the third round that
was definitely a large factor
and we're very much committed to getting
a algorithm that will be able to be
widely adopted
so
okay so that is kind of
what has gone on the past six years um
let me talk about the timeline in the
future from here now
the third round will end literally any
day now
we have made our decisions we have
written our report
it is undergoing the kind of the process
that we have to go through at nist to
get it reviewed and approved by various
people before we can publish it
my guess is it will still take a couple
of weeks i'm hopeful that by the end of
the month
we will be able to announce
which algorithms we will standardize
what will that announcement include
it'll include the finalist algorithms
that we would like to standardize
uh it would also potentially include the
alternate sphinx plus even though it's
not a finalist we have said that it's an
algorithm that we
could potentially select for
standardization at the end of the third
round
and
um
we'll of course have our report to go
along with it
a report we've worked harder to make it
a little bit more substantial than our
last report so that's taken more work
our announcement will also include the
candidates that are advancing to a
fourth round for evaluation
that fourth round will
be similar to our previous three rounds
it'll probably end up being a little bit
longer because we'll be doing um
we'll be drafting the standards at the
same time and so we'll our attention
will need to be um
working on that as well
uh the algorithms in the fourth round
will be to help us diversify our
portfolio from the algorithms that we
will select for standardization
it's likely we'll hold a workshop
sometime in the fall or the winter of
this year we haven't completely
got the details on that
and our goal is to release draft
standards for public comment later on
this year or early on in 2023
we want to get these quickly done
we'll put them out for public comment
we'd encourage everyone to take a look
at them
give us comments provide us suggestions
we'll then revise those in and fix
anything that needs to be fixed
and our goal is to have the final
standard published by 2024
so what does standardization mean uh
our current algorithms are standardized
in a couple of different documents
in a fips which stands for federal
information processing standard and some
sps which stand for special publication
so we will write documents that
completely specify how to implement
and instantiate you know the algorithms
selected for standardization
in doing so we will work with the the
candidate teams
to help make sure we've understood it
correctly and any details that need to
be included in the standard which might
not have been in the
specification
we'll need to select specific parameter
sets to include and
and give a uh you know describe what
security strength they are providing
if we need to seek feedback from the
community on any of these topics we will
of course do so probably through the pqc
forum
and then as i said we'll write those
documents and we'll put them out for
public comment as we always do with our
nest documents
we'll make whatever
revisions that we need to based on the
feedback and then publish them for you
so people begin can begin implementing
them and putting them into their
products
we'd again encourage everyone that we
want to
not put them into products until the
standard is completely done
there could be small changes from the
specification to the final standard
there won't be any major changes but
small things might need to be tweaked
i mentioned that we'd also have a
process for new signatures because we
have a just a smaller number of
signatures in the third round
so nist
we will also issue a new call for
signatures
shortly after we make our announcement
we wanted to get our announcement done
before writing the call for signatures
but we will be asking for
you know signatures like we we did
before um the deadline for submission
will probably be sometime around january
so that people have plenty of time to
design these uh signature schemes
this process will be a lot smaller in
scope than what we've done the past six
years
we're not looking to recreate everything
again
our main goal is we want to diversify
our signature portfolio
we're quite happy with having a good
structured lattice-based digital
signature
um but what we want to do is have
another general purpose digital
signature that is not based on lattices
so we want to get another candidate or
candidates that will fulfill that need
there could be other things that we are
interested in for example a signature
scheme with very short signatures would
very likely be of interest to us
so we'd encourage if you have questions
about that contact us and we can help
you know if
we're interested in you know in your
idea or feel free to just submit it
anyway
these signatures will be on a different
track a different progress than the
candidates in the fourth round the
fourth round will be going as soon as
the third round ends um
this uh
on ramp as we often call it won't begin
until probably almost a year after the
third round ends
and these algorithms you know they they
were just beginning the process they
will have to go through a number of
years of evaluation before
they could potentially be standardized
so obviously the more the mature the
scheme is submitted the better but we
will still need to carefully analyze
these algorithms
and so they'll be on kind of a parallel
track
from our current process
there are many important research
challenges
there's been a lot of work in these
areas during our three rounds of
evaluation and a lot during the third
round in particular
but i would say these uh these issues
are also not
settled yet there's a lot of work that
could be done internally in this we're
working on this and we hope to encourage
people to look at a variety of different
topics as well
i don't think i'll go through and talk
about any of these in detail but
they very much matter and we want to
still get the answers to some of these
questions
a nist is one of many standards
organizations we're aware of other
standards organizations and we've been
communicating and collaborating with
them
it's been good to see we've been pretty
united at focusing our attention
in it mostly in this process so that we
could have
all the cryptographers participating in
it
but there are other organizations like
ieee p-1363 they had some of the
earliest lattice-based schemes
standardized
the ietf has standardized some stateful
hash based signatures uh nist then later
also standardized lms and xmss
we've also given some other uh
doing some other work in post quantum
cryptography etsy has released various
quantum save crypto reports that have
been very useful for organizations
there's expert groups that have made
recommendations for particular
algorithms
iso has done a study period on quantum
resistant crypto
and we've also been in contact with
other countries that have been working
on standardization
activities
and
so we're grateful for this we hope this
continues
in conclusion um
i'd say the beginning of the end of our
pqc
process is is here you know we're at the
end of the third round where we are
seeing some of the light at the end of
the tunnel and we will select some
algorithms for standardization
it's not the complete end as i've
described this work will continue we
have the fourth round of evaluation that
will continue
and we'll have more digital signature
schemes that we'll be looking at in the
future
so we hope you continue to participate
we are grateful for everybody's efforts
we certainly cannot do this without all
the work that all of you have done
both in industry and academia
i'm doing performance benchmarking
security analysis real world experiments
um it's truly a
good to see
that we're all working together on this
so of course for more information you
can see our web page and i'd encourage
you to sign up for the pqc forum if you
haven't
that's where most of our announcements
in the discussion relevant to this is
going on
so again thanks again for the invitation
to talk and i'd be happy to answer any
questions as well
oh let's not go let's talk i'll speak
okay uh so
please raise your hand if you have any
question
is there any question from audience
uh questions
when you announce the the the winners
will they're also announcing which
parameter sets or will be tweaking some
parameter sets to be more conservative
than what we're in submissions or will
that be uh any such things be
pushed off to later in the review
process
yeah with our announcement i don't we
are not picking the the parameter sets
yet so that'll be part of the
the the work after to select which
parameter sets would be standardized
um i think our intention is to not have
a lot of tinkering we want the
evaluation that's gone on during the
three rounds to matter
but if there needs to be new parameter
sets that's something that we might be
open to we'd probably discuss that with
the community
but no we won't be announcing specific
parameter sets with the announcement
so easy okay
okay then press tab
my question's really about quantum
analysis i feel like there's been a lot
of classical a lot of effort by by
researchers from the crypto community on
in terms of classical
cryptanalysis
i haven't
got much of a sense that there's been a
lot of input from people outside the
existing crypto community so people from
quantum algorithms
um and even even the the five security
levels
i still don't know if if i really
understand what it means what's a
quantum attack on aes for example so do
you feel like there's really been enough
scrutiny from outside our community into
the quantum hardness
we would of course like to see more um
that's it's a good point you raised that
it's hard to bridge the gap between
different communities of interest
we try to include more people that are
experts in quantum algorithms we have a
few people on our team that are
are in that field and
um
from our perspective there's been enough
that we can select some algorithms for
standardization we would love to have
more research and learn more
but um
yeah that's that's going to be a
challenge it has been and will probably
continue to be
so is it okay then
professor bernstein please
it's actually the other part of it tanya
lange
that's when you mentioned in the
comparison of the lattice finalist scams
the speed comparison and the size of the
public key comparison but you didn't
comment on security comparisons
um could you say something about them
sure yeah so they're based on different
problems and in their specification um
documents each of the teams presented
arguments and made claims about the
the precise amounts of security that
they were given
um
nist is
happy with the the security discussion
of all three teams and all three could
be
selected for standardization we're
confident enough in their security that
any of the three could be selected based
on their security
um
i'm not sure if you're wanting
more details or if there's a specific
aspect of that um
yeah what i'm puzzled about is that
you're saying now that the uh parameters
are not going to be specified
as part of the announcement but you
you're saying say andrew has larger
public keys now they're also aiming for
more bid security
and so if the um if the exact security
is not actually part of the evaluation
or part of the decision now
then i don't quite see how the
comparison of key sizes would matter or
the speed comparison so
what did you fix and what did you
consider variable in that
well
we're not announcing them uh we have
thought about
the specific parameter sets that would
like
would likely be standardized but we also
wanted to have discussions with the
submission teams and what they felt
um what they would recommend some of
them included that discussion in their
in their documents
but we did we did look at the existing
parameter sets and the amount of
security that each parameter set was
providing and that was factored into our
decision
um
but on the other hand yeah we also
were not quite ready to select the
parameter sets because we wanted to talk
with the submission teams and perhaps
with the cryptographic community as well
so is it okay
so i got a question like okay
i had a question that i typed into zulip
it's rather long
it's a little bit theoretical but uh
because the breaks against rsa and
discrete logs are still a little bit
theoretical themselves perhaps it's
appropriate
a long time ago i proposed a system
which would be secure if either
factoring or discrete logarithms was
hard
and that paper was kind of rendered
obsolete by shore's algorithm which
attacks both but i was wondering if you
saw any proposals that tried to base
their security upon
two dissimilar
algorithms or if there was any work on
universal composability during in any of
the proposals
yeah so that's a good question um if i
think about the schemes that were
submitted
none are coming to mind that that seem
to be kind of designed with the idea of
combining two different security
assumptions
maybe there is and someone could correct
me
i think some of the discussion in that
direction has been that
you could standardize a post quantum
scheme and combine it in some way in
some kind of hybrid fashion with another
scheme
post quantum more classical
as a way of you know hedging your
security and as a way of transitioning
to these new algorithms
so in order to break your
your hybrid mode or whatever you'd have
to break each of the different
components
so we have seen some of that but i'm not
aware in individual schemes
that that was addressed too much
some of the schemes did talk about a
little bit
i can think of psych in particular since
they use a lot of elliptic curve
cryptography in their implementation
talked about how there would be a
natural synergy to combine it with
an existing elliptic curve algorithm and
you could reuse some of the
elliptic curve algorithms
and um the two would work well together
that way
um
and then i forget there was a second
part of your question i i don't think i
remembered what that was
no just whether there was any
um
effort to address this question about
you know we okay so maybe we like
lattices this week and we like you know
short vectors we like uh factoring one
week
elliptic curves another week but we
don't really have any evidence for any
of these problems being secure so i was
just sort of wondering why we don't try
to if we're really seeking the long-term
security for something why we don't
propose something that would compose
multiple problems which are apparently
dissimilar
yeah
it's easier to analyze each individual
component and then try and put them
together i would think and
if you're trying to build
an algorithm design an algorithm that
would be competing against others for
this process you probably wanted to not
make it
you know you wanted to have it be
smaller key sizes be more efficient and
combining more than one algorithm would
potentially hurt that
um
yeah
thanks
okay
um
is there any other question
oh there was a question about whether
your slides would be available and i i
saw there's a powerpoint but if you
could convert it to pdf i could put it
on the web sure yeah i can send it to
you
okay
okay here here's my question let's
speak again
thank you
so as a talking about appreciation we
will be sending uh doctor uh the summary
uh
commemorative uh plug and other
other mementos
okay and
let me showed
uh that block
so this way we sent to all uh dusting
the
doctor dashing movie uh as well as other
uh
memorative uh mementos so thank you very
much
thank you very much
okay uh let's have a blank
and we will start the next
session
from