hi everybody my name is abita hawk and
today i'd like to talk about our paper
logarithmic size linkable threshold ring
signatures in the plain model i bolded
threshold in the title because that's
what i want your main takeaway to be
how we achieved the threshold
part one background and contribution
let's start by explaining what a ring
signature is
in the ring center setting a party wants
to send out an authenticated message
anonymously on behalf of a set the set
is known as a ring
anybody can join the ring so let's
suppose we have these three characters
alice bob and charlie
alice is going to join by publishing her
verification key vka and keep ska to
herself and similarly bob and charlie
can
publish vkb and vkc and keep skb and skc
to themselves respectively
now this ring of verification keys is
publicly known
so at the time of signing a signer can
pick their ring
and they can sign a message
and
send it over
now any verifier can check that it came
from somebody within that ring but they
can't tell exactly whom
that leads us to our security properties
a ring signature should be unforgiable
meaning that you really do need to have
a secret key within the ring
to produce a signature
and a ring signature should also be
anonymous meaning that no external
observer can tell from whom that
signature came
and notice that
with an external observer that can be
anybody that's not in the ring and as
well it could be non-signers in the ring
so except for process of elimination
where they know that it's not them they
can't tell which signer it was
now in some cases we don't just want a
one out of n ring signature but we want
a threshold t out of n ring signature or
thring signature
one way to do this is by having parties
interact so let's say alice and bob want
to sign a two out of three
string signature
well they both know their secret keys
ska and skb and they can use them and
interact with each other to produce a
signature where a verifier believes that
at least two people must have signed
now any
party external to the ring cannot tell
which two
people it was it could be bob and
charlie or charlie and alice they don't
know
and charlie of course does know because
he knows it wasn't him
but in a bigger ring wouldn't be able to
tell which members it was
so that's the first way to get threshold
ring signatures interaction between
parties
now
even though external observers cannot
tell which parties signed
at least the signers do have to know
each other's identities
somehow alice had to find bob
and
let him know that there was this message
she wanted to sign and he had to agree
to work on it with him
in some cases like voting or a petition
where the message is sensitive
signers might not want to have to seek
out
other people to join their message
maybe they should be able to just sign a
message by themselves and then other
people can add themselves as they go and
we can remove the interaction
that's this concept of intersigner
anonymous string signatures
so
this is
the way that we got thresholdization in
our paper with intersiner anonymity and
we did it by forcing our ring signature
to have a deterministic part to it
with that deterministic part
signers could just sign by themselves
and a verifier could check to see if
they came from different people without
revealing their identities
so you start with this deterministic
part
and then a verifier given two signatures
just checks if that part is equal
for example
let's say that a verifier sees a list of
five signatures
then he can parse any two of them
and he can check the determinant part
and see
if that part is different or if it is
the same and he can conclude then that
it came from different or the same
signer
now
one thing to note is that we limited
this
so that the signatures have to be on the
same message and ring
this makes it a little bit different
from linkable ring signatures which some
people in the audience might be familiar
with
where if you sign once a linkable ring
signature once you're linked forever and
you
can and a verifier can always check if a
signature came from the same person
so in some sense
what we've done is more fine-grained
than linkability in fact we can add
linkability to our
base construction easily and
figure out what scope we want signers to
be linked on
so now that we understand ring
signatures let's talk about their
security properties in a bit more depth
the adversary is going to ask the
challenger pretend that's me a lot of
different kinds of queries
after seeing
all this kind of information he's either
going to produce a new signature
which thus trying to produce a forgery
or he will ask for
two honest signers and
the challenger me will flip a bit and
send him back a signature on one of them
and he has to guess which one it is if
he can he breaks anonymity
now in either case the adversary is
going to have similar kinds of
oracle queries that he can make to me
and those kinds of oracle queries should
mimic the real world behavior that ring
signatures have
one thing i want to point out is that
because ring signatures are an open
setting remember everybody could just
produce their verification key
themselves and just publish it the
adversary could even be a participant
in the ring and
that's why it's important to be careful
about how we capture the kinds of real
world actions we think an adversary can
take
so the four different kinds of queries
are these oracles that we've defined to
have a truly active adversary the first
one is osin so here the adversary is
going to ask
for signatures on honestly generated
keys
for ok gen the adversary can ask for new
keys to be added to the ring honestly
o corrupt means he asks on an honestly
generated key for the secret key
associated to it
and finally
the most important one for us is a
register or o-reg
where the adversary actually will
produce his own key by himself and send
it out
this is important
to
the open setting of ring signatures and
it captures the fact that the adversary
can actually maliciously produce a
public
key
now that we have talked about ring
signatures and their security properties
in general we can talk about our
specific construction and proofs
we'll start with the building blocks
there are four building blocks for our
construction
the first one is somewhere perfectly
binding hashing or spb
two public key encryption or pke
three verifiable random function or vrf
and four non-interactive witness
indistinguishable proof or newy
i point out here that spb pke and niwi
come from a template of a ring signature
scheme that we followed from bacchus at
all from eurocrypt 19. our novelty is
the use of the vrf to get that threshold
with intersiner anonymity and led to us
having to use different proof techniques
let's explain each building block i'll
start with verifiable random function
a verifiable random function is like a
pseudorandom function but you can
generate a proof what do i mean by that
well a pseudorandom function produces an
output that's pseudorandom
per the name which means that nobody can
tell whether that output is truly random
or it really came from this prf
a vrf has the same thing
but there's an additional proof that the
owner of the secret key can use to prove
that that
value really did come from the vrf
like aprf there's a secret key
but there's also now a public
verification key that anyone can use
with the value and proof to believe that
it really did come from that vrf
this is
a little abstract
the
point i want to get across here is that
there is public verifiability of a
function that produces random looking
outputs
the next building block i want to talk
about is public key encryption
i think most people in the audience are
actually familiar with public key
encryption but there is one property
that i want to point out if
there are multiple public keys and
there's a cipher text that has been
encrypted on one of them
people cannot tell
whose public key was used to create that
cipher text i have here alice and
ciphertext comes from her public key pka
and bob cipher text coming from his
public key pkb even with a known input
nobody can tell whether it came from
alice or from bob except for they
themselves who know their secret key
this is a property known as key privacy
the next building block is somewhere
perfectly binding hashing which really
just looks like a merkle tree
you take the
ring which is known and you can write it
as a
vector and then hash it up
as if you were in a tree until you get
to the root
and there's the hash value and the
hashing key that goes along with it
the difference between summer perfectly
binding hashing and a merkle tree is we
do have this property where
at
one index it really has to be that case
that we are bound to whatever that value
is that's where that name somewhere
perfectly binding comes from
the last building block i want to
explain is the non-interactive witness
indistinguishable proof so the
non-interactive part means that our
prover alice can just
pick her witness and statement and she
can send out a proof in a single shot
without having to interact with any
verifier
the witness indistinguishable part means
that even if there are multiple
witnesses for which the relationship
with the statement holds
that the verifier cannot figure out
which witness it was that the approver
used even if they know what the
witnesses are
one final thing
the newest that we're concerned with
have perfect soundness which means you
can't prove a false statement
i think
we are now ready to start talking about
the construction
remember that a signature construction
has
three algorithms key generation sign and
verify we have not put them together yet
we only have building blocks but now
we're ready and we'll start with key
generation and i'll start explaining
what sine looks like
the key generation uses the pke and vrf
the
secret key is the secret key of the vrf
and the verification key
is the verification key of the vrf and
the public key of the pke
so
remember anyone can join the ring so
they can create these values on their
own and just publish that vk
then
at the time of signing
the signer will start by doing this
they will use their secret key to
evaluate the vrf on
their message
this is a little bit simplified but they
get a value and a proof
then they'll use the verification key
and
they will
encrypt the proof of the vrf
inside the ciphertext
and
because the value is pseudorandom and
the ciphertext hides which key it is
nobody can tell which keys were used to
create these two values
we're getting started with a signature
let's let's continue
now you can't just use any old
verification key you do have to prove
membership in the ring so the niwi is a
new proof
that
the ciphertext encrypts a valid vrf
proof under some verification key in the
ring and the proof
verifies for that value under the vk
and then finally
we need to show that there exists an spb
opening showing that that vk is
consistent with h and h k
so our signature so far it looks like
this v
c t h and h k
none of this
reveals the signer and it
and the membership proof
with the spb opening shows that that
verification key must be in the ring
so we're almost there but this is not
quite enough
now
if i just gave you v c t h and h k
and gave you a proof that everything was
consistent
this
seems like it should work out
but we need something more for our proof
of anonymity we need to be able to swap
between the witnesses so there's one
more thing that we need to add
i told you before that the spb binds the
signer to their index they have to prove
that h and h k are consistent as part of
the new e
instead of just doing this once the
signer can do it twice and bind
themselves to another index that is not
his own
so that gives you h prime and h k prime
then
instead of having a newbie proof that
just does everything i told you with all
these values being consistent the signer
could
create the same proof but for another
index
at j
well he can't actually do this if he
doesn't know the secret key for j so
it won't be true so what's actually
going to happen is the new is going to
be an or proof where either everything
is true for some index i or it's true
for index j
so the entire signature ends up looking
like v c t h h k and then v prime c t
prime h prime h k prime where the proof
pi
says that either the first set of values
is true and consistent or the second set
of values is true and consistent and
only one of those branches has to be
true in an or proof
so the knee reproof is actually this
relationship r
uh with v k i and r with v k j
the reason that we did this is we needed
to be able to do the anonymity proof
where we swap between signers so
remember the adversary is going to
request
a signature on one of two signers he'll
pick index i and index j he'll get back
a signature on one of those signers and
he has to decide from whom it came
in the proof of anonymity we show that
we can swap between an honest signature
for sign or i and an honest signature
for sine or j indistinguishably thus
proving anonymity
and the way that these swaps are done
are going to be via hybrid
so
at the beginning with an honest
signature from signer i v i h i h k i
and c t i those are all true whereas
everything from
j is false and on assigner would just
use random values there
then slowly with hybrid changes we start
making everything true
but we get to this point where
v j
the v rf associated with sine or j is
still false and something is going to
happen
that makes it so that we can't make it
true
if both of those branches are true then
it's actually
possible for an adversary to distinguish
that
type of signature from the previous
hybrid and the reason for that is if
both of these branches for vki and vkj
are true then that means both of these
vrf values really did come from the vrf
which means they're deterministic and
they're constantly put together in this
way
an adversary could for example just
request signatures on all signers and
see
that
these
signers i and jay were always somehow
together and
that would not be
indistinguishable from a real signature
so we have come to a problem
those hybrid changes
are not going to work for us
the other thing you could do maybe
is could you make both branches false
and make sure that vi and vj are both
just random values
well
not really because the knee we has
soundness and so if both branches are
false then the knee we overall will be
false so we need some way of making both
branches for vki and vkj false while
still making this overall new true
we are going to do that by adding
one more or into our new
to make it so that the branch for signer
i and for or j can be false at the same
time we're going to add one more branch
f is a one-way function
and the relationship we're going to
ensure is rf which is f of ski is equal
to skj
so our niwi is going to be
rvki or rf or rvkj
let's look at the hybrids
in the original
signature we want to pick signer i and
so the branch for signer i is true while
the remaining two branches for cyan or j
and rf are false
overall the neewee will be true
then
at the end we want sine or j's branch to
be true while the other two branches are
false
we want to hop from real signatures from
sine or i to real signatures from sine
or j using the relationship f of ski is
equal to skj
we'll make two changes
we can make the relationship rf
true
and then we can make the relationship
for our vki be false
overall the new we will still be true
then moving forward
we can make
the relationship for vkj be true as well
and then in the final step we'll make
the relationship for rf false
this gives us a real signature from
signer j
all of these steps are indistinguishable
all the changes that we make for the
signers
themselves have to do with how the vrf
works or the public key encryption and
the relationship for rf making that true
or false is indistinguishable because
one-way functions are hard to invert
but now we have a problem
unforgeability can't be as strong
as we would like it to be because a
register
is now trivially going to make it so an
adversary can forge
even though honestly generated keys will
never have this relationship if we allow
the adversary to register his own keys
he can easily make it so that he picks
two keys such that f of ski is equal to
skj and then he would be able to create
as many signatures as he likes so
because of our insistence on being in
the plane model and having logarithmic
size ring signatures we lost our ability
to have a register
let's conclude why does our work matter
well it gives feasibility of a
logarithmic size threshold ring
signature in the plane model even though
it has weakened unforgeability
and it does give us one resultant
research question which is can we do a
compact ring signature with malicious
registration and still be in the plain
model
um thank you for your attention if you
would like to know more about our work
you can look us up on eprint or you can
email me if you have any questions
thanks