so hi my name is damiano and now i'm
going to present a giant project with
peter shaw titled multi-party
multiplication triples for speeds from
ring alpian
so the main contribution of our work is
the design of an actively secure npc
protocol for the generation of
authenticated pillar triples and the
novelty is that this construction
achieves sublinear communication in the
amount of generated material
so i will start by explaining what speed
is so speeds is an efficient multi-party
computation protocol for computations
over a large prime field f and it
achieves active security by relying on
the online phase of length phase
paradigm specifically we have this input
pre-processing phase called offline
phase
where
the parties generate large amount of
correlated material and later on in the
online phase the parties use this
correlated randomness to compute the
output of their function in a secure way
so without revealing any information
about the inputs
thanks to this paradigm the complexity
of the online phase is really low
so
the main type of correlated material
that we generate in the offline phase is
called beaver triple or multiplication
triples and as the name suggests these
are needed to compute multiplications
specifically we need one multiplication
triple per multiplication gate
and so we need a lot of them and usually
the generation of these is rather
expensive so which is exactly a beaver
triple as i said at the beginning we are
working over a large prime field f
and suppose that n is the number of
parties so bigger triple is a random
tuple of secret shared elements as the
one that you see on the screen so we
have x and y that are uniformly random
over the field and then we have a secret
sharing of their product
here the square brackets denote additive
secret sharing among the end parties
so beaver triple is the union of these
three terms and actually it allows us
only to achieve passive security
and speeds wants active security so the
construction introduces a mackie alpha
that is uniformly distributed over the
field and secret shared among them
parties
alpha is used to authenticate all the
beaver triples and this is done by
introducing some necks that are also
secret shared among the n parties
so we have x times alpha the mac over x
x y times alpha the mac over y and x
times y times alpha the mac over the
product
and yeah the union of the bigger triple
with its max is called an authenticated
builder triple okay now i'm going to
talk about the main tool that allowed us
to achieve low communication complexity
in our triple generation protocols and
this is called the pseudorandom
correlation generator or pcg for short
so pcg is a particular construction that
allows us to generate large amounts of
correlated material with no
communication and this is done by
expanding small correlated seeds so
specifically a pcg is an unparty
construction so let me draw and parties
and we tackle some correlation function
c so let's denote the outputs by r1 rn
so these are correlated values and there
is one for each party in particular ri
is addressed to party pi
so the pcg specifies how to generate n
small seeds k1 kn
and their generation is performed by a
trusted dealer so after
the seats have been distributed all the
parties can locally expand them so
without any interaction
obtaining large amounts of correlated
material so i will write that bar dpi
obtains the vector ri so p2 obtains the
vector r2 p1 obtains the vector r1
and with this notation i mean that these
n vectors are all correlated entry by
entry according to c
specifically its entry of the vector ri
has the same form as the i's output of
the correlation functions
so now i would like to talk a little bit
about security of pcgs and in order to
do so assume that the subset of parties
is corrupt
so clearly the corrupted parties know
their outputs and these outputs leak
some information about the outputs of
the honda's parties that's because the
samples that we obtained by expanding
the pcg acids are all correlated
so
there is nothing we can do to avoid this
liquid it's something intrinsic in the
problem
however notice that there is another
potential issue namely that the
corrupted parties also see
their seeds and these seeds may leak
some additional information and we don't
want that
so the security definition of pcgs
states exactly this
uh the seeds of the corrupted parties
leaked no information about the outputs
of the homeless parties except what can
be inferred from their expansion r2 and
ri
so at the beginning it may seem strange
that we base our triple generation
protocol on these pcg constructions that
need a trusted dealer for the generation
of the seeds
indeed the whole point of a triple
generation protocol is to get rid of
trusted dealers in speeds
however notice that the pcg seeds are
all small so usually it is not hard to
design multiparty computation protocols
that generate and distribute them with
linear communication in the seed size
so when we combust these protocols with
the expansion phase and this composition
is trivially secure because the
expansion is not interactive we obtain
protocols that generate large amounts of
correlated randomness with sub-linear
communication in the size of the output
and this is exactly what we want so
recently there has been some work on
pcgs for bigger triples and the first
work is by boy little at crypto 2018
where they designed a pcg that generates
and unauthenticated bigger triples for
end parties with logarithmic seed size
in the number of triples that are
generated
one year later the same authors designed
another pcg but now for authenticated
beaver triples and the seat size is
still logarithmic in end
however this construction works only in
the two-party setting
but what about authenticated beaver
triple in the n-party setting
well until recently no efficient
construction was known
but in this work we present the solution
with o of square root of finance in size
so the security of our pcg relies on the
ring lpn assumption which i'm going to
describe now so our setting is a ring r
which is the quotient between the
polynomial ring over the field f
and the idea generated by a polynomial f
of x
we also introduce two parameters the
first one is a small constant c
and then we have t that is roughly the
size of the security parameter lambda
we also introduce a distribution which
is denoted by hwt
and this samples a random t sparse
polynomial
over the ring are
and with t sparse i mean
that this polynomial has at most t
non-zero coefficients
now consider the following pair we have
a that is uniformly distributed over r
to the c so c is this small parameter
here
and then we have the inner product
between a and another vector e and e is
sampled according to hwt to the c
specifically that means that e is a
c-dimensional vector and each entry of e
is a t-sparse polynomial in the ring r
so the ring lpn assumption states that
this pair is computationally
indistinguishable from a
u
where a is again uniform over r to the c
whereas u
is uniform over r
so essentially the rpm assumption states
that even if a is known the inner
product looks random over the ring r
so the second tool that we used for the
construction of our pcg is called
distributed point function or dpf for
short so a dpf is a particular tool that
allows us to compress an n party secret
sharing of a unit vector into n small
keys
so a unit vector is a particular vector
where all the entries are 0 except for
1.
on this slide i deducted the nonzero
element by a red square and its position
is called the special position of the
unit vector
and we denote it by omega so a dpf takes
as input a unit vector and outputs n
small keys one for each party
and the size of the keys is sublinear in
the size of the unit vector that is
given as input
moreover even if the part is collude the
keys leak new information about the
special position omega and the non-zero
element the red square
and finally
the compression has also the nice
property that is invertible so the
parties can take their keys and expand
them locally so without any interaction
obtaining a non-party secret sharing of
the unit vector that was given as input
for the key generation
so what is the state of the art of
distributed point functions in the
two-party setting they are really
efficient indeed we know constructions
that have logarithmic key size in the
length of the unit vector that we give
as input however in the three-part
setting the constructions are not as
efficient indeed the best solution
have o of square root of n key size
finally in the n-party setting they get
even worse because yes the key size is
still of square root of n but there is
also a factor that is exponential in the
number of parties
so we can finally talk about our pcg for
multiparty beaver triple our goal is to
take a mc alpha uniform over the field
and and authenticated bigger triples and
compress them into some small material
so the first thing that we do is to
choose the ring r where we instantiate
the ring lpn assumption and in
particular we choose r to be isomorphic
to f to the n where f to the n is a ring
with entry wise addition and
multiplication
it is possible to make this choice
because the polynomial f of x here does
not need to be reducible for security it
can also split into linear factors
now take the mckee and the
unauthenticated beaver triples
using the isomorphism here and without
any interaction the parties are able to
convert them into one single
authenticated beaver triple over the
ring r and what i mean is that now x and
y are uniform at random over the ring r
whereas alpha remains the same as before
so a field element
the nice thing of the isomorphism is
also that it is invertible so the
parties are able to convert material
this kind into an authenticated bigger
triples over the field f and this is
done without any interaction
so we notice that all of a sudden our
goal has become to compress a single
authenticated beaver triple over the
ring r
and we are going to do this by
compressing each term one after another
so we start from x and y and as i said
before these are uniformly random
elements over the ring r that are secret
shared among the n parties
so suppose that the random oracle now
provides everybody with a random vector
a belonging to r to the c
each party p i
will compress its shares of x and y as
follows so first of all it samples two
vectors of
sparse polynomials ui and vi using the
distribution h w t to the c
we wanted to introduce with the ring lpn
assumption
so next pi sets its share of x to be x i
the inner product between a and ui
and similarly it sets its share of y to
be the inner product between a
and v i
so you understand that by the ring of an
assumption x i and y i now look random
even if a is public
but the entropy of x i and y i now is
low because they are described in terms
of sparse polynomials and the
description of sparse polynomials is
short
so next we compress the terms alpha
times x and alpha times y
and we start by observing that alpha
times x can be rewritten as the sum over
i and j of alpha i times x t where alpha
i and x j represent the shares of p i
and p j respectively
this can again be rewritten as the sum
over i and j of alpha i times the inner
product between a and u j
which is also equal to the sum over i
and j of the inner product between a and
alpha i times d j
okay now suppose that the parties have a
secret sharing of fi times you'd say
between the parties pi and pj only
so i use these indexes i and they in
the brackets to denote two-part secret
sharing between pi and pj only
so if the parties have these n-square
secret sharings they are able to obtain
a secret sharing of alpha times x
between the n parties due to the
linearity of the inner product and the
sum here
moreover this and square secret sharings
leak new information about the shares of
pi mpj to the other parties indeed in
order to leak some information both pi
and pj would need to be corrupt and in
this case what we leak is actually alpha
i and usa which are values that are
already known to differentially
so now our goal will be to compress
these terms instead of this
so what's the structure of uj your j is
a c dimensional vector over the ring r
and each entry is a t sparse polynomial
of degree n so here we represent these
polynomials by listing the coefficients
starting from the term of degree zero
and the nonzero coefficients are
represented with colored squares
so when we multiply you'd say by alpha i
the structure remains the same that's
because alpha is an element of the field
so the only thing that changes is the
color of the squares so the value of the
coefficient changes but their positions
remain the same as before
so how can we compress the secret
sharing of alpha times uj between party
pi and pj only
well we notice that each entry of this
vector can be rewritten as the sum of t
and dimensional unit vectors for
instance these would be those associated
with the first entry
and now we know how to compress secret
sharings of unit vectors using dps in
particular when we perform the operation
we provide the parties with
keys that leak no information about
alpha and uj to the parties because of
the security of epfs
and the material that we obtain in this
way is small in particular it is just
c times t pairs of tpf keys c because
there are c entries and t because there
are t
unit vectors per entry
and the size of these keys is
logarithmic in n because it is just a
secret sharing between two parties
so next we compress the terms x times y
so we do it similar to x times alpha
indeed we notice that x times y can be
rewritten as the sum over i and j of x i
times yj where x i and yj are the shares
of b i and pj respectively
and this can again be rewritten as the
sum over inj of the inner product
between a and ui
with
the inner product between a and b j
this last term can be proven to be equal
to
the sum over i and j
of an inner product between the outer
product of a with itself
and then the outer product between ui
and vj
i will define this outer product later
in the next slide so now suppose that
the parties have
a two-party secret sharing of ui
outer product with vj
between party pi and pj only
so due to the linearity of the inner
product and of
the sun here
the parties can convert these n square
uh two-part secret sharings
into a single secret sharing of extends
y between all the n parties without any
interaction
now our goal will be to compress these
two parts secret sharings between p i
and pj
so basically we are doing the same thing
that we did for alpha times x the only
difference is that now x and y are both
ring elements whereas before one of the
factors was a field element
so how is the outer product defined well
a ui and vj are c-dimensional vectors
over the ring r and their outer product
is defined to be the c square
dimensional vector over r where for
every l and m the element in position c
l plus m is the product of the elf
element in ui and the nth element in v j
okay now take the else entry of u i and
the infinity of v j which are both t
sparse polynomials over r
we consider their product but not over r
but over f of x since the reduction
modulo in idl commits with all the
operation we can always
make the reduction later whenever it is
more suited
now uh the product of two polynomials
over f of x is still somewhat sparse
indeed this is a polynomial of degree at
most 2n
and there are at most t-square non-zero
coefficients that's because all the
terms of a product are
the product of the monomials of ui and
the monomial of vj and since these two
polynomials have at most t non-zero
coefficients the number of nonzero
coefficients of the product will be
upper bounded by t square
so our goal is to compress the secret
sharing of ui outer product with j
between party pi and pj only
and ui outer product with dj is a vector
of this kind so in particular it is a c
square dimensional vector and its entry
is a t square sparse polynomial of
degree at most 2n
so since these are all sparse vectors we
can use the same techniques that we used
before for alpha times x and alpha times
y
in particular we can just
compress the secret sharing of each
entry and the latter can be rewritten as
the sum of t-square's unit vectors of
dimension to n
these on the slides are those associated
with
this entry that you see
on the top
and yeah now we are able to compress
secret sharings of unit vectors using
dpfs and so we provide the parties with
these keys that leak new information
about the non-zero elements and the
special positions
furthermore all this material is a small
size now indeed we just have c square
times t square pairs of dpf keys and
their size is logarithmic n because we
are just working with two-party secret
sharings
so the last term that remains to be
compressed is alpha times x times y
and as we did before we notice that
alpha times x times y can be rewritten
as the sum over i j and k
of alpha k times x i times y j where
alpha k x sine and y j
are the shares of part d p k p i and p j
respectively
this can be again rewritten as the sum
over i j and k of alpha k times the
inner product between a and u i
times the inner product between a and v
j
and as we did before this is equal to
the sum over i j and k of alpha k times
the inner product between the outer
product of a with itself
and the outer product with
between ui and vj
finally we can move alpha k inside the
inner product so this is equal to the
sum over i j and k
of the inner product between
the outer product between a and itself
and then alpha k times ui
outer product with bj
okay now suppose that the parties have a
secret sharing of alpha k
times ui
outer product with vj
between bar dpi pj and pk only
due to the linearity of the inner
product and of the sum the parties are
able to convert this and to the third
secret sharings into a single secret
sharing of alpha times x times y between
all the end parties
and this operation requires no
communication
moreover notice that since this is a
three-part secret sharing we leak new
information about alpha k ui and vga to
that version indeed the only way to take
some information is if all the three
parties are correct and in that case
diversity already knows alpha k ui and
vj
notice also that a two-party secret
sharing wouldn't be enough here because
for instance if it was only between pi
and pj
and
apk is honest
if pi and pj are corrupt uh we would
leak information about alpha k that
adversary shouldn't know
so our goal now will be to compress
these secret sharings here
previously we have noticed that the
outer product between ui and vj is a
vector of this kind in particular a c
square dimensional vector where each
entry is a t-square sparse polynomial of
degree at most to n
now if we multiply everything by alpha k
their structure remains the same that's
because alpha k is a field element so
the only consequence of this
multiplication is to change the value of
these colored squares but their position
and their number remains the same as
before so we conclude that alpha k times
the outer product between ui and vj is a
c square dimensional vector where its
entry is a t-square sparse polynomial
so in order to compress the secret
sharing of this between pk pi and pj we
can use the same techniques as before
in particular we can compress the secret
sharing of its entry and the latter can
be rewritten as the sum of t-square unit
vectors of dimension to n
and these secret sharings can be
compressed using a dpf in particular a
three-part dpf
so these keys that are obtained leak new
information about the non-zero elements
and the special positions
and their size is small
in total we have c squared times t
square triples of dpf keys but their
size is now not logarithmic in n but o
or square root of n and the reason is
because three party dps are not as
efficient as two party ones
so there is one last issue that we need
to fix in our construction specifically
dpx usually output secret sharings over
binary groups whereas our pcg needs
secret sharings over a large prime field
f the same one that we use in speeds
so generalizing the known constructions
for two parties is rather simple but for
the three-party case it is tricky
specifically the best construction for
three party is by a boonetal and it
outputs secret sharings over zero one to
the m
thanks to a trick by boy little it is
possible to generalize this construction
to groups of polynomial cardinality but
these techniques don't apply to large
prime fields
so at the beginning we thought we were
completely stuck but then we realized
that our pcg is secure even if we allow
some leakage in the three-part epf
in particular if two specific parties of
the three-party secret sharing are
corrupt we allow the adversary to learn
omega the special position of the unit
vector if we allow this leak as it is
possible to generalize the three-part
dpf by bonus hell to large prime fields
the reason why our pcg is still secure
is because when pi and pj are both
corrupted the adversary already knows
the special position omega
indeed we use the three party dpf to
compress secret sharings of alpha k
times the outer product between ui and
vj and since alpha case is a field
element the special positions are
uniquely determined by ui and vj
when pi and pj are both corrupted these
terms are already known to the adversary
so to summarize our pcg
generates n authenticated bigger triples
and we were able to compress the terms x
and y using the ring lpn assumption into
material of size c times t
times o of log n
and the complexity in the number of
parties is linear
so this applies also for y that has the
same form as x
the term x times alpha was compressed
using two party bpfs into material of
size c times t times o of logan
and the complexity in the number of
parties is square
same
happens for y terms of
moving on to the product x tends y
we compress this material into a
values
of size c squared times t square times o
of
times n square
using two party dpfs
and finally the last term x times y
times alpha was compressed into material
of size c squared times t squared times
o or square root of n times n to the
third
so we understand that the dominant
term is this one
so the final seed size of our pcg
is o or square root of n after having
designed our pcg we focused on the a
protocol for the generation of
authenticated builder triples
in particular we designed an actively
secure protocol that sets up the third
party dpf keys
and then we design another protocol that
generates and distribute the pcc seeds
with active security and with little
communication
i won't describe these constructions in
details because they are both rather
complex and the techniques that we used
are not extremely interesting anyway
regarding efficiency our protocol
generates an authenticated regulatory
pulse with some linear communication in
them in particular all square root of n
there is however a term that scales as
the number of parties to the fourth so
for a very large number of players our
solution may not be the best
regarding computations the complexity
scales as n log n
so we analyze the efficiency of the
protocol by considering the stretch
which is defined as the ratio between
the total size of the outputs and the
total communication
so the larger the stretch the better
we observe that the stretch becomes
greater than one for very large number
of triples in particular for n
approaching 2 to the 24 which is close
to 16 millions anyway even for smaller
values of n our protocol is practical
based on estimation by boy lethal
moreover the total communication is
roughly 10 times better than overpriced