hello everyone my name is pierre dartra
i'm a student of luca defeo today i will
present our work on the security of
oside financed by ibm research
oside is an isogeny-based protocol
introduced by leonardo colo and david
kohl in 2019 to generalize seaside but
unlike seaside oside is more structured
and we explored its structure to provide
an attack improving an id by onuki
osad uses a lot of mathematics due to
colo and cohen that i will need to
introduce first
as seaside osad is based on a
cryptographic group action so i will
explain what it is
then we will see how this cryptographic
group action is built in oside in order
to explain how the protocol works
finally i represent you our attack
and possible counter measures
now let's introduce cryptographic group
actions
the original idea was first introduced
by brassard and jung in 1991 and reused
by coven in his paper constructing the
first isogenic base cryptosystem
and surprisingly to have a cryptographic
group action we need a group and a space
to act upon
the group has to be obedient and the
action needs to be transitive meaning
that we have a simple orbit in this
space all space elements can be reached
from any element of the space with the
group action
it needs to be faithful also only the
trivial element acts trivially
the group action needs to be easy to
compute for cryptographic needs
and finally
it needs to be one way to ensure
cryptographic security if we know x and
y in the space related by a secret group
element g then g is hard to find
we can do a lot of cryptography with
cryptographic group actions including
one of the simplest primitives key
exchange
actually oside is a difficult man key
exchange to set up such a key exchange
with the cryptographic group action we
fix a public space element x0
alice and bob can choose separately
secret group element
gnh they will act separately on x0 with
their secrets and exchange the computed
data gx0 and hx0
then alice and bob will be able to
recover the shared secret key ghx0
by acting with their secret on the data
they receive from one another
they will find the same secret key
because the group is a billion and the
protocol will be secure because the
group action is one way
now let's see how the group action works
first we need a group that will be the
ideal class group of an order in a
quadratic imaginary field so i will
briefly recall what it is a quadratic
imaginary field is a field extinction of
degree 2 of a q that is not real
an order is a summary and a full rank
lattice in this field
if we fix an order o we can look at all
ideals which are simply lattices stable
by multiplication by o
there is a commutative multiplication
law of ideals with the order as neutral
element
the set of invertible ideals for this
law form a group and we have a subgroup
formed by principal ideals which are
basically ideals generated by your
scholar
the caution of those groups is the ideal
class group it is finite so it is
suitable for cryptography
now that we know how a group
what will be the space of the action
the space will be a set of elliptic
curves and a group action will use a
correspondence between group elements
meaning ideal classes and isogenes
between those elliptic curves
so i will briefly recall those notions
of course you know elliptic curves over
finite fields they are simply given by
this polynomial equation on the plane
and a point at infinity elliptic curves
have a group structure given by the
addition law described on the figure
displayed here this is why elliptic
curves are used in discrete logarithm
based cryptography
but here we do post-quantum cryptography
so we use isogenes which are morphemes
between elliptic curves
as morphisms between algebraic varieties
given by rational fractions and also
group homomorphisms
i give here two simple examples
the multiplication map which is an
endomorphism meaning an isogeny of an
elliptic curve to itself and other
finite fields the frobenius given by the
exponentiation of the characteristic
endomorphisms our special class of
isogenes mapping an elliptic curve to
itself and a form for given elliptic
covering
this ring is either of our finite field
an order in a quadratic imaginary field
this is the ordinary case
or a maximal order in a quaternion
algebra this is the super singular case
if you are not familiar with quaternions
you just have to keep in mind that those
are non-commutative four-dimensional
extensions of a queue
orders have the same definition that we
introduced before and maximal orders are
simply maximal for the inclusion
in isogenic base cryptography we often
use supercingular elliptic curves for
security and efficiency reasons
that i recall those basics we can get to
a side
if we have a super angular elliptic
curve and a quadratic imaginary field
we defined a k orientation as an
embedding of k in the quaternion algebra
made of linear combinations of
endomorphisms with rational coefficients
if o is an order of k we have a
primitive or orientation if o is the
maximal order in k mapping to the
endomorphism ring
put in other verbs it maps to the
intersection of the image of k
with the endomorphism ring
actually the space of oxide group action
by the ideal class group of an older o
will be the space of o oriented super
singular elliptic curves
now as promised i explain how hydrogen
is appear in this group action
if we have two k oriented elliptic
curves e and f
a k oriented isogeny between those
curves is simply an isogeny respecting
the orientation meaning following the
formula displayed here
the degree appearing in this formula is
roughly the cardinality of the kernel
we say that the isogeny is ascending
if the order orienting e
is smaller than the order orienting f
that it is horizontal if both orders are
equal and that it is descending if the
order orienting e is bigger than the
order orienting f
we are not always in those cases
except when isogeny has a prime degree
now
we fix a quadratic imaginary field k and
a prime l and we look at the graph whose
vertices are k oriented elliptic curves
and edges
isogenys of degree l
the graph is very interesting because
every connected component has a volcano
structure
on this connected component for instance
we have the crater of the volcano which
is oriented by the maximal order of the
field
at the crater we have one horizontal
isogeny and one dissenting isogen
below we always have
one ascending isogeny and l-descending
isogeny at each vertex and the
orientation by the order of index l in
the order above
hence the index
is given by the degree when we descend
the graph
for our side group action every level of
the graph can be a potential space
but as we go down we see that the size
of the level grows exponentially
so we need to choose a level deep enough
to make sure
that the cryptosystem is secure
once we have chosen a level and the
corresponding order o the ideal class
group of o will act on this level as
follows
to every o ideal we associate a
horizontal isogeny
and take the codomain as the result of
the action of this ideal on the domain
this correspondence
defines indeed a group action because
principal ideals correspond to
endomorphisms so that ideas in the same
class
act the same way
this is why we have an action of the
ideal class group
and finally multiplication of ideas
correspond to isogenic composition and
that's the reason why we have indeed a
group action property
as kolo kohel and anuki proved this
action is furthermore transitive and
faithful
but is this action easy to compute on
one way as required to have a
cryptographic group action
to make oside practical
we need to use isogenic graphs that we
just introduced
suppose that we use level n as a group
action space down here computing
directly the group action in this space
is almost impossible
instead if we want to compute the action
of an ideal q let's say on e n in this
space represent e n as a descending
isogenic chain
starting from the crater
and going down to e n
and we compute the action level by level
going down the chain which is practical
with modular equations
the results will be a descending
elisogenic chain again and the ending
element will be the action of q on e n
for efficiency reasons colo and kohl use
this technique only with a bunch of
prime ideals generating the ideal class
group
then they can compute the group action
by a product of this bunch of ideals
this is called restricted cryptographic
group action
the situation is the same in seaside we
have a restricted cryptographic group
action by an ideal class group
except
that the level used in seaside
in the isogenic graphs is way closer to
the crater only the first level is used
in oside we have to go much deeper this
is what makes oside much more vulnerable
to security attacks than csi
now at last we have what we need to
introduce the protocol
once we know the outside framework
there is a naive diffie-hellman key
exchange coming to mind
first we just fix a public
esogenic chain that is descending
we let alice and bob choose their secret
ideas as products of generator qj with
exponents within a range r
and we let them act on the public chain
with their secret ideal exchange the
resulting chain of the computation
and finally act on the exchange chain
with their respective secret ideals to
find a shared secret chain h
unfortunately this is not secure
kolo and kohel already knew it
why
because of the graph structure
let's say that we want to recover
alice's secret ideal class
if we know both chains e and f
it is easy to recover the secret ideal
class relating them recursively
first finding the ideal class at level 0
is trivial
and if we know the ideal class at level
i
we only have l possibilities for the
ideal class at level i plus 1
because of this equation
so we simply have to test them all until
we map e i plus 1 to f i plus 1.
so how can we make oside secure
first remember that the chains that
reveal all this information are not
essential to the protocol
they are just computational tools
but alice and bob cannot just remove
this information when they change data
so the trick introduced by colo and
correll is to provide horizontal instead
of vertical information
alice and bob will perform the same
protocol
but simply send to each other the action
of the qj in the neighborhood of the
ending element they found and not all
the chain
nonetheless is it sufficient to make
oside secure
the answer is no
actually
the additional horizontal chains can be
used to recover this descending chain
kept secret
in the key exchange
and as explained this makes oscillate
vulnerable to a key recovery
an idea introduced by onuki is to
leverage those chains to find a cycle in
the isogenic graph
or put in other words an endomorphism to
do that we have to find a principle
ideal that is easily expressed as a
product of the qj with short exponents
and then compute the action by such an
ideal
as we saw when we introduce the group
action a principle ideal corresponds to
an endomorphism or put in other words
a cycle in the orbit of the ideal class
group then once we have such an
endomorphism
we can actually recover the ascending
isogeny relating level n and n minus 1
in the chain
technically we compute the endomorphism
we found on the l-torsion to recover the
kernel of the ascending isogeny and once
we have the kernel we have the isogeny
so the attack works as follows
first we leverage the horizontal chains
to find the cycle
then we recover fn minus one with this
cycle
this way we can push the horizontal
chains to level n minus one
this is an easy computation
and find a cycle again
this is how we recover the whole chain
making those side vulnerable again to
the attack represented earlier
the difficult step in our attack
is to find a principle ideal of the
right form to be able to compute a cycle
easily
anuki struggled with this problem and
did not provide a practical way to do it
our main contribution is a solution to
this problem we noticed that all we have
to do
is to find
a short enough vector
in the relations lattice of the ideal
class group
because such a vector will define a
principal ideal
and if the exponents are short enough
we'll be able to perform the group
action
this way is actually more efficient at
one keys and breaks color and cohes
parameters
the complex step in our approach is to
find a short vector in the relation
lattice this is exponential but still
practical with colo and kohl's
parameters using bkz
all other steps are polynomial mainly
group actions including the discrete
logarithm computations needed to compute
the relation lattice because
the ideal class group is smooth
but in practice those polynomial
operations are very slow compared to the
lattice reduction because group actions
are very slow to compute
this is why
there is no known implementation of osi
to this day
nevertheless we implemented the protocol
and the attack with toy parameters
with those parameters we found that the
attack runs in reasonable time compared
to the protocol execution
as we explain
the bottom line is if we make the
protocol practical then the attack
becomes practical as well because the
bottleneck is not the exponential
lattice reduction
but
the polynomial time operations
can the attack be countered
yes
because our lattice reduction relies on
a strong hypothesis to work
we need to make sure that they are short
enough vectors in the relation lattice
to be able to compute a cycle
heuristically the first minimum of this
lattice for the infinity norm is given
by the displayed formula
so under the reasonable assumption that
the key space tightly covered the ideal
class group which is common
with a restricted cryptographic group
action we get that the first minimum is
short enough
because we have this formula
the question is do we have efficient
enough lattice reduction algorithms to
find short vectors
this leads to our first counter measure
make it hard to find short vector by
increasing the dimension of the lattice
the drawback is that it makes the
protocol excessively costly and
actually pointless because it now relies
on the lattice-based security assumption
that svp is hard but why should we use a
very inefficient key exchange relying on
svp if they are much more efficient
lattice-based alternatives with the same
or better security level
the second counter measure increases the
size of the ideal class group to make
sure that there are no short enough
vectors
in the relation lattice
because this bound is no longer
satisfied
however it makes oxide no longer a
cryptographic group action impeding
other cryptographic constructions beyond
key exchange that could be very
interesting
so to conclude our attack severely
undermines the relevance of oxide