hello thank you for watching this talk
on polynomial iops for linear algebra
this is john's work between alan
shapines and myself yin seung zhang
this work deals with succinct
non-interactive arguments of knowledge
or snags
in this setting there are two parties
the approver and the verifier
the approver is trying to convince the
verifier that's given the instance x the
prover knows a weakness w
such that x and w satisfy a certain
relation that is typically described by
a computation c
this job can be accomplished by a snark
a snark consists of three algorithms
namely the setup which often involves
pre-processing the computation c
the approval on inputs both the instance
and the riskiness
produces a proof string denoted by pi
and sends it to the verifier who decides
whether to accept this proof
the snark has the following properties
by succinctness it requires that the
proof size is logarithmic to the circuit
size sometimes this logarithmic
restriction also applies to the running
time of the very fire
by the interactivity the approval
generates the proof string without
receiving any information from the web
file
so one puff string can be stored and
repeatedly used to convince more than
one wire file
finally by arguments of knowledge the
proverb shows that the witness w not
only exists but is known to the approver
recently many snarks have been
constructed
most constructions can be fed into the
following pipeline
this pipeline starts from the
computation the c in the previous slide
which is mostly described by program or
circuit
the first step called the
arithmetization transforms this
computation into a form that is more
friendly to mathematicians
rcs and hpr are popular candidates for
this step
the next step which is usually the most
complex step is to design an information
theoretical protocol for the arithmetic
representation
this protocol is designed in the context
of an idealized model for example pcp
linear pcp ilp and so on
as pointed out by boone's accessor all
these idealized models can be viewed as
a special case of the polynomial iop
model a polynomial iop is an interactive
protocol where all the messages sent
from the prover to the verifier are
polynomials over finite fields
these polynomials can be huge the wi-fi
cannot be read the entire polynomials
because the verifier is much weaker than
the prover
therefore in the polynomial iop model
the verifier only receives an evaluation
oracle for this polynomial
the verifier may pick up three points
say y and j
and query this oracle to obtain fy and
fc respectively
obviously polynomials do not exist in
the real world so we need to replace
them by cryptographic tool called
polynomial commitment
this brings us back to the last step of
the construction pipeline where we
finally get a snark by compiling the
information theoretical protocol using
cryptographic tools
like the kzg or dark polynomial
commitments under the via xiaomi
heuristic which is frequently used to
transform interactive protocols into
non-interactive schemes
in this work we focus on the second step
information theoretic compilation
this step transforms an arithmetic
representation into a polynomial iob
the arithmetic representation is
typically described by matrices factors
and operations in linear algebra
the polynomial b however provides a
difference interface
the objects are polynomials and the
operations are evaluations
therefore the key questions in designing
polynomial iops are representing the
matrices and vectors by polynomials and
simulating the operations in the algebra
by those of polynomials
most existing works take the resolution
code basis representation where a vector
is identified by the polynomial
evaluations over domain which is a
subset in the final field this snark is
based on
the problem with this representation is
that the domain must have a nice
algebraic structure
so the choices of finite fields are
limited
a more straightforward approach is to
use the monomial basis
which directly embeds the vector entries
into the polynomial coefficient
this approach does not put any limits on
the choice of final fields
however
fieldworks take this approach as the
methods for simulating the linear
algebra operations in this
representation are largely unexplored
the only exception sonic is outperformed
by the popular works like planck or
marine that are based on the rhythmical
basis
to uncover the potential of the monomial
basis representation we construct a
polynomial iop
which rename climor after type of
scottish sword
our work reveals a rich set of linear
algebra operations that can be
implemented in the monomial basis with
competitive efficiency
claymore is built for the arithmetic
representation of circuits called the
hadamard product relation
shorthand hbr this is a variant of the
circuit's representation proposed by the
work of bruto in 2016.
this relation is indexed by matrix m
which is determined by the circuit
the instance of hpr is a sparse vector x
corresponding to the public inputs and
outputs of the circuits
the witness w consists of three vectors
that respectively corresponds to the
wires of the left inputs write inputs
and outputs of the multiplication gates
the instance and witness pair satisfies
this hpr if the multiplication of the
left inputs and the right inputs exactly
produce the values of the output wires
and the y values satisfy the linear
relation specified by the matrix m
the first step to construct the
polynomial iop
is to represent the objects in hpr by
polynomials
recall that we chose the monomial basis
representation
so for the vector a the entries of the
vector are taken as the polynomial
coefficient we denote the polynomial by
f subscripts a for the matrix we simply
concatenate all the rule vectors before
treating them as the coefficients
next we will introduce how to implement
the polynomial iop for all the necessary
operations each in the sub-particle
we introduce these star particles from
bottom to top
and finally compose them into the
claymore protocol
we start from module reduce which is not
a linear algebra operation but is
required in the matrix vector product
protocol
the most reduced protocol assumes that
the wi-fi already has two polynomials f
x and rx and convinces the verifier that
rx is the remainder of f x divided by
the public polynomial p
the protocol is straightforward the
approval divides f x by p x and sends
the quotient polynomial q x to the
verifier and the wi-fi checks the
polynomial identity deduced from the
definition of polynomial division as a
uniformly random point today
the equality at this random points
implies the equality of the entire
polynomials
due to the structural lemma
now the model reduced protocol is
finished
next is the inner product protocol
this protocol convinces the verifier
that the inner product between two
factors a and b is a public value c
when the verifier has oracles for
polynomials f a x and f b x
to achieve this
approval reverses the coefficients of f
a x
the reversion is achieved by
substituting x by x inverse then
multiplying x to the power of d the
maximum degree of f x
then multiply this reversed f x with f p
x to get h x
whose coefficients for x to d is exactly
the linear product between a and b
so the job of the problem becomes
showing that this coefficient of hx
equals c
to accomplish this the problem tries to
find such an hyx and express hx in this
form
it's easy to check that a polynomial of
this form is guaranteed to have
coefficient c for the disk power
with properly chosen gamma it's also
easy to find such an h bikes
so the prover sends the oracle of hbx to
the verifier
then the web checks the validity of h
bar x by definition at a uniformly
randomly sampled points j
this completes the inner product
protocol
based on the inner product protocol we
are now ready to implement the hadamard
product
the verifier has access to three
polynomials fa fb and fc
and the approval try to convince the
wi-fi that a times b is c where the
multiplication is helmet product which
is a fascinating for enterovirus
products between vectors
the idea
is still to use schwarzenegger by this
lemma the vector identity a times b
equals c can be implied from the
inequality between f a b alpha and fc
alpha for uniformly random alpha
so the verifier samples offer and checks
this identity
the right hand side is simply evaluating
as cx at alpha while the left-hand side
is the inner products between the
coefficient vectors of fa of x and fbx
since the verifier has the oracle for
fax
the wi-fi can simulate the oracle for fa
r4x by multiplying alpha to whatever is
queried to this oracle
therefore the wi-fi can check the
equality by running the inner product
protocol with the approval
now we are left with the last linear
operation and the most complex one the
matrix vector product
we introduced two particles for this job
first consider the case when the matrix
b is dense
we call this version the dense mvp
protocol
assume that the size of b is m times n
recall that the coefficients of f b x is
the calculation of all the row vectors
now for uniformly random alpha consider
reducing f b x modulus x to n minus
alpha
this effectively replaces all the x to n
with alpha
now look at the remainder polynomial rx
the coefficient vector of rx is exactly
the linear combination of the rows of b
by one alpha alpha squared all the way
to alpha to minus one
this is exactly multiplying the alpha
vector to the left of the matrix b
with this in mind the identity c equals
ba can be verified as follows
we multiply the alpha vector to both
sides by schwarzepolema this new
identity implies the original affinity
the left hand side is simply fc alpha
the right hand side is the inner product
between rx and the vector a
now we formalize this observation into
the following pascal assume the verifier
has polynomial equals fc fb and fa
to prove that c equals ba
the web file samples a random alpha as
discussed before
the prover that sends the remainder
polynomial rx to the rare file
the wi-fi first ensures that the
inner products of r and a is fc alpha by
the inner product protocol which we just
introduced
then the profile checks that rx is
correct by the mod reduce protocol
in this first go the running time of the
approval is at least linear to the total
number of entries in the matrix this is
the case even if most of the entries are
zero
this can be inefficient since in
practice the matrix is often large and
sparse
therefore for sparse matrix where the
number of zero entries is much smaller
than the total number of entries which
suggests an alternative protocol
where the running time of the approval
depends only on the number of zero
entries
to explain the sparse and vp protocol we
look at the identity c equals ba again
we multiply the alpha vector to both
sides as we did before
the left hand side is still fc alpha and
the right hand side is the inner product
between r and a
different from this mvp after the prover
sends rx to the verifier instead of
using the multi-radius protocol as in
density and vp we let the verifier
validate the rx with another approach
now the original problem has been
reduced to checking this new identity
we apply forcible lemma again by
multiplying another random vector which
we call better vector to both sides of
the equation
we are better assembled independently
from alpha
obviously the left-hand side is operator
what about the right hand side
this is where the sparsity of the matrix
comes into play
assume there are k natural entries in
the matrix with zero indices a1 a2 up to
ak call indices b1 b2 up to bk and entry
values c1 c2 up to ck
then the right hand side can be written
as the sum of kick items
rises sum in the form of vectors we
denote the vector of all the ck by v the
other two multiplicands are similarly
collected into vectors of size k
denoted by x and y respectively
then the sum is the inner product
between v and the hadamard product of x
and y
the verifier can then check this
identity by a headmat protocol
followed by an inner product protocol
the problem is how can the verifier
obtain the polynomials fvx
fx x and f y x
for f v x note that the vector b depends
only on the matrix b which is learned
before the protocol started
therefore the verifier may preprocess
this vector and generate this oracle
offline
however the vectors x and y depends on
the random values of and beta
which cannot be predicted in other words
so the verifier can only obtain these
oracles on the fly from the approval
for the proverb to convince the verifier
that these polynomials are correctly
computed
the parties run a circle score called
sparse monomial vector
we omit the details of this suppressor
from the stock
and therefore requested the audience to
the paper
now we summarize the above in the splash
mvp protocol
instead of fbx which contains the entire
matrix the wi-fi now has the oracle of
fv that contains only the zero entries
the degree of fv is much smaller than fb
when the matrix is sparse
the start of the splash mvp protocol is
the same as dense mvp
the difference between the protocols
lies in the validation of rx
in the descent vp protocol the
polynomial for rx is checked by the
simple yet slow mode reduced protocol
in sparse mvp more reduced is replaced
with a more complex procedure but the
running time of the prover is reduced
exploiting the sparsity of the matrix
now all the support goals are ready
the climate protocol is a
straightforward combination of the
matrix vector products and the high
demand protocols
here we only present the dense version
of claymore as the sparse version is
very similar
the approval is trying to convince the
wi-fi its knowledge of three vectors w l
w r and w o that satisfy
the linear relations specified by the
matrix m and public vector x and this w
l times w r is w o
in the protocol we use a small trick
instead of sending three vectors in
three polynomials individually we let
the prover can kitten its wl and wr into
a new vector wi
thus eliminates one online polynomial
oracle
to obtain the headquarter product
between wl and wr the verifier right
shifts wi and multiply with itself
the vector shifts are carried out by
multiplying powers of x to the
polynomials
finally the linear relation is validated
by the mvp protocol
now we have finished the description of
claymore
next i'll briefly discuss how to make it
their knowledge
in the polynomial iop all the
information the verifier receives from
the approver is obtained from querying
the polynomial oracles
in claymore there are only three
polynomials that contain information
that are not already publicly known
namely fwi fwo and h5x
for the first goal to be their knowledge
we want the verifier to be able to
simulate the query replies from these
polynomials without knowledge of their
content
observing the entire protocol we find
that each of these three polynomials is
queried at two different evaluation
points
so if we append two uniformly random
coefficients to each polynomial the
query results would also be uniformly
random
we first insert all zero columns to the
matrix m corresponding to the positions
of the random coefficients
then during the protocol the approval
inserts random elements in the witness
vectors before sending the polynomial
oracles to the very fire
the random elements are sampled in a way
that wl times wr is still w
when we multiply m with the witness
vector the random elements will be
multiplied to the all zero columns so
the randomization does not affect the
satisfaction of hpr
for h by x this polynomial is computed
and randomized by the approval during
the inner product protocol we will not
dive into the details here
finally
we analyze the performance of claymore
compared to the state of the arts
the metrics we consider include the
number of polynomials involved in the
protocol
either since by the proof of online or
pre-processed offline the number of
evaluation queries number of distinct
evaluation points
and the maximal polynomial degree
all these metrics affect the performance
of the compiled stock
here is the result the f here is the
maximal findings of addition gates
typically it could be two or three in
the protocol design we focused on
optimizing the number of polynomials we
have partially succeeded in this respect
this grammar has advantage the number of
polynomials compared to the rest until
the sacrifice of maximal degree
while sparse climate reduces the maximum
degree of disclaimer at the cost of more
polynomials and evaluation queries
in conclusion this work shows the
possibility of constructing polynomial
iops for linear algebra operations in e
monomial bases
including inner products animal products
and matrix vector products
composing them together we guess
claymore a polynomial lp that can be
compiled into snork for verifying
circuits computations
compared to snarks in the resolum code
basis
our snark has competitive efficiency and
no longer requires the finite field to
have a nicely structured subset of
proper size
thank you for watching this talk for
more details please read our paper which
is available on imprints