hello everyone i'm len ichibasi i'd like
to talk about post-quantum anonymous
one-sided authentication exchange
without random oracles
this is a joint work with kazuki
yoneyama
this presentation proceeds as follows
first introduction
second cc model for osak
that proposed generic construction of
osak in the standard models
first instantiation finally conclusion
let's start by the introduction
presentation exchange so-called a-gay
aka the cryptography protocol to share
communication key among multiple parties
through an authentic
network such as the internet
in this study we focus on it between two
bodies
each party has a static kpi
and in the key exchange section each
body generates our firmware circuit key
esk and generates our female property
apk
by using these keys
and send it to the other party
then each party computes a common
session key using these keys
so the ordinary aka is mutual
authentication
however in practice mutual
authentication is not required for some
applications
for example https transactions with only
several authentication
in this example
the server returns a static private key
and each certificate in response to the
grant's request
then the client will send it the server
using these
and then exchange keys
so
okay exchange without client
authentication one-sided ak may be
sufficient
in this paper
the ak with one-sided authentication is
called always aka
in addition it is desirable for clients
to be anonymous
for example to anonymity network
when the client connects to their
destination it passed through multiple
relays
in the red channel and one side
anonymous communication is used
so each layer cannot identify the sender
and finally
the exit relay communicates with the
destination through normal communication
in this way the client can communicate
with the destination with keeping his
anonymity
so
in enormous networks such as the tour
and the rifle anonymous always again is
required
if osaki is represent with the figure
sold in the page 3 always a case is
remove the current ssk
since it doesn't require a client
authentication
next i'll show the existing anonymous os
ak schemes
the gsu12 proposed security model for us
ak to be used in this study
and the big m12 and gt15 schemes are
guaranteed and a weaker fresher setting
than the original one
and the gk15s consist of radish and dh
and in some case the skin is not
poscondem
so it is partially post condom skin
these schemes are proved in a random
oracle model
so
as our contribution we propose generic
instructions
one the standard model and one in the
random oracle model
the ones in random in the standard model
can consist of industrial secure cam and
indistribute secure game with publicly
independent ciphertext called pkicam
well the ones in the random oracle model
can consist of all wcas secure camp and
all there should be a secure pdic cam
these constructions are guaranteed under
the original gc module
in addition we propose five
instantiation
in these base schemes the one in running
in the random oracle model is under the
cdh assumptions
and the one in the standard model is
first anonymous osaki schemes
and
this schemes a smaller online
computational cost of clients than
existing schemes
in the post quantum schemes the ones in
the random oracle model are
sidh based and seaside based schemes
and the one in the standard model is
only seaside based schemes but
the first anonymous osa scheme
here it is described as fully first
condom
because the existing schemes is not
first condom under some leakage patterns
but all schemes are possible in them and
are all leakage patterns
next i'll explain the gse model
the jc model allows the adversary to
wire up and modify and reveal previous
session key and reveal a firmware secret
key and reveal
static secret key just like the hdk
module
also
as an additional query it allows the
adversary to obtain the apks used in
each party in advance
so
in the gsm model there is a query called
reveal next
it allows the adversary to obtain a
biggest first session in advance
that's why epa's first session must be
able to be generated in advance of
flying
in addition due to the flying generation
the freshness is a bit unique
it considers wreckage for secret key
except for all riggage of each party
so repairing circuit key
our esk and ssk
must be considered from each for example
the secret key
used in a station are
rc and rt for the client and rs
and the guest for the server we need we
need to consider reviewing
one each
such as rc and rs
over rc and djs were rd or and rs over
rt and dks
in addition to this there are other osag
models such as for trs
the setting
but
those models are the application to the
setting of anonymous networks is not
considered
and the anonymity is not focused
so we focus on the gse model
next i'll introduce the proposed generic
construction of osak in the standard
model
so by removing the client escape from
the general reconstruction of ak in
fsxy15
it looks we can
simply construct osaka
so i'll show you
an example of the construction
the fs xy construction consists of
industrial security and industrial
secure cam
and the syntax is as
follows first i'll show the
fsxy construction
the schemes used this trick and called
their twisted pr tonic
to provide the radius resilience so each
party has access case to the two u's for
this trick
and each party has the keypair of cjk
dks as ssk and it gets
rs
svk
in the key exchange session first the
client
generates two randomness for the toeic
and generates our randomness for the cpa
game
and it generates a randomness based on
the tweak then it generates our
ciphertext and the key for the cjk
and generates our keypair for the cpa
game
and sends cg and ekt
to disciple
upon receiving this the server generates
randomness just like their client
and generate ciphertext and keys for the
cta cam and the cba cam
and returned the cybertext
finally each party equips the ciphertext
with its own degradation key
to obtain the shared value
here if we remove the client ssk we get
the naive fsx5 based construction like
this
the trick on the client side and the
computation of the
cj king and the toeic
on the server side are removed
so there is a protocol without the
removed parts it looks vegan construct
always a gay
however
there are two problems with this
construction
first by considering the reveal of
secret value one each
it is easy to compute chem keys
for example rtc and djs
are rebuilt
the adversary can generate dkd from rtc
and
decrypt cd with dkt
also it can degraft cc with dkt degas
therefore it is difficult to construct
on fsxy based
as a solution to this problem we propose
a technique to generate two randomness
from one randomness
it uses a soup random function to
generate from one randomness in this way
then
by releasing rc and rtc in this part
the reveal target for the client
can be
only this all
here i'll show
how to generate randomness for the
technique concretely
we generally generate as follows
first generate one randomness second it
uses a suit random function to generate
2d different values
in the suit random function space
finally it used two suit random
functions to generate two values in each
randomness space
here
can we always in intermediate rc prime
and rtc prime okay
i i'll show that this case
in this case we generate randomness in
this way
but in this example
the osa security cannot be reduced to
the cga security or the cbs security
for example the game randomly the cgi
chem key
in the game the randomness the
randomness of the cj cam is converted to
the
output of the random function in this
way
in this case when always aka adversary
activates
the test session
the institutions
generator need to return the sushi prime
and
shishistan and egdster
but
since simulator does not know
our rooster
so it cannot return the correct egg stir
so it cannot generate
correctly
so
we use three pseudo-random function in
the technique
next the second problem is ep case this
apks
cannot be generate or fly in fsxy-based
contraction
in this construction the server
generates cd based on the ekt received
from the client
so
offline generation is not possible
as a solution to this problem we use
pkic cam for distributed cam
the pkh game allows ciphertext to be
generated independently to the public
key
in this way the cyber text
can be generated independently to the
this ekt
so applying it to the protocol we get
the following protocol
so in this way all
apks can be generated offline before the
session activates
in addition for efficiency by reversing
the pci cam flow
in this way
so we can reduce computation for w
keychain
now i'd like to consider about about
security of our construction
from the freshness if the party has only
one secret key there is no need to
consider re-gauge
so
the crime site leakage is not considered
therefore since the service reveal tag
is
tighter hours and decades
so the leakage pattern to be considered
a only rs or only djs
first leakage of rs
in this case
the adversary can compute kd from rs in
this way but cannot compute casey
without knowing this rs
or this all
therefore it is secure
next
wreakage of the gas
in this case the adversary can con
compute kc with dks
but cannot compute kd without knowing rs
or this our
therefore it is secure
so
next about anonymity of clients the
clients never send information dependent
to him
id and staticy etc
in each session
so
the adversary cannot get any information
about the client from the ciphertext
next i'll introduce our instant agents
this is a comparison of these based
schemes and existing schemes
the over 2 is the first anonymous earth
against games in the standard models and
both schemes reduce the online
online exponentiation cost for clients
finally
the existing schemes are under the gap
dh assumption but r1 is under the
standard cdh assumption and uber2 is
under their standard dj ddh assumption
the next instantiation is the first
quantum schemes from ice genius in the
random oracle model
first
there is sidh based schemes consists of
cgi secure cycle cam and in the gps
secure pk
from sc20
here
this pk is converted to be to
convert to
ow cpa secure pks cam and then it is
used
next
the she said based games consists of the
cc secure seaside pc came from young 21
and should be secure she said came from
crm 18
here
this cam is converted
to the pkh game
in the same way
so these schemes are the first post
quantum schemes in the random oracle
mode
here
i'll introduce how to transform the
psych pk to pkicam
first
we'll remove the first and fifth
computation in ink and the second
and set and computation in deck
since we use the pk as the
cam and since our generic construction
in the random oracle module
is sufficient for their own should be a
secure cam
so
that
this
gm variant is used as a chem key without
passing it through the random oracle
next
we use the first
first and second computation
in anc
as
this wnc
and the third computation
as this
wnk
wn cuff k
and then we can use it as pkh game by
transforming it as follows
the last instantiation is the first
content skips in the random in the
standard models but only seaside based
schemes
the schemes consist of the cga chem
cclcam and the smooth project passing
from afmp20
and sysad came from crm18
here we passed the session key of the
cam through
the entropy smoothing hash function and
constructed it and construct it
as she said cam
and also this cam is compared to the pks
game in the same way
so
the schemes is the first first quantum
scheme in the standard model
finally conclusion
so we proposed generic construction for
osak
anonymous osaki the ones in the standard
model and the ones in the random oracle
models
also we proposed general web generic
construction and we also proposed
instantiation of the generic
construction
so
when the
teach based schemes is the first
dh-based anonymous osa gay schemes in
the standard model
and the ones based uh isogenys and
are the first post-countdown anonymous
osaka schemes
that's it from me thank you all for
racing