hi everybody my name is una fitla in
this presentation i will show you how we
have built a post quantum version of an
asynchronous deniable key exchange
protocol
and how we use this for the signal
handshake
this is trying to work with jacqueline
brendell felix gunter christian jansson
and douglas stabula
first let's review the setting of
instant messaging
alice wants to initiate a conversation
with bob
if both of them are online at the same
point in time this is straightforward
however what do we do if bob is offline
when alice wants to initiate the
conversation
in this case we can use a key server
and bob uploads a so-called pre-key
bundle to the key server ahead of time
then alice when she wants to initiate
the conversation queries the key server
to get bob's pre-key bundle
using this free key bundle she can
compute her first message and sent it to
bob who can read it whenever he's coming
back online
afterwards both of them can keep sending
messages to each other at their
convenience
this feature is called asynchronicity
another feature that we want is mutual
authentication that means that each
party should be sure that they are
actually talking to the party that they
think they are talking to
and the third feature that signal is
looking for is called offline
deniability
intuitively this means that
if you have a transcript of a
conversation then you can deny that you
were involved in creating this
transcript but we will go into the
details of this
more later on
the first few messages so when they
agree when they first agree on a key
this protocol is called the extended
triple diffie-hellman protocol or x3dh
for short
when later on when both parties keep
updating their keys to send new messages
this is called the double wretched
protocol
and let's have a look in more detail at
the initial handshake
here we have again alice and bob and
both of them have a long term key and an
ephemera key in addition bob has a
semi-static key
and first bob has transferred his
pre-key bundle to alice via the key
server
the pre-keep unlock bob consists of
several
diffie-hellman public keys
and alice also has round if you harm on
public keys and pairs them according to
these arrows here so alice's long term
share goes with bob semi static share
and alice's ephemeral share goes with
each of bob's shares
and then alice sends her own to defeat
hermann shares to bob so that bob can
compute the same tiffehaman shared keys
this protocol however is not post
quantum
because it relies on the diffie-harman
assumption which does not hold against
quantum adversaries
so we can see that signal consists of
two protocols
first the initial handshake extended
triple to the helmet which is not post
quantum
and then there's the double registered
protocol which can be replaced with a
post quantum alternative
for example from key encapsulation
mechanisms this was shown by alvin at al
at eurocrypt 2019
and in this talk we will focus on
replacing the initial handshake with the
quantum secure version
key encapsulation mechanisms have been
used as a post-quantum replacement for
the diffie-hellman key exchange in
several scenarios so let's review cams
to see if they fit for our purpose here
as well
bob has a key pair and sends his public
key over to alice alice then
encapsulates against bob's public key
resulting in a ciphertext and a session
key
she sends the ciphertext over to bob who
can decapsulate the ciphertext by using
his own secret key to learn the session
key
now both parties know the secret session
how can we use this to construct a post
quantum version of signal
we could try the following
bob has three chem key pairs a long-term
semi-static and a family key pair he
sends over all of his public keys to
alice and alice encapsulates against
each of bob's public keys
she sends over the three resulting
cipher texts to bob
the problem with this protocol is that
there is no ls to bob authentication
and bob doesn't know if this really came
from alice or if this was actually sent
by charlie
to remedy this we could add a signature
so that alice assigns the three
ciphertexts now bob can be sure that
this message actually came from alice
however alice can no longer deny her
involvement in this session because only
alice herself
can compute this signature
though the idea of using chems for a
post-quantum replacement of signal has
been around for a bit
previously brand led i'll have proposed
to replace the initial handshake with a
primitive they call split cams
however this primitive turned out to be
not instantiable
but let's follow the design idea from
the previous slide of using cams in
combination
with some form of deniable
authentication
and in this work we use designated
verifier signatures for deniable
authentication
separately hashimoto have used ring
signatures for the same purpose
so how do designated verifier signatures
work
alice sends a message m to bob in a
manner that bob can be sure this message
was sent by alice however he cannot
prove this fact to anybody else
so what alice does is she can sign a
message m with her own secret key and
designating designates it to bob by
including bob's public key into the
signing algorithm and this results in an
alice to bob signature
similarly bob can use the simulation
algorithm
to create a alice-to-bob signature by
using his own secret key as well as
alice's public key
and dvs schemes also have a property
called source hiding
which tell you that for each attacker it
is indistinguishable if a signature was
created using the sine algorithm or the
simulate or the simulate algorithm even
if the attacker knows both secret keys
there are some post-quantum dvs
instantiations
which were not published in the
mainstream cryptographic literature so
we believe they are in need of some more
scrutiny
instead we propose to build the post
quantum dvs schemes from two user ring
signatures
we show in our paper how to do this
with this we have the advantage that we
can make use of the big literature on
post quantum ring signature schemes
after we have published our work there
was an update to their work of by
hashimoto at al we showed that you can
build a two user ring signature from a
dvr scheme
so it turns out to user ring signatures
and dvr schemes are actually equivalent
for some security notions
now that we are equipped with a tool for
deniable authentication let's have a
look at the core idea of our
asynchronous deniable authenticated key
exchange protocol
both alice and bob have a dvs key in the
long term key
and bob also has a cam key in his long
term key and ephemera key
it begins with bob transferring his
public key over to alice
and now alice can encapsulate against
bob's long-term cam key and against
bob's
ephemeracam key resulting in two
different cam cipher texts
next alice can
sign these
to camp ciphertext with the dvs scheme
resulting in an alice to borb signature
over these two chem cipher texts
with this we have alice to bob
authentication while retaining
deniability for alice
hashimoto i'll use the same principle in
their protocol wherever they're using a
ring signature instead of a dvs scheme
as promised now let's have a more
detailed look at deniability
the signal specification says that the
initial handshake protocol doesn't give
either alice or bob publishable
cryptographic proof of the contents of
the communication
or the fact that they communicated at
all
in other words
if there is a third party and this third
party has access to private keys from
alice or bob and this third party has
access to a communication transcript
that appears to be between alice and bob
then this transcript can only have been
created by some party who has the
legitimate private keys from alice of
bob
and we have formalized this informal
requirement in the following way
so if we want to have a transcript
there's two ways to get this transcript
the first way is alice executes the
protocol as specified on the previous
slide by using the run algorithm and her
own secret key
this results in a transcript and a
session key
the second case is
bob uses a different algorithm which we
call the fake algorithm this fake
algorithm takes bob's secret key and
adds the results in a transcript and a
session key
and now the third party comes into play
because the third party should not be
able to distinguish
if the run or the fake algorithm was
used to create this transcript and
session key
and even if this third party has access
to the private keys of both parties
this is the deniability definition that
we introduce
and let me point out that there is some
design space to this deniability
definition
in particular
does the fake algorithm require the
secret key of bob or can you run it with
public data
another option to modify this definition
would be
does the judge get all of the secret
keys or does it have to decide based
only on public inputs
and thirdly
is the judge allowed to interact with
the participants during the protocol
execution
or does the judge only learn a
transcript afterwards
there is a deniability definition which
goes back to the remainder from 2006
and compared to their definition
our definition is weaker in the sense
that
our fake algorithm requires the secret
key of bob
however our definition is stronger in
the sense that our judge gets access to
all of the secret keys
and we believe this to be very important
to model the case of for example a legal
judge which is able to subpoena you into
giving up your secret keys
or if the judge is an asian state
adversary that can infiltrate your
smartphone and thereby learn your secret
keys
so all in all these two deniability
notions are incomparable however we
believe ours to be more suitable for the
use case at hand
and another downside of the definition
by the realm onward al is that proofs
for their definition
require some form of knowledge
assumptions in all of the cases that are
known to us so for all the proofs that
we know of
let me also point out that there is some
concurrent work by dobson and galbraith
from last year
and they have lifted the extended triple
diffie-hellman protocol to the setting
of super singular isotonies so they
follow the same blueprint but they rely
on isogeny problems instead of the
diffie-hellman problem
with this they retain the same
properties but in addition they get the
quantum resistance which we were looking
for
and there's also our full construction
so what you've seen previously was only
the core idea and our full construction
is called spqr which is short for signal
in the post-quantum regime
the full construction includes
semi-static keys to model the case where
ephemera keys which are provided by the
key server run out
also we secure our protocol against
randomness exposure
by the use of a twisted prf
we proved the security of our protocol
in a security model analogous to the
original signal analysis from congo net
al
and we also proved deniability of our
protocol with respect to our definition
let's compare the different
constructions for the initial handshake
protocol
so the first one is x3dh which relies on
the diffie-hellman key exchange and is
therefore not post quantum secure
it was recently shown to be deniable
with respect to the definition of the
ram android al
and it is we also conjecture it to be
deniable with respect to strong judges
so our definition
and it covers the full scope of what we
expect that means it covers real world
setting in which ephemeral keys may run
out and where you need semi-static keys
to cover for that
then there are two protocols suggested
by hashimoto at all
relying on cams and ring signatures
the first one is post quantum secure but
not deniable with respect to the
definition of tiramando at all to remedy
that
they added non-interactive zero
knowledge proofs
on top
to get this deniability
and we also conjecture both of them to
be deniable with respect to strong
judges our definition
which is however not proven
though both of them are not full scope
then there's our construction spqr
which uses key encapsulation mechanisms
and designated verifier signatures
it is post quantum and deniable against
strong judges
but not against the definition but not
deniable against the definition of the
realm under at all with the weak judges
though it is full scope
and both the constructions by hashimoto
as well as our sbqr are generic
constructions which you can instantiate
with different cams and ring signatures
nizix and dvs schemes relying on
different problems however this is not
the case for the last scheme six 3dh
which is hard-coded to use sidh key
exchange therefore it is post quantum
and also deniable with respect to the
definition of the real mondo at all and
for scope and we conjecture it to be
deniable with
against strong judges as
well but it's not a generic construction
all in all we are very happy to see that
there is many people working towards
making signal post quantum
and our contribution to that
is our protocol spqr which is a post
quantum replacement for the initial
handshake from key encapsulation
mechanisms and designated verifier
signatures
along the way we have introduced a new
definition of deniability with strong
judges
which our protocol fulfills and we have
shown that you can build dvs from ring
signatures
and then using a post quantum
replacement for the initial handshake
such as our spqr protocol
and a double ratchet replacement such as
the one using key encapsulation
mechanisms from alvin at all these two
in combination can be used to build a
post quantum alternative of signal
thank you very much for your attention
and please check out our full paper on
eprint