welcome to my talk i'm leo i'm going to
talk about updatable encryption
in this work we propose a new definition
for updatable encryption we call it
backward link unidirectional key updates
then we show that back quadratic
unidirectional key updates are strictly
still longer than
the existing ejectional
key updates
we also propose two secure constructions
of updatable encryption
first i review what is updatable
encryption
let's consider the following scenario
i saved her encrypted data on on the
cloud server
her computer is attacked and her secret
key is leaked
to protect her data
she generates a new secret key
she should not only build the secret key
to the cloud server so
she downloads all encrypted data from
the server they give them
equip encrypt them by the new secret key
again
and upload them to the server
this incurs significant efficiency loss
to resolve this issue we use updatable
encryption
in updatable encryption
we can periodically update a secret key
and ciphertext
an updatable encryption scheme has key
generation encryption and decryption
algorithm business as a standard
encryption scheme
and has two additional algorithms
one is the token generation algorithm
we can generate an update token from two
secret keys
in this talk we focus on ciphertext
independent updates where we do not need
a ciphertext for generating the token
the other one is an update algorithm we
can convert a ciphertext under an order
key into one under new key by using an
update token
if alice uses updatable encryption in
the scenario
that i explained first
she generates a new key and an updated
token
then she passes the token to the server
and the server can directly update all
ciphertexts without using alice's secret
key
one issue is whether a token leaks
information about secret keys or not
since the token is generated from two
secret keys
in previous works there are three
categories for key updates
the first one is the bidirectional key
update
we can infer a secret key from both
directions via our token
that is we can infer a new key from a
token and an order key
and vice versa
the second one is the unidirectional key
update
we can infer a new key from a token and
then all the key
however we cannot infer on all the keys
from a token under new key
the last one is the no directional key
update
we cannot infer keys from a token
all previous updatable encryption
schemes have a bi-directional key update
this is not desirable since such token
replicate more information about secret
keys
another issue is whether our token
allows downgrading ciphertext or not
there are two types of updating
one is the bi-directional ciphertext
update where we can both update a
ciphertext and downgrade a cybertext and
a new key into a ciphertext and an org
key
the other one is the unidirectional
ciphertext update where we can only
update the ciphertext
the unidirectional ciphertext update is
more desirable since the token gives
less information to adversaries
however all previous updatable
encryption schemes have bi-directional
key updates
a simple example of updatable encryption
is as follows
a secret key is an element in zp
a token is x sub e plus 1 over x sub e
where x sub e plus 1 is a new key
a ciphertext is an algorithm like
ciphertext
we can update a ciphertext by using the
token since x sub e is cancelled out
it is easy to see that this example is
the bi-directional key update and
bi-directional ciphertext update
the type of key and ciphertext updates
affects trivial winning conditions in
security games of updatable encryption
let's see an example
in the table each number denotes a time
period called epoc
in ue security we consider secret key
corruption and token
corruption in the corrupted key law
x-mark means the secret key is not
rigged
and the check mark means it is legal
in the corrupted token law
xmap means the token is not linked
and check mark means it is linked
in the bi-directional key update setting
we can infer the secret keys of the
second third and the fourth epochs since
we can infer from both directions
in the unidirectional key update setting
we can infer the secret keys of the
second and third epochs
however we cannot infer the fourth
secret key since we cannot infer in the
backward direction in this setting
if advisor is obtaining a secret key
that they want to attack
they can trivially break the security of
encryption
so the bilateral key update triggers
more trivial winning conditions than the
unidirectional key update
this means the security in the
unidirectional key setting
seems to be stronger than the security
in the bi-directional setting
however jam proves that the security in
the bi-directional key update setting is
equivalent to the security in the
unidirectional key update setting
this is surprising since the direction
of updatable encryption does not matter
much
however here is a question
why do we consider the universal key
update where key inference is the
forward direction
we can consider another unidirectional
key update variant where a key inference
is the backward direction
that is we can infer an all the key from
token under new key
but
cannot in the opposite direction
this is a very natural setting
to distinguish two types of
unidirectional key updates
we call the previous in directional key
updates for the credential key updates
let's see the backwardly clean
directional key updates are preferable
to the forward link one
here we assume that the ciphertext
update is unidirectional
suppose that the middle secret key is
leaked
then in the forward leg setting we can
get the newest secret key pr token
in this case even if we securely delete
all the ciphertext we cannot protect the
newest ciphertext
and updating ciphertext does not help us
since the newest key is imported
in the backward league setting
we can get
the the oldest secret key via token
in this case
if we securely deleted all the
ciphertext
we can protect the newest key and
note that i assume that the ciphertext
update is unidirectional
later i add that unidirectional
ciphertext updates could be standard in
the backward unidirectional setting
this fits the spirit of updatable
encryption
in this work we introduced the
definition of backwatering injection key
updates as i explained so far
surprisingly or unsurprisingly we also
showed that the back quadrantic
initiation key updates are strictly
stronger than the ford leak
unidirectional key
updates
this is in sharp contrast to john's
equivalence theorem
more completely we showed that
existing secure ui schemes in the ford
leak injection key update setting are
not secure in the back quadrantic
unidirectional key setting
we present two updatable encryption
schemes
one is secure in the backward link
initiation setting under the learning
with errors assumptions
the other one is secure in the no
directional setting and based on
indistinguishability obviously and one
way functions
this solved the open problem posed by
zhang at aj 52 2020
this is the comparison with previous
schemes
all known schemes are secure in the
bi-directional key update setting
and the bi-directional cybernetics
update setting
by jan's equivalence theorem these
schemes are secure in the forward leak
unidirectional key update setting
we propose the fast secure schemes in
the backquad leak unidirectional and no
directional key update setting
a concurrent and independent work by
slamming and streaks presents a secure
scheme in the no directional key update
setting
however the size of secret key and
ciphertext depends on the total number
of updates
in previous and our schemes
the size of secret key and ciphertext is
constant
let's see the backward leak
unidirectional key updates are slightly
stronger than the for forward liquid
first we see a simple but crucial
observation here
ue needs the power of public key
encryption
all existing ui schemes need pk power
since they rely on concrete assumptions
that imply pka
in addition
rmit montego melee and petroleum proves
that ue implies pk
so we can assume a ue key consists of
the secret key and public key parts
a token is generated from two keys
here and all the secret key is necessary
otherwise the token does not have the
power of converting an older ciphertext
into a new
how about a new secret key
in fact we do not need the secret key
part of the new key
let's consider our token generated from
an all the secret key and the public key
part of a new key
this token potentially converts and all
the ciphertext into a new one since the
public key part
of the new key is sufficient for
encryption
in addition the token does not have
information about sk sub e plus one
beyond the pk sub e plus one
so the token could be backwards leak
unidirectional and could not be used to
downgrade a new ciphertext into an old
one
in fact
our bad quadric injection scheme has
this structure
in contrast a token generated from two
secret keys is forward leak and
bi-directional
note that if we use pk sub e it is not
clear whether a token can convert aside
vertex
now i present a concrete example that is
secure in the bi-directional or forward
leak in directional setting
but not secure in the backwards any
unidirectional setting
john's equivalence theorem says that we
trigger the trivial winning conditions
in the by
direction setting if and only if we
trigger the trivial winning conditions
in the forward-league unidirectional
setting
we consider the leakage condition in the
table
in the by dash bi-directional setting we
can infer the second third and fifth
secret keys via corrupted tokens
as i show in the table the first sixth
and seventh secret keys are protected
in the fourth league setting we can
infer the fifth secret key but cannot
the second and third secret keys
however we cannot set second and third
epochs as a target
since we can convert a ciphertext and
the second and the second and third keys
into one under corrupted keys via
tokens
so
as in the bi-directional setting
setting second and third e-books as a
target
triggers the trivial winning conditions
in the backquadric setting we can infer
the second and third secret keys
but cannot the fifth secret key
here
we can set fifth epoch as a target since
we cannot convert the ciphertext in the
fifth ebook into one or under corrupted
keys in the universal ciphertext update
setting
thus
unlike the four oblique unidirectional
and bi-directional setting
the fifth epoch does not
trigger the trivial winning conditions
this corruption setting shows the
separation result
previous schemes are secure in the
bi-directional or forward-look
unidirectional setting
in the setting we can not set the fifth
epoch as a target
however
in the backward league in ejection
setting we can set the fifth epoch as a
target
non-secure schemes do not prevent
extracting a new secret key from a token
under other key
so it means known schemes are not secure
in the backward league unidirectional
setting
i do not explain security experiment for
ue since they are not crucial to
understanding the difference of
directions in ue
now let's see our construction
first i explain our backwatering
medicinal scheme
the idea is simple
i use fully homomorphic encryption to
explain our idea
a token is the ciphertext orban all the
secret key sk sub e and the new public
key p k sub e plus one
a rectangle denotes encryption under
some public key
a ciphertext is simple encryption of a
message under pk submit
to update the ciphertext
we encrypt the ciphertext by using the
new public key pk sub v plus 1.
then
we homomorphically decrypt the
ciphertext under pk sub e by using the
evaluation algorithm of fat
and get the ciphertext of m under the
new public key p k sub e plus one
this idea is based on fhe
however we directly construct our scheme
by using the key switching technique
so we do not rely on fpg in our scheme
the construction idea comes from
unidirectional perks re-encryption based
on the lw assumption
the token can be generated from an order
secret key and a new public key
so it is easy to see that the token is
backward leaking directional
we can also see that our scheme has
unidirectional ciphertext updates
if we can downgrade a ciphertext by
using a token
we can break the security of the old key
without the old secret key
note that we do not need to use the all
the secret key to generate a token
lastly we see our non-directional scheme
the idea is obfuscating re-encryption
circuit
a re-encryption circuit takes an old
ciphertext
decrypts it
encrypts the result
again
and outputs the re-encrypted ciphertext
a token is an obfuscated re-encryption
circuit
in the circuit the old and new secret
keys are hard wired but they are
protected by the security of obfuscation
so this scheme has the no directional
key updates
it is easy to see that this scheme has
unidirectional ciphertext updates
in our construction we cannot use secret
key encryption in the blog box way since
we use indistinguishability of the
sketching
we use punctuable prfs as secret key
encryption and achieve secure ue
let me summarize my talk
we propose a new definition for
updatable encryption
backward link in directional key updates
we show that existing bi-directional key
update scheme are not secure in the
backwatering directional setting
this is in sharp contrast to jan's
equivalence theorem which says the
security in the bi-directional key of
this setting is equivalent to the
security in the public unidirectional
setting
we propose two new ue schemes
one is backwards rig immediate channel
scheme from the lw assumption
the other one is no directional scheme
from io and one way functions
both schemes have injection ciphertext
updates
our take home message is the direction
of updatable encryption does matter
that's it thank you for watching my talk