hi everyone this is a presentation for
pkc 2022
i'm charlotte lefeber and it's this work
in collaboration with pierre carchmann
and the paper is named time memory
trade-offs for large white syndrome
decoding in ternary codes so we'll first
type with a few definitions on the
motivation of our work
in this work we will be always in the
ternary setting and consider linear
chords where n denotes the code length
and k the dimension
we will study a particular instance of
the fixed weight syndrome decoding
problem the fixed weight syndrome
decoding problem takes as input a
rectangular matrix full rank also called
the parity check matrix then a vector
called the syndrome and an integral
called the weight
the aim is to solve the linear system h
e equals s where there is a constraint
on the hamming weight of the solution
we will restrict ourselves in a case
where the parity-check matrix and the
syndrome are assumed to be both sampled
uniformly at random and the code rates
and weight rate are both fixed
in particular we will be in a setting
where there are many solutions to this
problem exponential in the code length
yet the search space is comparatively
huge making thus this problem hard
the main motivation of our work is the
wave signature scheme introduced by
debris a lazarette al in 2018
its high level view is quite classical
in code-based crypto the private key is
a structural parity check matrix under
public key is a random obfuscation of
the latter making it indistinguishable
from a random parity check matrix
next the signature of the message
consists of solving a syndrome decoding
instance where the parity check matrix
is the public key the syndrome is the
hash of the message and the relative
weight is fixed by the scheme in
particular we are in a high weight
regime
the knowledge of the private key
provides a trapdoor that makes the
syndrome decoding problem much easier
on the other side we must ensure that
anyone with only access to the public
key cannot produce valid signatures
therefore one needs to ensure that the
underlying syndrome decoding problem
must be computationally intractable
so to give a global picture of the state
of the art with respect to the syndrome
decoding problem this problem is easy
for a certain weight range in other
words a polynomial algorithm in the
codelens was formed by french
outside of this interval no polynomial
algorithm is known so the problem is
believed to be hard
in particular the weight used in wave
sneaker scheme is in the horizon but
this is far away from the gilbert
version of bone
note that this is said to ensure that
the syndrome decoding problem in wave
signature scheme is untractable for an
adversary one needs to know about the
best possible attacks at this particular
weight
and this has been studied by bricot at
all in 2019
they use the pg plus ss framework
instantiated with a combination of the
k3 under representation technique and
the cost that they derived is given here
however this cost is in time and in
memory making it making it unattractive
in some applications
that's why we propose in this work to
study the time memory trade-offs for
this problem
so to do this we just started the same
way as bricot at all and used the pg
processes framework which stands for
partial gaussian elimination plus subset
sum
this framework has been formalized by
them and this is a modular description
of what most isd-based algorithms do
here we won't present the framework in
all of its generality since we fixed
some parameters
the first step in the framework consists
of doing a partial gaussian elimination
on some rows of the parity-check matrix
and the number of rows is parameterized
by a quantity called l this is an input
to the to this framework
then we split the syndrome and the
candidate solution according to this
division
the next step is to solve a smaller
problem which is a sort of syndrome
decoding problem and the parity-check
matrix is given by h2 the syndrome s2 in
particular it has l-coordinates and the
solution e2 will have k plus
l-coordinates
we require that it is full weight and
one important difference with the
syndrome decoding problem is that here
we ask for many solutions
and the idea is that for every e2
solution of the previous problem there
exists a unique vector e1 such that the
concatenation of both vectors gives a
solution to the linear system
in particular we solve the syndrome
decoding problem if and only if the
hamming weight of the concatenation is w
and here it translates on the on the
condition on the hamming weight of e1
the desired number of solution that the
step number two is in particular the
inverse of the probability that e1 gets
the right hamming weight
so this framework allowed us to
transform the problem into a slightly
different one so in other words find
many solutions to a smaller sub syndrome
decoding problem
as pointed by brico that al this problem
reduces in reality to the subset sum
problem
moreover asking for many solutions
opened the way to several optimization
and in particular we can require that
solutions are returned in constant
amortized time
to go back on this l parameter this is a
quite important parameter
so from now we denote by sl the desired
number of solutions
to the small sub problem
what is interesting here is that when l
increases the size of s2 is going to
increase thus the problem becomes harder
but on the other side the requirement on
the hamming weight of e1 is going to be
much easier to satisfy
so concretely it means that the desired
number of solution is going to decrease
so this is what we can see
on the first stage of this curve that
plots the logarithm of sl according to l
so this l parameter will be central in a
trade-offs since one l parameter plus a
fixed algorithm to solve the smaller
problem can provide us one trade-off and
usually the memory consumption is going
to increase along with l parameter
so this particular plot was done by
fixing the code length in the wave
regime
note that l equal to zero corresponds to
french algorithm which is memoryless and
recorded uh shows the following l
parameters and it and it could provide
them solution it was able to provide
them solutions in constant amortized
time and in our case we are going to
explore uh the l parameter between these
two quantities
we are now going to see how can we
transform the sub problem into only sum
problem
from now i'm going to drop the two index
notation so that now we want to solve h
e equal to s with e full weight
we are going to use algorithm solving
the only sum problem also called the
generalized birthday problem
so this generalized birthday problem
takes as input our list each list
containing vector and the aim is to find
one element in each list such that the
sum of all of these elements give the
null vector
the syndrome decoding problem can be can
be transformed into all this problem by
doing the following so first we split
the evenly the parity check matrix
columns into our slices we do the same
for the candidate solution
and now the linear system h e equals s
can be rewritten as follow
so now the list l i is going to contain
full weight linear combinations of
columns of h i unless the last list
which
will also have uh the syndrome
subtracted
so this is quite a classical approach
and was for instance used by brico that
are in their work
so here even despite the partial
gaussian elimination done within the pg
processes framework we will be still in
a setting where the desired number of
solution is smaller than the total
expected number of solutions to the sub
syndrome decoding problem here
therefore in particular we are not
obliged to consider all possible full
weight linear combinations in english
each list
thus we have some freedom on the size of
the list
however on the other side we cannot have
lists as large as we want because in
particular each list contains full
weight linear combination of k plus l
over r columns of a matrix
so it cannot be as large as we want and
this is exactly what this constraint
translates
to so the underlying only sum problem we
are going to use algorithms and all of
them enumerate smartly a fraction of the
solutions
we have some freedom on the number of
lists the size of the syndrome and to a
certain extent the size of the list
so here are the algorithm that we
consider
the dissection and the k3 algorithm can
be seen as improvements of the
meet-in-the-middle algorithm and this is
also possible to hybrid them in what we
will call here dissection entry
and this is the algorithm that will
provide us our best instances
the algorithm presented here are able to
return solutions to the early sum
problem in constant amortized time so
with respect to time cost we could first
think that this is optimal
however sometimes the algorithm returned
too much solution
compared to the number of solutions that
we want so that the amortized cost
regime works only when we require at
least a certain number of solutions
and in and if this is not satisfied this
yields a loss
that's why we introduce the notion of
granularity and it's going to help us to
assess if an algorithm is adapted with
respect to this quantity
the granularity is simply the smallest
number of solutions that an algorithm
can return while not changing its
amortized cost
looking ahead the dissection is an
algorithm which is very memory friendly
which has on the other side a
granularity not adapted for many l
parameters and concretely it will only
give interesting instances for small l
parameter that corresponds to quite
extreme tradeoffs
in this work we spent a significant time
trying to lower the granularity of some
of this algorithm when it is too coarse
now i'm going to present the different
algorithms and we start with the k3
the k3 was introduced by wagner in 2002
so for simplicity we required that the
number of lists is a power of 2 so 2 to
the a where a denotes the number of
levels
so here is the example of a k3 with r
equals 8 so that the number of levels is
free
the target is split evenly into three
slices and at each level a meet in the
middle algorithm is applied with one
slice of the target
in our case the tree is balanced so that
the number of written solution after
each each merging is expected to be
equal to the initial list size
we can see that one solution written by
this tree is highly structured since you
require for instance that the first two
elements in l1 and l2 sum on zero on l
of a three coordinates by construction
therefore the k3 decimates the solutions
but this is not a problem in our case
since once again we do not want all of
the solutions so it's even an advantage
and even better than that because
decimating the solution will give an
algorithm with a fine granularity
and if we want more solution we can just
iterate this tree using different
intermediate targets so for example here
we can take an arbitrary vector t
instead of the zero target and here
replace the zero by minus t
now given the constraint that we want
solution in constant amortized time for
fixed l and a parameters there exists an
optimal choice for the list size in the
sense that it would minimize both the
granularity and the memory consumption
and both quantities are asymptotically
equal to three to the l of a
therefore given one fixed l one wants to
have a number of levels as large as
possible
but this quantity is limited because of
the constraint on the list stack that we
mentioned earlier so it emits it limits
the maximal number of levels that we can
use given one fixed l parameter
here are the trade-offs offered by the
k3 algorithm
on y-axis this is the logarithm of the
time cost divided by the codelet and on
x-axis the same for the memory cost
this diamond points is the cost that
bricot i'll found in particular they use
the smooth scale tree algorithm that
i'll mention in a slide combined with
the representation technique that i
won't present here
so going back to the k3 graph here one
point represents the application of the
k3 with one l parameters and the values
of l are increasing from left to right
not worthy is that this graph is made
out of several lines in fact one line
represents the k3 with one fixed number
of levels
for each line take for example the
orange line
it corresponds to six levels
and the right test point is the largest
l parameter such that we can use the k3
with six levels
so for any larger l parameter this
constraint is no more satisfied
therefore the number of levels needs to
be decreased
since in nokia is decreasing the number
of levels leads to a larger memory
consumption this explains why we have
some gaps um in the memory consumption
between when we change uh the number of
levels
in fact there exists a way to obtain a
smooth graph with slightly better
trade-offs this is given by the extended
k3 algorithm presented by minda and
sinclair and adapted in the ternary
setting by bricot at all i won't go into
the details but the raw idea is that the
merging at the first level is unbalanced
and partially dedicated to increase the
list size
and concretely it allows to add one more
level than what the constraint on the
list list size dictated
as we can see on this graph it provides
us a smooth curve on better results than
the k3
so now i will mention the dissection
framework that we explored in this work
too
it was introduced by dinner at all in
2012 and is another generalization of
the meet in the middle algorithm
i won't present the inner working of the
dissection but rather the key ids
so it's a memory friendly family of
algorithm that was designed initially to
be exhaustive so return all of the
possible solutions but it is still
possible to not return them all and
have um
and adapt slightly the granularity
but the the overall granularity is going
to remain somehow coarse
some trade-offs are possible with the
choice of the initial list size but
there are only a few choices that
provide solution in constant amortized
time
and contrarily to the category where the
problem is split in a symmetric way the
dissection decomposes the only sum
problem into a small one and a large one
the smaller problem has its solution
stored in memory while the large one has
a solution returned on the fly and this
decomposition can be done recursively
within the dissection framework
now i will present the possible
tradeoffs
on this plot the rate points represent
the trade-off offered by our dissection
with r smaller than 400
we did not increase r any further and it
would only add more points in this zone
of the graph that corresponds to quite
extreme tradeoffs
this graph was grown using one single l
parameter fixed to
0.0.04 times m
this gray horizontal line represents the
desired number of solutions for this
particular l
and in the dice and the dissection curve
does not reach it so it means that it
cannot return the desired number of
solution in constant amortized time
and the reason for that is that the
dissection has a granularity which is
not adapted here and this is true for a
quite large range of l parameters in
general the dissection matches the
desired number of solutions only for
very small l values
so we tried to lower the granularity of
the dissection and it gives us the
following blood dots but it gives only a
very small improvement
one last remark on this graph is that
after a certain point uh it there is a
little interest in increasing further
the memory because increasing further
the memory would only
give a small gain in the time cost
now that this is said we would like to
extract the best tradeoffs by varying l
parameters and it gives the following
plot where each color represents the
dissection plot
for one l parameter
to obtain only the interesting points we
can extract the outline of the curve
and obtain then this figure
and we can now compare the dissection
tradeoffs to the ones of the k3 so the
dissection outperforms the k3 algorithm
for small memories it is meaningful
since in this zone the dissection
granularity usually matches the desired
number of solutions and we can thus
benefit from the memory friendliness of
the dissection
on the contrary the k3 is less memory
efficient yet its granularity is not
limiting up to large earth values
so so far we have seen two
generalizations of the meat in the
middle which are by instance very
different
then one possibility is to consider a
hybrid version that somehow combines the
id of both algorithm that we'll call
here dissection entry
it's an algorithm presented by dinner in
and the idea here is that the lists are
merged in a tree structure just like
with the k3 but instead of applying the
meat in the middle on couples of list
now a x dissection is applied on list
doubles
so here is the example of one of the
digestion dissection tree that gave us
our best results it is a tree with three
levels and each dissection done is the
four dissection
at the moment we impose that every
dissection done is exhaustive and still
required that solutions are written in
constant amortized time
and we shall not forget the constraint
on the initial list size
in fact i didn't mention this before but
the four dissection is the base case in
the dissection framework and this is the
only one which is symmetric in
particular this is just an exhaustive
variant of the k3
therefore if we unfold in this tree what
happens within the four dissection we
obtain a tree
that has exactly the same structure as
the one of a k3 with six levels so we
might wonder what's the difference
between these two algorithms
one of the main difference between them
is in the merging strategy the k3
decimates solution in the somehow steady
way while the dissection entry is
locally exhaustive
so on this plot the run point represents
the trade-offs with the dissection entry
and the square ones with the k3
additionally there is here a color scale
that represents the value of the
underlying l parameters used for every
point
unless for this particular part of the
curve that i will
mention in a moment
one horizontal line gives two points
with the same l values in particular the
same target size and the same time cost
so now this is clear that the dissection
entry outperforms the k3 since it has a
smaller memory consumption
one possible explanation is that the
layer dissection is going to return much
less structured solution
thus it can explore more candidate
solution within the list
but on the other side for amortized
costs reason the dissection in tree is
going to return also much more solutions
than the k3 yet in this case the memory
consumption is still better
and because the memory consumption is
lower there are more l values such that
we can apply this dissection entry
because the constraints on the on the
list size limits the memory up to this
particular value
one downside with the layer dissection
is that it has a closer granularity
with the k3 the granularity was given by
the initial list size while for the
dissection in three the granularity is
the square of the list size
we can see that granularity problems
appear exactly at this trade-off t
equals m square and from this part of
this point one iteration of the layer
dissect of the dissection tree is going
to return too much solutions so that's
why in particular the curve rebounds
the bottleneck in the granularity was
because of the dissection granularity so
that's why to solve this granularity
problems we consider non-exhaustive
dissection so that its granularity
matches exactly the number of desired
solution
in particular by doing that we decimate
the solution quite rapidly so that the
memory efficiency decreases
it gave us the extra points in brown and
we see the loss in the slope of the
curve
in the case of the four dissection with
three levels by doing that we go back
gradually to what does a classical k3 do
when we increase the memory consumption
but in this case what stops the curve is
the constraint on the list size
one natural idea to extend the plot is
then to apply the smoothing technique on
top of that
and it gave us the following green pots
unsurprisingly the rightmost point
corresponds in fact to the small scale
tree with six levels so at this
particular point the four dissection is
just a four tree without any repetition
of the tree with intermediate targets
now let's see a summary of our results
this is a table with the asymptotic cost
given several trade-offs the first line
corresponds to the cost formed by
recruited al with time equals memory
we can see that when the memory
consumption relative to the time
decreases it is more interesting to
consider larger dissections
not worthy is that the product memory
time which can be helpful as a tool to
compare different trade-offs
is smaller with all trade-offs
and we can see all of the results
plotted on this graph
here this is clear that the dissection
in grey and the k3 in black are all
performed by layer dissection
for small memories globally what works
best is the dissection with two levels
while for larger memory we should rather
use a four dissection with three or four
levels
in this plot the cost computed is
asymptotic and many quantities were not
taken into account for example the
factors when doing operation in f3 to
the m and the polynomial factors in the
cost estimates were omitted
so we refined the estimate of the cost
by taking these quantities into account
the idea here is to have a sort of
intermediate cost between the asymptotic
ones and the full and accurate modeling
of the attack
here is the plot that we derived using
the wave signature scheme parameters
in particular lots of craft disappeared
here because these factors made them
uninteresting to use
for example the four dissection
reforlovers becomes always less
interesting than the full dissection
with three levels
now to conclude in this work we
investigated time memory trade-offs for
a particular instance of the syndrome
decoding problem underlying wealth
signature scheme security
to do that we used the pga processes
framework and instantiated it with the
k3 dissection and dissection entry we
spent a significant time trying to
decrease the granularity of the building
blocks so that it matched it it matched
the desired number of solutions in our
case
so this is all for this presentation i
hope that you enjoy it and i wish you a
nice day