okay actually I was going to kind of
start out with a joke so there's this
camera right here I don't know if any of
you been watching the remote feeds but I
had the privilege to actually watch Paul
as he was giving his keynote on Monday I
know so that camera was activated and
it's just kind of interesting seeing the
backside of the speaker instead of the
frontside speaker as he's giving its
address now I was trying to think of a
joke debt would go along with it and
frankly anything that came up with this
kind of tasteless so if you have
something that you would like to bring
that that's great I love to hear but I
liked that worked out really well didn't
it so what I want to talk about today is
about what Aaron is doing and it's an
interesting place these days so with the
v4 run out and the various strategies
and dealing with in policies dealing
with v4 run out how to get encouraged
people to do with v6 is its it as well
as dealing with s numbers going from a 2
by 2 4 byte ask numbers is a interesting
time and all these things are actually
occurring all at the same time and so
it's it's an interesting place to be and
also these things actually affect you
guys and I know that there's some of you
that actually cross pollinate from that
net augment news to the air in meetings
but not a lot of you and but most of
these things actually as as users of
this space these things do affect you
and I encourage you to be a part of this
process so what I first like to talk
about is our outreach efforts and Erin
actually participates in various venues
many venues that we're not really a part
of and it's amazing to hear about the
lack of knowledge that people have it
goes from what we mean we don't have
infinite supply of ipv4 addresses I can
keep on going forever I don't need v6
that cost me extra money and in sort of
encouraging people that hey you know you
really need to start looking at this
this is an important thing to do same
thing goes with four by two asses
actually we're trying to eat our own dog
food at Erin
and we have v6 enabled internally on all
our boxes and when i connect to various
boxes to do my work is all over v six
and it just works and what we also have
is we have a West Coast facility that
we're pairing with and we're picking
willing to appear with anyone best has a
that's willing to receive a for value s
and then ours is a 93 220 so if you want
to appear with us on west coast please
would be interested matt ryan's ex back
there and willing to talk to you we have
a couple people are doing this now and
so this is great going forward and again
we're trying to eat our own dog food and
this kind of goes beyond just regular
users this goes along with governments
as well governments are starting to get
interested in this because they hear
about this whole idea of shortage and
they feel like there's this sort of
compelling need to regulate the space
and how is the best way of doing that
and we've been spending a significant
amount of time actually educating
various government entities on what is
what is aarons role in this and how
governments can actually play along
another thing that we've done to kind of
help bring this whole idea of before run
out to up front and center to various
organizations it's what we sent out an
announcement to over 15,000
organizations that before run out is
indeed incurring and that you should be
planning for v6 and as an added benefit
now you have to when you get space from
air and you need to get on officers your
company to actually sign off on it
before you get the space
who is cleanup project everybody knows
that who is is a haven for spammers to
get your email addresses and use it for
various nefarious purposes and kasich
went lipa Liz love their their
information atrophied and there's been
various policy proposals I've been
pulling the floor to say hey we really
need to fix this up because this is
almost none useful so we need to go
ahead and fix this and so the first
thing that we've done out is that we are
sending out emails about two thousand a
week to various people say hey look you
need update your records please come to
Erin and make that happen and we're
currently estimating us to be four
months to actually complete as part of
the policy that we're actually following
through on this it also involves
reassignments so that phase one is
actually direct assignments where we
have actually existing relationship with
our customers the second part
reassignments is actually you on your
relationship with your customers and
actually registering that information
with us and part of this policy is
actually going out there and actually
contacting them as well and this is
something that you should be aware of
and say hey look I really need to start
cleaning this stuff up revoked address
space earrings pendants may forget
amount of time where the last number of
years actually say okay look you guys
aren't paying your fees we're going to
go ahead and revoke your space and
reissue it to someone else and you can
see here that we've been quite active in
making that happen you can see that
amount of space that we received here
and we've been very careful making this
happen in terms of okay we're making
sure that this information is the space
isn't routed and if it is we work with
those people and say hey look you really
need to pay off let's get together make
it's a nominal amount so come on guys
let's I get going on this and if
everything fails where the space is
non-routable the people are
non-responsive it stays in a sort of a
holding pattern for a year and then it's
reissued
recovered a asses same thing goes with
recovered a SS you can see that here's
the number of a SS have been returned
including in this is both to bite and
for bite and number of people at the
earlier stages received before by task
and the code wasn't quite ready at that
point and people said look I really need
to use something operationally here give
me a 2-byte ass and I'll come back some
other day 44 by and one of the things
that's now that code is actually
available in working that should no
longer be the case so hopefully you guys
can actually start looking at this and
again encourage you to use a 4 by das
I'm going to talk to stuff about stuff
that's actually an earring gear in my
heart and that is a very sort of
engineering activities that we have
going on within Aaron we have
essentially five different aspects that
we're actually looking at here one is
upgrading our existing services that
we're calling Aaron online and this is
actually a movement to move things onto
the web off of a template based system
using email and one of the things that
this gives us it's a much better sort of
authentication model in dealing with you
guys because right now this whole idea
of using email leaves a lot to be
desired from authentication perspective
we're also looking at improving the IRR
system and right now I know it doesn't
understand anything about v6 and this
isn't so good and we have a couple
people actually in house right now there
are focusing on upgrading the system in
integrating it with our existing
database and hopefully we'll have
something up by the end of q3 this year
so we will be able at that point support
v6 objects within our IR our next thing
is improving who is an AR who is we have
a couple different facilities right now
we're distributing our whois clusters
East Coast and West Coast and have a lot
more boxes and using a lot more
redundancy things that we've learned
from verisign where I used to work
and actually putting all those things
together so you would have a lot more
availability mass human operations team
has done a great job making all that
stuff happen and it's advanced sort of
billing you can say we're actually
looking at a replacement that who is and
there's various proposals on the floor
there's this one effort that's been put
out by the ITF called crisp and there's
a service at verisign a number of others
put out is called iris which is a
replacement to who is that might be one
up opportunity option another option may
be using some sort of web-based restful
based service that we're actually
looking at we're building internally and
hopefully will be piloting some time
over the course of this next a couple of
months next thing is rpki pilot we've
heard a lot of things about hey look
about rot hijacking doesn't happen a lot
but there's this still we have this
glaring hole we have a pilot that's
going to be available very soon now and
we're looking forward to putting that
out and having you guys actually test
drive it and the final part is DNS SEC
rollout we're doing at that again will
be available first part of July what I'd
like to do now is show you just some of
the things that you can do with Aaron
online and you can see here that one of
one of the things that we're trying to
do is make this whole sort all this
information that you're currently
managing sometimes well sometimes not so
well with tickets and so on from Aaron
we're actually creating a management
tool for you on the web and as we move
these services from email into the they
online system you can this information
will start being integrated within the
ticket system because he here here's a
screenshot of what currently exists on
Aaron online and as you go into the
ticket details you can see information
in terms of okay what's been going on in
the correspondence who's responding to
whom at what times and so on and so
forth so you have all this information
readily available on the web and one of
the other things that you can do is you
can actually easily update your your
pocket permission your organization
information on the web
right now and as we do this whether the
things that we like to do is we start we
like to start taking back those
templates and saying okay look this
stuff is on the web go ahead and make
this happen and this is going to be true
for all those things are kind of
one-offs things like organization
templates and POC templates and so on
this does not involve swip which is a
lot of people have automated and we like
to start working on a solution for that
but we're not going to be dealing with
that immediately but it's something that
we're looking forward to actually
replacing as well who is you can see
where that were just like every other
part of the Internet we're just growing
growing growing and we had some peaks
here at at the end of last year where
we're seeing over 120 queries per second
which is actually not too bad and the
system was able to handle it without
sweat next thing that we have going on
is our pki but you see here is work on a
resource certification this information
is actually thanks to it right we're
actually taking our code and porting it
within our system and it's a first part
of a hopefully multi-stage process and
putting this information together and it
will allow you to actually start playing
with these things issuing things called
Roiz and and seeing how it can actually
validate within your systems and so and
so forth so all this information will be
coming very very soon and finally what I
want to talk about its DNS SEC DNS SEC
is actually coming we're very close to
we're doing our testing right now where
we're going to be signing the zones that
were authoritah for all the slash eights
you can see a couple examples 24 dot in
a tarp all the way to 216 dad or DARPA
and we're doing this in two phases phase
one is actually signing the zones and
we'll be rolling this out on July first
and the second phase is actually
inclusion of DS records where you in
turn can let us know that your zones are
signed and that is dependent on the
provisioning system that we're putting
within air and online and we estimate
that to be done ready I first quarter of
2010 and you can see the specifics I at
that website or at the URL at the bottom
of the screen there or at the bottom of
the foil and you can actually follow
that and you can get the trust anchors
and everything else that you need it
very much
it is finally the right model which
they've been doing this for about three
years now so other stuff is fairly well
well formed in mature and we're ready to
go one of the other things I like to
talk about is the policies as I
mentioned before Aaron is in interesting
times right now with the before run out
and v6 adoption and there's just a lot
of information that's going across
whether it go from directory services
hey we need to have better data accuracy
and that kind of butter but forward this
a POC clean up that we've put out the
other thing is v6 for community networks
should they have a special exemption for
space global I a no to our IRB for
policy how does I Anna actually allocate
space recover space that that's been
given back by the community given to I
Anna and how does it come back to the
rirs making sure all those things that
were somewhat informal when for making
them more formalized now transfers that
actually is embodied and Aaron's policy
2009 dot one right now which was
actually a little bit controversial
because it had there's a policy has put
in place last year the board actually
put had these emergency provisions that
they invoked there was a little bit of
churn dealing with this and in the note
was actually it was good to see the
community came together and said okay
this isn't quite rate this is what we
want we'll put it together what you guys
have made is pretty close and they made
the modifications and now it's a policy
dealing with visa at dealing with
multiple discrete networks this is
actually a hole in the policy framework
right now and needs to be fix this
therefore before but not for v6
extending the life of 16-bit are two x
KS assignments Paul VIX did you came up
with a term of bike how many bits in a
byte and the final part is that there's
a lot of a lot of talk about what to do
with v4 run out and should we start
actually giving out less space as we get
close to the end and it's just a good
idea and that does again sort of a
controversial sort of thing extensive
the life
before by how much I don't know but the
whole idea here is hey look we got to
start feeling moving to be six people
might need a little bit of before the
bootstrap again but that is just a
little bit controversial next thing is
dealing with participation we really do
like to see your voice being heard with
an errand in the fall the meeting in
dearborn we're going to have a joint
meeting and given that the waiting
matters are going on I know most you
guys don't follow policy or care too
much but it does affect you and and
there's also things that you said golly
you know Aaron's evil place they have
all these evil policies that you know I
have to follow their dark Oni and all
this other kinds of hoo-ha well this
isn't really weird once I actually are
implementing these policy but you are
the ones that are actually putting these
policies together and if you don't like
them come to the floor and help help
make these things better and we would
really encourage that and to actually
follow through on that set if you're
Aaron member is free for you guys to
come to the Aaron meeting they have
great food so you know if you want your
belly filled that's another way of doing
it and the other thing that we have is a
fellowship program or we have one person
from each region we have essentially
three regions United States Canada in
the Caribbean islands and in in each of
those regions we actually will select a
person from that region to come to an
errand meeting where all the expenses
are paid and again all this information
is available on the web at the URLs down
below so again this is a very open
Aaron's a very open place we'd love to
have your input we'd like to go forward
we want to do the best for the further
internet and so and so forth so any
questions he'll put you guys to sleep
alright well thank you