the bright side in pretend it's a golf
score okay I'm going to talk a little
bit about list for those of you planning
to sleep through yet another
introductory tutorial type session on
list you're going to be disappointed
because I have only about four review
slides and what list itself is and
actually talk mostly about some new
technology that we've developed to make
least list easier to deploy at the sites
enough briefing on what's going on in
the IETF and then some probably familiar
stuff about what's going on with the
implementation Polly meant there's a
little bit of change their the most
press the most interesting development
there I'll give away the secret now is
that there really is work happening for
in iOS for this implementation and then
I'll have the usual spec references with
the slight twist and then some QA so uh
as you can i'll show you can see on the
title slide this is actually the work of
a bunch of different people two of whom
are also here namely Andrew Parkman is
here and Dave Myers here I guess I was
picked to come and give this
presentation because of a burning desire
to see Philadelphia and to visit east
coast weather where you can get a
workout in and a shower all at the same
time as I discovered during the hail
storm yesterday that was kind of fun
being in Northern California the weather
is really boring in the summer so this
is actually kind of an exciting change
anyway uh so getting back to a little
bit of history as I said they're going
to be about for briefing review slides
what provoked this whole Lisp effort
basically there was a workshop held back
in October of 2006 sponsored by the IAB
a bunch of people got together who were
concerned about scaling of the internet
particular scaling of the Internet
routing system and that's kind of what
originally motivated us to put the list
stuff together it actually came up over
during a dinner conversation that we had
back in October and it's since then no
kind of preceded in fits and starts
through various working group various
IETF working groups various operations
groups you know the usual nanog you /
cot right etc and is now actually maybe
seeing some of the light of day at some
point not too distant future
again it was motivated by a desire to
scale the routing system this is a
picture that everyone's probably seeing
thousand times by now actually brief
survey who here has seen a list
presentation before I expect to see just
about every hand in the room go up ok
good that means the review can be very
short anyway as I said it was motivated
originally by this graph you know growth
of the routing state it's up into the
right it's obviously not linear it's
somewhere between quadratic and
exponential we think according to Jeff
Houston's curve fitting and it continues
to proceed despite the global economic
meltdown one of the interesting things
about the pattern on this graph is if
you look at the period between 2001 and
2002 there's a clear flattening that was
the bursting of the internet bubble we
don't see a similar flattening up in the
upper right hand corner of this slide
even though the economic decline is much
more pronounced than it was back then
that's interesting i don't know if it's
something to be worried about or if it
just reflects a different sort of
economic slowdown that predominantly
affected the internet in 102 but is
affecting everything now one comment on
the upper right hand corner you see a
spike there and apparent decline and
then a resumption of the curve that's
actually not a decline that's a change
in the data collection I guess Jeff lost
one of his bgp feeds so a bunch of more
specific routes that were contributing
to his count went away the curve has
continued up using pretty much the same
pattern as the saying goes i have some
good news and some bad news the good
news is and this is going to plug a URL
that I guess is visible more on there
than it is on here of a slide
presentation that Jeff is planning to
give at some point in time that actually
suggests that stability of the BGP in
the global routing system has actually
improved over the past year which is
something of a surprise it's it suggests
that maybe we don't have to worry quite
as much about the rate of change causing
causing problems with cpu utilization
memory speed etc as the saying goes you
know we're not that sure of our facts
their quote mr. Spock from us a famous
star trek episode but so
you know the bad news is the trend is
still up into the right we're not that
sure about the data multi-home and
particular multihoming is still hard and
one of the nice things about list
because it actually makes the
multihoming problem easier to solve not
only for the global routing system but
also for sites it actually gives you
some traffic engineering and some other
kind of site pairwise source to
destination site optimizations that you
can do that you really can't do with the
global routing system and sending more
specifics Dave did you have a question
or comment you will quickly stood up for
a second no was it something good go ok
so what is list basically it stands for
a locator ID separation protocol it's a
way of taking the internet address space
and creating to address to numbering
spaces out of it one is a set of
endpoint identifiers eid s for short
that are assigned to host they're not
routed on the global routing system so
they don't contribute to the routing
system growth the other are a set of
routing locators or are loads that are
topologically assigned for most
practical purposes that means provider
assigns and they're used for a global
the actual global routing system the BGP
between providers what that separation
allows us to do is it allows a couple
things it allows first of all it means
that we can actually use both
topologically significant numbering for
the routing system which is the best way
in fact the only way we know to make a
scale but we can also have topologically
independent assigned numbering for the
sites which allows you to have things
like provider portability avoidance RB
numbering etc when we came up with lists
there were a bunch of kind of rules that
we set for ourselves not surprisingly
since most of the authors are Francisco
it's a network based solution rather
than a host based solution there are we
don't want it but that actually was more
driven by the second bullet which is we
don't want to have to change the
installed base of hosts and there are a
lot more hosts out there than there are
core routers and in fact a lot more
hosts and there are endpoints and site
routers no addressing changes again for
things within a site
animal configuration changed even to
things that have to change and it has to
be incrementally deployable as Tony Lee
said during I think an rrg meeting a
couple years ago you know deployment
wins you can't deploy something there's
really no point in designing and it's
addressed family agnostic in other words
it works for ipv4 and ipv6 and various
combinations of the above so this slide
and this ello plug for Dino all of the
non boring or less boring i should say
slides that have more than just text on
them are done by gmail because our
graphical wizard in addition to being
our implementer but it looks like all of
our animations are gone because we're
using the PDF anyway this is kind of a
very brief overview of how this works on
the left side of the slide you can see a
source right side is a destination
source wants to talk to the destination
it has an eid for a particular host
within the destination typically
returned by the DNS that's where you see
the little DNS entry here it looks just
like an IP address but it's not globally
routed to get from the source to the
destinations it's not globally routed
there needs to be some sort of translate
it's not really a translation it's an
encapsulation that gives you a globally
routable routing locator for that
particular Eid the way that that works
is the source will send a packet the
source host sends a packet just as if it
would send any other TCP open UDP packet
whatever to its exit router which is a
ITR our ingress tunnel router the ITR
will then encapsulate it with an outer
header that is routable and in keeping
the inner header that has the source eid
to the destiny ID and then an outer
again an outer header that has a source
locator going to a destination locator
which is globally routable I'll talk in
a minute about how it finds the
appropriate mapping it then sends that
packet off into the Internet towards
whatever the routing destination is for
the destination locator in this case
since this source is connected to
provider be it's going to send it to
provider be provider be will will route
it to provider ex since the destination
arlo is on provider ex is topologically
assigns
network it will get to the destination
the destination will look up the
appropriate mapping and then we'll send
back the response to the source which
then can install an entry in its cache
and then can send packets from source to
destination using an outer header with
the source and destination locators
added to the inner header that has the
source and destination the IDS that was
a lot to say and hopefully you've seen
this as I said hopefully you've seen
this sort of stuff before so this is a
review if you are interested in more
tutorial information let me know we have
tons of presentations I can point you to
one of them a couple things to note down
at the bottom the mapping entries have
some simple policy that allows the
destination to control which of its
locators and others which of its entry
points from its providers to its site
are used and for what proportion of the
traffic they should be used the
priorities control which are preferred
absolutely over others where the weight
controls whether it should be some
proportional loading across the
different locators along with as I said
in the previous slide I would talk about
how you find the appropriate epr for a
particular destination the ID well
that's where this thing called Lisp alt
comes in basically what list fault is is
it's an overlay network of tunnels we
spec out GRE tunnels in the in the the
RC or they draft in fact any tunneling
technology can be used with BGP running
over it so that the Eid prefixes are
advertised on an alternate logical
topology that's what we all stands for
of these tunnels so that something
connected to the alt virtual network can
get to etrs that are advertising the e
IDs into the alt network by doing so
they can get a map request from the
source to the destination which then can
respond on the underlying internet with
the appropriate locators a couple
different classes of all devices could
be a ETR and ITR that is connected using
GRE and bgp a map server map resolver
those are the new technology that we're
going to talk about in the next couple
slides
or it could be just an alt router which
is basically could be an off-the-shelf
Linux system doesn't have to be a
high-performance router just running GRE
and and bgp to connect to this virtual
overlay Network here's a again no Greta
no animations do you notice me very
disappointed that they didn't make it
but this is kind of graphically how you
use alt to find the appropriate et are
basically source has the source location
the source host has a PID that it's
received from the DNS I basically sends
it off again to its exit router which is
a ITR the ITR has in the normal alt case
the ITR has a bgp connection energy
every connection to the virtual network
it basically just routes on the
destination eid which puts the traffic
on to the virtual network routed across
the virtual network to the appropriate
ETR that originated in an advertisement
or that eid the ETR can then look at the
map request look up the locators for the
particular destination and return a map
reply a couple things to note if you
look in the upper right hand corner you
can see two examples of each yards that
are advertising BG few routes into the
alternate apology then you can see an
alt router that's aggregating them the
idea here is that the alt topology is a
virtual topology so we can basically
dictate how it's connected it's just
tunnels you can check if you need to
move from one point in the topology to
another you just change a tunnel you
don't have to change who you're actually
connected to so we think that the alt
will be pretty well aggregated and will
doesn't have to be perfectly aggregated
but because we can control the topology
it can be the other thing to note is the
blue line at the bottom here that's a
map-request that's the map reply that's
going back under over the underlying
technology I mean the underlying
internet topology basically from a
locator two locator it doesn't have to
go back over the alt virtual network
only the requests go that replies do not
so this map server basically it's the
easy way to talk to alt one of the
complaints we got when we came out with
the alt spec was you guys are talking
about doing you know making multi-homing
easier well one of the hardest things
about doing multihoming at least we've
heard from enterprise sites is doing BGP
and you know we've replaced regular vgp
with all BGP well a lot of people know
that's just as difficult as much of a
pain as regular BGP so what map server
does is it actually allows you to move
the DGP function into the alt routers
only and just use analogously to map
resolvers and map server or DNS servers
and DNS resolvers we have map servers
and map resolvers we're basically an ITR
just has to be configured to know where
its map resolvers our sins sends the
request there the resolver talks to the
alt puts it puts the route 20 outs the
map-request appropriately over the alt
to other alt routers to possibly a map
server that that is now advertising the
Eid prefix on behalf of its its etrs
that also don't have to run BGP now
there is a we use a IPSec authentication
header at the edge before the
communication from ETR to the map server
so that you don't have to have as much
static configuration and there is
authentication the ETR is still the
source of truth for a picker eid mapping
it advertises it using this
authenticated map map register mechanism
to a map server which then is what what
propagates it out onto the alt again
itrs only have to know about appropriate
map resolvers which by the way can be ma
anycast would expect instead of having
to do bgp and connect to the alt one
thing to note here that you'll see in
the next slide is that the ITR is
actually encapsulate the map request
that they originated inside them an
additional list petter because the outer
header needs to contain locators
in other words that essence the resolver
yes the resolver destination IP
addresses are our globally routable
locators while the while the actual
destination for the map-request is an
eid so you need to be able to route that
across possibly multiple internet hops
using a globally about the router bolt
locator before you can put on the all we
expect that most mapserver map resolve
or functionality will be in existing alt
routers although you can certainly
implement that using a separate box that
implements both the map server map
resolver and alt again this is kind of
the easy way the other ways the hard way
easy way you know contrast here's where
we show X TRS connecting using a map
server and nap resolver on the
right-hand side we have etrs that are
connect an ETR up in the upper
right-hand corner that has registered
with this alt router with MS and it
means mapserver the map server is now
responsible for propagating that Eid
into the alt instead of the ec are doing
itself and the upper left-hand side we
have an ITR needs to send a request for
a particular Eid prefix it's going to
just send it to a nearby map resolver
that it has configured the map resolver
now and as we see the upper pup row here
we show the extra layer of encapsulation
ITR needs this needs to look up a
mapping for 241 11 creates a map request
using itself as the source our lope
destination eid and then it puts an
additional header on top of that so that
it can route it to the map resolver
which may or may not be directly
adjacent to it by the way I'm going
pretty quickly all this stuff i think is
reasonably well described in the
appropriate internet-drafts which will
be referenced at the end the alt now the
map resolve our what it's going to do is
it actually will strip off the outer
header since it is the destination it
will then take the original map request
that was generated forwarded across the
all to a map server which will then put
in a dick but another header back on it
because it needs to route to
the destination ETR which is not
connected to the alt and therefore
cannot use the Eid prefixes as
destinations then just as with any other
map request processing the ETR looks up
the destination Eid and returns the
appropriate map reply with the locators
across the underlying internet topology
without going through the author or
through the map server a map resolver
this is kind of another view of the same
example that's showing kind of the
detail of the extra layer encapsulation
again the ITR wants to send a wants to
look up a particular destination 241 11
it's going to create a map request send
it to one of its map resolvers in this
example 1 1 1 1 265 111 again these are
globally routable regular internet IP
addresses map resolver will take off
that layer of encapsulation route it
across the alt which could be any number
of intermediate alt routers the to a map
server map server then puts another
header on it still the same map request
but it needs to get it to the ETR so it
needs to put our Lopes on the outer
header sends it to the ETR bpr then
returns the appropriate reply directly
from etrg ITI just one quick slide again
for an EGR to advertise a particular a
ID prefix into the alts no longer
connected to the alt it now has to do a
list map register which has an
authentication header on it sends to one
of its config well actually to all of
its configured map servers saying you
know I am the source for I'm the source
of information for this particular Eid
prefix here's my art here's my locator
set the map server then takes that and
advertises it into BGP onto the alt
which then propagates to the other alt
routers and is therefore available for
map for map resolvers to use again both
mapserver am map resolver are running
BGP and
GRE while the ITRs and etrs or not the
trade-off here is that more work for the
people of ministering map resolvers and
app servers and the alt but they're
being paid to do that less work for the
site administrators who have other jobs
like running their site one thing to
note is this interoperates with
traditional etrs and itrs that are
running alt basically the map reserve of
the maps maps resolve our map server
just participating they'll just like any
other device so as far as the other I
far as the traditional all connected
etrs and ITR concern there is no
difference this is one final slide on
map server that kind of shows dino's
concept of you know several different
layers of you know edge x TRS kind of an
intermediate layer of map servers and
map resolvers to provide a you know a
interface a simplified interface to the
alt core ok switching gears a little bit
that's the new technology part of the
presentation won't talk a little bit
about where Lisp is going in the IETF
Lisp actually has a pretty long history
pretty much almost from the beginning
with the ITF as I said it was invented
during a dinner conversation at the
routing addressing workshop IV sponsored
writing addressing workshop back in
October of 2006 we started then talking
about it at the following november two
thousand six IETF in San Diego we had
presentations at pretty much every IETF
either in the ROG one of the working
groups to grow working group internet
area routing area etc in 2007-2008 there
was a experimental Lisp off in Dublin
back in july of 08 it's not clear what
the weather this was an experiment with
the ball process or whether it was an
experiment talking about lists but it
was not exactly a success there was a
lot of confusion and we're not really
sure what came out of it meanwhile
there's been a lot of discussion on
various mailing lists in particular
the ROG list created some lists lists
etc and we actually actually was a list
a real list off chartered at the ice at
the IETF in san francisco back in march
and at that point we had you know kind
of review of all the lists
internet-drafts discussion about whether
to go forward with their working group
and as a result a working group has been
created that will meet for the first
time in july at the stockholm ittf
Darryll Lewis one of the list
co-conspirators is co-chair and Sam
Hartman who has a long history with the
IETF working as a co-chair and other in
other aspects of the IETF process is the
other co-chair in the last month the
cordless documents have all been renamed
as working group documents and there are
a couple of new drafts that have come
out independent of the cordless team
that discuss other attributes of lisp
and other ways to be used other mapping
database proposals etc it's actually a
pretty exciting time and we expect some
some lively discussion at the san
francisco at the stockholm idea quick
review of the implementation status the
original imitation is on under cisco
nx-os which is kind of the data center
product operating system it's originally
linux-based with a whole bunch of other
stuff on top of it our test platform is
a thing called we call a titanium it's
basically a pc with a bunch of gigabit
ethernet the implementation includes
list all interworking mapserver map
resolver and this thing we call league
for you know taking a page from the
definition of ping it's the list
internet groper diagnostic tool for
actually testing the mapping lookups
it's today its software switching only
it does support ipv4 and ipv6 both both
as both the underlying and the
overlaying protocols in any combination
I Tre Tre and PTR limitations and
there's list NAT for ipv4 only there is
really iOS implementation in the works I
don't have any dates or
a trained information or anything of
that sort but it is being worked on the
initial target is expected to be BTR
type devices that will implement the
loci d split functionality there's some
thought about doing an XR implementation
for using you for implementing traffic
engineering ITRs and ecr's kind of
within the network that talk is
currently a preliminary there has been a
open list of implementation for freebsd
out there for a while currently testing
the specs and working on
interoperability we've heard that
someone has has been working on a list a
native linux implementation and that's
something that we'd be really interested
in and would like to see more of if
there any other efforts we don't know
about we'd love to hear it pilot network
I'm going to skip right through this
come out of time uses a titanium
platform we use a couple of different
prefixes one thing to note is the year
GRE tunnels that make up the alt
infrastructure are using 240 / 4 for
those who say that you can't use to
force us for well you can in some cases
and we're using 32-bit essence to try to
push the state of the art this is a kind
of a map an overview of the pilot
network topology it's about 30 or so
sites there's kind of a core that
represents geographical distribution in
the middle there's Europe region there's
an americas region there's a South
America region and there's an asia pac
region with the different sites
logically connected via alt to those
those core sites deployment we do have
interworking deployed both there are two
actually actually two different Nick
business of interworking there's one
based on what we call a proxy tunnel
router which is a device that implements
list on the inside but also advertises
coarse-grained information of Eid
prefixes into the global routing system
and then there is also list mat
implementation both those are documented
in the interworking document we have
both of them running kind of in a in a
pilot mode and as you can see from the
site these URLs there actually are ways
to reach and use both of them
as I said earlier or as I implied
earlier by all the ITF effort this is
something that's that we've been trying
to get out into the community since the
beginning it's an open effort it's not a
cisco effort there's no IPR on this
stuff all the documents are
internet-drafts all are intended for to
go through the standards process and we
are actively seeking other
implementations and other implementers
designers testers etc if you're
interested please let us know and if you
are actually from one of the list beta
sites in your here and I haven't met you
out I would actually love to meet you in
person on a personal note so please come
and find me at some point here's the
list of internet-drafts as you can see
the the five core documents have all
been named renamed as working group
documents there are also a couple
several other drafts that discuss
implications of lists that aren't
necessarily protocol documents or are
working preliminary progress the
documents circled in red down at the
bottom or are all either researchy
documents or are things that we're not
currently pursuing and that's basically
it here are the references public
mailing list for the ITF list working
group there's the contact information
for the core list team and there's lots
more information including tutorial
presentations etc at the list for net
and list six net web sites and that's
all I have so if there any questions or
comments before we break for the break
this is a good time to offer them don't
want to keep anyone between between here
and coffee and snacks so hopefully this
will be quick Dave Vince I just want to
say that there is a Linux implementation
it hasn't been released yet it's been
written by these guys rock a Galliano
and a few others of his friends down in
Uruguay right and they expect to release
that I I saw I talked to him at the lac
netmeeting a couple weeks ago about this
and they expect to release
our code this month okay it's do you
know do you know offhand if there's is
based on open list or is it entirely
independent it's entirely independent
okay that's interesting it actually runs
on either linux or ns3 oh cool Oh 11
comment kind of referring to the last
presentation we hope that this will not
be an overnight success that takes seven
to ten years also I guess you re I think
you're next yeah so yada yada co
ericsson so i had a little bit of
additional information about the IPF
stuff and then a couple of requests so
the additional information is that we've
been getting a lot of proposals in this
space and the grouting scalability
multihoming and so forth recently and we
are considering other approaches as well
so for the Stockholm IETF which is
coming up in a month we actually are
talking about something called a
multipath TCP which is basically
something that looks like a regular TCP
for applications but it's actually
multiple TCP sessions between address
pairs on the wire and this is slightly
different trade off of of a solution
than than less but it basically allows
you to pump more data through then you
would be able to do with as a single TCP
session if you had multiple interfaces
so that's one thing that is is possibly
happening and the request part is is
that if you care about this space please
come to the least working group come to
the multipath TCP bath come to the ROG
the meetings are at the end of july in
stockholm and also if we're really cool
if we could test some of this stuff not
just list but they're also the other
things and both least and the multipath
TCP are targeting experimental
specifications which means we're not
quite sure that they are ready for real
life white deployment we know that they
have problems that they probably have
unknown problems as well but it was
really good to look at this stuff a
little smaller scale and find out you
know how well it works or doesn't work
so please consider that yeah just to
just emphasize Lisp is certainly not the
only work in this space we think it's
probably the farthest along is because
we've been working out for so long but
and but there are a lot of questions
that are still unanswered and the list
working group itself has a pretty
restricted charter but there will be a
lot more discussion of other solutions
at the next data queue right there's
plenty of solutions in rhe space but
only two are right now being discussed
in the ice yep and then we had to beat
the old fossils and sim sex which is
working group it's just completed this
work right next the front Mike if you're
up next yep that's straight down from
NIST means can you go to site 1313
okay previously there was a lot of
discussion about the first packet delay
and loss with the I mean with your map
servers and map resolvers is there
something here that that cuts down on
the first packet delay the response to
the map request there's nothing that
directly cuts down on the first packet
delay we are looking this is actually a
little bit beyond the scope of this
presentation but one of the things we
are looking at is mechanisms for doing
caching at the resolver which would
eliminate the delay for all the clients
of a particular resolver that need to
talk to any of the sites that have been
contacted by another one and one of the
things to note is that unlike like a DNS
or an ARP cache entry the cache entries
for the Eid to our locator mapping are
basically entire sites so the first time
that's the first time anybody behind a
particular resolver contacts Google
anybody else that's using that resolver
would not suffer the first packet delay
but no we're not looking at doing we're
not looking at holding packets or trying
to propagate them we the alt spec does
talk about the concept of a data probe
where you can actually forward the
initial packet across the alt that's
something that we can certainly consider
if the first packet delay is a major
issue but we think that that just has
some really bad scalability properties
but I just said we're looking at adding
more caching at the edge at the map
resolver to deal with that as for dos
attacks well the existence of the map
resolver by in effect protects all the
alt routers from dos attacks because
since the ITRs don't have direct access
to the alt writers they don't have any
routes they're not part of that the the
alternative topology there is no real
way to get the Gauss packets into the
alt system the other thing is that just
like DNS resolvers map resolvers can be
any cast so that gives you a way to
spread out a das attack among multiple
targets and reduce the severity of it
that's a good question it actually is
something that would be worth discussing
on the list mailing list
if you're doing caching that's great
that's what I was okay we're not doing
it right now but with something that is
with something we're looking at the
initial spec because we're trying to
keep it very simple does not call for
caching because there are some
differences in the implement caching
then you have to change the request
response dynamics so that the resolver
instead of simply forwarding the request
it actually has to carry state for every
request so that it can receive that
replies and cash them we've had that
we've got some ideas on how to do that
the map server map resolve respect does
allude to that but we're not
implementing that on day one because we
want to experiment with small steps
before we take these days but certainly
on him back Mike Sandra Murphy Sparta
doing business as cobham analytics
solutions sorry about that you may have
heard me say words yesterday about
origin authentication and bgp was an
absolutely necessary and we had to do it
first step for everything yep so slide
10 please so I see etrs registering site
eid prefixes with only a pairwise trust
model and maybe having eaten the green
berries on one bush and making a really
bad stomach ache makes me leery of all
berries on all bushes but that sure
sounds like origin authentication
validation necessary being my answers
yet another protocol right now I'm more
than a decade from retirement maybe this
is just good fodder for interesting
stuff to work on for it okay well you
know let me let me let me refer back
actually to the original spec on that
these basically the authentication
mexico's we're using bgp we basically on
the all the alt will be able to take
advantage of whatever bgp authentication
mechanism is a mechanism is created for
origination at the point where a map
server receives the request from a map
resolver i mean from up from an ETR
we're not trying to solve that problem
on our own because there's been tens of
years of work already on things like SPG
PSO bgp etc and the whole cider trust
model for the
certificate delegation all that stuff
that's all equally applicable to all bgp
as it is to global bgp okay so when the
map server starts advertising the prefix
yep they're going to be doing it in BGP
announcements with the same sort of
origin authentication so the site of
work applies on the all correct and and
the authentication header between the
ETR and the map server is a pairwise
thing that has established out of band
between the administrators okay thank
you that good is that your answer is
that what you're looking for I sure hope
so okay great two more questions and
then we are way over time so we're going
to quit after that yes hey Parker given
how long locator ID stuff has been
chatted about with a desire to pursue it
it's really nice to see this kind of
progress on something pragmatic well
thank you it's something that's been
talked about for since the 1960s
actually more recently in about 20 years
ago when the whole I PNG effort was
getting along milk kappa talked about it
the people that invented ipv6 kind of
totally missed the boat on this and now
we've decided that well this is
something that's really fundamental that
we have to now retro fit in and that's
what we're trying to do but continues
yeah these v6 largely dodged the
question of being created with with
addressing and and the stuff back 20
years ago that was frustrating was they
were there were ideas but there were
details and he can't really make
decisions about without the details
right and one interesting thing to note
of course is that one of our co author
is no kappa who's been a great proponent
of this over the years did notice that
yes in looking over some of the
documents they're all appropriately
technical and focused on the how and
what it didn't come across and what
might actually help
the recruitment effort and later the
adoption effort is something which is
essentially a non technical document
that talks about value proposition and
cost-benefit where the cost part is
designed to address people's fears so
for example the use of DNS for lookups
with packet handling was a huge fear in
the discussion 20 years ago and you've
overcome that and but you're going to
run into all sorts of resistant because
it's a deep psychological point right
we're already seeing that on various
manless sure but but a fairly brief
discussion which says here here are the
benefits being pursued and here are the
costs we think we have under control do
I detect a volunteer yeah I knew you
were going to say I would love I would
as I've heard said before I would
welcome suggested test suits and why
would welcome to suggest I want even
collaborate but I don't actually know
any of the details here and so I can't
say anything but I'm certainly willing
to work on it okay contact us offline
last question Ron bonica one of the
things that traditionally is made IP
unicast 40 well rather work so well is
that things that happen in the
forwarding plane don't cause state to be
creating things that happen in the
boarding plane don't cause control state
to be created okay list may bend that
rule a little bit and that there are
caches that are required that you need
to be built and when you have a cash you
have to worry about it being overrun and
being attacked all that sort of thing if
you given thought the how you deal with
the problems of caching I'm not really
the right person asked that question but
yes we have and Dino in particular has
because he's done all the implementation
work but there are I mean certainly at
the IP layer what you said is true that
there aren't dependencies for unicast
but if you look at our PI mean art by
definition is state this created on
demand and is a cash well so there is a
there is a precedent for that that model
it's a little bit different because you
only are your neighbor you don't do that
much arcing because you don't
that many neighbors whereas I think
enlist you have to create state whenever
you send a packet to a new destination
that may be multiple hops away to a new
destination site remember the cache
entries cover more than just individual
prefect in the individual / 30 tues well
that that's apparently unbounded number
isn't it though you know if this were
globally deployed that'd be lots and
lots of destination sites there would be
on the order of 300,000 today assuming
you don't do any aggregation we believe
that's a man I mean that's clearly a
manageable number in the global routing
system today and we believe that that
number will be a lot smaller when when
you do reasonable aggregation of e IDs
so yes we are aware that caching has a
long and illustrious lee mixed history
in routing porting state a lot of that
we believe was based on bad
implementations trying to solve the
wrong problem this is a much more
narrowly scope problem that you need
that you need to cash and the number of
cache entries is much smaller and they
don't have to be requested nearly as
often so I we think that it's doable I
mean one of the reasons this is an
excuse or experimental RFC proposals is
because there's a lot of experimentation
to be done and with a lot of operational
experience we have a little bit we have
a lot more to gain one thing that might
help is if we could shed some light on
what elements of caching work well and
which ones don't work well and maybe
explain away the bad experience that we
already have with caching it's a good
suggestion on one thing I will note is
that the folks down at UCL and Belgium
actually did do a study of you know kind
of cash dynamics and prefix prevalence
and how many things a typical site needs
to actually contact and the numbers
actually much smaller than you'd expect
so the cash according to their study the
cache sizes are actually going to be
much smaller than even we expect the
security analysis would also be
interesting because the cash is a good
thing
back sure all good suggestions please I
welcome the discussion on the IETF let
the little I'd IETF melons that's it
enjoy the break