okay hi everybody my name is Ricardo
liver i'm from UCLA and this is a
presentation about Cyclops so actually
this was this is just an update
basically on a tool that was presented
last year Nana and it pretty much
everything change except the name and
logo logo is still the same so what what
is new in Cyclops well basically right
now we have user profiles in the tool so
basically users are able to input
Network configurations such as
practically the S neighbors say s
origins and so on and Cyclops is able to
trigger alerts based on this information
except is able to detect events such as
routing leaks prefects I Jack's origin
changes and so on we also provide global
visibility in terms of ASC Jason serious
relationships and other type of
information by clink weights number of
articles rich link in addition to that
we also have a picture now that allows
you to monitor routes to DNS servers
such as root servers I'm going to go
over there next slides and we also have
a new feature called anomaly listings
basically it gives you a list of
anomalies such as boko zayas and work on
prefixes and practice that are longer
than / 24 and appearing in the global
routing system which so the basic
architecture of the tool is that on the
left side you have the rules of expected
behavior so this is information that is
input by the user and this information
includes the set of is is that you own
your network own set of practices and
the set of a s neighbors and based on
this information the Cyclops backhand
basically collects all the BGP routing
feeds from hundreds of sensors across
the network including vantage points
from ralphs use and ripe berries and PCH
and a balloon so about more than 700
vantage points right now aggregates all
these information and whenever it is in
from
a BGP announcement or a rocking table
entry that conflicts with information
that user inputs it triggers an alert
and the types of alerts the tool
includes right now we have alerts that
work on graphics level and we have alert
set to work on yes level on prefix level
there's mainly three types of alerts
origin change and this can be triggered
because either a prefix I Jack or
someone else decided to announce your
prefix caused by a Miss configuration
there's also alerts caused by next hop
changes if your graphics go to always
through a certain provider and San Luis
switch to a second provider and then
there's the more specific alert someone
when a more specific version of one of
your practice is being announced by by
someone else on the S alerts side we
have three types of alerts new prefix
alerts it means that your es is an
asking your prefix that is not on your
graphics list the new neighbor alert
basically it's an alert trigger whenever
you appear connected to another yes that
is not on your neighbor list and this
this type of alerts can be triggered
because someone is doing a false link
attack for instance the other type of
alert is transit and this is common in
in routing leaks so transit a as if you
are still yes there there's going to be
on alert if you're a s is going to
appear in the middle of some past
providing some transit that is not
supposed to provide so I'm going to give
you an overview of how to configure your
information in the tool you can access
the tool by the way the double double
with Cyclops that is the CSRT see you
later did you or just Cyclops at see
sotc later to you so the first thing you
need to do is you need to create an
account so there's a link there on the
right side will allow you to do that
you'll receive a confirmation email I
need to click there to confirm the
registration
after you're done then you can start
configuring your configure your
information first thing to do is to have
your own prefixes and for that you can
just input your guess name here or your
s number and Cyclops you automatically
detect all the prefixes and asked by
your network and you can later add this
to the system so you can see here UCLA
have all these prefixes here you can
uncheck the boxes that corresponds to
false positives graphics that you don't
want to monitor the next thing to do is
to configure what type of alerts you
want to see on each of these prefixes
and you can do that using these boxes
here so you can see there's the origin
change alert next stop alert and Martha
city colors so it will give you
flexibility to configure all these
alerts and also we can include here on
this column the number the s numbers
that are allowed to originate each of
these prefixes on second column you have
the allow next hops so this is basically
actually I don't have any case here but
you can have multiple s numbers here
it's basically a logical bar on this
next thing you're going to do is to have
your s numbers in this case we've seen
here is 52 UCLA and you can basically
type here your your organization name
Cyclops the automatic will find urs
numbers and then you configure basically
type of before that this is the s
neighbors actually so there's a third
step here which for each ASU basically
tell Cyclops which are your neighbors
and again the tool can detect is
automatically if you type just the s
number the tool can automatically detect
all the neighbors and then finally you
you configure the tool so that you began
basically tell Cyclops which alerts you
want what type of alerts you want to
receive and here I'm talking about TS
levelers there's three different types
of alerts as i mentioned new prefix in
your neighbor and trans
and after all this process is done
you're ready to start receiving alerts
and actually the alerts will come in the
form of emails and to also be they were
also be included in web interface and
you can access web interface and see the
list of all your alerts in this case
we're looking at two alerts a transit
type alert and a new neighbor alert and
you can double click these links here
and get more information about each
other like bgp message the trigger each
alert the number appears that saw each
alert and so on is an example of email
email alert the nice thing about this is
now you have this feature this in which
you can click the link and mark the
alert as false alert so that whenever
you have a recurring event at trigger
the same alert it will basically be
disabled and you will not be receiving
alerts that are basically false
positives again this the next slides are
basically some cases I find out using
the anomaly menu here so basically it's
the Vogons case and Bocas asns in this
case is a bunch of bull guns that cogent
was announcing this is another example I
found out possible in this configuration
hijack this prefix is usually enhanced
by in AS 701 and was announced by AT&T
at some point and yeah so basically we
need your feedback please go to the
website register it's free and send me
feedback to you can use these email
Cyclops yes I see you later that's you
we also have a Facebook group if you
want to join and that's about it thank
you so much
so we got room for one or two questions
if anybody has any questions
ok Thank You Ricardo