soldiers it good morning so I just
wanted to do a quick review of the
recent history of the global usenet feed
I thought some of the Greybeards in the
audience might find this kind of
interesting that what started as the
original social networking and
user-generated content distribution
system what is it like 30 years ago now
is still going so my first chart is the
monthly average of the global usenet
feed-in megabits per second obviously
the daily peaks are higher in the
monthly average so we're up peaked at
about 550 Meg's a second as an average
feed rate in December it was december
january just over the winter fitting an
easy curve to that it's a 26-percent
annualized growth for the last four and
a half years which is a pretty steady
there's kind of a big dip in the graph
and we look back and realized oh yeah
that's when a couple of eyes peas turned
off their usenet service last summer the
dip didn't last real long I think maybe
some pent up volume came flushing
through not Tom not long after I wanted
to compare the fee volume to something
yeah well anyway you know so you know
the way using that works is you take a
feed and you right at the disk and then
when your disks fills up you start
deleting what you had so you can keep
taking the new stuff in and to get an
idea on the total storage you would need
to hold one year of usenet one trailing
year of using at any given time here's
it you know so we're in the multi
petabyte range for a single copy of
these are using if you want to keep a
year of it going
but what's really interesting is with
the way that computers and storage have
gone as we're kind of entering a region
in time where you know we made it may be
within reach to never expire articles
again it would take a fair amount of
storage of course you have to multiply
this for your levels of redundancy but
we're onward and upward and that's my
lightning talk thank