um
so normally as you guys know i'm a
member of the beer farmers
um and normally our talks are tons of
fun
and um we do all sorts of fun things
uh to support the community um so
um basically right now um i'm not in
hacker mode
and i'm not really gonna be in corporate
douchebag mode either
i'm just gonna be kind of like telling
it like it is on this subject
um just a few things quickly about me
i'm pretty active on twitter i think
a lot of you follow me um if you're in
information security
i highly recommend your you go on
twitter um it is a good resource
and um you know if you follow the beer
farmers uh we got your back
if you run into a troll problem um
i've been involved in information
security since defcon 9
which for those of you i believe it was
defcon 27
this year um so i've been around for a
while and i've seen a lot of things and
i like to say i was in the room when the
commercial internet
gave birth which is kind of true because
i remember dial up and all of that
silliness
and so you know i've evolved um
into you know corporate mode where i now
i write a lot of emails
i patiently wait for progress on on
issues
i comment a lot in forbes and online and
i'm a ciso and i work for the beer
farmers
um so a couple of observations i want to
share with you guys before i get into
the meat of this presentation
which is really about my feelings about
global climate change
and i t and i t systems all right which
i realize is kind of a a pretty broad
topic
and there's tons of hypocrisy in this as
well
okay um and that's something that you
know
i'm i'm dealing with but i'm also trying
to rationalize it right
it's sort of like if you spend all your
time flying around the globe talking
about global climate change
are you really helping the situation
right
um so we have an image problem in
information security it should come
as no um no no thing we've got
hacky scare scary hacker which is me by
the way if you can't tell
we have carl von klauswitz who knows who
klaus woods was
big big time prussian general yeah and
then we've got
uh son to zoo uh for a couple of reasons
one it's mandatory to have a son to zoo
reference in a information security uh
presentation
but also he's a 15th century or 13th
15th century
chinese warlord so this is a problem
because when you start rolling out all
the military and again
first hypocritical thing i'm ex-military
but when you
start rolling out all the military
jargon
in cyber security you lose a lot of
people that haven't been in that
environment
okay so um i tend to try and use
in my presentations role models like
alan right
and um ada lovelace and hayden lamar
who without haiti lamar i wouldn't hate
my bluetooth rigs on a daily basis when
they cut out on a conference call for no
reason whatsoever
right but to be honest we have some
great role models
and what i'm what i'm really asking you
to do is when you
start doing presentations and stuff like
that think about
a more positive message and some of
these role models
as i try to get this to work again yeah
um
to use in your presentations and to use
as mentors come on in folks i'm just
starting the preamble you haven't missed
any of the good stuff
clearly there was a train issue which i
i will use this joke
okay so i've been on a lot of um
recent kind of like interviews and
articles about
national critical infrastructure right
especially transportation okay and
so they're all concerned about cyber
attacks right
on the train system i'm just gonna say
the train system in the uk is already
messed up
okay and i said the major threat from my
analysis
about national critical infrastructure
when it comes to train
is some dude with a leaf blower can shut
down the entire train system of the uk
with leaves on tracks
okay so you know let's keep this in
perspective because sometimes we just
get too much on the
on the uh on the hype machine so what's
sy jacks
um well sy jax is uh rowan's new um
ghost writing opportunity for our blog
hey rowan right on dude
appreciate that but um we do
cyber threat intelligence and i'm not
going to sit here and educate you on
cyber threat intelligence because
i'm actually teaching a course on it in
manchester um
at comptia on the 4th so i'm pretty
excited about that but you know we do
threat intelligence and
speaking of threat intelligence we can
see that there is a threat here
right it's a bit it's a large amount of
water and i i do want to congratulate
the guy that
designed this data center or lady that
designed this
data center that actually is containing
what could be described as a small
uh wading pool where unfortunately the
servers are located
so i've been thinking about this since
about 2015.
i wrote an article it might even still
be out there
and it starts off with cape spear in
newfoundland and
i was in newfoundland for a conference
and
it struck me at that point that
our planet is becoming more hostile to
human life
but it's also becoming more hostile to
it
to silicon and i want to explore that a
little bit
um we have a precarious relationship
i'm i i think anyone here
that lives in wales right now that had
servers in their basement
is feeling the effects of this type of
scenario and it's really gonna
again this is not a good news
presentation it i hope by the end of it
you're not just like oh i'm going to the
bar and i'm just going to drink because
there's
nothing that we can do about this there
are a lot of things because
like basically i turned 50 years old and
i went
i now have an opportunity to take my
knowledge and turn it into wisdom
okay and i need to impart to you that
next generation
that um there are some issues that
you're gonna face
in design in uh resiliency
in career and all those type of things
that are all going to be
that global climate change is going to
be transformational so
we we've got some truths here that that
we can talk about
that are not particularly good so
the first is we're trying to get to a
two degree
below two degree centigrade as a goal
and if you look back in the historical
research on global climate change
two degrees was like a catastrophic
level of global
climate change this was back in the
research in the 90s
so we've we've set our goal to just be
majorly screwed up as opposed to like
armageddon
okay but the problem is is that four
degrees
we were literally hundreds of feet
higher we have
a historical record that shows where sea
level had been over time
and my hometown of winnipeg manitoba
canada
and it'll factor into this in a little
bit but it was
under water of an inland sea called
lake agassi which then drained off
and became uh lake winnipeg and lake
manitoba which are the remnants of that
okay so my entire city about
i think it's 45 million years ago was
under water so something to keep in mind
and then we had this which is the really
not good news things
252 million years ago um
the planet warmed by five degrees now
that released a whole bunch of methane
that is seven times more destructive to
the environment
uh than carbon dioxide okay so we're
already seeing this i don't know if you
caught this discovery show
where they went to some lakes in the
north i think it was in alaska
and they they found some bubbles trapped
in the ice and they cut those bubbles
um opened like open them up with a
chisel and were able to set
fire to the bubble okay so that
tells me that we're releasing a bunch of
methane gas
so these are not cheery topics um and
they're important to start talking about
because
from what i've seen no one is talking
about this
issue and that's why my sort of 2020
series is going to be on this so
we have storms we're getting hit with
more active weather and i i'm not a
meteorologist or a climatologist but
i'll
describe a little bit on why we have
these problems and where they're going
to affect us
we have fires everybody can hear i think
is in consensus with the fact that
fires are bad um we have
floods as the poor people in wales and
yorkshire and all over the world are
experiencing
which may lead to a global i.t system
collapse
which could in fact be an economic
collapse so we're going to go through a
bunch of things
a lot of this is in a book called the
uninhabitable earth
i highly recommend you read it not
before bed
because you'll have nightmares okay um
and then of course
uh stormy daniels get it stormy
because it goes into this slide there we
go okay
stormy storms so there's
monetary amounts of money attached to
when a catastrophic hurricane or typhoon
hits a country and there's a couple of
things i want to talk about this
um from a cyber security perspective
we see two major attack
surfaces here disinformation is one
right and criminal profiteering from
phishing emails is the second
post event cleanup okay so
from a cyber threat intelligence
perspective anytime there's a big storm
anytime there's catastrophic damage we
pretty much know the mode that cyber
criminals go into
but from our perspective of major storms
who here in the uk has had a storm day
where basically the rail system shut
down you had to work from home
raise your hands yeah okay so if there's
going to be more frequent storms what
does that tell you about
the workplace and the workplace dynamics
that you're you're going to have
right not to mention the reliability
level of the trains and airplanes in
this particular country
right there's going to be more working
from home so there's going to be
more requirements from an i.t
perspective to do that
securely and stably right
um i've been recently watching a lot of
people melting down
on twitter over adobe light storm
and um their cloud-based offering which
apparently when you're generating like
4k videos it's kind of difficult to do
without
you know the bandwidth of gchq to
process
so we're going to see stuff like that
and we're seeing a lot
of damage um from this
and here's a really interesting thing
from this storm
that 7.5 million people went without
power okay that's got a huge economic
impact
i mean if you can't power anything
you're going to be
in real trouble and the other factor
here was in new york and new jersey
storm
storm surges were about 14 feet above
average low tide
okay so what does that really mean it
means
all of that critical infrastructure from
transformers
and um the dmarc points for like your
dsl connections
and your infrastructure related to it
services
gets basically turned off right
because of water and we'll talk a little
bit about how destructive water is
um in a bit but the other issue here is
that
this all takes a lot of time and effort
to put back together
after it gets wet okay and in fact what
we're seeing
is salt water is very corrosive so in a
lot of cases when you get these storm
surges
it leaves a bunch of salt water which
corrodes rapidly
right into infrastructure requiring all
of its replacement
right it's so bad that it can sometimes
take
weeks or months to get some of these
large transformers
back in operation because we just don't
have them
stocked away right we have to either
build them
and transport them or clean them and get
parts
we have this whole ecosystem and i'll
talk a little bit about that
so there's been a lot of talk about
innovative solutions which i think this
one
was the one that i was really kind of
taken aback from
okay uh the fact that they think
for 250 billion and 500 billion we can
just like
damn the north sea okay and so
as the atlantic ocean rises
the north sea is gonna stay the same
okay
now can anybody see what a problem that
would be
i mean it's great if you're living on
the south side of the uk
right facing towards france and germany
but maybe not so great on the other side
okay so again i i don't want to i don't
want you as taxpayers as consumers
to take this kind of i'm going to say
bunk and suggest that yes this is the
solution for
global climate change and sea rise is by
building a giant dike
for only one piece of ocean in the
entire ecosystem i thought this was the
most ridiculous thing i'd ever seen
okay so we have another problem
um the amazon we set it on fire
australia we set most of it on fire good
news we have you know six more
continents to go
so um that's all good we have another
problem though
and this is like so you look at that and
you're like
okay that's where i used to work from
home
so where do i work now the impact of
these kind of disasters is huge
not just from the pipes in the ground
issue which i'll talk about in a second
or the infrastructure that needs to be
replaced but we also find that in
catastrophes like this the
cell phone networks quickly get
overloaded and fall apart
like at an ariana grande concert okay
where it takes half an hour to send a
text message
so so our problems here is that
we are living in a very precarious
situation
where fires and wildfires can come upon
us
very very quickly and again this is now
from the cyber threat intelligence
perspective
is getting that warning out to your
employees that something bad is
happening
in a lot of cases these people had
between 30 to 45 minutes of notice
that's not very much okay
and and so we're finding that as global
temperatures
increases as we have these more extremes
and temperatures
our infrastructure and our builds are
not holding up
so as an example one of the major
problems that they had in the post
fire here was it got hot enough
to melt all of the plastic pipes in the
ground
when plastic when this particular abs
plastic
um melts it produces something called
benzene
and benzene is very toxic to humans
so you have in addition to this and
cleanup costs
you can't just like go in plant some
trees plant some grass
rebuild the building you literally have
to dig up all of the old crappy
infrastructure
okay and put it back so this is why
it takes a long time to get things back
on its feet
after you have a fire like this okay you
have environmental problems
so floods a little bit about floods so
literally this is the lobby of verizon
and i'm sure they got a lot of tech
support calls about their dsl not
working
okay but there are fundamental problems
that we're having
with this type of thing and we get us
government recommendations that are
saying oh
like you should put your generators on
the roof
okay you know this is all kind of well
and good
but the infrastructure that you have to
keep going comes in these cables and
conduits
in the ground so having a generator on
the roof
is very short-sighted because what are
you going to be powering
like nothing right so it'll all fall
apart
so this is one of the issues that we
have is that we need to build
infrastructure
that is resilient is capable of
delivering service
under these type of conditions and we'll
get into kind of
a problem and this is what miami is
going to look
like in 2030 or 2050. all right
now miami is an interesting little bit
of a problem that i'll get into a little
bit later
but as we can see this is probably not
good uh for the street lights um because
you have no street lights to see there
right
um and of course anything with a
foundation
is going to be in really rough shape so
if we look at the uk
a little bit we can see that clacton on
c becomes clocked in in c
okay and this is a big problem
and i'm i'm going to get into this why
this is a big problem in a second
yeah so this is the big one here
so this is what new york would look like
by about 2030 to 2050 again
and you can see um a big portion of it
the blue
is the water okay now
a 3.7 degree warming of the global
temperature
it's estimated would cost us over 550
trillion in costs right
now the entire global economy is about
225 trillion
so this is a problem now who here seen
the movie the big short
okay and that was about property values
and housing prices and
mortgages okay i'm gonna blow your mind
a little bit on how this
problem has manifested and kind of
suggest to you that we have another
major problem
so rowan can help me participate here so
rowan insurance organization okay
rowan is one of my clients i am a
giant insert insurance organization okay
and right now i have insurance policies
on all the buildings in the blue area
okay now let's just pick a number and
say
i have 10 billion dollars of risk
all right because i have to pay
a whole bunch of people if these
buildings go under water
all right now let's keep in mind that
little stat that i threw out there about
14 foot
um storm surge okay so
i say you know what i don't have 10
billion dollars of risk
so i'm going to pay rowan's insurance
company
25 million dollars so that
if these risks are realized he is going
to pony up
million dollars all right that's called
diversifying risk
and actually insurance companies are
mandated by the government to do that
the idea being
is that if we the risk is distributed a
bunch
of a whole bunch of different companies
right then i'm able to meet my
obligation to pay out the 10 billion
dollars
you with me so far well here's the
problem
i've sold a whole bunch of policies to a
whole bunch of companies and they in
turn have
sold a whole bunch of those policies to
a whole bunch of companies
the problem is is i'm going to have to
start paying out on these
but not immediately i'm going to have to
start paying these out as
some of these buildings get underwater
as some of that critical infrastructure
that runs
those buildings becomes corroded
polluted or has to be ripped out
so i am faced with a a small
dangerous dip up until the point we get
another giant storm that comes in
and does more than 10 billion because it
puts
half of long island underwater and at
that point
what am i gonna do i'm gonna try and get
a government bailout
just like the banks did when they sold
shitty mortgages
ultimately what are you guys gonna do
you're gonna pay for it
this is one of those things that blows
my mind because
you can see this coming right we can do
something about this
the you shouldn't be allowed to build
more stuff in areas that we know are
gonna get swagged by a storm or go
underwater okay here's another problem
that we have here
crop failure we know that the planet is
changing but yet we're doing the same
things okay a great example
is um the growing of rice
in regions like california okay and i
didn't know this until i started doing
the research but the california rice
crop is one of the largest in the world
you would have thought it was india or
you would have thought it was in asia
but no it's actually california now this
is a problem
because there are more humans being born
every day and rice is actually one of
the things that the majority of humans
out there on the planet eat
right so if we have crop failures
it has massive repercussions because
hungry people do angry things
because they're hungry in fact that's
one of the reasons when i was
actually in the military they could get
us to do a whole bunch of things
is they made us super angry all the time
and one of the ways to make people angry
is not to feed them
okay but this is an interesting stat
that came from my homeland
1.9 billion in losses in 2018 was the
fourth highest amount on record
not including uninsured costs paid by
all levels of government business and
individuals
so what is 1.9 billion
well think about this folks there are 35
million roughly people living in canada
so take 1.9 billion divided by 35 and
that's
just the cost of dealing with a crop
failure
okay so this is has a massive
repercussion
and we have a problem here too because
we have
most forty percent of the planet living
within a hundred kilometers of the sea
well fortunately here in uh uh dundee
you're on a hill that's good news right
but you're gonna lose the
probably that victorian albert
monstrosity that they built
oh well too bad uh with the
what is it with the 10 quid um coasters
right somebody was telling me about that
so we've got six million people
currently living in coastal areas
vulnerable to sea level rise today
and today's refugee problems are
straining political systems the syrian
crisis has created one million homeless
people
right um um projection for 2050 suggests
200 million climate refugees will move
to more
habitable climes unfortunately this is a
very
habitable climb all right so this is a
problem that will come to us we know
this is going to occur this is not
you know somebody looking into their
crystal ball going well it may happen
no it will happen right we're already
seeing
the effects of this but then we get
research here
whoops let's go back yes
the question really on a lot of people's
mind and bernie sanders said this
he said that syria is the first climate
crisis
uh war okay um
i don't think it matters to be honest
but let's let's just basically what
pisses you
off when you need something and you
can't get it not want
but if you need something and can't get
it now us
we're kind of special snowflakes when
amazon says it's going to deliver on
prime day and then it doesn't
we get pissed off okay first world
problems
okay but but this is really interesting
to me because
what they were trying to do is say that
the syrian crisis
that we currently have didn't have
anything to do
with global climate change okay but it's
still a freaking war
okay and i think that misses the point
that it's just going to exaggerate
and exacerbate the system that already
exists
so i'm going to go to tech for a little
bit okay
this is a picture of all the undersea
cables coming
in to various demarcation points and i
draw your attention to and i can use
this fancy laser
uh to this that was miami
so does anybody see a bit of an internet
connect connectivity problem
in the future absolutely and then when
you see
in new york and stuff like the these are
all the transatlantic
uh cables and stuff like that again in
very precarious
places all right so this is a problem
that we know
is going to come to and they're saying
the infrastructure could be underwater
by 2033.
all right and it doesn't look like this
is going to be like
even if it's 2035 and we're wrong by two
years that i'm going to be well probably
done by now
probably found in some cd bar and fife
um but you folks have got to deal with
this
right and then and this is why i'm i'm
out here trying to talk about this issue
so this is a real problem
a real fundamental problem so this is a
type 42 destroyer
it's uk's pride and joy they're one
billion dollars a pop
okay they don't work in really hot water
okay so this is where i'm saying if the
government's
toys to do national defense don't work
in super hot waters
in the gulf that affects the uk's
ability to go and kill people
so as soon as the uk has a problem and
can't kill people
we're gonna have to do something but
again rather than
dealing with the issue of oh my god the
water and the gulf is too hot we're
refitting
these things at taxpayers expense again
right to make them work in hot water so
we can go and kill people
all right yeah
[Music]
so this one is the slide that i wrote
even before
coronavirus hysteria hit everybody all
right
but i want to talk a little bit about um
human beings
and what we do when we're sick okay
especially with flu
what happens you get a temperature right
that's where your body temperature goes
up
all sorts of crazy happens to you
you have those fever dreams like you're
on absinthe
but generally your body attempts to cool
itself by
using its immune system to fight it off
what did i
what if i told you that if
you're already at 45 degrees centigrade
and you get a fever and your body is
already working really hard to keep
itself cool but now it has this
infection
what do you think happens to you
basically
a bunch of your friends show up and see
some kind words about you how you're a
kind person and a generous person and
stuff
you're dead all right so
dead is not a good state to be in
right nor is eating bat
apparently that's what patient zero was
for coronavirus
not mexican beer there's a lot of
confusion about that
so i just want to clear that up there if
you had any misconceptions
it has nothing to do with corona so
please
be safe out there right you can stop
watching kung fu movies
also known as a threat vector
right as well but my point here is is
that
these diseases that in this country are
unheard of
when you have that global climate change
when you have
moving and surviving because of mild
winters
you have major major problems on your
hands
there there's a particularly gross
article that i'm going to talk about i
didn't want to show pictures of it
okay but in canada we have a moose
problem okay the moose
was found to have over two ten thousand
wood ticks on it
okay super gross but the wood ticks
basically have thrived because a really
cold winter those minus 40 winters
haven't hit canada in a couple of years
enough to suppress
that wood kick population all right and
what are we doing
unfortunately wood ticks don't really
have a supernatural predator
in large amounts so they are absolutely
thriving
so we now have one of the majestic
canadian moose
right um riddled with these insects that
are busy sucking them
life out of them and driving them crazy
to the point where they're almost
committing moosicide
because you know sometimes they leap in
front of cars but
no my point being is that it's it's a
really
um precarious situation
i think there's another factor here that
i wanted to talk about as well is that
um we also have a problem with the
permafrost and i i said about the
release of methane gas being a problem
okay
here's another problem there might be
stuff
there okay that we haven't seen
in our society for a very long time so
as an example recently there was
outbreak of
bubonic plague in a place called siberia
and you're like bubonic plague
traditionally struck europe we had
1664 i think it was which is the black
death that
crossed europe um you know millions of
dead
so this is maybe my problem with the
current coronavirus coverage in that
they're treating this thing like it's
the plague it's not
right it's got about a i think the last
count was 2.3 percent mortality
rate uh chances are you're gonna die of
diabetes more often than you're gonna
die of coronavirus
okay so so think about that but
one of the problems is is that we pretty
much are done
when we get to 54 degrees celsius
at 54 degrees a healthy elder adult male
or female
person biologically cannot keep itself
cool enough so if you're caught out in
the heat
you're pretty much going to be cooked
our critical infrastructure
mostly made up of cat5 cable right cat5
cable
75 degrees centigrade is when it melts
and we've started to see temperatures in
vehicles
right and inside areas with no airflow
approaching that mark so what does that
mean it means that if you painted a
pedestal black and put it
out there somewhere in like afghanistan
it would get to a daytime temperature
exceeding 75 degrees and all the cabling
inside would melt into one gooey mass
all right so another thing to think
about we're in this
era right now oops did we lose uh
connection
i think the data projector might have
shut off
anyways i will not i only have a couple
more slides
um so this is where i'm saying
that we need to look at this is an
organizational risk to the businesses
that you're going to um start working
for and you have to think about
how can you um wrap your mind around
some of these challenges in terms of
like remote working
in terms of like building infrastructure
where to build it
how to build it so that it has some
resiliency
and stuff like that there's a broad
range of concerns here
right even just notifying your employees
of a particular situation related to a
weather event
for instance right um nobody should be
caught by surprise i think also like
when you go into planning
oops okay it's coming up um we just have
to contact them
fortunately i have them right there oh
yay okay perfect oops
oh it's now what is it
misbehaving is it my slides maybe no
it's the other one
check the input
oh okay yeah so this is
this is what i'm sort of saying is that
you can have
non-hysterical conversations about these
issues
okay and you can start putting it into
planning documents
right resiliency for hydro let's not
build it on you know in a flood plain in
the basement
right basic stuff right let's have a
plan
for when the actual internet cables
don't work
can we go with 5g hotspots are there
things that you
can do right how are you going to get to
your people when mertz
got hit this was really interesting from
the not petya wannacry
when mertz got hit um
they turned to whatsapp because they had
single sign-on enabled for majority of
their applications and no one could get
onto their system because they got
ransomware
so they had a plan to use whatsapp um
to continue communications right the
other thing that
saved their bots is they had a data
center
they had a domain controller in africa
and what happened was they were running
a flat network when they got infected
the ransomware hit all of their um
infrastructure and active directory
controllers
except the one in africa because guess
what it was down
it was on a saturated link so the atmos
the
ransomware didn't get to it so quite
literally they got super lucky in
rebuilding their infrastructure
so one of the simplest things that you
can do for your business
is perhaps to create a uh data a
sorry an active directory server let it
replicate
and then turn it off for five days bring
it back up let it replicate again and
turn it off for five days
so that if you do get ransomware or god
forbid
a pipe burst and fills your basement
where your server is
you at least have your active directory
to get everybody back underway
so there's one more peril that we'll
talk about and then i'm gonna
release you guys to the hounds um
it's this so mother nature is the
ultimate malicious actor
okay keep in mind that she will break
your arm all right and
this is a really interesting thing to
talk about a colon
a coronal mass ejection cme event
now we've had through history we've had
a couple of things happen
in 1989 we had this solar flare that
collapsed the ontario quebec
a power grid yeah no one cares because
it's canada
but i'm just saying it can happen okay
we had six million people
now a larger event that looks like that
that hits
the earth is gonna do a couple of things
uh it's gonna
generate an inordinate amount of help
desk calls
no i'm kidding it's gonna it's gonna do
that but it's gonna do a whole lot more
if we lose some of those large transfer
transformers
especially the ones for instance that
power our electric trains
or plants or things like that right
we are going to have essentially a giant
reboot that we'll have to do
and who here really enjoys rebooting
ancient servers on a friday before a
long weekend
anyone yeah exactly it's like i also
like to stab myself in an
eye and my hobbies include pepper
spraying myself
so this is this is a major problem
because we have systems especially
national critical infrastructure we've
never
turned off okay now one of the problems
is is they've also been there for maybe
40 50 years so the people that actually
turned it on the first time
they're dead so now you're gonna have to
do
some of the most amazing feats which
it's possible to do
but you gotta have a lot of time and
effort
and potentially money to do so the
turning machine has anyone seen that
um at the betchley national computing
center
yeah a few of those did you know that
some of the machines that they used
to try and decode the enemy stuff they
rebuilt from scratch by looking at a
couple of pictures
of it to try and figure out how it
worked okay
we might be into the same situation
when we're trying to bring up all of
these systems
that we have without what
without the three key things that i tell
everybody that wants to get into cyber
security to say
in a goddamn interview here they are
what's the first thing
my passion is network diagrams
my passion is configuration management
and asset management
you don't need a third thing because by
then you're hired
okay it's that simple you want to get
into cyber security
do stuff that no one else wants to do
right
that's it but i'll tell you right now
people that are good with documentation
for network and for systems and that
kind of stuff
they rise really quickly because what do
executives not
understand anything in email or chat
what do they understand pictures all
right
so if you can express something as a
picture where others have failed
you will be employable and you will be a
very rich person very quickly
so that's it for me uh
thank you so much i know we ended a bit
early
but that's so that you can all get super
depressed
[Applause]
yeah but one of the problems is that
if i build my house in a place that gets
flooded right
and then i get insurance it doesn't
cover the cost usually of moving me to a
new place or a new house
in a place that doesn't get flooded so
there's a flaw in the system that allows
you to continue to rebuild in the same
place only to get flooded again and
unfortunately we saw that on the um
we saw that on the news on bbc where
they're
where they're interviewing these poor
folks in wales and yorkshire i think it
was
who would be like this is the eighth
time we've been flooded
and i'm like well why can't those people
move and they're like no they get paid
to rebuild
in the same spot right it seems
counterintuitive i'd be like
i will pay you more to never pay have to
pay you again
for flood damages like here's an extra
100 100k like by then can you imagine
making eight flood claims like how they
even still get insurance is beyond me
right
like it certainly doesn't happen in
north america it's like
usually a one hit or two hit deal right
there are some other things that i
didn't get a chance to talk about that i
really wanted to
was one of the things about ocean cable
and hurricanes they know likey um
at all and one of the problems is is um
you get these wave
actions happening this is where like
post hurricane
you hear about like ships that have been
unburied and stuff like this
well post hurricane you don't hear about
the fact that some of these cables have
been literally ripped out of their
seamounts
um and stuff like that now they're
starting to bury them
uh they used to just kind of lay them
across the ocean and that also seemed to
attract sharks weirdly enough
there's some some interesting footage of
uh sharks attacking
undersea cables i guess they think
they're like a giant
bitey um you know food type source
anything else other facts from my mind
will spill out as we go on any other
questions
all right let's not build data centers
where
in basements all right guys thanks