hi everyone
so this afternoon i'd like to talk with
you all about story of
the current state of smart ticketing in
the united kingdom
but before i do that i want to give a
brief introduction about myself
so i currently work as a software
engineer for skyscanner over in glasgow
and i'm working on payment systems over
there
uh over the summer i graduated from
abertay in an ethical hacking
i probably have a really funny accent i
moved to scotland 40 years ago prior to
that lived in the dominican republic
and was born in california before then
i'm really keen
on the interaction between security and
user experience
i'm also really interested in embedded
devices payment technologies
and i'm really into public transit as
well
so this talk is essentially an overview
of a lot of the research that i
completed as part of my owner's
dissertation as well as some later work
that i've done since leaving university
so if you often visit major cities you
probably have a drawer
full of transit cards so here are a
handful of transit cards that i have at
home
from a couple of cities across north
america and europe
now in the late 90s the department for
transport in the united kingdom
formed this organization called itso
with the idea of trying to develop
an interoperable smart card scheme in
the united kingdom
so essentially back in the 90s they
foresaw that this is going to be a
problem
they figured okay different cities are
going to launch different smart card
schemes
they're not going to be compatible with
each other and it's going to end up with
people having to carry
all sorts of different smart cards
around in order to be able to travel
so they wanted to tackle this problem
and create a scheme that would solve it
before it was even a problem to begin
with
now it's so has been widely deployed for
quite a while now
the english national concessionary
travel scheme launched
its own cards in 2008 so
allowing people who are over the age of
or who are disabled to access
free or heavily discounted bus and rail
public transit services additionally in
scotland
there's a similar scheme available again
for disabled people and folk over 60
and at the moment there is a discount
for people between the ages of 16 and 18
although next year bus travel will be
made free for everyone under the age of
19 through the same scheme
additionally the department for transit
for transport have mandated that it so
be used
for any new smart card schemes launched
in the united kingdom and they've made
this a condition
as part of the rail franchise agreements
that are used
for the different train operating
companies when they are awarded
contracts to operate on particular
routes
one example of a of where it's so can
come into play
is with the alberta university student
cards so
this is what my student card looked like
when i still student here
and one thing that i was really
interested by
is that there's this it's so logo on the
back of the card
and i when i was first given this card
shortly after moving to scotland i was
immediately curious as to what this
implied
because it meant that my student card
could potentially do a lot more than
just let me
print and get books out of the library
as it turns out i was right um i can do
the aforementioned two functions with
the university there are a bunch of
different features that the council
in dundee facilitate through the use of
the smart card as well
and i can also side load uh various
different travel products onto
the smart card as well so i can put bus
tickets on it
um i can put um bus tickets that are
valid across all of dundee and east fife
on it
uh and i could also load on glasgow
subway pass you go credit
um and this is something that i was
really excited about when i first moved
to the uk
uh four years ago just the fact that i
could take my student card
issued in dundee go to glasgow put it in
a ticket machine
immediately put money on and just be
ready to travel i wouldn't need
any more cards i could just use this one
card and then essentially
i'd hopefully be able to travel across
the whole of the uk
now at the end of uh december 2016
uh all of the itself cards based on my
fair classic
which is what my student card was based
on expired
and this meant that i was no longer able
to travel using my student card
and i was kind of stuck in that i had
about 10 quid left on the card
which i no longer had access to so i
went to spt who managed the subway in
glasgow
and they weren't super enthused that i
had been using my student card
um to access the subway um they offered
to transfer the balance over to scot
railcard which is one of their supported
cards
but sort of really discouraged me from
trying to use
any other it's so card that they hadn't
officially agreed to have be supported
right
um which sort of seems contrary to the
whole purpose of the specification right
it's
supposed to be interoperable you should
be able to just mix and match cards
but you know okay this is at the
beginning of 2017 so
you know it's been a few years since
then hopefully things have changed
and indeed uh back in november transport
scotland launched a campaign
to motivate people to consider smart
travel
instead of using regular paper tickets
and the like and they make this point
that you can
pick smart card any smart card right so
hopefully this means that the situation
has gotten better in scotland right
so okay fine i went over to
and who was the organization that i
originally sort of had
issues with and the frequently asked
question says okay well you can use your
your subway smart card on a variety of
different bus
operators but you should check with each
of them to see
if they'll accept it um so i did
and i went and checked that with all of
the operators that are issuing
smart cards in scotland and as it turns
out it's a mess
um there are a lot of
tickets that are issued by different
companies that they will only load on
their own smart cards
sometimes you can cross-load tickets
onto
different companies smart cards in some
cases for
example if you have a student if you
have one of the advertised student cards
and you want to put
explorer dundee bus tickets onto it you
have to take your card
to their office and they have to
activate it with their system
so you can't just go on a bus and use it
there are some circumstances where
different
issuers have different types of cards so
scottrail offer both
um anonymous cards and they offer cards
that have your photo on them and
depending on that
you're restricted on what kinds of
tickets you can use
um but this is very far from having any
sort of
integrated transport right the fact that
you you even have a table that looks
like this
um is just way beyond the scope of what
your sort of average
public transit user would care to try
and figure out
so what this means is that in practice i
now just have a drawer
for uk smart cards right um
now admittedly i probably have a lot
more smart cars than the average person
does
like given that this was something that
i was explicitly researching
but even if you're just someone that's
going within scotland
you're still probably going to need
multiple smart cards to use across
different cities
but okay let's take a step back um
how is this supposed to work to begin
with right we can see that that's sort
of
20 years on after the specification has
been developed things haven't really
gone to plan
um and as an ethical hacking student i
was really curious to understand
is this actually secure what is the
security mechanism that's built into the
specification
that allows arbitrary public transit
operators to
write to different cards and still have
confidence that their products aren't
going to be tampered with
so as it turns out given that it's so
was commissioned by the department for
transport
you can actually go and freely download
the core it's a specification from their
website
you can define the pdfs online you don't
even have to give them your email
address or anything like that it's just
a one-click download there are
12 parts to the it so specification
of course they start numbering them at
zero and these cover
all sorts of things ranging from how to
speak with different smart cards
how to encode data on smart cards what
kinds of products are supported
uh across the scheme how the back office
system should work how they should
communicate with each other
but it's so it's quite broad in in the
scope that it covers in terms
of how to set up this
unified environment and the core
principle behind it so
is that you should be able to have
different products existing
on the same smart card without
prescribing a particular underlying
technology
i think my student card is a really good
example of this where
the specification is flexible enough
where the university were able to
continue using smart cards for student
cards
but just being able to add on this
additional transit functionality and
this is really neat because it means
that the underlying nfc chipsets that
are used by different issuers
and even within different generations of
smart cards within the same issuer
do vary quite a bit so for instance spd
in glasgow for the glasgow subway issue
both my fair ultralight as well as
a sort of it's so proprietary smart card
scheme
um but in addition to that there are a
ton of different deskfire
cards being used out in the wild as well
and the way that
the specification manages to accomplish
this is by defining a three-layer model
that separates
how products are defined on the card the
shell on the card which
is essentially the equivalent of having
a folder on your computer that stores
everything on the card
and then you have the actual card layer
so that that's the actual underlying nfc
chipset involved
and this has been designed so that from
the bottom most layer the product layer
things can be kept fairly generic
products aren't
uh formatted differently for different
chipsets and then
at the shell layer that's where sort of
the compatibility measures come in
to normalize things between different
chipsets
so within an it's a smart card
everything is encoded inside of a data
group
um and what what this does is you have a
header at the top
uh which is your label you have the data
set which is all the actual information
that you want to have inside of that
packet
and then you have an instance identifier
which is a unique identifier for
that data group on the card and you have
a seal
which is it says mechanism for
preventing tampering and i'll get back
to that
in a little bit later data groups all
come together to
form a directory within the card shell
so essentially
the the way that this works is that the
data groups are all present
on different parts of the smart card and
your directory
contains the labels for each of these
which tell
a device that's reading your smart card
where to find these products on the
smart card
and then combining the information from
the directory
you can go and look up um the various
smart products
and get an idea of what's on the card um
additionally it so has this log format
which
allows for things like journey histories
or for transaction histories on
pay-as-you-go wallets
so it's sort of similar concept in that
you have
um various log entries which
are defined as orphan it's so product
entities and that they're not directly
added to
the card directory but instead they're
referenced
by um a product's log and then you can
go from the product and look up each of
the
the orphan products to determine what's
happened uh with that
so as i said these would be things like
when you top up your card
that would be a log entry uh when you
tap in at a station that would be a log
entry as well
and because it so has to be compatible
with all these different chipsets they
very quickly realize that they could not
simply rely
on the chipset level security so
all nfc cards provide at least some
basic
mechanism for access control so be it
having to present a key in order to read
or write information
to the card all the way through to doing
actual
cryptographic operations on the card in
order to prove authenticity
but because this varies quite a bit um
it so decided to
implement their own cryptographic
signature mechanism for all of the
information that's stored on the card
so that they wouldn't have to rely on
that
the problem is that the signatures that
are stored on the card cannot be
verified
without access to an it's so secure
application module
so also known as the isam so the isam
is is essentially um just another smart
card
that's located inside every single
ticket vending machine
every ticket barrier and ideally the
handheld readers used
by train conductors to validate whether
the tickets on
your smart card are valid or not the
problem with the isam though
is it's something that within the ito
specification holds
a lot of power this is the same module
that's used
to generate these signatures as well as
verify them
now the insole specification does
provide mechanisms for
restricting the impact that a stolen
isam would have
so for instance an isam can only emit a
certain number of season tickets before
it has to be centrally reset
um but despite this they're still great
incentive for
public transit operators to have as few
of these as possible
in the wild just because of how risky it
is if one of these are stolen
so with that in mind there's this
extension to the specification
called a remote point of service
terminals and the idea is that
instead of needing physical access to
the isam
at the point of validation you put your
isam inside of a data center somewhere
and then you connect to it over the
internet and you ask it to perform the
validation for you
and then you just write that over to the
card um
a more practical example of where this
is used and where you
might have actually seen this as a
consumer is the concept of remote ticket
download
so a lot of public transit companies
that use
smart cards have started allowing uh
passengers
to load tickets onto their smart cards
without having to go to a station first
um by allowing tickets to be loaded
through
smartphone apps so this is an example of
the scottrail app
so i tap my smart card to the card
it says there are no updates currently
available for the card and that just
shows me information about what's on the
card
but if i had purchased a ticket
beforehand this would go through
and actually load that onto the smart
card
um and this is secured because what
what's happening is that your phone is
just
acting as a vessel for the remote isam
to speak with the smart card with so
your phone isn't actually
very involved in the process most of the
heavy lifting is happening
on the server away in a data center
somewhere
so unfortunately the isam operation is
literally the only
part of the it's a specification that's
covered by nda
um and given that the the whole reason
for a lot of my research is that a lot
of this stuff isn't public to begin with
or at least the impacts of it aren't
public
i wasn't interested in signing an nda
and still to this day have not
signed an nda with it so so this in mind
i have no idea how the isam works very
few people do
even if you're willing to sign an nda um
you sort of have to have a justification
for
needing that information um but
despite that there are still a lot of
other sections in this specification
that we do have access to
and while we don't have access to the
detailed operation of the actual isam
we do have access to information about
how all the surrounding services around
the isam
speak with it what kind of data they
send to it what kind of data they
expect back so
one of the core principles within itso
is
that they need
various different public transit
operators to be able to read and write
from smart cards that were not issued by
them so
the way that the specification tries to
handle this while still keeping write
access secured
is by using a key
derivation algorithm to generate keys
that are unique for each smart card
based on a secret algorithm that's
stored on the ice app
so this means that as long as you as a
public transit operator have access to
an isam
you can then get right access to
all the sectors on a card by deriving
the keys for it
but the problem is that you need
information
from to begin with in order to derive
these keys
in particular the iso specification
requires that you have access to
format version code the key strategy
code and the key set version code
all of which are stored on the card
itself
so this creates a kind of catch 22 where
in order to
derive the encryption keys for the card
so you can communicate with the card
and read and write information from the
card you need to have already read
information
from the card to know that initial
information right
so the itso specification doesn't try to
do anything clever with this
um they just outright say okay that's
fine
uh and they compromise on giving
everyone read access to
all of the information located on it's
so smart cards
so this means that you can read out all
the information on a given smart card
using a key that is generic to all the
smart cards that
are based on that particular chipset
type and these keys are either
published on the itzo website or are
fairly easy to determine on your own
um as a hobbyist that's brilliant
because it means that it's really easy
for me to go in and understand what
data's on
my card so despite its relatively open
nature
um when i began this project and still
to the best of my knowledge
there are no open source implementations
of any tooling
to interact with a smart card i mean
sure there are apps on the play store
that let you read information off your
smart card
but those are all closed source so as a
hobbyist that's not really interesting
to me
so i went ahead and wrote one so
using the publicly available
documentation i wrote python tooling for
the card data
that's available on github the code is
terrible don't look at it
too closely yet it was literally written
for a uni project so there are no unit
tests
um but it's licensed under the gpl so
everyone is free to use it um as long as
you
um but there it's gpl
to prevent sort of commercial entities
from just taking it and and
making changes to it and keeping those
closed source
so uh pi travel card provides
an extremely basic uh command line
interface
um so in this case uh it's located in
nfc reader on my computer
and then it's just going through and
dumping some basic information about
my smart card but that that's just sort
of a sort of high level understanding to
to get an idea of whether this is
working what's more interesting with pi
travel card
is the underlying api that's provided
for hobbyist developers to build their
own tooling
um to interact with smart cards so
this is the python script which goes
through
and at the very top i'm
opening an nfc session and grabbing the
card data
after that i'm going through all the
products found on the card
and i'm looking for a store travel
rights product so that's what's used to
store
pay as you go balances on a smart card
then i'm looking to see if that product
belongs to the glasgow subway and then
if it does
i'll go through and print out
information about that
so there's just all sorts of information
that pi travelcard tries to return
about information that's located on a
smart card
um so in addition to giving you its own
interpretation about what information is
on the card
you still get access to the raw byte
streams for each of the individual data
groups on the card
so as a researcher it makes it a lot
easier to understand
the relationship between what are the
bytes on the card and what those bytes
actually mean
so now i'm going to take a moment to do
a live demo
okay so um
at the moment uh i just have a smart
card reader attached to my computer uh
unfortunately it's on the left hand side
uh sort of because of the hdmi
positioning so it's a bit hard to see as
an audience member
but here i don't have any smart cards
attached to it
now i'm going to take my trusty scott
rail smart card
put it on top of the reader
and i get information about my last two
taps on the glasgow subway
so that's me tapping in uh at a station
and tapping out in a station
and the total transaction cost was four
pounds 15.
so once i had that tooling i was really
curious to start
thinking about okay what can i start
doing uh with these smart parts right
so uh as i mentioned my student card was
originally issued
using the myfur classic chipset which
has
plenty of very well-known and very
public vulnerabilities for it
which essentially allow you to take
control of the entire card by being able
to derive
all the encryption keys that it uses
so using these vulnerabilities i was
able to clone my student card
uh onto just a blank nfc card
so um over on the left saying uh
unknown my fare possibly clone
but on the right this is a publicly
available it's a smart card checker
and it's still happy that my my card
looks fine it seems valid
um but sort of as i mentioned this card
did expire at the end of 2016
um which kind of sucks um because it'd
be neat if i could keep using that card
right um
now the problem is that tampered cards
cannot be checked offline without
physical access to an isam
so i went ahead and changed the expiry
date i changed the card number
but it still thinks that the card is
valid because the app just doesn't know
any better
and it can't know any better because of
how the specification is written
there's just no way for it to be able to
determine whether the card has
actually been tampered with um
unfortunately
i will not be demoing this because i
would really rather not get deported
so please don't ask me how i did that
the information on how to do it is
fairly publicly available anyway
but this is really a problem when uh
trained conductors for for a certain
local train operating company
often use their corporate phones which
don't have access to an isam
for ticket validation additionally when
you're traveling on some of the routes
operated by the strain company
there's often a lack of mobile data
service available so
it's not really feasible for them to
make use of
this remote isam functionality anyway
because
there's just not enough there's not good
enough mobile data infrastructure
available
for them to be going online to validate
each of the tickets
and this is this is just a really good
example of where
requiring specialized equipment in order
to do ticket validation
just leads to ticket validation either
not happening
where i might like wave my smart card at
an instructor and they'll just go cheers
pal
um or they'll half validate it in that
they'll see what information is on the
card but not actually be able to tell if
that's genuine or not
and this is this is part of the problem
with losing an isam
being an incredibly risky proposition
for a public transit operator
that so specification says that if you
have an isam
in some sort of device that's going to
be moving around it has to be really
heavily secured
you can't be able to extract it from the
device without
needing a tool to open it up um
and so as i was saying like operators
are directly incentivized to deploy
as few isam's as they can get away with
while it's still a crucial component to
validating the integrity
of any smart ticket issued on the it's
so scheme
and further than this i sort of think
that it's those directionless
flexibility
really gives public transit operators an
excuse
to be lazy with their smart card
deployments
it is really easy to just lift and shift
your existing paper ticket products
onto smart ticketing products without
considering
all of the other possibilities that are
facilitated by using a smart card to
begin with
and a really good example of this is
this document
published by the rail development group
who at the time was known at the
association of train operating companies
where they've essentially gone through
every single paper ticket that exists
within national rail
and they've tried to map it to the ito
specification
um and in some cases they just haven't
managed a few years ago scott rail tried
doing advanced single tickets that is
tickets which are restricted to
one particular train at a particular day
and time
uh on it's so smart cards and they just
couldn't manage to actually encode
what time the ticket was valid for so
you could buy a ticket
for a train which is way cheaper and
then just travel on
any other train because the conductor
has no idea which train your ticket is
actually valid for
um so i mean the sort of question is
like if not it's so
then what um i think in an ideal world
we'd discontinue these weird drm
encumbered m tickets that some train
operating companies provide
um and switch to just unrestricted
e-tickets
um which other train operating companies
provide which lets you just print them
out on ticket stock
on regular computer paper or just be
displayed on a mobile phone without
downloading an app
um and it'd be great to see more train
operating companies use these
e-tickets for advanced single so scott
rail for example have still been
dragging their feet on supporting
e-tickets at
all because they're still trying really
hard
to push for their smart card scheme
additionally it would be really great to
see
fixed origin destination stored tickets
on its own so things like
singles returns or car nets uh just be
discontinued in favor of simplified
zone based ticketing but even better
than that would be something
like an account based pay-as-you-go
scheme because
the whole thing with smart cards is the
computer knows
where you've gone you're tapping in
you're tapping out
and the computer is a lot better than
you are at figuring out which
which ticket is the best value for any
given travel that you're doing
there's no reason why i as a consumer at
the beginning of the day should have to
decide
whether a single a return or even a weak
ticket is going to be the best
value for my travel when the computer
should just be able to figure that out
for me
and i think a really good example of
this is some of the work that transport
for london have done in this industry
um and when transport for london
launched uh
sort of started beginning uh their
investigations into smart ticketing
technology
they were forced to innovate and that
there was nothing else available at the
time
and the very early nfc technologies that
were available
were extremely limited in terms of how
much storage space they had available
so it would have been completely
impractical
for transport for london to ask people
to pre-load
a single ticket journey on their
smart cards before travel every time um
so sort of go through these um in 2003
oyster launch just for season tickets as
i said
because of this restriction with space
on the card season tickets are way
simpler you're loading
one on for months at a time um
the next year they introduced pay as you
go journeys for both buses and rail
uh the year after that they introduced
automatic daily price
capping so this meant that um as a
passenger on tfl services
you could just ride all day and if it
turns out that it would have been
cheaper for you to buy a day ticket
the system just goes okay i'm going to
pretend you bought a day ticket and it
caps
your usage at the price of a day ticket
but likewise
if your journey if you're traveling
uh doesn't meet the price of a date
ticket then that's fine
you're not wasting any money because
you're still only going to spend
up to that point 2010 they rolled out
oyster pay as you go to all national
rail services within the capital
um in 2012 they were the first public
transit operator
in the world to accept contactless bank
payment cards
for use on their services and today they
now process
one in 10 of all uk contactless
transactions
and they're one of the largest
contactless merchants in europe
in 2016 they then licensed that
technology to cubic transportation
systems
who are rolling it out quite
successfully in various different cities
across the world
um so sydney recently launched um their
contactless travel scheme based on
tfl's technology a few months ago and
new york are currently
in early trials for their
contactless base scheme as well and
i think the really interesting thing is
oyster kicked off
in 1991. now if we think back to the
first slide that's
seven years before it so even started
and yet throughout all of oysters
history
oyster has never been and still is not
an it's so smart card
it has always been its own smart card
that uses its own proprietary backend
system
and i think the sort of crux of this
problem is computers allow us to just
scale
problems that we'd otherwise make better
solutions for
because it's way easier to just throw
brute force at the problem
than it is to actually sit down think
about it and try and come up with better
solutions
and with that in mind i think it's time
that we stop asking
how do we migrate paper tickets to smart
cards and we start asking
how can we leverage the unique benefits
that smart ticketing provides
before i close off there are a handful
of people on the screen that i want to
thank throughout
this research i spent about a year of my
life conducting this research
and i definitely wouldn't have been able
to manage it without everyone listed
here
that mind thank you for listening
uh so we have a lot of time for
questions
uh so if anyone has anything they'd like
to ask
i'd be happy to answer as best as i can
uh sure sam in the back
do you think um
[Music]
sure so uh for those of them here the
question was given the state of
the the fractured privatization of
britain's railways
what would the feasibility of a unified
standard to combine all of these
be and i think this is why transport for
london is also a really interesting
example because they're the only place
in the uk where they've actually managed
to do this
but it's also because transport for
london are the only organization that's
actually been willing
to step up and handle fair settling on
behalf of all of the different transport
companies
the entire point of it so is that it's
decentralized so nobody has to handle
fair settling for different transit
providers
but this also means that if i have pay
as you go balance on my card for glasgow
subway i can't then go and use that
on um like the time and where metro
they're just not compatible they don't
touch each other
and i think unless the uk government
steps in
and starts facilitating that fair
settling
we're just not going to see a unified
smart card scheme
the likes of ov chip cart in the
netherlands where there's just one smart
card that works across
all public transit in the company in the
country using one pay-as-you-go balance
and so in practice i think what's
probably going to happen is
the uk government's unlikely to step in
in that role and instead we're just
going to see more of a shift toward
contactless payments
where the banks are acting as fair
settlers instead
anything else
all right brilliant well you just have
an extra 20 minutes before lunch
um but i really appreciate all of you
giving me your time today
thank you