giving up my house but still we're gonna
have I promise you we're gonna have a
good time
so for this presentation I try to come
up with kind of a provocative title
which is like do you need a security
team right which makes you think well
we're talking to say right so um but
we're going to work through it and um
you know talk through a few things um
and hopefully have a good time
um before we get started so I work at
trusted Tech we're in a security
consulting company based in Northeast
Ohio work around the world all different
kinds of things
but one of the things whenever I go to a
presentation I always think like well
why should I listen to this person
that's talking right like you see a lot
of presentations and what I always say
is I'm certainly not smarter than
anybody else but I've been doing this
for a very long time
um
so I've been at Charleston tech for
about 10 years prior to that work for a
security startup for a few years that we
sold to Oracle and before that wasn't
security Consulting as well uh and I've
really been privileged and fortunate to
work with organizations of all sizes so
everything from sole proprietorships um
you know where somebody writes the code
takes out the trash
um
you know does all the sales all the way
up to the fortune 10. um and so a lot of
board presentations a lot of working
with different organizations we got to
see what works and what doesn't
um as far as uh certification I've been
a CI SSP forever um
and have a ISO 27 0001 lead auditor I
let my PCI qsa expire a long time ago
and a couple other things but very
familiar with a lot of the Frameworks
and standards that are out there
so I was on Twitter I think it was and I
read about how to give a presentation
and it said that you should give your
conclusion first uh to kind of
let people know what they're going to
hear right and tie it back to it in the
end
and I think the important thing is
um over the years I've really come to
the conclusion that a lot of what we
think of as security functions or
security roles uh also could very easily
have a home in other parts of the
organization
um
they can very easily be distributed to
other functions in the org um and and by
that I don't mean just training
everybody and saying security is
everybody's job right it's really the
different things that we think of as
security roles really can be done by
other functions um and with security
providing an oversight and a uh kind of
a guidance and governance function
so that usually upsets a lot of people
because people wonder you know what am I
going to say about that and we'll get to
what I promise
but also I think it's really important
to consider the source
um we're going to talk about you know
kind of My Views uh with how specialized
Securities become it's very difficult
oftentimes to have a full team and
Outsourcing it can make a lot of sense
in a lot of places but of course I work
for a consulting company right I mean so
I want to be very clear right I mean
it's kind of like if I tell you that you
need you know something that's very
important that I disclose that's the
industry that I'm in right I mean you
know they'll be unfair not to
um but uh yeah I think hopefully uh you
know we're gonna say is going to make
some sense feel free to ask questions uh
yeah let me cut me off whatever else
throughout this
but another thing is of course having a
shocking claim right and you know if you
look at this article from a while back
you know it talks from Bloomberg it
talks about you know how many job
openings there are right
um you know some sources will tell you
there are a couple million job openings
right
um and you start to wonder whether
that's really a shortage or more of a
misalignment of expectations the other
piece is really the definition of what a
cyber security rule is I mean there's
some that are pretty obvious right like
a pen tester or certain governance roles
perhaps but a lot of what we think of as
a security function is also a basic I.T
function in a lot of ways right so if
you have a firewall admin who's putting
in Secure rules right is that a security
role or an I.T role
um
the other thing is you know there feels
like there's not necessarily a shortage
of people that want to work in security
but there still is a shortage of people
um who are who are great at it in a lot
of ways and a lot of these things aren't
art as much as the science and you also
with individual specialization there are
a lot of people who might be very good
at one technology right or one function
that might be very good at you know
application security or they might be
very good at a certain specific
technology
um
but that doesn't necessarily mean that
you can hire one person that can do
everything right oftentimes you need to
have these larger teams where it's going
to make more sense to kind of spread
these functions and rules out sorry
across different you know functions
and there also seems to be a huge
shortage of organizations that really
understand the market Hey Kevin how are
you so
um so Kevin and I work together
sorry sorry to call you out in the
middle of this
um
I also think you really like real quick
aside I was saying earlier I was on a
stage just like this at the Federal
Reserve a few years ago when I fell off
right in the middle of a presentation so
I'm a little nervous about walking
around so I'll probably do that a little
bit less
but it's funny because you know in this
industry you tend to get a lot of
recruiting emails
and they're absolutely ridiculous
um you know one of the things I've
always done is I will always talk to
recruiters I know a lot of people don't
like to and for two reasons right I like
to know what companies are hiring
because maybe they need us to help do
some work is one thing but another thing
is you know I'll have friends and I have
people that are looking for work and if
a recruiter wants to call me about a job
I'm happy to what are the requirements
what are the expectations maybe I know
somebody right
um and help help in that way
but they'll oftentimes look for somebody
that can do just this really broad range
of things you know and and with things
that just don't exist in one person and
oftentimes we'll have a really low
salary to offer for us and it's not
realistic in the market
um you know people are also oftentimes
looking when they talk about like a CSO
or whatever
at mid-sized companies the other guys
want somebody that can do governance
right policies build a program do
strategy but also get their hands dirty
and plug things in and configure things
and everything else and fewer and fewer
of those people are existing in the
market and they're commanding a very
high salary so something to think about
as well as we look at whether or not
we're going to you know continue to
structure Security Programs in the way
that we have
and one of the things is because there's
so much specialization as I said I've
been with my current company about 10
years and been in the industry
longer than that but in the old days you
know I felt like I had a really good
handle on just about every security
domain out there right you could really
know and have some awareness of you know
most of the security software
um you know you could kind of have an
idea of of all these things
but now it's gotten extremely
specialized uh you know their tools and
software out there that are less a tool
or software or more so a career right
there are certain things that you might
buy for the environment that you then
have to hire somebody that's a
specialist in it
um
and it's just continued to become more
and more specialized and I think has led
to uh you know additional Outsourcing
and other things like that
and when you start to continue to look
at organizations and how much
specialization they can have right are
they going to have 20 different people
that each of them does a very specific
different thing as opposed to utility
players and I'm more of a utility player
myself but oftentimes utility players
are going to have that depth of
knowledge in every domain
and one of the things I open them think
about is you know if you go back a
couple hundred years you could read an
encyclopedia and have a pretty good
summary of you know what humans knew at
the time right I mean there's a lot of
nuance to that I get it
um
when I was growing up I'm 44 so I didn't
have the internet in my house when I was
in high school so we used to go use the
card catalog and do research that way
but I've always been a procrastinator
and I'm super lazy and the only
encyclopedia we had in our house was
decorative if it was a funk and wagonals
from like 1870 and so when I was really
late in assignment I would use that
stupid thing right and it was fine right
I mean you know nothing's changed from
1870 and now from you know the year the
country was founded or something like
that
um but back then I used to look at that
thing and just you'd read through it and
you could just really that's pretty much
what people knew right I mean you could
know all these different things
and in many ways I liken that to our
industry right you know a number of
years ago you could really be a
specialist in all these different things
and now it just feels like it's gotten
so big
um
kind of on a similar note
um on assessments years ago I used to
say that on the plane ride out you could
usually just about write the report
right 15 years ago because you knew
exactly what you're going to find right
every organization had the same problems
and that's very different now
um people have gotten much better at
that but it's something to think about
right especially as we you know for
anybody that's in school now think about
what you watch your career path to be
right and especially if it's highly
specialized on technology you know how
much work that's going to require over
the years to stay on top of it right if
you want to be a specialist in something
very specific it's a lot to keep track
of
um you know on the advisory side where I
work obviously regulations and things
like that are are similar in many ways
but to that end you know I think a lot
about you know what is our actual role
um you know is it to advise right that's
what I do a lot of I don't necessarily
you know plug things in or or make
changes but oftentimes give advice on
what to do or consult and make
recommendations
um testing I mean obviously that's a
huge topic uh you know a lot of people
that I talk to that's what their
interest is in they want to test things
in implementation
um and kind of moving towards you know
one of the things that we talk a lot
about
um is existence versus Effectiveness
right so how many controls do you have
you know what's in place what does your
program look like versus does it work
right so do I have a lock on my door yes
does it keep anybody out no
and are we equipped to you know kind of
build programs run programs you know
Implement tools run tools etc etc
and again you know we think about
specialization and how we're structuring
security at organizations that becomes
more and more important as a
consideration
another thing especially when I speak to
anybody at schools is to talk a lot
about
um kind of the information security
industry versus kind of what we think of
as hacking culture Etc et cetera and
kind of what we picture for that
um especially for kind of a career or a
future role
um you know I love working in in
governance
um you know I like to joke that you know
there's never a governance emergency
right like we have a whole incident
response team
and as we know they're busiest around
holidays right because that's when a lot
of this stuff happens no one has ever
called me at two in the morning and
asked me to write a policy
okay zero laughs I got like one laugh
out of that like I like these test jokes
and if nobody laughs and I kind of know
like what I'm dealing with my usual one
is we talk about like the cloud and I
say like it's a nebulous concept
nothing it's a good dad joke and you can
tell who took Latin right when they were
younger too right
um but anyway if that joke doesn't work
then I just kind of roll like it's
whatever we're good and if people laugh
at that then you'll get you'll get all
of me so
right that's just how it is
but it's something that I think about
you know is that
you know there's there's a lot of
culture and um camaraderie and other
things and a lot of parts of our
industry but there's not necessarily
like a like a GRC scene right there
aren't people that are um you know you
don't see like a lot of like cool
sweatshirts with like you know policy
development on it right
um but for anybody going into the
industry or thinking about the industry
for me it's been a um a very uh
rewarding
um thing to do I love what I do
um
people mock me um they said um you know
that I'm the youngest person they've
ever met in GRC which is not as true now
that's true 15 years ago
um
there's that work
but we start to think about security as
a function right and you know you can
get a hundred different definitions of
information security right you ever do
that like you know you go look it up I
was actually looking it up there's like
50 different definitions so just insert
your own in your mind right so whatever
you're thinking the definition is it's
that that's what it is that's what we're
going to use that and that's fine
but then we start to think about where
does information security sit you know
and it's obviously starting to blend
more and more into privacy and some
other things
but is it a function of risk management
right we hear a lot of people say that
security is just risk management or
doesn't become a business function you
know especially when you talk about
um you know if you're working in the
industry now how often do you deal with
these third-party risk assessments where
your your customers and your clients are
sending these big spreadsheets that's
about your security controls right all
day long and so in that sense you know
security is oftentimes a business
function right having that stuff in
place versus a technical discipline
um
and one of the things that I always
think about is that if all of us who
obviously have an interest in the
industry and in this topic you know
debate these things then how how are
people outside of the industry ever
going to get a handle on it and how are
we able to communicate what it should
look like to the rest of the
organization the other thing that's so
challenging is security is so different
at different organizations
um I'm not going to call anybody out but
I see some yawns so if you want me to
spice things up just like give it a
give it away we're good spice it up
let's spice it up let's do it all right
but
um but the other pieces is security is
so different in different organizations
right so like what's going to work at a
you know a Fortune 100 is going to be
very different than what's going to work
at a 50 person shop right and the issue
is that oftentimes they have to meet the
same requirements right I mean just your
data isn't more secure because you're at
a small company and you don't have the
resources to protect it
so again as we just kind of think
through where security is going to sit
um in the organization and overall as an
industry
um those are just things I think we need
to think about
so I'm not good at I.T at a whole just
FYI like so I I'm doing my best with the
PowerPoint but it gets me every time I
um
my wife so my wife so my wife and I
value education like a lot so we have
two master's degrees between us
but they're both hers
telling a story earlier you know during
the pandemic because I gave a lot of
presentations with zoom and whatnot the
number of times I'm like frantically
like trying to text her from my office
like run down and help me figure out how
to get the screens to work is very high
or if my kid in the summer if my kids
are home like my 11 year old or my 15
year old they if they were here right
now we'd be having zero technical issues
I can promise you that
we start to think about you know again
security is a specialization but
really it crossed over into so many
other functions right and you know like
who's going to eat your lunch right is
that is that a cool thing to say is that
kind of stupid
probably it's stupid I get it all right
but you start to think about it right
like if you work in security how much
time do you spend working with the legal
department right because here's my thing
I've been doing security for a long time
I've been doing compliance for a long
time an advisory I'm not a lawyer right
I don't you know so you we need to work
with legal departments to interpret what
the law says and then help them meet
requirements around it right
um you know it's kind of like it's like
I'm not an accountant I mean I can do
your taxes as well go to jail but I can
do your taxes
um but you know or privacy you know
privacy is continued to grow right so we
see a lot of standards and requirements
around privacy and things that are
really overlapping with security
um and that's obviously the kind of
Confluence of legal and privacy and also
audit right you know security so often
as an audit function
um I like to joke that I I love it
auditor so much I married one
that that show goes really over really
well like Issa or soccer like the
auditing groups but here here I kind of
bombed but
you know so a lot of things that we do
traditionally you know are we there to
check things or are they there to
provide guidance
in finance even right so Finance they're
oftentimes coming to us with these
requirements
um or general I.T right because again so
many of the rules and functions that I
think we've traditionally thought of as
security really are often as better
suited to Sid in other parts of I.T
right it's it's
um kind of better way to kind of spread
things out and IT addresses the Staffing
problem
of course procurement right so we spend
a lot of time again as organizations
dealing with third parties because
there's so much risk there right if you
look at a lot of the big stories over
the years you know you'll read you know
big company hacked right that's the
headline but the fifth paragraph is like
well it actually was a service provider
right it was actually some marketing
company they used that had their data or
whatever it is so procurement has really
been kind of moving into the security
space as well
um
and so we'll see where it goes but again
I just think that the way the industry
is structured and the challenges that
we're having is going to lead to us uh
continuing to move a lot more of this
stuff to General I.T with our oversight
so another piece is
educating everyone it's kind of funny
because everybody always says security
is everyone's responsibility I mean it's
true right
um but it's not what they're going to
think about all day
you know I actually
um because I'm older so in my day you
know there weren't like information
security degrees right so I have a
finance degree
um
and so I think about that like I don't
know anything about like I mean I took
all these accounting classes but I don't
know the ins and outs of accounting so
why would I expect accounting to know
the ins and outs of security right so we
have to help them and and um educate
them and this is going to lead us right
into our next slide we're getting to a
point I promise
but you always hear the example everyone
talks about like sales or accounting
they always pick is like the example
um you know that it's not necessarily
hackers it'll get you it's the you know
Bob in accounting
but again I think it's always if
somebody can take down your whole
multi-billion dollar Company by clicking
on one thing
maybe that's a problem right maybe
that's that's not their fault on some
level right you know if you think about
it if you you know use Vehicles as part
of your job you know it's my it's my job
absolutely to know the laws and follow
the rules and you'll be able to fill the
thing with gas but I don't need to know
how to rebuild the motor right I don't
even need to know how to change the oil
right as a user you know so where do we
start to draw those lines
there goes
another piece I think that said that's
incredibly important
um is understanding the business
I've talked to a lot of people that I
know
um because just working in this industry
a lot of your friends tend to be people
that work in the industry and oftentimes
we'll hear just these stories
um and they're always told with just a
ton a ton of flourish about breaking
into some system or whatever
um I remember years ago I was at a
conference and everyone's gathered
around this one person that was telling
a story about like hacking something
and it I mean it was amazing like the
this person should be in movies the way
they tell stories
but at the end I was like oh that's
really cool I was like so you know what
was on that system I was like oh it was
for it was actually for a parking gate
in a parking garage
it's like oh it's like it was at a
hospital I'm like oh okay I'm like so so
what could you see like what do you mean
I'm like well could you could you see
the credit card data on there no
what could you see like maybe who was
coming and going because maybe I guess
you could use that somehow I was like no
it's like well what could you see it's
like well I could see what time the gate
went up and what time the gate went down
like all right I mean but my point being
is you know that's obviously you want to
fix that flaw but how does that affect
the business right
um
and what's really you know been
interesting over kind of the time that
I've been in the industry is people used
to always joke about security was always
going to say no to stuff right and
here's the thing
like if a company has an opportunity to
make a ton of money on some new product
or whatever and Security's like no we
can't do that what are they going to do
we're gonna make the product right so we
want to just make sure that we're giving
the message in such a way that you know
we're helping them you're helping to
lower risk and make things better
um you know another thing that I've just
noticed across the industry is people
want to get to zero risk well there's no
zero risk right I mean how did everybody
get here I'm guessing some people
probably walked which I guess could be
dangerous with the ice but most people
drive right driving is one of the most
dangerous things that you can do
um for any of us but we still do it
right so we're always going to have risk
in the things that we do
and so
a lot of times what I'll see is people
that want to get to zero risk and then
nobody wants to listen to them because
you're never going to get to zero risk
right it's making sure you get to
acceptable risk or understand the risk
um Etc because we're not the FAA
um although that's become a really bad
example lately with all these like near
misses but traditionally you know the
FAA was just such a fascinating
organization because they really did
work to get to zero risk when I was a
kid
stupid touchscreen all right when I was
a kid you know my dad used to travel a
lot he'd go to Europe and planes would
like crash like it was a thing right I
mean you remember that in the 90s so
there would be plane crashes and I used
to worry when he traveled and these days
like my kids don't even understand that
as a risk right I mean when was the last
domestic plane crash it just doesn't
happen and it's because the FAA I mean
if a plane crashes in the middle of the
ocean they will use submarines and bring
up all the parts and reassemble the
thing in a warehouse and then fix it on
every single plane out there right I
mean but that's just not how most of
Life Works getting to zero risk
so it's really just understanding you
know how we can lower that risk and help
organizations do that
um
and when security really understands the
business and what's what its goals are
and can help them meet them
it's going to be much better integrated
into the organization
um and and really Auditors and
Regulators can be your best friends
right because they can help you
um you know one of my favorite stories
is I work with a pretty large company
years ago and I went out to visit them
and they were super excited to see me
um which almost makes you feel good
because I like that you know I think I'm
fun but I was like oh why are they so
excited to see me and then well they
just got an audit report and they didn't
understand what was in it like what do
they want us to do I'm like well where
are they they're like well they're a
floor above us like let's go ask him
right so we go up there and like we just
talk to the audit team about what
they're looking for and what's going to
meet the requirements and you know what
the issues are and like everyone was
like so excited like I was a hero I
didn't do anything I was just to go talk
to the people that give you the audit
report right um and and so that's my
thing right so talking to Auditors
talking to people who have stakes in
this is super important
so another piece that I would like to
bring up so what is that so my kids like
these would you rather books you ever
seen those
drink a gallon of ranch dressing or
drink a gallon of ketchup
my kids get so max I'm like I'm not
doing either
like well you have to pick one I'm like
no I don't
I'm six foot three and you're like three
feet tall I'm not I'm not doing either
like how are you gonna make me do that
but the point is right is that in life
though we have to make choices
and if somebody comes to you and says
would you rather pay for a software
security team
or work to get your developers to write
better code right so would you rather
have two extra developers and have all
your developers be running secure stuff
or would you rather add a bunch of
people later in the process to do
security well for most companies you
know the answer is oftentimes going to
be more developers right they can they
can do these things
um
and again especially now in today's
economic climate and as hard as it is to
find people I think that's going to
continue right and this is going to be
especially more true for these
specialized roles right things that are
are still defined as security functions
even though they're probably better
suited as general i t functions
like the example I used earlier you know
is a firewall admin or somebody that
does iam
like how would you count that in your
security spend
right because that's a question I get
asked all the time right it's like well
what percent of my it budget should be
security
I don't know unless you tell me how
you're defining security right I just I
don't know because it's you know as a
part of this ftes the whole FTE whatever
else whatever it is there's some things
that are very obvious
um you know if I'm buying product X then
I have to have any way to run the
company and the more secure version is
10 more so what is the security spend 10
that 10 is the whole thing or whatever I
just you know it's just it's a challenge
that we run into
um
but just as we continue to to mature the
industry and and see these organizations
you know is going to be thinking about
you know where these different roles and
functions are sitting
another piece to think about is you know
our reporting structures
um how often how often do you hear
security should not report to it
right that's a pretty common refrain and
just over the years there's some very
clear examples of that you know if you
have um like real world situations that
you kind of modify to be able to speak
about is you know the I the head of I.T
is incentivized with a bonus to ship a
product
and it's an insecure product and so
security is like well you shouldn't ship
it well if security reports to I.T what
happens
probably get shipped right
um
but does that necessarily make sense for
technical Implement implementation roles
right so if you're out there configuring
firewalls or you know doing IAM
functions does that make sense to sit
outside of I.T
um or is this only does this only become
true if information security becomes a
true governance and kind of advising and
risk management role
and you start to think of security
moving over into again that more
governance Rule and then the
implementation becoming more of an I.T
function
does that sound ridiculous anybody does
that make some sense
nobody cares okay all right
so the comment was around
um uh ISO and that and just how the
different you know categories and
functions all work together and I'm
right with you
um I have uh I have a lot of thoughts
about different standards and Frameworks
um my overarching one because you don't
want to hear me ramble about Frameworks
for like eight or ten hours
uh is generally the biggest issue that
we run into
um I don't mean we as a company but just
we as an industry is that people will
oftentimes take these Frameworks or
standards and want to use every part of
it right so like the new cyber security
framework it's great but the subtitle is
what for critical infrastructure
production and so it's a great it's a
great way to structure a program but it
may not apply every part of it may not
apply to you if you're making t-shirts
right it might be different if you are
critical infrastructure Etc so that's
one of the things too is to kind of pick
and choose
um where where possible not you have to
comply you know with these different
Frameworks and standards
we could pivot we could talk about ISO
and nist all day
that's my thing I'm telling you no
nobody wants to do that
I'll do it we can um after this if you
want my card like anybody I'll talk
about Nissan ISO all day it's cool I'm
gonna try to sell you anything we'll
just talk about it
but I think you know with everything
that we've talked about is that this
decision's gonna be made for us right it
doesn't matter what we want or what we
think
because we can't necessarily find the
people that we're looking for
um anyway and again just especially with
all the specialization
um you know like I mentioned when
recruiters are out there looking to find
people they're never looking you know
you know or they're often I was not
looking for these very specific roles in
most situations
the vast number of them and maybe
because I work an advisory and that's
just who calls me but they really are
looking for somebody to do everything
it's like that's cool like if I could do
every single thing that you listed in
this call you know in this email you
sent me I probably Drive in a Ferrari
right I wouldn't be driving my my Toyota
product right
um
and even if you are able to find people
you know what a budgets look like
because that's another thing that we're
kind of seeing is you know budgets are
changing right and the kind of wild west
of you know security spending is you
know seemingly contract in a lot of ways
and even determining like what skill
sets we need you know is not necessarily
something that or they start really
thinking about it tends to be more
reactive than you know proactive
um
and the other thing that we see I think
too is a lot of duplicative roles
and again that that comes down to a lot
of the the very technological things
but the big one is is that third parties
are going to continue to tell us what we
have to do right and oftentimes when we
think about you know requirements we
look at laws and regulations and
standards and everything like that but
one of the biggest ones people forget is
contracts right so other organizations
requiring us to do stuff right and
what's interesting about that is it
won't always really be something that
technically should apply to you right
but that you still have to comply with
it just because that's their rule so
again I think we're gonna we're gonna
continue to be told what we're going to
be doing
now again always to bring it back around
I work in Consulting right so I pay my
mortgage because people use third
parties right if they people didn't use
third parties then I I have to go work
somewhere else right so I want to be
really clear about that you know if I'm
standing up here and I tell you how
great you know tomatoes are for your
health that's cool but you should know
if I'm a Toyota farmer right it's fair
um
but I do think the key becomes you know
what to keep in-house and what not to
keep in-house you know what are the
things that we can Outsource or things
that we can use very specialized
services for
um
and what are we going to do ourselves
and uh you know what are what's going to
be different in every organization
so Mike is leaving because he's giving a
presentation next
not because he's bored
oh I don't want to be like the first one
to leave and then everyone else's life
leaves too it's like a party right yeah
we're all out right
um
but when we start to think about like
what to bring in house and what to you
know Outsource or what to use
specialized third parties for
um you know it really does depend on the
organization and its function you know
think about a manufacturer versus a
software company
manufacturing is fascinating to me
because again I used to almost use it as
an interview question like 10 or 15
years ago
um is I would say if you were to walk
into a manufacturer
that has zero compliance requirements
zero customer data zero credit cards
nothing else how would you sell them on
the need for a security program right
and that's like one of the hardest
questions ever right I mean it was maybe
you could you know back then it's um you
know maybe you could sell them on the
availability piece or what have you
um but it was just a much different
thing but now everything's connected
right it's all this iot every single
thing is connected to everything else
um and so it's much different but their
needs are going to be much different
um
I also everybody ever seen the movie
Tommy Boy
probably one of the greatest pieces of
Cinema in history
but it's fascinating right because when
they wanna when they want to destroy the
company what do they do they don't
delete their records They just change
everything right so they don't just burn
all that paper they change it so all of
a sudden the brake pads that are
supposed to go to Peoria or go to
Cleveland and whatever else so you know
that's another thing that obviously you
know a lot of those companies are
concerned about is not just the the
availability but also you know the
accuracy of that data
but even in the sense you know when you
talk about Outsourcing and again I
always want to specify like I work for
organization that has an IR team so I
want to be really clear that I'm not
here selling you anything this is what I
think right this is uh um but I'm
talking about like even internal IR
plans right like what does it make sense
for most organizations to have an expert
in forensic technology
or malware reversing or whatever else it
is a bigger company sure right but those
are things that oftentimes you know are
better outsourced um you know it's
better to have some kind of flow chart
where there are things that we know we
can do internally on day-to-day stuff
you know and when do we pull the rip
cord
um
or at what point does a company become
big enough to have a red team right or
or any of those things and that's
obviously Up For Debate and it has to do
you know with complexity as well
um but also you know I think the other
piece that's going to become extremely
important is this third party risk
management
right because again everywhere I go
everybody I ever talk to one of their
biggest issues are all these vendor
questionnaires right it's all this
third-party risk management it's all
they're just getting hammered with it
every day
and what's fascinating to me is
sometimes even at Giant companies you
can go talk to a giant company with
thousands of vendors and they'll have
like three or four people doing
third-party risk management
right um so I think that's something
that's going to continue to grow
um and it's going to be kind of
interesting so that right there that was
my quick anecdote
you can see my screen
but I think as we continue to look at
um distributed security functions you
know it's going to continue to really be
outcome based
because again all that has what we see
with programs is very reactive rather
than you know building for the future
orientation anticipating what the issues
are going to be
and looking at what we want to
accomplish and you know what are our end
goals
um
and other piece is who's determine the
end goal right because how often times
in organizations do you see risks or
issues being accepted at a certain level
of the organization that the board would
never accept they knew about
so really pulling everything together
and making sure everyone is working
together to understand what our desired
outcomes need to be and should be and
how we're going to get there together
oh that didn't work hard there is
and again another thing um I always say
that we'll never be out of work in this
industry because everything changes so
quickly right like it seems like every
few years like you see a story that's
like oh they're fixing the password
issue or they're building like the most
secure thing ever I'm like oh man what
are we gonna do for work
right you ever see those and okay but
you always see those I'm like okay what
like what am I gonna do because I'm not
like I don't know what I would do when I
was in school in the summertime I used
to work on a golf course and I mowed
lawn some of the grains and stuff I had
to be there at like 5 30. it was the
greatest thing ever right if every job
paid the exact same amount that's what I
would do right so if we solve the
security problem that's cool I'm gonna
go do that okay I'm gonna go I'm gonna
go back to the golf course
um
but it's just amazing because every time
you think maybe things are going to get
better and they're going to need less of
us
um something new comes out right it used
to be that we focus so much on building
walls around everything and okay things
are getting more secure and then all of
a sudden everybody's sharing data
everywhere all the time with everyone so
okay I guess they need to see it
um
but if you look at you know a lot of
organizations
um
if you look at you know
software as a service the cloud right
platform is a service everything else
Etc as a service
is that funny is that funny
okay that because I got like three
things that were funny so far
maybe four depending all right
I'll keep trying
you miss 100 of the shots you don't take
according to Michael Scott quoting Wayne
Gretzky
there's five all right
um
but no I think that's a model that we're
starting to see right because a lot of
organizations that we saw throughout the
years you know were very good at
applying policies and procedures and
everything else to on-prem but then they
move stuff to the cloud and I'm not
saying the cloud breaks but all the
policy procedures they developed over
the years suddenly no longer quite work
or quite fit with what they're doing you
know in the cloud and so now they're not
following their own policies and the
model there you when you go to
organizations
um you'll oftentimes see a ton of
contractor badges they're everywhere
because they bring in so much
Professional Services to do all this and
I think that's probably going to be a
continued model for security right I
think a lot of security is going to
continue to be Professional Services
um also keep in mind that the same
security structure is not going to work
everywhere it's not going to be the same
thing everywhere and I really think it's
going to be a fundamental um you know
shift in just how we think about
security and how we're implementing
security and and maintaining it and I
think especially for anyone in the room
that's a student you know you're going
to see that over your career it's going
to be very different I think that we're
kind of at a point where you know things
have kind of morphed over time but it
feels like it's starting to accelerate a
little bit
um
so with that I'll have some time for
questions
does anyone have any
yes those are
so the question was in kind of
governance and GRC are there any skills
that are more desirable you know for
individuals that want to enter it or
grow in it
um so two things first of all grab my
card after if you want because I'm
always happy to talk to you about it
um you know my career throughout it both
early on and you know every every step
of it there have been so many people
that help me and so I'm always happy to
do the same and um but yes I think one
thing that's so important is you know
unless you go out and start your own
company and everybody you know that you
can't just tell people what to do right
so I think in life and everything else
it becomes we need to learn how to you
know make arguments and persuade and
educate and inform rather than tell
um because it's so I know that soft
skills it's so obnoxious how much people
talk about soft skills but it really is
true right
um and so I think especially in advisory
roles it's extremely important
um you know to be able to articulate
messages well
um to talk to people about the why and
not just the what you know it's you know
even if when we're talking to end users
if you just tell people what they have
to do I mean some number will do it
maybe even begrudgingly but if you
explain to people why it's important
you're going to get a lot more
compliance and I think in governance and
an advisory that's extremely important
as well right so making sure that we're
telling people why
um and and you know that kind of thing I
know that's kind of broad
um and I don't answer your question
the other piece is
um from a more tactical perspective
is you know if you're getting into
compliance standards and everything else
if you can really understand how they
overlap
that's a extremely important skill right
so that you can help people in the sense
of if you do these three things it's
going to cover these parts of these you
know standards if you those four things
is going to cover these parts Etc so
that instead of looking at every
requirement
um you know on its own you can see where
they overlap and do things once
but as I said I'm gonna be completely
open with you like I don't I give a lot
of presentations and I don't get a lot
of people asking about about how to get
into GRC so call me anytime and we'll
talk about it and yes I will anything
you need
they do
I'm so I mean as I said I I love
advisory
um and and again it's just I joke that
it's like the Dermatology of information
security and not in like in in the and
I'm talking about the schedule because
again right if you're going to be a
doctor like Dermatology is the way to go
for two reasons right one is they do
procedures right and procedures where
you make all the money
and the second piece is there just
aren't emergencies like I said I mean
there's not like a dermatologist on call
you know like on a on a holiday at three
in the morning you're not running you
know you're not flying into the hospital
to you know do something right so same
thing with GRC and advisory
and it's Contin it's grow and it's grow
so much
um
because you know what organization is
never going to get smaller
government right who makes laws and
regulations there you go so it's just
but I really think especially if you
look at kind of how few you know um
regulations there have been I mean at
some point they're going to be you know
they're gonna probably uh the Dam's
going to break so I think we'll always
be in demand for those things
um
the other thing is I think is making
sure you know how to work with like
legal legal teams
so the question was around you know
where my security reports to and you
know can it report somewhere aside from
it
um without kind of somebody having that
specialized I.T knowledge that summarize
it pretty well and and kind of what
we're seeing out there and the answer is
we're seeing everything right so again
just because you know I think
information security is still very new
as a industry and as a role and
everything else you know and and you
know it hasn't helped um that there are
a lot of regulations out there that now
require organs have a name CSO right and
so oftentimes I'll just toss that on
somebody right it's not necessarily A
Defined role so somebody has to sign off
that they're doing it so I think the
thing is is always backing up and
determining like what the head of
security or CSO rule is you know is it a
true board level position not not that
commonly right
um
and whether it is you know somebody
that's kind of the head of I.T security
or is it someone that's you know more in
a governance role and when it comes to
highly regulated environments
um oftentimes you know what we think of
or what I think of as security
requirements from a more compliance or a
regulatory standpoint ends up following
to like the head of Enterprise risk who
then kind of delegates it down to
somebody in a more technical role so I
know I'm not clearly answering your
question but but the answer really is
it's all over the place
um the other thing is it oftentimes has
a lot to do with internal politics and
organizations
um you know people don't want to have
that move in different places or
um you know things like that so there's
not I don't necessarily have a clear
answer for you except that we see it a
ton of different ways
um and just given how different
organizations are there's not really one
clear answer or clear way to do it
did I answer your question
mostly 90 80 percent
73.6 that's I graduated from high school
with like a 2.3 so I'm on it
yes
so how would you go about it
so the question was how would you kind
of sell I would I would be very clear so
so a mid-size Manufacturing Company
security and I would be clear out
selling them on the ideas different than
me selling them security right because I
always want to clarify and be honest
about what I do
um on the idea of security it's become
much easier to sell just based on
availability right because things are so
connected and if you look at
um organizations and how long they can
stop their line without going out of
business you know is a pretty clear one
the other one is as much as a lot of
people hate regulations or hate GRC
for security people I mean I loved it
for years because it was the only reason
a lot of people did stuff right if I
come in there and try to explain to
somebody why they need to do these
things it's like get out of here Alex
but if I come in here and say hey the
regulation says you have to do this or
if you want to take credit cards you
have to do this my job's much easier so
I think it depends um you know depending
on what industry they're in you know
there are certain regulations around
manufacturing the other thing is that
the manufacturing regulations are
growing so you start to see um and sorry
I I don't want to get it wrong
especially if this is recorded but I
forget what it's called but like the
like the the auto manufacturers
Association or whatever it is you know
starting to push security standards out
um as part of their quality stuff you
know like the like light there's like
lighting groups like you know for like
lighting manufacturers that are starting
to push out you know certain security
requirements as part of their quality
standards Etc so it's showing up
everywhere so that's one way it's moving
into
um the manufacturer but usually is the
availability
um the other thing is do they have
contract data you know you know what
data do they have the other thing is
it's really shocking
um I think in manufacturing environments
people don't realize what's connected so
they think something is you know not
connected or vulnerable but then it's
like well actually that system that's 75
years old has something hooked up to it
that you know tells you what level the
materials are at and that talks back to
our you know sap and all of a sudden
that becomes and then that pulls that
whole thing into scope for whatever
so to answer your question
in a really roundabout way
so it depends if you give me like a more
specific situation I can answer it for
sure
that's that that's the thing is is as
you bring things online and it's just
having it is having a strategy for it
and I hate to say this because you know
as a third party absolutely you never
want to sell like fear uncertainty and
doubt but internally right if I'm if I'm
an employee manufacturer then I'm happy
to be like well look at here's 10 news
articles in the past two months that
show manufacturers that went out of
business because they can't make stuff
because they were compromised
I hate to give that recommendation but
internally like that's I hate when sales
people do it but internally but I think
that's one um and the other thing is I
think look for you know whatever the
manufacturer is
um specifically I mean if they make
steel then fine examples of Steel
manufacturers if they you know and
because I said manufacturers such a
broad thing I mean they could make
Pharmaceuticals or they could make you
know parts for fighter jets or they
could make I don't know like
those troll to holes I don't know
any other questions
yes
it's super well it can be super tough
and it depends right I mean a lot of
stuff is check the box
um
it really depends on the organization
and kind of what their goals are the
fact of the matter is
um you know if you look at companies
like
think about all the companies that have
gone out of business in the past like
five or ten years right did they go to
business because their security was bad
no like companies do stupid things right
I mean they make bad marketing decisions
they make bad HR decisions uh make bad
financial decisions
um you know I mean you can't you can't
go shop at Kmart right now and it's not
because they have bad security right I
mean it's so so all I'm saying is you
know the expectation that companies are
going to do everything make lots of bad
decisions but do security really well
right it's probably fantasy so it really
depends
um and again I do think that
I promise you we're not going to get
into like specific compliance talk
because everybody's gonna hate me but if
you look at things like you know like
like PCI 4.0
um you know PCI has like really evolved
over the years back in the early days it
said like you had to have a web
application firewall that's what it said
you could literally it could be set with
any Yeti and as long as you had it
he was a check mark right but over the
years it morphed right to become more
prescriptive and people like as much as
people like beat up on PCI at least it
tells you exactly what to do right not
like hippo like HIPAA feels like it was
written by Consultants to get more
billable hours right it's like you can
interpret however you want but like PCI
is very specific and even that you know
now it's moving a lot more towards
judging the effectiveness of controls so
and again nobody wants to talk about PCI
but
now at least if you're checking the
boxes and those boxes are being checked
thoroughly then you're going to be in a
better position so I think it's it's
probably a multitude of things that are
going to move us towards that
um but it's a tough situation plus
nobody wants to spend money they don't
have to it's like it's like insurance
right
I'll tell you I'd say I'm 44. I've been
driving so now 16. I've had zero claims
on my insurance ever
right so you have all that money I've
spent and if I had invested that
conservatively right I should have just
not had Insurance Taking My Chances
right but again people just don't want
to spend money on something they don't
have to do
can I answer your question sort of okay
any other questions
let's do it I love fun questions
what
what do you
so here's the thing so I got my start
running documentation many years ago
um and before I go into security
um so I worked in I worked at a website
um like a media website doing coding and
that kind of stuff and then I got into
like process documentation
and one thing that's kind of funny is if
you ever are like sitting in a Ferrari
and you look at the owner's manual and
you look at the media supplement and you
look at the screenshots on there you
will see that the radio station in the
screenshot is a Cleveland radio station
because I wrote a lot of the owner's
manual for it
nobody cares but it's fun here that's a
funny fact
um and so I've done I've done
documentation forever and you know the
the answer is the policy that I love
best is the one that somebody had the
most trouble with
consultant like you can't be in
Consulting for as long as I if you don't
like what you do because it just burns
you out right
um and so policies are one of those
things again it's like I mean are we
saving lives no but is it pretty awesome
to like walk into an environment where
someone's like oh we've been having so
much trouble getting this done and I
don't know how to write this policy and
you can help them out so that's my
favorite policy to write
I can answer your question without
really answering it because I I mean
there's like there's not I don't have a
favorite policy
all right
any other questions
yes
I have not I played the old one which is
not there anymore
um but no I I need to go to the office
because actually so I was I gave a
presentation I actually I gave a six
hour training
um a few weeks ago and right before the
training
um they tell us they don't have a
projector
so I'm like hey Dave I need a projector
so of course he ships one to my house
and so I use that and this is a long way
of saying that I have the projector
sitting on my desk at home and I have to
take it into the office so I have to go
in there anyway so
but yeah I'll go in there and play some
video games I um
so I'll tell one quick story all right
so back in the old days we so we have a
um
we have a super Super Nintendo
um in the old office
and we played Mario Kart a lot
um we're super busy now if it doesn't
happen as much but I was always
traveling as I was out working so I just
never played and so I would get beat
every time I played like every single
time everybody made fun of me like it
was awful
and so
um my wife now but we're just dating the
time I went home and I told her so we go
and we buy a Super Nintendo we buy Mario
Kart and we played every night for like
three hours we play Mario Kart
and then so I go into the office and um
this guy named Dave Thompson who was
always just the greatest video game
player ever he has the high score on our
pinball but I go and they're like oh
let's play Mario Kart and they're like
all groanings they don't want to play
with me so we start playing I just nail
them all right I win like by a lot
um because I've been practicing for like
four months and then I've never played
again
so yeah
pardon
it's yeah well I wasn't good as a kid
either
so it was it was not like riding a bike
because I was just terrible
but yes so yeah I'll go and check that
out
any other questions and I always say so
I've worked so I I worked as I've been
to trust that 10 years but prior to that
we worked in a different consulting
company together
um and then he kind of went off and I
went off to a software company you got
back together but everyone's always like
like what's a Michael yeah working in
Dave Shadow I'm like it's not a shadow
it's a glow
right like I love it like we've worked
together forever but I I've never been
anywhere where I didn't get a question
about Dave
he's awesome yeah
all right well thank you everybody so
much as I said it's always I wasn't sure
how big of a crowd we get talking about
GRC and advisory given the competing
track but I appreciate everyone coming
out it's been a great pleasure
[Applause]
all right thank you so much so we're
going to go ahead and start the next
talk at 11 o'clock that will start from
both rooms so in this room we're going
to hear from Carrie Randolph but other
than that you'll have a 10 minute break
and then we'll start right back up at
11. thank you
welcome back everyone to the 11 o'clock
talk we're trying to stay on schedule
here with both sessions going on at the
same time but this today we're going to
hear from Carrie Randolph she is the
senior security consultant for ghosts 30
Pro previously she was the CIO for
Oklahoma's Department of Education and
she was one of the co-founders of
besides Oklahoma so without further Ado
we'll go ahead and introduce Kerry
Randolph on her presentation of working
smarter not harder to thwart modern
hackers take it away
[Applause]
hey good morning everybody it's my first
time in South Dakota coming from
Oklahoma so I'm really stoked to be here
and share some information with you guys
I hope you find it valuable
today we're going to learn a couple
different things we're going to learn
how some Russian State actors are
bypassing Duo MFA I'm going to walk you
through how we've exploited IPv6 we're
going to talk about how we've extracted
ldap service accounts from fax servers
to eventually gain domain admin
how to find systems with default
credentials how to review and Harden
your system configurations also why many
vulnerabilities with the CVSs of 10.0
should not be on the top of your
remediation priority and we're going to
end with a step-by-step repeatable
process to identify vulnerabilities that
your vulnerability scanners cannot find
a little bit about me and my company uh
we're a small firm about four years old
out of Tulsa Oklahoma I was co-founded
by Jeff and Susan Wilson Jeff has
extensive amazing background working for
the NSA Federal auditor Susan leads up
the legal side of our house is our
company's president
um I'm lead to the GRC side of the house
and Ed Crandall does Business
Development we've recently added a new
team member for client engagement but we
specialize in bone management pin
testing risk assessments were very
strong in the HIPAA space we're seeing a
lot more come through with glba and FTC
safeguards and general virtual CSO
Consulting
a little bit about me Annabelle gave a
great introduction I went to local
colleges in Oklahoma also local tech
centers I placed a strong value in
getting hands-on experience not just
theoretical I have a strong background
in public sector about 10 years of
experience working with state government
I'm proud very proud to be a co-founder
of besides Oklahoma which is a security
conference happening next month it'll be
our ninth year I'm also a founding
member of technohoma which is a
non-profit in Oklahoma that works to
facilitate different user groups across
the state hack nights coding groups
we've got crazy amounts of channels for
every topic and programming language you
can think of in Tech
so today what we want to start with
thinking is how do hackers think you
know it's not all necessarily devious
whether you know it or not every person
in this room is a hacker starting with
kids have you ever watched a kid trying
to open up a cabinet door where they
know that the snacks are or how to
figure out a toy or how to work a
smartphone those kids are hackers they
have no fear that they're going to break
something they're constantly
manipulating things one tactic doesn't
work I'm going to shift and pivot and
try something else that is what they're
doing
um my toddler has actually locked my
phone up for 15 minutes she's enabled
accessibility features uh to for a
for the blind where you have these crazy
touch controls it's crazy what all kids
can do and you have no fear of breaking
technology
so
from our company this is a little bit of
our methodology for pen testing and we
want to start with thinking about
external Networks
and how do you identify your exploitable
weaknesses to an internet-based attacker
your traditional traditional malicious
attacker who has that true outsider's
perspective to your network
um and you want to start with the
vulnerability Management program and why
that's so important uh regular ongoing
process of identifying assessing and
Reporting and managing weaknesses and
vulnerabilities with new clients we see
known vulnerabilities affecting 75
percent of their systems and that's on
average and this leaves a massive
opportunity for hackers
um vulnerability Management's important
it's required requirement for many audit
compliance risk management Frameworks
nist nist 853 specifically calls it out
IRS SSA sieges PCI there's lots of new
things going on with FTC safeguards
those deadlines have been expanded from
December to June cmmc if you're in
manufacturing and DOD contracts Center
for Internet Security also calls out
continuous phone management as a
critical security control
so what we're seeing here this is a
chart that's breaking down new
vulnerabilities identified year to year
25 times increase in new vulnerabilities
discovered in 2022 from 20 000. and you
might think why are there so many new
vulnerabilities being discovered for
2023 we're on track to hit 24
000 new vulnerabilities discovered in
that year alone and the answer is
hackers and research groups are becoming
more prevalent hackers are no longer
operating as individual groups their
Fortune 500 companies it increases their
bottom line to find new vulnerabilities
that you have to
protect against and try to remediate
recent studies are showing that most
Security leaders have a vulnerability
backlog of over a hundred thousand
vulnerabilities
the average time to fix a single
vulnerability in 2021 was 202 days or
seven months
you have a backlog of 100 000
vulnerabilities and it takes you seven
months to fully remediate one how are we
going to do this most orgs are still
struggling to patch log 4J new stuff is
coming out about log 4J and that came
out in December of 2021
um and they've got references here for
where you can go and you can look at
this data for yourself if you'd like but
you know there's obvious technical
challenge but I think a lot of the times
we forget about people what are our
processes and procedures
um you know how can you ever work
through the sheer volume of
vulnerabilities if you're not using
consistent methods of prioritizing
remediation I've talked to organizations
that have zero scheduled maintenance
how are admins ever going to be able to
remediate vulnerabilities a bulk of them
there is some type of patching and you
have to reboot to apply patches if your
business doesn't support maintenance and
say no our systems have to be online 24
7. you can't have regularly scheduled
maintenance what are Security
Professionals or your assist admins
supposed to do it becomes very very
difficult to do just basic maintenance
and again attackers are more well-funded
than ever before and they have more
resources and more incentive to discover
these new weaknesses
uh so at go security pro we've
identified what we have we coined as our
three pillars of an effective
vulnerability Management program and the
first step is identification
do you
conduct automated external vulnerability
scanning where you're getting that
perspective of that true malicious
attacker do you also do automated
credentialed internal agent-based
scanning the value with that is if a
malicious attacker does get a foothold
in your network where all can they go
maybe you've got a really hardened
exterior perimeter but what if a
credential becomes compromised they get
the foot in the door where can they move
what can they do manual testing is
important and all three of these have to
go on on a regular basis we've seen orgs
hit with uh you know exploitable RDP
exchange servers network devices you can
also see exposed non-vulnerable services
like database ports SMB signing web
server content that maybe shouldn't be
accessible
so the reason why you need both
automated and manual testing is this
automated testing is going to give you
that
Auditor's perspective are you just
trying to check a compliance box and say
yes we do this you will see you know
you'll have full access to all
vulnerable applications like Adobe
Reader Java all of those from the
attacker's perspective you're actually
testing for vulnerabilities so the
auditor's toolkit doesn't identify
um
and that's really important to do both
when you're testing for exploitable
Ability it helps you find those things
that the scanners aren't going to find
you know maybe you couldn't fully
remediate a vulnerability but you were
able to introduce some compensating
controls maybe you can put it behind a
DMZ maybe you can change some firewall
rules how do you actually go through and
verify did the changes I made fix this
did it reduce the take it all back to a
risk management framework did my
compensating controls actually reduce
the likelihood of this event occurring
or this vulnerability being exploited
you also have to have manual inspection
to look for false positives
vulnerability scanning on web
applications is notorious for throwing
false positives those web apps are
working exactly the way that they're
supposed to but it can trigger finding
you need manual inspection to make sure
you're getting all assets
I mean if you are only scanning a
section of your network and maybe you
don't even know I mean it professionals
will go into places all the time and
their inheriting systems they're
inheriting networks how do you do that
Discovery and make sure you're
protecting all of your network maybe
you're on a college campus and okay hey
I'm seeing all the faculty but then you
forget about oh there's this little
group of computers in the library lab
those aren't being managed what's going
on here so there's tons of
vulnerabilities that you can find that
are not going to be being picked up on
vulnerability scanners weak protocols
default passwords week configuration so
when we do manual testing we always find
several default passwords that have huge
impacts on the organization and I'll go
into some of those in a little bit more
detail as we go on
so digging into the external network
when we do external network bone
scanning what do we see
Legacy TLS some of these will show TLS
1.0 and 1.1 are vulnerable to man in the
middle attacks which will risk Integrity
of authentication and the data sent
between two points like a website and a
browser they were deprecated by the
internet engineering task force in 2020.
there's also weak SSL TLS configurations
remote desktop Services proxy logon
default credentials you know the use of
weak encryption ciphers Des three days
rc2 all of these are known to be
affected by the birthday attack which is
a essentially just a brute force method
with some detailed math for short Cipher
blocks
we once had an organization that they
had extremely bad luck they were
switching out a firewall and while they
were switching out firewall they didn't
realize that RDP was enabled on a server
so in the short amount of time that they
were switching out their firewall they
had a breach because RDP was publicly
exposed and facing
so I want to walk you guys through
something that we thought was pretty
cool a relatively new hack that we
started doing last year and this is
exploiting IPv6 I'm going to walk you
through the attack sequence steps one
through three here is basically
intercepting DNS and we want to force
victims to authenticate to our the
attacker system unless of course being
ethical hackers in this point people
were paying us to do this we weren't
just doing it for fun
um so men in the middle six is the pen
testing tool exploits default config of
Windows to take over DNS default DNS by
default Windows supports IPv6 and
actually prefers it over version four uh
Windows systems will request DHCP
periodically so attack sequence uh
you're going to run men in the middle
six uh I've got the script up there if
you want to take screenshots of this
feel free to go ahead the D just Limits
The Man in the middle activity to just
the target domain
Windows is periodically going to lose
that DHCP version 6 Discovery man in the
middle is going to pop in and respond
with DHCP leases get some fake IP
addresses and then link some local
ranges into think DNS server
then we're going to use a regulate tool
we're going to relay intercept
authentication to admin controllers
again not going to fully go through the
script there but feel free to take
screenshots if you want to use it and we
have all the different syntax there to
find and this is going to do wpad
spoofing and credential relaying it's
selectively reply to DNS queries to add
redirect authentication to the domain
controller
um within minutes of this pin test we
had an export of all user accounts and
all Group Policy settings
if I have your user accounts it's only a
matter of time before I can crack a
password
uh alternatively we can also relay that
authentication to specific Target hosts
um
I thought local user as an admin we can
get the password hashes if I have your
hashes only a matter of time till I'm in
this is something that vulnerability
scanners do not find this is identified
through manual detection prevention
methods listed here disable your
vulnerable pump your vulnerable
protocols get your firewall set to block
IPv6 disable some of your other settings
group policy and enable SMB signing
that's another thing flip of a switch
change a group policy push it out
so this is fun
service accounts default credentials and
fax servers uh pen testing world this is
like a little plot of gold at the end of
the rainbow
so what we did we were pin testing and
we found a fax server no big deal we got
in you might see some faxes maybe a
little bit of Phi maybe a little bit of
pii putting on the organization but what
we found is from a basic user account we
could see the configuration and we've
masked this we want to protect our
clients obviously but we can see here is
the fact server is authenticating with
ldap they had a service account that was
mapped to their login server which is
their domain controller and we could see
the user account now the login password
is masked so we couldn't really see that
so what could you do here
we can change the configuration so we
decided to stand up our own ldap server
and we redirected it and we reinforced
plain text authentication then we had
the password
unfortunately for the client the service
account for that effect server was set
up as a domain admin they had not
followed principles of lease privilege
so we were game over one fun fact just a
our firm when we do pen testing we set
an engagement and once we obtained
domain admin it's not fully game over
for us we reset and we go back to the
back of the beginning of the drawing
board and we start testing again like we
had not obtained domain admin to see
what those other attack vectors might be
so how can you identify these unknown
bones what all is out there there's so
many different systems there's so many
different softwares what can you do so
again these manual testing is needed
whether you're using qualis tenable
nessus rapid seven they're not going to
detect default and weak passwords
vulnerable protocols like POP3 and IMAP
in your Office 365 environment they um
any support for legacy TLS thinking
about third parties the speaker before
you know talked a lot about third party
risk management do you require unique
accounts for each individual at your
third party support Personnel or is that
admin credential for your MSP may be
shared among five ten fifty different
support staff at your MSP how are they
securing that credential with privileged
rights into your network these are all
vulnerabilities that can be exploited by
attackers so even when we have these
volumes in our inventory of known
vulnerabilities
for whatever reason they're not getting
prioritized
so we talked a little bit about default
credentials on average we find 18
default credentials on internal networks
with new clients
laziness with setting up systems so I'm
going to walk you through this is going
to seem a little rudimentary but hey
here's what works right so this is step
by step what we do first we're going to
run nmap we're going to see what all is
out there again feel free to take images
or you know take a shot of this script
it's going to work over everything
um
so once we have those URLs and IPS for
their systems we're going to extract
those URLs and then we're going to just
open them up in the multiple URLs
Firefox plugin and we're going to start
working through tabs
we're going to manually start googling
each of the products they have and what
are the default passwords for that
system common default credentials are
going to include admin admin admin
password or admin and a blank password
some less common ones we've seen for
like Dell remote access controls is root
Calvin
um I've got some other printers out
there some ABCs some badge access
systems
so many of these are kept with default
credentials and again if I can log into
those systems and I'm there where else
can I pivot or move laterally or other
things that I can find or are those
Associated service accounts potentially
domain admin or have higher levels of
Rights
so that's covering a vulnerability
identification next up we're going to
look at prioritization and communication
you know are you prioritizing based on
risk and exploitability not just a CVS
score are you accounting for changing
threat landscape what is actually being
exploited
in the wild in real time what exploits
are people actually using and how are
you regularly communicating those top
priorities to it teams maybe in a bigger
organization you have someone that's
doing volume scanning and is it someone
on the applications team to fix this or
is it someone on the servers team is it
if it's IIs is it applications or is it
server is it networking or is it server
who is going to be responsible for this
and how are you communicating once you
identify
um so this is just a simple screenshot
from uh from qualis it's a normal
vulnerability dashboard that you might
be used to singing if you've used one
before and you log in and you see 187
000 unique vulnerabilities
it's overwhelming it's incredibly
overwhelming and where do you start
um how do you pick which one to do first
um how can you take this technology and
then also from an administrative
approach you think oh hey I've got this
tool that's identifying my
vulnerabilities but are your staff
trained to use it properly how are you
integrating the people elements and the
processes to actually be effective with
your program
so what we do is we incorporate csis
known exploited vulnerabilities catalog
I think it's up to as of last night it
was 896 items and these are
vulnerabilities that sisa has known that
a malicious attacker has actually taken
action on and had a successful result
another thing that we do is we bring in
red team analysis we're not just looking
at those scores of top tens we are
looking for the things of what make our
hackers happy if they go into this
system and they see this
what is going to get them in what is
something that's very easy to exploit
SMB signing is huge if our hackers see
that they're going to get so happy
especially if it's on a domain
controller
um you can export full lists of users
and makes it really easy to then start
doing credential hashing
and sometimes even things is like auto
run and auto play
if we can exploit that and if we're
actually physically on site what type of
USB drive can I plug in and it's
automatically going to execute
so doing a little bit of a dive into CSA
known exploited balms these are the
volumes that have been exported and
here's a breakdown of their different
scores
the 10 out of 10 this represents 1.4 of
all known cves not just the sisa
vulnerabilities but all known
vulnerabilities with a 10 out of 10 CVSs
score
if you start trying to work through your
10 out of 10 and there's let's just say
we're just looking at the Cecil ones and
there's 124 of them it's going to take
you seven months to remediate one on
average you're never going to get out of
working that 10 range because new
vulnerabilities are being discovered 25
000 bones discovered last year we're on
track to have around the same amount
discovered this year so while the sisa
catalog gives us insight to those
volumes that are known to be exploited
you know what else can we learn
what we're seeing is attackers know that
it's very common hey this has the
highest score I should start working on
that first that's the most critical
right so what they're doing instead of
exploiting those high risk very critical
vulnerabilities they're stringing
together attacks using multiple exploits
from that five to eight range
so like SMB signing I think that's like
a 7.5 maybe somewhere ish in there on a
CVS score so they are being smart it's
the same intelligence that we have as
Defenders
um or if you're a pen tester too you're
looking through these things if you can
string multiple attacks together that
are less likely to go under the radar uh
it's you're going to be in and it's
going to be easier for you to perform
your attack
um
list only presents about half a percent
of all known vulnerabilities and it's
really an amazing reference and but it
can't be your only influence on what
you're prioritizing
um so what is not in the CSA catalog uh
here's a handful of things that are on
there these are things that red teams
find but automated scanning does not and
a lot of these things come down to
configuration how are you enforcing your
group policy
um so we're going to switch we're gonna
that's external network we're going to
look at internal Network and what do we
see
uh we see patching Legacy stuff and
configurations so with patching are you
doing operating system patches what
about your firmware what about your
third-party software
um we see Legacy systems and
applications
um you know patching is really such a
broad and simplistic term
um in comparison to how good patching or
bad practices will overall affect your
security posture most major volumes are
zero days that get a special name you
know like print nightmare or blue key
paternal blue those things are so severe
they're going to be remediated by
patching and it's going to be very high
priority and high visibility so you know
maybe you have automated Tools in place
to push OS patches but do you also have
the means of patching third-party
software that can be difficult
especially for smaller shops that don't
have an Enterprise level budget you know
outdated Adobe Reader and acrobat
there's massive campaigns going on right
now especially targeting HR with
LinkedIn and indeed and they're sending
malicious PDF files and if one of those
recruiters open up a PDF that they think
as a resume and they happen to have a
legacy Adobe Reader Adobe DC on their
systems it's a high probability that
just by opening that PDF that they think
is part of their daily job duty is going
to infect their system
um Legacy is just understanding the
severity of no more patches how do you
explain that to administrators and yeah
hey technically it's still running it's
operational but what is the impact
there's no more security patches there
is no more support from the vendor from
this
um you know we talked about default
credentials earlier uh but what about
shared credentials what about
non-expiring credentials I had a risk
assessment binding
for a shared credential for a client
that had an MSP they had 50 support
staff with access to that credential and
they had a breach
forensics pointed back to the msps
account you know did they go into the
details of full forensics and
accountability there
um I'm not at Liberty to speak but the
point is the more people that know a
secret is means it's not a secret
anymore and then you have other
regulation and other compliance
requirements like HIPAA has a unique
attribute access rule it is a HIPAA
requirement that every single individual
has to have a unique attribute so when
you go back and look at your logs you
have to be able to clearly and
definitively say it was this person that
took this action
uh Wii configurations
um these are all things that a lot of it
will tie back into policies and
procedures it's not the sexy cool
hacking Mr Robot stuff that you see on
TV there's a lot of cyber security that
is downright boring and a little mundane
policy and procedures are are really a
huge piece and serve as the foundations
of your internal security program
fishing bypassing Duo so there's a
situation where Russian State actors
gained a foothold at a non-government
organization through a weak password
whether that was a default credential
you know April 2022 exclamation point or
2023 but the account was active in A.D
but it was unenrolled in Duo so they
were able to enroll that accountant Duo
and it prompts for re-enrollment so the
user was still active in ad so they were
able to get enrolled
and at the bottom we're just walking
through you know what that duo login
looks like where they're hey verify the
ownership and then they have the QR code
that they need to sign and they are
completely activated within Duo
once they were in as a standard user
they found print nightmare
from there they were able to execute to
privilege escalation to administrator
and from there they could disable Duo on
certain hosts and there's a script if
you want to see what they used there's a
little bit of that that was redacted
just to protect the client the the NGO
that this happened to but you know Duo
configured to fail open so MFA is not
required if the duo server cannot be
reached
then they were able to RDP into domain
controllers you might think you know
what could we do to prevent something
like this and avoid re-enrollment
scenarios avoid fail open configuration
from a boring policy procedure you know
think about reviewing your accounts your
periodic access reviews what are your
termination procedures like does it
actually get notified within a
reasonable time frame that someone's
been terminated or is no longer with the
company you know ensuring those inactive
accounts are fully disabled and active
directory and not just unenrolled and
then print nightmare you know that's
huge that's something that you should
have patched it's actually also in
ceases known exploited vulnerabilities
catalog and make sure that you don't
have fail open set that is not unique to
Duo
um another hack that I find really
interesting because it used multiple
attack vectors uh was the Uber hack in
September of 2022 it's now been
attributed to lapses what happened was
they fished for credentials
once they got credentials they were
stopped by Duo
so then they did an exhaustion attack on
Duo and they had a per a certain identif
person that they had already identified
and they wished them they called them up
on the phone and said hey I'm so-and-so
with it you've probably noticed that
your phone's been going nuts with Duo
notifications we're having a little bit
of issues MIT I need you to verify
what's your authentication code on Duo
right now
the person gave it to them
so they were in once they were in with
that person's credentials they've
located a Powershell script and inside
of that script was hard-coded
credentials and those credentials
happened to be for their privileged
access management system
so from there they're in the Pam they
could give themselves access to anything
that that Pam was managing so they give
themselves elevated privileges oh I want
this this it was like a shopping spree
with Daddy's credit card
um so we've now found that over 70 77
000 employee records were found to have
been exfiltrated user data was not but
they got
a cash a big fat loot box of tons of
employee data
uh we configurations uh remediated with
group policy SMB signing it should be
enabled and required this is simple
through group policy if this is on a
domain controller you're open to Mana
middle tax through SMB poisoning null
sessions land man
null sessions are going to allow
unauthenticated attacker to get that
list of local users when it affects
domain controllers you can get a full
listing of domain users once again once
you've got that list of users you can
start doing credential sprays in Brute
Force null sessions allows any
authenticated user to obtain sensitive
information about the system
landman and tlm V1 it's just a weak
method for encrypting passwords it's
open to man in the middle attacks
default auditing isn't necessarily A
vulnerability but it is a risk if you
don't have audit logs going back 90 days
to a year you're likely not going to
have enough evidence if you do have some
type of security event or intrusion and
for bigger targets and bigger
organizations we're seeing more and more
that attackers will gain that initial
foothold
and then they sit and wait
you know maybe you've seen in movies or
something and you see a sniper getting
into position and they're on the ground
and they're there for days weeks slowly
moving into the environment same thing
as malicious attackers they're gonna get
into that environment and they want to
try to stay undetected for as long as
possible so they're going to take teeny
tiny small movements in your system do
some Recon figure out where they can go
and not be noticed and what all they can
find so sometimes they might be in your
system for more than three months if you
don't have audit logs going back then
you're not going to be able to tell when
did this actually start
and then default ldap you know again
with the back server examples if you if
you have open DC's then with default
ldap then it's going to be pretty easy
to get that privilege privilege access
right
and password controls are
pretty standard I have a feeling that
most people in this room have a pretty
good idea about password controls but
we're going to go into a little bit
anyways and organizations when I'm doing
risk assessments I see a lot of things
with how are you managing local admin
accounts laps Microsoft's local
administrator password solution is a
free built-in tool for active directory
and you might think what's the big deal
you got local admin we still have group
policy from 80 that's setting everything
up and controlling everything if I have
the local admin I can change local
policy
I can stop a machine from checking for
group policy and updating and enrolling
in group policy if you get local admin
it's only a matter of time before you
can Elevate from a local admin to a
domain admin so this is a great free
tool whether you're setting the same
username and password across all ad
accounts or local admins for each
workstation in your system I'd very much
encourage you to use this free tool get
that unique credential for every single
local admin on your network
um so this is probably going to be
really remedial but I left it in here
because I thought you guys might find
Value in taking it back to your clients
your customers your constituents
um recent pin test that we did two
percent of employees had one of these
passwords in a similar syntax where you
have first letters capitalized month
word whatever season
did rotate your password every 90 days
what's the season we're in what's the
month we're in followed by the year and
an explanation exclamation point
these passwords are very easy to
remember but they're also very guessable
do you have tools you know what can you
do in your systems to prevent stuff like
this there are certain tools that are
out there that'll allow you to build
like a loud list and block lists for
certain passwords or certain syntax you
can prohibit consecutive letters and
numbers you know ascending or descending
um with Azure ad with at least a premium
P1 license you can enable custom band
passwords and you can add entries into a
banned password list so you know Dakota
2023 exclamation point couldn't be a
password potentially at Dakota State
University
also thinking about reusing power
passwords across services
and you know where's the value in a
password manager I personally use a
password manager I understand the
concept of putting all your eggs in one
basket but if I have a 20 plus character
complex password and I back it up with
MFA remember we can't depend on just a
single layer of Defense we have to
multi-layer things to have a true scope
of security
um but you know that benefit manage of a
password manager is it's going to let
you generate that random secure password
a unique credential for every single
service that you use
um do you guys remember when Colonial
pipeline was hacked in 2021
it was chaos on the East Coast from DC
Baltimore Maryland area all the way down
to the Carolinas in Georgia uh was it
gas stations in DC 80 some odd percent
of them were out of gas
and 40 on down the coast there were
pictures in the media of people going up
like plastic Walmart shopping bags and
filling shopping bags full of gasoline
because they were scared and they were
hoarding it it was mass panic in the
streets
um the president had to issue executive
orders because aircraft could not refuel
they were out of fuel at airports so
they had to have executive orders to
change
um the laws governing how fuel can be
transported across interstates
Interstate boundaries they had to change
that
um so what happened with Colonial
pipeline is they compromised a
credential for a legacy VPN
mark one Legacy VPN
compromise credential weak credential
maybe how was that password configured
did they have configurations in place at
oh after so many failed attempts this
account's gonna lock up
and it was single Factor Authentication
remote access single Factor
authentication once you have username
and password you're in and so yeah one
single password was cracked at Colonial
pipeline stopped their production for
three to four business days and it was
mass panic on the Eastern seaboard
um so again I think you guys are all
going to be this is very remedial for
you but I thought you might find it
valuable to share with your constituents
um which password stronger
you guys want to shout out one or two
why
exactly modern password standards are
complexity aside longer password is
better uh some quick stats on how
quickly or how long it would take to
break one of those passwords and just a
reminder white space is considered a
character
so we configurations what else can we do
a lot of organizations are going to put
out benchmarks but you're also going to
see CIS a lot of organizations and
companies are no longer even writing
their own benchmarks here's the link to
CIS come do what they say to do it's
going to give you a step-by-step
breakdown so CIS for those that don't
know it's a global non-profit it was
founded in 2000 it also operates the MSI
Sac major companies tenable like tenable
doesn't write their own benchmarks
anymore like nessus they Point
everything to CIS
but if you're going through these please
note that a lot of them are very
extensive it's going to walk you through
every single setting and configuration
in that environment so the last I looked
like the Windows Server 2019 guide was
over a thousand pages long
these are things that Consultants like
me and my firm we would love to come in
and help do these things but we're also
going to tell people here's the
resources that you can do this yourself
I get it you don't have the resources or
the manpower to do it but if you do uh
these are totally things that you can do
yourself and these are there's resources
out there that are free and open to you
that you don't necessarily need to pay a
lot of money we work with organizations
anywhere from you know small non-profits
where the nonprofit director is HR and
I.T and the CEO to large Enterprises
with 30 40 000 employees
so you can also find guides for other
cloud services Azure AWS gcp Oracle
um you know this is another thing that
you can do that does not require hacking
skills this is something that you could
set an intern with you don't need
Advanced skills to say hey this is the
system go through and start making these
configurations but of course do it in a
mindset that you're considering change
management don't go wild west on this
and start making changes in prod think
about how your changes are going to
affect your end users
um you don't want to make processes that
are overburdened and change things that
in a way that's going to affect the end
User make sure you're following your
processes
um but you know also verify your Source
make sure it's a reputable Source going
to CIS uh if you want something that's a
little bit more secure you can look at
dsa's stigs so if you're looking at like
a security level CIS are great their
benchmarks are fantastic but if you want
something a little bit more robust more
secure you can look at DC stigs
um some things that will not be in CIS
that you may have to dig for a little
bit more might be some stuff like
Microsoft Azure devops GitHub oauth
recommendations o wasp is another great
resource from some things some
development systems that may not be
covered by Center for Internet Security
so again just step by step some things
that we'd really like to call out you
know again the SMB signing is huge
um and it's just you know this is what a
portal might look like if you're going
through that step by step
so that's prioritization and
communication next in our third pillar
is regular accountability
your finding bones you've had a risk
assessment done
what are you doing next are you meeting
regularly to discuss progress are you
identifying the obstacles and adjusting
that remediation strategy
um you know effectively
and then also how are you communicating
progress to leadership
so many times and part of what I love
about my job is having moments and
opportunities to help it teams tell
their stories a lot of the times we're
quiet we're in the background people
know when things go wrong but they don't
know all the things that we're doing
well so what are the steps that we can
take to tell leadership this is what
we're doing this is how we're serving
this is how we're protecting you
um so again you can approve what you
don't measure tenable rapid seven qualis
those are all going to give you
real-time snapshots they are not going
to retain historical data if you want to
be able to tell your story and know how
you can improve measure what you want to
change you have to do some data
analytics you have to do some data
capturing and do some measures
uh and then also thinking about how
you're going to gauge exploitability you
know what is that defense posture
against moderate attackers and how do we
really be effective on reducing
exploitable weaknesses
um this is some graphs just straight
from Power bi been anonymized from some
of our clients um so what we'll do is
like we'll track uh end-of-life
operating systems over a time period and
again this is dummy data so we can see a
breakdown of different EOL operating
systems it seems like every week a new
flavor of Windows 10 is becoming EOL
um and you know a Gambit of other older
Windows operating systems there but we
can see slow steady progress right we
haven't fully remediated all of our
Legacy os's but we're making progress
and that's the that's the key to all of
this um the previous speaker made a
comment about you're never going to have
zero risk same thing with
vulnerabilities there are so many coming
out you're never going to have zero
but how are we constantly making
progress and improving our environment
uh some other tracking here you know
overall vulnerabilities by month how
does that change and there's you know a
Gambit of you know different lists on
the top left there blue keep was a big
one log log for Shell unsupported Adobe
Reader that's sometimes you get into a
business uh situation where oh I can
open PDFs I'm just fine and Adobe has
killed off licensing it's not supposed
to work anymore but you know have we
actually went to a modern licensing uh
long term the better you communicate and
tell your team story The more leadership
is going to understand your work and
ultimately invest in security not just
monetarily but also through policy
enforcement there are so many times that
organizations might have good policy and
procedure but maybe they make exceptions
I worked in an organization where we
implemented rules about screen savers
because screensavers allow you to bypass
screen lock security mechanisms but we
had a director that had our own little
meeting space in our office and she had
a TV connected to a computer and she had
to have a little fish aquarium
screensaver on her computer
so one of the most targeted people in
the organization that would be
spearfished
we let have a security exception so she
could have a fun little fish aquarium in
her personal conference room
um
maybe some bitterness and a little bit
of jadedness is coming across even in
the Stream we'll see
um but you know all of this to say the
more leadership understands and supports
security and how everyone really plays a
piece in it in some form or fashion it's
going to better enable you to thwart
hackers and those attacks upon your
systems
um so an interesting story that I want
to share with you guys and just a tidbit
that you might find useful we see a lot
of EOL server 2008.
um so off the cuff you may only consider
upgrading the operating system you know
part of the process of vulnerability
management and risk management is having
a realistic approach to what can we do
maybe it's too big of an impact to
upgrade server 2008 maybe we can't do a
lift and shift into Azure maybe or maybe
you can or maybe it's a legacy
application and we can't afford the
resources whether it's people or money
or time to also upgrade the application
rewrite code because we've got to
upgrade the application so what can we
do it's not going to function on a newer
OS
Microsoft is actually taken a little bit
of a Brilliance dance on this it's one
of the most beautiful marketing things
I've seen them do
if you lift and shift Azure or Windows
Server 2008 into Azure they're extending
support
you got an on-prem physical server no
they're not going to support it anymore
but if you put it in Azure where you're
most likely to not move it out then
you've got extended support through uh
2024. so even when you have
accountability something as simple as a
regular meeting where you can discuss
stuff like this with your peers gives
you the opportunity to come up with
creative Creative Solutions you know
it's not always oh man we're stuck with
this because we got this Legacy
application and no one will invest money
to buy the new application and then the
huge project to do everything that we
need to do to make it functional on a
new operating system or find a new
solution there's lots of different ways
that we can remediate vulnerabilities
buy ourselves a little extra time
whether it's something like this or it's
some type of other compensating control
that reduces the likelihood of that
vulnerability being exploited
um this is the basic vulnerability
management maturity scale generally what
we see is people begin with
um
looking at patch management
that's your basis establishing patch
management we see a lot of clients that
have established some sort of security
program or more in that defined area
they have some periodic credentialed
bone scanning
maybe a periodic pen test but what are
they actually doing for remediation what
we want to do is we want to get
everybody into this optimized State
you're doing regular credentialed and
internal scanning as well as external
scanning you're getting both
perspectives right what's the true
external malicious actor seeing and if
they get that foothold in the network
what are they seeing after that we want
to be able to track performance metrics
and then also we're remediating not just
on that CVS score but what is actually
being exploited in real time what are
those things that are ridiculously easy
to exploit whether you're a script Kitty
or an advanced pin tester
um
so what all are preventative measures
how do we reduce weaknesses
vulnerabilities and risks from the start
um we see a lot of time there's safety
third
and Safety and Security can be
interchanged a lot and you might lose
some digits if you're doing security or
safety third so bring Security First
help your organization get in that
mindset that security in it is here to
help you not hinder you all too often
they see oh you won't let me pay my
bills while I'm at work I can't go
shopping while I'm at work why are you
stopping me from doing these things why
did you make my process go from three
clicks to five clicks
help your teams and your organization
know that it is there to help you you
know if something goes wrong with a
rocket launch
and there's a security or a safety issue
does Nasa say oh let's just send them
into space anyways you know it's like a
9 out of 10 risk we'll just roll the
dice we can accept that one right
um no they scrub the mission they fix it
and then they go back and then they
actually go ahead so some of these
things we've talked about along the way
if you've got a weakness of default
credentials deploy some standards create
a checklist create policy and actually
take that policy and then implement the
technical controls that enforce that
policy do you step-by-step requirements
that have to be completed do your
periodic reviews and testing you know
how can your management help you set
aside dedicated time to do these things
I know a lot of people are like I'd love
to do these things but I don't have time
to do them you have to have supportive
Executives and Leadership that carve out
time and see the importance of doing
these you know have you do you have an
inventory
if you don't know what all your assets
are how can you be certain that you're
protecting them
um you know it's the whole concept of
you can't protect what you don't know
that you have and that periodic testing
is going to help you identify those
devices that may not be getting patches
we've seen issues where hey we've got 10
systems that are missing this patch and
that patch and that patch and we go back
and look and maybe it's a cumulative
update they've got patch one and now
they're trying to get patch three but
they've missed patch two
how do we get other teams involved to go
out and actually inspect and figure out
what's happening immediate leads to
discovery about bigger issues and
without doing those periodic and regular
testing Communications accountability
you're not going to discover those
things that could affect things not only
outside of iot but also the business as
a whole
um so again management support is
crucial for these
um
unless you know you've got a really good
incident response program or a good mmsp
and you're just prepared to financially
respond all of your incidents that may
come as a result of not following these
another concept that I wanted to leave
you guys with because I found that it
drives home really well with people who
are not Tech and especially not security
is this is a basic cyber security
triangle you're going to see this most
likely in any cyber security 101 class
so the idea is in a happy world you
would have a little dot in the very
middle of this triangle a nice little
balance of security functionality
usability but if we think about this
the most secure computer they in the
world so if we take our little Dot from
the middle and move it to the tip top
where the security it's a computer that
you never turn on it has zero
functionality zero usability so how do
we help Executives understand we turn on
the computer you need to have antivirus
you get on the internet you need a web
filter you get email every use and every
functionality that you have you have to
have a compensating security control
um another analogy that I've seen that
helps very well with end users is
substitute security and safety and think
about driving maybe you drove here or
you took public transit to get to the
conference today would you get in that
vehicle and take it somewhere if it
didn't have brakes or a seat belt go a
step further and think about specialized
systems so maybe you have systems that
work that are accessing PCI Data or
HIPAA data those are specialized systems
running or even OT thinking about
operational technology rather than
Information Technology what do those
systems look like and equate that to
driving and think about like Formula One
and NASCAR
those specialized systems those
specialized Vehicles not only have
brakes and seat belts the drivers have
to wear helmets they have to wear fire
suits you have Emergency Medical
Services on standby this is an analogy
that I found that works really well with
end users at all levels and then also
Executives so helping them understand
that yes we took your process from three
clicks to five clicks yes you have to
log in with not just a username but you
also have to do MFA that's reducing your
functionality it's reducing your
usability but it's adding the security
in place that we need to have for
today's environment
and that's the end of my presentation
I've got some contact information here
if you guys want to connect with me or
my firm but are there any questions from
the crowd
yeah
shoot
Packers
it can be okay well the question is uh
the slide that we had about like with
the sisa distribution background uh
there was let's see let me get back here
so we can see it
um and it was you know thinking about
attackers and not going after the 10 out
of 10 CVS scores and really looking at
you know the five to eight range of CBS
scores
and you know is it kind of playing a cat
and mouse game of what you're choosing
and the answer is yes
uh you are playing a cat and mouse game
you're you're doing a little bit of
whack-a-mole I've got a whole I've got
an exploit I've got a vulnerability here
let's smash it another one's gonna pop
up so when we're talking about 25 000
new vulnerabilities discovered last year
on track to have the same amount or more
discovered this year it's going to be a
constant battle but what you do is you
layer your perspective it's thinking how
do I prioritize
and you can't look at just a CVS score
alone you have to look at your
environment and then you have to get
that perspective what's actually being
exploited and that's where the sisa
catalog comes in as you can see hey what
is actually known that someone did this
exploit and was able to breach a system
and then you also layer in that red team
ethical hacker perspective you know what
is actually likely that I could do this
hack so if you see something you know
like the SMB signing or the null
sessions that's lower in the middle of
the score but then also thinking about
your it team and what's easy to fix
um you know can I knock out a
vulnerability just by pushing out a
group policy update and that's a heck of
a lot easier than going to Executives
and telling them I need five or six
figures added to my budget to replace a
system
um so it's a balance and it's thinking
about slow steady progress
you know what can you any type of
progress is good you're never going to
be able to remediate any everything
whether it's a vulnerability or a risk
that's been identified so it's a balance
and figuring out what's right for you
and considering all those different
perspectives uh does does that answer
your question all right yeah yes sir
okay so the question is
um
ultimately who should be responsible for
risk decisions or who what actions are
you taking so if an incident does happen
where oh my gosh we got hit and there's
this vulnerability that was a 10 out of
10. we knew it was in our environment
who's accepted that risk and the answer
is yes there should be an individual
um I I personally don't think it should
be in I.T unless it's an executive level
um
to me that comes back to policy and
procedure each organization needs to
figure out what works best and what is
right for them so when you have that
Foundation of good policy and procedure
you outline roles and responsibilities
you have a defined risk management or a
vulnerability Management program and we
say here's how this is going to go and
you know maybe like even the same thing
with change management you have a
standardized process we say okay we're
going to have our patch Tuesdays and on
patch Tuesdays we're going to patch
regular maintenance items but then what
is our plan for zero days when those
patches come out so for me it's about
having definition and it's whatever
works for you if you have an I.T
position and Executives decide yes we
want it to make that decision then
absolutely if that what works for you
and that organization great ultimately I
would like to see executive support and
it would be another executive at a C
Level or a risk management director
saying this is an acceptable level of
risk because you're not just looking at
the risk to
someone getting in your network and data
potentially being exposed I think a lot
of the times Executives think okay well
there's the monetary value what is it in
the monetary value of a data breach but
how do you monetize the reputational
impact
and you know think about organizations
that
um how many people were using solarwinds
but you don't anymore
what's the reputational impact and the
long-term look at your business and the
other piece is for me anyways is getting
Executives to understand I've had
clients tell me oh we don't care if any
of our data gets out there
and
nobody's going to come after us and
hackers are no longer going after Boeing
looking for a top secret missile plans
or something like that to sell on the
dark web it's it's not what you see in
the Spy movies it's the concept of how
valuable is your data to you a few
months ago an Electric Co-op in Colorado
was hacked and they lost like 90 percent
of their customer records
and their customers couldn't pay their
electric bill because they had switched
everything online uh it only had their
business side there's no record yet that
actually hit the OT side like the power
grid and everything but it's how do you
start recovering from that what are the
impacts of your reputation losing
business data and hackers are operating
as Fortune 500 companies they're not
looking to resell your data for the most
part it's how valuable is your data to
you and will you pay that Ransom that's
probably more than you asked for but is
is that cover it
all right
I'm glad I didn't disappoint checklist
done
all right does anyone else want to tell
me how great of a job I've done with
this presentation like this gentleman is
so kindly done or any other questions I
can answer for you today
going once going twice
all right thank you all for being
attentive if you want to hang out in the
room I'll be given another talk after
this
[Applause]
all right we're gonna go ahead and take
a one minute break and then Carrie will
go on with her next presentation about
hacking trust establishment
by Carrie Randolph and she's going to be
this time talking about hacking trust
establishments take it away
all right so yay back-to-back talks
um you guys were in the room before uh
you guys know me
a quick introduction
um I've got about 13 years of experience
in the industry
um from Oklahoma Oklahoma trained and
educated it's been about 10 years since
state government uh Gambit Litany of
roles listed there I'm really proud to
be a co-founder of besides Oklahoma and
I found him under of Chuck Lahoma which
is a non-profit in Oklahoma a little bit
about my company we're a small firm out
of Tulsa Oklahoma specializing bone
management pen testing risk assessments
virtual CSO work so today we are going
to focus in on trust
being being trusted trusting others this
is a massive topic that could very
easily be a two-day training session my
hope today is that by the end of this
talk you'll understand different types
of trust and how to quickly establish it
with others keeping in mind that like
all things security you have black hat
you have white hat there are as many
black hat reasons to establish trust as
there are white so I strongly encourage
you during this talk let your mind
Wonder think about those Evil Genius
opportunities uh scenarios and
applications that you might leverage
trust in a different uh in a different
way
so
um I'm not a psychologist I am a fan of
social engineering and physical pen
testing I've never actually been paid to
do physical pin testing I've won social
engineering challenges and stuff at
various conferences but again I haven't
done this professionally so this is all
just internal experience
um so I think it's different to
understand the cycle the psychology
background of trust and psychological
safety where trust is actually a
component of psychological safety it's
personal it's individual it facilitates
questioning and risk taking the more you
trust someone or feel trusted by them
the bigger risk you'll take it's why
kids have no sense of fear around their
parents they do crazy things because
they trust that no matter what they do
that parent is going to protect them and
take care of them
understanding and taking consideration
of trust factors can increase the trust
that other people have in you and it can
change your relation friendships and
interactions in every respect
professionally it can improve the
success of your Social Engineering
strategies and your pretenses can
increase sales through better client
experience and Customer Loyalty I can
prove your team's productivity and
reduce turnover
um so two main types of trust
cognitive trust effective trust short
version of this cognitive trust is Bob
has his sispy and 20 years of experience
his qualifications match our projects so
I can trust him effective trust would be
Bob looks like my cousin and I really
like my cousin Bob's got a really nice
smile so I think I can trust him
cognitive trust is you know capability
and consistency it's trusting someone
because they they said that they follow
up with what they do so when I gave you
my credentials and my background at the
beginning of this presentation I
attempted to establish cognitive trust
with you you should trust me because I
had this experience I've done these
things I've had this education this is
my skill set this is why you should care
and Trust what I'm saying so by
outlining this talks agenda and the
focus points I laid out consistency
this is what you're going to expect to
hear in this talk will I actually be
consistent I think we're going to roll a
D20
um it's about you know most of us here
probably rely on cognitive trust coming
from a technical background do we have
the appropriate Knowledge and Skills are
we competent in our jobs you know our
clients customers teammates they trust
that we have the right skills and the
technical Acumen to build deploy
maintain and secure their systems but
while you might be capable are you
consistent are systems running smoothly
in your environment because you test
patches before deployment or does
systems frequently crash
both of those things are being
consistent working right all the time
crashing all the time you're being
consistent but how would it sway trust
one way or another with your customers
or your clients if you're consistently
maintaining your systems do your clients
and your customers begin to believe that
you care more and bleed over from that
cognitive trust to effective trust
because they think that you care if
you're not maintaining their systems do
you really care do they trust you less
so in Oklahoma
it is
um
we got two main colleges Oklahoma State
University and Oklahoma University and
at OU games they have a slogan it's
Boomer Sooner so somebody else out
Boomer you're gonna get sooner airports
around the world people tell you you
randomly yell out Boomer you're going to
hear us sooner in return
how can you use that type of consistent
behavior in people for social
engineering pretenses
if I'm in an environment and I want to
misdirect someone or make their eyes
look somewhere else can I have a
colleague Yale Boomer knowing someone's
going to turn and go sooner and then
maybe I can sneak into a room or go
somewhere I'm not supposed to
um so you know think about uh you know
another consideration is what if you're
hiring an entry-level security analyst
what preconceptions would you have
against that person or towards that
person what if you're new hires in their
20s
what if your new hire is in their 60s
both could be fresh out of college
same level of Education
what type of inherent level of trust
would you have with each of those
different individuals
so again an effective trust we're
thinking about
emotion humans are naturally emotional
creatures effective trust is also Trust
of the heart it's empathy trusting in
someone's capacity for caring
um it's less of a science because
everyone has their own internal biases
what inspires me to believe someone
cares and I should trust them is totally
different from another individual but if
we think about these things and we
Implement methods to establish
effective trust it goes beyond a normal
relationship it builds a deeper bond
that leads to loyalty commitment
devotion people will go measures Beyond
out of the ordinary for people that they
believe
care about them and if you establish
that effective trust so if systems are
having you know there's more issues you
know does it really make people think
that you care more or less if you're not
maintaining their things properly in
their systems if you're able to maintain
and improve operations do they have a
better mindset are they more likely to
listen to you when you're pitching hey
we've really got to make this change for
security you're not just doing it
because you're capable it's no longer
you're doing it because it's technically
the right thing to do you're doing it
because you care you're bringing it up
because you care about the company and
The Business
um so why bother Trust
why bother with this at all and the
answer really is we can't help it uh
humans we are born physically premature
we are dependent upon our caretakers we
cannot take care of ourselves we are
hardwired to establish bonds and social
connections trusting one another to
fulfill our needs we're born to engage
with others and that's really what trust
is mostly about is how we engage with
people I'm an introvert so when I
started writing this talk and I wanted
to really focus on social engineering
I'm I had this thought and
I'm born to engage with others
am I really do I really want to engage
with a lot of people no I want to sit in
my own little space I want to write
reports I want to have minimal
interaction when I'm interviewing people
for risk assessments but really the
answer is yes I mean we want to engage
with other people and we might think
about introverts and texts and we don't
like to talk and we want to be in our
own little space but have you guys ever
been to Comic-Con or even events like
this
you get a little nerd that's sitting in
their sock watching logs all day and
somebody comes up and asks them about
their job their eyes light up and they
will not stop talking someone wants to
talk about how like agility converts
into crit chances and doing Theory
crafting I'm gonna geek out and talk all
day to you about that even though I'm an
introvert
um so even when people think that they
don't like people they're still that
intrinsic hard-wired need to connect and
engage with people
um so uh but you know what else can we
do with trust as adults and
professionals why bother you know what
do we really get back out of it and
here's you know a couple examples of
some things if you can quickly establish
trusts in an interview does it increase
the chances that you're going to get the
job offer they trust that you're capable
they trust that you care what are you
bringing to the table in the
organization can it increase Innovation
among your staff maybe your staff feel
more comfortable to speak up they trust
you that this is a safe space to bring
up new and different ideas and then also
completing role-specific tasks you know
getting clients to trust sales staff hey
I'm not just trying to upsell you I
really care about you you should trust
me I'm recommending things that are good
for you if you're doing social
engineering work if you're a social
operator if you establish trust is I can
help you get Recon data just from a
simple phone call
um you know figure out who your you know
your uh your spear phishing Target
should be and then also get executive
leadership of your projects if executive
leadership trust you they know that you
are capable and you care are they more
likely to support your projects
um so diving into effective trust
tactics or on the black hat side how to
manipulate effective trust to your own
advantage
we have verbal methods of how we can
establish effective trust my very
favorite thing on this is can you help
me
on the other end what that's going to do
is that's going to trigger so many
different things psychologically in that
person's mind because everyone's had a
bad experience calling customer support
I just want someone to help me stop
transferring me from person to person no
don't give me another 1-800 number to
call
can you help me
begin your conversation with that and
it's most people want to be helpful they
want to be that person yes I can help
you I would love to do that
um and maybe you get someone on a bad
day you're doing a social engineering
pretense you're viching away and you
don't get the right person on the phone
they're not going to fall for your
tactics hang up
call back again
um you know just keep doing it till you
get the right profile to fit your attack
um you know in my last talk
um I went into details of uh Uber being
attacked and being hacked in September
so the way that worked they they fished
for credentials when they got once they
fish for credentials they got stopped by
Duo once they were stopped by Duo
multi-factor authentication they did an
exhaustion attack on Duo they started
flooding everybody with Duo
notifications so people knew that
something was wrong they targeted one
person and they called them on the phone
hey this is Joe and I.T we are having
some issues with Duo today you probably
noticed
um to help us fix this we need you to
tell us what is the Dual authentication
code on your phone right now the person
gave them the authentication code they
were able to get into Uber systems from
that standard user account the attacker
saw was able to access a Powershell
script that wound up being related to
their Pam their account manager and
there were credentials hard-coded in
that script so within that script they
immediately had access to a service
account credential that had domain level
credentials they could get into the Pam
and give themselves access right to a
various amount of systems
um you know what are your plans for the
weekend or holiday maybe you're talking
to people in the office and that little
bit of a question begins to establish
hey I care about UNF that I want to know
what you're doing outside of work you
can also mirror communication Styles you
know what are people's uh body language
what is their Cadence or their style of
speaking you know telling an honest
story that provokes empathy sometimes on
the sales side of the house you know you
can establish that empathy with a client
and telling them a story like hey yeah
I've went through this maybe they're
going through a breach tell them a
similar War Story establish empathy I've
been in your shoes I know where you're
at and people feel that connection they
are more likely to be open and trust you
uh non-verbal um if anybody here has
gone through any type of interview
resume training you've probably heard
the value of a strong handshake uh
genuine Smiles uh versus like creepy
Smiles if you try to go into like a
social engineering pretent and you're
giving like or like a really weird smile
you're gonna come off as creepy if you
can't do a genuine smile on command just
don't try it know what works for you
maintaining eye contact if you make eye
contact with someone it shows that you
are genuinely interested in what they're
saying you're engaged you're paying
attention you're paying attention and
then sometimes something as casually as
leaning in when someone's speaking
you're naturally drawn to the things
that you're interested in and sometimes
that physical body movement portrays
these things that you may not think of
otherwise
um other things that you can do uh
handwritten notes uh thank you cards go
a long way send people a handwritten
thank you note for something that they
did
um I'm from the south and from the south
when we love people we feed them because
it makes you happy and content so bring
people snacks and treats you want to
start establishing trust with people and
show them that you care in your office
space bring them food
um take those moments to do you know
like positive affirmation statements and
you know maybe in the background of your
mind you're thinking oh my gosh you know
Chris nailed it on that project
tell Chris that you did amazing tell
them what you loved about their work and
what they did and another big thing that
really stands out for me personally is
owning your mistakes and apologizing
I've had guidance in the past from other
mentors about never apologize for doing
anything never say you're sorry own it
and just you know what you did what you
did you made that decision for some
reason and that particular scenario so
just roll with it don't apologize for
your actions and I have through my own
experience I disagree I'm a full
proponent of being candid and
recognizing situations internally where
maybe you could have done better and for
other people when they hear you say hey
yeah I'm really sorry about that I made
a mistake don't lead with excuses or
this was my intention start with an
apology then explain some of those
qualifying statements that other people
might need to understand how
you understand your actions and how you
care these are all things that will play
and a lot of these tactics and scenarios
are generally short-term tactics focused
on you know social engineering how can
you make that first impression if the
receptionist trusts me will she let me
bypass and then am I in the building am
I free reign am I unescorted what are
those visitor control policies that I
may be able to get them to not follow
because they trust me
um
so think about those things for
cognitive trust or how to manipulate
cognitive trust
um
being yourself verbally that really just
means being open about all your
capabilities
everyone hates the interview question
what's your greatest weakness
likewise everyone on the interview panel
hates hearing my weakness is also my
greatest strength I'm a perfectionist
we all have real strengths and
weaknesses do that little bit of
introspective research and think about
what are yours but being open and honest
or candid about your own capabilities
you can begin to set expectations of
consistency I'm capable and I'm
consistent that's how you get to
cognitive trust you know your teams
begin to understand how everyone comes
together one of the presenters earlier
was talking about different specialized
roles in security and how can we know
everything everyone has to have a
specialization and if I know you know
I've got five people on my team and if I
know each of their strengths we all know
how we can come together and compensate
for each other's weaknesses and make
each other better in the long run it
becomes a more productive and caring
conversation when you discuss shortfalls
at performance reviews maybe you're a
manager and you need to talk have those
hard conversations with your staff about
where they're failing in their
performance where they need to do better
and if you have this type of Converse
station and you be cognizant of your
tone of voice how you're inflicting
certain words or syllables it's going to
come across on how the recipient hears
your message
um
you know at work I've had an issue where
I'm very hopeful but I'm internally very
pessimistic
and when I talk about the need to fix
problems it comes across very
pessimistic that puts everyone else in a
pessimistic mindset coming to a meeting
and think about hey yeah we've got this
problem we have a security thing we need
to fix but how can we be optimistic
about it
hey if we do this it's only going to
take this amount of time this amount of
money whatever we need to do but we're
going to fix this problem be excited
because ultimately in the background of
your mind you're excited about fixing
the problem not that you have a problem
to solve
um so adjust your mindset and your
perspective and let your voice carry
over into
um you know focusing on being happy
about the solution and your recipients
are going to hear that too
non-verbal some of these are the same as
effective Trust again icon contact
dressing for the part
um like today I really wanted to dress
up Ultra Femme because I love how it
shocks especially a male-dominated
industry but practically it's cold
outside and yes thank you thermal shirt
but you know if I'm going to go to the
state capitol I'm going to be in formal
business attire I'm not going to show up
in you know jeans and a jacket and
cowboy boots which in Oklahoma cowboy
boots are acceptable formal attire I
don't know about Dakota but in Oklahoma
they are good posture and it reflects
confidence it really does
um and you know something as simple as
adjusting from standing like with your
feet really close together or going out
a little further and it's kind of called
like a superhero pose where you're
standing with your feet kind of shoulder
width apart you got your shoulders back
it conveys confidence your facial
expressions you know are I I love
playing poker but I do not have a good
poker face
so think about those things as you're
talking to people and you know carry
that dress for success mentality I
absolutely hate it but with your
audience it does make a huge impact
um you know I walked into Silicon Valley
in a suit you'd be laughed at you'd
never be taken seriously but you walk in
in a black hoodie and a pair of jeans
and some Converse then hey you're one of
us
um so it was kind of funny um
we went to Defcon and my husband decided
to tag along with me he's a history
major he is not Tech he's a wonderful
person he's great to talk to
um but he tagged along to an after party
and we were told to dress up so we did
and the only thing he brought with him
was like a really really nice suit
like over a thousand dollar suit it was
is super nice so we're at these After
parties and we're talking Tech and he's
like just drinking margaritas having
snacks and people kept coming up to talk
to him
because he was dressed in a suit at a
hackercon they thought he was the money
man they were getting him drinks and
chatting him up and it was like the most
hilarious thing ever he's like they keep
buying me drinks I'm gonna keep drinking
them and
um you know just history major Marine
love in Vegas uh so your appearance does
have an effect on people
um you know this little Tech wizard is
just sitting in the corner snacking on
some cheese and having a private
conversation
um another thing with dressing for the
part Goodwill is a treasure Trove for
social operators you go into Goodwill
you're gonna find an old Polo with a UPS
logo or a FedEx logo walk into a shop
put on those little brown khaki shorts
and a belt and have on a UPS shirt pack
an empty box and a clipboard
nine times out of ten you're gonna get
past the receptionist because they're
used to seeing delivery people coming
and going and you're gonna have free
reign of that building
and I mean you can do that with so many
different things
for establishing long-term Trust
the best advice I can give you with
cognitive trust is maintain your
integrity
think about consistency follow up with
people do what you said you would even
if it's insignificant maybe you casually
tell someone in the hall like I used to
have issues with my technicians all the
time they would be out on a call fixing
a problem and somebody would want to
stop them and hey can you fix my issue
right now well you really need to submit
a ticket and you tell them hey you know
I can't come see you right now I've got
something I've got to do but I'll email
you before the end of the day before you
know it the day gets away from you you
haven't sent that email yet you need
time to sit down and write that
meaningful thought out email that's okay
don't do that but send them a quick note
and say hey I'm sorry I told you I'd get
back to you by end of day things got
away from me I'll follow up with you
first thing tomorrow
maintain your integrity in every single
thing that you do
and that's really going to be the core
of being consistent
um I'm perpetually late fashionably late
I might say but beyond time if
something's really important especially
if you're working with a client or a
customer show up five minutes early or
at least be punctual that shows that you
not only respect your time you respect
their time if you see that you're on a
meeting and it was scheduled for 30
minutes and it's going long hey we got a
couple minutes in our meeting I want to
be respectful of everyone's time or did
people need to leave or do can you or is
it okay to stay on a little late
those are the types of things those
little things
um you know maybe going back to the
example where you made a mistake can you
candidly address your inconsistency
hey I normally 99 of the time I'm going
to be spot on every change every patch
that I push out is not going to break
things but then you push a passion oh my
gosh we gotta road to our rollback plan
can you own up to that mistake in your
environment Express what you did
Apologize showing that not only that you
care but you're addressing your
inconsistency which bleeds over into
your cognitive trust and then you take a
step further and you communicate what
are your plans to make sure that this
doesn't happen again and how we're going
to address it moving forward
re-establish your integrity as soon as
you lose it if you do lose it
re-establish it immediately
so some of these things have a more
Lasting Impression than others because
it carries over to both types of trust
but you know when you think about
reverse engineering what other people
need it's essentially empathy it's
putting yourself in someone else's shoes
but also taking it a little bit deeper
you know for the example about you know
sending the end of day email
if I didn't send someone an email that I
told them hey I'm going to email you by
end of day then I don't do it what are
they thinking
she doesn't respect me I'm not worth her
time
does she really value me or care about
me and how does that affect their
perception of me what if it was a CFO
and eventually I've got to go sscfo for
a budget is that going to affect my
budget allocations later on so you know
if your security projects are always
getting denied go back and analyze how
did you present your idea how did you
talk about this you know how can you
request or you know adjust your project
to instead of highlighting how it fills
the needs of you and your security team
how does it actually fulfill the needs
of the company
maybe I'm going to talk to the CFO first
before I talk to the CEO let's tell the
CFO hey if we fix the security impact it
reduces the likelihood of this exploit
which has this cost for data breach
here's the calculations on cost of
reputation and our business how can we
change that so ultimately we're
fulfilling our own goals but we're
manipulating someone else in a good or
bad way are we really manipulating them
or are we tailoring our message for the
audience it's kind of a fine line there
again white hat black hat you can use
this tons of different ways
um you know maybe you really understand
why vulnerability management is
important and it's a foundation of risk
management and a good security program
but leadership Tunes out every time you
talk Tech make it personal for them make
them Care by outlining
um how your goals also further theirs
how are our goals in alignment the
things I want to do is eventually going
to help you get somewhere else where you
want to be as lame as it sounds
sometimes look at your company's mission
statements if they've set strategic
goals for the organization shift your
presentation so you're aligning to the
organization's needs not your needs
um and we kind of went through this
really quickly but yay for helping
Dakota client get a little bit back on
track one of the things that I want to
leave you guys with is Maslow's
hierarchy of needs so if we go back and
think about why bother with trust
the answer is it Fields a need it's
human conditioning to connect with other
individuals and using these different
tactics and others to establish trust is
kind of like learning to ride a bike
you're not going to be good at it when
you first start out you're going to fall
a lot you're gonna get back on and then
your shoelaces are going to get caught
in your pedals and you're going to learn
hey I need to make sure my shoes are
tied before I go ride my bike you're
going to build these things in your
security environment you're going to
figure out you know weight distribution
and how you should do things how can you
pop a wheelie you're going to figure out
some specialized things
um and then you're going to learn so
it's the same thing here with
establishing trust with people you might
suck at it at first but keep going with
it you're not going to be a great pen
tester at first
start with can you crack a password on a
Microsoft Word document then take the
next step
um but you know maybe you're not always
the best at communicating your
capabilities but you can use some of
these tactics to make sure your
leadership knows and understands your
capabilities you know do you want to
request training if you can better
express your capabilities and your
progress that your teams have made could
you get a raise are you more likely to
get a promotion within the next year you
know if you start an internal security
awareness campaign
how do you help your end users to stop
thinking about you as the paranoid
security person
and seeing you as that trusted advisor
that really cares about them and the
company you know we're not just doing
security for the sake of it we're doing
it for a goal and because we care you
know and if they begin to believe that
you care you've established that
cognitive and effective trust with them
are they more likely to report things
they understand oh my gosh I misclicked
but they I need to report it and you
know the quicker you can respond to an
incident the more likely you are to have
a lower impact so if your staff care and
they understand that you care
they're going to be more open to
security they know that you're not just
doing things arbitrarily or it's not a
Power Trip you're doing it for a reason
um you know and how would it change the
dynamic of your team if your team trusts
you and they trust each other are you
going to have greater Innovation are
they going to feel free to like hey I'm
going to you know propose an idea maybe
we can automate some things through
scripting and I almost said I had some
database devs that went through and did
a data diagram
flows and they found a spot where they
could save themselves 15 minutes a week
big deal 15 minutes a week
do the math
15 minutes a week over a month over a
year
that's money for somebody's promotion
that's money for somebody's raise to
keep them safe and happy in their work
environment
um so there's lots of different Dynamics
to trust
um and again I hope you guys have at
least learned one thing new whether it's
black hat white hat different ways that
you could do it in Social operations in
sales or even in an executive level
and does anyone have any questions for
today
thoughts insights want to share
something new you learn something you're
really excited everybody's going to bum
rush the local Goodwill
all right y'all well you've been lovely
um I know it's time for lunch and
everyone's hungry and it's ready to get
a snack so I appreciate your attention
today I'll be hanging out at least for a
little bit uh so if you want to find me
have a conversation I'd be glad to have
a chat or if you want a card
um hit me up on LinkedIn dma um be glad
to answer all your questions or
at least tell you I don't know the
answer but we can find out together
[Applause]
awesome thank you so much Carrie so
we're going to be resuming with the
sessions in here at 1pm and that's going
to be with Aaron Baker talking about his
Custom Tool but until then we'll take a
10 minute break until 1 pm
all right we're going to go ahead and
get started today's presentation is
going to be about to you by Aaron Baker
and he's going to be presenting his tool
on nightcap Aaron has presented at black
hat this past summer and has been
working on a ton of different cool
security related projects he's done so
many things like research malware he
does so many things I don't even know
about so I'm excited for him to teach
you guys all about his new tool that he
developed so take it away
hey thank you thank you so much
um thanks everybody for showing up but
yeah so this is a tool that I've been
working on kind of off and on for a few
years now
kind of going at a slow with school and
work and everything like that but um
yeah the tool is called nightcap so
about me I'm from Wyoming my background
is in a mobile application development
and large-scale automation I'm going to
be graduating this semester with my
bachelor's in cyber operations as Annie
was saying I presented it black hat this
last summer I wrote a tool called
subparse does large-scale automation of
malware analysis which was really really
fun so malware research I do pen testing
and part of the CCD Club
so this tool is kind of a general
purpose red blue purple team utility
belt it allows for the automation of
installing as well as the setup in the
environment
for tools that have reporting and don't
have reporting it will automatically
allow them to now have reporting so kind
of kind of fun
shareable installation packages so say
you're working on a team or you have
different companies throughout
you know the states or whatever you can
basically give them the same Essence as
like an executable and install it into
the framework
um
the name so when I initially was
starting to build this I was at the ru
internship here at Dakota State and
built a tool called bust a pcap for
Network traffic and then The nightcap
always reminded me of like this is all
owl with the top
um some features of the tool it allows
for backup and restoration of your whole
environment this way then if you're like
transferring to a different PC or if you
have a team of employees you can
basically copy it one for one across uh
each each platform it is platform
independent most of the back end is
inside of Docker
which allows for the team
collaboration
Auto report generation it has a command
line and a website of it and yeah the
nice thing about the tool is it helps
remember all your arguments so you never
have to go look at you know the GitHub
or the Man pages again to to actually go
remember them you're able to set
defaults and stuff like that when you're
running the tools well
uh customer customizable you can do two
different forms of installation packages
so you can have remote
server that would actually be hosting
all of the code that would be then
installed onto the systems or you can
actually have like a full-blown
executable where all the code is
directly packaged inside pros and cons
to both you get more virgin control if
it if it's you know all inside of the
executable but a smaller package if it's
if it's remote
uh the reporting 10 points are all
customizable as well so you can
basically place the data
you know anywhere you want it to and all
the reports are going to be generated on
the website of it
um and there'll be exports at some point
just haven't haven't quite got there on
that
all right
so different use cases
um honestly the the sky's kind of the
limit I know that everybody has their
own tool sets that they run all the time
different languages
and it's kind of nice to be able to have
everything clustered in one spot so you
can customize this tool belt to your
specific needs whether it be pen testing
you know blue teamwork if you do
research or forensics type stuff I know
for a little while I had a tool that was
installed in here that would just unpack
different binaries for me instead I have
to do the manual process every single
time just pass it to file and it was off
all right so do a little bit of a demo
we'll see how it goes
um yeah
pretty small
is that better for you guys
good good okay
all right so
get some of this other back end stuff's
pulled up real fast
all right so it is a python package
um right now we're just going to be
running on the Local Host I don't want
to be running a Docker on my system
right now but it does allow for the
installation uh inside of Docker or on
localhost if you are doing an inside
Docker it will set up the environment to
allow for multi-language support right
out of the box so right now you can
support every single version of python
and golang and and that automatically
gets installed I am going to be allowing
it to support rust and Ruby as well and
then try and do like playing Powershell
some different Oddball stuff
so
um
so we get this
a little welcome page
um this I know it says Docker instance I
modified the config a little to to make
it work for this but uh um this is going
to be reaching out to my actual server
um it is using the docker Daemon
um which if you guys do much with Docker
you can not run on your system but be
able to connect to the docker Daemon on
your system to have a go to a remote
host
so it does have a instance there I
do use a Ubuntu container that's what uh
if you didn't want it on your localhost
that you'd be using so just go ahead and
connect
arbitrary banner and stuff like that you
know gotta gotta make it look like
Metasploit
and that's kind of a little bit of what
I modeled this tool off of was the way
the Metasploit does stuff then again
it's Ruby python you know there's that
fight
um right off the bat has help menu we
don't have anything
currently installed so we have no
modules so we should probably just go do
that so go into settings
um there's different database options
right so if you were to
um be working for like company X as a
like consultant and you're gonna go to a
company Y and they had this this program
you just have to go in and change the
database
and you'll be able to pull the installs
from from the remote stuff and be able
to instantly have a set set back up for
the other company
basically to make it as modular as
possible
um I know with a lot of tools I've wrote
modular modularity was a huge deal so
with this tried to do the same
all right
so inside of here we can list the
installs uninstall and as well as update
I know that updating is a huge deal
especially with like custom tools right
I mean you got to go find that exact
folder you got to then repo from git or
go through their their custom way of
doing it so basically this is would be a
little wrapper to then go through all of
the tools that you have and then
automatically update them for you help
save save time and just kind of
streamlines everything
so
where's the filter
all right so we'll just install
real fast
sorry
I fingering stuff
so it's going to go ahead and just
install the package uh automatically
crease new environment installs
everything that's needed for that
environment this allows to or this helps
support version Independence so you can
have the exact same tool with
conflicting packages in the back end and
then it'll automatically run your tool
against that environment it does that
for all the python versions as well as
golang
which is kind of Handy you know with my
background side of Dev work it was
always a pain when you had conflicting
packages I mean it can cause all the
problems and a lot of wasted time
all right so if we go ahead and just
list this out
um it's able to show you know the author
you got the details and then the path
um just like metasployed is going to be
what you use to to go ahead and like
execute uh that specific one so we'll
just go ahead and exit
and does allow for tab completion and
then you can go as deep as you need to
and then it tries to do path correction
as well
which can kind of come in handy
all right so with the options I just
like metisplay you know it has the
preset like variables
this this allows uh or this makes it
easier so you never forget what the
package actually needs to run
um it will air out if uh you know if
you're missing one it does have like the
required right there for the domain the
required you can have multiple versions
or multiple instances of it which
definitely helps for the end user if
it's a brand new package that you have
and they're not used to it to basically
you know enforce it
um so there's default and then there's
set for the two different options uh two
different ways that you can
basically set a variable on the package
default will allow it to set it inside
of the database so that when you exit
and come back to it that it'll still be
there set would be for like a one-off
instance where you just need to change
something say verbose City or something
on a tool and you don't want that to
continue on
so just say default
anybody have a domain that they want me
to use
now I'll do these Google
all right so let's go ahead and run it I
don't have a
a project setup so it won't pull any of
the reporting so we'll just go ahead and
say say no so it did cancel the
execution
so this is the project side we can say
projects
so you have select create and you know
destroy let's say create
let's see
um you can always check the config 2 at
pretty much any point inside of the tool
this will show you know the verbo City
whatever database you're connected to so
I have like three or four different
instances that I'll roll back and
forth between two uh for these
um sometimes you can get a little
confusing the project side of it
um so say that you're doing like pen
testing or something like that it's
great to be able to break all the
reports Down based off of each client so
kind of following that that whole
methodology
so just go ahead and run this tool
and
oh it should be good
so basically we're able to see the tool
actually running all of the uh
information itself is going to be
displayed on the screen but then we'll
be able to capture basically a copy of
it
um
hopefully this also works
um here trying another tool real fast I
apologize
do
so the package name for this it does say
old
um
so inside of the config files which I
can show you guys a little bit later uh
you're able to specify a commit ID
um that way if you are part of a Dev
team or whatnot you can go to specific
instances like of those tools if you do
uh update
um
it will go to the newest version of that
tool
um just always
great so this is going to run it as you
see it's very quick I mean this is just
DNS information and then it does
automatically pull it before we go and
look at some of the uh web stuff
um
show you guys a few nice things as far
as like if you were to go to a different
environment being able to instantly go
get all of your tools back reinstalled
all the environments set up for you
without having to manually do it so
we'll just go into settings
so inside of the system there's a backup
option
so with the the backups so you can
backup and restore
I did have one earlier today that I was
going to use for the con but basically
you just say backup and then you'll just
pass it
the
system path that you want it to go and
there we go it backed up everything as
far as the installers and you get a
if you guys can see that
not really but um basically the file
extension that I have for that is NCB
which would be a nightcap backup then
this system actually will generate NCP
files which would be the package
installation files
team if we uh go here actions
um we'll just go ahead and
uninstall all these
so now what we can do is resort to the
previous state that we had
now we'll go ahead and go through each
one of the packages that we had and
reset up all the environments that we
don't have to
um I know that like with me I was going
back and forth between like different
Linux distributions all the time or
Windows to Mac and you know not my
desktop or you know somebody else's or
somebody's Cloud right
which uh you know getting all the tools
back sometimes there's you know
conflicts with even just the the service
or system that you're you're currently
running
all right so the reinstalled
um
so yeah
all right let's hop over
[Music]
um
to the website of everything
all right so uh off of the dashboard
all right so right off the dashboard
um you have like the project listing
itself you're able to delete it or say
you wanted to use the web UI we'll say
like you know test
and then if we go back
um
back in here
automatically updates which is kind of
Handy but we can look at the reports
that are actually being generated
um
and there we go so like DNS Recon does
not natively support any form of uh
report generation or anything like that
besides you know putting it in a text
file and depending on what you're doing
it's really painful to go through you
know hundreds of text files to like
actually look for something off of the
subparse tool that I wrote we were able
to like pivot off a data so that's
something that I plan on introducing to
this tool would be like you know you
have this table
say you want to look for like this value
throughout all the reports for that
company be able to Pivot and kind of dig
deeper into the information you found
um
see
um it does
support
um tasking so with the tasking say that
you have like six programs that you run
like back to back to back and that's
always like your flow you'll be able to
basically set up a task it is broken
right now but you are you can set up a
task to make it so it will auto fire and
do that whole chain of events for you
that way you know you're saving time in
our industry you know time is money
um so we'll just disc Arrow fast
there is one other
um
package that I'd like to show you guys
so this is also DNS Recon the exact same
same tool we just ran except this has a
alternate report so we can see the
differences between those
right so now this ran we'll just go
ahead and refresh this go back into here
um so they're just kind of daisy chain
you know time stamped so this was the
previous report this was all on the
table but say that you want them broke
down by different types right so now you
can see that hey here's all the a
records or you know MX records or text
records
which basically allows anybody who's
developing their own packages for it to
completely customize what they want the
view to look like instead of being
conformed to that specific
template the templates themselves are
all 100
dynamically generated and that's based
off of the Json that is used to develop
the package itself
um inside of the settings for this
um you know dark mode and the ungodly
white I don't understand I'm sorry I
just had to Blind you you know
dark mode should just be default for
everybody
um so inside the packages you can get
some more uh more information about
um
the the package itself the language that
it uses
um the uh you know author you can
uninstall directly from the web UI as
well so say that you are
uh somebody who who prefers web over CLI
you will be able to basically use the
whole thing from here there's a few
things I got to wrap up on that before
it's completed
to forgot to install the go Lane package
so let's go and do that real fast
um
so right now I just have one anybody use
asset finder
by Tom nom nom
okay
um Susan as you can see right here it
does check for the support of the
language and then this one does require
the 1.18
um
I'll just run this real fast for you
guys just to
prove that we got multi-language
there we go asset finder is great for
those of you who aren't familiar with it
say that you give it like a company name
or domain or something like that you're
able to find a lot of URLs that could
potentially lead to other points of
failure or other things for you know if
you're a Bug Hunter to to go ahead and
test
definitely recommend checking it out
also for companies it's great to see
what information you can find on your
own company that other people could
potentially uh you know use against you
or or break
um and there we go so yeah we got the
the go
which I mean if I was to do this
manually installing each one of those
make sure all the dependencies were set
up on top of getting the virtual
environment set up it definitely
wouldn't be that quick on top of like
then turning around and running it so
basically the whole goal of this program
is to help with speed I mean there's no
point on spending
half your day setting up tools to turn
around and run them for what a second
two seconds to find a bunch of data
um
so
inside of the settings and then the
packages
I'm allowing for the creation of the
install packages through the through the
web UI
so we have the the author information
we have GitHub and then this is the code
side which the code side will require a
lot more you know you got to give it an
entry file you gotta specify you know
where is everything on a go but as far
as the GitHub
it's quite easy you know basically just
give us your dot get URL
inside of the the programming language
information these are the two languages
that are supported right now
if we go look at python
we got all the different versions so
traditional python if we go down and
look here you know we got iron grass uh
Anaconda
um
moving out C python down here somewhere
but uh yeah so uh basically
making sure that regardless of your
underlying needs uh that the program be
able to at least helps set it all up
um not saying that there isn't going to
be
um issues with some packages depending
on like what their specific requirements
are but this uh at least do its best
and then
basically just be able to download it
right here it'll actually send a query
out to our server and then generate that
package and then just download as it
basically a zip for you guys then your
your executables already to go
oh
this is currently not set up but you
will be able to install directly from
the web as well
ended up throwing some of the stuff on
the site together relatively quickly
this last week
that went a little bit quicker than what
I was thinking but uh but yeah uh I
guess does anybody have any questions or
any packages they might like to see at
some point
not without a different
file so uh it's a good point I'll show
you this
Okay so
inside of here so this is the one for
the asset Finder right so for the
goaling
this is the Json that all gets broken
down so you have the the language
the GitHub
and then you have a report design
you also have this which is for report
filters right so say that you're looking
for very very specific stuff just like
that DNS Recon one how it was all broke
down
um
like this right so we have like names or
grouped regex that you'd be able to use
on that
um but this this design is how
everything's going to look so as it
stands right now you wouldn't be able to
roll back and forth between two
different report like templates but that
is something I I do want to add
so this would just be for the
traditional standard report and that's
going to be
what this guy looks like where you just
have a table and everything's broken
down
versus that alternate one
where you have like the very long regex
expressions
and then your styling like the report
the report data and then everything's
broken into sections right so right here
we have different components these
components
you'll be able to stylize all the way
down so this is how we get through with
the auto report and generation pulling
it from here so you have the components
so this one would be a table and then
inside of this table we're going to say
all of our data and then everything's
broken down for the header and then the
cells so it's very customizable
um and it will have heavy documentation
on this for for like all the Json but
it's be easier to implement on the
website of everything
um
and yeah then you can you can always
change the layout too so say you have
you know 19 20 different tables or
something like that you'll be able to
move the tables up and down inside the
the report template
um at some in the future it will all be
able to be modified from the web though
um
yeah I know that was uh quite quick but
um kind of a interesting Tool uh I don't
present the most I'm usually
behind on the keyboard so hopefully you
guys like it if you guys are interested
in the project or or want to to use it
it will be up on GitHub I do we'll put
it back on this guy I do have the
GitHub link and everything kind of ready
for you guys
um
so if you guys want to follow on there
or whatnot I got the subparse program
and lots of other fun little tools
so some of the other stuff that that
will be coming is finishing up the
tasking we're going to add like Sox 4
and Sox five I know like with all the
malware research that I was doing
um being able to Tunnel everything and
run it through Tor
um definitely helped so depending on use
cases and stuff
um
some improvements to the Web different
languages that we're also going to
support if you guys ever have like some
Oddball language that you want more
support for I'd definitely be willing to
do it there's my GitHub and my Twitter I
don't do a lot on Twitter but yeah
um
so hopefully hopefully you guys like it
find it useful at some point or what
thank you
[Applause]
awesome thank you Aaron so he's going to
be sticking around a little bit so if
you have any questions feel free to head
on over to him and ask him questions
otherwise we'll have our next talk at
2PM when it's where Charlene Goldfield
is going to be giving us a presentation
on cyber security law and regulations
surrounding that so we'll break until
2PM
so that was really interesting but yes
as Annabelle mentioned I work for DHS
um I wasn't working at DHS all the time
before that I was working at the Federal
Communications Commission I worked at
Department of Justice so I had like a
couple of like experiences in different
agencies so um it's kind of great to be
here because you get the break from the
bureaucracy of DC
um and uh the uh nonsense sometimes that
happens I can say that I'm in my
personal capacity but at the same time
it's really great to be in that area in
that space because you get to be in the
conversations and actually bring in some
common sense at times especially in this
space and I know that I am speaking to
many of you that are mostly
technologists or actually experiencing
the things that we try to dictate in
policy so I tried to make this
presentation as broad as possible but
again I don't consider myself an expert
in the things that you do I am an expert
in the law side of things and I learned
things from those like you and your
positions that tell me how it works and
I learn things along the way so one of
the great things about being in this
space is that I've been able to like
teach myself stuff and actually take
other classes and supplement my learning
under my ethical duties as an attorney
which is kind of cool versus when you go
to law school and you just do some like
property or something like that it's
like you get what you get and that's
about it right so that's the cool thing
about what I do and I also get to work
with really cool people in the policy
space that have been in your positions
or have worked in technology companies
or done things on that side and they
actually get to also bring in the policy
side and bring in more common sense and
be like this isn't going to work on
paper for those that are doing this on a
day-to-day basis
so
one thing
I wanted to go ahead kind of give a
little glimpse of my background and why
I think you know law and policy is so
important here let me I think that it'd
be worth
like this so I have worked in the
federal government space for like six
years now as a lawyer and before that I
worked in like local government back at
home in Miami Florida and I did some
stuff here and there in the policy side
and so I think that it's so important to
kind of understand the basics of what
the lawyers and the policy people are
thinking about in the room on this side
because you all bring the experience and
understanding where they're coming from
too and how it all works on that side
with the law and policy will help make
your jobs a lot easier depending on what
you do right so that is why I wanted to
bring in this presentation and of course
feel free to jump in if you have any
questions along the way or if there's
things that maybe I didn't bring up that
are crucial to understand and that way
you know we can have a conversation if
you have anything further we can discuss
about it right so one thing before I
forget is that I have to say that I am
in my personal capacity and I am not
expressing the opinions of DHS or any of
the federal government I have to give
that quote so
um ethical things there so
um really quickly when we talk about
like Cyber Law and policy although we
always had the uh deterrence model where
I guess the security angle of things
back when the you know the technology
era started or computer and the internet
we had like the antivirus software
that's about it right and then slowly
things progressed here and there
historically however as a result of 9 11
and the creation of DHS right we started
thinking about how our adversaries and
National Security play a part in
technology and in the you know terrorism
space we saw how terrorists or foreign
adversaries or however you want to
Define them utilize technology
to recruit their individuals to provide
disinformation to just you know spread
awareness of the things that they do for
their positions right because terrorism
is a domestic political International
movement right so we saw how that on
that space is utilized for technology
but then there's another side to it
right there's the Cyber side there is
the hacking side all those things that
we discussed and I know that the
commander this morning spoke a little
bit about those things those are the
things that I try to focus on as well
but it's all like interconnected right
so that is why I wanted to raise some
hypotheticals on the Cyber side of
course this isn't everything that
happens every day
but even though these might sound kind
of a little funky they can happen right
or at least they're issues that can come
up so
the first thing is thinking about if
you're responsible for purchasing
certain telecommunications or networking
equipment right and if you're thinking
about buying that if you're an
information security officer a ciso
somebody who's responsible for buying
this equipment right for building your
networks you have to think about the
fact that if you're using a foreign
company right because they're probably
going to come in at the bid that's
cheaper
or they're gonna try to persuade you to
think hey my equipment is so much better
you know we can work hand in hand better
you have to think about who that foreign
company is and what they're trying to
provide you and if it's something that
could affect U.S competition because
that's one of the things it could affect
U.S risk or national security risk and
is it banned because we have equipment
that's banned right or at least
quote unquote on a naughty list is what
we call it during the fcc's policy
the second hypothetical is looking at
whether you are um a ciso right and
you've been locked out of a computer you
get a call saying I've been locked on a
computer
there's something weird happening I
can't access anything there's like a
weird little Gremlin thing happening
right
what do you do right do I have to report
this should I report this like what's
going on how do I save the data can I
pay that Ransom if they're asking for
Bitcoin if they're asking for money
right all those things are things you
have to think about because they're
obligations legally policy wise and just
for your position and your safety and
we'll talk about what that means in a
little bit
and then third you are a ciso who is in
charge of systems for a company right
you are made aware of a data breach but
are told by the c-suite to make sure
this goes away that also goes to the
second hypothetical can you make it go
away like that quote unquote right
absolutely not don't do that please
um but we'll talk about what that means
and like why we say that and why we urge
you not to do that for purposes of
shareholders if you're a public company
let's say yeah those type of things
so
um why do we care about law and policy
in cyber right these are some of the
four basic things that come up and I
think someone mentioned this morning
Tick Tock right the CEO went to Congress
I can talk about them in my personal
capacity right
um
um they uh had the CEO for tick tock on
the U.S foreign relations side come and
testify in front of Congress to ask him
a bunch of questions about you know how
is it unsecure should we make you sell
can you even do that can the US
government make you sell yes we can we
can make you sell
um but
um regardless these are the four things
that we always sort of
getting conversation with regards to
technology and cyber and policy we're
worried about this space because of
national and domestic security we have
deep fakes we have hacks we have
ransomware we have foreign adversaries
we have all those things to think about
and that's why Us in the law and policy
space are like hey we have to take care
of all that's happening because it's
happening in real time all the time
every day right
we have economic purposes so yes we do
worry about National Security
we worry about our homeland we worry
about critical infrastructures but we
also want to make sure that we are
competing right this is a global economy
we want to make sure it's fair that all
companies compete fairly on our end and
that we're also making sure that our
talent is here right and that we take
care of our talent and then also that
we're not just letting companies export
freely in a bad way right because that
can happen or that we are making sure
that we can compete fairly in the US and
that our economic interests are being
protected that our IPS not being stolen
or intellectual property and things like
that so that's why we always talk about
in cyber uh policy and law with regards
to economic purposes
then we have industry balance we want to
make sure that we create a fair and
stable system so we're not having
companies underpin other individuals or
other companies foreign companies
underpin U.S companies
and then also that we're making sure
that the companies that we're working
with are creating good standards right
like because as you saw or you know as
we talk about these things a lot of our
technology space is unregulated right
and so depending on what side you're on
maybe you think hey we shouldn't
regulate that's another discussion right
but regardless in an unregulated space
we make sure that those companies you
know responsibly act right like they
take care of their their people and they
take care of what they're doing
especially if they're holders of big
data and then at the same time that
they're creating these standards among
themselves in a community right
so one example of just this one because
I was reading an article about AI
AI is expensive AI has a lot of data to
build like chat GPT open Ai and all
these other ones the biggest investors
are Amazon Google meta
Etc right like the biggest top companies
but what about smaller companies how are
we going to be able to help them compete
in this space because if AI is going to
take over right or at least not take
over but you know be part of the system
right which is great I think that AI is
great I've used tragic BT it's awesome
right for teaching my classes sometimes
so but if we want to make sure that we
are creating a balance right we don't
want to just have the biggest companies
at the top controlling everything or at
least that's what the article is arguing
how do we make it fair for everyone to
compete in this space especially if it's
the next revolution of Technology right
so that's another Conversation Piece
there
so yeah so
um one of the things that I really
wanted to you know if you you know
listen here and you're like I don't care
about law I don't care about posi I'm
just here because I want to hear like
the main gist of anything is this
that cyber security is no longer just
about information technologists in one
group the people here on the other group
et cetera et cetera we're all coming
together and I hope that's the point of
this conversation because I want to
learn from you just as much as you
probably want to learn from me because
lawyers are here to protect people from
bad things right or at least that's what
I you know my my oath was like I don't
know about other attorneys and usually
as the only attorney in the room
sometimes people are like oh God damn
attorney great but you know that's not
the point of at least our goals in this
space well that with us attorneys and
what we do we try to make sure that we
are here for our client and that we can
protect them at the same time let them
do what they want to do
in a great like in a scale of things and
a balance right and making sure that it
doesn't violate anything and go against
the Spectrum so this quote right here is
really interesting because you have
someone from University of Maryland a
program director he actually runs their
uh JD side of things or law school side
of cyber as well as the master's program
side of things and he talks about how
it's so important to make sure that you
teach both sides of this space
and then you also have the national
cyber strategy that just came out by
President Biden and I mean that's just
basically policy it's not like law or
anything
and that strategy is also actually
important because you know people in the
space always look for that strategy like
what's the executive government looking
at and what is Congress being urged to
look at right and one of the things that
came out from that report is looking at
what government's role is in this space
and basically it's the protected systems
ensure private entities are you know
particularly critical infrastructures
being protected and that you know that
we carry out the core governmental
functions such as engaging in diplomacy
collecting intelligence imposing
economic costs enforcing the law Etc
right that's a lot for Cyber Law and
policy that maybe years ago people be
like why why is this about investment
right but now it is right and I think
it's just as valuable as making sure we
protect National Security risks
so one of the other things that I think
I've sort of implied is that we don't
want to create these separate little
entities or groups because we have
lawyers that look at this of what you do
like this right like lawyers think that
that's exactly what you do every day in
this space if they're not Cyber Law
policy individuals right and they're
like what explain to me this in layman's
terms right and that's why I have this
little picture here I don't know if you
can read it which the shirt that says a
threat actor equals someone who wants to
punch me in the face right like
explaining things in layman's terms for
people because us lawyers also probably
speak to you and you're like this right
you're like what is happening like
you're telling me all these things like
Fourth Amendment protections of privacy
and security and you needed a warrant
and you need this and you need that and
you know and you're like what is
happening I'm not getting arrested am I
like what's happening so that is why
again I want to emphasize that my
conversation here my presentation is
mostly to make sure that we can all come
together and discuss what's going on
every day right in your spaces and in my
spaces right
so a little bit about the timeline of
Law and policy right I talked a little
bit about 9 11 right and how it kind of
shifted things in how we think about
National Security overall right and then
how we thought about technology but then
we kind of saw a little bit more about
Cyber Law and policy being implemented
or discussed in the executive branch in
Congress and in States right because now
right now you're seeing a lot of States
doing their own thing with privacy with
cyber protection with cyber information
sharing and so you're like how do I get
control of all this information like if
I'm working somewhere in like Florida or
Illinois or wherever I also have to
worry about what they're monitoring what
they're telling me to do for my company
or wherever you might work at
so first of all we had President Obama's
efforts and regarding this space right
one of the biggest things in his space
or in his I guess presidential term was
looking at information sharing right uh
Congress and you know executive went
back and forth as to whose obligation it
is to you know share information should
we require companies to share
information when you have data breaches
um are we violating certain violations
or privacy violations of companies are
requested to share information and then
they're like looking into their systems
and then probably looking into you know
people's records things like that and so
from that conversation back and forth it
resulted in the um cyber information
sharing Act of 2015 which basically says
Hey companies if you share your data
breaches with us right then we will
protect you in some way by making sure
that you don't get in trouble if you're
monitoring and Defending Your systems in
some way right like if you are looking
into records you're not going to break
any privacy issues you're not going to
break any Fourth Amendment issues ETC et
cetera right and then exchange you're
helping us the government report these
data breaches and helping you in
response and we don't know what's going
on right so that's one thing it doesn't
make it obligatory it doesn't make it
mandatory in any way shape or form it's
more of a mutual relationship right and
then on top of that we saw him or
President Obama talking a lot about
implementing legislative proposals
reports on Cyber focusing on
um you know diversity in the cyber
security although mentioned like in a
little sentence and cyber crime right
making sure that we are also monitoring
that side of things
um then uh you saw the nist and nist is
the National Institute of science and
technology or standard in technology and
it's its own sub-agency and they have
great Frameworks by the way right and so
they created their first framework 1.0
for small businesses for companies and
for you know all types of entities that
have some cyber capabilities in them
right so they created this first
framework to guide entities on making
sure that they're protecting their
systems and they're always building up
on it so I always put this one in here
because it's really important you had a
sub-agency in the federal government
making sure that they're providing and
pumping out resources to these companies
way before cisa or the cisa sub-agency
was created right before cisa and that
way that you're able to inform companies
and you're able to inform small
companies and you're providing all these
great little checklists
then you had Trump's presidential
um Arrow right and a lot of his
initiatives not only created sisa
actually it was ciso was long talks and
eventually it got passed in law and then
it was created under the DHS
sub-agencies
but then also you had a lot of bands
right you had um technology bands you
had Tick Tock being wanting to be banned
you had WeChat at the time which now I
don't think WeChat really is as popular
we had that talk and so that's where in
his presidential you know timeline he
was talking a lot about banning these
Technologies and that's where we start
seeing a lot of these discussions like
we're seeing now with tick tock
and then we had the creation of sisa
which is
um this sub-agency in DHS that really is
helpful in making sure that they're
projecting our critical infrastructures
right what do I mean by that I have a
slide on that but clearly it's just
basically our electrical grids our gas
companies all the companies that have to
do with our critical infrastructures of
making sure everyday lives of of U.S
citizens and U.S people are not affected
by cyber breaches or any cyber related
incidents right
so sis is there to help protect them and
to help coordinate with them and provide
them resources
then I put in cyber Solarium commission
and they're actually an entity that was
created
um by Congress as well and they're there
to provide this group of individuals
that are private leaders
um uh federal government leaders as well
and they talk about what's next for
cyber and how do we make sure that we
protect our cyber systems and one of the
things that came up from that is making
sure that we look at it from a military
civilian coordination right because
there's a lot of military leaders in
that group and so they were focusing on
deterrence and so when they've released
their first report they talked a lot
about deterrence how does that look like
and now they're building their second
report and so that was a really
interesting Commission because a lot of
people got good stuff from that report
and they saw that there was a
composition of very different leaders
across the board private and public that
were helping to create you know this
policy in itself
and then lastly we have President Biden
right now and we've seen the strategy I
just talked about and a lot of his
initiatives which is focusing a lot on
expanding information sharing but then
also critical infrastructure and he did
release his executive order which is
looking at improving Nations cyber
security and that came out like a year
ago I think or less than a year ago and
in that cyber security executive order
that's mostly like sort of law if you
think about it because it's his way of
issuing some law in some way
um it looked a lot at zero trust
implementation and making sure that we
are building up on that information
sharing and working with companies and
private part Public Partnerships
great so then I wanted to briefly talk
about the national cyber security
strategy because I think that it's not
only been a long time coming but I think
that it focuses a lot on diversity legal
responsibility resilience and ransomware
protection
um so one of the core things is making
sure that we're closing the loophole on
regulating certain aspects of our
critical sectors so making sure that our
electrical grids and all those that
compose of those companies are regulated
correctly or at least have been
addressing the gaps in those regulations
for cyber security looking at elections
and our election Frameworks Etc they
also Focus there on legal responsibility
and I wanted to highlight that because
in that strategy they want to focus on
Shifting the liability from um from
Everyday People right because in the
report it talks about how whenever
there's a data breach or some kind of
major cyber incident a lot of the costs
goes to Everyday citizens like people
consumers people that buy these
equipment Etc and so instead of making
sure that they don't you know everyday
people don't have to have the burden on
themselves they want to shift legal
responsibility on these companies or
what they call the data Brokers or those
that manage big data right like those
that are responsible for everyday Big
Data of their um of their company
so that's something that I wanted to
highlight and then of course
um resiliency is always important but it
focused a lot on that and their
discussions on making sure that
um you know there's loopholes being
closed there too
um but then you know that there's ways
of countering threat actors and that
systems that are affected in some way
can recover quickly and and then
incentivize as well those individuals
and entities that have strong systems
currently in some way shape or form
so those are things to look at I think
it's really interesting strategy and
really important because it kind of
shapes the landscape of policy and law
in this space
so this so what right like why why is
this important why is this discussion
why are focusing on all these different
laws and policies and things like that
important right and that is because lots
of legislation comes out from different
states and from the federal government
you know in 2022 you had 40 states that
introduced 250 bills in this space right
and only 24 were enacted but out of
those 24 things can get really confusing
right in the 117 Congress which has
passed right now it ended like mid
January I think there were 498 bills
related to cyber security that were
introduced only 13 passed but most came
from executive orders so most of the
action in the space was coming from
President Biden's executive orders so
but even with those 12 again things get
complicated things get dicey and that's
why you sometimes have the low lawyers
in the room when it comes to the space
that you may be in to understand and
help interpret what's going on in this
space
and then also because we have to
consider all the new and improved
technology that's coming from out there
and um you might think oh well you know
we've been talking about AI for a long
time we've been talking about Cloud
technology for a long time
et cetera et cetera but in this space
there's new things that come up every
single day for example like I mentioned
in the first hypothetical and I think I
could talk about this
um there is the ban of starting
equipment right like certain companies
are a No-No and that's public right it's
public for everyone to see under the
fcc's website
but those equipment sometimes can come
through in some other way right they can
be sold through another procedure and
you may not know or they may be
incorporated into another equipment and
you may not know that it's being
Incorporated within the major equipment
itself that's a new issue no one thought
about that right you're like what do you
mean you didn't think about that how
does people want to think about that so
what happens now right like what do I do
how do you address this issue and so
that's where Avi um people in the room
in this space come and talk together and
see it figure out what's legally allowed
to be done and what do we do on a policy
level as well right so those type of
things happen every day in this space
but then you also have like new things
that are happening like chat gbt again
lots of conversations about that the
risk that can happen from that
Biometrics the government collects a lot
of biometric data but other companies do
too and there have been a lot of states
banning Ai and banning the use of
Biometrics right like I think there was
one article talking about concert venues
hockey games those types of
entertainment venues collecting
biometric data and how the government
wants to consider like not allowing
companies to do that right or you know
Banning sort of this biometric
collection of data because they think it
violates privacy
then you have the metaverse right I mean
people are like oh well what's the
metaverse I mean it's really new and you
know there's lots of things here and
there it's very fickly right but at the
same time there's a lot of issues that
can come from that and you'll again the
same conversation you have meta and you
have all the major companies at the top
trying to get into this space and sort
of monopolize in this space so what
happens when they do that and what
happens when it expands more what are
the issues there so we have to think
about those type of things too
and The Internet of Things even though
that's always been around for a while
right at the same time you still have
issues happening in that space the
vulnerability of those equipment but the
everyday use of that equipment from
people right my fit you know my Apple
watch the Fitbit Etc like all those
things are still in talks and still
discussed in this policy legal landscape
so I wanted to quickly focus on critical
infrastructure right you're like what
does that mean and for those who do know
what that means I apologize but just
really wanted to focus on that
um here you have only like the 10 or so
that I that I usually come across a lot
within DHS but there's like 16 in total
that cisa and DHS are supposed to be
protecting right each of these sectors
are so important in cyber and some
people are like well what does the
energy well not necessary energy but
let's say water right what does water
have to do with this right a lot there
was one hack in Florida that happened or
at least attempted to happen and it
could have caused a lot of damage right
um it could have depending on who that
hacker was if it's a foreign adversary
they can put some you know figure out a
way to get into that system and do
something bad and affect many citizens
right
energy sector right you know our plants
chemical plants you know our voting
systems health care right hospitals
being breached and causing lots of havoc
and killing people at the same time
right like that's all important and a
lot of people that don't understand the
space sometimes are like well I don't
understand how it's going to affect you
know the electricity grid what does it
have to do with National Security a lot
right and I think that they just don't
see a lot of what happens every day
because they just get the stories that
they see which are like once every
couple of months right so that's why you
know at DHS and just in general I was
this is why it's so important to be in
this space and talking about law and
policy because we're trying to protect
all these structures infrastructures
here
so now quickly I wanted to kind of focus
on like sort of these like certain
spaces within law and policy with
regards to cyber security and one of
them is data breaches right
and what is the important takeaways from
this in this space well companies have
an obligation to inform of major data
breaches
um pursuant to state law right like so
your state might require you to inform
them or inform in some way whatever that
process may be
especially if you are a public company
and you have shareholders you have a
board of directors you have an
obligation to be truthful at all times
especially if it affects their pockets
that is a rule right the SEC or the
Securities Exchange Commission they're
considering and they have been talking
about this for a while is requiring the
obligation to inform about major data
breaches when it comes to public
companies and how will that affect the
company itself how would it affect you
and your positions what's the liability
there and how much money is it going to
affect the company right because that's
the major bottom line is money right so
um there is always some kind of
obligation in some way now federally
there might not be an obligation from a
company to inform about data breach but
again we try to create that
public-private partnership and in
exchange we try to make sure that we can
collect some of the evidence that's
happening there and try to have what
quote-unquote your back on certain
things right like there's certain things
the government can't do but you know
just making sure that we can
um calm the the incident that's
happening there
and it is suggested that companies share
breaches with federal government so that
there may be much more protection and
more opportunity in the long run later
on
some important policy and law in this
space right you had ppd41 which is the
presidential policy directive that's
just another fancy word for policy right
that looks at United States cyber
incident coordination and that's
important because sometimes the federal
government doesn't get it right right
most of the time and so they sometimes
don't understand what to do if there's a
data breach you have many agencies that
try to come together and they're like oh
this is my thing or this is my thing and
it creates a lot of conflict right so
this PPD or policy here is trying to
make sure that we create a streamlined
process
so it better helps the person that's
reporting the breach in the long run and
it doesn't create conflict
so a
security safety review board that was
created not too long ago which is under
DHS and they are there to basically
review certain breaches that happen in
public companies or private companies or
private sector
and the vet board is composed of
different privacy on private leaders and
then government leaders they come
together and I think the latest report
that they issued was the incident of log
4J right and what happened there what
can we learn from it what's the next
steps for companies in this space so
those are two of the major things there
legal case right and this is what I was
referring to at the beginning
um if you don't protect I mean excuse me
if you don't disclose a data breach and
you are intently deceiving the company
and your CEO and you just want to make
it go away
please don't do that because you get
arrested and you can serve time and this
is what happened to the ciso of uber and
he back in 2016 there was a major data
breach he did not want to disclose it he
told the CEO I took care of it there's
nothing that happened you know he just
covered it up in some way and then what
happened was that he was charged
federally now this is like the first
time this really happens right and there
was a lot of conversations about this
like well what's going to happen in
future cisos or people that are put in
this position that are considered Chief
right security officers but in reality
it's just like a term and you're used as
a scapegoat for these situations or what
happens if you contract that out to
other third-party companies what's the
liability there there's a lot of open
Dialogue on this and this is where the
whole issue of Law and policy come in
and you know having those unknown
factors happen in a space that you're
like well data breaches that's pretty
you know up forward front you know
they're we settled on this right not
really now there's this open question
here so one thing that I want to focus
on because I think it's really important
it was a recent issue that happened
then we have global data transfers and
law enforcement requests and what does
this mean so I don't know if anyone's
familiar with the shrem situation or if
you follow policy well
if you are a company that does business
with European companies you have to
follow certain steps because European
companies under the general data
protection regulation look at privacy in
a different way than U.S companies or
U.S in general
they have more extra protections than us
right we don't have a federal Privacy
Law so we have different states that
have different you know standards or
laws but generally or collectively we
don't have that
so it's really hard sometimes for
companies that do business overseas to
sort of transact with each other because
then you could violate their laws or
their gdpr violations right and that
carries big fines big money so I think
Facebook or meta now was find a lot of
money for it in this space
so that's why it's really important to
like understand what this is in a
nutshell right and the only reason why
it's become even bigger thing is because
back then or at least in some way there
was a privacy Shield so the Department
of Commerce was the person or the agency
responsible for handling this sort of
back and forth of you know having you
know transacting with businesses in the
in European union and in the US right
and so there was a thing called privacy
Shield where if your company signed up
and you know there was like a whole
thing that you had to do
you're kind of you know directed and
advised by Commerce and these groups of
people within the Privacy shield and
helping you sort of transact one you
know with the other companies in Europe
but then you had this case and that's
where I had the law here
um you had this case by this guy named
Max drums who's an Australian Advocate
privacy person who said absolutely not
the US is so shady that you can't trust
them with our European data and why is
that well because we have something
called fisa section 702 that is actually
going to expire soon that came out of 9
11 and the Patriot Act and basically
there are certain safeguards there but
we can collect certain information from
you know companies like Google Microsoft
Etc when it comes to National Security
issues and there's certain things that
are brought there with regards to
collecting this information and that's
where law enforcement requests come in
too and so
um the max schremes guy filed a case in
the European courts
and he won and he's and they decided
that we don't have the proper adequacy
protections of privacy for their
citizens so now we've been going back
and forth there's been a new executive
order by Biden where it creates like a
whole new system for making sure that we
protect you know privacy and but then
balance it with National Security and
our collections signals intelligence
data
but of course he's you know Max has just
said he's going to keep filing cases
until we like get it right I guess so
this is just something for you to be
aware of because companies you know
especially tech companies and
um our technology comes very Global and
so we're always going to transact with
European companies right like that's
where a lot of business comes from so
that's why it's so important to
understand what this means for the space
and then also law enforcement so there's
something called national security
letters or
nsls or there's other names out there
but basically FBI and our federal
agencies can sometimes collect or
require companies to give up some
information under this National Security
letter without a fourth amendment
warrant so you have to go through some
hoops et cetera et cetera but there are
requests that are made and there's tons
of them that happen every year so
um you know there's public information
out there about this it just does not
secret or anything like that but it's
something to look out for and understand
because they can come to your companies
and say hey we need people's email
addresses or we need the following
individuals and this is why so things to
look out for there
then we have our products and vendors
section right and this is kind of going
back to the first hypothetical
so what does this mean if you are a
certain telecommunications company or um
you know company that does you know
certain networking you know routing data
back and forth user traffic Etc
um there's certain things that are
banned from you using certain equipment
from certain companies and things like
the secure and trusted Communications
act as one under the FCC
there is now supply chain legislation
talking about banning certain companies
that are not good for supply chain in
the U.S because of National Security
risks and things like for example not
just
um you know networking equipment but
also like security cameras right
especially if your companies have a lot
of government contracts right
and then Federal Acquisitions Security
Council is another one who basically
convenes under the White House and they
basically manage government contracts
and those type of vendors there
especially with regards to their
Networks
well this is why it's important to
understand this section because if you
are in charge of you know Contracting
out equipment or purchasing or just the
way that you build the networks there's
certain things that are a No-No of
companies
and then there's other issues that are
considering in this space like for
example the chips act which basically
promotes say my conductor businesses and
making sure that we can try to find a
way to just
um have semiconductor capabilities here
in the US and not just be it be all
Central in certain parts of the world
right
um and so we're trying to promote that
Commerce side of things
um and then government contracts if
companies are doing or you know
transacting with governments or with the
US government making sure that you're
following those rules there especially
if you have business with DOD or things
like that
and then software development there's a
lot of talks about if you are building
software that there's certain you know
rules and certain things that you're
abiding by because there might be
certain legislation in the pipeline with
regards to risks in that space too
all right and then Network
infrastructure development
um this is another big space because of
zero trust right zero trust is not a new
thing but it became a new thing
quote-unquote when uh President Biden
released his executive order on
improving cyber security right but also
because we have seen a lot of
conversations regarding smart cities and
you know developing 5G and all these
other big futuristic type of you know
transaction of services for Citizens
this is why it's important to kind of
understand this area because of the fact
that we're focusing on the critical you
know infrastructures and regulating
those spaces there
and then lastly what I kind of focus on
in my work is foreign investment
technology right so we have these
stand-up committees that look at our
incoming transactions in the you know in
in the space of anything that has to do
with like technology data critical
infrastructure and we're just making
sure that if there is a foreign company
or a foreign country that is trying to
have a stake in our U.S company in
regards to this space right we're
reviewing threat risks there we're
reviewing how does that look like in our
country how does that look like in the
National Security space but there has to
be some kind of National Security risk
attached to that right we also look at
something you know like called team
Telecom which looks at submarine cables
looks at satellites and other networking
cables and networking Landing stations
and seeing if whether there is a law
enforcement risk or law enforcement
capability going on there in that cable
or Telecom ability in that company and
at the same time looking at whether a
foreign country or foreign sort of
company is trying to come in and look at
that space and take a share of that
company as well so
um that's why it's kind of just a you
know
you know wanted to provide this
background because I think it's really
important in this space because you
might hear these types of things and you
wherever you may work one day and you're
like well I don't know what you're
talking about so it's just good to have
like a knowledge of what does that mean
with regards to the federal government
and an investment in you know if one day
Uber or something like that comes in
right
so um that is for that section and I
think
I am done with my Spiel but I can open
it up for questions I know that I
probably provided a lot to you but I
welcome anything yes sir back there
yeah um good question
um the same thing that would happen
since they are critical infrastructure
um same thing if there was an investment
for example so agriculture or USDA is a
non-voting member of this space of
foreign investment Technology reviews so
if there is some kind of risk there or
if there's a foreign company or a
foreign country trying to look at that
space
um they are you called in to kind of
provide that expertise and to kind of
analyze that threat risk there because
that is important too and it is one of
the critical infrastructures and we tend
to look at that really closely too so
there's that space but other than that
it's mostly being kind of regulated
under this foreign investment space
any I think I saw one yes
yes
resistance
professional
avoid some of the political religions
yeah that's a good question and I
probably won't provide you any more
insight than you know doj is the one
that handles the Computer Fraud and
Abuse Act Right and they're always
issuing opinions or advisory opinions in
this space right and so I think that
that's something new in this area that I
don't think they've really like looked
at and unfortunately I don't have like a
concrete answer for you however it is
something that is sort of in this
landscape that we need to focus on
because I'm not too familiar with this
incident in Missouri but there is a lot
of talks back and forth about okay well
what happens if you're weaponizing or
utilizing this laws and regulation for
your own sort of political agendas or
sort of like how do we provide more
protections or less protections when it
comes to sharing or you know making sure
that we are providing like some kind of
boundaries so that we do have a better
partnership and I think that's what the
principles or the strategy that came out
kind of focus on without really like
saying this a specific topic right but
it's more of making sure that we provide
this balance because if we don't sort of
give some kind of trust Factor right to
our companies and to our private sector
um then how are we going to make sure
that they help us in the long run for
our goals and our mission right our
mission of whatever agency it might be
so that is a good question unfortunately
I don't have a concrete answer for that
but um there is always constantly like
talks about more advisory opinions in
this space especially the the cfaa and
making sure that we are not
um you know that we're we're answering
the loophole questions because that's an
old law right like it hasn't been
updated in a while it was created back
when we just had like Netscape or
Internet Explorer 1.0 right and so I
don't think there has been any more
updating of it in a while and so I think
that that's something that the
department of Justice might be looking
at in some way
yes sir
yeah um so to clarify you mean like how
does it start right how does this
process start it's very very voluntary
so
um believe it or not some like very rare
scenarios where the committee will be
like we need to look at this right now
because this company didn't report this
transaction very rare
um it's a very voluntary process and as
I was mentioning it's a it's it's a
partnership so a lot of the times
companies out there are aware of what's
going on right and they have the lawyers
they have the big lawyers that make
money that are advising their clients
when they say hey I'm deciding to sell
this amount of shares or I'm deciding to
sell
half of my company to this come you know
to this other foreign company that and
my company basically transacts lots of
data or um I focus on AI you know those
type of Industries
um and these lawyers will say hmm
um I think that you need to look at this
and they'll say look at this whole
entire spectrum of um cepheus which is
what it's called in this foreign
investment review because you have to
look at this and we have to work on this
and so it creates like a voluntary
process where they will file this
companies will file these reviews to us
right and it's basically a bunch of
questions and we kind of look at that
and we assess from there and we
determine whether we need to keep
looking at this further so it's a very
um voluntary process and it's rarely
ever a mandatory sort of we're coming at
you basically because we don't want we
want to create that relationship right
we want to make sure that we're creating
this open process and we're taking care
of not only the the needs of this for an
investment sideway because we want to
create competition we want to create
economic incentives we want to do all
these things but we also want to protect
the other side of things which is our
mission our national security interests
and also our U.S people right and making
sure that there's a fairness in that
side too
does that answer your question
right so um really do we say there are
times where where we won't find out
right like there might be some time but
eventually we do find out right because
in some way there's another agency
that's involved in this committee that
has some kind of information right and
it will come through in some way but
again I from my time that and it hasn't
been that long in this space of um the
four investment side have I seen
um something where this happens where
it's not uh reported in some way
yes
yeah great question so there are a lot
of
um sort of like core you know companies
not companies excuse me like
organizations out there like um the ncls
which is like the national County uh
legislators or something like that there
if you Google them they're a great
resource there and they actually I think
provided me with these data and these
points and they were it was in their
website and they have a great chart of
like mapping out what privacy
legislations out there what has been
passed Etc so those type of
organizations that kind of Lobby for
states or that Lobby for counties is a
good one
um another way is to making sure that if
you are in this space and you're working
whatever position it may be having a
good relationship with the um attorneys
involved right but so every company is
probably going to have and especially in
the space some Council right and so
making sure that you are made aware of
what's going on and that you um sort of
speak to them right put yourself in
those meetings because I'm sure they're
having meetings and kind of inform
yourself of what's going on or making
sure that your group your team whatever
it may be however you're composed
understands that they should be sort of
briefed on these issues too because you
all need to know what's going on out
there too and so making sure that you're
aware of this is great and having that
awareness and reaching out to those
folks is good too so looking at also
those organizations out there that are
lobbying for these sectors like
Governors associations another one too
that have really great resources as well
yes
yes I'm sorry can you I can hear you
crypto okay
um so crypto right
um that's mostly SEC right the security
Exchange Commission they're the ones
that are sort of looking at this space
and so and so is treasury as well right
they're the ones that are more into that
space I do more of the critical
infrastructure space
um so I don't have too much information
on bitcoin
um or blockchain for that matter right
um but um they're the ones that are
working on that however from what my
research has shown and just reading
things like there's not much concrete
legislation on that and that's because
you know there's a lot of back and forth
as to like this is supposed to be a
space where you cut out middleman and
you shouldn't have any regulation but
then as you're probably doing your taxes
you'll see things like questions like do
you own digital currency right or things
like that so those are some sort of like
you know law improvements there like
like just reporting and making sure that
people are reporting those currencies in
their taxes
um but what happens after yeah I'm not
too sure but it's a space that still has
a lot of open questions in that
okay yeah
worked on legislation related
yeah
yeah no a good question so I think it's
a mixture of both and you're not going
to like that because every other is like
well it depends
um and that's because again I am a firm
believer in the way our system is run
right like our bureaucracy is you know
we have our states and we have our
federalism right
um but when it comes to like privacy
like something needs to be done because
all these states are doing different
things and it gets confusing right and
it creates a lot of barriers for
companies but it also creates a lot of
barriers for users and
um you know the internet we depend on it
a lot and it should be a global thing so
if we don't if we're not careful with
the way that we sort of legislate the
space it can create a lot a lot of
localization of data where you'll have
like certain you know countries just
focusing on their data and just having
like a barrier there you'll have like
you know us on one side and it's just
not gonna like speak to each other right
and so I think that that's something to
be aware of
um and you know just making sure that
we're sort of promoting that digital
sovereignty of you know but protect our
interests but at the same time we work
with each other and so if we have
legislation that's so like cut you know
like in pieces like privacy for example
then that can create some risk there too
like that or if we don't address like
data transfers then how are we going to
communicate with each other one day
right so I think that in that space
Federal legislation is important
um but then again there are certain
things that states should have a say
like Biometrics right like every agency
in the states have their own thing that
they do every state has a different
thing right like South Dakota's
interests are very different from
Florida's interests right so I think
that that there is where you should look
at well what space dictates States
activities
and I think that's my time so um thank
you all this was great I hope that you
got something out of this and if you
ever want to like reach out to me that's
my email there but thank you all and it
was great to be there thanks
[Applause]
presentation is going to be all about
building a security program from someone
who's done it the hard way so without
further Ado please welcome Parker Seaman
[Applause]
hello everybody thank you for making uh
making out to this talk uh there's a lot
of fantastic speakers today and so I'm
very glad to be included in that
um I know the talk going on in the other
hall right now is very interesting and
actually the guy that's giving that is
my neighbor of the hotel
um talked a little bit last night really
cool guy
um
if you could help me with messing with
him a little bit please if you see him
tell him great talk and make up little
things about his talk at just like don't
exist like say like really great really
great talk I liked how you were able to
make the John Deere talker John Deere
tractor speak in Spanish
um but enough about that more about me
as said
um well we'll get to about me we'll do a
quick little overview we'll have the
table contents here talking about why
you should and shouldn't listen to me
um planning a path for your program some
tips on software for building your
program the longer part will be on the
soft skills that go into making a
security program work with the people
who was actually going to affect and
then just kind of a quick recap on it
but a little bit about myself my name is
Parker Steven
um I work as a principal security
engineer at neurocore and I am a
communication manager at openvoice OS
which you can think of like kind of like
an Alexa but it doesn't record you and
doesn't work as good but it's neat
um
and my talk is more so going to be
focused on if you're somebody who
started as
um or rather has an interest in working
in security or finds themselves in a
situation where the the workplace they
are at does not have a well-developed
cyber security program
that was the case that I found myself in
a couple of years ago when I joined my
current work workplace as devops joined
and there was nothing in in store there
very quickly I started taking under
security projects under my wing and
trying to improve the
um
mature return mint maternus of our cyber
security program so that we could
actually withstand something that
happened to us
um and over that time I made some
mistakes but have made a lot of progress
and learned what it takes at least for
my situation to why or rather who how to
create something that can actually
function and have some sort of semblance
of security rather than things just
working when you don't face any
adversary or any adversaries
so I want to talk a little bit about why
I have some creators to talk about this
um and I'll add a little bit more
context to that in a second of that
but but first it's the
the reason why I think I have some
authority to speak on this is like I
said when I joined my workplace there
was nothing in terms of security other
than like base compliance type things
that
um Regulators might have for us or
customers might ask of us
and from there I started to increase
things incrementally
make us some more secure in ways that
aren't simply required of us but that
would actually help us
withstand some sort of attack
and I feel like I've got some decent
accreditations to this I've spoken at
some other security another security
conference I've got a master's degree
from this University
and I've been uh very
um
social for for lack of better terms in
the cyber security field
why you should take what I say with a
grain of salt is that my workplace is
unique it's a startup type thing
with
somewhat of a some that's somewhat
established but still changing very much
um
and my process is still ongoing and I'm
also still made mistakes and I see
myself making more mistakes in the
future because as good as I am in a
number of things I'm wrong a lot of the
time
so with that said take what I say with a
grain of salt and pay attention to the
the broad Strokes rather than on the
specifics
the arguably one of the most important
parts When developing your program is
making sure that you've planned ahead
rather than just trying to fit to make a
quick patch for whatever you see the
immediate issue is
um it when you go into a environment
without any sort of Protections in place
it can be
enticing to jump right in and try to fix
it as fast as possible and in some
regards that might be okay idea but when
you're wanting to improve a workplace's
security you want to make sure that
you're planning for the Long Haul
um if the companies this uh
understanding is that they're going to
be there for a while and they're going
to want to make sure that the solutions
put in place will be long lasting simply
putting a patch into place a Band-Aid on
a broken bone will not last
so
how do you make a plan you ask people
who are smarter than you
the the sisa CIS nist all of these
different organizations have a lot of
resources available for being able to
help you create a framework a plan and a
process for you to create a program that
helps you improve your security
the
um oh shoot my words are gone uh
regardless the main point of the plan is
to your plan should focus on
for fixing these smaller aspects of your
workplace rather than improving the
things that might be more fun while
doing an intern an internal pen test or
an internal phishing type campaign might
be more fun you should probably make
sure that your password policy is strong
make sure that you have MFA enable it on
different things on all of your software
make sure you have a you have an
inventory of what you're actually
supposed to protect those aren't as fun
but incredibly necessary for making sure
that your environment is secured
when you're looking into tools to help
secure your workplace there are
um obviously a lot of options out there
and a lot of them with varying prices
a lot of different Enterprise
technologies will give a a high price
tag and promise a lot and they might be
able to be helpful but you want to be
careful to make sure you pick something
that is actually going to be well
fitting for your workplace and not
overdo it and on the note of overdoing
it you um
apologies
if you if you're worried about
finding a place for cyber security
program a budget might come to mind if
nobody has ever put time into it they
might see the addition of security
tooling as a burden especially a
financial one so it's useful to make
make uh oh no my slides are we're going
wrong oh well what was supposed to show
up is some examples of some various open
source softwares that are Enterprise
grade and can be paid for but typically
what those types of things are is the
software itself is open source and you
can pay for to either have them provide
you support or to host it for you and
those are a good way to get kind of your
foot through the door to show how much
um a tool like that can really improve
things it doesn't add much to cost
whatever whatever the time and possibly
server hosting cost it is to host a a
waza server or
OSS EC ossc I forget the name of it
specifically a showdown license to help
scan your network the time and resources
that basically that go into something
like that cost much less than paying for
a full software suite but can provide
some deliverables to you to take to
hello
was feeling bad about the process and
that there were still some people who
were upset about it and when I mentioned
when I was having a review with my my
boss I mentioned the people who are
upset about it he said oh well they
always complain about things
so
I don't mean to devalue the time and
effort that goes into doing something
like that it's sort of a give and a take
or a better column a bit of column B in
that you should spend some time to make
sure you bring everyone along with you
educate people about the risks
except that it's not always going to
work sometimes it's just like that
um so to
great uh there's supposed to be more of
these slides and the demo gods do not
like me today but that's fine
so
to conclude the
most important parts are that you should
make sure you have a robust plan in
place When developing a a program
uh make use of Open Source and
less expensive software to help justify
the needs of cyber security and spend
time with the people to ensure that they
are with you if they can't love the
changes being made at least help and
spend some time to help them understand
it
now any questions comments concerns
heckling
what's up
bigger plan things and some smaller plan
things
I did try my best
to explain you know here's why this is
important here's what this is going to
do
even though it seems inconvenient or
it's going to take
a budgeting position
which came across me they felt like
ever did you ever experience any kind of
pushback for your
recommended security measures
so the question if anybody couldn't hear
it is
um when proposing types of security
improvements sometimes you get pushback
on them whether they're large changes or
small changes and they come from all
forms from budget to technical to
everything and how would I address those
pushbacks
um I'll admit at the start not well we
had this one software suite that we were
using and I noticed I could trace back
the version of that software to the
founding of the company and I brought
that up in a meeting and I said we
should probably get this updated it's
publicly facing and needs to be updated
my boss said well we can get to that
this year and I went this year
I had been at the company maybe five
months at that point
and I got lucky that nothing worse
happened
um
addressing pushback with software that
or changes that they don't see as is
necessary I think
um
providing examples of Industry standards
and where this is useful elsewhere is
helpful that can be sometimes harder to
find
um
in cases where you can't
find examples to help back up your
evidence or
find them unwilling to work with you in
creating a plan that works for everybody
in terms of changing things
polite persistence
which is a nice way of see saying being
annoying for a long time
um
because it's not often times that I I
believe people dislike the security
change exactly it's that people don't
like having what they have been doing
for a long time suddenly changing
um
so providing a road map and
gentle reminders of how this can be
useful can help break down those walls
you don't
um to further the analogy of the wall
you don't need to destroy the wall just
ship at it
does that answer your question at all
anyone else
what's up
five billion
sorry
I say we have about a hundred ish and I
would say
oh it's a little less than 100 but I'd
say about 10 10 or 15.
more than I wanted less than I expected
what's up
can you say that one more time please
so the question is what do I mean by a
robust plan and I think the best way I
could try to explain that is
when you're proposing security changes
to a company that's never had this or
never had this in the focus you're going
to have a lot of questions about why
this is necessary So the plan should try
to meet them where they are seeing
issues with it
um
having a good timeline
and
trying to help show where this is
necessary
um
on top of that
making it known that if you weren't
there
that this could still continue to
function
um
yeah
any other questions
or
I will also open the door too if you
have any advice for me who is still very
much learning I'm open to anything you
have to say
yep
no but what I so really what I managed
to do
I'll tell you the first time I propose
it to my boss
my plan was like a three-year plan we're
going to integrate things into entity
systems get automated increase registry
that way
cut clear here's our options here's how
much it's going to cost boom boom right
and it failed miserably it's like we
have no room for this in the budget CEO
is never going to go for it this isn't
going to work we need to see the benefit
I'm like okay well let me
so what I managed to do was I you know I
read
like restructured my proposal and I kind
of scooped in more Automation and better
user experience with improved security
and I kind of made security as of I've
like made it look like it was secondary
in it but
um it really was my end right so I made
the primary like single sign-on things
like automation
um with you know improved user
experience in that way as well as
rolling in things like password manager
and that kind of thing making their
point
everybody what I also said as a
secondary benefit hey we have integrated
things with our identity system and MFA
on top of that because you need identity
systems or single sign-ups right
exactly uh for those who couldn't hear
is uh compounding of what I had said
about how to
[Music]
um
work with your company's dislikes of
security to help try to use those to
build up into something that's more um
fully fully idealized is that close to
what you're saying
anyone else
right thank you all very much for coming
to my talk and for coming to Dakota Con
in general I hope you have a wonderful
rest of your day
[Applause]