but soon
my presentation is about developing of
the new graphic models for computer
network visualization
let's just add to the world or
visualization so you'll see these models
first two older is a representation
computer network of the cases that will
be using there are three cases here
attacks topologies metrics will be more
than enough
how do i visualize that tax so the right
hand side there
the metrics which is showing the attack
attack's we have pulses here
the vulnerabilities which allow the
hacker to do these attacks so exploited
this vulnerability
it leads is the record to new host and
sub network connected to can move to
another one yet another one so it is
higher than the diagonal
we're moving forward and we're moving
back and dissipation
source and destinations and ports
it was can one machine many ports
it's a line and a plane
so you can visualize this a scan and
pattern on the right hand side
our world coordinates sources and
destinations and the skin
is it easy I'll doing visualize the
metrics and
mom you can add Leafs to it
so here's a circle the current you can
result in the left hand side of the
right hand side you know to the
vulnerability with you
which equals nine the outer part is a
result of the previous canning
a typical state or the network and the
metrics does not allow us to visualize
the most metrics that we can highlight
them with color transparency we do the
customization so that we can see the
cells the structures which help us
understand what this network is all
about it
one of the most effective for ways to
visualize the metrics given fear because
it's a spatial we have a router to which
the courses are connected way over this
rectangular with hosts
so an orange one is a router
inside there are plenty of routers etc
etc so one router with the one hopes
typology graph this is the simplest way
because it's intuitively clear
if you need to project a few pirate
isn't apologies and you just use this
visualization like something right
it costs them their combined
and then they combined again
what's a link here and what's related to
where is marked with a color for the
direct lines curves etc
we can be expanded in the shape of a
tree
it's so good but it seems like that we
have three base concepts upon which this
models of these
what are the concepts the first one is
they're all 11 concept for example we
have called called coordinates
even the simplest ground for the sooner
soy de and demonstrate that the tree map
he had
and the graph for the connections we
have some graphic elements
so what's developed for India graphic
models
what is the trend in visualization first
of all the work with David the
customization of hosts
when I was single out what is required
and the encapsulation when we had all
the hosts together
so these two graphs is actually one the
next one is designed we have realized
finally the design is not effective only
marketed but it's very good for
visualization
as far as we can see here is a trend for
the variable design need minimal design
etc and interactive part through the
interactive part of the user is
operating with the data through graphics
another revenue
it looks good so all of these models and
handsome of deficiencies and they
coexist
therefore the graphs have learned
plenty of some free time
the free space they pulley visualize the
metrics the trees can only be showing
the hierarchy and the mattresses
they also leave work quite a lot of
space
you me and our solution here is to use a
new concept based upon collisions
so let us imagine it's our host is our
self and we have a connection with the
host if their cells have no connection
we put the separator here at analog a
Libyan just because that's just for
example you are in the leathery amazed
only the shining
the nation
you can move from one room to another
first call
plenary approach
then we have the longest relationship
was a whole imagine these are the nails
or put them in a board we apply the one
trying relation keeping the structure
serious tax structure was single out the
sales and the diagrams
turns out the tiled of the triangulation
will be using the model here and we can
identify the host the triangles centers
and we have approximately this structure
triangulation and the graphical model
we'll show the separators and the
deficiency
we can only apply to one area networks
yeah
this way
let's just take a look at their
languages will be comparing it to the
graphs
mama
in our model will be showing the size of
the cell and the vulnerabilities are
here
what does it look like
let's compare just threw a special
aspects you perceive it in a better way
you need to have a special cases where
you can apply to its subject based upon
looking to expand it to the wrong
for example if we make a sectional to it
we will have a prison
then we can come up with different
representations we can show it in forms
of cells and lines
the next one we're going to put in
different values and we do not serve
consider our graphic morning only has
one for visualization of the computer
networks but also for visualization of
other pro systems and then we would like
to say that the graphic models
other ones that we explore the most one
we we use design we use these concepts
and basically I think that our
developments will help us move forward
thank you very much sit across this is
the way to problem you have a gross i
will potentially can which vision
did you try and visualize the four
months so it would have a very nice and
slick presentation will try to do it for
students and it seems like that he did
not perceive quite right
it was very hard on yourself did you
have such experience of visualizing data
structures in particular i'm in charge
of gave visualization of the computer
networks that can be in the future apply
to the monitoring solutions but you you
can do something to visualize the
formats the security formats
in fact the way to public very much
similar to the doc bot
thank you