nobody me as they would always in you
okay yeah I'm already incurred from
mural security systems center i was
speaking about viruses anti viruses
android solutions and the research that
we conducted together with my colleagues
but before we start I would like to
start to ascii to ask you how many
android users are here
please raise your hands those of you who
are using an android device
please keep your hand red
raise those who are protected with
antivirus solution
I thought that there would be even your
people here but i have conducted this
survey with my colleagues and seems like
the right half as many protected android
devices as other devices in our study we
want to take a look and how the
anti-virus applications working
by taking an android smart friend and
using 19 top applications we wanted to
show you what would they would be
capable
there are plenty of other applications
used here like application manager
anti-spam application and are shocked by
the ball you solutions which costs six
thousand rubles and is offering you to
become your financial advisor
seems like that the main function of the
antivirus association is malicious
software skinning and that's what they
wanted to do here
for this we will need
possession
A virus there are plenty of such viruses
on the internet so we wanted to create
our own wires but for that we needed to
know which functions we wanted to
implement here in the anniversaries are
plenty of your bank in Troy Johnson and
we have realized the SMS and into
interception but it did not work out
quite completely so we added life data
data encryption here and the phone
blocker
k 2 PK we called this miniature software
this application was made up of three
parts the first part was an active part
it actually it is actually launched with
the application is showing this nice cat
the second interception card part is
sniffing through your SMS messages and
the third part is the coming
commands us some center message exchange
who had a web service which was a
mission control center
i will show it to you later the
implementation of the virus was done in
standard ways i would like to show you
that from the active part of the
application we launched two processes
and the background
the first one to intercept their SMS
messages the second one responsible for
the Mission Control Center data exchange
let's take a look at the banking tour
John blueprint someone receives that an
SMS message someone reads it through the
file system by sending a mission control
command you need to know just the phone
number
this message can be sent from that phone
would be deleted
the second way is a little bit more
interesting
it's a clear listening way and sniffing
of all of the involvement SMS messages
but it's no longer available in android
higher than 4.4 you can use this text
message very easily that was not the
only function that was used there
it would also block the phone and to
unblock it later and cooked the data and
decrypted when people sent you the money
at the first scan the total virus
antivirus did not detect it
although in couple of days the situation
changed and that the number of detects
rose - 21
which is a good demonstration of the
data's change between the leader basis
and a couple of days with shield 26
detects out of 56
we cannot do more
it was a total wireless
but we're talking here about mobile
applications
so we use the realistic devices
that's the testing smartform with 19
applications installed but as you can
see this station is not changing only to
detect out of 18
these are the only two antivirus is
detected by kaspersky and mg mobile the
type of virus was only detected by
kaspersky the mobile virus that there
was a breaching confidentiality other
applications did not see any threats now
phone and other five reacted to them as
a robur barcode scanner on the trust me
and you are attracted to kaspersky
maybe they know something that we don't
know in a couple weeks visitation
changed and six and two hours programs
detected us
is that a vast workout and dr. Webber
added that was the maximum number we
knew that we would not be able to
achieve more detects and we started the
main part of our study to bypass t
antivirus software up through station of
the code is best used here by taking a
few a few skaters and creating our own
we wanted to bypass the antivirus
installed on our smartphone
we have to a few skaters
they can only work with the source court
but word is embedded into android
one of the features is that it's the
only one of the other skaters it can
delete all the informations even their
strength
the second one a letter e features
stronger encryption by using the salt
algorithm scan revealed that term
apart from that other virus
we use the den droid virus because it's
signatures were familiar to most of
their antivirus software and the
modified android from where we removed
some information and some of the
functions
after such modification the number of
detects reduced by slightly polishing up
the software some of the anti viruses
detected that a lottery is showed a much
better result
mainly it was about encryption for the
blood work to reduce the number of
detects is wrong
virustotal and mobile antivirus showed
approximately the same trends a part for
most of those two up for skaters
we took a few more the features here is
that it can work with white code that
can be a cried throughout the case file
and you don't need to use the source
code of the application here
let's take a look at the manifestation
athletes
first of all it can add an additional
method here to every class second law
it can change the names of the reference
capitalized is changed into capitalized
ABC 123
it inserts to go to procedures from the
very beginning till the very end and it
also support the encryption all the
strings of the code
what are the results my Adam
the virus table results are averaged
between the Lateran problem
mobile antivirus is reduced it to three
detects which is good but it's not
perfect
we actually wanted to achieve zero
detective
we created our own up for skater just
like Adam it can work with white cold
we called it
Eva it can encrypt strength
the packets names and creates an
absolutely new structure four buckets
and folders
after filling station it has encrypted
them encryption was used here by using
sort algorithm with a very monkey
the skin and revealed more impressive
results which is the single detect from
mobile antivirus ease of us was the only
antivirus which reacted to our cat virus
virus total also had the good results
three out of Tennessee but that was not
all you can combine different
application methods even simple
repackaging reduces the detects a number
of times
half of the anti viruses will not detect
you in this case we use Adam and Eve
together you'll get the single detect as
well but unlike the mobile device where
our last was the only one performance
it was a lot v3 but our vast did not
detect it
kaspersky did not detected one
encryption was used as well as other
popular antivirus programs and we
thought that that's basically what
what's up is requesting what if we
appreciate what's up there were three
ways
repackaging Adam and Eve the
modification turned out to be so strong
that the application with crash the
application even the fe education is
successful the application still wanted
to reinstall itself yet to antivirus
accountant and a vast reacted to the
infected files
it's the same a vast which really
reacted to our malicious software after
Eva application which reveals some
paranoia
what would be the conclusion out of it
would be difficult to bypass and mobile
antivirus know what do we really need it
do we really need such antiviruses they
do protect us against some of the
threats but it's not panacea
just like we were able to pull it off
total antlers you can buy passage of
google plan to play market which we
didn't do of course we didn't want to
spread onto hers software
thank you very much i'll be headed to
take your questions
ok
if that crossroad means keep river
national population
admin rights related question it
requires just the rights
exactly what what's up is doing with the
country require administrator rights
the next
do you have detected in one time when
you launch the application
he has some of the anti viruses and the
detect launched but unfortunately not
all of them could react to our cats
malicious software and other viruses
when we scan it we cannot detect it
we were testing it in many ways and some
of the anti viruses that has a function
available when it checks all of the
packets global applications and some of
them reacted to such viruses but we also
did some complete phone scanning for
every version for obfuscate version for
Android for the cat etc
did you conduct any tests
for this see based android applications
see libraries are detectives detected in
the worse way but we use Java instead