Michael yasha he will be discussing
reverse engineering of binary formats
with the use of Chi struct thank you for
the introduction my name is Michael
reaction and first i would like to
introduce ourselves and why we're
engaged in doing what we are doing my
company a white box labs
max controllers for aquariums
areum's hydroponic dads for a beer
brewers cheesemakers winemakers all
kinds of a closed or equals fears
there is also a aquaponic which is about
having aquariums with fish installed in
Helms which fish eat the grass which are
inside those aquariums
well which fish can be a hidden by a
home residents and forth which may be a
very interesting
a source unlimited source of food for
say developing countries
just a few words about what is
controlled by controllers in such close
systems that a lot of sense and such as
water level a leakage gauges detectors
temperature gauges water control gauges
which is very important for aquariums
for which is crucial
Oh to be able to be in control of the H
dissolved oxygen and so on and so forth
flow sensors in mitigations lighting
sensors
we have to be in control of our light
bulbs
the lighting systems that we use to
leave our aquariums terrariums and so on
and so forth for some aquariums which
are used for decoration purposes
it may be a necessary to install cameras
for owners to be able to enjoy their
Fisher emailed land since all systems
are a really expensive it would be a PT
a-- you for the fish died a while
the owner is on vacation for example
which means that there should be
redundant power supply systems which in
turn i need to be controlled
according to studies such a century's
help to control various actuators such
as pumps dozers source of lighting
heaters
automatic feeders for fish skimmers
reactors at hog chemical devices which
are in charge of us are you taking the
environment and aquariums various
reallys all bars that may be in charge
of supplying Paula to of various devices
there may be a more complex Paul control
systems which is relevant for bigger
aquariums
the size of the ocean areas and so forth
challenge number one that is encountered
by typical user customer who may want to
install in the corium smart aquarium in
helm is vendor lock-in
what is it about
there are about five major vendors
manufacturing the corium systems you
made by a controller natural controller
for example which means that it will
only be a compatible with other nation--
equipment which systems are not cheap
having both several thousand hero or
worth of devices such a customer will be
reluctant to switch to a competitor's
product because they will never be
compatible
we've initially bought systems being the
same sensors or browsers or other
devices because of being based on a
proprietary protocol for example we do
not manufacture our realm of sensors
we're relatively small system however we
manufacture a controller that is
compatible with all the third party
products and we achieve that through
reverse engineering of proprietary
protocols and implementation of those
protocols in our controllers
now to the main point of my presentation
and i'm going to start from a general
overview of the task name let a reverse
engineering of binary data structures
what we start from what we do what we
seek to achieve how it is done
traditional how it is done
now apologize in advance for repeating
myself from time to time problem
some of my points may sound trivial
however to make the picture full i will
make them
what is normal and reverse engineered
for us communication protocols are
particularly interesting for other
reasons above because those protocols
are used in controllers and devices they
control
very often it is very interesting to
explore in better form where the
software embedded in various systems for
which there are no source scouts for
example we uh me need to explore the
algorithms their base them examine their
safety
sometimes it is necessary to attack them
or to protect them to reach them with
additional features and so forth
next the various of container of file
formats interest in land
internal ax the files such as text files
or various or Scout source files are
enclosed in a containers based on a
known formats and it may be interesting
to explore those formats for a
compression for industries now of
various executables executable file that
can be executables or byte codes
normal byte codes are based on formats
which very often are complex enough in
modern executable they normally have
sections we something embedded the are
based on their logical structures in
order to understand what's in the file
in order to extract some resources from
that or notified or engage in doing some
more useful work with the use of
december's it is necessary to understand
the structure of the file to be able to
analyze it for more wear and so on
now working with a content files such as
databases tables playing tax graphic
sectors
well the range of tax may be a really
broad including extraction of content
files from games
or reference catalogs
should such content be in an unknown of
binary of your mouth free to be reused
not just two copies from screen about to
obtain it's very quickly in
machine-readable format
I can distinguish between two main for
our main approaches but today I'm going
to focus on the approach which is on the
right hand side it is about exploring
the code if the code is available
it should be loaded to a disassembler
well the second approach is exploring
the data proper to understand was in
there to identify patterns which
patterns can be analyzed and implemented
in order to be able to read processors
for such formats
based on our experience i can say that
and where the second approach is viable
of for us white first lap there is a
number of Licensing constraints will
hate to find ourselves in court
we don't want lawsuit to be set forth
against us
they're all but sometimes this approach
is the only possible if the number of
devices as big but what we may not have
a board for example of there is just a
spot on the board and we need to extract
the four where some help
how do traditionally for his work
they can work with
of files or five systems or discs or dis
carries for example once i encountered a
situation where what happened some ten
years ago we will give them the broken
just carry for at least some information
to be extracted from it and we have to
deal with its blood system and it
required some kind of reverse
engineering various boards
uh well in order to be able to extract
data from various kinds of memory now
intercept the traffic nine percent of
time is normally found on that
everything will be in the pickup format
only in one percent of cases will you
encounter a different format
what do we want is an output
what to those engaged in reverse
engineering want is an output normal and
it is a format description but while
other is now a standard format
there is no standard for such format
description
normal an a/c like approaches are used
sometimes people try to use videos
tables showing the distribution of bits
and bytes in the memory
you can have a look at the RFC
illustrating the popular of PNG format
that you can also see a here the
signatures described as chunks
you can see this type of bytes here and
there another example of this RFC is
about the UDP protocol of the developers
of RFC decided to present
everything here is a table and we can
see the structure of a UDP datagram is a
table for 32-bit some help
probably ought to fit the page but
anyway it can be used
now this is description
all the popular LF format which is a
popular format for storing the content
of executable files
it is presented as serious of a text
paragraphs with inserts in some eighty
percent of format descriptions that I
have seen people engage in developing a
substandard formats and the standard was
only passed some time ago
- define various lengths of variables
one by two bites the developers of this
decided to use the word l32 a half or
off one should find the section in the
standard describing it
regarding the functionality of this bite
what it is about and so on another very
funny approach
some of you may be familiar with out a
format can be described else of art &
posters are published you can be printed
out and put a wall
the one engagement reverse engineering
is always expected to produce a parser
or a decoder to parse the code
oh well everything is moved to the
memory and distributes between the named
cells on of the slide you can see an
example of such parser a written in the
c language
what can be seen here
individual structure elements are red
here 1 of x 1 and 3 is reading a certain
subprogram is used which either read the
bite or a ward of a certain length we
have all the proper checks with the
return of the correct of program type
well ironically there is not
standardized library in some ninety five
percent of cases people or write their
own libraries for this and what you see
here is an animation loading a project
it is a gaming anjam for which such
library with a Z of preferences was
created
and all the way around people
normal you want to obtain generators or
encounters to assemble everything back
and from all those cells we make up some
file
well everything goes in the opposite
direction in the same way your library
is written in code is written to
complete such a transformation
well these two slides are very much
alike as well as the code there is
traditional approach to such clear room
or engineering their engineer study is a
dump for a long time comes up with a
pose as a saying that leaves cells may
contain this or those cells might
contain that if it is simple hypothesis
it is just checked manually to make sure
the different tiers of those structures
are aligned should formats be slightly
more complex a processing code is
written to do or what you saw on the
previous slides
however it's not uploaded to the memory
instead of that it is uploaded to the
some debugging us set out to check the
hypothesis which is an intermediate
program designed to transform the income
to visualize the incoming file
for the purpose of hypotheses checking
in ninety percent of cases it has found
out that they're reading meals is not
ideal for reading from the flow and a
later
in a minute I will show
why why this project and it's not a
trivial task of putting all those
variables in one line with ending
transformation and so on
well with this we end up with yet
another library we compile we start we
check our hypothesis for of this
particular program and we repeated many
times until we find answers for all
questions or until we find ourselves in
front of an obstacle we cannot eliminate
what kind of means are available to
those who want to do this work 99
percent if not one hundred percent of
those present here have seen
four  years or
editors at least once
never was i am going to demonstrate it
to you
this is our great Russian few editors
sometimes used
that's what we can see and meditate on
front of prior to proceeding to more
sophisticated tools i will allow myself
to give you another example that i'll be
using in order to illustrate how those
tools work i'm going to use the format
of the game
do what which is one of the simplest
container formats it was used in really
impatient for games
the original development was done
between 1995
92 in 95 you'll find a lot of borough
code here borrowed from earlier projects
the format itself is pretty sample on
the one hand on the other hand it on the
straights all the interesting elements
that can be encountered in our container
format we have magic here which is kind
of a signature the four bytes from the
beginning of the file
they are letters I don't you find our
file you those letters are not the
present their the engine well a sound in
our message that on the header we see a
4-byte filled with our in experiments or
other number of files or in our
container
yeah there is also the shift indicator
index offside the index itself is not
directly linked with the header it does
not follow of the header with this index
underscore how fast we can read our
structures 8 + 8
well 16 16 white land alone or one
structure corresponds to one file one
reading the file the engine first
results complete now which files
it has internal where to look for them
however at this stage the engine does
not read the files themselves with
proper or parser of this format
one should not read the content of the
files all the files that are present in
the container until the are really
needed the files themselves are shifted
uh yes it is mentioned in the field they
get the found with a 16 the sounds the
main platform is us in told us is pretty
simple
another example of more advanced
software which is software of a high
level and here we need something more of
than just taking our hypothesis
there are hex fears and editors with
templates you can see some seven of them
and total the are between 10 and 20
though so highlight a dream of the to
highlight of the green are those
accounting for some eighty percent of
this market they are 0 1 0 editor and a
Texan ear
well the first one
the former is currently passing you
Elvis movie to a hex inator
there are other of yours and editors
with templates to but there is no point
in discussing them now
space Cape
I beg upon the for typos
it's should be 0 1 0 0
it looks like this so the difference
between from a dumb sex editor is that
apart from the has dumped and some
reputation of this hex dump in
symbolical we also have a tree of
structures marked so within this file so
we can move in that tree
we generate this tree using this kind of
code
this is an absolutely imperative type of
codes and please take a pay attention to
that we create two structures in the
header structure and the index entry
structure and then we're saying that
first we have a header and we do it
apparently by calling some function to
move and then sign the final entry array
the X inator looks
similarly that's also a dump
also a tree that
you can take a look at the X inator has
a tree editor that other one hand should
simplify it safe for the task of
describing the format but on the other
hand in my opinion it's sometimes easier
to do it from director of the keyboard
then i've been using this editor the
grammar is the same
looks like this both for the file
template and X inator vaccinator is just
a bit some more declarative more verbose
it has certain elements of the
capability to take some structures out
of these after this format and reproduce
them separately outside this main tree
so what's good about these hex editor
says they show the tree of objects and
their values right in the life file with
examples things like that in some of
these editors has a visual treat editor
and the show which are places in the
binary stream objects take so what's bad
about them
the first and most important thing is
the imperative character for 101 it's
one hundred percent imperative
it says see like language as we've just
seen for most others there are attempts
to implement a declarative language but
once it lacks in functionality
developers
solve the problem in a very simple way
using XML or some other format to the
describes the grandma
they insert a tag where they insert a
script in Python or Java Script that
does the dirty work that the declarative
formats including doing
focus on the representation in the
layout file attention is given to colors
comments and things like that but you
don't actually use it
value itself when it's about the formal
description of the format these editors
don't do a good job of automating for
instance if you want to run some
hypotheses on thousands of several
thousand two packets and get some
statistically valid result is impossible
so loading these packets one by one in
such an editor and trying to learn
something about them
looks quite foolish almost all these
editors read the file and market
I like it out or fully the memory so
you're loaded and the container will be
a red marked up and in the process of
this marking up for instance for what
working with some large image DVD or
blu-ray dias
it will immediately be stored in the
memory boat and nothing good will come
out of it except perhaps the octa it
it's all a proprietary closed software
with all the drawbacks soon drawbacks
so with very limited
ability and to impact the development
going to add some ideas
what else does a person trying to do for
might reverse engineering typically have
you can go towards white shark and other
traffic analyzes i am sure that most of
the energies have seen such a tools at
least ones in fact the it looks like a
dump and then some tree built out of it
and then there are pros and cons for all
socials
there are lots of wash of the sectors
that but they also one hundred percent
imperative and so they are very
difficult to implement even if you want
to start the investigation of a format
with writing at the sector
it's usually a bad idea because it
becomes too difficult to do it
there aren't so called EMS a also known
as maxscript also known as by no
maxscript also known as multi script
it's a family of specialized scripting
languages intended to derive data out of
binary files popular in the community
and doing a reverse engineering of games
so this is an example of a wild file but
again
there are two big problems about that on
the one hand this is indeed that is
indeed a good database of accumulated
former descriptions
there are lots of embedded algorithms
but it's imperative and it's only
intended to solve one problem
for instance in most cases it just to
take some file out of the container and
container and that's it
there are lots of other formats
there are lots of formats and it's not
going to dwell in them in detail
this is the so-called been pack which is
the declarative and compose into a c++
also extendable by c++ inserts
there are lots of academic projects are
written in different years and flashing
once and then gone now forever into the
limbo
now there's how the so-called and dev dl
forward in fact this is the closest
thing to what one with wish to have and
what would wish to work with its at the
clarity of format xml like it's trying
to describe the structure and basically
all the past few years in some tools
appears to you to use it but when I saw
the complexity of this
no formats well this picture here is
perhaps only three percent of the total
description of the file pick up
so when I saw that so it became
absolutely an interesting for me so it's
really a to general and its intended for
assaulting a more generic task have been
a lot of a task of attempts to create
the clarity descriptions of binary
structures as applied to one specific
language
so what do i want to present a day and
to share with him
ok I structure that we made
as follows from all the bomb is a
declarative language of binary data
structure description
we tried not to use imperative things at
the description in the case why former
is compiled into the source code of the
target language so we're initially
trying to get these so-called passes and
now we are supporting about five
languages at the output and basically
there's nothing standing in the way for
us to extend this list we have a
visualizer for now fast-forward
prototyping as a relay development
working with cat I struct does not even
touch the code and doesn't write the
code the script or some or anything else
until it's required until automation is
needed which looks very much like the
original in three base to visualize a
visualizer from other and I guess I
forward is basically the same as yellow
it's easy to write alternative compilers
and tools so you don't need some special
any special
editor's one other reminder how do what
format looked and header files
I'll payload so how can you describe it
and quite I struct first sir william
methods and they top level class is
going to call the doom dada which you
can see from the idea and then we
disassemble the format's reverse
engineer former just arrived from the
internet platform so by default all the
integers will be little indian and also
we write a comment application of
comments indicating a which software is
going to use this for months
then we have the sequence of attribute
descriptions so that go one by one all
these advocates will be read in this
sequence the beginning of the next one
is equal to the end of the previous
adjusted for alignment now let's see how
the attributes look out four of them a
line four bytes ASX coding magic in this
index and the school cutie cutie signed
into the gentle bites and same index
offset we have ID the I the identifier
that will be written in the codes
following the rules of the target
language is not to stand out and
examples are shown here how is going to
be a written in Java C sharp and Ruby
and there's a type
it's a type of indication it can be
primitive that's embedded it can be user
based so you can be absent in this case
it will be considered to be a byte array
without any interpretation the primitive
types integer or strings
integers are presented in the following
way
the first letter is unsigned or science
urs then we indicates specify the number
of bytes of this type and if needed
so we also indicated with signal to be a
little indian or big Indian strings
they're either known length in bytes of
symbols or there are strings a bit that
come before the Terminator in ninety
percent of cases
20 in see these are sea strings
sometimes before the dollar sign
no strings and rarely some other options
or are we are in the string to the ends
of the stream a file or the current sub
structure is valid so only the type s TR
and size 42 for the known length for up
to the Terminator we call type str said
and as a terminated oxa up till the end
of stream a type s TI and size us true
now we can use a kite I struct instances
these are almost the same as attributes
but indicating the patient Israel
position from where to read
they are indicated separately sequence
order is not important for them and
apart from other things apart from pasta
type that have already described their
on repeat and repeat expert we can set
the repeat of an attribute for some
fixed number of times by indicating this
in the expression or we can educate and
one ended
repeat up until the end of the string of
the stream and all we can indicate
specify some condition
I was small discussion to the
expressions that can be used of course
it's a special language that we have
introduced inside it automatically
translates in the target language
keeping the tire the types of the syntax
is similar to a an average see like
language and it can be used together
with such attributes for instance you
can say repeat expert 54 all these
languages it will mean repeat the
attribute five times you can indicate
repeat expert full bar which will need
to repeat the attribute that as many
times as indicated in the integer full
bomb attribute within the current type
of class
you can specify that the bar is the
attribute of the next class
compare it with the tea for a string and
it will correctly fascinating to the
target language you can have create some
more complex sophisticated conditions
related to SA or territory operator and
the right user types that show
that's a specified in the types column
it says the same a declaration or
announcement as in the three routes you
can use a sick into sin types
similar things but they are implemented
and the glasses and you can refer to
them after the task as a separate type
we can also note here and education to
IO root and the sky oh this is done so
that by default within the type
specified reading it should be done from
the string of the same time so we'll be
running about and refer to the beginning
of the index rather than to the
beginning of the file so we are
specifically indicated him that we're
going to take addresses from the start
of the three of 73
it all looks so quite difficult from the
first glance which in fact it isn't so
you can all be compiled it compiles with
a simple compiler a call and the input
we have a case file and the output in
this particular case a module for python
and you can immediately connected use we
import we can we use a the static method
from file in a little of the file and
after that we can address it directly
the fields of this class is not to read
this file we can ask the number of
elements the number of files in the
container getting it
we can ask the name in this particular
case of file 42 we can open up a file
and write the content of the file that
we want into it or we can look at it in
the visualizer in a visualizer and the
view would be very similar to the one in
hex a doors
yeah you can see the three you can see
the dump for the location of the dump
oh you can move
we'll see and move between dependencies
between elements so on so forth
so that's basically it I think thank you
yes this is it does so we have shown the
capabilities that lowers a pass
structures of fixed format with field
length depending on attributes and
computers from expressions with
conditional fields with feel repetitions
whatever from the start of the stream
with the women arbitrary set off set in
your own stream and in the third body
stream thank you
yeah yeah question
questions are welcome to ask a question
do you have the capability to process
the data transformation for instance we
have a data format you need to unpack it
and then
no data is some encrypted format and we
need to a process as a data imagine
their coding base64 so first you need to
decode it and then in code again
excuse me I can translate
so what's being said without a
microphone can you suggest that the
speaker presses the button
yeah
well my question is I'm sorry the
question I destruct is is it free
software always paid for it is free
can you please suggest the speaker to
press the microphone button because at
the interpret it doesn't hear what he's
saying
this software is distributed for apache
or met licenses and somewhere in get
love but do you have links where we can
download it here it is
thank you so much the question why did
you give up on TSN one for some reason
it was absent from the correct
comparison list it's also the clarity
and quite non-trivial protocol so use it
for instance to the entire telecom
business is based on an sn1 it's a long
story
to be brief because of high complexity
and less than ideal supportability of BI
tools
so perhaps what you mean is not is n1
about ACN one edr asn.1 itself as far as
I remember
obviously it's a whole family of formats
and for the most part
s & 1 when people refer to as one they
mean
also the RCR that generally speaking i
have almost no relation to this
these are just realization of formats
cumulus that carrying this game came up
with in the format that is so yeah that
would be my brief answer is it possible
to analyze the data compiled for
different platforms so that the
structures would be the same but the
data being represented in different ways
for different platforms for instance
Intel spark so reversing not only the
order of bytes in one attribute but also
the entire structure is there any switch
or a way to indicate there's a
capability to use this conditional
structure so that sour in the middle of
a decision making that for instance
further we're going to have a
substructure specifical intel or spark
so by the platform flag it appears in
so if there's some educated to the
specific platter specific platform the
indication and a file
yes and the data yes if in the day then
yes of course using this leg
you know you can can let's say a switch
passing to one instruction or the other
thank you thank you very much for your
presentation
please pick two questions that you like
most thank you
well in that case perhaps I will
and what its to the guy who asked about
processing
and perhaps the one to the guy who asked
about conditional processing
yeah thank you thank you very much