teach us another winter is your shadow
much right now
it's a night in the western hemisphere
is the modernist writers of all invited
mafia is keeping the way
so good morning ladies and gentlemen .
hello venus and mercury from kaspersky
lab I here we have gathered here just to
take a look at who plays for the Mafia
the actual effects of the technology
which was developed all the recent years
nice fire walls etc can result in only a
very well-known application can i
launched use the internet is the truth
not really that's the view of the
whitelist the concept which has been
reincarnated in different ways you with
this year by community firewalls white
leases and applications we are not
perfect
illogical and the drugs and logically
you cannot split the black and the white
yes we did Charles really did you ever
try to get all the doors close to you
yeah yeah yeahs anymore I did
all I did
sometimes you failed nothing in the
childhood but now I done really well
developed a few criteria and martinis
you know if three applications out of
the white list so if there is an
application with a trusted certificate
if you download
malware you should be analyzed would
take some statistics we check what are
the applications connected to the
suspicious service and download
something they were trusted applications
section
what we ended up with was this the
result for a few months for detecting
approximately 30,000 protections from
different computers and servers located
or 90 from the world are
it's a global problem
we were trying to find out how these
applications turn out to be the airwheel
thinking about the vulnerabilities
direct hijacking would wear found is
that a large number of applications
no whitelist for analysis where
applications years with containing the
browser components
one of the popular years you know models
you are you here his system remains
later
internet explorer components do you know
how it happened
let's get this . an actual factor in
this functionality and the erp systems
go
we think this analysis for their own
name is injected the cold into an
earpiece system
the system was going to post terminal we
hear those cards i will send to the
processing center and the copy of data
were sent to the hawkers hear from you
and your dumb cat version eight six
o'clock in the morning
they have been a still asleep I did
would connect to this address
download on 65 and how was it was not a
zip file per se
yeah
it was launched in an executive file a
good application sometimes
do not download executive files normally
date download scripts and I'm really
honest they launch another file a
with the dll files and for the both
movie file and trips and do not acquire
are downloading suspicious executive
files again he might be necessary on my
scale
well download a lot of files
and more files exact files and your name
well for some reason for some reason to
be somebody else the place with a model
and we're in the lies that you know the
first category was deed or supports he
does bought so far different types of
almost all of them you were made in
China
they're not huge
it was all the hostess the SQL server
I was watching the server yeah going
under throughput capacity was quite big
but it might be easy
it was in between there are no last
grills and also the data which is stored
at those service
it does the decryption and the utility
pop some of the server which allows you
to play with the database and they
exploit the role of vulnerabilities
that's on the one on the other hand the
exploitation of vulnerabilities was not
the first one via for instance very
often
they used direct hide chicken instead
here and we detected a number of cases
one either download in we see
instruments populated even now if you go
back to them with mass media and how
direct I chicken is used there will be
going back to the incident investigation
with the D does bought so just sent here
for ddos attacks 2013 13
that was not they would brute force we
want
you know what you must be quite active
layer in 2015
there was some information that those
were the people who are usually dll
substitute methods you here is
substituted by the UDF libraries and
mysql so it was direct hijacking and
such
we all right let us think about that
we need to mention that it is a very
popular technique
along with the Chinese all of them by
using such methods
what does it look like there is an
archived with the executive file
he and the dll file in it which looks
innocent
yeah but you know there's a trick in
there
it has a profile night it has a proper
export you know one problem exactly what
the file is launched shirt recognizes
the dll and download this just does not
look delicious
animation or just blows this code from
the dll file the address space for you
mom
as far as you can see it
it does not really look like a very
malicious activity
this is a very effective solution and it
works
this is how all the heresy starts in the
system
number three and how the malicious
software gets into this list when the
operator the administrator the user is
downloaded in torrance with the bat file
inside a very popular case with
accumulated some statistics on
well applications from different lists
downloading malicious software from
India China and Russia all these three
countries are notorious for using the
free version self different software was
a cracked version of different software
by using payloads we figured out that it
was really popular in china chinese do
some doors bolts etc
he is this hijacking we walk in
massively yeah yeah
through those whitelist applications
that they either use d else or they do
not use exact files or the DLLs oh
really using scripts and the embedded
utilities and I they would still be
using some power shell and West scripts
to pull out some information
those of you who are warned to armed
protected
what do you do two more DLL hijacking
chicken
so first World analyze your software
hardware utilities applications that can
actually show the deal hijacks it still
remains a very relevant solution that
it's not exactly so we're on the
inventory and we limit these
applications their internet access
traffic accident where do we find the
magic bullet
white list defaulting on deny there is a
magic bullet there is such a solution of
laser technology and it's even affected
from the other hand we still have some
human error
you
we're going to use to purchase and was
definitely the correct way
how simply nice around mafia with the
city but to help the dancing around will
be 1 by peaceful citizens
thank you very much what processor
yeah
spicy was in serious and thoughtful
mystical think a lot like to clarify
this
about linux
do you have such solutions for linux you
mentioned into mysql but also related to
Windows you can do it
here it is
actual idea would be exactly the same
so infuriating
we don't have the real cases here thank
you
when each other
the quad what was both a coke addict
statistic a with amber color statistical
time school teacher what I want to come
over from Christina pogo the worst ever
and Christina I came over somewhere
somebody with sits slightly to the
traffic um is not only on a teacher
sistema or which they're kind of pipes
much substance
I keep watching a movie with protective
about me just or interruptions in your
potatoes tablets occur
we lost a motorcycle you don't like your
sunglasses but I'm websites for not for
some closure and usually the Scorpions
rainia don't suppose it wasn't
prosecuted
we're treating low easy to get to meet
alena now completed state again
it's a tie game to you in a couple hours
in your potential t-shirts occur
you're putting your wish to 177 against
Leeds the tracker , structure to you
want to concentrate on your work but be
shared components traffic yes the
professional pic to the back for a
Bielecki that or against that she had me
motorboat of epidemiological data lost
apparently 00 financial struggles a
boost your career
our store about us giving us the Messiah
your depression yet to win a bit early
across a particular individuals could
incite them the liberal agenda ,