how many people here that are running
operations facilities have ever picked
up a geographical map and looked at your
area and said where are the common
transportation routes that one disaster
might knock out yeah a lot of people
have it there was the fire in the
Baltimore tunnel a couple years ago it
took out huge amounts of capacity
because especially as you get more into
suburban areas there may just be one
physical path and the only way you're
going to be able to work around it is
possibly satellite now whether that's
something you want to promise your users
whether you have an insurer that will
support that I don't know but these are
things to look at now let's talk about
voice over IP specifically what breaks
well the first thing that will break you
know usually is on the customer premises
and that can be any number of things you
know Howard that they have you know is
it an analog phone that plugs into a
set-top box is it that they've got an IP
phone most often before I eventually
threw away our IP phone and there is a
guy was working it refused to put a tftp
server in the local machine so every
time there wasn't a momentary power
outage I lost the default route and the
the IP telephone couldn't get its code
any longer uh depending on what you're
putting on site or in the neighborhood
say if you've got fiber to a
neighborhood and you've got a pedestal
in it it's not a bad idea to consider if
you've got the pedestal to put maybe a
DHCP and tftp server in there because
you know you lose neighborhood power
everything is down and if they can't get
beyond your point you know their host
pdx is our another problem one of the
things I have found is that if you are
going to any fair sized enterprise it's
unusual
well that you can throw out all of their
voice equipment chances are for example
they've got a maybe a voice messaging
system that they like and they don't
want to throw it away if you are dealing
with anything in the air safety or
aviation industry they have their own
unique ARINC defined for wire analog
circuit or adapter that nothing else in
the world sports so basically what you
need to start thinking about is you go
to them and say what do you have here
what are things that won't be scored and
then start thinking about how do you
give them a t1 equivalent out of your
premises router and that usually will be
adequate is is tell them that's a t1 and
they can live with that but if you try
to make some things like a large Rhydian
say message switch or a conferencing
bridge they've spent a lot of money on
you know they're just not willing to do
that the next thing that happens is how
do you firewall voice over IP and that
depends there are two ways of peering
voice over IP one is it used to ordinary
bgp puri and you let the voice sessions
keep up with each other if however you
want stateful failover that you might
normally do in a net or a firewall that
won't happen you tend to need a session
border controller function which is
basically a stateful firewall you can't
have more security in it but that's
basically what it does and it
understands sip and essentially can
access sip proxy there turn out to be a
lot of reasons when you have a soft
switch in there that are other common
elements that you contract out for now
traditionally your regular telco cub
facilities we had the ss7 network and
they got their directory assistance over
that they got their local number
portability their 800 look up their 911
all came in there the chances are
whether you're an enterprise with the
coil manager and
don't need local number portability but
you need something or if you're bringing
in a soft switch you don't have ss7
connectivity most of the time to that
instead what you need is a third-party
sip vendor tends to be the way you do it
so even if you have no customers that
have their own voice over IP you still
may need to have one or two session
border gateways in your operation center
so you can continue having the necessary
operations support thing billing you
know again people often out take their
their soft switch and they run their
bill into a third-party provider local
number portability 800 look up all these
things there are now service bureaus
that do these probably cheaper that you
can do yourself if you're a large not a
very large facility but again think
about the failover mechanisms the hazard
upstream talk to you and I'm sure by now
in a telco sense one system I dealt with
recently was kind of interesting is they
are a company that actually owns a very
large amount of the fiber in southwest
and they have a couple of small telcos
that they provide on it but they've got
thousands of miles of now OC 192 fiber
and they sell bandwidth and I said okay
well how do you communicate your they
are not going to go though with anything
like local sip local voice over IP they
bring it to channel banks and only then
then they put it on to a sonnet ring and
then they just as a stub and feed that
to the OC 192 network the way they
actually connect upstream is they have a
central office which that does nothing
but talk to their interests change
carriers in and at that point you can
talk to that switch expects gr 303 which
is the X bell core specification for TDM
to your environment so when the people
start bringing that up it's probably a
typical sonnet or ATM interface but
again what they often have to talk to
their up streams is regular telco
equipment it may be a small switch but
it's a telco switch and it doesn't know
about IP does not spell it so what again
you wind up doing is you may give it
some ds1 Sordi s3's and it understands
that and soft which can produce it out
of its media gateway one of the critical
things that goes on ok well that is
light blue and light blue is that if you
look at the architecture of most self
switches today they are split into two
basic functions there is the call agent
the does the call agent actual call
processing find the trunk so on and then
you'll bunch of media gateways and the
media gateway depending maybe actually
oppose the plug into them it may be g1's
the whole idea of a media gateways
programmable and it's got different
interface cards you can have regular TD
unplugging into that you could have
Ethernet is going into them so on but
that's you're essentially you're you're
next for want of a better term and they
have to go to someplace intelligent to
find out how to write a call and that's
the call agent Park what happens is that
anyone remember going back to when we
had nice fast nice going to fit bps
lines and you are bridging and you have
root wars that the root in two different
places because timing reasons would
decide hi I'm the root of the spanning
tree and you notice a no I'm the root
and they'd sit there fighting each other
that's exactly what happens now in so
switches is that they typically have
redundant call agent boards in a single
enclosure but what in general if you try
to get say ok I've got two main central
offices so I'll put one call agent board
in each one this is often not a good
idea unless for example the last time we
did this and everyone involved was
comfortable than it would work is we had
two mile apart OC 192 facility between
the two locations and they had actually
and failover strands on it one of the
big mysteries not given out of soft
switches is if they have multiple call
agents and the call agents get out of
sync you have the whole system thrashing
for control the way several vendors do
it is they run essentially the RRP
between them and this gets interesting
as well because typically if you two
different sites and children's in town
you probably route between them but
routing doesn't work if it's going to be
the same subnet so you often have to
have layer one or a layer 2 connectivity
between your central offices otherwise
you know if they're built into the sauce
which VRP to figure out which call age
is detective or even if you've read out
and call agent boards in two separate
machines you'll typically have one set
of the RV in each room and then one that
goes between the data centers and one of
the hardest things that turns out in
these cases is to get below layer 3
connectivity because PGD Abbott's at the
way to do it you often need to run
facilities or you may wind up saying no
I will accept the risk of losing one
facility and one call agent because the
probability of the voice over IP network
going completely crazy because it's got
unsynchronized call agents is probably
higher than losing one of your central
offices so think long and hard of how
your central offices are interconnected
unless you have absolutely bulletproof
lines between them essentially set them
up as master slave padule call agents in
the soft switch in one of them but don't
try to spread them across the two lock
two facilities unless you control the
physical facilities in between it's just
not something you can trust to let out
video is another problem first how does
the video come into your facility
satellite feed maybe modder places that
will be the case could have come down to
you digitized yeah
but remember that if you've got HDTV or
so on you've got multi-bit gigabit rates
coming down if this viber coming into
you fine but if not one of the things
you have to do is go out there and start
saying okay am I getting this on a
satellite what can break with the
satellite do i know that if there's a
wind and it gets out of alignment can I
put it back sometimes yes sometimes no
depends on the size oh one of the
specific problems ran into Iraq was that
now is allowed at least all the base I
know there's only one contractor that's
allowed to put in vsat dishes because it
gets windy enough out there and with the
sandstorm with it being abrasive then
unless you know exactly how to tie down
that satellite dish it turns into a
lethal frisbee apparently this is
actually often you know thing is you're
not wearing that people should have
worse and rockets you're wanting because
the things they don't have enough range
to get to you the satellite dishes do
and I've seen if Higgins one was a
humping had about a one meter dish sunk
about a footage with side and I could
picture out on the Great Plains and so
on you getting winds like that so if
you've got a small dish be very sure if
someone knows how to install it that
it's failsafe or you know that it's you
know the equivalent you've got it
unchain because a high wind or tornado
certainly you know can launch the things
and since there's somewhat aerodynamic
they start floating and when they hit
they hit hard you will also obviously to
feed you got your streams coming in but
to distribute your customers you need
multicast I don't understand why this is
but I have found with small telcos that
want to start dealing with video you
start saying okay here's your head end
and you multitask Andhra they say what's
multicast then the other thing is that
I've noticed
you get it to the last router before the
distribution network or a switch that's
feeding into that now typically they've
had someone go in and let's say it's a
diverse area so they set up him or
whatever the multicast routing is the
whip usually anyone that's close enough
to set that up it's fine where the
problem comes in as they don't know how
to set up igmp and they don't know how
to set up a multicast static route in
their last hop router so if you get cold
did these tend to be the first places to
look last 3-4 times that there was
supposed to be a video turn up but we
get called and nothing worked we tell
made it into the router and you said
excuse me here's here's the head end
this is where your multicast is coming
in these are your interfaces there's
nothing in between them the router
doesn't know how to get there it's not
that it's direct connected as you know
yeah but these were unicast and you just
plugged it in everything would work
because it's direct an act multicast and
that way pick a group thing has to get
igmp and pay SD igmp upstream to ever
the multicast routing takes place and
it's just not a telco its concept so if
you deal with the telco trying to a
video one of the first things you want
to sit down and be sure they understand
the ramifications for multicast just the
same way is if you're dealing with an
ISP that starting out voice over IP they
don't understand typically the
reliability requirement for voice
another question is if you have video on
demand is that something that's an
upstream provider so you have to have
some sort of upstream communications pea
so they can know okay you've just joined
his multicast group or do you have to
have servers on site well if your
servers on site remember if you've got a
few hundred channels you might want to
listen to and a couple hours but that is
a big disk so you have to consider those
things that be aware on that
and the same way is you will have people
trying to steal service it doesn't
matter if they put in more equipment to
cost them more than subscribing it's not
as much fun now one of the questions is
how do you know about a disaster well if
it's dirty flap if you're on nsp set you
will get early warning but actually
we're around here you know this is the
whole idea of your peering contacts so
on if your start seeing multiple places
going down it may be worth some phone
calls and saying you know what's going
on and I don't care what your boss
thinks of heavier TV set or two in and
up have one always on CNN and on the
weather channel and be sure that you
will you put them in even though it
might not be good even though you
normally feed them with cable guess what
put an outside antenna on them emergency
services may call you now one of the
things that you can have happening is it
may be that ranging anywhere from a
threatened damn to a fire that's getting
out of control one of the things may
very well be especially you've got a
reasonably hard enough is good idea to
talk to your fire and EMS people ahead
of time to see if you could be a mutual
assistance to each other there was a
situation during Katrina where they had
to make one very hard decision on
England's of the right one apparently
there was one really big inner toll
telephone switch office in downtown New
Orleans and somewhere else was a chilled
water facility supplying it and as the
waters came up they lost their chilled
water and they made a conscious decision
to pull a fire engine off an active
working fire to go over to feed water to
those dvds that if you know if you lose
or upstream and then you also did this
for one of the ISPs that you know if
your show water you can lose
and chilled water gave more and more
popular so it may be something we're
ahead of time having a long talk with
the fire department and say you may be
dependent on communications coming
through this facility maybe you want to
dispatch them or maybe you just have a
booster pump but you could give us the
kind you know they use if they're
drawing water from a river in couple of
intermediate hops they often have things
that go on the back of pickup and that
may be enough for your purposes another
thing that I guess I knew one day when I
was I don't know if I you know and it's
always the distinction of you nerd or a
geek or which but whatever it was I was
fairly high-ranking one and development
organization and I just had a nice
window office you know I found out there
was a snowstorm going outside the job
was couldn't see through somebody sent
an email uh it really is a good idea to
look outside occasionally uh now that I
was for weather conditions but fires or
another thing and one of the things we
learned out of 9 11 and this is actually
something that's I don't lanciano nanog
mailing lists but has come out to be a
problem that most people don't think of
now in New York what happened is the
high reliability providers had a week's
worth of diesel for their generators in
South Manhattan and you know they hadn't
made arrangements with police and fire
even was blocking they would get
shipments in before they were out of
fuel but within 24 to 48 hours their
generators started quitting anyone know
why dust and it turns out this is not as
obscure it's not just the Twin Towers
cuz da knows where in some conversation
said she that happened to us in
Northwest when we had mount st. Helens
and then I talked a friend who is in an
interior area and British Columbia and
they have their completely ring by
forests and a bad forest fire can do
this to you the air filter may cost $15
but no one was sparing them
and even if you have a local fire but
say in a chemical warehouse or something
which is putting out a lot of soot that
could be enough to jam your generator so
it's some of the cheapest 15 $25 Ian's
been is keep a couple extra air filters
and also remember if things quit that
may be the reason another thing
depending on your location is that
generators are safe enough nobody's
going to pick them up and steal them
generally that is not true however of
the starter battery would someone can
take off with a couple of bolt cutters
and get money for the net a rock of
crack it is always a good idea to keep
at least one spare starter battery
inside and a locked room trickle charged
and of course put a fence around the
generator may or may not help you but
there's losing things with it now if
you'll turns out and let me come back to
fuel business links to the gun it when
you want to talk to your providers and
your customers look at all the ways of
communication you have guaranteed at
least two of them will go out so it may
be that you know you might be overloaded
on on cellular telephone and I have a
way out of that which we'll get to but
it may be the short message service
works when you can't get dial tone for
Cole pagers may work we also dealt with
this a lot in hospitals um there is I am
on the trauma and critical care mailing
list of the site of trauma fellows and
there were some major issues like
Houston try to get itself tremendously
ready for Rita but they still wind up
with situations where the ambulances
couldn't talk to the hospital and so on
they were variously they had no common
frequency or some of the things they
need elected the power company all they
had was the ability to phone them there
was none
else no one had ever thought of having
it even though the power company itself
has its own radio network put it you
know the ideas if you're a hospital if
you're in enough if you are in a power
company talk to your other critical
infrastructure people and said do you
have your own private radio for example
they often do said good can I get on
your network for emergency use and they
said gee yeah we're the power company we
might have a power pole tip over and
someone yeah we'd like to be able to get
directly through to the emergency room
so you know it's just people haven't
thought about this now here's one of
your problems again with telephone is
everybody says 800 numbers what happens
if you lose the 800 database nope or if
someone's trying to call you tube it was
listen I cfb you remember those a few
years back somebody in Israel no did in
a s 7007 they redistributed to sprint
Europe out to everybody else in the
Middle East at least to talk to them and
what I heard the way that cuts off was a
little informal situation as the
comedian was swollen up that the guy
that was up watching his knock meltdown
went out looked up the owner of the
other isp which had no night coverage
and he was hauled off by police the
potential terrorists be he was scared of
heights apartment door pounding on it
said I'm going to teach you how dr.
redistribute EG fake but it did solve a
problem oh look satellite phones can be
useful now there's an interesting
landline it's obviously go down cellular
may go down cellular may not and or you
may be in a special category how many
people here are on guests WPS how many
have heard of them ah wwn CSCO
national communication system now it
used did anything ever knew anyone
remember every calling someone on area
code seven-ten I'll bet you haven't
because 710 is the unlisted area code
that is what you what happens is I
forget what the acronym stand for gets
is the priority on on landline used to
be that you dialed 710 and you got a
prefix code and that by piss is although
controlling the telephone network oh why
don't you this is wireless priority
system which is again it is something
weird signals the switches you have to
get these government approved it's not
that hard it's just that you know
basically communications providers are
considered national critical
infrastructure so if you want to get a
gets line for your NOC you're not going
to get a lot of grief about that I know
all the people on the cisco and SP SWAT
teams have in fact the wireless phones
because they wasn't just asked her about
it is a she had nsp said her own cell
phone the WPS cellphone a page or I
looked at her person it was like looking
into frys uh you know I wonder do you
have money in there anywhere or it just
seems to be all communications equipment
uh anyway gets his a sip will you fill
out some applications you talk to them
this units I was involved with an ass
communication system when it was under
the Defense Department and what it has
the Charter is for emergency
communications restoration the original
goal was in the event of nuclear war how
did you start to reconstitute critical
services oh it's now on Homeland
Security which meant at least during
Katrina and Reno while they tried you
two things the FCC being independent of
Homeland Security wound up doing the
emergency priority management because
the NCS people were allowed into the
operation center you know it was a
problem but anyway with gets know what
it is there is a pair
I understand either there are actually
both 809 800 numbers you get a card that
has a access code on a smart card or not
but essentially what you do is that then
you get put into area code seven-ten
where you are and no matter what load
control is present this Mother's Day or
whatever you will not get a reorder fast
busy tone you will get through and you
know hospitals can get this to again the
Emergency Operations Center in Houston
didn't know it existed and that was for
the whole county and that has been top
general hospital which is one of the
trauma centers wireless party system is
new it used to be for just one wireless
provider and now they've got a couple on
it if you get the phone also it will be
a secure wireless phone ah the way that
they do it is it one it has regular
priority attention and probably sell
protocols know about is don't block this
call of other stuff is coming through
but apparently what happens is that if
you have a major out of blood norleans
you might have lost your local two or
three cell towers the WPS phones we're
still getting through because they had
to priority signal so the other cells
started listening for them I don't think
you'd go up with power or not but I know
they have been working on this problem
that may it looks like a regular phone
but it's actually a government crypto
with an unclassified encryption unit in
and all those same size in the other
cell phone they're still experimenting
with us but these can get issued and I
don't know how only issuance time is
gets I don't think case long at all to
get onto once you satisfy some of your
significant communications provider and
in particular if any your local
emergency services hospitals would ever
go through you even for internet access
that's a legitimate requirement there is
a a system called a dms services or DM
is services a disaster management
interoperability service which for some
reason no one has ever explained to me
is
the URL fort is www cm is you know for
some reason it's CM eyes work they
couldn't get a date I don't know why but
what this is is it's a open system
essentially its government free code
that Mabel can get runs under windows
extensible object-oriented that runs
essentially the incident command system
which is the standardized procedure of
oil fire and emergency from local to
national to deal the major event and the
systems have gotten very interesting on
this they have now they were giving them
satellites and they still are because
what you can do on now the edema systems
they get it up for example on the dirty
bomb test at Boeing Field in Seattle
there was a trial of it to give you an
idea what this thing can do and again if
your local people haven't heard of
demons you may want to go talk to your
emergency operation system because what
will happen is they started out and said
okay here a couple laptops they're
projecting the idea and they put up the
area of supposedly the immediate
contamination with a street map and said
this is where the radiation source and
said okay and then they put all the fire
trucks on hunt with the fire chief said
hey that's not done too big and they
said okay what are you going to do next
guys and said what do you mean you've
got a radioactive cloud what are you
going to do with it and then they
started hitting some more keys and
literally they've been given us
requirement give you on getting
extensibility the software two weeks
before the event the next thing they did
is they pulled in the EPA's toxic cloud
dispersion model and got a lie National
Weather Service report and they
predicted where the cloud was going to
go and and then he said oh well yeah but
how do we decide where to evacuate
instead gotcha they then did and this is
across the internet went to the census
and they said what time of day do you
want us to assume and they said well
let's say it's not so good and a
highlighter all the apartment houses
hotels and hospitals in the area that
would be high density housing they said
daytime here your high density office
buildings
these are where you need to go to and
then they slap the satellite photo on
top and said this is where the plume
will get blocked by a hill so you get
time to get there or that is a
collection point they went beyond that
then and said they have essentially the
equivalent of ebay on there except for
emergency services it started out and
said you know I'm fire department I need
more air tanks or a compressor they now
have a system on it where we'll go out
on the internet essentially people much
like on ebay bid is say hey I've got an
extra compressor truck in a hundred
Scott air packs you need them and the
you then look at who's close to you and
get it so these are some of the things
is now if you're a local fire department
doesn't know that exists and you're
willing to get them connected to that
you think you're going to prom maybe
getting an emergency generator or water
pumped from them one hand washes the
other in this stuff but again I very
rarely trying to think it was this his
go or down a presentation uh for those
of you in Cisco or uses one a one
contact for guests and WPS is Wendy
Garvin or I think if you just call up
though the NCS people they'll start you
on the process you know it's just mostly
it's not a big deal as no one's ever
heard of them this is after what your
service level agreement is now when you
go triple play what you need to start
thinking about is that is this but let's
put this one someone picks up you know
you got all dial-up customer how many
times dial custom order am I going to
get connected to AOL or whatever but
someone goes to the phone well be your
average ginger and say there'd better be
dial tone in that phone they pick it up
there's often right and I you know
secondly one class of mine I said is
there dial tone in the phone you haven't
picked it up and he said I'm said well
is the light on your refrigerator where
the doors closed and suppose it I know
he said good how do you know
Chuck well the light bulb burned out
less you are never replaced it but the
reality is dial tone is saying hi I'm
the phone network I recognize you and
that is not exactly the level of
expectation people of head when they've
been ISPs that it's always going to be
there and this gets vehicle thing that's
about a hundred forty years ago when
Alexander Graham Bell decided he wanted
an order for delivery pizza and had
realized he had intended telephone first
but in 140 years the telcos may not have
learned a lot of stuff what they have
learned a lot about his emergency
restoration sometimes they don't get it
right one of the my all-time favorites
was a blacked out of region they had got
50,000 years were out of New York is it
was summer and extremely hot and con had
the power utility yes anybody that's got
their own generators could you shed load
and go on to your own supply and okay uh
yeah he also had 48 hours worth a
battery behind that so they figured
we'll be okay now at some point or
another though it was still going on i
was getting end of the 48 hours they
were start the battery that one
generators had died the batteries were
starting to go low and they had loud
alarm bells that went off when this have
all they knew just look throw the
transfer switch and get back on utility
power however there was no one there to
hear the bell and why was that because
this was in the old bell system everyone
in operations was attending a manual a
mandatory seminar on high availability
so yeah I mean this is one of the things
again try to talk to the health of
people and again there's a lot more
awareness of this none or a terrorist
situation one I started as biochemist
and some of the things that I see with
with chemical plants and transit scare
me you know much more than things like
did you taste in point if you've got a
railroad line anywhere near you in world
war one when the Germans first attacked
with chemical weapons
they use 160 tons of chlorine on an
8,000 meter front that killed almost
everybody on it cool now there are tank
cars the chlorine its water purification
it's around everywhere the standard to
track our sizes that go around on
railroads carrying chlorine are 90 and
55 tons what if one do rails or even
better what if jurors puts it into a
tank round into one of them you've got a
mile that may be lethal without
protective gear so that's one thing to
consider that you know again it may even
be in some cases if you know you're near
a chemical plant you may want to hit
hazmat gear in the knock it because you
may need to just to get out miscs
foremost camino for industrial chemicals
aren't that bad and then again they're
unforeseen consequences a a lot of water
systems are converting to use
chloramines which were not nearly as
talk glory all and that's a nice idea it
works taste a little better and so on
but one thing that nobody thought about
chloramines happen to be excellent rust
inhibitors and I was either Tucson or
Phoenix I forget the first few cities
that went into had the ceramic ware
pipes and this city had cast iron which
was held together by the rust and as
soon as they caught a reward
purification all the streets were
exploded so when you start saying
something for a voice what's your
service level agreement for voice well
at least where i work for nortel only
we're doing carrier switches the rule
was once up always up and that is the
telco attitude so if an ISP starting
over phone services you know it's not
just that you can't reach 911 because
maybe you don't have a 911 service in
there and says you can't phone anywhere
this is a liability issue there I never
want to be in a house for example that
only has unless it's multi-home voice
over IP at least one a cell phone
because you know it's like someone's
morse code or even better than the army
saying about a handgun is you only need
a pistol when you need one very very
very much so again mission-critical data
will whose mission is that you know some
online shopping facility or is that the
emergency communications for the
regional emergency dispatch you may have
you know you may want to find out when
you get on to get sore WPS find out who
else around is on it yours might be out
but the thing is you need in your
locality build up a people network of
the emergency services and do it ahead
of time the FBI will help out in this to
some extent in that they have now been
asked to be consultants on to brief ISPs
ahead of time if you have a major attack
of some sort on your facilities you know
collect so since not all offices have
people that know about communications
they will let you know where is the
nearest office I mean let's face with
some if you closest it wait a minute
where's my typewriter what's this thing
with this TV said in front of me ah but
there one thing but talk your local
police fire so you may dig around find
your communications people and come up
with you in fire service this is called
mutual aid and it's something that for
some reason I hp's will call it each
other and help each other but they don't
necessarily recognize that the regular
emergency services may be able to
provide that kind of help and again if
you're going to triple play business
nobody really cares if the gaming system
goes they're gonna gripe about but if
it's something like I'm still for
example we have the hospital hospital
system on there they use the cable
system there for their medical education
medical dispatch I am told that the way
that it works out that every so often
just to be sure that civilians don't
watch it you know like every half hour
you know they show somewhat doing
hemorrhoid surgery or something and
scares everyone away and
zeppelins are supposed to watch now this
again what is being expected how much
reliability out one of the interesting
things this is the blast door to
cheyenne mountain and they have i decide
to go to close they'll keep it inactive
there will be a small staff in there for
quite a while or basically since the
Soviets head yes s18 missile a try and
mount was no longer in vulnerable but
they didn't a cost-benefit said you know
inside this mountain it's cold in here
and they demonstrated how much they
saved on air conditioning power but they
finally decided that now that they've
got that what was formerly the Space
Command is now the Northern Command and
he has domestic responsibilities they
wanted more office space and so on so
now they've moved it to the outside area
at Peterson Air Force Base but they have
a different way of looking at things for
example their idea of backup power this
if I'm you see it goes way off into the
haze in the distance those are still
generators going back for 60 day supply
now is this something that expect well
how long does some expect you to stay up
and just like it's happened apparently
people were proactive in Manhattan with
the telcos there and the ISPs is the
Fire and Police Department said you have
a generator we know about that one
because a fire hazard and to do you need
how much detail do you have and Mike
unity of a police escorted refill after
a week or something so those plans were
all in place how many of you are in a
situation where you have diesel is if
you give them 48 hours a week if there's
a major disaster is there some way that
a convoy can get into you there are a
number of factors that come into power I
one is obviously if you can come off
more than one substation uh there was
one now is interesting I always have
favorite power story was I believe
science building at Stanford and a lot
of places gives it a pop and comments is
going on diesels and it is to
substitution feeds it was about as good
as you can get but then about three in
the morning once there was some of these
great big bang flash lights went out and
people running out to the smoke and
there was the little fragments of beauty
like Bert meat coming down well it
turned out there was a big mechanical
power transfer switch among the three of
them and a pair of rats set up
housekeeping inside and started doing
rats thing when they want lots of little
rats and shall we say there was a dead
short and it took out about three feet
of buzz bar not wire rigid copper you
know how you're going to get that fixed
at three o'clock at the boarding and son
started complaining because it turned
out what they said we're disconnected
from the internet well turned out son
was single home to that site on the
theory well they put so much backup
they'll never be down anyway diesel fuel
has got a shelf life there are several
factors most of which is it tends to
collect water in the bottom so you need
to keep turning it over it's also from
my I'm not a mechanical person but but
people told me about generator motors
you really should run them about once a
week for 10 minutes be sure the bearings
are all fine and the starting battery is
OK and you'll use up some fuel and you
just simply want more fuel deliveries
every so often so you might as well use
it up because I think it best in the
last two to three years now we're
talking the batteries and air filters
and fencing here's an interesting
question and again this is something
happened to Katrina and at least one
place actually and thought about this
one of the hospitals had its generators
on a mid-level of its parking garage
what they had done though is they put
for various reasons and good reasons
they put the fuel tanks on the ground of
them well the water was up between the
second and third story of there and they
still had power to keep up so was it you
know it's not a question of refilling
those tanks is what happens if you
sucking on a fuel tank and there's
nothing coming in as far as air you have
been and here they actually were smart
enough to do what they do on commercial
ocean-going oil tankers they ran through
a cooler and they vented the exhaust of
the generator back into the fuel tanks
which now puts a blank of an inert gas
on top of it and also if you do that is
if you're you know in Minneapolis or
something you may need to have diesel
tank heaters but if you recirculate the
exhaust gets into it not only does it
keep a vacuum forming not only to
protect you against fire will help keep
faisal warm now I'm sure they're
probably cold climates where we need to
chill the diesel but those are the ones
that running into them so rising water
is one thing is believe it or not if
they're built for it properly and
they're vented if they're either to the
air or to the exhaust line your fuel
tanks will continue to work underwater
there are issues about though how high
you want them to be or what is under
them uh I keep getting different stories
about what happened to World Trade
Center 94 70s was that you know I've
heard different levels of how high they
were the main diesel tanks were at
ground level but they had supplementary
tanks at least up to the ninth floor now
the emergency operation center was above
that but I think right now there's a lot
of research going on about how high is
it safe to put even a backup tank also
your problems like this with your
uninformed power systems if they have
the liquid electrolyte now this is not
followed too often but the National Fire
Protection code I believe says you do
not put liquid electrolyte batteries
above the third story otherwise you're
too much danger of acid electrolyte
pouring down on the rescue force so here
you may have some things as a you may
need if you really want to keep going
you may want to think of something other
than a liquid
to light up and then it's the case with
the rats you need to figure out is there
any common point people don't usually
think that switch with a you know
elaborately through like that would
break but it did okay now availability
as a mentioned is something that is a
relative thing and you have to remember
the real experts on rules it's always a
good idea to give a Ferengi in sales
you've got a difference in business
services and commercial and residential
so on what's the parrot availability is
it quota made the visit they ever work
late do you have maintenance windows how
about for voice over IP or TV not just
the amount of volume is it's got to be
up all the time and when it comes can
you have a way of providing resources
and is there a situation where if it
you're up links are partially destroyed
let's say you're getting a video feed
from someone is it possible if that's
physically diversely right on different
fiber in an emergency situation might
you preempt that and get that hooked up
to a telephone feed at the other end
it's been done also another thing to
consider peace Levario to virginia and
remember that cable tru TV franchises
are normally on a city or a county basis
but very often it may be one company or
just sometimes because of zoning and
where you put the large satellite dishes
all the headings or near each other so
even though it's not called for if you
get together with cable providers though
often interconnect they're not allowed
by carapace and TV over it but for
internet that's usually not territory
voice they can get that connectivity and
they may even have satellite uplinks no
matter what you do though
there are going to be failures in the
local loop of cable or so on and you
know it gets sometimes when you call for
help I think the thing that's most
annoyed me about outages on cable is
when they've got you on hold for too
young 30 minutes or so which is more out
frustrating saying your call is very
important to us or to their saying if
you go to our self-help site on the web
I go back and forth I'm usually ready to
kill what I have found is they used to
in comcast and I found that their second
level center is in Halifax Nova Scotia
so you if you get someone really
clueless at first local ask for
escalation and then sound Canadian or
say something about hockey or something
and suddenly they can't do enough for
you but one of the things you may want
to even for home offices this something
I'm very actively considering doing is
that can I get can you is let's say
you're a cable provider and that's what
you're providing broadband even though
that your competitor can you strike a
deal with a local telco saying that will
you give us a bulk discount if we
multi-home sites on your dsl some nice
deals have been cut and it's kind of
win-win for everybody I mean yeah
Kayla's going to be faster but the thing
is they are physically diverse media
other than yeah maybe coming out of the
building but once you get out of the
street they're going to be quite diverse
you hope excuse me that is that again
maybe not a giant phone company but if
you're going and let's say you are
providing cable broadband you go to your
local business office of your telco
that's providing dsl and say we
guarantee to buy so much bandwidth s
back up from you will you give us a cut
rate on that and they say what is it and
these are sites we've already lost you
so sure that gives us back a good deal
or but thing is that if you find the
right merci
caring enough people if you're a cable
carrier you may get very good telephone
service rates and vice versa and the way
to sell it to them is convincing them
that they otherwise would have lost any
revenue out of it these are the typical
now getting into the various kinds of
threats is you know if you're doing
hosting what happens you know you have
single failure server failures I'll show
you some things we did with interesting
hosting center not long but you have to
make some of the decisions if you post
or servers at one site is it hot standby
warm stateful standby or cold standby
before you say throw out cold stand by
one of the sites i work with are
deliberately has a they have to due
process or cisco 75 hundreds at each
site one is cold the reason they have
the duo are ESPYs and everything in one
of them so they figure that's safe you
don't fail over but the extra one is
they can do Mike the code or iOS
upgrades on it and they won't do that
and that some tour is eat sometimes what
you might want to do is even get an
older cheaper unit and keep it there lot
of telco central offices are triple
processor for that reason one is active
what is hot standby one is the one you
do maintenance upgrades when do the
maintenance upgrades you then swap that
that with a hot standby so you're never
down and we usually think in terms of
two devices but there's a lot to be said
about three I like my back hope
animation again we've gone over a lot of
these things but again is there a single
medium failure ah are there things you
can't do anything about yes and you may
if there are times you need business
insurance there was at one was then
bowing computer services but the pace
had moved at that point but somebody was
trenching in his great new
that was going to lay new fiber for
something and drilled into their duck
and not only though it blew fiber into
it crashing into it was there and then
it pumped concrete behind it now I think
a lot of us tend to forget about sub IP
technologies and how they can be useful
there is still a role for layer to one
of our clients is there is my over
client has got to datacenter as I
mentioned there there the Midwest are
about 20 miles apart they have plenty of
dark fiber between the two one of the
things that they are basically there are
specialized hosting services it's some
of his application that I don't really
understand but they said hey it's not a
problem you can essentially single
transaction failover no problem so we
can totally do we have duplicate IP
servers so what they give but we need
for them is we set the two sites and
they had 75 hundreds coming in with
twitter and ISPs and we then ran that
over to the other side over there are 50
but then what we get is we put a layer
34 37 fifties in between running
spanning tree between the two sides and
we put duplicate IP addresses on the
servers at each side well as long as one
was up and the rope was over on that
side it went to those IP addresses but
as soon as they lost layer to
connectivity they would automatically
fail over to the other ones with the
same IP addresses we also had DNS on any
cast so turned out that with a way they
were really hard to handle with routing
with j'ellooo you know now i will say
that on all of these servers we are dual
nics we had the one phil goes to the
customer but then they can have unique
internal addresses for maintenance but
that worked out real well even if you
are have IP and you're doing service
provision consider private vlans for
security and again if you do something
like that call agent case you are like
if you have to run vrp hsrp jail be paid
between sites you
are either going to need physical
connectivity or layer 2 conductivity or
I've had to do this with some tunneled
bridging through layer 3 and it was
truly ugly you can do it you know you
can do a GRE tunnel between but convince
it's all one subnet but you really want
to do that again you typically is in
these situations for medics which for
example you have 7 v orfe addresses that
have to be trapped each pair of coil
agents has unique pair of unique
addresses and a virtual address and then
the second group has a second one and
then there's a sort of a super Vrba
wrote on their own would set selects
between the two clusters so you actually
percolate your way up through seven
addresses that can be actually on four
servers but that's what you really need
to do to get a reliable source which now
IP works but again don't think in the
box any kissed is very nice for DNS I
for other services like sinkholes oh
you're how do you handle your virtual IP
address again mission you have to think
about how do I handle virtual IP
addresses whether they're failover for
routers or they feel over four servers
now if you're going to voice over IP
your biggest problem some you're pretty
cool in this mo at some point you
another you're going to have to connect
to the rest of telephone world now if
you have one what's actually a good way
to do it if someone offers you a sip
proxy the chances they know that sip
exists and they could offer that and
they could make you know church who can
so the guy comes to you and says I offer
you a sip proxy and it's over metro
ethernet if they knew to form that
sentence they probably know what they're
doing however in one case we dealt with
was they said oh how do we do that well
we have a nortel
as 200 the connects near exchange for
birds you can end to that and he said
well yeah but how do we connect to it it
just got t ones and he said yeah and
t3's too so what we did is we wound up
with the situation will give analog
phones went to a local loop the then
went into a t1 channel Bank and or a
couple of them and then in ones when OC
192 mesh came off the OC 192 mesh a gig
e or at till he won again and fed back
into the upstream switch now why were we
putting in you know DWDM OC 192 in order
to run t ones over i never did figure
that out and they said well it's going
to be for the wireless and I said what
were I said Oh wireless we're going to
get into that business okay anyway some
ways out of this problem if someone is
looking as your upstream is saying we
want gr 303 and say okay how do you want
it they said well ATM would be good or
sonnet what's in the jar through every
spec and you say you look at your
equipment you just thrown out maybe some
older routers than it's on it interfaces
and you've now got nice Metro Ethernet
gig Ethernet 10 gig you get nothing to
do with it well this is where the
private wire emulations service comes in
which is an MPLS extension and
essentially it can make cisco has guided
kind of in a proprietary implementation
juniper and a couple others now have
both Jeff it's also then check it's been
called dry martini or Gibson but these
are various ways we're through an MPLS
Network you could come off it looking
like a t1 Sun at ATM so on and is the
rug exactly since let me have it now but
it really doesn't matter you don't have
to interoperate with anyone because if
you go to cisco and cisco and you know
you've got mpls inside this is what
gives your up
hgm interface and you previously
throwing away your ATM switch so pw III
is it stands for private wire emulation
and to edge to edge well to me that
should be pwe ete or I don't know how
they get the three in there but that's
the way it works but if you really want
to connect and use full services and
have an intelligent telephony network
you need sip not because if for example
you can actually peer in there are you
can set up now plausible peering points
for sip in a metropolitan area and you
are essentially a layer 5 period point
and it turns out to wind up getting your
economics for delivering telephone
service especially locally if you start
peering or even if you've got people
that are out of your immediate area but
they hate you say to them hey you know
we're IP peered now we got plenty of
bandwidth do you have sipped and he said
yeah we accept you except sit fine let's
pier and suddenly you're four states
away and you get essentially 80 quality
voice network with very little problem
the sauce which doesn't care again how
are you going to distribute your
pay-per-view that's one of the things
that is not to be thought of you it may
be that the cable provider does it for
you but much of the time that's a
satellite feed and they expect you to
store it somewhere how eventually though
one thing you the table out there now
that's coax that's going to have to go
fiber remember we've got the mandate
this year of the FCC to start going
digital on new TV and you got to get
HDTV going that won't work over coax it
just doesn't have a bandwidth so one of
the questions is sooner or later you're
going to start tearing out the coax
there's no use for any more what do you
put in to replace it fiber to the curb
to the you know that's the household to
the building there's a whole business
here fiber to the building if you're
going to say office buildings in hotels
you come in there 10 gig and said hi and
if it a 100
meg you know utility connection no big
deal and this is going to pay either you
my team do if you're the cable carrier
do it or you've said took talk to your
cable carrier and get ready to do it
will cooperate on this we want to run
through this quickly a couple things to
bear in mind now you didn't answer my
question about used car salesman what's
the most important machine in the
hospital is there no one any longer
listens to Monty Python the machine that
goes paying yes the one that tells you
the baby is alive I see we need remedial
my money Python here but the different
thing is that's a very real question to
ask your time how do I paint now how
many of these things will let things go
through them even if the router
interfaces if you're trying to ping one
ro are going to return icmp echo reply
it is a very frequent thing if you're
doing dynamic assignment if you're doing
DHCP and you're a broadband provider and
somebody calls up what's his current IP
address how do you know another thing to
look for that I've run into several
cases recently is look very closely may
talk of the vendor about your high-end
routers it may be that can you update
the backup blades it may turn out that
there's an internal bus it's said to be
one backplane but if they're really
buckled backplanes and you will be
intrusive if you pull the processor or
there may be something work for your
interface cards if you want to be
physically we've done it you need them
in different rows on the same machine
again talk to your vendor and find out
for when they talk about single point
field they usually mean processor or
memory but it may be that there are
active components in the back plane that
can die and usually if you can figure
round them find you have to know where
they are the worst case ever ran into
though was with cisco 7000 we get nice
power supplies
yuddam power supply failure three
gentlemen took over fine we shifted got
a new one to ship and then the horrible
truth King this thing was sitting in
wrapping raised floor so we have the
power supplies are down here all the
signal cables are going to be straight
at the back all this dream relief bar
and then dropping down under the floor
we start to pull out the power supply to
replacing discovered with cables behind
it there wasn't enough room to pull out
power spot find out before running
cables if every card no matter how your
cables run in the rack if the cards can
come out you did the way we solved that
was we were eventually able to get some
of these five year old son to come in
and crawl inside the rack and we
directed him to help pull it out so
again all these things how do you ping
oh this is and backup stuff here that
I've got going on really things because
they've been through on multi Hamid I'd
like to really try to throw this over
questions and also is what are the
weirdest things if had happened to you
operationally because they will happen
to someone else sooner or later my
offering comes it was happened to be at
SAS institute which is one of the best
organized but modern data center you
know the whole big software operation at
the time they fit around everything else
and their local phone network one of the
things that says had done is they built
this huge video production building to
do their training tapes and if a while
they learned that this was a the largest
at the time video pressure facility in
carolinas and start running out time and
people come in and do eggs on it well
one day just got a car company said we
wanted to our new car ads for it and
it's sure sign you up for a day in this
facility what happened with him on that
day is what they had not told they were
going to bring in these cars again we
got a way to get it in there we've got
these cast members you know problem what
they did not tell them was that one of
the cast was alive tiger well somewhere
in a taping the tiger decided he was
getting
board and he wanted to take a nap and as
a cat he wanted a nice warm place to
take a nap to some decided that the
video control board would be a great
place to do that so he went in and
luckily the operator wasn't in there at
the time and no one was going to go ed
he stretched out on the control panel
not everything stopped pretending for a
few minutes and then Tiger woke up again
and he decided was a nice place and he
did beam cat the way little boy cats
mark places daily they have liked and
wanted them back to they now had a very
wet control panel I'm told it took them
three months to deodorize the studio ok
what's your equivalent ok fair enough
i'll call it formally the end of it at
this point you know i had some
multi-homing scenarios book in there
already was separate seminar on that's
not going to go into it what I'm really
trying to leave you with is get outside
the box on emergency services think
about alternate voice communication
there are a lot of options available to
you think about your local hospital fire
police all that will work with you they
may not know they're going to work you
can make a good case for DMI services up
i'll put this on an analyst also are
some places though you may want to
contact and get some of these services
and then mainly a business opportunity
but certainly these are ways to keep
things up thank