alright thanks um I'll just dive right
in let me know if you can't you have
trouble hearing me just you know wave
your hand in the back there I'm not sure
how far this will carry and there's no
portable mic alright so I'll try to get
to the very last slide as quickly as
possible because the bulk of this
presentation is intended to motivate the
discussion which will hopefully come
right after I've been working on windows
networking about 11 years and the past
six of those years have been spent on
rewriting the networking stack which
will ship in Windows Vista so i'll be
talking a little bit about the out of
box changes in behavior for basically
every windows desktop that runs vista
I'll also talk a little bit about some
of the capabilities that are there under
the covers but that are not turned on by
default along the way I'll talk about
some of the lessons we've learned about
the approaches we took to making these
huge changes and where I think we need
to go from here based on those lessons
so first a quick look at the timeline so
I started to work on the design in 99 by
two thousand one we had in our first
milestone mid-2002 we had TCP data
exchanges up and running late 2003 we
had the new stack in the main bills for
Windows meaning that every install every
install of the pre-release saw has had
the new stack up and running so a couple
things to point out here first of all
work on the new stack hat was ongoing at
the same time we were working on Windows
2000 XP server 2003 XP sp2 as part of
why it took so long but then secondly
also that we've been sort of fine-tuning
the behavior of the stack for the past
three years so a lot of what you see
already reflects what we've learned from
the deployments that we've had both
internally as
across the beta programs that we've had
those lessons are continuing up until
this very moment in fact I had to change
the slide deck Justin now because we had
changes that affect what I'm going to
say today as recently as this past week
these are some of the guys who have been
working on the new networking stack you
can imagine this grew from a team of
about a couple people doing the work to
what the picture you see in front of you
right now so what's new I mentioned
earlier that v6 is on by default that
means that Windows desktop will discover
v6 connectivity if it's behind a NAT it
will configure a serato address for
itself if it can fit the Texas 64 router
it'll pick up a 64 64 address and so on
and so forth up through native v6
connectivity there are a bunch of other
changes as well a few of them I'll talk
about today so i won't go into detail on
them on this slide we have built-in
support for equal cost multipath routing
meaning that if you have if a windows
machine sees equal cost or routes to the
same prefix it'll actually multiplex its
traffic over them black hole router
detection which has been historically a
big one for us from the point of view of
support costs is enabled by default
we've changed the the set of options
that we negotiate by default on with TCP
window scaling is always negotiated by
default as is as our selective
acknowledgments and then we've upgraded
the algorithms that we use for
congestion control and loss recovery so
we're we're now in New Reno stack F RTO
support is enabled by default as well as
de sac our old ephemeral part assignment
used to assign parts from 1024 all the
way up to 5000 that's changed so now
it's compliant with them the ion aspects
in that area meaning it starts from
about 49 k and goes up to 64 K and then
finally there across the board there has
been a fairly pervasive focus on getting
rid of registry keys so I kind of left
earlier
and someone said maybe folks would just
go turn off ipv6 in the registry because
that's not that's not the way it's done
so as much as possible we try to figure
out what the right thing is to do
dynamically and team the stacks behavior
on the fly so that's it for the stuff
that is turned on right out of the box
in addition there's quite a lot that we
put in that we left disabled either
because we didn't have a compelling
customer case for it or because the
infrastructure implications and the
infrastructure wasn't quite there yet or
for any number of other reasons one is
that ecn is configurable it was actually
on by default and in some of the earlier
betas and just based on the issues that
we've seen with various equipment from
vendors not working or kind of choking
when it sees on ecn bits we've scaled
that back a little bit it's a strong
host model meaning by default will only
send out an interface will only use
source addresses on the interface which
they are signed we you can actually
configure the week host mode as well in
environments where that's important I'll
skip over a few of these because I'm
trying really hard to get to that last
slide in the amount of time I have /
socket we have extended statistic
support that means essentially that you
can turn on TCP east at the stats mabe
on any given connection and look in
detail at what's going on from the point
of view of the congestion algorithm flow
control and so forth connection offload
is built in if you have the hardware
that supports it and then we support
attempting IQ second all traffic so you
can put the machine into a mode where
whenever it's communicating with the
pier it will always try to negotiate
IPSec and if it succeeds it will proceed
in secure mode otherwise it will fall
back to clear text mode and then escaped
through the last few of these so first
case study looking at what we actually
went through in getting to the point
where
we felt comfortable in turning on ipv6
by default you can think of this as
happening in multiple phases the first
phase was where we were doing our
experimental bootstrapping we had an
add-on for windows 2000 that you could
download and install that had a cute
that added ipv6 capabilities and we use
that to do early self-hosting improved
it in XP sp2 in windows server 2003 and
right now you know we have we well not
public 64 but public teredo services so
by default out-of-the-box any machine
that's behind an app can configure at
array to address for itself the second
in the second phase which overlap quite
a bit with this first phase we
identified and tackled a lot of issues
that had to do with the infrastructure
and the service is actually making it so
that you could use v6 in a realistic in
a real way so native ipv6 and I sattar
outers getting then getting equipment up
to spec finding the bugs and getting
them fixed so that we could at least do
our internal deployments absorbing ipv4
and ipv6 in dual stack mode things have
gotten a lot better there's still a
little bit of work to do particularly
when you start looking at some of the
higher and applications in a lot of the
equipment but currently customers
actually can start to look at doing ipv6
deployments at least on a limited scale
I'm using the technology that's
currently available phase three is
widespread deployment and by that I mean
getting to the point where we can turn
it on by default for everyone which is
the case which has been the case since
Windows Vista bid beta 2 and secondly
actually being able to run in an ipv6
only mode so we have a growing number of
desktops on our corporate network that
basically only get ipv6 connectivity and
we make we make we try to do this so
that we can identify what are the things
that have built-in dependencies on ipv4
so we can find those dependencies and
fix them before our customers find them
what have we learned the hard problems
you have to that you have to find those
early and the only way to find them is
to get code out there up and running I'm
curious just by show of hands how many
folks here have these six hosts on their
networks okay yeah so thinking it would
be a higher number but the key lesson
here is that if you don't have a v6 host
on your network you should start looking
into I mean you will have them soon if
you're in operator because as soon as
windows vista ships you'll start seeing
this v6 traffic on your networks the
second lesson figure out what the right
questions are and what I mean by that is
figure out what are the questions that
you really need to answer in order to be
able to make a simple yes no decision on
deployment in our case we have to look
at a wide range of things what are the
key applications that users expect to
work both on the desktop as well as on
the server in order to have a realistic
story for supporting an ipv6 deployment
and that applies both in the consumer
operating system you know folks you know
running their PCs at home as well as in
a corporate environment and the answers
are very different so it's important to
figure out what the environments are you
want to support and start getting your
hands dirty and getting things out there
up and running qualifying equipment and
so on this is an ongoing effort for us
and we still find issues with equipment
you know in environments that have
issues with ipv6 but we're at the point
now where we're comfortable with the
current configuration of Windows Vista
and RC 1 and RC 2 and v6 is enabled by
default the bulk of hosts will get v6
connectivity via to raid 0 which means
that if they're behind a NAT will
actually turn ally pv6 inside UDP now
tirado is a special case because it
never actually registers addresses in
the DN
and simply having the Teredo address
will not cause you to use quad air
records from the DNS I'll talk about
that a little bit as part of this next
discussion so the key thing to take away
from that is currently the primary use
that you'll see for ipv6 is in
peer-to-peer applications applications
that have their own mechanisms for
exchanging IP addresses ipv4 as well as
ipv6 addresses so v6 capable nodes and
we'll ask for both a and claudia records
and there was a presentation i believe
at nanog several nanos ago maybe about
the impact this would have on the DNS
infrastructure what we actually have
seen internally is that there has been
minimal impact on our DNS infrastructure
we haven't seen any significant data on
public deployments in other words the
behavior of vista beta-1 beta-2 machines
in the wild dan kaminsky sort of an
expert on dns had some research that he
did that i've put up there you can go
look at his on his website on what on
his take on the issue but how do things
currently work in rc1 evista well first
of all this discussion only arises when
you actually have a global ipv6 address
by default the DNS clients in Vista will
not query quad a records unless there is
a global ipv6 address the way that the
client works in rc1 some fine tuning and
RC 2 is that it will send a queries
first as part of the devolution and then
when it gets back an authoritative
answer then it will follow up with a
quad a query to that specific server in
general what we expect is that this will
result in a significantly smaller than
you know 2x increase in the amount
load that you'll see for the DNS from v6
deployments this is a change from beta 2
and so far what we've seen is that this
algorithm works fairly well for
mixed-motive deployments where you have
both the v4 and v6 records in the DNS
now what does this actually mean in
practice on the public network an
application will typically only have a
global v6 address when some or rather a
node will only have a v6 address when
some application is using ipv6 Torito
has this logic in place where it tries
to configure an address it tries to
activate its to radio ipv six address
just in time basically when an
application explicitly tries to use to
raid 0 now an additional change we made
which was even more conservative is that
if the only global address you have is
after 80 address we won't send any
quality queries at all so this really
scopes down the use of ipv6 in the
default mode in networks where there is
no native v6 or 62 for deployment it's a
purely peer-to-peer applications so that
includes some applications out of the
box like our windows collaboration
feature which uses on pure name
resolution to discover hosts dynamically
and set up ipv6 connections between them
there is a quite a bit more detail on
this at the link that i put here on on
the presentation so what do we learn
from this well the key lesson is that
the feedback that we got third hand via
Nana would have been great to get first
hand actually I'll have a place where
you can send feedback at the end of this
slide but I'll go on to the next case
study before I elaborate on that point
tcp receive window auditing so what does
this do the challenge we set for
ourselves as part of hauling this
networking stack is to make this
compelling in other words to depth to
take away you know the old stack and
replace it with the new
really want to be able to make a
significant stride forward in the
behavior of the networking stack
something that customers would actually
care care about something that will
resonate with them one of the areas
where we made such a big step is in the
area of end-to-end TCP performance
historically the stack had has been and
this is the case where many stocks has
been bounded by 64k window which is the
size that of receive window that ax t
see that the TCP can advertise by
default window scallion allows you to
advertise a larger window window scaling
isn't always enabled by default not all
peers that you request windows scale and
from will honor it some mission
equipment out there actually still gets
confused when it sees the window scaling
option but we set out to tackle actually
all of those issues and be able to scale
the performance of his deck end-to-end
across a variety of paths by default out
of the box without any registry treat
weaken so what was our design well
basically it was to estimate the
bandwidth in the network on the receiver
side not on the sender side which is a
little bit more tricky and stay tuned
our window advertisement based on the
estimates that we generate on an ongoing
basis for any given connection now for
these estimates to be of any use to us
we have to enable windows scaled and
because without windows scaling the most
the largest window we could advertise
would be 64 K anyway so we'd never be
able to keep the pipe full of keeping
the pipe full meant advertising meant
you know having more than 64 kilobytes
of data in flight between the two
endpoints so without really trying our
ms calm msit folks on running connection
between a pair of them actually between
a vista bucks and a win2k the reeboks
saw 4dx out of box improvement with this
algorithm and this is that when you
think about it I when I talk about this
algorithm
I usually have a picture which shows the
discrepancies between the pipes over
which a typical stock has to run over
you have everything from you know 63 you
know a 64 kbps ISDN link with you know I
don't know tens of milliseconds of
latency to a satellite link you know
with the 100 megabits you know capacity
and when you do the multipliers to find
the band if it late products then you
compare whatever band if you'll a
product you get to 64k there actually is
a big difference in some cases the
difference is for DX so now the
immediate feedback that our msit folks
that as well you know you're going to
use a part of the capacity under network
and we need to be able to prioritize
traffic we also have support for policy
based costs out of the box in Windows
Vista which allows and hosts actually
categorize the kind of traffic they have
based on dscp markings and we're
continuing to improve in that area now
so they're some of the responses are
that we have group policy knobs in place
so that you can roll out policies to
entire enterprise that will scale back
the the auto tuning algorithms basically
are artificially throttle itself and not
use and not keep the pipe as full as it
could and then the policy based costs I
I mentioned our expectation is that
we'll start seeing paths get used a lot
more efficiently by default by its
nature the algorithm is designed to
sense what the available capacity is and
try to use as much of it as you can
without impacting any other TCP flows
that's what we've seen so far I'm in
practice and the deployments that we've
had have largely the feedback from our
beta testers has largely been ecstatic
we've also had feedback from service
providers who have said yeah well you
know we've seen a spike but the people
who are actually getting the benefit are
pretty happy with
but that they're getting the expectation
naturally is that when if everyone
internet if everyone on a network has
you know auto-tuning an auto tuning
stack what you get is that everyone we
get about the same share of bandwidth
which is what the goal is for TCP flow
control in general so the challenge here
as in the previous case is how do we
actually close the feedback loop how do
we monitor you know the behavior of an
improvement like this on an ongoing
basis so that we understand you know
better how to design the end host
behavior based on the requirements and
observations that occur that occur
within the network infrastructure that's
a feedback loop that I think doesn't
really exist today and starting to get
something like that going is one of the
key subjects of this talk compound TCP
is an algorithm where there is a real
opportunity to do something in this area
I mentioned i talked about auto tuning
which is enabled by default and which
will be enabled by default in windows
vista in the clients which is shipping
pretty soon compound tcp is an algorithm
which is latent in the client but we're
looking to enable it by default in the
server operating system where it's much
more compelling the basic idea behind
compound TCP is to look at what it takes
to recover from fairness on wide area
networks particularly wide area networks
that are very high capacity and ramp up
into the available capacity faster than
classic TCP does most of you are
probably familiar with the sawtooth
pattern that classic TCP has and you're
familiar with the degradation in pipe
utilization that occurs over time as you
can as you repeatedly take a loss and as
the window gets larger and larger it
takes longer and longer to ramp back up
to whatever I'm throughput you had
before Vegas style algorithms solve this
by basing the windows that they use not
detection of loss but on detection of
variations in the latency under the
assumption that increasing latency is a
sign that the pipe is starting to get
oversubscribed the question for us is
whether we could take some of that
approach which historically has been
very unfair to classic TCP full flows
and incorporated into the operating
stock in a in a way which is not only
fair but also preserves a significant
amount of the benefit so what we ended
up with is something we call compound
TCP the algorithm is based on some work
that Microsoft Research Asia did the it
combines both the delay based window
with a loss based window the idea is
that as you when your window is smaller
or when there's less buffering in the
network the lost based component of the
window dominates so we behave more like
a regular TCP and as your window gets
larger or as the delay variations become
more detectable to start behaving more
like a delay based CCP immunity we allow
you to refill you know capacity faster
so results the same ms con folks who saw
the 40 x improvements when they turned
on the this algorithm it gave them an
additional fifty percent improvement so
about another doubling in through /
which I'm again is not that surprising
when you look at the at the actual
sawtooth graphs and you look at the
amount of time that TCP spends in
ramping up into high bandwidth
high-capacity pipes so we also have done
some engagements with the UK mrd and
Stanford Linear Accelerator Center to do
to understand the behavior this argument
understand its fairness to two other
TCPS so we have further confer
confirmation that a recovers faster and
we also have evidence that it's actually
more fair than a high-speed TCP and a
number of other algorithms this is an
area where we're continuing to
do research and so if there are folks
here who are interested in this sort of
problem we're very very interested in
working with you and thinking through
how we go about deploying a thing
deploying logic likely like this on a
scale that allows us to really
understand it enough to roll it out you
know on a widespread basis so I made it
to my second to last slide which is the
key one I've hinted at a lot of what
this talk is really about it's not
really just about the changes that we
made in Windows Vista when you look at
the timeline that we went through to
actually get to the point we are at
today with you know completely new
networking stack in Windows about to
ship you know to millions of people and
what that means for the internet a lot
of the work that we did was to make to
actually establish a platform that would
allow us to innovate a lot faster and
would allow us to pull in a lot a lot
more new functionality on an ongoing
basis into the networking stack being
able to do that requires having a
feedback loop between the folks who are
deploying the end hosts software and the
folks who are actually operating the
networks in the wild where that software
manifests you know all of the corner
cases and all of the interesting
behaviors that that are key to
establishing the viability of any
particular algorithm whether it's for
congestion control or for flow control
some of the things that we're looking at
from for future in as future innovations
on top of the platform that we have
today is IPSec everywhere so I mentioned
that will actually try to use negotiate
we have a mode where we will try to
negotiate IPSec between any pair of
hosts but that's not enabled by default
it's a latent capability so you can go
configure it but it would be what we'd
really like is for actually to actually
always attempt IPSec by the fall what
does that mean what does it look like
and deployment you know what needs to be
in the network to actually support such
an operating mode
peer-to-peer traffic patterns i
mentioned that teredo is primarily
leveraged by peer-to-peer applications
and because it's a platform capability
that we're starting to use a lot more
aggressively we'll start seeing more and
more applications relying on the
peer-to-peer platform that's deployed
and that's available inside or
individuals vista that'll change drive
further changes in traffic patterns
because it'll become a lot more a lot
easier for even casual application
writers to write applications that be
that leverage peer-to-peer traffic
patterns and then finally botnets
distributed denial of service and
ongoing area for us and we're always
looking for ways we can make it harder
to use the networking stack as a
platform for launching distributed
denial-of-service attacks as much as
possible we like the cost to be pushed
back onto the attackers wherever
possible so we've made changes in the
past in that area for instance limiting
the rate at which windows machine will
make outgoing connections that are hot
in the half-open state and we're always
looking for errors for improvements that
we can make over that algorithm to make
it even harder to launch denial of
service attacks so with all that said
what do I actually propose so this is
the hard part because engagements in
general are tricky to meit's a design in
a way that provides value for both ends
of the engagement and also our
sustainable on an ongoing basis you
don't want something too decoupled
because then it just sort of a trophies
and you don't want something that's too
high cost because you know then
participating is high cost so there's no
real benefit so what I what I'm sort of
proposing and what we've come up with so
far from our end is the notion of having
open questions for now related to
Windows Vista if their concerns or areas
where you'd like to know more about what
we're doing or where you have feedback
to offer us and actually on and on a
more regular basis have our in
Engineers you know coming and answering
questions as well as you folks engaging
with us in on the issues that you're
facing and other impact end nodes and
how they impact this sought the
networking software that we're building
and part of that means actually starting
to collect metrics around the behavior
of and posted both what the
infrastructure sees as well as what the
end hosts see we've had very limited
engagements with operators in the past
to start just in for instance in the
case of auto-tuning but I have a feeling
that it might be something that that
that kind of engagement might be
something that's interesting to other
folks so we're open to that as well and
then just in general keeping keeping
tabs on you know where we're making
progress where their issues and having a
forum that folks just to know about and
can count on for bringing these sorts of
concerns and that's all I had so I'm
open to thoughts questions requests for
clarifications if you have feedback on
anything you've heard from me that's an
alias you can send it to tcp/ip feedback
and I'll take questions I have a
question over here other the other side
oh sure over here I'm kind of curious
about the performance improvement is
that a windows to windows client to
server interaction do you get the type
of performance connecting to none
Microsoft servers for the auto tuning
the only change that you'll just have to
be running a Vista receiver any server
that understands Windows scaling will
give you you know that improvement and
then offer a compound TCP you just have
to have it on the sender because it's a
sender side change so in general we we
don't really I mean when if obviously if
you have a sender with compound TCP and
a receiver with auto tuning then
you'll get Marvin improvement than if
either side just as one of the
algorithms does that answer your
question um it does thanks and I guess
just the other general observation is
it's TCP is one of those foundation
things that you generally don't imagine
really getting modified all that much
without great review across a broad
spectrum of folks I mean everything
depends pretty much on the TCP stuff so
I'm wondering is this is going to be
released with this new thing prior to
that broad discussion based interaction
so so just to be clear the auto tuning
algorithm actually is standard tcp it
doesn't make any changes to the TCP
protocol all it's doing is it's changing
the way that the receiver picks which
window it advertises which is well
within the scope of you know the rfcs
now the the part that actually does
change behavior is compound TCP and
compound TCP is not enabled by default
in Vista and that's part of the reason
why it's not enabled by default it's
because we want to start engaging to
understand its behavior better question
yes sir notice keenly that there's going
to be our plan to be support I'm not
sure if he had said it was working or
not for more or perhaps easier access to
diff serve configs perhaps a socket
option when established can you could
you repeat the question I'm not quite
done yet you were saying I heard there
was plans support apparently for easier
access for user applications to set
diffserv bits to to define things upon
binding to a socket well this is
actually where there's easier support
for administrators to configure diffserv
bits for applications sure is also
basically you can roll out a policy
saying you know the following
application you know Lexi you know gets
the following marking you know and it's
traffic or traffic that matches the
following pattern
you know on a glow you know enter you
know organizational why'd you know gets
the following monitor I see so that's
that's not supposed to be something that
is our placement perhaps for queuing
control of stream or is it supposed to
be able to push that congestion closer
to client perhaps saying to a set of
machines that you're all behind a dsl
and you only have a half a make up my
router can't sort so I'd like all the
machines to do so and pretend as if the
congestion is occurring perhaps within
the IP stack itself it's not happening
someone meant what well specifically
this is for cases where you have an
admin in the picture someone who has
actual control over the machines return
knowing can you know configure them so
it's not for consumer environments for
instance the service provider offering
service to folks at home got that answer
your question yep thank you so John
Kristoff I have three questions if it's
going to take you more than a med to
answer Oh be happy to take it offline
the first is you'd mentioned something
about how if you get an authoritative
answer back you you'll then said the
cool send the quad a query and I just
wanted to maybe clarify that because
usually you're probably getting a rear
hitting a recursive server and so the
answer it was not actually authoritative
per se the second question was regarding
the choice of firm reports that you use
and I know the UNIX is have tended to
use the range that you mentioned but why
not just use the entire you know 1024
and everything above just as default and
then lastly can you say anything about
sctp and implementation and maybe sort
of what's things you you see that are
going to be who's using that what
they're going to use it for that sort of
thing okay first question I'm not quite
sure I got it but basically when we if
we get it back an answer a specific
answer then we'll follow up with a quad
a query to that specific server that
make sense yeah you said authoritative
answer I just wanted to clarify though
okay and then the second question was
about the femoral men was the ephemeral
ports oh yeah a femoral port so now the
issue with that is that there are
actually a lot of registered parts that
we need to avoid this has been a problem
in the past in this 10 20 40 to 49 k
well 1024 to 5000 certainly there are
parts that are registered to people with
ayanna which were which would originally
conflict with the dynamic assignment
logic but so these are you just are I
was assuming maybe incorrectly these are
just port you're choosing as a source
port for an application are you talking
about yes our sports so for instance if
you are done if your ephemeral part
assignment allows you to choose parts in
the range 1024 to you know 5000 what it
means is that an application may get in
a source part which later someone else
will come along and try and bind to
because it's registered to them does
that make sense and then they fail in do
they are they're unhappy okay and then
the last one was sctp oh yeah sctp so
we've looked at sctp over the years
currently we don't have any plans to
support it some of the key features that
sctp could potentially offer we've tried
to incorporate support for for instance
better support for multi-homing
connections we have api's that make it a
little easier for applications to do
that the biggest stopper for us has been
the willingness and the investments in
getting people moved over to complete in
your transfer protocol and you know what
that means for you so in some ways it's
like for us it's like tackling another
ipv6 you know at the same time that
we're tackling the ipv6 where I'm five
minutes but actually 10 five minutes
behind schedule so let's just finish up
these questions we have out there and a
little but you had mentioned that your
diffserv control point stuff is intended
for an environment with an administrator
anything to prevent it or discourage it
or you know
from being used in by like by rogue
applications in such environments or you
know in in you know or rogue users you
administering their boxes to do bad
things with it well if if users have
adamant privileges on their machines
then note that nothing can prevent them
from abusing any packet marketing scheme
so the answer is no we haven't done
anything significant there yeah I have a
question on a toroidal and ipv6 so my
understanding is that teredo will not be
turned on if ipv6 native is available so
it's more maybe a comment so coming from
somebody with trying to deploy this to
some more customers what happened when
we have a native v6 connection to one
customer another customer as a v4 not
and you steroid oh my understanding also
is that today there is no such thing as
a territorially to connect Geritol
clients to native ipv6 clients so what
should happen ok quick clarification so
why is it that you say teredo won't be
used if you have I mean it Tarata won't
be preferred over a native ipv6 address
if that's what you're saying but you can
have both the native and a 64 and deter
a to address all at the same time so
essentially my question is what happened
when two customers want to do a
peer-to-peer application based on night
56 one of them has native ipv6 and via
the other one is only ipv4 nut and
Ventura door so that leads me to my
second question which is that or or Adam
a second comment which is that currently
there's no there are widely deployed to
radio relays but there's nothing to
prevent people from deploying to radio
relays and so in the environments where
we currently use to rato aggressively we
have some other
mcmechen mechanism other than DNS to
exchange addresses the pier name
resolution protocol is an example and
they're out of box applications that
leverage to raid 0 they use PRP to
exchange addresses and in general that's
sort of the model unless you if you have
native ipv6 connectivity and you need to
talk to someone that only has two rato
then either they're asking someone who's
willing to relay traffic for you or so
another way to ask my question I'm sorry
I need to cut this off we are 10 minutes
behind schedule and I have to get in and
i'll be out there during the Greek I get
to talk about a lobby after Kurt's so
thank you very much