my name is jono
um I am a senior technical threat
intelligence analyst within the kind of
wider PWC uh cyber team
um I love these introduction slides not
because well I'm not really relevant
like you can read everything there is to
know about me on this slide but I like
taking these opportunities to talk about
my team
um because without them I well I
wouldn't be standing up here today not
they didn't save my life but they did
allow me to kind of go into a field
completely by accident
um I can't really get into it now but I
confuse the word instant response for
international relations on a job
application and actually ended up in TI
just completely by accident so I really
shouldn't be here but thanks to the PWC
team and thank you to the VB team as
well for selecting this talk I'm uh
super humbled and very very grateful and
I guess when I when I think about what
really interests me about TI and what
really makes me excited about doing
research is being able to tell a story
um most of the malware that's analyzed
by the PWC team and I'm sure by CTI
analysts in this in this room is it's
not boring but it's really hard to tell
a story about it
um you end up having to kind of debug
stay in either go back to the debugger
it's not sexy it's not cool but this is
a story of a threat actor that actually
has like a really cool story
um and it's pretty much the only reason
that I put it in for a request for
proposal is because I I like it I think
it's cool but I'm also burdened with
having to to tell the story I have 30
minutes to tell the story of attractor
that we spent eight to nine months
analyzing which is that sucks like I
would like to spend longer but I'm using
this agenda as a way to kind of help me
more than you summarize this activity
and present to you basically our
research over the last well just under a
year
um so
who what am I talking about I'm talking
about a highly likely china-based
product now I don't love the diamond
model all the time but in this instance
it's actually really helpful because we
have a really concrete idea of what and
who red Dev 26 actually is as I said
it's highly likely a china-based threat
actor they have a very very specific
tool set and this will be quite
significant later on in the presentation
when it comes to attribution not the
attribution always matters but in this
case it's it's kind of contested
um the tool set that we're talking about
is a dll loader that we call shelf
loader and that leads into a final stage
payload which is kind of like a reverse
shell it looks a little bit like
interpreter but it's it's a fairly
standard reverse shell it has upload
download file right read capabilities
it also has very specific victimologies
we're talking South China Sea countries
or rather entities based in countries
within the South China Sea as well as
the East China Sea too more recently
there is infrastructure overlap between
campaigns or at least in the earlier
campaigns recently we've seen a turn
towards more less shared infrastructure
and more one by one campaign basis
however some of the victims which aren't
related to The Campaign appear on
multiple IPS so I again if someone could
help me answer that question that'd be
awesome because I don't know why that is
but with the kind of introduction of the
threat actor out the way it is time to
talk about well how we got here because
it's always interesting for me as an
analyst to hear how people start
analyzing activity and this is also a
great opportunity for me to shout out
one of my one of my best colleagues and
a close friend John Southworth bits of
binary on Twitter who basically passed
me this because he had too much to do
and eventually we ended up expanding
this into the threat actor that it is
today but essentially I was given this
sample from February 2022 which was
targeting uh well it looked to be
targeting the asean conference that was
going on in the same month
and I looked in our threat intelligence
repository and portal and saw that we'd
actually seen similar asean targeting
back when there was a previous Summit in
May 2021
if you I by chance looked at the dll of
that report in May 2021 and found that
actually and I don't know if you can see
it on the screen all the way in the back
because I've struggled all day but these
two dlls they're different but they are
very very similar similar enough that I
was like okay
bit weird I should probably keep
investigating this
now this is where stuff kind of gets
complicated because
in May 2021 the IP that was used
was attributed in open source to apt-41
or barium yeah barium
and then this activity in February 22
was attributed to Mustang Panda or
bronze president both of those are
china-based threat actors with their own
bespoke ttps
now I fell victim to apt-41 in well not
me I I wasn't hacked by apt-41 but I
fell victim to the victimology kind of
trap of apt-41 and I actually said in
our first report it could actually be
APC 41 based on the infrastructure
when that report came out in February
2022 it was actually it actually came
out that the it the IP that was used in
that campaign that was attributed to
apt-41 was downgraded so actually I was
left calling it apt-41 without any
evidence which that sucked but it led me
to think if I can find two dlls that are
very similar that are almost a year
apart they're about nine months apart
that look very similar that do exactly
the same thing
what what else can I investigate and so
I made like a very brief ER rule it
wasn't pretty it wasn't cool but it did
get me to a sample from January 2021 so
we're still in February 2022 having made
that asean report however
I am now looking at a binary from 2020
January 2022 so the month proceeding and
then after that I said oh okay right
well we've got we've got quite a lot
here I should probably do some more work
on this threat actor and I did and we
found 17 other binaries uh one of which
is from 2019 and the rest are from 2021
and I will say that most of this
analysis was not done through malware
analysis I did very little re at this
point it was just spray and pray Yara at
some of the strings and some of the
malware and hope that it actually works
and it did so we ended up with again I
hope you can see this red is not a good
color in light but
in 2019 we see one binary
we don't see any until 2021 a very
specific event in 2021
and then the threat actor just continues
to ramp up activity let me just check
the time continues to ramp up activity
all the way
into
2022 all the way in fact up to August
2022 was the last binary that I've seen
with this rad actor it seems to me at
least that from 2021 onwards we see a a
specific goal in mind when they're
targeting whereas in 2019 well they're
not using the reverse shell in 2019
they're using cobblestrike so the
operations are a bit less clear
and that makes me think and I have to be
very careful because in threat
intelligence we often use assessment
confidence or confidence assessments I
should say in fact we always use
confidence assessments
and I'm going to have to not use that
right now so forgive me TI gods for
doing what I'm about to do
there is no activity between 2020 no
observable activity between 2020 2019
and 2021.
between the year 2019 and 2021 we see a
kind of shift in code base
and we'll see that when we come on to
the changes in the binary But ultimately
what we see is actually the threat actor
makes the binary less clean in 2021 than
they do in 2019. in addition they stop
using Cobalt strike and they start using
this reverse shell that I will kind of
talk about in technical detail in a
little bit
which makes me think
we have clustered all of this under red
deck 26 just by virtue of the fact
malware and infrastructure and
victimology because there is overlap
across all three which is good enough
for me
but
it is possible that actually as we know
china-based train actors do love to
share code and there is overlap across
multiple threat actors and I I think
about shared malware Shadow pads plug X
and poison ivy etc etc all of those
malwares have been shared across
multiple threat actors it could be that
actually red Dev 26 doesn't start out as
red Dev 26 starts out as another threat
actor and what we're clustering is Red
Dead 26 is actually
another threat actor reusing code base
from a previous generation of of malware
but who knows it's not my well it is my
job but I don't know that that part
so this is what happened when I actually
mapped it out now I will say full
disclosure I did what I thought was a
really nice graph of all the dlls nobody
in my team agreed with me so we ended up
with this as a compromise so this is all
the raw archives that have I have seen
related to Red Dev 26 activity as you
can see Myanmar starts off as being a
really big Target now again there are a
couple of caveats or rather cool little
tidbits that I actually have time to
mention you can see oh I'm going to use
the laser all in one this thing here you
can see a 2019
timestamp that's wrong the thracter
realistic probability as far as I'm
aware what they do is they take the
actual legitimate all-in-one font which
is a font package for uh that was on the
president of myanmar's website they
repackaged it with their own dll now I
don't know whether they put it back
inside the the actual legitimate place
in the in the present of myanmar's
website but in BT the ITW URL is that
link so I don't know make of that what
you will but either way the threat actor
uses or repurposes a legitimate zip
package for their own ends which I
thought was pretty interesting and then
we kind of see this like cluster
and then we see this one here uh this is
interesting for pretty much non-related
reason but I'm so glad I could actually
segue into it now
this this ZIP includes a a Word document
uh which is related to a an article made
by oh you're really testing my
preparation skills now oh made by a an
Asian youth
um
Outlet when I can't remember the name of
them but I'm sure I could after this
talk like directly after it I'll
remember it
um it was it was the article was made in
26th of April 2022 and the packaged the
original early modifications of the
document was April 26 2022 but the
latest modification was the 5th of May
which is exactly the same as the zip I
speculated or I made an assessment a
confidence assessment with a realistic
probability that actually the threat
actor had poised to Target whoever they
were tasked to Target they took the
original translation of the document
which was English and then they
translated it badly into whichever
language they needed to for the Target
and in this case it was Burmese which is
the official language of Myanmar
um one also really interesting thing to
note before I I I'm on time that's fine
one interesting thing to note here is
this this is where we see red Dev 26
start up operations again which is
actually February 2nd 2022 or at least
the dll is compiled February 2022.
uh in the first of February 2022 that's
when the Myanmar coup starts so we see a
very specific date of a geopolitical
event followed by Red 26 activity and
that is followed up again the
Philippines there is a lot of discussion
around the relationship between duterte
or Rodrigo duterte's Philippines
president and Xi Jinping or the kind of
the CCP in general around their
relationship and the pivot back towards
the United States well we see three
three pretty distinct Philippines
targets Philippine targeting or
targeting philippine-based entities
throughout the November into December
into early 2022 kind of Nexus
and then we have some random well I say
random there are asean events going on
but it's it's not as cool as Myanmar of
the Philippines in terms of like
consistent targeting but we see clearly
Red Dead 26 has a motivation when it
comes to kind of targeting of entities
and then we have Thailand which is this
is roughly when discussions begin about
are they going to be shared exercises
between Thailand and the and the CC and
the pla which took place in August 25th
of 2022 which is great so
we've kind of mapped out the threat
actor what do they actually do how do
they actually operate well this is an
overview I don't really know how much I
want to kind of go over this but
essentially
we are fairly certain realistic
probability realistic probability to
highly likely confident that the threat
actor uses spear phishing as an initial
access method I say that because we know
that most of the campaigns that we have
observed use either Dropbox or a G Drive
Link which you would click on and the
payload would arrive on your system in
downloads
it doesn't execute automatically which
leads me to assess that the threat actor
has two
has to convince or coerce the victim
into targeting or clicking on the link
and we'll see in a little bit that they
do some methods for to try and encourage
that and and that includes very kind of
Spock standard things which include
um using a PDF logo for an executable or
hiding the dll on system all that good
stuff basically doing as much as
possible to kind of hide operations that
leads into what we'd call shelf loader
which is loaded via a benign X cutable
which then downloads
in memory a payload which is kind of
like a second Stager which calls to a C2
that C2 downloads a load of a load of
Shell Code which is then rc4 decrypted
and a 9x or key decrypted or decoded
sorry into the actual command or the
reverse shell payload
this is shelf loader
um if you ever get given the binary and
I will say a full disclosure that I will
be putting are your rules for this
reactor and their binaries on our public
GitHub probably tomorrow when I put the
slides in but it will be up I promise it
will be up this is the function I want
people to focus on it's the kind of
where the resource sits and we'll talk a
little bit about how the threat actor
does this or the techniques that they
use to change over time because it
wasn't always this way they have
improved their techniques over time and
changed some things and that's cool
because we like
we like stories and threat Intel we like
the ability to see not Hands-On keyboard
level stuff but the ability where to see
whether threat actor has made choices
cognizant choices and some of these
choices are really cool so I'm not I'm
not kind of prefacing my whole
presentation but there is some cool
stuff coming that isn't just this
um you can see here the
the
how the malware pulls the next stage
payload from the C2 so again I don't
know if you can see this but but I'm
going to use the laser pointer again so
you have the first six bytes which are
actually a fake TLS header and it's a
way for the malware to kind of spoof
Network traffic and then you have these
three bytes 170303 and hex which the
malware will check for just to make sure
that actually this is the right payload
that's what we're looking at
the these nine bytes in total are the
rc4 decrypted or the uh not the rc4 the
X the nine by X all that's used after
the rc4 the rc4 and the nine by xor
never change uh from 2021 all the way up
to now they don't change uh if you're
watching this red Dev 26 please don't
change we've really enjoyed uh having
not had to work all that hard after
reversing one of them but that's
essentially shelf loader uh it's it's
between BPF door and Crimson wrap from
transparent tribe it's about somewhere
in the middle of complexity but the next
stage functionality is a little bit not
trickier it's just more interesting the
thrac uses a double pointer structure so
what they do is as you can see here they
basically make a structure of apis or d
words to apis that they call and then
they'll use a separate structure which
you can kind of see here they'll use a
separate structure to call that
structure
um and that's how they load apis into
their command shell and you can kind of
see the functionality of the command
shell they've even included flame text
strings which is really nice of them but
you follow the you follow the functions
and you can get the functionality that
you need
there is an interesting victim
from August 2022 with we assess that the
victim has uploaded the Shelf loader
binary they've also uploaded two other
files alongside with it that one of them
is a golang backdoor seems to be bespoke
I haven't analyzed it enough yet
alongside a kind of a networking
protocol like open source GitHub
executable which again more work needs
to be done on that but maybe you'll see
me here again next year to talk about it
but we we assess that there are more
payloads after this this is just kind of
the the beach head for them to kind of
start doing what they actually want to
be doing and we know the payload works
it makes sense to me that they haven't
altered all that much
because
they they have victims we've seen in the
netflow victims beaconing out to the
evict uh the c2ips of the malware so we
know it works and we assess that there
isn't enough information in open source
for them to actually have to change
anything so
uh this is why it is what it is
so we can talk a little bit now about
the changes made some of them are more
fun than others and some of them can be
perceived to be a bit more superficial
than others but they are nevertheless
interesting I am again very sorry if you
cannot read these slides they seem
really clear when I look at them at a
laptop but when you're staring when
you're at the back of the room it's it's
a lot more tricky but I've kind of tried
to use black boxes to make it a little
bit easier so you can see here that the
threat actor decides initially weirdly
to go for just the executable they hide
the dll in in the system and you can
easily unhide it but if you don't have
that if you don't untick it as it is
defaulted you won't ever see it and then
weirdly so this is from 2021 and this is
from February 2022. um I don't know why
they've decided to do this thing again
where they've added the dll back in I
assess it's because it's called
acrobat.dll and because this has an
acrobat logo they they assume that the
the target needs the target believes
they need acrobat.dll
um no idea but that's an interesting
change I have seen them now go back to
the method of not only having a dll and
a DOT XE but also an Extended resource
which is the word document that is
loaded to the Target as a benign kind of
hey it's all it's all fine when it's not
really and then again some of these
changes make no sense to me but they are
changes so I have to mention them this
is a binary this is from 2019 the threat
actor has two exports
um and then they go for this this method
of having up to 302 there is this one
really weird binary that again if people
want to do more research on I would
highly recommend doing it and then tell
me how you did it because there is one
binary that is a bit of an outlier in
the rest it has so usually they're about
20 to 35 exports sometimes they spoof
legitimate dll exports but this in this
individual case they had 302 and the
sample runs nothing like I'd expect from
shelf loader um so there is again more
work to be done there is it that there
is another actor using this code base
no idea but it's interesting and that's
cool we like interesting we like more
research to be done
uh I have nothing more to say about that
except for the fact that you will see
when you look at shelf loader the threat
actor becomes more
aggressive in their naming of exports
I'm not going to use the swear word but
there is like a consistent Square where
they use for their dlls or their sorry
their exports rather which is
interesting
um it seems to me and we'll talk about
this actually in the next couple of
slides but over time
the threat actor starts making these
really weird choices for their binaries
and this is stuff that doesn't impact
the functionality it doesn't change the
way the malware functions or operates it
is literally just for the analysts to
see
so we start off here with using font
support as an open event
it's fairly benign however in 2019 there
was none of this they actually used none
of this they didn't create an event they
didn't do any of this there was no
storage size for INT there was none of
this it was just very plain and we'll
see it in the next slide it was very
very efficient in its code base so we
already begin to see in 2021 the thrag
to start to go
I can probably get away with this we
then start to go into a bit weird
territory with like I work in JP uh new
line calling the create event MTV USA
which again I don't know how many people
have an MTV application on their laptop
but it's a cool create like a cool an
event MTV USA makes no sense to me and
then I still don't know who what Bryce
team 11 is the rest of the like
the rest of the shout outs if you will
on red dive twenties from Red Dev 26
malware makes sense to me this one
doesn't so if anyone after this talk has
any indication of what Bryce team 11 is
more than happy to hear that
then we get into the really weird
territory where like my dream is to make
money to support my touch okay and I'm a
programmer that lives at the bottom
again it's just printf it doesn't do
anything it is literally just for the
developer I don't really understand
again why then we see stuff like this uh
hyphae lee who is a he's actually on
Twitter he's a kind of reverse engineer
malware analyst I don't know who he
works for but hi if you're watching uh
we also saw Moto Sato was also copied in
as a create event as well who is also a
researcher who works in Japan
and this is where things get really
interesting because this is May or April
to May 2022
a a u u a r u s is Mustang panned yes
uh I mentioned before that Mustang Panda
was mentioned in attribution
it was never
it was never put in open source outside
of
um some VT rules that hit in the
community section of VT the only way you
would ever know that Mustang powder been
attributed would be if you had a VT
account and you could see the comments
now in may 2022 after this binary was
posted a threat Intel Outlet did a
report that aligned Red Dot 26 with
Mustang panda
there is I do understand why they've
done that because there is some overlap
in the benign executables but at PWC we
we just haven't done that yet and again
I will talk about this in the takeaways
attribution is fine as long as you are
confident we're talking about why you
attribute X is y whether that be with
external third parties or within your
own internal team it does not matter how
you attribute as long as you're just
doing it with confidence and with some
form of evidence but this is weird and I
thought this was very strange they begin
to get more sweary
and a bit more
it's it's clear by April 2022 they know
they're being watched
or they know that they're being
um analyzed and yet they still don't
change any of the malware they don't
change anything just the strings within
the binary which I found to be
relatively uh well interesting it's not
even useful it's just interesting and
that's what threat Intel is all about
really
this is the less superficial stuff the
stuff that is I found to be quite
significant I actually said earlier that
they don't change their code base they
actually do change their code base
um so you can see here this is the 2019
binary you can see how clean it is
there's no extra strings there's no
extra fat or fluff it is just virtual
Outlook do some memory virtual protect
run it and here we have do persistence
mechanisms then do some virtual alloc
and then do create thread so we already
see some some changes but not I would
say in an efficient way it's just it's
just bad or at least inefficient I
shouldn't say bad because it works just
inefficient and then
the threat to really changes things up
because they stop using Create thread
and they stop using the start address as
a way to Pivot into their their newly
formed dll what they do is they use
they use apis that have callback
functions so graystring w is one if
you've ever heard of it it just bitmaps
like it Grays out a bitmap area and in
update formats hey so what you do is you
just basically use a callback function
within the API to load the resources
it's not clever but it is interesting
and it threw me for about 10 seconds
where I was like where's create thread
I'm lost so I found an undated format
and said oh okay fair enough cool
also the way that the malware loads the
apis is interesting too
not the apis the resource
you can see here this is the technique
the thracter uses for about 10 months
from 2021 uh well from 2019 actually
it's two years isn't it 2019 all the way
to May 2021
where they have a resource that's a big
Clump in memory and then they just
unwind it using an algorithm and here is
what they do from about September 2019
20 September 2021 all the way to now
where they put the resource in these
functions and they're about you'd see a
chain of about 30 35 functions that have
these encoded resources that are then
put inside this function here that are
then Unwound and appended to each other
to eventually end up with the with the
final stage kind of loader that calls
the C2 that loads the the command shell
the reverse shell which is interesting
they also use these like weird Keys
sometimes it's just as simple as being
like an md5 hash of a key and sometimes
it's Larry W cash dollar six again
threat actors choice not mine
and so I'm coming to the end
um and I guess what I wanted from the
from the end bit was what we found
useful as a TI team
um
Espionage takes a long time to
understand and ransomware service
operators too having done research into
Darkseid and black matter it takes a
while to understand what the threat Act
is all about and sometimes you won't
have any ideas sometimes you're left
with speculation which isn't
intelligence it's it's just speculation
and it's fun but it shouldn't go in
reports as confidence assessment
um so I would always advise threat Intel
Outlets to take time analyzing stuff and
that includes re like scrub it clean get
as much done as possible really know the
op codes in and out and with that comes
the bottom Point Let's see if I can call
the point there yeah documentation like
even if you're not writing a report on a
malware document it and I am so guilty
of this I don't document anything if I'm
not report I used to not document stuff
if I wasn't reporting on it I would just
kind of have it in my brain and go yeah
if that comes up I'll I'll absolutely
remember it I never do so please when
you analyze document because your team
when they pick it up will remember or
rather have something to go off and
won't have to start from base zero and
then finally
be comfortable with attribution like
it's all good uh you can you it's not
you can get things wrong but you can
have competing hypotheses with other
Intel Outlets or even within team
members as long as you know why you
attribute X is y and it isn't ridiculous
then that's that's cool and that is
actually everything I want to say so
thank you so much guys I really
appreciate it
thank you
well thank you jono uh we have time for
one or two questions any questions
or you all want to get a cup of tea or
coffee
well in that case uh well thank you for
your presentation then please join me in
thanking Yono
[Applause]