Michael I got 11
just left my slow
close for yeah
05 places ok technology and I will 30
show was official second folded Club of
list of arrests
the just whole almost what's
flesh and how we start using it a
special for many many years so we're it
use it to a magnetic
a recording for most of types of data
will store
should also know that more than 100
years ago i download still use a
every day a lot of hard drive still in
use
a and the June pure soap for using
mileage record or so
dress become smaller and smaller but to
even
is a become a small it's only speech or
a its Israel drive produced in 2005
love the technology it I'll almost the
same like 100 year ago
I'll the same general principles 0
when you look deal with my collegiate
record or you could modify any piece of
data
almost independently from each other
soul while
usually disc is divided among multiple
sectors but it's %uh
just for synchronization for easily
access Inc
the precise accessing data physically we
could address
anything any peace %um here also any
sequence so
you could modify data as we lack and up
for many years of use a show of magnetic
good recording devices so industry
%uh studied fell to properly work with
them
and the how to handle sensitive data
that stored on magnetic dry ice and fell
to destroy the data and their outdated
raisers Thundercats exists the
allows people make sure that they that
date and that well
would be able to read by buy anything
else actually not many people I'll
use that standard slow ways they need to
delete delete data items are a major
search about those up to follow
published already but up several years
ago wolf
im actual in 1948 new technology
came to a life full flesh it will see
invented by
some Japanese get good belief and the
in love 1988 and 1989 two companies
produced so force saw a commercial
samples that were available
for public up so more
Res lows this principle hands they have
two types of
my Maria up and or and am and
their bill base it on doula different
types of logical elements
not or not and about to actual is or not
to a big difference between
them well in low in the view of my
presentation %uh flesh torches
electronic device so no moving parts not
parts no mechanics
unknown making it feel to move and the
its the store electric
a of charge somehow points
its complex you think I'd I really don't
understand how it works
up love I studies electronics for short
time but
not enough and the modem technologist
save that
data stored in flash memory be available
for reading
the at least then euros and some sample
sale
allows you to read data up two hundred
years of two evils
return inside the flesh and the
searle warts bolt this theory how well
what was the proper tools if less how it
to actually war
its a very different from
magnetic drive from government to crack
or yes we could write
any beats independently soul
I'll be good modify any piece of data
independent of each other
was one exception re you do
erase data dip up before we hear
but you're right so so it is no
just modify Inc up 021 all 120
we could easily modify it any one beach
but 20 brittle back do one state we need
to perform a race
and a race perform not therapy
not survive by don't block and local
usually several kilobytes
sold to erase single beat you read data
from
all also beats from the whole block
arrays that look
and right all youths back so it's not
worry
good idea to look to form such low
operation
soul of a some optimization algorithms
involved and I will love to talk about
that a little bit later
and another up big difference low of
less memory
in looking for racial reasons the
magnetic drive
is limited number of array cycles I was
much needed rescue August modern
good schools high quality magnetic drive
see you good
right to the the same sector or vote to
a huge amount of times
and it's still more so fine soul you
will have
no problem with up reading or writing
data to
does that sector with list of your
limited tool
small number of erase cycles their blog
so what you looking to raise a
for example for all that's less than
1000 times
you deliver a below
to get all once all all love us
beats I'll sit in one state after I so
love
loco consider to be a bad I'm it should
be excluded from later use
%uh Gupta up devices so look good types
of less
the increase the number of cycles to me
know
%uh but the actually oh well operating
system
follow like Greenville so work with file
system while
it's slower alright some sectors were
y'all home for example love and you
I'll access to some dark story to any
file the doctor you need to update data
about last access time
so a every access code leaked to
write cycle and probably two or a cycle
solo up to
the this problem while makes
the musical less completely different
love from hunter a point of view
place when we're usually divided the
inlet several
banks %uh physical Chiefs and the every
cheap for a healthful multiple blocks
inside it
and every bloke if multiple page for
eases 0 for use a show pays usually
divided
in two parts data for to reach should
represent
user data and so-called spare part
that could be used for storing some
additional information that is necessary
for properly can link
%ah everything that happens so his flesh
and usually is there are three types of
data could bury two meals for a right
it's slow information that some pages
also hold local
already broken so it's could not be
array that anymore
up also other could be information about
ever her reaction some types of less
use error correction for norinko for
example 1b
for the rice error so if you have all
the while
R&B in the page you could still use this
page using color correction algorithms
and the sure I'll this the spirit area
could be used for holding
the physical the logical my pink
information because so
up there are some might think lehrer up
do you do a physical properties of less
so because we can't
rights to all the things that after
every time we need to modify
handle shooter no girl real little Inc
algorithm sconce %uh that elderly khalsa
Z ain't still
make ever rich little Inc ever reach
rear end of the whole less on the same
level so
every page cole slaw seles you
you DL conditions should be raised equal
number of times
doesn't matter up reach logical place
you are trying still
successful writing the ever reach
numbers
or I cycles should be evenly distributed
over the whole
less and if you are achieved that goal
I'll slipped less real I'll serve you
as long as possible you fuel up make
this algorithm small primitive falwell
flesh we'll be here destroy it by rising
so
much sooner so love this algorithm so
it's
dynamic process when your flesh you the
connected to flash controller something
happens inside the flesh
so love up its trying to optimize
so each page 2 a race to be spaced or a
map
and the algorithms usually very
complicated to its default by if less
manufacturing company companies
and the usually a it's not public
because there are several public
implementations for relabel income
treatments but
so nobody we shall there it's exactly is
used by into for example
its kind of trade secret and a subtle
worthwhile
logical check 360 flesh device
%uh was there are two types of devices
love just type
is so usual USB flash drives that
connected to USB port
it's so so let's play drive it starts
that's the sort to you for the camera
%uh mostly is there a trying to preserve
to you of up view jewel hard rights so
what you have for
logical access by sector
level so %uh you need to New only
number of separate unit you want to or
read or write
all every single minute think it's is
performing inside the device inside the
flesh cart on site use be drive
very special controllers: a a response
all those responsible for doing such
operations and from user points-of-view
its all inside device 40
solid state drives a people
decided that the up its
good idea to say dual controller let
some pages not to use it
anymore of love because slow file was
deleted from the filesystem
soul up if you're or put up a rating
system
that overall few simple solid state
drive the end you call don't involve
Coldstream call much
when you erase some file the serological
sectors that belongs to that files
owner is no not use it I'll for sure you
could write some data to eat
but actually from the view of filesystem
sup sector is
empties there is nothing usable inside
the and
file system driver report still flash
controller
lip wage logical place with some number
is not use it
anymore and trust in throat controller
remember this information
and after that when he drank two read
this page
by its logical lumber controller
or report all zeros or just
reports there is no such sets are
available so
it seems that for a forensic point of
view for extracting data
%uh you look technology into a plastic
knowles a dream poland
allows you to look to raise data such
ways that
its impossible to read another type of
lossless devices
embedded devices I'll very slow
mine borked wrong I believe iPhone 4s
so up during development all that
the title devices the manufacturing
companies was the already Newell said
the real deal is flesh
and a usually is a note to a embed
additional this controller or that so
handle like control inside your flash
drive fall
of les cartes full for the camera the
you some interface from central
processor to flash memory
and handle all your little Inc El
toritos
and all the stuff that's related to his
my pink between the
logical to physical pages they can
delete
inside the software inside the field
where the Tron on that device
and the using ca that knowledge that
you're working for a split
flesh it's much easier to optimize use
the show
less memory it and the force
eat dil work longer a and the reduced
number of array cycles ansel
this
little bit the logical and physical
pages
between number of senator and number
physical page swear this sector is
stored
right now it's called list translation
layer
and I'll when you look to
on your device a for example iPhone
its read that information about me think
for a lot less
hold it in memory during all low
operation time
and the perform last night in Co
for any request that sector you you want
to read for from the flesh
but you to read of all current might
think
story in place a game in some new
patient flesh
and the currently closed
if you do 200 for your device physically
for example by disconnecting cuz battery
%uh information about my pink youths
not complete solar you will Anita up
additional time when you doing on the
device before operating system loaded
to collect information about proper
meetings are at such a late Middle
East's inside the film were usually
up to represents less integral
device was out result errol's in making
and the using flash translation layer up
its a possible tool trip report still
less control a result some patients not
to use its sole some
dream called so lots of logical page
number albeit not let the turtle
and the central Warsaw both whilst
happen when you were out trying to 25
some data
old racial standards for migrating Drive
se
the cook usually fades that to
raised thirty they turn up on some
sector you need to
overrated multiple times missile love
templates
slowly all some random data in so long
what's happened well you'll just
other writing some logical sector of
less stress
actually it as I said earlier I you
can't alright
on the same page because %uh tool
modified date all that base you need to
erase whole block
but the bloke you I'll hold some also
usable information
and though it you need to or a map that
information to sell
also play just or you could just not
remove information right now
you could just a lucky to a mule page
that not use it
for yet and change making soul
the same logical lumber will map to
other physical page
so do think first so I'll writing for
some sex or
for the ample physical place number one
was use it for storing the data
after you're right a game new page with
almost random number a number is the
defined by a place to place a layer by
viewing pleasure below the real
level in Calgary dance you patients
choose a and now my pink
point for all that logical from the same
logical place to absolutely different
physical page but Brilz notion of data
that will store it off last
it's not to raise it its probably
in the future it would be reserved by
garbage collection algorithms
all by remapping tell the Eagles if you
have lots of free space and need to use
a
race-based a game and I'll
actually you in most cases you can't
predict
when it happened so %uh you up
have no postrel all a how to force
the flesh controller to erased some
specific physical page
that in in in little in impost campaigns
so sensitive data you want to race
and the actually do I start
was thinking about less so during
concerts on
Isles a curtain alarm what's happened
inside it
and the its slow most agree with those
up
selfless translation layer on Isles
devices implemented
you in the field where so the if you're
knew how to look inside the Apple silver
and its
not big secrets are many open source
project to this on the subjects
Sola you have chance still see
walls elderly cancer are use it to the
this flesh and the you put try to figure
out how the war
and the 4i iPhone
for example and other Isles devices so
I'll
spirit data of every play space contains
actually do significant to our values
just the value is logical page number
soul is the number of logical page
is that maps to these physical page and
another a number at use the update
sequence number
soul when you're right in flesh for the
next time
any page this number is increasing by
while
its slow this is through for
I form for a CDMA modem it deals so some
up youth recently
inventor 200 I don't know how to say
ordered by EPL
a blessed i've called bpm perfect
Beijing you
so a its look kind of less typeset
bronte said there will be at No us
physically a broken pages
I don't know how well the to achieve
that but
up there are no but pages on that flesh
from
the point of love you for a lot less
control
so up when you look pale information to
both
logical page number and the about
sequence update number you could just
built lip Inc for any logical
page to multiple physical pages in
cortex order so
you could find multiple States of this
of some logical page and the facial be
ordered in time
and I believe it's it's very big
achievement
love for a whole point of view for rent
for forensic point of view
when you look could find how old this
file
lost change it during time you could
gift additional information
of unfortunately not every peach story
in multiple states
and some pages r us toward him single
the state last while
because prevails look what this was a
raise that we'll the
up a garbage collection or email pic
%uh but anyway you could build the
history and sometimes
and the several more sabol how to access
of less controller at the lowest level
up for sure our operating system have
that success
and Carmel half wait to read the
Comptroller
and the is there a up a colonel service
available inside the I also the
to a responsible for dealing quiz
user-level applications
that allow stool Rizza and right page us
on the flesh
and I'll the so I'll
level also was flown to in low I also he
and I also
4 but in all five Apple decided
2003 so people who want to use it
and as a just remove read support for
read and write requests souls
the us carol service still exists a a
tear for external metal so you could
call it but you call it
you could call it for obtaining class
Jorma tree you would find
was a number of plants number of pages
so the number of bytes a
you love up spirit area and so on
but you're unable to reads up pages
but the Azera at least to waive the
skull to bypass this limitation
a filth lol wat you still owe your
customized with Cornell
from previous morsel of love I also for
example aisles for
up bro you will have some problem we've
flown
filesystem at logical level because
there are some
improvements in Niles fife and I'll 60
related photo aisles for
but you will have the same level of
access the flesh
so you could just read data using hold
yourself operating system
and another approach you could just
modify colonel in memory
till force it to a already implemented
as a
read capability and after that again you
will be able to
read the data and the in love
around the school a distributed result
I also for more updates file so I PSV
a in some other sulser art glance I
publication is this clan
the not into computer and the
mobile phone but in Torrance caramel and
user
in in use or you have little
applications that
issues so request still
external metal to of layoff less control
or use our client
and reads data so you could find samples
how to how to do it I'll to work with
the sorts
and the
this technique a Los love people to look
Gipson content of less for a long while
all too well
a four devices the its slow although
I falls for o2 iPhone 40 I am
the first iPad and felt for generations
of people
%uh so low it's so you'll to a although
sellable clothes allows you to look
custom kernel and the
run an application like soul who are you
have
ability to get access to the stifles
over the phone
if you will jailbroken jolt device or
owner of the device jailbroken a game
you have
for the chance to modify colonel in my
memory
and the a again you could
are you old data from the flesh so but
sometimes you have problem because its
conflict with running
operating system and adjustable the full
sole you need to try
how to a code to force it war and the
for sure a if your Apple or half
good relationship with Apple for example
you are US government
I you could to ask able to sign you're
on these comps and
lost your Corolla and the around your
programs that will allows you to
read the whole doubles the flesh its
slow process for 64 gigabytes son
so devices it takes made 256
our first to read as a whole less but
for its could be da remover you need
just computer and
cable for iPhone and/or
up several more Tsubo how foreign stick
it to forensic if the
part of for criminal it criminalistics
so that
%uh search for proofs for the court
soul I'll 0 up general approach 404 s
exists
extract s many evidence thus s possible
was ok what defines us or sums evidence
unfortunately
a it's not to forensic a because
when you do that on your phone even
result loading operating system
flash controller starts walking and some
pre-made think
already called Akure so you could stop
this process actually orkut
up opens the device look on soldiers
that the flesh cheap
but in this case a you'll also
you will need to North Face another
problem was
all Motorola mobile so files devices so
use cover basic food groups in an all
day to start of flesh is aggrieved
so you could get data but all of the
data will be greeted
and you need to get some groups and keep
and that he is
embedded in process server so you
couldn't reads a key/value you could
just
run cold on processes up to outperform
operation was that the keys so
up early for you with us older the flesh
so you will not succeed
anyway but I'll
when you ought therefore reading of the
same device
twice you will get different results not
completely different spot
multiple pages would be rhamat between a
to let them sell free the date and
the main question though youth Vera
secure a way to a raise your date the
from the flesh on on such type of device
and dorsally for me I still have no
right and sore a not I'm not sure
s AC from the elderly to slurp
the more you'll drive its feel to it was
date the souls
the less amount of free space the first
or are they to a real return
to look a with raisins the whole block
but for example real slow some while
iPhone 4 the was just use a foot they
stink
I find 40 different Korpi solves the
a partition map also love the Phil
sector of the file
that now belongs to file systems that
false information about the
reach parts of flash storage are belongs
to reach logical logical partitions
and the I'm not by analyzing that 400
versions so I could for growth
I'll what may pink of law space also use
it to do you think I'm still a shelves
operating system so
you could just follow the logic over the
installer
just play it by seeing for different for
some because
a lot of free pay just left on the
device and there was no need to order it
rides I'll
up early you news that
lol modern mobile devices have ability
to load
remotely wipe all data and the
they did not by wiping every place on
flesh
say why pink only one significant part
of
that is encryption key it's a a randomly
generated when installing the operating
system
and after you raise it you will be
unable to read all data
and to avoid 20 such situation lamb
up by raisin key you actually not to
move to throw flesh
poll up my up some part of flesh
to special area called if a simple
storage
its motha are controlled by general
algorithms all three or leave a link
leveling it's the Campbell in other way
answer I'll special pot of flaw
I'll scold that up
use it to remove all data from that part
soul
no a muppet page sonata no pages up
half previous version those that he will
exist after a reason so EPL
think about it to the because in the eye
also reveals a
left a they hold he
in the last sector although the logical
partition and
raise it but it still preserved in
Lowell some
page of for summer all copy of some page
so I'll I don't know how to race less
properly up by re-installing Co
operating system on the Apple device you
for sure destroys the
friction key so nobody will be able to
create all the data
unless he already have your key for
example if he examined curator for the
hill
device before but a of still open
question love how to do it from software
layer
so what comments you need to issue on on
your device to erase that they
and I need to mention lol themself
my former company I worked for and part
of this research most performant so
do with my employment in Eltham south in
lower cooperation with the
111 ca %uh any
demand some guys from soviet-era
actually they made
so perfect research almost as the same
time like me and Andre
in last summer and the publisher 22 lol
its slow result solely if you need some
details or even cold that possibility
dorsally media was unable to compile
I'll souls to a you put just visited the
site
Soul Reaper so the article about
low-level love
access to Isles devices and the probably
will find additional information on the
subject and I want to thank
so through purse conference on the arm
w/
for the chance to present your my
research
and thank you for listening if you have
any questions I'll try to hustle
thank you thank you to the truth
I think one of of the most important
question was already on sought because I
think many people are interested how to
to whitewater the two flash memory in
the situation but some
okay we still have to wait other
questions about the topic
looks like everyone is our up wit
fight up thanks a lot
where is the mapping tables
toward and how is that not %uh
you overridden or erase too many times
actually all
might think is stored in two parts tell
sparked you slow
US plan and the logical page number
public schools number a logical page
numbers that start in the span
area of every page so high readings the
whole class
you put reveal that information and also
or a special page slow of call
must've lost love varies Ltd chance of
finding such pages
as a room at two and the era is use it
to store up
now they thought just correct
information lol
I'll for evolve less but I think many do
not utilize all of that information is
updated
and %uh next time you boot into %uh
plus come to love not to use it to eats
a whole class is just fine
the last all Tomas to blow and got also
mission froze up
souls %uh local is cited us
slow usual lost souls could be it to
raise the game
%uh if you need to love free space after
every time
your for 400 mutation of the
letting tables you just choose new feel
offense for information science
solo its again it's dynamically place it
in class but with
me some limitations
okay other questions pre
doesn't look like so delicious thank you
very much okay thank you