okay hi everyone and was talking about
hiking and Croft
so i've a electronic engineer
mostly a was for the kind of mechanical
hacker
a things and ans
currently studying to become a product
finer I'm it so the local as well as in
London
learning how to make RT shit like like
this a
so when you talk about crafting hacking
a people immediately
think about 3d printing is the as the
conservative confluence point between
other potential were packing and
printing stuff out into
into the 3d physical world a but in this
talk a lot of folks look more on
%uh low-tech so just before Christmas my
friend Connie
within by then and she was trying to get
this
keychain engraved with some mathematical
symbols
seems like a pretty pretty simple job
you take a 20 gravest
given the mission they should engrave it
but
a fortune you re engravers were set up
to either Stumpf
I with a I excessive metal stamps
ages that means a for you can certainly
some accents as well
and couldn't handle mathematical symbols
hot I am
she went to industrial laser engravers
they had some no problem engraving and
the a
any any shape possible ways that affect
the phone app but they couldn't deal
with
constructing the artwork in the right
file format so despite the fact that the
the technology is the is is progressing
after being
in the world laser cutting it without it
was impossible to Justin gave a simple
keychain
about two hundred years ago if you go to
any engraver shop on the corner
UX find a guy like this who would be
great hit with a hammer and chisel
and you could have almost any design if
you're seizing
engraved on the spot for somehow where
overall technology is the votes were
also for guessing some
existing technologies that work lush
more powerful in certain ways sir
I something the hacking is a former
Croft
Packers I'm calls people have I think
very much the same mine says
we've both focus on that the setting
things
and we I think both the things for
for the love doing a good job so it's
more Michael P
in 10 makes it economic ought to
timekeeping sense for
for us to design piece of software to be
extra modular and really extensible and
clean elegant
but we do it for the same we do it just
for its own
to the internal eighty doesn't
necessarily sorry official necessary but
it's a
we do if the love and that's definitely
something that the cross the forty
I'm I think hackers can lay in front of
people who I think of you can go from
hackers
and we can both end of a six-speed doing
the same kinds of things
so the first section is about using
hacking tools
for better Croft I wanna talk about it
Jeff Francis
I've gotta for takes all the moment a
have been working for Fears
reverse engineering inkjet printers to
make them a
much more powerful 3d printers so
favoring differences
work this way you have a a an incredible
ah
up on the left the a and being phased
out into a
a chamber where is heated rapidly and
get the checks its
by the the force of creating the steam
behind the drop is essentially
there's also this kind which is a pesar
electric
membrane seeking to flex duplex this
little membrane electrically
and then pump out a little chocolate
like that on us could drop
on going on Pisa printing this is a
crazy
you can go it's a media arts or a PC
world or whatever
a pickup a printer like this a for
yeah about forty erased possibly even
see for now and it can
second deposits for picking me to drop
this site tying a tiny droplets
huge degree of precision a its
instructors and got up I'm not sure
about
19 microns your hair is about fifty or
or 70 microns wide so it's the pretty
incredible that we can pick this
technology up for
such a low cost but the the question is
can we help this technology thing
achieve more
this is a very much a razor blades
business model
where the the the printer is sold
possibly it's a loss
to get you into a relationship with
manufacture
where you have to buy more more Inc
Andean cultures the
almost as expensive as the printer but
there's an opportunity obviously if we
can get for the
interface to the printhead and harness
this really high tech
printing technology to print of sherry
materials
maybe if you're into by attacking you
could use its print DNA arrays for
at the NASA a if you're a
took off to like me you might wanna
Prince Eltham I wax and use a pic of
things as well so applications
so anything on these machines the policy
see
a what are these print-outs which have
in this case for
teacher accepting red find reasons
yellow and black
inks and then on the other side a this
is the print plate
he might possibly not we'll see on this
projects over there's a
a paraffin gray lines down the middle is
always love
a inkjets I'm from print head nozzles
and though ninety
locals in align almost very very type it
I think that's about 20 meters wide
and then that is mighty black novels and
then 30 30 30
sign was entering its a very very high
density agnosio sup
print rapidly if you take it apart
further
that's what if it looks like and this is
what it looks like from the back
I can see the three ports for the colors
the 14 for the black
and this electrical interface here and
on that shit
on us flexible circuit board in the
middle that's all target
thats chip have a serial interface to
the or
yesterday mix serial and parallel
interface to the printer
and in family has some a multiplexing
which it uses to switch on to the
different levels we want what we want to
do
is a drive the print head is very low
levels so that we can
directly control over those whom we have
more access over the hardware consider
having just have
at scene photographs the mood or E-coli
mojito
some bullshit we just want to be noted
directly controlled in those
so that's that's the goal every girl in
a little bit closer
a we can see me this is appealing the
partying in five different had you can
see how the
how the ink is distributed from the
input port of into
up to little funny holes you can see
that the amount over
refinements and engineering complexity
in these
in the spring has is really incredible
and it's acceptable for
no money so definitely a good a good
hack
platform so there we're going to be able
to supply laboratory materials for the
printhead relevant issues the couch is
that we supplied
so I made with the reservoir Malave and
melts at the about the print head on
awesome so here we can see up
printer the places things interesting
stuff cook a
so I wanted to prints liquid wax on life
on my platform because I opens up
potentially 3d printing if you're pretty
tiny droplets they've
a a fellow file a Form
voice though is that material you can
make a.m.
quite complicated 3d structures with
opening tip printer
anything a lights a plume rise UV
polymer or
just directly using something like
blacks which you can heat up
Jets and says and that has an advantage
over conventional into
inc's because think tanks or suspension
a pigment particles
in the a liquid carrier and not the sort
of your problems with a into its getting
blocks and
Epson printers are famous for getting
blocks continuously because they have
the separation over
the intake of fish from the in Egypt I'm
a printhead which means the pin is very
high quality because the cultures
already just a dumb buckets in with the
engineering is in the printer
but obviously it means that be the pain
has compiled over just printing liquid
wax
it's no problem there are no pigment
particles we can just heat up the wax
and its liquid so there's a little
heater
sec ago I made this is a a big power
transistor which is essentially just
being used
as a heater just short of the transistor
in control occurrence
and they have a heater and then just
next to is the temperature sensor
and a a little bit of control
electronics see set the temperature
a you can see that the the
he's a part of it works you know what
actually comes out also that was easy
next business which I ataxia the pinhead
itself so
because the ports a very small we needed
a kinda gasket material for
officially gotten so we just use the
later cuz its cuz else a little caskets
I also a double sided sticky tape for
the second half
a really cheap quick khaki wave doing
some kind of
almost microfluidic assembly
if there's a the print head with the
gaskets a oh and yes but didn't actually
work
have because the because I have a V
double sided tape fails very quickly
with the
being overheated in separate so then we
tried
a silicone sealant from a being
deposited by
stenciling its release cut and sew
sweetie over the Senseo and then
you've got your precision silicone
gasket and now works for a little while
but eventually became became
and that's the main problem with this
machine moment this is very leaky so you
have any ideas for better feeling
they let me go finally eleven upon some
place a couple other gaskets and some
mechanical
confessions if it wins place and let us
about work
so reverse engineering electrical
interface there's been a few times this
in the past
for various Epson printers a
particularly the possum for Chase recall
this is a DNA printer
a cove where an American University
it it turns out that's the a
inkjet printers are a very well-used
research tool of people use them
particularly in and biotechnology
usually they use
up in the city research grades machines
that it may be a few hundred thousand
follows um and really they have almost
identical
capability to your 40 euro a
medium large printer terms if the
chocolate sizing
everything but the be only difference
between two couples
if the the said the party platform is
it was like to be hackable is something
that you can I'll
adjust the to the kind of driveway forms
to just how the
how different things like was work it's
just exactly like the
Epson printer but you just have more
access so the question is can we buy
reverse engineering re
Epson printer create a korchi style
packable platform for less than a few
hundred thousand dollars
India a spoiler the author is yes
so the first place to look when your
service engineer peace effect consumer
electronics
is look at the patents reading them is
exceptionally painful and I would
recommend doing that
but if you just look at the pictures you
can begin to get a a an idea what's
going on
this is the election in space between
the the printer and the printhead
it consists of a a to Serial Bus is
for byculla and black tater
I'm not entirely sure why the set for
this is probably some luv
a.m. auctions Rizzo gradually evolving
the stand is back and forth the
different different platforms
a also the top be this is a an analog
wait for which is actually delivered to
the
the PC a membrane actuator the soaring
the first flight so the as a the
ramp goes up that's the a very much maps
onto the physical motion
if the diaphragm moving up to fuck in
the ink and that
moved up slowly and then that rapid
downwards
a of the curve is the dropping injected
and as the flood recovery for the but I
found to be back up again
said just by controlling the shape of
this I love wait for
we can control the motion if the
printhead
and potentially adapts to different
kinds of things that different
different periodic properties
and you can see the the this patent is
talking about having
different parts of the printing cycles
that you can pretty actually different I
i misses a topless
and have different levels of grayscale
just completely nuts better for my
fly thing I was any interest in getting
Inc out different have nothing more
so here it is a the kindest domestic
level a
the top we have a away form and in that
controller IC which was the
a the small brown objects on the
flexible circuit board
on that something will be able to
control internally has
control over some switches and
essentially multiplexes the analog
waveform
on for the different droplet firing
missiles
and by setting up the image they serve
the serial bus you connect
for example we know the second third and
fifth novel for the high voltage
and then when you give it the high
voltage spike outcomes being from the
image
now look set up print data bus on the
left this thing which I to hack
so they'll also have a really cheap open
source
packing tools available this is the open
bench logic sniffer which is a really
cheap things about
thirty-year a a quite high speed power
help of sniffer
I just attach to between the printer in
the print heads his bedroom asking see
that
with me printer with me USB connection
coming in from my laptop in the existing
printer control board there
and about Justin's affected the ribbon
cable that leads to the printhead
and a task that logic sniffer which is
in the middle Asus capturing some traces
for this is the this is the the traces
captured from the a
from the print head and I was very happy
to see that they lined up
pretty closely with both in the patent
so immediately I was able to figure out
what the different
I'm signals were a and I built my own
piece of hardware to
to try to replicate those signals this
is basically a kind of
flexible development platform for
controlling
the shape of the analog I'm way forms
that
delivered to the top clips /a drivers
and also for just love
um adopting the Paulo bosses as as
necessary so the moment this doesn't
have reserve USB interface for anything
it just takes
a prefect image which you load onto it a
let
produces the Creek Drive signals
that's for my way my away forms look
like play a
II Section inspiration from the date
sheet but from the apartment and also
from the
a.m. from the way from that I recorded
from the Epson printer
but I found the printing the wax was
very different from printing the
water-based Inc find a buyer about with
the the shape of the way form to
tries to get anything out of print head
but I did manage to eventually I guess
and drop it out
and its thermal is quite a flexible
working for for love
released Olivia the the materials if
you're interested in designing your own
and hacking your own printer
potentially has yellow portion a
a memory attached to it digital to
analog converter
a high voltage amplifier a so you can
actually
this visa way for the directly
synthesized from every
you can you can actually just see on the
on the slow possible trace
individual bits in the a in the way for
step-by-step so we have really any shape
way for we like
and about that makes it quite flexible
for printing different materials
so this is the complete attacking
packing powerful we've got my
a my control interface their next to is
the temperature control over this
maintaining the the printhead 54 degrees
a.m. and then there's the be will
mechanics is just harvested from
a couple of printers and put back
together again your VM
that backing board also have a couple a
stepper motor drivers as well so it can
to the motion control part as well so
results
a this is the LEGO brick and on under
the microscope
a if we see if you can see that we've
inkjet in just its allies wax their
on for some observed a copper substrate
was interested in using the wax is a a
as a service for printing circuit boards
as well as for printing 3d wax objects
thought I was pretty little actual to
copper to see how the a how materials
such together
this is my favorite photo is of some
tiny 3d structures
a made out of laxity the tiny droplets
fuck
stocked up each one is 1000 drops
hi and again this is also for the leg or
breaks you can see that the
the technology is capable of some pretty
ridiculous a
3d revolution and this was after
obscene also I they should it so well I
was really lucky a
as soon as I could get away from the
right shape to get blacks actually to
come out a thing
speculated recover it for in and and
this is what I came up with those
I was very happy I think there's a lot
over potential for taking a quiet if
ever
that's a close-up view follow these
things
pretty crazy I had those lucky enough to
have access to
a go to university professors friends
with
a composite microscope set up so this is
gonna come visit me too
locals the photos a different focus
that's the case we see the 3d structure
thing quite nicely
a.m. here it is printed out onto a
a piece of copper rose to print a solid
square head
other than one st I actually came out
with the individual was the initial
print calls is a bit messy but
for this there's always the quiet hi to
the resolution a accessible as well for
making
second both potentially I thought I try
to print this out with his lawyer
this is my pre flashed a third occasions
my controller foresee this is the
biggest image I can print at the moment
you too
yeah by lack of flash memory already got
a few hundred k to play with
I'm it is that isn't a good to go to be
badly but
superior comfort you can fit printing
their
about a small window look for sure yaaa
can see the image coming out
motion control happening
all of the images that comes out and
services on copper so I've tried dat
shit
and played a little fed report a outside
for
so this is a try to personal revelation
that a little bit further you can see
the edge over one year according to
and we both know quite quite dense text
that i think is that it's definitely a
to be a promising a rapid prototyping
technology for printed circuit boards
and also I think printing 3d
wax objects say that is what I've got a
text when I get around to it
a hopefully at the moment is also
problems with Apple
getting into the system makes me feel
like Nicki pinhead to
reservoir interfaces and as soon as
their droplets the
as if there ever was in there the whole
thing just fails and you have to have
pump it all back through so I need a
better way of priming the nose
incident Leo epstein printer printer
does this as well as a little um
a little kinda vacuum cup for women also
when the
when it pops the pretty the carriage
that of your pages here
what's this finish printing it means
that carried over here parks and then
this lol
platform comes I'll sucks a with little
personal site publisher sucks all the
ink three to try to clear it out a
bubble 30
I need to implement something similar if
unbelievable the open to those with for
forty years I just
can't believe it so yeah this is a on
this is from a commercial a wax Inc
testing machine
a.m. that exists for rapid prototyping
jury and a and then talk of things
so this is a this is a commercial
technology but the the machines oversee
crazy expensive and also extremely slow
the
the machine that prints Prince this
thing out
he has won things and also I'll
thank you as the because of flawed
objects like think this is a really
powerful technique this is an ancient
ancient tradition lost wax casting
I'll where usually soul call
lack subjects a and then converted into
metal
it has the advantage of being
ridiculously high resolutions the via
the wax is really almost perfectly
represented in metal the in the process
but unfortunately it destroys the moss
to up but when you combine it with 3d
printing you can print out what's lost
is
in Polk and potentially make a as many
ridiculously high resolution copies as
you like
so I use this technique for June retail
sales just
included this you can see the kinda
rough process the starter for the whites
loss to
assesses up on a base mix up some pasta
up ford also backing out the air bubbles
put it in a kiln to file the offensive
very weak lost so Paris a material
into a very high temperature a so very
high impact ceramic
a which also has some course that it's
so the actress Kate 24 the matalin
a and then after a few hours in the kiln
the foster Paris has become space hopper
to
you can pull the liquid level in the top
a and I'm using a vacuum table hits you
cool the air
also the mole to allow the metal support
went off
and that is pretty amazing media
actually um
just gets through pulled through the
polls in the a
in the process so this is a completely
solid block a blast so there are no
holes or anything but
the because of the extremely small force
so just by putting a vacuum
table on the bottom play really hard
vacuum that's an officer
Fulham is there an insult I had many
failed attempts like that's
as I go centrifuge see pumper relaxing
holiday upon the
so over it harder and I got some quite
nice results at the end
muncie tied it up a bit you end up with
a 3d object
so this will in 3d printed this was
crafted by hand in the
making the weight loss to take a long
time I'm very excited about the a the
possibility
doing it a cat fancy I'm also an
competency
metal so that was packing for better
Crofts
up the next day with second half my talk
is about using
Croft for better hacking as so this is a
project like this
a fans a news they wanted this payroll
um do you video display some losses
%uh to display the lyrics to the songs
while there on stage
could be crazy go see through them a
yeah whatever pays the bills
says a yeah they often forget their own
their
X yea well eg it's been very dovish
K for say hey I thought of it so it
works to make it to make a 3d
efficiency to to sell the products that
basically but then
there wasn't really time to actually
have them a CNC machine tool
and then they can really be 3d printed
cuz they have to be very
robust for for touring a and surviving
the cut across conditions a
have a touring performance so I just
made everything
initially by hand with sores and files
in this a plastic
a a.m. pretty traditional craft
techniques
so yeah printed out my cat in in 2d
stuck it on top of the a the bits a
plastic and coming out with us or
I let him take enough photos for you can
see the author as the kinda starting
point you can nominate also layers if
this
this material is called acetate
cellulose acetate plastic
a and its basically not used anymore for
anything other than
custom spectacle frames because of
classical takes an hour since the
injection molded Torre
sometimes machines a but this stuff is
is is really optimized for working with
your hands you can get
if the Hazrat very nicely with the so
conventional
woodworking tools essentially and a used
to be
Eastern Cape very common for spectacle
manufacturers to make their frames this
way by hand
I'm has lost property of being so little
in North partially soluble in acetone
see you can layout
many layers a the plastic and then on
them all together with a a saintly
and then of the sounding and cussing you
can get some quite nice
3 services wants to get back curved
shapes you can also see them perform
this material so I
played a little wooden mold with the
seven degree
thankful that I wanted late the plastic
on top just it is up with that
with a hairdryer and it just to traipse
beautifully over the plastic notes the
only inning sophisticated
just the basic tools was the that the
two
always need to be connected electrically
so there's this little tunnel that the
case either between the laminated layers
and allows the a single skate 3 so when
it's a bit more
ok if you will for I'm photographs
making the the temples the site pieces
the classes so via so for the plastic
object print out the image from
SolidWorks and just my little sore
cut out the shape far let's get the 3d
come to us
sounded a Senate west to make it nice
neat surface
and then but a milling here just to
attach the hinge pieces I am
toolmaking is really important step and
something that the hacking cough world's
definitely share sometimes it's worth
just making a custom tool just for one
job
and this was a little custom GI made for
manufacturing other little
side pieces %uh the hinge rivets
a so this is a a wave basis that the
chick for cussing
also pieces metals the same length and
injuring two holes in
for accurate position and using that to
like to make a few things that all
a diesel silver pieces I had to make
many of them cuz I kept messing up the
%uh the next part which was
soldiering the little pins on the back
to make a vivid so those the four rivets
that we're the closest together
a you can I'm silver sold them than
you have to remove the flux a of the
woods this is a a weak acid solutions is
just as of the flux
for Slough and they have some supplies
over this
if it's a different place another
peaceful aspect to this
this plastic is them that you can
actually
polish a chemically say instead of
having to go through you
finer and finer and finer grades some
paper let's hope agrees
you can just get it roughly to a student
reasonable finish
and then poke it in plastic in ascertain
for a few minutes
in the surface will serve partially
dissolve away and leave you this perfect
it was perfect finishes up the
terrifying of course because if you do
that soon on
you just end up with some sludge say
yeah I I did manage to dissolve one face
a little bit too far
I was very sad about so that the another
muscle feature this loss these
losses they perceive the and accuse
for playing the content the constant
speed record on that office but they
have to be synchronized up to the site
so this this the RF link to the glosses
and the antenna is a little
a little while others buried inside the
plastic over over year
when it comes out to him so so quite
nicely a packed away and
us with a live from the back a.m. I made
these things to place again same way
print out the cat data
cut-out with us or um I use the laser
engraver hit see
a.m. mark the backs via
with losses this is real real
combination of the old and the new using
simple saw to cut out the sake then I've
gotta I've got a little
CNC laser engraver this use this for
coming out
a coming out level but it's it's it's
very nice a sieve mocking
sepsis actually I i think im gonna
skippers on this but I want to make some
classic
inserts to attach the a to such that
level two classic a chance
I wanted to know the services to make
them rough so they could
bed into the classic family a and
I don't have a tool that can a the
company work on such a small things I
made this ruling so
out a pair cigarette lighters so again
if I'm that kinda very use mentalities
we've got around to can
you can really make some quite nice
tools doing some quite precise work
a staffing little inserts and since the
plastic
and he's a he's a very small fast as the
one millimeter screw
excellent service the same but in the
past second is quite possible to make
all this stuff
just with you have seemed a little bit
of practice
so it was the electronics inside the
losses this is a
a ASTM 32
a Cortex m4 development powerful
and adjusters Minh City Gaza talks a lot
of
a people coming from the
the more civ informatics I to packing
traditional
a software engineers and
and security guys and when they come to
the world of
over hardware a starting from
maybe scratch a is quite often to pick
up
the Paco make a tools that are around
what we ought we know performance of I
got
but I think now um I really wouldn't go
for the art we know I'd go for something
much more powerful because they're all
some
a incredibly powerful embedded hardware
platforms coming out
that all easy to use a little extra
point of view maybe less easy to use my
software point of view but you guys are
all
your approach so for people say I you
really have access to some incredible
tools this is a
10 euro PCB you can get from Farnell
a in Germany I and it's got a hundred
sixty-eight make
cortex and fork or make a gram
and some really amazing for for this
cause I like seventeen different on the
modules that can configure
analog inputs and outputs and it's way
more calls than anything in the kinda
out we know make a movement
seen and I i yes surely people all
moving across the
a via the software tools for driving
these things occur in a bit of a pain
but
a you guys can handle it well you see
who fucks i text message
as a good place to start because it's
I'm very easy to
very easy to use as you can most this is
a commercial EVA tools I'll
really expensive but this one's free
it's got pretty good the next support
snow open source unfortunately there are
a KYC at NGO which
open source a PCB editing tools
a which all pretty decent but
to us $3.00 for some reason a this is
the
PCB layout so good
can use to hit me yep good if if
so PCB layouts from your sensei take
your take your
I topper logical view from your
schematic editor that was the the white
step
you can export see the kind of
topographical view
which is that the physical connections
in in copper and then use the layout of
the tracks
and you end up with the with the design
like that for this is four layers of
copper
a with lace the wiring on the inside and
the outside and some power
power planes in the in the middle a it
is quite a quite a dense design but its
a still fairly easy to do with these
the these quite quite cheap and
accessible tools
so once you got your circuit um we
didn't actually have time to
a to get it assembled by a by PCB
assembly house
fortune is quite easy to do it associate
your karoge
I'll you can gets the you can order the
PCB's
a all the some pretty rapid services
this one's actually Forte
a four-day turnaround to get the PCB
from a
email to a physical objects in my head
say they're all
really really Rapids PCB fabrication
services available now
a will say if you want to see so that
that was very expensive to get very high
quality PCB
in a very short period of time if you
want a very cheap prototype
you can go to China a and with about two
weeks you can get custom PCB's for
ridiculously low prices like 20 years or
something
and go see if subjects of back and forth
in China has been refined but very cheap
um this does really easy to get access
to
a you can also order these stencils up
for
applying the soul though so the these
this came from a UK company
has a one-day again a one-day turnaround
for forty Pouncey
email some cat data and they'll ship
your LASIK I'll stencil for trying a
soda
then you can just take your soda paste
so the place is a bit like
caviar is tiny tiny balls a soda in this
kinda liquid
a if looks good a so it behaves much
like toothpaste you can kinda squeegee
on C or
on to your contacts and then when he set
up the little balls a soda melts and
then
a.m. could do together and form for your
joints
influx gonna boils away a so this is an
alternative to soaring by hand
and it's this is hell production
electronics is late
in huge quantities the soldiers stand
sort and
the parts place by robot busty placing
the pulse pretty easy so
16 10 secure components you end up with
hopefully a little perfect oil
love solder paste on each pass a
slightly sticky so it's quite easy
just place a component on top sticks to
the
sticks the solder paste quite nicely a
for about 30 race you can get a toaster
oven us replace the
you know several thousand pound
industrial unit Leslie us the profile
this with the fam a couple
closer to grow of I pretty much fits the
to
hits the JEDEC to which is the
industrial body to
that regulate substandard PCB assembly
it pretty much
hits the time temperature profile cuz a
with the Praxis gonna jiggling the
normal opening the door the right side
you can actually hit here
hit the specs pretty tight a soft about
the they come out with all the
components over the place
and the just give you an idea of time
this was
four circuits with several hundred
components on each one
a and probably forty or fifty different
types of components least one
and once with a little butter prices you
can get quite replacing I think I
I started I started assembling this
project I started squeezing the solder
paste to 11 p.m.
and by 4 a.m. I had for a
complete circuit so is a very very fast
wave
a producing very high-quality output
prima Croft 11 back in you can to if you
don't have time to make
motor pool a bits of development
hardware I estimate one PCB intensive
Cup it's a pardon
the and stuff too test it before
integrating into the classes
discussing that lasts a to make the from
pedals losses
the system organic LED displays a.m.
from China
Alibaba express a talk called is the way
to go
for a it credit who
components the kinda stuff any year some
sonya putting into the mobile phones
are available on Alibaba express a for
pretty after chipping in pretty life
volume say
you gonna be prepared to do it or
emailing back and forth the
and deal with it but its English you end
up with some
pretty amazing access to parts if you're
prepared to
go through the pain a yet this is the
simple device from the back says choir
quite then since Integrated Products and
is not far away for a visa consumer
electronics at this point you know
you've got a custom enclosure
I which would only be an injection
molded part with tens of thousands
view reserve tooling costs made that
with my hands with you know for a couple
days work
I ended up the same policy is as you
could have a
injection molded so it really is
possible to you see
really simple craft techniques to make
consumer
a level out for overseeing a prototype
volume
but if you're doing a Kickstarter
project or something you want to impress
somebody
it might be worth a.m. 3d printing
something that's
a going to resemble but not completely
emulate the final output
in last possible with handcraft
techniques to achieve the final outputs
just using a bit if develop a decrease
in the a bit patients
so this one advocating the sort of Croft
and hacking fusion together you can
actually produce very high-quality
output
so it's fun for blacks a no security
ahead
a safe area later very a
also wants its citizens over security
call I want to somehow justify my
presence here
by starting some conversations about to
attack aircraft
and a security implications i mean
obviously as
implications in physical security up
because a lot of our audience that
they've been
a in the in the media about kind of the
house its 3d printing and
and homemade home 8 a.m. guns or
this is well a bit closer to home German
hacker
ray a made these three different keys
that hope
a I think as last year and
defeatism shitty handcuffs with them so
this the something happening in the in
the in the physical security
whirls a in the confluence if
Crofton packing sunny lockpicking that
I'm not exactly certain what it's going
to and offers
us is my work so i just want to mention
that we love this stuff was essentially
done
in my flats a student at the moment I
have a lot special cash
saga 1 workshop one living room
everything space
we're together say a no excuse to go
if you've got a bit of disposable income
what you IT security professionals you
can
some for the division 2 tools and that's
that it's a solid investment
so you're there were cops like details
you got any more information the
thanks very much
thank you very much with crew yeah i
working with you
for work in the video to go on his
summer
we go to a swim
we do we have the to include your
connection here you're a player
a plugin was so close that possible
thanks
see what happens it's also her father
it it's a bluesy yes it looks like
floor of
it's the
u2's and
dreams
yes we can
yes
questions yes sprayed with greater
so i'm used must have given you some
disposable income the
through yeah
very obvious
this is just a month but going to look
like there's a
so the glasses they that display that
the like something I would say to that
the audience a about that
the big bro
dealing with by rebuild the added I
okay more questions or
we would like just what's the deal the
fifth
%uh I
definitely do with the vision problem
250 better
I does he look at bill begins in tiny
periscope Invidia exhaust
I with out a bit over lenses
and if possible to use your mobile phone
with men
for the camera is only about you can
identify with expenses
Maria co-pays you can see the world
down into a tiny when using SIFT sounds
horrible the movies
she said my name is a big project it
back to life inside
I less I thought I'd different from
they look more questions
good
celebrations
as fellow at paper for the crosses as
yeah cool
if it was up to the bachelor and the on
the board yeah it is
I'll show you the say the inside you
was the last player to be named some
roads are slick losses
this is absolutely the perfect
absolutely everything is a
is with the Impala that is a pretty good
they say they are pretty high
feel like I still say feel lazy you will
really like the salt star
the 14 once Road the
way the basic for sends enzymes
decide no yet the highest
of weaponry is he said you think about
are you both go to a views about $300
million our
battery Cassell these with a
the informed by grew up
worked in the end is about to attend win
six movies
think PCP way
and and adhesive stuff
girl
support
point
is that the aft
21b radio yeah if okay
%ah whereby tickets for Muse concert
Rosa
where to buy tickets for Muse concert
cop
hood yeah has been through
our security orbit so yeah healthier
every for you days yet
so Jeff what are you going to do after
the talk
oh yes oh yes a for you with you don't
answer
just on from your designs to 1:48 left
Treasury and it's about with her is
about the size the
surveillance personal surveillance tools
living in a tizzy
feature like you yes I
over just saw this so not through the
this the sounds and I love to talk to
you guys about surveillance
in public here you
both actual you just know it was about
your way
hands the public needs some
response you see I think sir
possibly with a open source surveillance
tools and
totally distribution between governments
or the
police forces or with her love
corporations access
Jose and our with and
perhaps if we except things out
maybe we just need salsa use of those
watches us aidid
yes as you can so on media a break I
very you see sony vivaz I feel because
those
the physical stays both
the with
it
and South say he was the only thoughts
would like to you majority of words
will his lace I just worry about
on a yep okay thank you very much
F