up a lower-body car
want one thing set first a within
minutes to turn this camera into a
rocket launcher
we tried calling you but the and and
than 50 well
okay so um hello
to the first talk today I'll
like michael says it's all about come
across I'm packing stuff
so we're both from here in W on the side
this nothing you I'll so let's take a
look at the good
to we will first ever saw the
introduction
what is this talk all about what's this
%uh may be interesting to
to a camera all such a thing then
obviously this camera has something to
do with IPS a talk titled sets
so we have a look at the rear transport
protocols that are in use
we also had a look at the different
communication mode this camera uses
and we figured out some
attacks against this camera arm
and yet there will be a few conclusions
I'll
fault will come to this later okay
so arm first of all what this is about
and
the last one or two years there are
a lot of cameras dropping into the
market which came with which come with
some my IP connectivity all some network
connectivity
a just to make the thing fans here to
make it
more usable to look at the photograph
like up
the chance to upload pictures in into
the clouds on the fly on
all that fancy stuff arm also
this opens up new attack house and
potential security risks um
we have focus on this device in front
this is the ER
you swung the axe which is the latest
biggest rate this
camera are from Canton so
this has all the the connectivity itself
up and by the way takes great pictures
so but the camera
up up nearly the same size
saw arm I got a bit of marketing here
this is directly from the
Canon USA website at South
okay um it has a built-in Ethernet port
and it allows fast and easy transfer
%uh from the client life events directly
to
the network or a PC absence good
I'll also there is some
wireless file transmitter which is up to
No
to the camera um so it also can do wifi
missus yup pretty cool if you want to
use the stuff for
like I said transferring images or
other things but also it means the
camera doesn't
you need to be attached to network like
physically attached
to get into our attacks okay so here's a
screenshot way see the
is an import on one side of the camera
and
also this little great thing on the site
is like the the WiFi module okay
um so who is the potential target of our
attacks
yeah it could be remiss to Reuters or
room some people working for him and
they usually wear this kind of equipment
with like the rocket launcher lenses in
front of the
and a those kind of people
tried to I'll set up and passos
I'm wait for other people's so
yet both those are pretty much the
targets arm
so what if one evolve
kind of guy could get the real on it it
images first directly from the camera
before they go through some
censorship of stuff like that all
what if one could upload but ima just a
camera
and after the event just point out the
cameraman and so
oh you up I think you know some quite
interesting photos on this camera
%uh you should take a look at the cover
um
also what if one could turn the camera
into the surveillance device
cuz yeah this camera obviously it could
take
in Texas %uh pictures on so but
what if the camera to take pictures when
you don't expect okay we will come back
to all those questions later
and seeing or we can also
okay so so much to the
introduction so it's pretty much all
about the camera and its network
connectivity
features but also about kind of new
attack of are like up
your all the good stuff's coming back
okay so I love when we start no research
the first thing was like to get hands on
one of those cameras
but wasn't that he's in the first place
up
after quite some convincing up we
managed to get one
so we played around with the network
connectivity
and we started at the lower level so we
first a look at the underlying protocols
which in this case
obviously is if another as a different
port
but give also Wireless lan:
wire--the while the songs
arm over or this face layouts or
protocols
on the cameras FaceTime speaks than a to
Skype you
it doesn't implement ipv6 yet
so your everybody's using a few for
of course so you don't need ipv6
as a like that I think can I think so
okay so we're at a look at the
traditional attacks
we also started on a layer 2 and we
figured out so
ops moving on the cameras isn't it
rubles so it s
nothing like sticky up and freeze or arm
something like that also if you just
float the camera will
love of I could just like around 100
packets
seconds but still not done much but its
enough to just do not have service so
that works like if the car
I'll obviously it's built for taking
pictures and not
for withstanding if attacks
so arm I was nothing surprising
so nothing new here on it's just good to
know that these attacks
still work on that kind of equipment
so we moved up the layer or a bit
so we get to lay a three-layer for which
is standard TCP IP
just and all the scenarios on
we also figure out all we're tester and
its came out that's physically
connections are
easily resolvable why just sending
disappear reset
so also on this layer nothing new but
keep this in mind it will come back
later on
okay so all along for camera
itself got different communication modes
so you have a big man you a lot of
configuration of turns I'm you can
two's between for different called
communication modes
so the first thing is the to have to be
uploaded mod's
business your just playing 2k so the
camera takes a picture
I'm instantly uploads the picture to
on FTP server and network
for second communication mode this deal
and a
which is some kinda a standardized
interface for
I'm consumer media devices to exchange
your consumer media I guess arm
for this camera also features to appear
deal in a I'll like protocol stack
it also got a built-in web server I'm I
was wondering why vote
I think just because it's cool or
because everybody know those needs to
have a built-in web server
and then there is a a proprietary
fall moat which is the so-called use
utility mode
which nitsa proprietary can um
software installed on your PC to you're
like remote control the camera
okay now this is
mania the Sun a for communication modes
up we have a look each of those moats
I'll
we will just go through them of one by
one
okay so let's start off with the f2p
out yes
formals side
all us
fun
yeah so just %uh 20
just me this
well you stuck
in
check check take us
yeah so you can look at the for
at first we had a look at the FTP Upload
mode and
yet just two points above something out
so
how you configure it and home
you have to use a camera so
there are some buttons and the
small joystick in at the back of the
camera
to for all through the menu and so stuff
and yeah obviously you have to provide
a the target server and
looking for dan Schultz a into the menu
so the camera know so which will upload
the pictures
and yeah maybe some
non-technical guy once to
a yet wants to minimize the efforts to
taken the password and and stuff and the
just choose a week 1 to
used less the characters for example
because he's not then to the into the
security
and yeah of course maybe also with the
up as well as for the wifi and
yell in case of the FTP up remote
if it's connect its to the network
and you pull the trigger the
shoulda parts of to the pictures shot it
immediately
tries to upload to picture to the FTP so
and your you don't sites
of FTP of you might know
STP is playing to text no
crypto at all yes along although also
nothing new here but we're just
went through all the different
communication notes
yet and because of that once you are
in a man in the middle position or else
we call it in this talk
men in the image below um
you are easily the able to
sniff credentials because this
transmitted in plain text
just said look at you have a look at you
Wireshark
and also
you are able to the sniff all of the
data transmitted
so you can also easily expect
every picture the camera close to the
FTP server
and you may be able to um upload your
own pictures
to the FTP server of the photographer
or the contractor of 24 paparazzi
or yet the FTP server
of another attack a I have no idea
and yeah
as it's easy to the
spot the credentials in a way short term
for example
we r I just want to show how you how
easy this
to restrict the pictures because
from some few might not know how to
extract
pictures from without Wireshark with
right click or something
boats you just used to you
or shell so hero two screenshots
one on this in 10 of the the next slide
so we have our um
host misstep packages in this trace file
and just use TCP flow TCP flow is
them a tool to extract
every TCP stream out of work capture
and you sick leave TCP flow stores them
and separate files so
every one of these files this a known
TCP flow for example every
ftp command sent to the server the login
already put come on for every image
then we just use
foremost which is in recovery tool
full forensics or recovering Daytona
corrupt its
from I'll try for stick
from frightful something and we just
provide
every the every of these files
um extracted by TCP flow
and what for most us is it creates these
open folder in your working directory
and stores lock files what he was able
to
extracts and also
all the the files he was able to extract
in the typical flexible
and all of these pictures from was taken
by the by the camera
and uploaded to FTP to the FTP server
and
all of these pictures can be expected
from no just with to a command-line
tools on
standards the Linux system
though there is one downside for example
if you have
some pickles any FTP connection there
might be some
yeah some shifts in the picture
the to to spot %uh and book they might
be easier for you
easily recoverable were I think also
retransmission parts of the image
yeah me but that was the case by
and in one of peace 14 images
so yeah thus basically it's
on the FTP site
and we want to mix with the on a moat
RK so all the second moats so-called
communication mode of this camera
yes the deal than a Moz yeah we are
certified we've got a nice logo here
up we speak didn't deal on a swell so
but what is it about the other it stands
for digital
Living Network Alliance register
I and is like to own
and mixture of protocols and file
formats
um which are used to transfer
media between different media devices as
I said it's small for the a consumer
device those
like you maybe a year to be at home
speak stealing a so it has a network
connect to an or once it's connected to
the network and the cameras connected to
the network
they both just on send out
UPnP packages to the local network and
discover each other and then figure out
oh yeah the camera got some pictures
over there I'm able to display pictures
maybe use a want to
%uh see the pictures on the camera on so
on and so on
and in this whole process they mainly
use a like I said UPnP for discovery
so to find other devices also capable of
given day and once they found those
devices
values just plane HTTP and
a XML to excess the media
so there are some XML file its on the
camera which can be
just download it which describe liked it
I'll
directory structure or all the images
inside of the cover of
and also they contain links to actual
media files
so arm the downside of the land a
is okay there s no authentication at all
so if you see a deal on a speaker in the
network's second just access it
0 also
there are no restrictions that of
so defined discoverer of on the network
in a deal on a moat
I can access all the image to start to
become
I can access all movies on the camera
and
also yeah I can
download all the images can enumerate
them
and just crap about of the camera
um also idoney any tool for this
because my browser could didn't
eliminate client
a set then use mainly HTTP as a transfer
protocol
and a XOM out to describe their
structures so yeah I could also be
Indialantic
clients just browsing to the camera
arm so dealer named this plain and
simple
off but it got no security features
okay I will help back over to POSCO and
now the good stuff starts the beginning
like the the first two Moz we're kind of
boring
nothing special nothing new we just get
the mattress
but not all something good comes yet the
text part is the bills & Observer of the
camera
and have it on the web that pic the
publication is always a good
so this moats its lease coltie Wireless
file transmitter server mode
which is actually the wifi deweiss
sysname also wireless file transmitter
so and another marketing
as a from can you say
Kansas use a frozen to capture
you and download images remotely
so what if someone else
is also able to capture view and
download
images remotely without
knowledge of the owner of tomorrow
and
the web interface of the camera is
basically
some small Ajax I can the
kind of thing and the embedded Web
server is
only capitol capable also managed of
handling h2b get requests
yet it's an actually it's an embedded
system so it's not that powerful
and just keep it simple
and do what you can with the stuff you
were able to handle
maybe the thoughts of the developers and
every other request method this concert
was a full for
response so
yet even had request for justice for all
yet
so they Fay doesn't implement anything
else than
HDPE get so basically if they
implement that the equity 86 requests
and responses and
and Flickr click stuff and
sending stuff to the web server lawyer
firm
get perimeters and the
camera with XML which is parsed
for why a javascript on blindside
so that's all they implement it there
extent interface
just whistling the it HDPE
gets method
and also
Veris some notification
for me yep the that service
more your bets over actually uses
shitty HTTP basic a alt
what only on one specific
you are I so if you post to the IP
of the camera you will get 4 waters
to the lookin a page
or through the specifics euro well the
us over response with them the meat of
them
authentication my out pitch to the basic
after you've of indicators successfully
the
took you two sips and all the other
the urals just request is the cookie
a.m.
authenticated or not intel's it will
a.m. redirects you to page which set
which this there is a someone else on
this over
for you already you're not logged in
please go to decide and
lookin another time
and let's have a look at the session
cookie
yes was what what's
what's wrong with it to the basics of
yeah there's no transport
a.m. sperm yeah
encryption there's no the encryption at
all
via the between the camera and you feel
broza
so once your again man in the middle
you can also sniff the the looking
financials
but as as we may the see in a couple
slice
we don't meet them we don't BT
credentials at all
so that's heavy the have a look at this
cookie
the cookie looks like this session IV
and surrendering nothing wrong about it
but this string is rather short so
this is a 4-byte session ID
this also means the total number
of possible session ID's this forever
low so and what do you think
how long would take to uproot force
65,000 different 80s
on a web server
yeah and be just thought we saw the
session ID
and its its for quite it's basically an
integer
and we just thought
WTF because it's the a WTF
so up so from yeah as it says in the
name
says they just a.m. spots
two characters and so
the set before its simple to prove false
love four bytes session the ID cookie
we just implemented in six lines of
Python code
and to check all of the possible ID's
its took yeah 18 to 20 minutes
just because the a embedded Web server
was just able to manage one request at a
time
and has a yeah and it took some time up
to one second per request
and it's an embedded system its bills to
take pictures not for serving portal
something
and we just recorded in
shorty mo I'm all speed
foot forcing and setting the cookie and
accessing the web server
I will show you
so your I am year in studying
our pet scripts and you see the pros in
the background
and as I said before it's
takes the up to 20 minutes but we took
care that these
the session ID you read use an odorless
where the low
I've just seen some session it is that
have only
to characters in it and
yeah think me just a.m.
some of them may just have one bites
of assessment of yeah interview if
you're lucky the years ago
just upset tonight it's one so yeah you
for forcing
this finish really quick so no or
powerful setool
just phone develops session ID and this
issue
its three characters and not for
so now we take our cookie and
and show you from the speech
for yet it the fact that was six if we
have a
well it's a session cookie and just the
prints out
please try again 3c relook and
firm yet its business basically says
the user was that same login names over
the existing so
but itself this every time
it's just so steps toward H HTML
site on the camera
so
we adjusts both use a browser to set
alone session ID cookie
checked all the unnecessary boxes and
make it the session cookie
and HD only the reload the site
and now we are accessing the
be into the ref from Dan's of or camera
an issue see here there are different
malts
with a view we can access the so which
of the camera April through the videos
two images don't know them we can even
upload images
through the home CF card and also
we have a camera controls it
businesses see here
we are able to take pictures with this
30 button we see some settings of the
camera
and also we see some configuration
settings of the camera
Andrea also able to remotely
change them and
this big book see you is
the life you of the camera so do you
the sugar pops up and you getting
an image every seconds from the
from the sensor so in this case
we can we can just use the camera in the
as a surveillance device for example
a.m.
a scenario fruitful for this attack
might be some further prefer sitting in
this hotel room
using the hotel why Atlan or
wifi and you're sitting in a in the next
room also accessing
me effeminate and you just
see the Camry Cymru announcing
some packets on bootup and its
just show them I'm a Canon try to hit me
and steel only downside
for this is a kiss a.m.
the session gets actually invalidated if
the
camera gets into it's a bit mode and
the amount of time became more will take
to get him to sleep
if no keys are pressed or something firm
are configurable so if
the camera gets into sleep while you're
approved closing session ID
firm yeah you are not able to get this
your part like a boss 01 spec connector
and up to life you up and running the
camera doesn't sleep at all
so once you're in you're in
their minutes for all the moment so now
we have
full access to the life you the store
images and the camera setting
I'm this also is possible
if the on of the camera is also
suffering
on developing to face and a camera he
might fear
the confused why the cameras ordered
couldn't the web server is running so
slow foot I don't think you would expect
30 for closing session at beyond its
yet the the requirements a set before
a.m. so minutes of time takes up to 20
minutes
the camera has to being the WFT server
most which
starts up the the web server and
a valid section IV has to be open before
but the owner of a camera so
if they're is no looking from from the
owner
so there is no way that session ID but
it just takes 20 minutes to find out
if there is one okay
so I'll now we gotta get to my favorite
mode oMG it's called the
yes utility Malta as I said before it's
are
proprietary tool using
kind of proprietary protocol I'll
speaking with the camera with like
highest
a rights you're able to get over the
network so
this this as: close to route as your cum
by not injecting exploit go to the
camera
so from this
just a screenshot of the utility on the
PC so
if you're connected to a camera you can
%uh start downloading images
you can a through the remote routing
so basically all the stuff you can do
with the web interface
but this is just a good car in the
background in the protocol there are
even more options
so I'll
was a stranger of the 2016 up and
running connected to the camera so you
got
a lot of your screen ago and you got the
camera controls and all that stuff
up so just to give you to a view of the
tool I'm its capabilities then yes you
see is
more less an extended version of the web
front-end
your okay
so I'll as a set
this is a really are reading lights
remote
so you have full control of all camera
controls
that doesn't need like a a manual
I'll twisting of the Lance or stuff like
that
from you also can up and I'll look
pictures
the turn up and download movies arm
it may even be possible to
record sound because the camera is a
video camera it also got a microphone
arm I didn't figure out how to turn on
the mic
yes but there are a lot of like Canon
proprietary
option second sup in the protocol and of
nothin for all up to
so there might be a chance for recording
salt
arm okay also
what both this tool and a camera do like
technically
are first of all day discover each other
again
and this scenario I'll SSDP if the
simple service discovery protocol
and multicast DNS issues so
they both ago and just screaming
direction of the broadcast
I'm hopefully find each other
up the walls of the discovery up
protocol called
p2p it. is used for the communication
also this mold must be really high
secure
because it needs and initial camera
software parry
you need to Press a lot of buttons on
the camera out to put it into pairing
mode
and then your need to click on your PC
to pair with the camera
so this must be sick you
okay what started the parrot Janet to
pair to
kind of exchange credentials I guess
that's what parents should be fortunate
arm
yes I set the camera has to be put into
repairing most about a menu
you can't do that remote um
and also repairing his signaled while
party custom us
so if you put the camera into pairing
mode it's more or less
except pairing from every device or out
so it just sends out arm
want to cast in aspects with this magic
tea I deduct canada.com
um text set to a lot of zeros along and
a lot of Jeff's
that's a signal for your I'm I'm out
Canon camera and I want to appear with
someone
arm this is what it looks like if the
yes eternity detects
appearing the first just so-so care of
on the camera
got this Mike addressing this IP address
and it wants to be picked
click Connect to pair with the camera
okay so
if you to click Connect what happens
this the software connects to the camera
while
this protocol p2p I P will come through
protocol in a second arm
this protocol also includes an
authentication
both if the camera is an appearing alt
the camera
except every authentication mountain
serial data center it
after what's the credentials are store
on the camera so that
only that one client with that specific
authentication information can connect
to become a writer
at least that's what it shouldn't
we'll see okay
let's get to p2p I P that's the main
protocol used here for communication
%uh it feels a little bit like use be
over IP
because I'll physically I P though
so-called picture Transfer Protocol over
Internet Protocol
are sanitized and a very nice I sold the
comment
and sanitize fire Association of the
International
emitting industry yeah
best pro I am
it's more or less a rep of okipe
so pitifully the pic to transfer
protocol as Walt
all more or less all media devices
speaks
why you speak so if you connect the
camera while your spirits explain pitted
if you connect your mp3 player out to a
to computer and then pops up a little
window which that's all media device
discovered
we want to browse it than actually it's
not like browsing a mass storage device
but in the background
this protocol pity is used through
access the media device
so p2p IP is just a wrapper around
you speak for the call because
very decided to just put the protocol on
IP
I don't need it some more information
like
all we need a landfill we need some type
field
and in the end there is justice are to
know p2p data
so I just got tomb of you
on I said before it feels a bit like
use be over IP arm because the
packard land for this very limited and
also units that they to entirely all the
stuff like
I'll sequence numbering aren't
up all that stuff again and again
so okay arm
here's a screenshot of two-layer model
so you gotta
p2p protocol on top you got the p2p I
pirupa then you got TCPIP and
some network layers
okay pitifully IPA got someone typed
that says p2p I
in it come on request that that sounds
interesting
um this come on actually does the
authentification for the connection
and its includes to types of
authentication
beta which is want 16 fights GUID
and host industry
so I'm my first fall was okay
discover host named up could be possible
if it's a Windows or Mac
I'll but all lost 16 byte
to you I D that would be hard to
brute-force
so aka ridiculous the four
um this is just one of those 50 per unit
per month
request so you got like to pick a plan
to get the pic that I
than you got the famous GUID
which looks pretty random are after
whatcha got
hostname this is just so ever and
YouTube 16
and then you got a trailer
are remember this blue string
it will come back in a second
ok it's all obviously we broke the
fourth round spermatids well
otherwise I wouldn't be talking so much
about p2p and all that stuff
arm so let's see for client hostname
as I said before could be easily
discoverable
if it's a Windows machine or Mac who
just broadcast or hostname all the time
in the network
arm but regardless to cover also accepts
connection from different host names
so I think that all three lakes arm
brought yeah actually it doesn't matter
which hostname sup
just connect the camera are also
what I discovered was searching for this
6 invite you I D
this that it was not start nowhere
on the PC this GUID is
unknown to the clients of and that made
me think it's
a while the software doesn't know the
authentication material used to connect
to the cam Russell
where is this GUID coming from
so actually its broadcast the and
office go to form by the camera itself
why you can't so on what this looks like
as this we also got the famous
Tidd can invite com I've now
it's just a random string instead of
lots of zeroes falling and lots of cops
we saw before
no okay this string doesn't match the
GUID
it's a different story but as a set
yeah it's kind of obvious case so of
after putting
little brain into this problem I came
out up with this
short I from statement and after getting
the
tido can not come through this %uh the
loop
we just got back the blue streak that's
exactly the GUID
I showed you before arm on to us
on on the arm picture of the
for the call
ok it's so now on what are going to do
with this
of indication the theory are we figured
out the camera
only allows one connection at a time so
if a user is already connected to the
camera
the use that needs to be disconnected in
some way
to let us connect the camera and as I
mentioned before
oh yeah oh well the TCP reset
attack is possible so you can just
you got to well-known ports arm
also there is quite lot of states are
going
through on this to port so you got pic
TCP Windows
it's not that hard to two hits all RTCP
recess
a attacks are absolutely arm
doable in this scenario ok it's so now
we got to use a disconnect that
so terrorists a lot of space for us
to the camera so the process of this
attack with pretty much speed up
just listen for the camera to pop up
to just up announce itself
than the obfuscate the authentication
data
which is pretty easy with those for
Python statement
than disconnect the client software if
connect
an off-the-wall disconnect yourself why
it's his p2p ike
and of course a fun with other people's
make
picked okay I got assault team on this
on as it's a life the more I will hope
that the works
aka so I'll I just wrote a little tool I
will
months it up what it does it just
licence for the camera under
local network so the camera is asleep at
the moment so I will just wait it up
it will connector while Islam
thats around us of the wats I'll and
will announce
itself on multicast DNS so it just takes
about a few second to associate to the
to wetland to get and there's a cute
dress on
all that stuff but
after I'm I connected to the wifi
I'm connected to the wifi so
civic unrest
trying really hard what's wrong doesn't
can't connect to the wifi
their
see a
have you tried turning in for ago yes
I do so
yeah that's the thing with life famous
when they fail they fail horrible
K
I'll let's see armpit tyrants from
soldiering
lost four days you're pretty purchase
I'm kind of programming them
yeah thank you
%uh threats
I why on earth
up a of
for
okay the camera doesn't get an IP
address
up to al
oh yeah reset the ext that's a good idea
its
us yes its absolutely but not us
fair
access point to sporting good thing
boating
I still got an IP address no
minus gone saw
aka wrist other apps we will
start the camera at Willard out for the
way flan
hour or more you know what maybe
it's too noisy in how many access points
can you count
yes we can just switch to the senate
year as an easier for
I think we're all just be just like
and hour ago before that targets us
test data set up and it was working on
the fourth floor
so yeah was working quite smoothly
okay of
there we go we just need to be patient
sale
the camera now I'll just announce itself
to yeah I'm here I'm a camera assesses
I feel about the IP address idea of this
case that the GUID
and after what's it's just a job of lift
the photo to connect to the camera
so once I'm connectors i-ten
read out the configuration so it's
either stuff like
up I don't know the current a picture
that is set
a camera more though
some were should also be the lands
named and stuff like that saw
after getting for
configuration I can also list all the
files
but I cannot also but I cannot only
lists the files 0 this what for
I can also download the files
um ok now trams up to Mac
that's good so you will see the picture
starts on a camera
Justin about the second to
yeah so thats
one of the pictures the first one from
one or development sessions from the
patch
yeah this is like the whole office looks
yeah
this whole all the guys working on the
batch look
the last week trust me I'm an engineer
yeah
and also
this is what we produced and consumed so
okay now that we got all the pictures of
the camera
what else to do so I thought
it my rights be interesting could just
got a little life you
out of the camera so
I not implemented
RK that for
the wavelet inside interests really trap
long leave this rose about the 20
pictures the second now I'm barely
getting one through for a sec
okay so of
your few small way flout so if you able
to
get access to occurred on
1bx internet wrote you see some
detective
I yeah don't let the cum flow
either
so up you know
what what what some other I'll think of
some photographs using the all the way
flow on the Starbucks with lon
everywhere else freeway flannel around
yeah think like
the sea with a few days ago I'll and
nothing about somebody else being in
that network segment
so almost anybody in the same lawn
can excessive camera regardless of the
mode it's in
can carlotta images and somewhat Stephen
can
upload images scanned yeah
like gets the life you out of the camera
turn it into a surveillance device and
I'm still looking for them microphone
because I wanna the camera be a fun
that would be awesome you actually a
able to record record a video
and go to tougher rules so you've solved
yes but that's just a worker of
for okay
well what are the condom at us so I am
NOT
that much there are
only one to say it like that just enable
the network functionality
and for the trust that work environments
and if you're using with lon
use WPA news WPA
exclamation mark and also only is it
in a trust that the way for okay
saw that's mainly it we got a few
conclusions
I am and this say like
s even more and more
like daily life equipment comes equipped
with
network functionality all the old and
boring
and you like flame attacks they're
coming back
and I'll bite you in the ass because
they are now attacking systems you don't
even know about they have network access
and yet
again up there are
a new throw another new process
of attacks but there are old attacks
against the new class of device
and your I don't think
a the regular normal photograph
kind of guy knows about
of spoofing of stuff like that it just
wanna upload the images into the cloud
as fast as possible
so this phrase strippers speed used to
see
it had has 73 of results yes really
it has happened before and will will
happen yeah things will change
striker I'll
but that's not all various even a new
and more advanced camera than the one
the acts like its up
or want some kind of image quality about
now got on
bill then Wireless access point yes so
you can connect your mobile phone
to the inbuilt access point
and control your camera why I saw
Android up
so that is awesome is not
I wanna see some traces of this book
we don't gotta and I got our hands on
and 16 yet
up any chance us somebody gotta
sixty sponsorship
well up silver okay but
I think we'll have a look at this in the
future so
okay as I have to say this not time
enough
though one minute fifty is blinking red
for just in time so
thanks for your time
are there any I'll fast questions
we got like one of a minute left speak
for us
okay
sorry your
likes that is an option to switch off
the network functionality isn't yeah
it's great here
added got free TV Live
yet yet
use another question question fuzzy
a yeah you don't it's a farce just sent
100 opera seconds on the network cycle
guy POSCO
see if you don't we need to because the
exploitation yeah that would be really
interesting
to get a real like a a payload onto the
camera
arm but I haven't had the time yet to
have a look at the operating system
running on a and I guess it's something
really ugly
because can and ships the sky with their
own like
see if you use which are called image
procesos
I don't own the must be running some
some real way it's
real-time OS so but now that's
our own but just finished I may have
talked a little bit for some some
to the advertisements about Samsung
Galaxy Tamaraws
yeah maybe this kind of devices but the
might be much more interesting for
exportation
yeah and I bet it also speaks pretty
VIP I so
yet last question non
no remaining okay if the ranks of the
questions I think I've never be
opportunities to be disguised a the
breaker
a they won't escape so
maybe fall asleep I of but don't worry
remember charm for the wake the hot ask
the question so that's i think thats a
so a.m. thought new POSCO thank you very
much
yeah I hope to talk to Paul