okay welcome everybody a.m. any worse
already introducing on or work our talk
and ourselves um very detailed so
thank you very much an oath talked on
everything told
so by on enjoy lunch pretty good so
I pretty good summary yeah but some I'm
I think it's much more interesting to
to get in some more details a but frost
a.m.
transaction um much just an IRA we r
rocking with all that stuff we're doing
penetration test code reviews
a.m. sometimes audits on to
the goods rose engineering and very
often we have the problem
that our customers are asking us okay
how critical is a problem
and then we have to say okay it's pretty
good all it's not critical
its some kind of medium rated that to be
a question
and some we gots lot of experience
over the last years and doing that and
such was the main reason
why I'm the idea popped up okay I'm we
need something
%uh and special to to do it very good
rating
aunts the talk is about or
ideas and results and mobility is if you
want to have
to some introducing growth
to will yet thanks for the sect
production I benefits but yes we will
split this talk civil arts also want to
at a because I have to be really close
to speak up a little bit um I also want
to come back to an O's introduction as
you mentioned became up with a
metric that describes ability is
actually we came up
were multiple metrics you that we
changed over time and this is
one of the topics want to research
topics
at the NW probably s one of the
longer lists durations until we
came to a somewhat final result um
and securing this process we
came across several pitfalls that you
have to avoid when you want to rate
vulnerabilities
so there are two made Marius
on that you want to cover Shetty's
pitfalls with you to tell you okay
what you should do should not do when
you want to rate vulnerabilities
especially on a large scale and then we
want to present your our
approach on it is based on a lot of
experience that we
gotta both from assessments penetration
tests on its whatever we
arm did you customize advance
experiences
customer sites like Twitter with a fast
guys think about
thinking about this problem but I think
we
got some rather good ideas in their
and a very good summary everything we
saw
up experience so um
this sehn duffala talk for us we will
if you /url slightly I'll more
comprehensive problem statement
them with it so far like other village
Creek rating is difficult there are
pitfalls
we vote tell you about those those
that we'll have a look at existing
approaches
conceive holiday to you all on
deal with those pitfalls you have
several
Devils India I'll and
we will require your heavy index up to
ready off so that means the second day
it was to deny yesterday but its
late in the morning so I hope your fit
for them into action
and after that potentially outlining
some shortcomings of those approaches
I'll we want to show in your direction
that we were going to
and to be honest also outlined some of
the limitations
almost as approach arm but I'm pretty
sure you will be able to figure this all
out
buddy at the store so I believe
pretty interesting a.m. Michael me it
will be like
week what's up to talk to us during the
development of our approach we
probably you of disagree it's then we
agreed
I so it was hard work to comes to a
conclusion in the end
ever followed the keynote we've always
fighting yes over trade fight
but this is like the the end of a long
period I
what else Flobots writing several emails
before troopers like
was blood sweat and tears yep I'm not
sure about the auto but there's like a
waiting in them we'll see that
alright so when we first came up
worth the questions at all rating
vulnerabilities
efficient large-scale wat that also
last August I guess when we
accidentally is somehow hurts
the question from different sites I'm
okay how can we do this how can we
trekked vulnerabilities how can the rate
goes
arm and went to deal with this question
because so far we well using CBS
using it basically also recognized
different shortcomings of this metric so
Gaza
have our own interest in developing
something better and to analyze this
question set
so one very basic problem is
even though many key notes that how you
don't have an idea about environment
I'll usually you still have a lot of
just call it other abilities yup um
that you get off in your environment
they can results all
Yuka revealed them because of
penetration tests
audits arm you also doing automated
their abilities getting
and some probably one of the biggest
sauces to maintain
a succulent and now this is a seam a
solution that is also generating a lot
of
just call if other abilities yup arm
so huge list of stuff that you have to
take care of
so the next problem in this process
is this just as an awesome on the
vulnerabilities
usually is not in the list other
database full of stuff that you have to
take care of if you have a database for
that
and now of course you have to decide
okay I'll what do you want to address
at all what they want to dress for lost
I'm
a regicide got how they keep track of
that
so the to bigger problems associated
with
you don't have enough resources to take
care of all abilities
at the same time i think thats pretty of
US one
the job familiar with
the the next to one so probably less
obvious but
from my experience thing from from all
of our experience
they also called a cool and the most
environments
so typically also level that lack of
information
abilities of existing problems
for example on you get a penetration
test report maybe
the description in them is not answering
all of your questions
all those just metric based approach
others from
bought others liked 5 process of three
so you don't have enough information
abilities to assist
you and
also very big pitfall that we came
across multiple times as
that but the findings belong to
different
on departments at least when it comes to
fixing bills
so we also have to have a kind of a
the some degree of protection between
the different departments
inaudible artificial fixing and even if
not I'll
so you're the internal security
Department
I'll you have all the information
understood the vulnerability
but then operations department the
database depart
whatever they get this finding in
whatever format you provide them
and they have no idea how to fix it so
this is also very common problem
it is all the perspective of the
internal security risk
up are there there are coming to a smart
guys from the outside
a also have to tell you something they
provide you the old way
beltway with information let's say five
other villages
whatever so as to bring all of that to
get up
and in the end just have to make a
decision
just is either which one abilities to I
want to fix
not all medium to long laid up
whenever notices I never
yep on Eva the might be buffeted by the
great reasons to
never fix other bits
will discuss bodies of I'll their of
beasts
so mom in this program s
be identified its to relevant suspects
which are the most interesting once I
know what the net
on the ship back to give up just
bresnahan
Charlotte what's us we really appreciate
it
a lot of feedback because as much
experience as we have
I think its many custom environments as
we saw many
other abilities piece of I'll they can
still dream of
substantiated opinions top so
if you have an additional disagree or
agree with something
in free to privacy so the first part
as the prioritisation of liabilities
of the better way bureau
realization of fixing those cities
this is one aspect missus obviously
closely
related operating of severity for their
abilities
and second aspect you want to arts up
all relevant Asma questions
and in doing so you need to take into
account the different
both parties need to know and what they
can provide
so this only so much penetration test
that can provide
reports but these other
most relevant um aspects in our opinion
and fast outline of the topic so
speaking about vulnerabilities is always
nice but we actually want to look into
some
actually existing approaches and holiday
approach this operating problems and you
will have some concrete
a specific examples of other abilities
to
discuss yeah um that's because we are
doing
um service rating arm based on metrics
since years
I think we started about 2007 2008
um to put metrics for severity rating in
our
and pen test reports um because it's
quite a big problem
um to say something like okay I think
this vulnerability is a critical one
and the administrator on sauce over I
don't think so
and I'll yaa arkansas again discussion a
fight
yeah but um to half reliable rating of
a of severity of finding survivability
I'm you need something more then like to
I think it's pretty cold units
metric approach so we were starting
looking around okay what kind of
security metrics are available
ansa in about 2007 there was just one
metric available that's was usable for
this kind of
a information and that most CVSS common
viability
scoring system so from
we started to you to use this metric no
reports
ants CVS s is a wall the false
metrics dealing with at least by the
abilities and findings
but some a.m.
the basic idea of a CVSS walls
related to pets management decides
which pictures have to be installed
frost
other was intention for CBS s ants
we said okay lot of other villages are
about pitching so this might also be
used for useful for penetration testing
so I'm we started to use it and nowadays
CVS s is really widely used a lot of
up companies are doing um
severity rating of viability space on
CBS s
Nestle's provide CBS as informational
findings
um Microsoft to does it and a lot of
other companies
a providing this information boats on
this company's
are also dealing with patches for the
software
you know soul but some as a sets
in the pasta um there was nothing else
that whilst
almost usable so um we decide it's too
a.m. to CVS and and you notice quote
about
when you have a hammock everything
starts to look like a nail
yeah look that's right
yeah anthems CVSS false Crites
interesting because some when we were
talking about
um vine abilities um
one other problem is that's
companies have different opinions about
the criticality
of findings um some companies think
this sequel injection is for critical
finding
and another company %uh and has opinion
all fall
this finding for for our business
a is not so critical sold out different
views
on um on defining based on
on the business purpose of the company a
so um
another interesting point loss that CBS
was introducing some kind of
environment to view um to the
criticality
is was not just like sequel objection is
always bet
a.m. it was like okay this sequel
injection
might be best for this environment all
this company
so what kind of company a.m. relate its
um you want and of course from
because he is a small soft focus and
scope on on patch management
you had some for it on Sat some time to
pick questions like
what is the impact of of the viability
what is the target distribution
if a 1000 when the Service are affected
San
it's clear you have to install as pets
but quickly um
if you're talking about some let's say
one system
basement a.m. but almost everyone has
already forgot me
I'm might be not so important to install
this kind
the pet on this kind of system that but
this was related to
um Petrus and the guise of
arm CVS s hats a quite interesting from
law
um strong moth a.m. I'm not
the biggest and a strong of I think a
simple formula might be
more helpful yeah but I'm that that the
formula and
the especially the they had three
categories yeah
Wildcats Rick category they called the
base metric I'm
with related to the characteristics of
the finding of the phone but it
availability some kind of temporary
metrics
related to the exploit ability and Petra
availability
of the viability and then the already
mentioned
and environmental metrics
information related to the customer %ah
company
environment the base metric never
changes
no characteristics of finding a
viability
temperament tricks might be subject to
change
for example because an export becomes
available yeah
and a the environmental metrics a.m.
i think thats shouldn't change so often
yeah but there's also the possibility
that song
some stuff in the right environment for
change and
a.m. the rating especially the following
up
a.m. it uses a concept that's
%uh the temperance call that's cake
related is based on the results of the
Mets
a of the base metric and environmental
school office also based on the temporal
scoring on the
base core and environmental score this
also the
find a school that's the concept behind
the formula
we have some questions that are on certs
a.m. the CVSS from concept
like in defector six of the findings
basement recall the base
met a group excess Victor are the attack
are
is a viability accessible from the
internets term
from a company that brought or is this
just a
local problem yaa on the excess
complexity love it it take complexity
um you need lot of know-how to exploit
this issue all can everyone don't know
the to learn to
run it do need to be authenticated its
time to explore its viability and was
what is the impact for confidentiality
integrity and never
and availability are then
a.m. the temperament to poop a.m.
exploit ability which means is a prick
exploitive able
reliable have on something like a
wal-mart a
just like module or is that just a
proof-of-concept
Rs no proof of concept all no kind of
cold
avaible at this for downloading from the
internet
um what's a repudiation never our
pictures available
official fixes workarounds and that
stuff
and report confidence how reliable
kansas also off the hook by the ability
someone claiming in a news group a I
found a zero-day for iis6
yeah and I get so um local system um
privileges was almost a cut which
on this comp it true because of the
architecture but anyway
yeah Rs um vendor publishing a security
advisory describes the viability
thats what report confidence is about
and then
the environmental parts what the
collateral damage potential of the
viability for example
um maybe the ap photo/frank falter will
stop working
you already know that so us know seems
to be this kinda viability for Frankfurt
yeah I what's a target distribution I'll
a all systems affected some systems
affected
and what up the requirements regarding
the
security goals confidentiality integrity
and availability
of the assets um
where r ratings of by the abilities so
interesting approach approach up um
but at least we had its some problems
over the years because as are already
set
and CVS is related to pets management
and not for kinda find abilities
that you would get when you do a
penetration tests
so um to dig a little deeper into CVS s
me for belts small deval with some
interactions so time to wake up again
even if lunch is not so far away anymore
aunts where we started to work with us
CVSS of course the first thing we did
balls
writing a cake you later and some
for now I have rewritten the cake later
that's a new roth Mississauga metric
multiple versions of
different calculator yeah and to have
fun
1202 to all the metrics stuff we're
doing
W the what we want to do now is this
um we have chosen the viability
thats I think well-known to the
community
it's called sequel injection so someone
who doesn't know what single injection
mean starts that's great
okay ants what we want to do now is some
we want to do it's a view to rating
of a single injection problem based on
CDSs draws in true by the way um I
noticed just some work in progress
working on CBS as
versus three what's this focus still
relates to those into
still it seems like that addressing some
yet we will see it's a long way to go
maybe view of Ostia
so let's see I so um we want to do 730
rating for CBS
s a.m. some facts yeah
we have webshop so it's %uh for us from
the second section problem a again
that's shop in Florida
with and enjoy when someone is suffering
for example the spectral
so we have a secret injection problem in
a webshop
I'm in the power metal it's a in a in
its your permit of
doesn't matter and
sorry did get from
close of a I okay so I'm
see prediction problem and the first
thing is a it's a workshop
so first you have to decide what's your
take effect of
possibilities are
is it local problems Boca means only a
an authenticator its a user with Tom in
excess something as can convert
is the kind of Justin network which
means
from the DM's that all from from a
company while Islam something else
on network means from almost everywhere
so
what have you to suggestions suggestions
defense webshop network
other opinions guy good
I get it stays relevant parts up
if it is a subset of
see yeah
such field okay up every measure to
europe
from yeah your rights that some
some some of the problems a.m. when
doing this cut if
of rights yet %uh and that's also the
problem if you are doing this kind of
rating
sometimes some other questions pop up
that Yukon on saw
in that easy way like okay it was such a
treat
okay know I know I'm successful from the
Intertek announces a question
now some time some other questions my
pup that are not so easy to answer
good you little bit faster for the next
Jones
okay so okay let's rock it a complexity
no medio and high
we already loaded lot depends everybody
I
knowing all because advanced
I alright okay so
we agree on low a.m.
do we have to do health education it was
such cute
nuns okay so is from facilities
a zara.com potentially impact
no partially completes
everything's gone
see
me
but okay Disney it's a very interesting
point from
from with from the dismiss that's right
yeah
ok if we have a lot of giants yeah
that's right
that's why we have chosen this a this
example yeah
because a.m. it raises a lot of question
no
I'm it divers if you're talking about
let's say
my personal secrets over 2,000 yeah or
something like your approach to seek to
solve a
yeah that's a big difference and
at least by be its
it's a problem to answer the question no
so um
but finally our job now is to do single
injection rating
with CVS s your a.m.
maybe read okay we were able to extract
some of the data from the database
so let's issue that we didn't have to
I'm
operating system excess so
partial complete and remember on the
slights
in the AM if to make a decision now
that's right
withstood okay
at red jobs posso
completes overruled I
I okay integrity
okay I i think none is not an option %uh
maybe yeah okay so I'm again the crests
apostle
and completes posso integrity
it completes see conviction your
me it depends what kind of exploded its
yeah it's a question of the
proof-of-concept
yeah maybe
I or okay asked again
possibly completes
okay I think complete wince little bit a
little bit
even though I die I don't see why we
have confidentiality possible
equity lead yet for this example
okay availability democracy
villages affected yes or no
completes possibly okay get the arms
posse completes
okay complete rinse but someone
essential mind yeah that's a also
insisting yeah
because no one asked one interesting
question that's my dress up later
I'm availability is some that you can
access the data
whenever you need it
the tip it depends yep it depends to
and thats points a little bit into the
direction where the problem is
okay this question yep
I
here sec
so
yep that's right
with execs that's one of the problems
yeah you actually actually to like
this slights fuzziness
us and the layering text I think we
should missus of course
likability let's say a we have some kind
of proof of concept
also am hi I mean so it's a kind of wall
or be destroyed more do you want me okay
this information is publicly available
in the Internet as lot of documentation
but because it's this rupture of
to us it's only
one particular yeah song maybe it's more
kind of proof of concept to but
on the other hand it's the attacks are
well-known
so sequin texan sects
sex rings as proof of concept I won't
room but we're talking about the
congress
specific
it is a Juicy Couture of course
Gulf Coast checks
know but I am it depends on the a text
string because %uh some
I think other the question is about this
some sick or cells that are not so well
known
but these were related to other to their
Secret Santa
%uh let's assume it's an arkansas
okay what do you mean
hi functional
raise your arms functional hi
okay functional winds
remediation level what we have
office to fix temporary fix bug
Roquemore fix available
we don't talk about undefined
its Auriga I
if temporary fix a favor
okay if and
okay office for official fix
Chris I of ok a temporary fix
woo block routes I
okay interesting loss options yup
know if it's available I
I'm okay I think workaround realz thats
very interesting yeah buddy in those
affix again seek
injection to somewhat surprised I
I pick
adds up I
where are you you know a but I i think
you saw another pro
again its yep
custom is
itself so if
great the music
makes with interest the other
penetration tester from our point of
view
said custom us customer okay
usually the customers to pay for these
kind of assistance
okay then we have report confidence
unconfirmed
uncorroborated confront
okay I think that we have to answer this
question because it relates so the
quality of all confession testing
methodology
so I say it's confirmed
of course okay a.m.
environmental school or this information
to be comes from the customer
so it's about the decision he has to
make and
I'm using my mic um
collateral then its potential
yet it no medium medium-high a high
and there are some kind of the
explanations about this
Heinz 57 Val babies i catastrophic
whose or property damage and Los
catastrophic yeah
is catastrophic
kids your business remember the keynotes
doesn't really tell your business
might will affect it depends
right it depends yep
his yeah but I'm
if you have a sequined checked in OK a
sonya is still there
yeah I yep
yet Evans animals still
also depends cost them to go out of
business a
um a Muslim
do you think an awesome go out of
business if that would be a single
injection
I don't think so to be honest to
yah so but that again
another interesting discussion yeah
because I'm
is just
so okay value to kind of kind of settled
is a little bit so this this
follow-up integration test subjects
all-party honest information that is
most difficult yeah especially we don't
discuss it if you say
for from our point of view a I would
take this information
no say if you say from my point of view
its high
when you get too high because this
information
relates to your business and if you
think
its high than its high yeah
so I'm we can't help a.m. I'm
explaining what's as soon as they do
means a
a.m. them to give you a better
understanding on how to fill out this
information
but finally it's your decision and if
you don't agree
to be with me throughout this the spot
and if you don't agree
you can change it as you like because
this brings
your business scope into the rating
and also if you remove the keynote
follow slights um problem of Minnesota
guys dick
us to test to operations or something
like that
Security Department so this also cap of
Understanding between business
operations and so this questions also
very hot concept
okay let's move to the next one target
distribution of the laptop
sequel instance yet seem insincere
1 of 1 with one bird one workshop
we always taste that 61 its one
Repsol of one tested workshop so
a.m. if you're dealing with that
applications from 0.2 it's always one
hundred percent
yeah the other approach would be okay
count the number of that trumps
hectic a operating in the environment
maybe you can say something okay it was
one of
of 5 web shops a.m. but doesn't make
sense from 0.2 few
yeah so just a horrible but okay we say
it's 100 percent what are the
requirements for %uh for the
confidentiality
I think these these although are kind of
depends west side
to schools with a high to Aunt greater
demand for tension hai
than reissue that integrity availability
is also a hi
and finally with gets
the CD is as fine school on 9.5
10 is a maximum a looks good
possible injection right
okay what um
what you want to to to demonstrate was a
song its operating is
I'm especially CVSS is raising lot of
question
its not so easy and to fill out all the
options
I'm getting a lot of things to know from
the penetration test
and a you had a lot of things to OSC
so um was first approached
boats was lot of open questions from all
sides
okay I will switch back to the slights
what else
alright um I think we have the big
demonstration year for CBS ass there are
several
this one the other approach this forum
complete metric
which is see WSS you see they
on chanced upon their ability to
weakness
a.m. which is an interesting thing
because I was referred to by their
abilities in the first place from all
the inputs is
salsas if you remember that and
vulnerability
is not always a very accurate arm for
everything you discover
responsibility usually relates is
something that you can exploit
some all so they also
claim to be able to school weakness us
we will have several examples later what
the difference
is exactly I'll idea it's
to elect brought a few the publication
they want to follow
automatic scoring process um
12 loll more custom
um rating of own by their abilities and
to be assess
all kind of security to let the problems
Mike cool
a lights on the cross and it includes
also
just a CVSS characteristics of two be
sales of like environmental requirements
and they also for
three groups at baseline a group that
takes office group
and environmental group arm
there is another relevant thing at this
currently versions the robot 8
and it is dis worsened since two US I
don't think the ups
updated their website on very much so
they are kind of not making progress you
so
the difference are only just on all of
that both the fine just
sometimes it difficult understands what
it say what exactly is the meaning
and if we cover
score ranging from 0 to 100 bounce
def four categories for each finding
which will show you dislike it so this
is basically the options
you can chose from for every for each
peron it up
that I showed you ants there's
one big thing that I see as a problem is
to quantify its
factors acreage effective from 0 to 1
will always refuse discussions about
this victim's
then yes like finding confidence proven
true prove locally true proven false
um in this case it's somewhat in tutus
I don't think um I directly get the
meeting approved local in true
me that we in all cases and there are
are on it up examples to 'em
even lead to more confused like got it
with CVS
its comparable thing there are some
around a dozen
their with think a really relevant but
select overall handling
s follow it far away from of
so SP running out of time I believe it
that way
you have problem similar to see Jesus
fearsome good approaches and that
but unfortunately the work going on so
um and some environments we also like
rating of other abilities on the
risk-based approach
that's you is distinguish between
threats and vulnerabilities
which is a very good idea again save you
a compact
laid up and generated using the three
basic
run it is likely that vulnerability and
impact
which somewhat you which is applicable
in a very broad scale
but yes not very much information
you want us to a long like explain the
vulnerability effect explained like the
it factor
explained impact factor up which books
but then you always stuff like go high
degree of
subjectivity falls in us the right stuff
so I just a very general approach
but might books for might work for
several things
but a few actually went to rate specific
vulnerabilities
all it's too difficult each
then of course because assault so a
customer brought us home
but the Houston very big environments
obliterating fun abilities they take
some time sorus base
brought into a call havel so impact
scoring
on and then the end they also like
medium-high
on although rating just like um
sub several other on scoring systems for
the Decatur ecosystems
like the usual well as engineers also
provide see this as quality as over 125
school
available though criticality a
I criticality om the
there are a lot of different approaches
of I think with I'll CBS as we had a
very good example
up hotels booked wat already some
pitfalls of
but it's just summarized as up up
to summarize such a real problems with
the lack of information
for a lot of Parana us as we saw we had
a lot of depends
we don't know what is it about so this
is a custom software from
what is it aunt
what do you want to rate um I will again
postponed is a little bit sorry for that
and was filling it in we dentist us with
interest Department
what information can the penetration
tester provides what the state interest
up Security Department want to know
rations want to know these kind of
problems
and once a good value of its for example
we would be incredibly happy with the
metric to this very easy to fill in for
us
you have no idea how much time I am
by their ability ratings takes take
follow reports
as actually one of the except for like
cleaning out of the typos from our guys
I it's one of the most time-consuming
parts
of the report generation we would love
to have a very simple metric
some accurate results but is to read it
and is it okay this is critical why is
that
it's hard to get that yet mean take
another test
and you get a lot of phone calls for you
get asked about different
other ability rating so it's also no
interest to provide that information
onto the custom I'll suburban this a
question to ask
term also for also pointed out the
problems of
except of a web metrics
alright so we also the okay
what he wanted to hear you take you
excellent schools okay I'll
so of course we try to come up alone
approach and
we soon noticed some Hall
similarities are just little comic strip
some of you might know it
another already totally got a lot of
meeting since last August movie
basically every meeting came up with a
different approach
and at the end of each meeting with yet
business got this will book
and then two weeks or four weeks of the
we look that is a
yeah we have to adjust some
and so we went on
dick
like this
walls up I'm that's also one of our main
advantages
um the experience and lot of I'm
examples for for the rating from from
all the assessments
okay so um design goals on symmetric
balsa and provide a superior to you
rating that can be used for proper
privatization
I'm off on abilities because that's a
small
one of the most important questions okay
what kind of our abilities to have to
fix
first I'm okay sometimes
I'm I have some problems as my present
are not able to use it and pressing the
wrong buttons
sundress and the prop I'll known as a
very
although I'm running a personal firewall
a.m. when I'm located in the
nuclear conference network and the wrote
some warning so
maybe some of the guys are playing a
role in trying to a computer's
to not today guys I
okay a so it was about writers Asian ans
the question what kind of fun ability to
have to fix
for us yet it should be lightweight
approach
was easy questions clear questions
I am that can be all that gives some
interesting information related to pen
test results
maybe all that results from also
discussing a
to his magic for of all results and easy
and efficient to on saw questions clean
your questions results
a lot of a dependencies and to our
questions that are popping up so um
we decided okay um what are the
questions we should answer
um from all sides and from the
customer's perfect
perspective ants finally
after a long fight sry agreed to five
categories
early I'm still not particularly happy
with the names of them
its yeah but that but the newest fabric
I so make me because that's a huge
problem I
as a maybe you can't come to continue
our fight later on answer
that's it so I'm the first category was
about characteristics of the
viability um exploit ability
impact mediation what's with
is also questions asked very very often
and of course again
the environment are because arm that's
important
to get some kind of individual rating
I'm
customer related rating looking at the
characteristics
we also have the excess Victor yeah
we have something we call required
privilege
level compromise
level I'm roots show the
the things we can fit into those points
later on the 20 and the question
is a qualified proof of concept so
it's the pen tester really exploit the
vulnerability or is it okay I have fun
of my tits ken
Anza let steps God is telling me there's
a significant problem
okay check secret sexual problem
which might be notes a a good source for
that lately
then expert blood's ability on
basically all also what we always get
asked is okay and who is able to exploit
that
what he fought um so after required
skill level
as it like an automatic to will simply
use a script kiddie that can exploit
this vulnerability or is it a very
skilled and motivated
attica and with the time to exploit
along
does it take them as a skilled and
motivated
take out that still to implement Siro
the exploitation
because there was like a known problem
problem but no home
solicit develop exploit code because is
nice but code available
will take them at least two to four
weeks to you develop this exploit code
aunt the city to buy hardware
any other equipment inflight
entertainment systems
cannot detect the cross occurrence apply
the plane for dim sum
kind of research spot right to commence
an offer that
yeah I then this is some
the last one insider know how require
yep
some so
human resources that website where we
want to clearly distinguish between
results just yeah it's a certificate the
differences
spend time versus have a lot of money
for example to buy
a play you or something else
as well as like inside on the whole do
you need to know intelligent user names
are you need to know
source code of custom developed
application something like that
and the most relevant item in here
enabling
mother ability pressed if required is a
vulnerability in
the cat only be exploiters part of a
chain:
like to you Jeff like other Realty that
gets a system access and then you can
on local root exploit something like
that to change vulnerability is
its its it's also about the naming of
the description of the finding
your and the cold but also a strong
fight because we're discussing okay
I'm what about this kind of change
exploits
your and how can we solve its use stuff
like this
or a.m. gif if the soft another name
but it's also about the testing
methodology yeah for example you looking
for cross-site scripting looking for a
single injection
a and of course might maybe you can
combine some other findings to
fully compromise the system I am
is its useful a.m. to to write another
by the finding like combined cross some
secret action whatever take
for um
I'm leads to system compromise
of focusing on the on the more the
turbine abilities and finally
a.m. to stop the fight we agreed okay we
were put the stuff
insight no so we have we have both
possibilities
we can use this um um for for making
some kind
of a relationship to another fallibility
some kind of change
exploits but we also have the
opportunity to say
we're talking about a system compromise
fire crisis gripping and single
injection and whatever's injection
and a local root exploit and so false a
sobils options a possible the lysozyme
rocks the channel on so if this is a
very very simple such
because as a still for incredibly
complex problem to address
we didn't want to have actually CrossRef
references
like reference into other findings
because that's not maintain
that's really not maintainable soviet a
single switch
if this an ailing mother on their
abilities present
yep this finding is more relevant
because we actually be exploited
after a hurry up a little bit so a the
next one is impact
to make it wrought um we set okay
we don't want to talk about
confidentiality and the level of
a in and the level of from
a section of a confidentiality it's just
on so the question is compensated
effected
yes on No we don't care about how much
yeah because what again one of the
Court's well was too
on so the question quite easily
so a.m. and that relates to come for the
cells integrity and
availability than mitigation effort
basically how much time do you have to
spent fix it
and does it depend on the phone party
yes to ask the window for a patch to
outsourced development for eventual
something like that
now you might wonder why this does
increase is a the grid is a severity you
of a vulnerability system comprises a
system
mice middle like fix but is also very
struggle it in the end to custom also
wants to know
what do they want to fix August so if
you can
supposedly you have to completely
identical on their abilities
resulting critical impact
left same other abilities want us to fix
within one day
but the other one you need for weeks 621
that you could fix within one day fast
because it increases your
secured to the immediately you don't
have to wait for for weeks
so that's but dislike increases the
criticality if you can
live sex easy you want to
have to security benefit now not in four
weeks and then again like to one day if
and praxis because you can like parallel
book
still wants sis elementary approach
okay that's one loss the environment
a the first part I'll throw things trust
level of
accessing entities what kind of users
are using a.m. the applications a system
whatever
for example the people all the people in
the brought
external partners just to enterprise
your or only a department in your
enterprise
%uh so-and-so what what's the kind of
trust Washington
trustworthiness the trust level of this
accessing entities
its easy out to have some policies and
guidelines and your company and tell
your people hold
a how to behave yeah then have contracts
was part nurse
and regulate that or evening a.m. try to
to introduce some kind of guidelines for
the world
for all the users outside in the world
then very important from all sides the
data classification of the assets
your um are you dealing with public data
I was confidential date up
yeah and a.m. the expression this
is a target or the acid a critical call
business service how important this is
stuff
for you then and to soccer 11 problem if
you are on site guy okay
and this availability important for your
application yes
so it's always the same answer so we
tried to
22 to to make a question like 10,001+
our outage be tolerated it's a
and some across its Rick was again a lot
of Finance
eff ort I'm to my computer on some okay
no
justices again missus like the most
accurate version of this
yup there's a lot of us in this but this
from our experience
this is the idea where you like get an
idea how critical the application
that system actually yes last but not
least other external or compliance
requirements that relate to your
education services like PCI and for
false
so I'm that was also one point
then um went to do something lighter I'm
a great Fecteau wrote how important are
the individual questions for the rating
some are more important than other us
%uh
I'm to hurry up a little bit that other
values I want to I'm
and discuss them in detail and finally
I'm
we ended up with a from 0.2 few quite of
simple formula
that's only the complex representation
yeah
so I'm if you remember I'm optimistic
not a smarter
yeah it's just about I making
multiplication
of the wait and a.m. the results
a summarize values your ansa
by the flood was hundreds divided to the
maximum possible results that's also
again some rice
um we try to keep up the formula quite
basic
because I think and complexity also
kills is this kind of
um I'm ma such a putting into the
application
okay next short the mall
you up I'm of course we have
also another lunches waiting but nooo
said we can go over time for 10 minutes
I area
yeah we dunno not well trained by and oh
so we are not guilty
it's alright let me know if you let
tumko leaks some that are known to like
Choi hear themselves talk I
that's what happens we help
okay to tell you that have to do with
time on Friday
I okay let's %uh let's go to lou that
you have
W I it's because you always calling me
the other two
I up
that's a bit of hot sauce on a social
wasting your time
so I I let's have a look at a at the
metric
um the RW Rep it rating system
that's a %uh how we called it yeah
year five characteristics exploit
ability impact
environment mitigation a and to
nice and fancy the graph to visualize
the stuff
%uh the options offers the access
Victoria internet business of Business
Partner Network
corporate network not network segment
consideration
local system required privilege level
authenticated a
of indicated authenticated user
administrator
compromise Leveaux which this one of the
most important things from our point of
view
privileged system compromise which means
root access
untrue system compromise which means
something like
excess was use a nobody owns we have a
major Dolce mine a Dolce
are we talking about major information
disclosure my the information disclosed
I'll
or stuff like best practice violation
there's a book that tells you that you
don't use HDTV
that you have to use the it should be
only attributes
when setting cookies a not looking at
your requirements maybe want to deal
with the quickness and job creation is
up
world-famous trace yup
way yeah
that we have a a lot of yes and no
questions
was a qualified proof of concept
document we have to exploit ability
take a skill sets scripted user IT
professionals
good unmotivated take time to exploit
less than one day until more than one
month
financial F-four private feasible
company feasible all government feasible
think about Capt salt site there
yeah I'm surprised yet
editing by the present required inside
all required
well as a set confidentiality develop
effective
related to the process state on the
assets
%uh with have some kind of relationship
to the data classification
on the system you see the trust level
department at the price partners public
data classification up the process state
of which also requires that you have
some kind of data classification to all
tools
question a hopefully you have
and then just call to the business of us
can run all
tolerated external requirements lock
mitigation for again less than one day
and more than one month
and I'm the checkbook depends on
third-party software
and I think now let's just have assault
lookouts
sick with injection again yeah because
this might be much more easier a too and
so is he so our point of view
excess vector ok it's the same yet
because we're assuming the same
viability
yeah so its Internet required privilege
level
wasn't so it fits oats authenticate
another ticket sorry compromise lever
that we have a system compromise
no that we have a denial-of-service
scenario
no a.m. that we have a major information
disclosure
yes now by the way to make the thick
stuff much for easy a
if you own a troy if you want to fill
out major dos all major information
disclosure
its rated at the same leather so on to
switch
also makes the stuff much more easier to
fill out
so what do you say its major information
flows
it take a stance that Snooki use
IT professionals good motivated to take
up
scripted time takes yeah
its a.m. time to exploits
less than one day okay
financial F or private feasible everyone
agrees
know if not then and not everybody who
present inside an are required
no company says he defected yes
integrity yes availability
yes trust lever
public or workshop
up data classification
public who went on
confidential strictly confidential
it depends but at least you
should be able to answer this question
up so
let's assume that's a confidential
some credit cards data it's not so
important report from my point of view
um social five dollars a.m. and you get
five
after Sony XO
yeah that's right okay is a cooperative
Business Office
again it depends spots you can answer
the question
to okay we assume the same
environment as to CBS so is a
cooperative Business Office
kenya oo to tolerate its
in all or yet okay no checkbooks
external or compliance requirements PCI
yet mitigation
before less than one day okay
depends on third-party yes
yes okay
so mmm
we get all rating looks family law
yeah with charm all CVSS rating
also a super-injunction we feel that's a
critical problem
your metrics s as a critical problem and
just two end up this example let's
assume
that we have a sequel injection problem
on the public system
um that just gives you some catalog data
no credit cards are processed no
confidential data processed
is a sequel injection problem still a
critical problem
in that case who thinks it's still a
that's true %uh some does not
the song no no clear decision
of the and raising yeah but but let's
assume from from look for the better
part
we have internet yes I'll
unauthenticated
its might be not not
a major information is close up anymore
because it's about the catalogue
and you can browse the kid looks so you
would get the data anyway
so it's all only a minor information
disclosure
a.m. is confidentiality effect it's
no public tater catalog
isn't equity effect it's
if you can change its too okay
availability effect it
might also be true but me something to
tell if you change
then we have to change the data
classification
its public up if it's just the capital
of
might this be a critical business
applications it depends spots
to be I would be what assume that is a
is one
about at least you're you already get
the state yellow
yeah just changing the pair which gets
of which creates more familar with a
sequin texan problem um address only
effects
the system with peptic data ants
finally with alt a privilege system
compromise
which would change the situation of
course if you can take over the break
the system
so it's reasonable the small point of
view
the sort
yeah all that's right so we are 67
no all yeah not
tech I okay okay that's as this as a
shot
I'll do then we have to amend points
finalize so
I'll if you wanna do if much more
index not this point we have a %uh CVSS
and I think we already
I'll laid out some of the relevant
points you so
you see that was easier to fill out with
the same results
you able to adjust most of the stuff but
yet two examples are you can say we
choose to man up
a nice way actually be prepared more
examples
some of them most of them fit of course
because be giving a presentation
yet I pots
there are something at the beginning
because of
audit findings something like a week
past month policy
um on if you if you stumble into that if
and so it's official backup but they
still need it
even though this is not necessarily the
focus of a penetration test would still
matched
order to increase overall level of
security thing
that will help them so such let's just
call it
audit findings you will not be able to
school like 100 percent picture with
this metric
we are out of touch we don't think it
will fit that into that metric
will come up with other one you'll see
because we're break the usability
finally and trying to
and to to everything was was one
approach it will break the usability
and that false 100 megawatts was to make
ought to construct a usable one
I think what we make the entering the
talk with metrics a hot
be discover that the hard way I mean
it's not a big surprise but still
few thoughts if you discover it and
have a clear understanding of the
questions that both sites
arts months there are several questions
in this metric
a pretty sure some of you want at West
is in this category was that formulate
it that way waste is increasing or
decreasing the stuff
arm actually to try to two approaches
from
doing nice categories and using
information you know one group that
together
um you will miss some points always at
the question in mind
both sites can on so and want to months
and the singles at least between
directly exploitable vulnerabilities
single injection on not directly explode
on
vulnerabilities audit findings
insufficient backup
sup stuff this request if watch
an hour really still really interested
in topics
there's probably more to come chrome the
conclusions again got metrics our hearts
a he saves that produce hot fights
bottom learn to
but there were traded for doing the
sites up but from our point of view
I'm we are in the face if you could say
okay we are trojan
a old of nine to and
I we think that's it's more usable are
at least better usable than CVS as at
the moment and of course more intrusive
than
a CWS s um
which didn't have any kind of
improvement since almost two years
a.m. it's a kind of starting points the
to work for example was some kind of
intern custom metrics
error um if our concept doesn't work for
this for you a.m. we are rather might be
some
special cases a.m. where are our
approach
won't work let's say the best way but
be tried to test it Rhys all these kind
of
a special cases looking at trace
HTTP trace method and a bird looking at
findings like HTTP only attributes not
sets
yeah this kinda fading fine except all
always discussed
if they are real findings or on I'm
how to deal with them Orantes a
for now I'll as we said that we have a
lot of example findings we can use for
the rating
but at least a metric need some kind of
experience from the field
and that's why we have produced a strong
this tool will be
ever able not shortly after the
conference because as one
other thing that I want to put into the
true the possibility to say if your work
yeah not just have to cater data like
putting in OK
I'm reading a sequel injections a
statement
safe so you have the possibility to
loaded again
and to another rating or at additional
ratings and
after implementing this functions it
would be released
and together with maybe blog post on
news that we will see
and earthed will be for free so you are
able to download it
and the tour will be available for Mac
OS X Windows and Linux
a not only and it's not based on Java
I yeah I
I okay and finally
a.m. thank you for asking questions
during the talks I like that much more
than done
asking for questions after the talks so
thank you for interaction and if you did
notice that
breaks moment and hopefully this
that ants maybe you notice thats a.m.
would give you one minute to think about
it and the terms of tokens
and before ending up with all slights
just a short
didn't okay and thank you not suggest
over lunch
yeah