hey everybody thank you so much for
being here today and sticking around for
our closing keynote it's my privilege to
introduce Jeanette Mann for us so
Jeanette is the Assistant Secretary of
Homeland Security for cybersecurity and
communications that means that she is
the highest up person in the United
States government who only works on
defense in cyber security and she has
been a really good ally of those of us
in the private sector especially those
of us who care a lot about the upcoming
elections and what we need to do to
secure them and it is wonderful to see
our government investing in that area
and having somebody like Jeanette who
actually knows what she's talking about
for us to work with and to coordinate
with before that Jeanette went worked in
the White House in the Obama
administration and national security
council she's had a variety of positions
and DHS she was a military intelligence
officer in the US Army and I just found
out a Girl Scout which takes you on that
whole arc and so we're really happy to
have Jeanette here let's give her a warm
welcome
thank you coming Jeff
[Music]
[Applause]
I feel like I'm about to have a recital
so I have to apologize first we've had
all this cool sort of informal
interaction and I'm gonna dress up and
using a podium like a typical government
speaker but I spent a lot of time
thinking about what I wanted to talk
about here and you know for me I can
give kind of a cybersecurity talk off
the cuff talk to everybody about all
these cool policy things that were
trying to do but I decided that I wanted
to give a speech about being a woman and
so you have to forgive me because I've
actually never done that before and so I
wanted to make sure to really focus on
and for those of you who are not women I
apologize better not luck next life but
try again but I do hope that some of
these thoughts will be relevant to all
of you and so with that let me just talk
a little bit about my at least my best
advice for what it's like having spent
my entire career in very male-dominated
organizations so in a but before I start
I just I really want to thank you guys
for pulling this conference together
it's such short notice it's really
amazing it would probably take my
organization six months just to find out
where we would have the conference much
less actually invited buddy to it and
for those of you who came and
participated I got to hear some of the
the previous talks and there's just
really some amazing people that some of
them I've heard of some of them I
haven't I'm gonna start following you on
Twitter
we got Twitter accounts by the way we're
very excited at at and PPD underscore
Manfred
also DHS actually has the at cyber
handle I didn't know that we didn't use
it very much
we're working on the the whatchamacallit
the picture if you it's a little lame
right now but so really just want to
thank you all thank you for having us
think for the presenters I just you all
are such role models your level of
competence is just amazing and so let's
talk a little bit about what I'd like to
call the Mothers of Invention modern
technology think about it it stands on
the shoulder of giants and many of those
shoulders are female we must all
recognize that women are not immigrants
to technology but co-founders and fellow
pioneers paid a Lovelace to find the
first algorithm before computers were
invented
Joan Murray led teams at Bletchley Park
in cracking codes in World War two
Admiral Grace Hopper helped design COBOL
my own great aunt actually wrote some of
the first programs for the Navy and went
on to become a leader at IBM this list
is just the tip of the iceberg of these
Mothers of Invention but currently women
only occupy 11 percent of total
cybersecurity positions in the United
States in a world where there is a
critical gap for cybersecurity talent
this is not good enough we need to do
better and then we will do better we
cannot provide for the long term
stability and security of cyberspace if
we are not leveraging all of our
available talent more importantly we
can't honor the legacy of the brilliant
women that have come before us in World
War two many women filled in as factory
workers to augment industry for the war
effort we face a similar gap today but
the challenge will not end with the
signing of a peace treaty this is an
enduring mission we need more women in
this space to fill a talent gap we have
now and continue to fill it in the
future that means our work here is never
done well our legacy is pioneers and
founders in this space can never be
taken away from us it can be hidden or
left unexamined I am proud to see a
surge in popular culture that explores
the rich history of women in tech and
brings it forward for public awareness
it is reassuring to see the contribution
of these hidden figures recognized I'm
also proud to see events like
say and others which give women and
others a platform to learn from one
another
take stock of our progress and
understand the challenges that many of
us still face I'm also proud to stand
here and say that my employer the
department of homeland security has
continued to honor our shared legacy in
my position as assistant secretary I
follow in the footsteps of Suzanne
Spaulding who's a former undersecretary
for my organization dr. Phyllis Schneck
was former deputy undersecretary for
cyber and our current secretary Kirsten
Nielsen in my time at Department of
Homeland Security which has been about
10 years now I've served in a number of
positions as Alex mentioned I was in the
National Security Council I was a
previous secretaries cyber counselor and
a variety of other things going from
back in 2007 when we actually started
this organization and I choked we were
still arguing about whether
cybersecurity was one word or two words
the one word one out against my better
judgment it's not it's not one word
sorry but I've seen a seen a tremendous
amount in the time that I've been there
was you know in the beginning nobody
paid attention to us we were just sort
of these nerds kind of talking about
like doom and gloom security scenarios
and turns out most people don't
understand how the internet works and
they don't really really want to I think
and so my own path has been fascinating
because you know I was there when I was
in the White House when Sony happened I
worked on OPM I've been in sort of the
negotiations with the Chinese and some
of the challenges that we've had with
them in the progress that we're trying
to make with them and and I've seen the
government really struggle with a lot of
complicated questions and I think we're
getting better
I think we're recognizing the the
balance and the trade-offs that we have
to make but we're continuing to work
through that
I know companies are continuing to
address these challenges
and but the one thing that I have
learned is that I have to continue to to
take risks and I have to continue to
lean forward and I have to continue to
be a strong voice and we believe that we
as Alex said we're the advocates for the
defense we're the advocates for the
critical infrastructure community the
private sector those that may not have a
voice in the policy-making process and
so that's one of the reasons we
encourage so many to work with us
because the better that we understand
what the private sector needs what
they're struggling with what potential
consequences they could face if
government takes certain actions the
better advocate we can be within that
process so other women in this career
field have had similar paths building a
diversity and experiences and personal
relationships on the way but there is no
right way forward each position has
given me new experience
learning opportunities I've changed so
much in terms of what I thought we
should be doing and cybersecurity ten
years ago to what I think now all based
off of these different experiences that
have had and every single one of those
choices to take a new job was stressful
but I decided to do it and lean forward
and I really believe it's made me a
better person and and frankly a better
leader and advocate so I want to talk
about some specific lessons that I'd
like to offer that I believe have served
me well and I hope will serve you all
particularly for those of you who are a
little bit younger in your career I
still haven't admitted the fact that I'm
older than I think I am but I'm working
on it
so first focus on the work and being
competent in the work even if it means
doing it for free or lesson you'd like
to make okay at the end of the day what
matters most is the work and the
recognition that you're competent in
that work it's not to say that there are
no other factors that can undermine what
we do or how we advance but our work
often meets extra scrutiny and the glare
of skeptical eyes but where we may see a
hurdle
should also see opportunity skeptical
eyes forced us to be creative to be bold
and to ensure the work we do is
unparalleled and beyond report reproach
it prepares us to work effectively
quickly as a team and with a mind to
communicate our thoughts in rationale
these are all traits of effective
leadership we should also recognize that
the advantages inherent in volunteering
or simply doing the work there are a lot
of jobs as they said that I took that I
wasn't sure it was exactly the right
career step for me but I saw an
opportunity and I saw an opportunity
frankly to fix something that was broken
there no shortage of good ideas in tech
no shortage and there's a shortage of
those I believe that are willing to
follow through and those good ideas this
is risky an initiative could lead to
nowhere receive no buy-in and often
there's no guarantees for credit or for
advancement or frankly somebody else may
get the credit and the advancement build
your trust groups and confidence none of
us can know everything nor should we
much of what we do is a team effort we
talk a lot about this concept that we're
been talking with folks about about
collective defense my risk is your risk
thinking about cyber as a global digital
public health crisis and thinking about
how we have managed those sorts of
scenarios and applying that and the only
way that we can be successful is by
doing it together but I believe that the
only way you can individually be
successful in this space is to have
these groups of trust people that will
tell you you cannot you cannot be an
expert in everything I went to bog a
couple months ago I guess because we did
some work on Demark and I realized how
little I know about email very quickly
but you just by being able to have
trusted people who will advise you tell
you where you're going and and where you
probably need to shift we can augment
our decision-making power and expertise
by building these personal and
professional trust groups I hate the
term networking because that sounds like
mocktails and cocktails and all that
other stuff and there's a lot of
networking by the way going on then
Moscone Center a lot and I think it's
really just an excuse for people to have
those cocktails it really needs or
frankly try to sell a product or trying
to get your next job I'd rather it be
about relationship building as our
careers progress many of us are thrust
into roles where scope of
responsibilities can exceed our own
personal areas of expertise I've
personally been there many times in
technology cybersecurity the situation
is compounded by complex
interdisciplinary problems that often
require a quick and decisive action as
we advance throughout our careers we
have an untold number of opportunities
to build relationships with those whose
expertise and insight complement our own
maintaining and strengthening those
relationships over time make us all
better and serves us all of us well as
we face new challenges take risks as if
you had nothing to lose and you probably
have a lot to lose especially as you get
older and have kids but we have to
continue to take risks as we continue in
our careers
there is a distinct tendency to take
fewer and fewer risks to temper the bold
and creative ideas that had initially
propelled us forward when we were young
and frankly didn't know any better
there's an argument for this approach in
other industries but not for technology
we stand on a ground of shifting sand we
must constantly move forward never look
back and evolve to adapt to our
environment and the threats we face we
should never suffer the innovators
dilemma more importantly we need to
recognize that we as women bring a
unique perspective ideas that are fresh
and new we must lean in on this as a
natural strength and is a critical
contribution to industry what's
wonderful wonderful about technology and
cybersecurity industries is that it
creates an environment that is prone to
competition internal and external I said
it was wonderful it's not always
pleasant but it is the cool thing about
it a bold idea baguettes other bold
ideas and bold action and turn also
creates bold action
I found often times it's simply moving
forward with initiative can set off a
series of events that direct this
natural competitiveness towards
constructive ends and quick action you
spend a lot of time in the government
talking about problems seeing
being about problems my opinion we don't
spend enough time fixing those problems
and so my tactic has been even if I
don't have full authority you just
launch something and say here's a plan
to tackle this problem what do you all
think it's quickest thing everybody
realizes hey that's my job and so
they'll start to quickly figure out a
better way to do it which is fine that's
what I wanted them to do but now
suddenly a variety of initiatives some
of them that have been public some of
them that haven't
we've got people moving just by saying
you know what there's a problem and I'm
not just going to talk about it I'm
gonna offer a plan and frankly I'm gonna
be very aggressive my mom kindly calls
it tenacious it's probably obnoxious but
you just keep focusing on actual
tangible actions and offering solutions
but also being willing to take the
feedback when others have better idea
for you so this means putting yourself
out there it's not always easy
it means taking decisive action it means
being bold
it also means most importantly weighing
our decisions towards disruption rather
than the status quo I believe we must be
fearless I'd like to remind you all
before I finish or not newcomers we're
not strangers in a strange land we are
coming home to continue the work of the
brilliant women who came before us this
means we need to change our view of what
our place in technology is we must see
ourselves as fulfilling a legacy and not
merely making up for lost time
we shoulder a mantle of responsibility
to find talent in ourselves our
daughters and our sisters and pave the
way for them to share in the great work
that we do the future of our technology
and how it changes the very world we
live will be written and defined by our
efforts to do so I know this is a heavy
mantle but I take it seriously and I
believe you should too there's little
doubt we will often face an uphill
battle but we will do what we always do
we will pick up a shovel we will focus
on the work and we will get it done
thank you
[Applause]