we don't really like to give back to the
community which is why we had a CFP
voting voting by the attendees and you
also notice on your badge like some
color codes so we actually ask you guys
to pick the talks that you are both
interested in and it's a way for a bit
of a passive networking so we don't use
a speeding in a bad place for like look
around the guys that have the same color
good and you have a common interest also
for those who actually voted during the
CFB for the talks about the speakers
that your message that the media during
the lunch today you'll actually be
sitting down with them and Hira chance
to catch up with them and the idea
behind all of this is mainly because you
know when when it's an incident and
stuff isn't working so well you don't
normally go to your vendors will help
you actually call up your friends right
so hopefully create more meaningful
new connections for you guys to to be
with also if you guys need introductions
if anybody has a really decided on which
doc you like to not be network to know
you want to change your mind just over
two russian contact the other guys up
any specific speakers are you want to
speak to just look at all the group of
guys in gray shirts with names behind it
and will help to introduce you the
specifics because also in the spirit of
it all of which is happening today and
so far this week we actually decided to
do an all-women fireside chat to
celebrate the achievements of women in
ninety it's not happening tomorrow it's
actually a free event is from 6:30 to
8:00 so there's some of your colleagues
who are based out of Singapore all
happen to be in town and they like to
come please encourage them to come over
you can register on site is also big
thanks to our fireside panelists
especially mister below shows she's
actually flying in from Netherlands
tomorrow for the fireside job and she's
literally flying Netherlands Singapore
speaking for about an hour and a half
and then fly back on the Frankfurt so
big stepping in and doing that that's
pretty much it
hope you guys have enjoyed enjoyed the
talk to help select hopefully guys make
some new friends and you have a lot of
fun and so without further ado let me
introduce miss Chris lovejoy was your
frog president of equity solutions to
deliver the keynote 1