enemies to dimitri British school
certainly today will tell you about it
before it and how checker can compromise
your company if you have your employers
as a peer pressure using only one that's
so cool little bit about me and said my
name is military security researcher in
your company relies on business
applications I did a lot of interesting
test for different earpieces terms most
of them as a PA system that's why I know
little bit however tracker can try to
compromise is this type of systems as a
separate work in Europe scam company we
our group of security researchers who do
security assessment for different
enterprise systems so if you do not know
what is this a piece of cake recipes the
most popular business applications in
the world a lot of different
international companies use the soapy
answer your PC's to force it works on
the slide you can see a lot of
well-known local bloggers of different
companies all these companies you that
subpoena for these for their business
processes and has a different platforms
but we can dedicate humane it's a
possibility Raby AP as a punitive
general is the people's object it's a
behavior it's more than solution of
and supports memory data base by
platform it's my mind solution from its
a big company today would improve our my
talk discuss how to compromise company
through all this all these systems but
today I will tell you about my bio so
this Policy or bring your own devised
this policy permit employers of company
to bring personal mobile devices like
smartphones tablets etc to their work
ways to use those devices to access to a
business information for daily job so
and of course companies cares about is a
confidential information that why is
this classification MGM or mobile device
management this type of application and
now to city administrator rules control
employers devices and solutions allow to
apply different policies on them about
force on the table etc
allowed to control what different
application which users can install
those devices allow to tricking users
get location of the phone etc
actually very useful for system
administrators and today and of course
it's a big company has MDM solution it's
a PFR and today I will tell her about
what about security here forever
it's been four was released in 1997 my
company session express the profession
was to which allow to system
administrator get a remote control
user's computer right now we have
reference number 706 exactly this
version we analyze version seven point
all 75 but modern version is a seven
point oh there's politics so very
typical personality for MDM solutions
allow us to get all information about
user about user tablets get information
about activities about call about cults
about messages allowed to apply
different policies on the slide you can
see a picture of the left side you can
see a phone 404 area you the show is
power
for a client or the portable devices for
a client exists for all modern operating
systems for 400 mile or even for Nokia
Symbian operating system so I frankly
and contain try to get information from
Users forum send this information for
the weight of a forest server start on
the company for campaigns Derby web
server administrator consult with each
other about a ferrier we should mention
about policies which exists in a
subpoena for its appeal for exist three
different policies remain policies
enrollment policy configuration policy
and application policy Roman political
policies described how blind will be
connected to forests error into this
policy administrator create a special
court which users enter into a foreign
client actually it's not just called it
quote from ural shortening services like
it
tenure on something like that so in
admitted a panel at the city
administrator as a Peace emissary to
create this time Europe court and
provide escort to the user does it mean
if if you try to root for a different
Daniel coats probably we can get
information about different different
other sources for Cydia and how climbed
under 10 which type of 40 shorting
series it was used it's a very simple
the first letter of described which
Danielle Harris was used for example of
the obvious example screen you can see
the pro-choicers 8903 the next one
policy configuration quality regardless
of this policy has appeared mystery tour
which for example possible policy was
will be implemented
Portable two eyes and mister can disable
or enable a morale is able
Lu two point black-and-white least for
my foreign I find it also visible green
shirt or maybe he can
Gration like a situation which allow
users use for only work hours etc it's
very a lot of different configurations
can be said by administrator and the
family its application political again
written policy but interesting 'cause in
this policy administrator can point
which application will be installed on
the portable devices during the
connection so administrator can point to
application in Google Play
after and interconnection network
connection is application will be
applauded the portable device also
mister can applaud their own devise
their own application on the application
policy that's how we can install an
application broadway's it's so of course
its appeal for air collect all possible
information about user or portable
device but call publication hardware
information application formation which
application used as a truck this house
administrator panel looks like you can
see is formation about hardware about
which operating system used for anti
about these about Bluetooth as possible
things and also information about
activities about where we're
what the network was used as a
communication cause of area used
different protocol for communication for
use HTTP protocol for admitted racial
you know its net protocol is a protocol
for up for its profit or protocol
four main world so and some 40 miles and
push notification through Google or
Apple cloud also positive reviews so I
the main exam had frequent use of
protocol for getting and retrieve
information from the server its proper
protocol encryption exist or security
things also available so it's your right
now I understand what is the fire out
works and what is in them thar we've
been forever nimble and put the wall few
good things which I was into a subpoena
for first of all its application thank
you all for a client was a skate for
example if you try to compile Android
application for Android plan for our
area you can get a human-readable
classname at the 2004 skate even the
complaint or craft during the complaint
process it's it's a good thing is also
widely considered to be called HDB
request for
Afaria it's also a lot of different
parameters exist even if you change one
of them is to be several reject your
request so also means very hard to
understand how it works it's a lot of
different parameters and other good to
things like Rudy takes the top that bad
things more interesting for me
rebuilt itself was a misinterpretation
an attacker can send XML request to the
various ever without any optimization
and point this request their own IP
address and during the person is this
XML API will try to establish connection
with pointed IP addresses and during
this connection disclosed some
interesting information about person
about companies etc it's very useful for
future attack
of the serious side we find a lot of
different overflow mine explosion killed
civilians syllable abilities attacker
concerned just a big request will stop
it's very stupid but they exist so
that's how an attacker can easily stop
its appeal for reliability breezy but
for big companies even the type of
service attack is very dangerous course
sometimes it if we can stop your PC's
tomorrow as a political system some
business process can be stopped also so
another one example but we should
resolve execute arbitrary code on the
operating system of several of authority
over right now as happy course close
within the next 10 abilities it's a lot
of different part of it will use of
different places in its appeal for it
can be some help setting for example in
this file setting fire to find the name
of operating system and both 44 this
user of course password is encrypted but
groups but with encryption also not very
well if you talk about eclipse and
actually encryption is good option it's
so creeped out ridden by found a lot of
people in 254 scored a lot of which
allowed to enter Israel decrypted all
sincerity stuff for example these key or
these key sequences are used as
encryption but again and keep the turkey
very very accurate encryption key its
very best practice so that means if I
know this key you can easily get
information or encryption from it and
sometimes with the very strange
encryption function like this one group
think actually this function do nothing
just just returns exactly the same thing
given X but I said well it's a shin
that's why this why probably a lot of
different way based on ability exists in
two and we found fewer abilities I will
tell you about taught how to take a
result and figuration can inject
malicious payload
malicious payload into administrator
panel but first of all I'm sure
described what happened if we will try
to sent connection request to their
first ever result in inflation if you
try to send to their parents ever
where where we point when we send if you
send
I'm enjoying for I want to free I have
read our blog what happened of course a
pirate or as a client is not approved
but what interesting of the
administrator panel of the device least
devices remain workplace for
administrator Depot place went when an
open invite list will be showed
administrator and the device least we
can create a lion we our Android
our money
some information about this forum about
i mean but this device will not be
approved so that's how we can inject
some information without vacation into
but our goal it's inject JavaScript and
injection exist in to IM field so we can
we can point to build our generous keep
a log into administrative panel but
little problem exists cause I'm on the
life I am it can be only 50 50 chance
that the plan but we cannot create any
useful law but we can say a lot of
different requests be different I mean
and point john was a little per load
after that will be concatenated in one
useful malicious javascript
out work we just sent you a request to
in into each equipped with a little part
of our people or just a power law and we
can contain eight or this little parts
for creating one big jobs people not
know I will try to show your day
foreign minister device
if we repress
I know a lot of different we can
so without implicating formation
malicious JavaScript
and finally its control devices the
instruments as the administrator or
administrator can control through the
estimates it's a very you admitted for
example if employer moved their bra top
secret information arbitrator can send
SMS 0044
looking device for example provide
different type of calm and in for exist
different common for example why perot
or otherwise modify for applying new
policy for example etc so it looks like
as much for looking user and smiles
contains few parts remain part its
signature here so if we will send SMS
with signature
recline try to burn this is my client
may seem to the Sigma Xi you know for a
for a client control
the type of this mess will not show up
for the user so I thought the signature
by 64% vacations drink after that idea
of common and common name which will be
executed if we provide successful
notifications doing so the most
interesting part of this message of
course interrogations thing actually
question is is she a 256 but we should
know what exactly was hashed his
campaign through freemen well it's a lot
of mister Asian session
ClientID and transmitter eighty actually
transmitter aideed's just their writing
so we should know session blind lady and
surveyed a good session but if you try
to compare for example Android
application for we can see actually
tried to compare not only one try to
compare two different has the two and
the approach the first has our typical
which contains session planned idea
sarah brady but the second one itself
has vowed SessionID contains it contains
ClientID twice separating so that means
we know only too well use ClientID and
severally so we don't know which we
don't need more certainly be very
corporate so the question is what about
client and server a be an attacker get
this without interpretation or not and
how it works
actually better idea or several can be
can be resolved without any indication
by sending any connection required to
the fire fighters in certain every
response to the server information about
Arabia so what you need you just send
any requests with appropriate you get
information about charity so we need
only one client I D or we also
discovered ClientID is based on I'm so
if you know I'm
phone you can get in from generate
ClientID so that means if you know I'm
other phone you can create as controls
for other my question is how to get
permission about i mean actually
a very big question but I decided a few
ways for program information disclosed
from some other application code is we
should stop all implored the wisest
course some of them can trust me to
mention about I'm on security should be
request the server and an attacker can
temper nation next one way to build this
into a secure area for example power
it's a certain herbal teas exactly this
way I will use on the root cause of the
phone is also predictable contains
certain number of part number etc so
company by a lot of France for the
employer and if I take you know what i
mean you can increase value for I mean
trying to brute force and you know as we
know messages do not show for the user
is how can be invisible for the user can
use a brush fourth and finally exists a
special devices different I'm a culture
of its special special devices which can
provide information about phone
connected to the
station so so that means I'm it's not a
problem now
duma time
now we should get information about I
mean I said we can use our abilities
explored with malicious JavaScript
JavaScript code into admin panel and get
information about all connected for
information about any of this phone send
that information back to their tech
can rate get information about several
great different comments comments
get exercise to the bail or would you
rate again we can rate you can click
with 16 an hour per load
waiting
get information about transmitter 81
we've had some s for protection
and we have our Android who is this and
we can send them
and
and generate random password for the
user for the lock screen enables the
lock screen that's how that's why after
the after the comment user do not know
possible and cannot unlock their phones
for example
looking again send us a message
but my favorite
wipe comment
we just send information from the phone
was what it was and shooting down so
very interesting and I think if someone
from top management of big international
company was will be surprised if in one
day we'll get the type of customers and
also mention about
company-owned formation about critical
document on their porn will be wiped so
that's how it works
presentation
of course a close responsibilities for
your system if you should install
whatsapp in all these pipes but the
conclusion is four different enterprise
solution securities should be the main
things got even disappear 48 solution
which protect user data which showed now
protect data critical date of companies
but even into security solution exists
this type of leader bill DeWeese allowed
an attacker to compromise company
information for this company that's why
companies should be very careful when
they try to implement different security
to security solutions so if you working
bee company please do not forget about
get about security assessment and sit
around and do not buy any junk solution
which some guys try to sell you thank
you very much