and I'm a researcher at citizen that
which is academic research group based
out of the Munk school of global affairs
at the University of Toronto so that
likes to study what we call the
intersection of human rights and
technology and so one of our main
interest is looking at targeted attacks
against civil society organizations and
then after bus and so this started back
in about 2009 when the Loudoun orville
new foods now a prior I discovered what
was dubbed as net which was one of the
first documented major cyber cyber
espionage networks and this was
initially found three investigating
claims targeted attacks against Tibetan
organizations so this is often referred
to as apt or an advanced persistent
threat and so in this case these attacks
are very very highly targeted against
civil society groups and pretty much
face them and this kind of constant
stream and they're particularly
vulnerable often because groups have low
resources for example they don't often
have dedicated ITC to help them out and
put it take care of that so one thing
that we did do is last year we publish
it was the strongest research report
over it was a study of about four years
and looked at attacks against 10 civil
society groups but so sorry that was not
targeted threats done that
and so I'm just gonna go through a few
different areas so as I said a lot of
the started with attacks on that end
this is kind of people I've known about
the longest since it's not very visible
sorry this is kinda have typically what
we see we'll see these emails being sent
to people and they kind of follow up in
the same format where they'll say that
they're from someone who is within the
community or someone who someone may now
I was pretending to be and things and
they might reference often you'll see
references to events like
self-immolations also much 10:39
uprising anniversary of the uprising
we'll just see these huge amount of
emails coming and where they often have
an attachment and a plea to kind of open
it and these attachments will contain
materials that have been repurposed from
either mailing lists or news or often if
one person has been compromised then
we'll see their personal example
being used to try to infect others and
so often these attachments historically
they've all been using Microsoft Word
Finder abilities and despite the fact
that I can win this advanced persistent
threat people think advanced it's more
persistent and so will typically see the
same SEBI is being used over and over
again even after they patched you don't
really need this kind of sexy o'day to
actually compromise people if you just
keep on going after them so recently we
did see a better but still using these
kind of same tactics having this
attachment tending to be from a real
group but they started being a
PowerPoint slide just simply like thats
and San Ramon roadies I came out and
really use a package manager and
essentially what you can do as you could
imagine they are remote install file and
Jeff that was actually an executable
originally these were being loaded them
to start later the abilities were
embedded executables that were then
copied over the temp folders so you
don't actually have to worry about
firewall rules trying to stop the
download of executables the primary
factor for this was like I said this
PowerPoint presentations because you can
save them as a PowerPoint show and I
just that and then they would
automatically launch and durability
would be triggered and so this was in
actually any sort of it was just a
larger car which meant that you could
kind of see this seamlessly the sort of
transition and this is actually just
again repurpose content from a major to
an organization and so this was a little
problematic too because typically people
would be told hey watch out for a
program rushing
watch out for if you see what kind of
liquor and then reopen with different
title for the document has been going on
for so long with it
community they had developed all these
sort of training campaigns for example
this major one was detached from
attachments with the idea that you just
didn't open attachments and didn't use
attachments to send things you could
prevent a huge portion of the tax and so
this was really trying to aim to get
people to change their habits and change
their behavior but of course as people
change their behavior the tactics of the
attackers as well so in this case it was
dark and getting people taking advantage
of the fact that they might implicitly
trust this kind of covered sorry cloud
service instead of taking into account
like even if they don't want something
from Google Drive it can still be
malicious
and so particularly in that community
technology is this way that they can
enact connected people beyond borders
and it's something like as they say it
can be sending people to jail and so I
talks within the community will see this
sort of different campaigns and one
thing we talked about so-called actors
and so we try to look at how can we
identify connections between different
campaigns whether they're in different
regions or organizations so one thing
that people the class is our families
not always be the best indicator that
there's this sort of common enemy
because source code for iraq may be
publicly available or maybe being sold
typically in asia we see home-grown
around in different areas like Syria
will often see repurpose crime or in
other regions will see commercial
malware such as Ben Fisher hacking team
being used so one other thing that we
look at his command and control
infrastructure which is kinda just this
clear clear that there is the same actor
again going after various groups and so
we also look at the contextual
information what is being used in this
attack is it coming from what is obvious
source in center using similar tactics
and so I just wanted to quickly actually
go over our family that we do often see
and it's called plugs and so in this
case it's one of the more advanced drops
that we see being used in Asia and it's
been used for a long time in 2012
particularly when it involved they
reported that they actually identify the
creator based on things for example like
the PDP PDP PDP and so it kinda
disappeared for a little bit off the
radar and then later the same hour and
like him back to us with all the
identifying information described as
well as getting rid of debug messages
and things like this is a demo version
and so like actually I called you out
loading which is pretty similar to
jackie and so you pretty much have a
trio components where you have a sign
little an executable and so this way you
do have the side of trust executable
that is running and then it's just
simply I'd also surprised about it we'll
see lol and then the other thing it does
is it has this encrypted binary file
that contains the actual payload and so
then it is never actually been there it
simply in memory and so as analysis of
this right has been published then we'll
see things for example when it decrypt
data memory a kind of strips out
information from the header in this case
thankfully interest by Ben and the pea
coat and tie dye on its fine like acts
as these kind of typical features like a
keylogger taking screenshots in Iraq
files and it also has a lot of features
like you can have tons of
command-and-control servers with this
one is taking down then you can always
use another it also often uses DNA for
example just Google's is a good one that
way if it is being used against an
organisation what you can do is simply
avoid detection through their lives and
then also has multiple options for
communication protocols and so often we
see does
loading the favorite target for this is
my preference maybe funders
in this case this is a secure and we
actually saw this is not against the law
but also in Hong Kong and so this case
we kind of overlap we're back in the
spring we had actually the exact same
being used against any group and that
was with the repurposed earlier as well
as individuals in Hong Kong and Anthony
its collective heart attacks in Hong
Kong after me but so this is just one
example the slight slight recovery
purposes and then in the email it would
be impersonating the system for
membership a member of the Legislative
Council gave this presentation and so if
you're not actually aware these attacks
being aimed actually it can be really
really easy just to simply go okay this
is a legend and so in this case this is
very clearly the exact same this is the
same threat actor but we do see some
comment on keez against attacks and so
in that case it's really debate about
this is how much sharon is going up
across groups
is simply one first time flies that
actor is they're sharing of tools of
tactics and so well our focus is on
andrea we've actually seen overlap
between documented attacks against
industry our guys as well as government
and so one of these popular just
Rodriguez has actually been energy
sector and so perhaps unsurprisingly
because of that we have now started to
see attacks in Burma which is quite new
and so again this may be a little
surprised because there's just such a
huge transformation going on there and
the country is very rich in natural
resources and there's also have
investment from China and so a lot of
NGOs are concerned over these
development projects or the
environmental and human rights impact
and so we start to see again sorry these
emails are very clear but in this case
there's this email that was sent to
environmental group is working on issues
related and it was I had to redact it
was actually pretending to be someone
within the group and was just
referencing news article about the
special economic zone and Japanese firms
operate on it and so in this case does
have a link to a Google document which
is again the same sort of tactic being
used against other groups
you kind of get around education
awareness plans that I do it
campaigns that have been adapting and so
in this case it was really kind of this
weird roundabout thing we're headed to
go drive with actually linked file that
was supposed to look like a patent and
then I had just to download provider and
so this again with the same family that
we've seen in various attacks all over
which perhaps unsurprising this time
they were using the executable
there's there are and so kind of
underwear the connections are with other
campaigns because one we saw that was
using a related c2 to the sample it was
also using a revoked certificate samples
are any one using a revoked certificate
against Japan organizations and also
exactly the same time all the summer
we've started seeing this year drew
large volume of attacks in burma that
all sorted using the same our families
and started making increase to friends
and doing a little bit of research here
and the general reaction was oh dear
lord everyone is owned and a lot of this
comes from the fact that even for
example them I'm our government website
was compromised and so they started
serving up an hour and what I thought
was pretty interesting was very now says
was actually globalized recognized
recognized organization in the whaling
industry
I hear it was again there's just not
we're being hosted on the site and saw
that it was actually again it was plugs
but it was the same exact same an
executable that we saw being used
against our groups
and so we've actually just kind of
continued to see attacks related to
Burma not just with projects but also
with other similarly our families that
we've seen against the two organizations
I'm so considering all that are going on
there it's probably somewhere where
we'll continue to see it happens I was
related to current events into media
going on there so we just actually
recently put out a blog post today
giving more details about campaigns and
we also have several blood post to
specifically about that ban Khong
connection and so I guess I think it's
fabulous become more about Funcom
because my stuff
show more case study should ease myself
I had an eye on the web I focus on my
happiest time I I like to help those
democrats both democrats to analyze
those samples because no one willing to
volunteer to do this kind of work i mean
a nice work and also done both of like
like labor labor Association ngos Human
Rights Association stay with us for an
artists so this is our own here and also
made and I focus on doing my part time
PhD in my various school of science
technology due to some machining
attacker propounding attribution and
attribution and for a parade i mean they
time I'm it's very interesting if I'm
not working as an aging company is a
column sec to do some bad monitoring and
also the anti-dole solutions so that's
why I know station right I got little
bit pressure from ICO but I don't care
no because I'm represent the exam today
ok let's go ahead and 45 seconds war
machine
criminal national secret I don't have
any spy gear Spy everywhere no problem
and ok case study about apt against Hong
Kong observation against people in a
political movement and against the
website then this is now
observation you expect any packing
square I want to press up 79 that you
could go up in the room right because
you could from the sum from you chipped
in and about what is right and also
katie has already apart on those
projects and explain away the pain
behind observation actually fall for us
sorry for the past 18 months and
including our business scope is very
good football including NGOs democrats
University even very tinny charity
companies the ass too are you going to
fix our computers are sorry we just
analyzed attack on the face but we will
i get for this organization what they i
mean who is attacker we don't know who
is behind but we know that they really
like have a very good point dates came
as US when they are on saturday on the
sunday we didn't receive any attack and
very incidents if you're hitting some
China or days but some soda national
days in the process of October or even
some golden week of the shopping we
didn't receive any attack for past three
years so I don't know who is behind but
I I know they need holidays alright
alive as well and we just know that use
the Chinese characters and we didn't
capture and last mouth like rats
collapse this kind of superpower agency
to know every part of the China
copy every week and you know just how
obvious you know that's why we can't do
it like that and also we are not as
Indian like we could get this kind of
funny string when we could know this is
from the first and second department and
further division wherever brother so
before the apt one report and friendly
printing a report about apt one other
comment so that's why we can't justify
who is if you ask me who is behind us I
can tell you and we are the most of them
put a c2 Mbps serving Hong Kong and
second line of the internet service for
wider isn't quite fun actually today
that we got law enforcement Gaza from
Hong Kong but he's not working in that
division but anyway then BB port many
years ago many years we've reported a
concert they simply ok we got a case ok
then we took the undersea 2003 just
unplug the machine that's a finished
case coast and I are you going to see
two are now I'm sorry that this is not
how the police and the police police are
out there I P is an ongoing but when you
go to the other place than the surface
not there is our pantry is in mainland
China the case also coast so we are long
but that's why the artist to artist and
some even or but righty i mean democracy
and other people police and say are you
losing any money now so we can accept a
case ok I want to do that
ok well as their favorite a low they
like a lot like people immigration
immigration to get a lot a lot of hours
poison ivy China may want so if there's
an operator in this room I suggest you
talk about with about this 2014 the top
administration choose for your next a
low right because you're low people pay
for it
like many people ok don't use poison ivy
is too boring or just simply refers to
top one is better more commercial one
much much better if their operators here
and certain also observed a single
server for talk attack I found a
reference to other people in hong kong
they don't use the single server 45
purpose
shows something but some of them and
they used to force me to against like
legislative counselor of the films they
used for fishing or fishing other
apartment or phishing site looks like
this like a business when they accept
order and they got ok the project's cost
money is collected and they got another
business is doing fishing banning the
use the same server compared with the C
two other attackers will you really have
a dedicated target will use the same
support you plan to put the server as a
stealthy so I find it there bro I should
think they don't want government so that
money would not be so stupid you know
Chinese Japanese mary's mother so that's
because I don't think it's one Chinese
government is from the new business
agency to do either they put the same
server to do different purpose and now
people to know that you didn't work
right to disclose the city or GPS
ok we got some green dot no worries
don't feel asleep here
ok pieces my grading I see JFK are
different attack and cancer by both ok
level 0
defacement and phishing site they simply
just because fishing side that had to
print web site because the problem is a
lot of ngos a lot of democratic parties
they didn't have fought people to do
their profession design enterprise
management on the idea and is simply
just use PHP pocketbook educators desk
and he's like my secure victory over
death definition and put it on the
complement system ok well but didn't do
any passion and also the left at the
percentages represent how many cases RBC
to analyze this kind of attack never
want putting an executable and frame
inning and Akamai sites come to my site
is common for for for that because
to such as horrible they don't they face
it is simply put a link is a credible 22
in fast to spread out to play low
through those to those supporters oppo
people we visit the website ok no one
ever to send emails from Google Mail
Gmail and drop off a you have got some
documents that are you human form for
you to fill in and say hi did some
secret source of the documents you need
to download from the chopper from the
Google now and also supports Google
chief administrator asked you to reset a
password they use different techniques
very funny you signify the Chinese Hong
Kong is traditional Chinese English if
you do a more professional operator its
new treaties with Chinese sometimes so
that we can use this kind of phishing
emails but we found a lot because it
uses Google Yahoo to go and top US
israeli heart attack where they are
ready come from but I got some tricks to
know where they come from
level 3 sending malicious attachment to
exploit I suppose is the same as Katie
the cases cover in different political
attack packets about and poison ivy and
robert was being see something light up
before sending more customized I mean I
support it and some encryption he likes
a lot okay I sometimes I find one time I
found myself cause this is pure X 964 is
the key
but I'll I didn't notice a report last
week because of a few years ago but they
like to use the extra and for those
customers encryption but for that and
also I just 11 to two samples but in
taiwan a lot a lot of customized
encryption and is a heart attack by the
antivirus software and there were five
malicious mobile application I will
explain this in details for espionage
purpose I got a real case study and
there were six is about
against our sites for this about what
website I'm in trouble already finish
our case study with a professor from
information system in Hong Kong
University of Science Technology and
also refused two offers on the copper is
our our group members to consider is how
I cut if I actually coming
straight level five and six so that you
can no worries and revolutionary
commitment but you know because some
kind of movement so yesterday some
friends asked me to be careful about
umbrella movement but anyway if you go
to Beijing China don't carry any yellow
amber yellow things or even stickers or
otherwise it will be checked by them and
say hey are you involved in this kind of
movement so I i'm serious so that's why
then the current samples accurate in
this case study 1 the pic mobile
application and actually this
organization no problem hope you guys
doing such kind of how many people are
pissing people how to coding and
programming in hong kong but very
strange is that one day they got SMS
message sent to different audience and
say hey I pissed on its application and
CO and you could help coordinate occupy
central that means the umbrella movement
and also prefer to work with different
hope for educators and method for
analysis as well as win when we got this
number i mean this message check out and
joined a peace sign tobacco for
education for the Coordination of Occupy
central ok maybe separate enjoyable
sometimes then maybe you just get over
it but it was very fun yes it's not
received
midnight its me see if I mean that the
idea is when during the evening time
from six to ten more or different
occupying areas for for beating
forecasts of gathering for discussion
and every night
not just one time we also by this time
of year of time and all this message
when the people more people group that
in occupation areas they saw this
message is not send it by morning time
early morning time no real nice I didn't
mention here but my slide but this is
how they do it very considerate of the
we often work to the Occupy central
areas that this conversation for us to
have a free application ok what you
still inside for the application
possible this year and actually four
hours talking about but they're
interesting is that they will produce
that happened on a PK powers attempt to
try to sleep and other message right but
right now in hong kong there's no one
who's this week so that's the point
looks like they just be used to coat
and capturing outgoing call to my phone
and I mean on the receiver I mean
competition POW's we find that they hope
hope and we call them to this letter
dated comes up we want our extension and
here this is the coat ok and put it here
for this is output be calling part
because the outgoing call for that
capturing and save it here at home
directory up and that the path the kind
of we want to put a recording under this
folder in hong kong people at Target
happy we got this kind of application ok
is interesting is using BrdU a secure
location and try to figure out what is
your location but if they do more if the
operator to more recent research should
be say hey I do it now
Hong Kong so good research here so they
leaked their identity but that's the
point I used to do to to mention about
prime location
findings
IP is still working so they're still
alive but I didn't report any policy
because I want me to stay alive it's
more fun than you could I be addressed
is how cold in this room service as well
and this one I would pop out details
about this IP address is aspect to be
the series over but sometimes comes in
sometimes life sometimes not like a
sister to be able to stop by Nasir and
other than when you look at the coop
extra couple go to start new consumer
credit history
contest baby as a magistrate actually we
got the whole application become hard
and put put under natural account is
open to public if you are interested I
was actually linked to study the dish i
mean the application this nice than they
like to put out a plea there so I tried
to crack the password every time I see
this I would try to crack it but it's
very difficult you know muscle strength
I just hit with a very funny screen you
know is there any finished now the party
is about the people just about
application for me I observed the one of
the IP address I mention this one
10 11 or 1.54% and when I check out this
is bad for the 2014 17 September ok this
is a corporation we ICP das easy to the
IP address list with software that IP
address I mention and you can see what
you do officer is to changing all the
time after the other than the data for
year of six months and 14 in the
preparation of every used his IP again
ok to be soft difference en
domains and then an awful lot of quick
and I'll show you this is the Sprint
from passive totals rank up to brandon
has different doc rhetoric of CNN in
this year in July and August and how
about recently just two days days ago
when we started this and also does some
fishing sites like match.com Katie we
all dat we are in the early early
October then I would like to reduce
didn't use the same IP address or the
e-mail address for the single purpose of
attack attack
sometimes they need to business today
except different assignment and
operational mission to other work
because but now the Legislative Council
on holidays so when the holidays they
also need to get more business when I
get a kiss or so need to do some general
one ok but that's my observation there
like it's very tough you know doing this
kind of operator ok for this IP address
is always in the correct IP addresses in
Peoria and also find here
photo there is mention about the samples
the samples here you can see there's a
key under this IP address before back to
the tune of the 2012 June this year as I
mentioned in the member because about
this lie about level 02 level six then
it looks like they are willing to using
the same trick to back to this level 12
put out executable and other compromised
website copy of the people to do it
through the hidden meaning or somethin
my friend so you could find it and I
suspect when you turn it is israelis and
simply hope those hope method is like a
key locking as well and send it back to
the same server with the hopes that
policy and budget is very limited they
just open different posture receive and
send up a low so that's why we need to
show sympathy ok
this is the case that he won perhaps a
case study too and I think if you are
living in Hong Kong or pay a lot of
attention to Hong Kong aches this is
really impressive one because this is
not about malicious attachment this is
about distributable out of service
attack that it's not just last 12 days
is not about money
oK so that's why I would let you know
more details in this and for me to race
repins participate as a bunch of their
party to the punishment has 24 they're
looking web hosting website and also to
give the comment about instant response
one or one of our roads our fellows in
the board and he is responsible for you
during the attack traffic which is the
internet service providers ok so he's
also one of the company to undertake
protection and he does attention as well
for this or by the background you could
go to disrupt this public sly for that
but as I said I I work with Rico offers
to the case study the case that he's
already have a job and confirmed by the
Hong Kong University right now is we
will send you have a business will
because I I don't think right now the
University of California Press showcase
at about this time a large scale of it
ok this time I am NOT going food for the
for the Harris they attack Iran outcome
and PLP is to put books is the rep
the booking website booking website
owner or they're organized organizer
their response is from 214
important of June actually that he'd
also attack against the couch where the
water quality and service covering more
surveys of the race for the domain for
the pope to educate right along the
fence and also poked
organizer also add 50 free and also
ended up being a service provider for
more better specs resources to defense
that you don't attack 15 and 16 when
that happens on WoW looks like you have
a very strong defense they tried to
initiate already initiated 100 billion
yen us with questions today Ms on this
is not my sometimes you can check back
to the digital attack map if they are
not quite check out this kind of
historical records from this on the
Google digitized map and Amazon say hey
now stop it you're willing to me which
is charged EUR worries more shuttle
money but you give us 100 billion yen as
we go again and and also the CDN service
and your domain is famous Hong Kong and
also under attack and with the picture
of it at 10 gigabit per second
ok because he could wash and fruit of a
traffic but you have no more resources
to their existing crimes including Yahoo
so drop we also can't take any the party
in the party so the only guys only agent
want us to deploy
only for metal prints but we limit our
service but you know what is charged is
just about the only child about 200 West
or even got huge
I was 17 ok that hackers you know they
are very committed people initiated yet
as an entity does attack but the picture
of it is about 150 gigabit per second
unit is cumshot pic is about in hong
kong mister one word of a night of the
traffic about watching the World Cup but
all the time the three days we suffer
this one discount warning about her and
was the outcome looks like I still
member we are very frustrated with just
being hit with punched but no no other
message our last report the police but
police say hey you know any money now we
are sorry but that is it
China China Telecom for investigation
ok but you have
announced two weeks but the organization
very very very smart this time ok
extent of time and even your website we
got people that means that you simply
just gearing up to insert a paper right
and also them cultural project your
copper project is about a lot more for
kept for dedicated nameservers to
increase the defense right by the
blanking the story and get that have to
find that we still can't get done
website the pope's organizers extended
period of time they do the last resort
on chanti like a final battle 300
gigabit per second he does that had
taken place before the voting because
the working person not yet officially
they're free DNS profession
antipersonnel track of what has 100
million staying at her perceptions
DNS product with 128 MB per second DNS
requests also there's a one attack we
have we didn't mention is about as a
self service which will be negotiations
attack is a new attack by gulf Air metal
prints poster in the traitor and say try
to do a lot of renegotiation for the
service which is a pretty for that
reason they master there was that had a
more and also they initiate a lot of
large amounts of random and no
assistance request you know operator is
a business agency they need to get the
money they may be simply deposit 40% to
70% of the money so neither show some
work people you know this is like a
crazy to see whether to bring it done
but for how come the counter medication
is transfer some powers to something
service providers and use any concepts
of September consumption attack and how
could you not widest some rest
audience response and widest
extent I could go up against you for the
defense and also we also the pope also
organizer updated and reputation to
minimize depends dependence on the cloud
hosting and water system around a crop
right and at the same time in the
morning time but in the past hour on the
same day the operator is not in fact
here for the attack with the capital
money to deposit the more money we tried
to bring down if they are in the Chinese
University of Hong Kong once you've
brought you want to assist or even
including your weed idk
organization education no one could
assess but they failed of course because
chk greatest problem but you see how
committed are how crazy they are they
they want to break down there is no
money para website information nope just
maybe and no banking statement and 21st
they have no more videos attack suddenly
stopped and I have check the 21st and
22nd is not Saturday and Sunday ok but
it's done and it may be awhile how to
really get better
remaining money for the project they
have no more ideas they sent out some
emails SMS service to because SMS usage
report and even send out some because
some fishing website I put books
underscore s of course this is easily
attacked and brought on by Hong Kong
Hong Kong domain registry before this
case what you learn i think is much more
important more serious than than the one
about those malicious attachment for my
handling for my handles incident before
because the disparate 14 days
attack of this morning
server is already deployed their
infrastructure is already boarded air
and also some attacks from China I B
also from Hong Kong and also to server
topic no one stopped to stop about his
country crest know that's why I asked
questions too can you handle this kind
of attack in your home run it's not
about for my handling some commercial
case of a DDoS attack or something some
super and coach trading companies they
will say no I'm want at you they were
gonna actually occurs Rihannas reforms
you hey I'm going to attack you I'm
going to ask you to pay me for six
thousand RMB ok I get your free days
this is my number this is Mike you
contact the customer service area and
may peace as opposed to calling me okay
and if you don't pay and we attack those
commercial 10 honest but there they told
me that I we are not attacking you
you're super entry code trading company
but once we attack you BB to get more
resources get more zombies attack you we
can undertake other business so better
to settle you just as 4,000 so please
stop this legalization for commercial
attack but here the pope no one call us
email no one has a security or you know
we can ask them to stop the campaign
money to settle the things but the
structure that infrastructure services
here is there already so that's the
point
can you imagine this kind of company or
agency was behind this kind of resources
to launch discover tech for 14 days
door entry or something
infrastructure critical infrastructure
and I can you translate that of a true
this is very scary remember this server
I mean this machine I mean this system
just a booking website is about the
website for the hong kong people to work
for the next to vote for their
preference for the how to what is the
past proposal to let the next chief
executive only there's nothing during
where you're working for anyone but
looking for a passport proposal next
chief executive vice president and
there's no credit card information
Hong Kong identity card information no
address no privacy information because
all of them will be stored in the
database and encrypt so they can't do it
for any benefits for that so it's very
inside I want you guys to know about it
ok this is my and not make history for
any questions I'm thankful to our
citizens and also Katie also work with
me
together to this discount delivered this
kind of attack attack
operate you enjoy it because I hope that
you'll also pipe also talked about
different political parties are
supportable attack projects at the same
time for us to meet and deliver some
kind of case study in hong kong how to a
different tack
touch then different dimension of
prospective for you guys for reference
instead of just mention or just
malicious attachment though any
questions for us
but I suppose I need to promote a
citizen and as well in the city and that
there's the rub cycle of prop message I
learned a lot from there and the
reported publish regularly then that's
very very nicely with and call up to go
and indeed house is very nice thank you
so much for listening