hello everyone my name is okay and today
i will talk about our joint work with
thomas eisenberg and massey liskewicz a
white box masking scheme resistant
computation and algebraic attacks
so before going into details i would
like to give a small history of palantry
the seeing stones by j.r.r tolkien so
these magical stones are created
for many purposes but the simplest
intention is the communication in middle
earth
however these stones are dangerous as
they are possessed by sauron the dark
lord so one of the most important victim
is saruman dwight he was corrupted while
using or trying to use a device by the
whispers of the real owner of palantri
to darklord
so now sauron owns the device and can
read
the user's minds and can see memories
even if the deepest secrets are not
secure anymore so
what we can see from from here is saron
as the adversary in this scenario on the
device can inspect your memories and can
manipulate your minds which is whispers
so now let us consider
uh this example in our setting as
adversary we have the same purpose as
sauron revealing the secret revealing
the sensitive information
when we compare the capabilities of of
both two cases we see a similar
structure so while sauron can inject
thoughts by whispering and see your mind
our adversary can inject faults and can
whisper
can inspect
memory
okay what can we do then uh the only
thing that we can do actually
are our stack strengthening the our
implementation and now we would like to
quote this beautiful line from earlier
works when the attacker has internal
information about a cryptographic
implementation the choice of
implementation is the sole remaining
line of defense and this is this is why
we need white box cryptography
so this model is is used to protect
service
secrets purely in software
where we can actually think about the
environment as hostile
and one of the examples is is one one of
the rising services today the streaming
services this can be music your gaming
or or or video
so also mobile payment systems can be
seen as an example however today all the
um old academic proposal has been
practically broken
so in this work we tackle this problem
and propose the first combined masking
scheme that can resist state of art
white box attacks combination and
algebraic attacks which we give the
details in the following slides
so we analyze two security notions in
cryptography which in which we show that
they're actually incomparable the first
one is probing security against
competition attacks and prediction
security against algebraic attacks
we give concrete constructions for
arbitrary orders of computational
security and
firsthand secure or second order
prediction security moreover we prove
this security of this this constructions
to um to give this uh proofs we need a a
we need to provide a novel security
definition and the novel composibility
proof for prediction security and and um
and which we extend actually from from
the previous work moreover we supported
our results with the with the with the
verification tool by bureaucrato which
is uh for for for prediction security
and mask verif for probing security and
finally we provide a proof of concept
aes implementation to analyze the
overhead and security features of our
design
so let's deep dive into the into into
state of our attacks on whitebox systems
um the first attack is based is based on
a well-known physical attacks on
embedded devices as you know the
embedded devices that run a
cryptographic algorithm are vulnerable
to physical attacks and another way an
adversary can use such an information
such as power timing or use an active
attack to implement a fault injection
in a very basic scenario the secret
value can be revealed using a
differential power analysis
and this idea is later applied to
whitebox system in 2016.
so the idea actually the same um the
such general analysis
the idea is actually the same as as the
such analysis and the only difference is
actually the source of traces
in this version an adversary can
simulate the power traces by softer
execution traces so these can be memory
accesses intermediate values or written
or red values
so these attacks can be found in github
page such in marvels and you can
reproduce or attack these attacks on on
nearly all white box system in the
literature and this actually shows us
how how impactful these attacks are
and
of course
as
a natural approach we actually trying to
find the contract or how to how to
contract these attacks and what we can
do is to take a look at
take a look at the
back at the good good old masking so
let's recap the boolean masking here so
here you can see we have x0 until x1 are
randomly selected and the final share is
actually
represented as in this as in this
equation you can see in here
and and and and finally we denote this
secret sharing by uh with with n
and and plus one variables and the main
ideas is actually simple as you know the
the
the every n-tuple is indeed independent
of the secret
so this is the main idea of the the side
the the countermeasures of against such
analysis
however we cannot just rely on masking
because the strength of the masking is
actually related with the noise within
the implementation and a differential
and
a dc adversary can produce noise-free
traces
and of course that's why we need to we
need to do we need some more additional
noise accelerations sources such as
shuffling or control flow of skeleton
these methods are introduced to um to
increase the noise in in a masked white
box implantation
so
now let us take a look to the algebraic
attacks
which is another hit for the masking on
white box systems
so this is introduced by two different
teams against uh famous other ink
pointers the strongest design in white
white box context in 2017
so the idea is
is is to third first finding a window
that contains uh the secret sharing
corresponding to a value that can be
predicted
then the question is to find finding a
linear combination of of the nodes that
gives you this predictable value
and this linear combination
is actually reveals the sensitive value
of course if we increase the order of
these combinations for example if we
look for quadratic combinations of of
your nodes
this will result in a higher order
algebraic attacks
okay
while we are thinking about how can
implement masking on white box systems
the algebraic attacks actually break are
our every hope as you can see from the
previous slide
we don't need to consider the masking
order the attack works on every
every order as long as the masking is
linear
therefore
the boolean masking no matter what the
order is is indeed vulnerable to first
order algebraic attacks
so
uh we have seen two main attacks and now
let's take a look how can we define
security security against these attacks
which key which actually gives us the
the foundations of our design
so
let's start with the probing security
the easy one
this is a well-known model introduced by
ishaito very briefly it implies that the
adversary obtains t intermediate
variables per execution where t t is is
a fixed integer and our goal is to prove
that every set of t intimate variable is
independent of the secret
and the second notion is is against
algebraic attacks it's a quite new
notion and in this case adversary can
obtain all internet variables but can
only use a lead order combination to
combine them so if you think about if
you think about our previous example in
the in the against the other other
pointers what we actually do looking
into the linear combination so that
means our order is order is first order
combination which is which is linear
combination and therefore that's that's
why that that that's why the boolean
masking is actually vulnerable to first
order objective attacks
and here against uh for our security
notion our goal is to show that
the probability of distinguishing two
sets of plaintexts by looking at the
lead order combinations
of the circuit notes should be
negligible
so this is an important notion important
notion for us first of all
um it is seen in the previous slides it
it's it's quite new like 23 years old
and it provides security against a very
powerful trade on whiteboard design and
maybe this this might be a keystone for
the next generation generation of
masking therefore we would like to have
a closer look at this model
so
as we described earlier
this model
analyzed the behavior of a function fc
that means
all the d order combinations of the
circuit not
circuit nodes um
from this highlighted area and this area
is actually gives us
a stag and if fd2c means that
we looking to do every deed order
combinations of of the nodes as you can
see in this slide so if if the equals
one that means we only look into linear
combinations
or of these nodes if the equals two we
looking at the quantity combinations we
can just multiply two nodes and add some
some some so
at the rest of the shares so
that's the main idea um now let's
consider two inputs x and x prime
and the main idea is is to finding a
function from f f d to the c
such that this function
is constant or high bias when the input
input for the input x and vice versa for
the for the for the x prime so
let's let us let us recap recap it again
we would like to find the function such
that um in a very basic scenario for an
input x
this function should be constant so
um
so this is this is our this is our
encoding function and this is our
circuit function and
when we think about this this circuit is
a combination of of our encoding which
is a you can think about the secret
sharing function
this should be
a constant function
um so
if if an adversary cannot find such a
function that means that the prediction
security
i mean the main idea is is that so the
the prediction circuit requires every
function from your set
should have love bias
although uh one of the notions indeed
covers the other they are actually
incomparable let's take a look at this
the first example we have the boolean
masking example here
as we discussed in the previous slides
we know that an end order boolean
function
is actually
vulnerable to vulnerable algebraic
attacks and
we know that it's actually secure
against probing attacks if it's
applied correctly
now let's take a look at them like a
look at the
minimalistic quadratic masking by
biberico photo
so here you can see the decoding uh
function of the scheme is as in this
slide
here
and
and it has proven and and and um and and
it is as proven as it's secure against
first order algebraic attacks
however when we think about the sharing
we can see that the sharing of uh x0 is
three out of four uh which implies that
the probability of of
uh
probate of the of the final share is
equal to the x or which which is secret
is three out of four so that is
that's
so thus it is actually not secured
against probing attacks
so as a result what we can see is
there is no comparability between
probing security and prediction security
and we need both notions in our proof
and and this is the main reason why two
countermeasures were proposed on top of
each other to prevent both attacks in
the earlier works
so what we learned from the from these
two attacks is the following first of
all we need a regular secret sharing to
eliminate computation attacks and
secondly we need to increase the
decoding order at the same time to to to
gain resistance against algebraic
attacks
so now let's let's remark the building
masking is in this left-hand side
now the question is how can we increase
the decoding order so the idea is simple
we would we need to share
a single share so let's say x0 in this
example
we would like to represent extra with a
multiplicative masking such that x0 is
is a product of of d plus one random
variables and the rest of the shares are
actually stays the same
and
um
and and and we denote this masking by an
nd masking scheme
um so let's so before going into the
into an example we would like to take a
look at the encoding and the decoding
decoding function here so here instead
of having um even if we have an n plus
one random variable now we have d plus
one random variable for for for for
multi multiplicative representation and
and and the minus one variable for just
selected randomly
and the last uh player's share is
actually calculated by a product of of
your
product or multiplicative represented
share and the rest of the boolean rest
of the linear shares and now the
interesting thing is here are our
decoding function as you can see there
are what
what what we did is actually trying to
de increasing the
decoding order here you can see uh we
did the degree of of our decoding
function is is d plus one
and now let's let's take a look to an
example where n equals three and d
equals one and here you can see the
boolean masking on the left hand side
and you can see that we increase the
decoding order by representing x0 with
x1 x2 tilde plus x one tilde
um so this is this is this this was our
our um our data transformation now as a
regular masking scheme the data
transformation is is followed by
by gate transformation so we we provide
the secure exor and and refresh mask
gadget and the foundation of these
gadgets are actually the same as as a
boolean masking
so however now we have to be careful
of the intermediate variables that
actually represent x0 because
yeah and let's let's say let's take a
take a look at the basic
example of secure exit operation here
you can see every every every share
besides that and is is share wise and in
order to secure the correctness of the
digit we need a variable u
and here you can see the the concrete
constructions for first and second order
exactly and using a similar ideas we can
transform end and refresh mask operation
for our purposes and for the details of
this gate we would like to refer to the
paper
and
so what about what the cost of of this
transformation and um what is the
overhead so here we can see through
three main parameters that that we would
like to take a look um these are number
of xor and and required randomness
so as you can see from the example
extra example we have a special
subscript uh ui and ux represent
representing the number of uh
and and extra operations within this
special variable that we
that we
defined in the previous slide and
an observer for d equals zero the
gadgets are actually become uh become
the regular uh secure mask operations
for the exorcist of course there we
actually increasing the total number of
shares which gives us a linear increase
and the cost of the operations of u and
and as you can see from the highlighted
values and for for for for you for ux
and ui this can be one and two as in
this example as you can see here um
these are actually small values for for
example
um
for the end gadget uh again the complex
is n square but now the main overhead
comes from this uh spec
from the from this the form of a
specific variable we
and for refresh mask we actually see a
similar pattern of course now we we need
a more randomness for in order to define
this operation
and we interpret these results more at
the end of our presentation when we take
a look at the as implementation
okay
until now we we reconstruct our scheme
now we would like to focus on how to
prove the security of our design let's
take a quick look at how the proof
techniques are working in our settings
starting from the from the probing
security so as a caveat of our scheme
only a subset of shares is actually
uniformly distributed as you can see
extra is is actually biased
thus an adversary can predict um x0 with
high probability
so therefore we are actually losing um
one probing secured order in order to
gain algebraic security
so in our proofs
we see these nonlinear shares as public
values accessible by the adversity and
therefore
the simulation
for our simulation-based proof can also
access these values
and and we we show that in nds and this
scheme provides security against n minus
one order attacks
and moreover we supported our results
with
them with the verification by mass wave
and these verification calls can can be
found publicly available
now let's take a look at the the
predictive security proof and the main
idea is simple as we described in in the
prediction security security definition
we need to show that every linear
combinations of our circuit should have
low bias when the input is fixed
that is the nodes are a function of your
nodes or your combinations of your nodes
should be a function of of p arrange
or your randomness source
so it is so it is already shown that due
to linearity composition is is actually
easy to prove
and and therefore the
the an adversary cannot distinguish any
sets of inputs
and and for for our first order gadget
we we use a tool provided by berkovito
to verify the security of our design and
the interesting thing is is actually see
you can see the bias bound of gadget as
you can see
these are actually independent of your
linear masking or drain
and
now let's take a look at the second
order security the idea is quite
intuitive intuitively extended now the
combination that combinations that we
need to take care
are or become quadratic and moreover the
first order bounce should be much lower
than the uh pre-response and again the
idea is what what we said before
the adversary cannot distinguish any
sets of inputs
okay
however the the
one one thing that we need to take take
care of course the combinations
composition
however the quadratic composition cannot
be extended in a trivial way as we need
to consider combinations from from two
different circuits um
the so if you think about the second
order combinations from two different
circuits that's by linearity as in the
as in the previous result this can be
done easily however when we think about
the combinations of
two first order combination from two
different circuits when they when they
add them together when we combine them
together now this
that needs to be special um attention
so we proven our our are our protein in
two fold first one is parallel
composibility
and and where the gadgets are operated
in parallel and the second
and the second is it's okay sequential
as is in this is in the figure so
therefore we have proven the composition
in in parallel order and
gets the circuits that operate in
parallel and sequences uh and and
circuits that um operate in sequential
order so
but the proven at the end is the
composition of an arbitrary circuit so
what can we interpret how can we
interpret these results so this is the
this is our this will be our main result
here so
the probability of an adversary to
distinguish two sets of plaintext is
less than two to the minus 128 if the
window contains at least a 1.5 000
random notes
so these random nodes can be supplied to
the circuit um in in in in a in a in a
in a very basic manner is that is you
can think about as the random
dummy nodes these nodes don't need to be
act in your circuit but there has to be
some random notes so that the adversary
will not be able to have a window that
contains the secret shares and
less than 1.5 000 random nodes
and and that's why we need an additional
obfuscation there on top of every white
box design
um in the final part of our presentation
we would like to take a look at the
proof of proof proof of concept as with
that with a performance comparison so
here you can see that this light blue
line corresponds to the previous
approach where two different masking
schemes are needed to combine
to get the desired security level and
now the bottom blue line
corresponds to the regular masking
scheme without and without a nonlinear
component
now
we can combine from our intuition from
the overhead and see that
r due to the structure of our skin it is
efficiently increase the security order
in a dimension of n here you can see
however uh still the
the nonlinear order is actually
bottleneck of our skin
uh for the randomness course you can see
that again we have this uh we have the
light blue line corresponding to the
previous approach where two masks are
two masks are needed and the bottom blue
line corresponds to the
the where there is non nonlinear
component um for the random scores we
see a similar structure also and better
results with respect to
two different using two different
maskings i'm asking at the same time
now in conclusion
we have proposed the first masking
scheme that combines a linear and linear
component to achieve resistance against
both computational algebraic attacks and
prove the security in both
bot probing and prediction security
notions that are incomparable
we we provide a first
and second order prediction security for
concrete constructions of n1 and n2
masking schemes we'll provide a proof of
concept a bit wise as128 implementation
the leakage and performance analysis
thank you for your attention if you have
any questions please feel free to feel
free to contact us or if you're
interested you can you can find more
details on our eprint and if you would
like to take a look to the verification
code or analysis code please feel free
to go to visit visit our github page and
here you can download our masquerif code
and analysis and also the as128
implementation thank you