in this talk i'll be presenting our work
entitled cutting through the complexity
of reverse engineering embedded devices
this research is joint work by members
of the automotive security group at the
university of birmingham
myself sam thomas
ian
so let's begin
suppose you're tasked with checking if
some device contains vulnerabilities
where would you start
would you look at the hardware
well we could go from the hardware
perspective and attempt to obtain
schematics try to identify different
interfaces to interact with the device
for example jtag or virus peripherals
over wi-fi or lte
but generally for an arbitrary device we
don't always have access to schematic
diagrams or a list of all possible
interfaces
furthermore some of the interfaces might
available might need to be reactivated
so all of this requires quite a bit of
manual work and intervention
so how about going from another angle
the software or the firmware
well in this case the firmware to what
typically these devices have multiple
components running different pieces of
software or firmware the baseband for
instance might use a real-time operating
system or the interface exposed to the
end users might run some variant of
android
and to complicate matters the source
code for the firmware will rarely be
available
and it won't easily easily be
downloadable from a vendor's website
either
so in this case to analyze the device
we'll need to reverse engineer some
aspects of it in order to answer the
question does it contain any
vulnerabilities reverse engineering is
an iterative process we gradually infer
facts about a particular device or
system under analysis by observing how
it responds to certain stimuli or by
drawing conclusions by reading the
disassembly of its firmware
so in the first instance where we
interact with the device directly we
tend to treat it as a black box we
supply some inputs
and observe what we get as output
of course this can only take us so far
so in almost all cases we'll dig deeper
and open the black box so to speak
and in this case we'll end up having to
reason about the firmware and some of
its components
but then we can ask questions such as
what code is executed when i supply x as
input
or i know why input should cause the
device to do z how does it perform z
as a general methodology reverse
engineering device happens in three
steps
first we'll need to identify its
interfaces so those that we can interact
with externally such as the wi-fi and
those that offer us a means of looking
at what's going on inside under the
packaging so for example jtag or a
traceable
next we'll use one of those interfaces
to obtain its firmware now for some
devices the firmware may be available
online but we have no idea in reality if
the firmware running on the device and
that which we can download on the
vendor's website is indeed the same so
we'll have to dunk or extract it to make
sure
finally we'll analyze the device and
this can be done statically for example
by loading the the firmware into a tool
such as ida or jeedra
and then reading the disassembly
or performing dynamic analysis by
interacting with the device using
hardware such as the usrp
but in general we'll use a hybrid
approach since both have advantages and
disadvantages
so great we have a good methodology
forming our analysis
unfortunately things aren't so simple
if we choose to go the static analysis
route the firmware itself really will be
just another black box
to make matters worse even industry
standard tools such as ida pro or jidra
do not form well out of the box when
analyzing firmware sometimes they miss
functions or disassembles things using
the wrong instruction set for example
when we have arm and some instructions
in the same firmware
on the other hand when analyzing the
firmware using a dynamic approach many
devices will have nice debug features
removed although there are certainly
plenty of devices that have some form of
tracing hardware those interfaces will
generally be quite limited
for example they might be quite
coarse-grained and only log the address
of basic blocks executed in a temporal
order and this is kind of a big problem
when a single component of a device
might execute many tasks concurrently as
their control flow will be interleaved
and so we'll have to have some way to
make sense of the trace
these mechanisms can also be limited in
other ways too so for example we might
only be able to obtain traces up to a
certain size or if the firmware executes
a tight loop we might observe that some
trace packets get dropped
finally when we have such limitations
it's often attractive to only trace part
of the firmware but which part should we
trace it can also be the case that while
we can restrict tracing to certain
portions of the firmware we can only
define a limited amount of exclusions
and inclusions
so in the face of all of these
challenges how can we analyze devices
effectively
well that's the question we attempt to
answer with this word
we propose a principled framework called
incision that attempts to add some order
to the chaos of analyzing embedded
device firmware by simplifying upfront
reverse engineering tasks
tasks such as obtaining a relatively
complete and correct idea of the control
flow of the firmware
and locating regions of firmware that
correspond to particular functionalities
our framework is built around the open
source disassembler jigra so that it
neatly fits into standard reverse
engineering workflows
so how does indecision work well from a
high level it treats reverse engineering
as a feedback loop that combines static
and dynamic approaches in tandem
the main idea is that instead of
treating the construction of a knowledge
base or database for our firmware and
our reverse engineering goals is
decoupled we can instead simultaneously
improve our knowledge representation of
the firmware being analyzed and also
identify areas of firmware we want to
analyze in more depth later
in the first step working from a very
basic database of the firmware ie just
auto analysis performed by our
disassembler we form a reverse
engineering goal which we encourage
using a domain specific language we call
this a policy
this might be something along the lines
of the device deals with the lte
protocol where does it process x layer
next we use that policy as input to a
process we call region inference
which essentially tries to match parts
of the current firmware representation
against our policy
it also contains a second stage which
groups disparate regions that
successfully matched into a large into
larger functionality groups akin to
compilation units
and we use these regions that are
identified to build trace configurations
to perform tracing when our trace
mechanism is limited in some way
next we perform trace capture
and then we use the trace as input to a
two-stage process of control flow
extraction
this essentially identifies different
flows inside the temporally ordered
trace of basic block addresses
outputting the regions corresponding to
context switching logic and task code
finally we integrate the extracted
control information from our trace back
into our database
this process might produce some database
conflicts due to incorrect disassembler
configurations however we attempt to
resolve those automatically
and now we arrive back at the beginning
of the feedback loop and decide if our
improved knowledge database is good
enough or if we should continue and pose
further queries to the process
if we choose to continue then we update
our reverse engineering policy and
follow the process again
so now the high level idea of the
workflow our framework enables i'll now
describe each component in more detail
starting with the firmware database
so the database or knowledge base is
essentially just a jiva project
we assume this will be given as input to
incision and will probably be created
manually
the process of doing so is generally not
too difficult and it really just relies
on us loading the firmware so defining
the basic memory mapping and layout
integer and then hitting the auto
analysis button
as for the execution tracing we assume
that the trace mechanism used will be
hardware based as we're operating on
real devices
but we don't assume that it's perfect so
it might be lossy i.e sometimes events
might be dropped if that is the case we
assume that we can detect if and when
that occurs
we also assume that the tracing
mechanism might be limited in a number
of ways so for example it might be
limited in terms of the number of ranges
we're able to trace or it might also be
limited in terms of how much we can
actually capture in more go
so in all to trace the firmware we'll
have a trace configuration as input
which we can view as a list of intervals
of the form start address and address
and as output we'll get a list of
program counter values ordered
temporally
representing the basic blocks that got
executed
next i'll describe reverse engineering
policies as i mentioned earlier policy
is just an encoding of our initial
reverse engineering goals
we base them on the observation that
many of these goals can be expressed
using simple queries if we treat the
firmware and its traces as a kind of
knowledge base
by simple we mean these queries are not
about relationships they're more about
if particular patterns exist so
concretely a policy is a vector of for
one of a better term indicators that
point to a particular part of firmware
or trace matching some criteria
so on the left we have a policy for
matching against reference login strings
around a call to m copy
and on the right we have a policy
matching a repeated load from a memory
mapped peripheral register which we
would identify within a trace within
incision we include policies using a
simple python embedded dsl which is
exposed by a g-drive's scripting
interface
we match policies by locating regions of
firmware and parts of traces
corresponding to indicators
repeated indicators such as our purl and
loop example from a couple of slides ago
are matched using the database and
traces while other kinds of indicators
are matched using just the database so
the references labels and symbols
we rank the strength of indicator
matches by their density hence we
consider firmware regions with many
matches that close together by address
to match move strongly
indicator matches are assigned the
bounds of the functions that includes
them
we group matches if they occur within a
small delta i.e the bounds of the
functions are quite close together we
base our approach to matching on how
firmware is composed
that is while a firmware block contains
everything from library code tasco to
earth's components each of those
components will be contained within its
own region of firmware
hence related functionality will have a
natural grouping within the overall
firmware blob further the sub components
of each of those regions will also have
a natural grouping by functionality as
the structure of compilation units that
make up each of those components will
almost always be preserved
we can visualize it as so
so viewing the firmware blob as many
compilation units concatenated together
within each of those larger components
assuming the firmware developers
followed reasonably good development
practices we'll also observe that these
components themselves can be broken into
units containing related functionality
and so each compilation unit contain
functions perform related tasks and this
is why we tie matched indicators to
function boundaries so we'll often end
up with many matches
and these will form the regions for our
trace configuration however some devices
will be limited in terms of the number
of regions that can be traced at the
same time if we have more match regions
than regions we can trace how do we form
a good trace configuration
well we form configuration by merging
some of the identified regions relying
on the observation the related
functionality tends to have good spatial
locality
to perform this merging we use an
algorithm called agglomerative
clustering
this works by iteratively merging
regions that are closest together by
some distance metric and in our case we
use the distance between the start and
end addresses of each region
so following obtaining a trace now we
need to make sense of it recall that
traces are just a list of addresses
corresponding to the executed blocks
ordered by the time in which they were
executed so we need to perform some kind
of processing to extract the real
control flow for each task and bit of
context switching logic we do this by
locating so-called boundary patterns
which we use as a heuristic to identify
one trace's reporting control flow for a
different task or thread of execution so
if we view this box as the whole phrase
then what we actually have is many sub
traces concatenated together
to find the boundaries of these sub
traces we start by following the
execution of whole trees using the
disassembly from our database when we're
unable to resolve the transition between
two blocks we consider that point as a
possible context switch and then
consider the preceding box as part of a
new sub-trace
now with these flows we attempt to
discern between context switching code
and passcode
we do this because context switching
code tends to dominate our traces and so
by excluding its bounds from our traces
we obtain better traces in the presence
of limited tracing capabilities we
discern the two types of code using two
methods
the first is based on the observation
that when entering task switching logic
or interrupt handlers we end up with a
pattern such as this where the flow on
the left does not end in an indirect
call yet the next block executed
corresponds to a function entry point
so unless we observed an error in the
trace we must have transitioned to the
right hand block by non-standard control
flow i.e a context switch
similarly when exiting such a routine ie
a context switching machine we observe
another pattern where we move from the
flow on the left to the right by an
indirect branch that then doesn't end up
at the beginning of a function or basic
block i.e more non-standard control flow
unfortunately these two heuristics are
not enough to discern between task
switching code and normal code since
traces might contain drop packets or
have excluded regions therefore we also
attempt to find when such patterns are
repeated across the entire trace which
tends to happen very frequently and for
that we try to locate repeated subplots
within our traces since our traces tend
to consist of hundreds of thousands of
events locating repeated patterns
naively is infeasible fortunately the
number of unique events in a trace is
usually much smaller than the trace
itself by many orders of magnitude
and due to the simplicity of those
events i.e that they're just basic block
addresses where you can encode our
traces as strings which can be analyzed
using very fast and efficient data
structures
namely suffix arrays and longest common
prefix arrays we use the longest common
prefix arrays to find subplots in our
trace that share a common prefix
similarly by inverting our trace and
then computing the same data structures
we can find repeated suffixes so after
separating out the different kinds of
flows in our trace we finally rejoined
the separated subtraces into larger task
level traces
now assuming a few trace packets are
missing we attempt to stitch the tesla
control flow together by following the
corresponding disassembly in our
database so for example if a sub trace
might end on address a and the next
start on a plus one we would stitch the
two together there are of course some
edge cases for example if one trace ends
on a call instruction and then resumes
on a function start we need to somehow
resolve that luckily these edge cases
can be easily worked out so finally we
end up with a collection of control flow
graphs that we can integrate back into
our firmware database which we do using
a process called feedback driven
refinement this process essentially
completes the feedback loop integrating
our dynamic trace information and our
staffing views of the filemaker
it works by adding any new control
flashes discovered due to our trace into
the database and is followed by
performing an auto analysis pass to
build cross references and discover
further functionality reachable by the
newly added edges this process might
trigger some database conflicts due to
incorrect disassembly and so on but we
can mostly work around those
automatically and if not flag them as
needing manual intervention which we'll
show later is rare and when it is
required is easy to resolve finally we
close the feedback loop by selecting a
new policy based on our updated database
or stop to analyze the firmware in more
depth using other methods
lastly i'll talk about how we evaluated
incision
well we use three metrics for our
evaluation real world usability
correctness and human effort we assess
each component incision separately and
also use it to perform some real world
reverse engineering tasks
the firmware data set we use is composed
of 10 firmware built on top of two open
source real-time operating systems free
rtos and zephyr
and two end user firmwares which we
extracted from real devices so a renault
body control module which is a bare
metal firmware based on the v850es
architecture and a huawei r216h wi-fi
hotspot we analyze the baseband
component of this device it runs vxworks
which is a real-time operating system
and it's based on the arm architecture
the first experiments we'll look at over
correctness
in our first experiment we evaluate
region identification and grouping
to do so we use the baseband firmware
since it's the most complex in our data
set and its trace mechanism is less than
ideal
and therefore a good test of incision
the mechanism is limited in a number of
ways for example we can only capture
trees up to one megabyte in size it
drops event packets and the number of
regions we can restrict our trace to is
limited
the full details of the tracing setup
consult appendix via our paper we obtain
a ground truth for this experiment by
manually reverse engineering the
firmware with the aid of embedded debug
strings and some leaked symbols we found
online
we identified regions of the firmware
that processed different lte layers and
estimated their boundaries
we then formed policies we expected to
identify in these regions and use them
as input to incisions region
identification and grouping algorithms
we use the area of overlap of our ground
truth and the regions identified by
incision to judge its correctness for
the policies tested we found that the
regions identified by incision matched
well with those we identified manually
their overlap with our ground truth was
very high and exceeded 90 in all but one
case
in this next experiment we evaluate our
control flow extraction algorithms for
this we constructed 10 firmware based on
free rtos and zephyr
we used open source firmware so we could
easily test different system
configurations such as task switching
frequency and the number of tasks
running concurrently
this allowed us to simulate various
potential worst case conditions
we also attempted to simulate a
worst-case scenario by including some
task code that repeatedly performs
indirect calls an effort to mimic task
switch behavior and therefore induce
false positives
to capture traces we emulated each
firmware using qemu and recorded a basic
block trace
since these traces were effectively
unbounded we sampled five
non-overlapping sub traces of fifty
thousand block addresses for each
firmware
to evaluate our algorithms we
established a ground truth by
identifying the regions of each firmware
that perform task switching interrupt
handling and correspond to task level
code
for each firmware configuration we
assessed if the decision was able to
decide between the task code and context
switching code and if it did so
correctly
as you can see from our experiments we
found that for firmware based on free
r2s incision worked flawlessly
however for the firmware based on sofia
while in most cases it was able to
identify the routines of code performing
interrupt handling and task switching
and decide from task code we found that
where indirect calls out number task
switches incision failed to identify
those test switches correctly we believe
that a real trace exhibiting such
behavior is likely to be rare in the
next two experiments we evaluate the
utility of our feedback driven
refinement method the mechanism we use
to close our reverse engineering
feedback loop
we use both real-world firmware for this
task and capture a number of traces for
each
we use those traces to measure the
degree to which a baseline database is
improved by our feedback mechanism
to do so he measures the number of
correctly identified function starts
after integrating the control flow edges
extracted from each trace into each
firmware's database
we establish correctness once again by
manual analysis
we also break down the number of newly
identified function starts by which
mechanism they were discovered by in
order to measure the effect performing a
further static analysis pass on the
database after integrating newly
discovered control flow edges
as we can see for both firmware
integrating control information
extracted from traces increases the
number of correctly identified function
starts
or for the bcm the increases do not
change after triggering an additional
analysis pass for the baseband most of
the improvements can be attributed to
this step
in addition to evaluating the
effectiveness of our feedback mechanism
we also analyze the database conflicts
and errors it can induce
to do so we use the same firmware and
traces as the last experiment and count
the number of errors detected when
merging extracted control flow into each
firmware database
we provide a breakdown of these errors
those that are technique can address
automatically and if those fixes are
correct and those that require manual
intervention which we assess in a
separate experiment
the traces from the bcm we encountered
no errors more for the base band we
found 53 in the first trace of 88 000
blocks and 188 in the second trace of
200 000 blocks
of those we found that for both over
half could be fixed automatically
and if those fixed only one was reported
as incorrect
in fact after some investigation we
found that jitra actually caused this
incorrectness due to its non-returning
function detection paths which it
performs as a default as part of its
auto analysis
in this next set of experiments we
evaluate incisions usability on
real-world reverse engineering tasks
for the first task we attempt to emulate
our bcm firmware from reset
since this firmware relies on a number
of peripherals and our emulator does not
provide support for them our objective
is to discover satisfying values for
checks against peripheral registers that
would otherwise cause the thermite to
stall in an infinite loop
we use incision to aid us in identifying
the location of these checks and to
measure its effectiveness we record the
number of basic blocks we're able to
execute following identification of each
check and report the improvements to the
firmware's database due to incision
we perform this experiment iteratively
we attempt to capture or control flow in
our traces and hold capture once our
trace buffer becomes full for example
when it becomes saturated by the
presence of a poland loop
we use incisions region identification
and policies to identify the location of
the checks in our firmware database and
manually identify the values required to
exit each polling loop and then provide
these values in the corresponding
peripheral register during the next
iteration of our analysis the following
graph visualizes the number of unique
blocks traced after each of those
iterations
as we can see we identify a number of
stool states and are able to use
incision to bypass them all thus showing
incisions effectiveness when aiding a
common reverse engineering task in this
next experiment we use incision to aid
in identifying how and where
cryptographic keys are stored and used
within our baseband firmware
in addition to traces we also use ram
dumps to perform this analysis we use
incision as a means of improving our
firmware database to make the search for
keys and the functions that use them
easier
this is based on the fact that a better
database will contain higher quality
code and data cross references as well
as more functions
since our objective is to identify where
keys are stored and used we use incision
to help create locate references to high
entropy buffers that are referenced from
regions of firmware handling the lte
protocol
to evaluate incisions effectiveness we
measure the reduction of the number of
buffers to analyze due to the database
improvements it performs
we also confirmed that some of those
buffers indeed correspond to
cryptographic keys manually
to perform our task we take first take
two traces using general policies to
help improve the initial database
we then identify the regions of firmware
corresponding to task switching code and
we use those to form trace
configurations that exclude the bounds
of those regions in subsequent traces
we then take a number of additional
traces using policies targeted targeted
at capturing traces of different lte
layers
we find that overall the resulting
database and identified functionality
regions we obtain allows to reduce the
number of potential key buffers to
analyze substantially from thousands to
tens as a result we were successfully
able to identify a number of lte session
keys correctly and the routines that
processed them
again demonstrating incisions ability to
reduce the effort of performing
otherwise tedious reverse engineering
tasks
in this last experiment we assess the
human effort of using incision
we recognize that performing such an
experiment objectively is difficult
hence we rely on a metric we can
concretely measure the number of tasks
incision offloads to its operator and
the complexity of those tasks
we do this by measuring the manual
intervention required to rectify
database errors and conflicts due to our
feedback driven refinement algorithm we
rank the tasks by their complexity those
that require no effort those that
require low effort and those that we
consider high effort
we classify low effort tasks as simple
changes to our firmware database the
first is that as those that require
adding a new function start and the
second is due to recreating a function
start due to perhaps a disassembly error
or an error induced by an auto analysis
pass
we use the traces from our baseband for
this task and recall that most of the
errors in those could be addressed
automatically
for those that could not we fix them
manually and then categorize the effort
required using the classification
outlined on the last slide
overall we found that all errors that
could not be rectified automatically
fell into the low effort category and of
those the most common by a very small
margin were due to us having to create a
new function start none of the errors
were high effort
so in conclusion the errors we found
were low effort and even though our
traces consisted of hundreds of
thousands of events the errors that
needed manual attention tended to occur
very infrequently indicating the manual
overheads induced by incision are
minimum
so to conclude in this talk we presented
incision a framework for reverse
engineering embedded device firmware
we evaluated our framework and its
components based on three criteria
correctness usability and human effort
and also showed that it's effective when
applied to real-world reverse
engineering tasks by analyzing two
end-user devices
thank you for watching our talk