good morning
together with thermapeters i'm going to
present our work improved
leakage-resistant authenticated
encryption based on hardware esco
processors
which is a joint work with olivier
brancher and charlemont from ucl in
belgium
as a starting point i would like to
recall what leakage resistance is about
and in summary the idea is that since
countermeasures against cyclone attacks
are very expensive
it can be interesting to avoid
protecting all the parts of an
implementation with equally strong
countermeasures
and if possible also to identify which
part of the implementation to protect
and how much
for example in 2017 bertie encourage
showed that if you want to encrypt and
authenticate a message
it is possible to generate a fresh key
with a key generation function that is
dpa secure
and to compute a tag with the tag
generation function that is dp secure
while leaving all the rest of the
computation leaking in an unbounded
manner which can of course lead to
substantial performance gains
now if you look at the state of the art
the first question is how to implement
the key generation function and the tag
generation function
one solution for this purpose is to rely
on masking and this is for example what
was proposed by bertie and kotors in
2019 with tdt
the interest of this solution is that it
has flexible overheads
because overheads that are at the
implementation level and for example if
you don't need sectional security you
will not pay anything
the negative point is that it requires
expertise in order to implement masking
securely
so as a step in the direction of making
things easy you have ciphers like izap
where the idea is to obtain dpa
resistance thanks to weakening
and therefore to rely only on spi
security
and here for example it is shown on the
right figure that you can generate a
fresh key
by absorbing your fresh nonce very
slowly and at the extreme bit by bit
and finally last year at chess
there was a paper called retrofitting
where the idea was to use aes and shaco
processors
by relying on the leakage-resilient plf
on the left
and the observation there was that
even sps security may not be trivial to
obtain on low-end device and therefore
hardware acceleration can help for that
and of course if you have that you can
also make the scheme more efficient
especially if you are able to digest the
nonce a bit faster
so this leads me to the outline of the
talk
the first thing i'm going to do is to
describe a flow in the tag verification
of the retrofitting paper
then i will discuss again the challenge
of obtaining spa security on low-end
devices and especially the challenge of
evaluating sps security
then thomas is going to describe how we
can fix the integrity flow of the
retrofitting paper with a new mode of
operation called lrbc2
and finally i will discuss performance
conclusions and other results
so i will start with the flow issue
and for this i will start by recording
what are the two main solutions to
perform tag verification with leakage
the first option is to work in the
direct sense
to recompute the tacto
and to perform the verification b
process of the figure
in this case it is very important that
the verification is protected against
epa
otherwise an adversary can use the
leakage about toe in order to mount
forgeries
alternatively it has been shown by
bertie encourters that you can also
perform an inverse based tag
verification
which is the verification a process of
the figure and in this case you can even
leak about verification in an unbounded
manner
now the problem with the retrofitting
paper is that the tag generation
function is based on a prf which is
non-invertible
and as a result
the tag verification is a dpa target
and this dpa target was actually not
covered by the most theoretical analysis
this is of course a problem because the
main case study of the retrofitting
paper is firmware update
which requires a secure tag verification
let us now look at how the verification
dpa works in practice
so on the right i pasted a piece of code
describing a 128-bit comparison from the
retrofitting paper
and this is mostly
four 32-bit source between the wheeltech
t and the candidate tax s
the basic attack on adversary can
perform is the following one the
adversary can choose a garbage cipher
text
he can ask to decrypt the cipher text
with many different tag candidates s
and he will then recover attack t thanks
to the leakage of esxorti
the results of this attack on an arm
cortex m4 are given below
and we can see that we can recover the
tag with confidence with approximately
1000 traces
and we also have very similar results
with the cortex m0 and m33
this already allows an adversary to push
garbage ciphertext into a device which
could lead to kind of denial of service
attacks
but we also have a more advanced attack
if the adversary knows any valid message
ciphertext pair
because in this case
the adversary can also compute the
random string air that was used to
encrypt and this is just the xor between
the message of end decipher text
he can choose a malicious firmware m
prime and then he can compute a valid
ciphertext c prime that will allow him
to push this malicious firmware in the
device
so we see that we have a problem with
the tag verification of the retrofitting
paper
and before moving to the solution i
would like to come back to the main
assumption of this paper which is that
we can have sp security for its leakage
resilient prf
so for this i pasted an example of
leakage resident prf on the left
and what we do there is we start from
the master key k
and at every stage of the prf we are
going to encrypt a zero or one plain
text
depending on the value of the nonce and
then after 128 stages we are going to
have a fresh kiki star
on the right we have exactly the same
kind of construction based on a sponge
then of course this freaking can become
more efficient if we are able to digest
the nons faster
because if we can digest b bits per
stage then we are only going to need 128
divided by nb stages
and this leads to a trade-off because if
you do that it also leads to a spa with
two to the nb possible inputs
leading to the question how fast can we
go while maintaining
side channel security
and essentially this requires assessing
the less investigated sps security of
the construction
as a result in the paper we try to
assess the site channel security of aes
co-processors ideally in a worst case
manner
we use three main steps for this purpose
which are pretty standard
first we selected points of interest
based on their signal-to-noise ratio
second we reduce dimensionality thanks
to a linear discriminant analysis
and finally we perform the template
attack in a principal subspace
we perform the attacks for two to the nb
inputs and we use different levels of
averaging
the results are represented by the two
figures on the left for a 32-bit
hardware co-processor
on the right for 128-bit hardware
coprocessor
the x-axis is the value of nb so the
number of inputs that we can tolerate
the y-axis is the median key rank which
is the security level
and the colors are for the different
levels of averaging
and what we see is that
for the 32-bit hardware co-processor we
really have to stick with nb equals to
one
if we want to
maintain a 100 bit security level
by contrast for the 128-bit hardware
coprocessor we can tolerate a slightly
larger nb of maybe 4.
what's interesting is that we get
slightly different results than the ones
of the retrofitting paper which
suggested
slightly larger nv values and the
take-home message here is that
sps security is quite difficult to
evaluate because it mostly depends on
the site in and attack signal
and this is for example different from
masking where
the security will depend on the
signal-to-noise ratio which is easier to
evaluate
in particular the signal can be very
sensitive to set of
variations and profiling methods so the
main take-home message is that we should
take security margins when we want to
use this type of constructions
i will now give the floor to thomas who
we'll explain how we can fix the
integrity flow in the retrofitting paper
with a new mode of operation called
lrbc2
as a bonus he will show how we can do
that by using only aes co-processors and
this is interesting because aesco
processors are still by far
the most popular in the embedded
security industry
and it will be in two parts first he
will briefly describe how we can do the
message processing with block ciphers
and then he will describe the tag
generation function
thank you francois xavier
it is now my pleasure to present you a
new one pass mode
so in the design you can see the three
steps
so on the left-hand side you have the
key derivation function which generates
two n-bit state
and on the right-hand side you have the
tag generation function and we will see
in the next slides how we compute t
but for now let's concentrate on the
middle the message processing part
the picture is actually
an encryption of a message that can be
split into two message blocks m1 and m2
and at each iteration at each processing
of a message block
we have of course to turn the message
block into a ciphertext block
and to refresh the state
so from k1 and l1 we first get k2 and l2
after the first iteration
and the next state must be vue
as a hash function of the previous
ciphertext block
so that means that at the end we will
have a final state k3l3 which is the
hash value of
the ciphertext
now let's take a closer look at each
iteration
as you can see we make four calls to the
block cipher that means that in practice
we will have four computation of the aes
in order to process 128 bit of message
this is actually pretty efficient
remember we need to have a hash value at
the end that means that at each
iteration
we can rely on a compression function
and due to a result from bart mining we
know that in order to have high security
when only using block cipher
call to a block cipher
we need at least three block cipher
calls in order to have high security
so this is our starting point
you can see in the first iteration all
the block cipher in black come from
mening's compression function
we simply had to choice among all the
possible invertible linear maps
those who are fully compatible with the
confidentiality of the mode
and in red we add one more block cipher
call in order to create a random n-bit
value in order to store it with the
message block
perfect so we repeat this
until we have processed all the message
blocks and we get the final state at the
end before going into the tag generation
function
perfect let us see now how we compute
the tag t
and also how we can verify the validity
of the ciphertext so the validity of the
tag t
to see how we compute our tag t let us
take a look at the existing solutions
so in the picture now a b represent the
final state
if we want to mimic the solution of the
fac paper in two years ago
we will first replace their mask block
cipher with our prf
the one that was analyzed in the
previous slide by francoxi
so if we do that
we have an x value and this x value
is next used as a key of the next call
of the block cipher
in encryption this results in a tag
value t
but in verification so in a decryption
carry
the verification is not directly made on
the t value otherwise you have a simple
dpa on that value
so you have to invert that value and the
check is made on the a value
however since we cannot rely on masking
as in the fac paper
the x value can be revealed can be
leaked by a dpa
indeed the adversary can simply make
distinct decryption carries with many
distinct t
and x
x will be leaked
so we cannot rely on that solution
let's take a look
and at another solution so the
comparison cannot be made on t so if we
invert it doesn't work so let's take a
look at what happens if we make one more
call
to the block cipher in the forward
direction
then
we will have a solution
a la isap
so that means that
the check is not made on t but is made
on the z value and 0 is a constant it
can be any other constant of course
and actually this solution works
except that the integrity
only hold up to the birthday bound
and the reason is as follows
imagine that the adversary make many
encryption carries
from that queries you will get
ciphertext with a valid t of course and
with that t can simply compute itself
the z value
okay so we have
many good z value and t value for
encryption
now the adversary also makes decryption
carries many many
and
you will get by dpa all the z value of
that cipher text
these ciphertexts for the moment are not
valid
but by comparing the z value
of the decryption carries in the
encryption carries
with a good chance
the we will have a collision on the t
value that means that the collision will
not occur on the z value but before on
the t value and that means
that
the adversary will be able somehow to
guess a good t
for
ciphertext that was used only in
decryption carry so you will win the
integrity game
so we will have to look for another
solution
and the trouble actually with this
so the one in the forward direction
is because
the z value only depends on
an n bit value so let's try to see what
happens if we manage to compute z from 2
and bit value
here is what we get now the z value
depends on both
the value t and the value y in blue
which is only computed during decryption
in order to verify the validity of the
tag
and the ciphertext
okay so to compute y in blue we reuse
the fmr key x once
and in the key input of the block cipher
call we simply add a constant
we show in the security proof that as
long as the adversary is not able to
mount a dpa on t or an x
then we have the high security that we
targeted
somehow t and y
is a state
which is collision resistant
okay so the value y is something that
the adversary can get by dpa in
decryption
during the verification and the z value
as well
but we will show that it's not possible
it's not
feasible for the adversary to
get to mount a dp on t and x
to see that we have to go back on the
final
state after the the computation
of the message block
and a and b
is something which is actually not
random
we do not have a to n bit random final
state
so both values a and b are actually the
output of a smaller compression function
so that means that
we can hope not to have too many
collision on that value and this is
something that we exploit in the proof
we rely on a usual technique where we
define alpha as a multi-collision
parameter that means that for all the
smaller compression function we tolerate
to have alpha multi-collision that means
that a single value that is repeated
alpha times
but if we have one more collision then
we abort in the game
and of course the probability
to abort increase very very much with
alpha
okay
so
we can
think that the adversary will get alpha
possibilities in order to target x and
so that means that the
the block cipher to compute t you will
have the same value x alpha times
with distinct value of a
actually the adversary has more than
that that is because we do not simply
have a collision on b but we might have
a collision before so
we the adversary is able to use
previous collision in order to increase
the amount of repetition of b
with distinct a values
okay
fortunately it is not possible for the
adversary to have alpha cube for
instance so this is we only have to
consider what happened just before the
last block cipher call that computes a
and b
so with with alpha square repetition of
b we will of course have alpha square
repetition of x
and now the adversary will try to mount
something which is not really a dpa so a
no is fixed we simply have two alpha
square
computation with x since the value x is
used twice
during in in the
computation of the tag
okay
so from a critical standpoint we can
have high security really high security
but of course the more alpha
increase the more we have to hope that
the aes in practice
uh will
be safe against the sba
so in practice if we want to have
112 bit of integrity that means that we
need an implementation of the is where
we have an spss security
that with with a nb equal 7 and we
saw before in the slide that is
something that we do not have
is the implementation
so we just have to look for a situation
where the adversary does not have alpha
square repetition but only alpha if we
have alpha everything will be
better
and to get that we simply have to add a
simple tweaks in the design and we had
one more block cipher call here before
going into the
the long prf
and by doing this we
managed to
have repetition on the w value only
alpha time
and of course with this we have all what
we want and for the targeted bit
security
we only need the sps security of the
implementation for nb equal 4 and this
is something that we see that we can
hope to have
so that means that with one additional
block cipher at the beginning before
going into the the long prf
have a solution that we can implement
today
of course from the start it would have
been
possible to use a second time a big prf
in order to have the high security
but of course here we see that in the
tag generation function we simply use
the long prf and in decryption four
additional calls to the block cipher and
of course this
four calls is much less than one more
call to the prf
that's all i wanted to say about all
mode now i'll let franco xavier
ending the talk
before to conclude let me say a few
words about the performance evaluation
of our schemes
the two figures at the top of the slide
represent the performances of lrbc
instantiated with the aes
lras2 is exactly the proposal that
donald just described
lar aes3 is a two-pass variant that
provides stronger confidentiality with
leakage
and then we implemented the retrofitting
proposal with and without chato56
coprocessor
we can see that for short messages on
the left of the figures lrbc is always
better than the retrofitting proposal
and this is mostly because we have a
more efficient tag generation function
on the right of the figures we see that
for long messages lrbc is better if only
aesco processors are available
and the retrofitting proposal becomes
better once you have a share 256
available as well
and as expected of course the 128-bit
co-processor that is on the right
provides better performance than the
32-bit one that is on the
left this leads me to the conclusions of
the paper
first our results recall that securing
low end embedded microcontrollers at the
software level is challenging and likely
to be very
expensive in this respect the lrbc mode
of operation aims to offer good of the
shelf security whenever aesco processors
are available
more precisely lrbc2 provides optimal
integrity with leakage
and confidentiality with leakage in
encryption only
lrbc3 that we described in the paper
additionally provides confidentiality
with leakage in two passes and we hope
that this gives ready to deploy
solutions for the iot
finally we know that spss security is
highly non-trivial to evaluate and to
ensure
and therefore it leads to the open
question how to obtain sps security in
software for example using the shuffling
countermeasure
thank you for your attention