hi everyone i'm rachael from delicious
paris
in this video i'm going to present our
work on how to quantify information
literature
including code-based masking this is a
joint work with shivanki
claude garcia susan menachem and
janukatanji
in this talk
we first gave an introduction of
code-based masking then present our
protein theoretical liquid
quantification
we
apply it to the phenomena masking which
is based on charmian's secret sharing
and show how the redundancy in masking
can only increase the side channel
leakages
in fashion analysis a sensitive variable
x is a 18 in certain forms
then the leakage can be viewed as a
combination of some functional x
and
alloys and
a commonly used city is assuming
environment
noises the additive white equation noise
so to protect a
cryptographic implementation
one of the most way
established contributor is the masking
in particular the masking provides
probable security and it is in
the algorithm like a big level
its cost
increasing critically with the security
order
typically in polio masking lettex is a
sensitive variable
y is the masks and zip is a mask's
variable
then given ancients its encoding is as
follows
the first chain is
is constructed by
xor with the secret as the sensitive
variable and
all as the masks
and as the strands are the
random mask only
as we know
the mass as a brilliant masking can be
unionized into the code based masking
from
codeine theoretical perspective
let us say b k pieces of
inform
and that is a equal to x g plus y h
where x
has uh key pieces of information
why has tmasks and design be
encoded into z with ancients
g and h are two general matrices of an
inequality and d respectively
so we note that the only condition in
code-based in generalized code-based
masking
is that cmt has only zero code word in
the intersection
in addition if n equal to k plus t
there is no redundancy like in rpm and
direct sum masking otherwise if n is
greater than
k plus t the masking is a redundant
here we give two examples
the brilliant masking and
the inner product masking
on the left the blue masking is the
simplest encoding without an xor
the g and h are binary matrices with
only ones and zeros
on the right in ipm
the first chain is constructed with in
the product
operation involving rfi
as we show fi i in the first column of h
comparing with the plain masking only
one column is changed
and we can recover the brilliant one by
setting off i
equal to one
so the blade masking is the special case
of
ipm
next we present a brief history of code
based masking note that these references
marked in blue are the first proposals
the observation the first
observation is that the little screen
and the phenomena masking will propose
the in 2011
and the original ibm was 2012.
at last the most general case was
proposed in chess
in this paper we'll focus on this
journal case and show how to quantify
the information literature
the connection between above masking
schemes are showing figure three
we highlight
two groups
first thing on the left we have a ratio
dough
including bone masking in a product
masking and leakage screen and also
direct sun mating
they all have no redundancy
on the right so we have a
column in a masking which is based on
shamyang's secret sharing
it has it can be configured with
redundancy in a glitch free context
context
therefore two natural questions that
series
how to measure information leakage in
different scheme
and the secondary
how to choose the optimal parentheses or
optimal code for each scheme
before we move into details i will
recall some definitions and the
transformation
the first one is the two distance
as the dual code delos as cpap
gave an inequality it's a dual code is
that each code of each codeword array
is also going to all cut code words in d
next uh some substandard representation
and code expansion by which we can
extend an inner code from a bigger
finite five to a sub three and f2
next
as the
awareness notion is called with a
numerator
which denotes an inner code to
with the phenomena
for an inequality of parent term
kt
it's a written numerator is as follows
the coefficient of bi is the number of
code words of handwritten i
in particular bd is called the casing
number of b
for instance
for the linear code 844 we have a b0
equal to one
b4 equal to 14 and the p8 is a
one in addition we can define the
adjuster casing number of two linear
code c and d
so b prime d is the number of code words
such that there's a code or die
in
quantity but not in policy
next i will show how to measure the
necklace in code base masking
in this work we consider two preview
models
in the bit probably model each program
only gets
one bit of information
while in
waterproofing model each propagate
elevates the information
the corresponding security order are tb
and tw respectively
so in side channel analysis the leakage
function turns a bit vector into
a real value
which are denoted as a procedural
linear function p
then the numerical degree is defined as
the maximum number of coordinates of
beta
which is the coefficient
of z power i
in liquid function p
some some some examples are as follows
for msb and the lsb in differential
power analysis
which is
current
commonly known as the dom
z power i is
is always the only one called the knight
of one
in the midway selected model each bit
appears only once and they return to
their
their sum
in both cases the degree
equals one
and the last example has the second
order liquidus
with a product of
first two bits
it has a
it has a numerical degree equal to two
then by using liquid function p we can
define the
saturn linkage as
electrical to pj plus and with gaussian
noise
the then the problem is the how to
explode the leakage
in side channel analysis the distinguish
is to check whether the leakages and the
different value of x are different
correspond to whether the variance is
zero or not
therefore we can define the sr as the
ratio between the variance of
information and the range of noise as in
combination
taking hemi weight leakage into
consideration we have pj equal to
hemorrhage of j with power d for high
order moment
then it can be decomposed as follows
as in
equation 6.
the first part are the terms with the
numerical degree smaller than p y in the
second part
with degree exactly equal to d
therefore we have the following theorem
for asana
in code-based masking so inter it
involves the two distance t and the
adjacency number b prime d which depends
on both
uh called the cmd so it consists it is
consistent with
the security order improving model
next from an information theoretic
perspective
the mutual information between the
literature and the sensitive variable x
is computed by two entropies
the total entropy hl and the conditional
entropy h elective x are given as
follows
so
then we have the following theorem for
visualization
in code-based masking so as in equation
8 we have a
mutual mission between l and x equals 0
when the degree of p is smaller than
zero
which is a consistent with probably
model
a proven security order and if the
degree
of p equals the two distance
the mutual motion is linked to the two
distance and
adjust the casing number
as in asana
visually we industry say the impact of
two distance and
adjusted the casing number as in figure
four
in particular the slope of the course in
log log
representation
is equal to slope
and
uh
and the vertical offset is linked to the
b prime b
an example
of 4 bit cases of tuition
rpm is shown in figure 5
the slope and the vertical offset are as
expected
therefore we propose a unified
evaluation framework for gcm
in which
the side channel security can be
characterized by the two distance and
the adjusticacy number in addition
the optimal code can be given by
maximizing
the duration d and minimizing the
adjust the question number
b prime d
we next
apply our approach to access-based
phenomena masking
as pointed out in chest 2018 the
phenomena masking is
connected to
the reducing code
the
the ice code is defined by choosing a
phenomena with
order equal smaller than t and evaluate
its m public point
then
we can
then we can show
the connection exceed explicitly the
generation matrices of gnh as follows
in particular each share corresponds to
an evaluation unites the reduction code
next considering
an instance with the solutions and the t
code 21
which is the first order secure masking
tnh as follows for the sake of
simplicity and also because of
the equal equivalence of body in the
code we can set fi alpha one equal to
one
and
the other two parameters are alpha two
and f three i equal to alpha power g and
i have power t
respectively the sharing is that the
equation ten where we only have one
random mask want
so by applying sim2 for mutual mission
we can evaluate different code in ss
based masking clearly the black curve
the best
code
under the approximation in symmetry are
more accurate when the noise increases
next we give an exhaustive study list in
table one
different code can have various
two distance and
they're just the case number
as shown in the last column
we give
the best cases of code
for
31 as a space masking and the comparing
of comparing with the state of that
we show a systematic approach to find
the best code
innovation will show that some
parameters are
the worst
the worst cases
and are not too recommended for
practical use
in particular for the first time we
illustrated the
impact of
both
called the cnt
in its exceptional resistance of gcm
i didn't also evaluate the impact of
redundancy in coding in code-based
masking
again we record the sharing in 3-1
essays based masking
we have a one-chain for redundancy
we will compare the information carrying
in the in the section and in two out of
situations by using mutual mission
the results are shown in figure seven
on the left
we have
we show that
three combinations of tuitions have the
same
same two distance and down the right so
we
give one instance of company combination
that has small smaller decisions
two observations can be made
firstly solutions always carries
carry much information than tuition and
secondary
the security is determined by
the weak
which is combination of
two chains and in general cases it's
determined by
t out of n chancing
access-based
phenomena masking
assuming
a similar result is showing you guys for
different chords and
different combinations
finally we conclude our talk
so in this paper we perform the coding
theoretical approach to quantify the
side channel resistance of
the code the base masking
we use both asana and mri as
liquidity metrics and the proposal
unified the framework for evaluation
and for choosing optimal code in gsm
so our
our open source are in github available
by using following uniques
we also
highlight
that
we want to show
how to find the best code by
presenting detail on the investigation
on the trace of signal basis
for
code expansion from a big identifier to
specify basically size f2
improve
improves on september 17.
just have chess so welcome to our talk
and
please take check our paper for details
thanks for your attention please contact
me if you have any
questions
you