welcome everybody
here i will present the foundations and
results from our paper keep it
unsupervised horizontal attacks meet
deep learning the paper was published on
chess 2021 my name is guilherme petting
and this research paper was elaborated
together with my colleague bukash and
professors stephan pichek and leila
batsina this is a work from teal delft
and rod about university
we propose an even supervised attack
against public key implementations
as we know horizontal attacks are
applicable to real-world protected ecc
and rsa implementations
however due to practical limitations
horizontal attacks tend to deliver a
high amount of wrong beats resulting in
a low
success rate correcting these wrong bits
is not very trivial mainly because we
cannot know where these wrong bits are
actually located
to solve this problem we propose a deep
learning based framework that
iteratively correct wrong beats from key
candidates obtained from horizontal
attacks when a simple horizontal attack
delivers only 52 percent of correct key
bits from a private key our framework is
able to correct these wrong bits and
deliver 100
of accuracy
first let's start with some background
information from our research
when attacking protected ecc
implementations an attacker can for
instance query ecdsa commands and
execute multiple signature generations
in the target device
the adversary can measure side channel
traces for instance power consumption
from ecdsa executions
a main operation in an ecdsa execution
is the scholar multiplication that uses
the private key
normally a protected scholar
multiplication would implement scalar
blight encounter measure making each
scalar multiplication to be computed
over a randomized key
additional counter measures include
pointer randomization for example scalar
blinding factor are usually 32 or 64-bit
random numbers
let's consider a protected scalar
multiplication besides this color blind
encounter measure vulnerabilities can
still be exploited if double enough is
implemented with its naive algorithm
in this situation we can easily
distinguish the patterns of double and
add operations inside a scalar
multiplication interval
from these patterns an adversary would
be able to recover the private key bits
from single trace by passing all other
protections
the solution is therefore to consider
the regular double-end solutions such as
marie ladder and double adat
always
in this case as we can see in this trace
illustration double and add operations
are still distinguishable from each
other however these two operations are
always executed for every private key
bit making the power consumption profile
protected against sba attacks
as a result a protected scholar
multiplication should implement at least
uniform double and add operations
message or coordinate randomization and
scholar gliding
together this counter measures mitigate
non-profiled attacks and profiling
attacks that are based on multiple side
channel traces an obvious solution is to
attack single traces through horizontal
attacks
in practice a first step to implement a
horizontal attack is to identify trace
intervals that represent the processing
of a single private key bit
then using battery extraction mechanisms
the trace is split into several
sub-traces the amount of subtracts is
equivalent to the amount of private key
or secret scholar bits
exceptions happen when a sub trace
interval represents more than one
scholar bit which happens in windows
color multiplication that also include
precomputations in our work each
subtractor represents a single scalar
bit
main types of horizontal attacks include
horizontal correlation analysis
horizontal collision correlation or
cross correlation attacks whole line
template attacks and cluster attacks
in this work we considered clustering
attacks as this type of horizontal
attack has less practical limitations
to implement a cluster invasive process
against a single scholar multiplication
trace a k-means algorithm for example is
applied to each sample column from the
sub-trace interval when an adversary can
identify points of interest inside the
sub-trace interval it is possible to
obtain a key candidate from each
clustered point of interest
at the end the adversary would combine
all key candidates into a final key
candidate this can be done through
different statistical methods in our
paper we follow the most simple approach
by selecting 20 points of interest then
we apply k-means to these points of
interest and at the end we combine the
key candidates with the majority rule
these types of attacks encounter several
limitations usually tracy splitting into
subtracer requires the knowledge of the
implemented scholar multiplication
algorithm it is expected that an
anniversary would consider target
documentation which is good which could
be available in the internet or even
reverse engineering
also to correct the wrong beats from a
recovered key is not an easy task in
principle as the attack is fully
unsupervised the locations of the wrong
beats are unknown to the adversary and
the brute force alternative becomes
infeasible
as i mentioned before in this
presentation this work proposed a
solution to correct error or wrong bits
recovered from the previous attack
method such as unsupervised clustering
attacks
let me first start explaining the
principle behind our proposed dp
learning approach
recent research papers demonstrated that
deep neural networks can actually be
robust against noisy labels from
training sets
in our case noisy labels would be wrong
bits from the recovered scalar bit
for the two classes classification
problem if the amount of wrong bits is
lower than 50 percent a regularized
neural network should still be able to
learn the main classes from the training
set
as a consequence predicting a separate
validation set that should also contain
noisy labels could result in a correct
prediction the network in this case is
not getting confused by the noisy labels
and still making correct labels
association
now how you explain the execution flow
of our proposed iterative framework from
a set of sub-traces we first divide the
set into two separate subsets that are
initially labeled from an unsupervised
clustering attack
next we train a neural network with each
of the subsets the third step
corresponds to the relabeling of these
two subsets in this case we swap the
subsets and predict the neural network
that was trained with one subset with
another subset
the output prediction should now contain
a lower error rate in comparison to
initial labels as a last step the two
subsets are combined and shuffled after
the process starts all over again
in our experiment we always run the
framework for 50 iterations
in a first moment the framework is
executed with neural networks having
fixed hyper parameters across multiple
framework iterations
to deal with noisy labels we considered
in compare the different types of
regularization methods for comparison we
start by running the framework without
any explicit regularization
then we consider dropout dropout plus
data augmentation and data augmentation
only date documentation is based on the
random shifts applied to the subtraces
in a second moment we randomize the
hyper parameters and define a different
neural network at each framework
iteration in this case we also combined
random hyper parameters with
regularization methods
the motivation for random hyper
parameters is simple training the same
neural network multiple times with
similar labels will overfit the model
very soon during the training process
therefore different neural networks will
reduce this overfitting
for this work we consider two data sets
that are software implementations of ecc
on arm cortex m the implementation is
based on curve 25 519 and uses
montgomery ladder for this color
multiplication
as an extra protection the montgomery
ladder implements conditional swap for
constant time operations in the first
data set the c-swap is based on
arithmetic means and the second data set
uses pointer and swapping for the rest
of this presentation i will refer to
these data sets as c swap are it and c
swap pointer
in total we measure 300 power traces for
each of the implementations as each
scalar multiplication contains 255
operations with a random scalar we will
have a total of 300 times 255 that is
equal to 76 and 500 subtrees
for each color multiplication
measurements this color is randomized
this is an illustration of how we
pre-process the data sets in order to
split the full scalar multiplication
trace into a set of sub-traces
the first step is to identify each of
the ladder steps and cut the full trace
accordingly in our case for each
sub-trace we select the interval
corresponding to address and control
executions mainly because we explore the
leakage present after field or ecc
operations for from each ladder step
the c-swap are arith's data set will
contain 8 000 samples for each sub-trace
and the c-swap pointer data set contains
1 000 sample per sub-trace
we also performed a leakage assessment
on the data sets in order to understand
the leakage present in our measurements
for that we use a t-test and signal to
noise radio
using the true labels and
signal-to-noise radio we can clearly
identify the leakage locations inside
the sub-trace intervals for both data
sets
when we consider the labels obtained
from the unsupervised clustering attack
which has an accuracy of 52 percent we
can see that detected leakage is not
very significant anymore
however the main snr and t test peaks
are still located around the same
regions indicating that this 52 will be
enough as a label initialization
let's see the results that we obtain it
by applying the proposed deep learning
framework
in terms of training configurations for
each neural network we consider 10
epochs as the overfitting happens very
soon as a consequence of the framework
iterations the batch size is set to 64.
250 scalar multiplications are
considered for training which are
divided into two groups each group will
then contain 31
875 sub traces
a separate set of 50 scholar
multiplications making a total of 12 750
subtraces are used as test set in order
to verify the accuracy at the end of
each epoch
now i will shortly describe the neural
networks that we use for the case of
fixed hyper parameters
for both data sets we consider similar
convolutional neural networks where the
main difference is the carrier size and
stride in convolutional layers the
network contains a first average
building layer to reduce the
dimensionality of traces followed by a
batch normalization layer and three
convolution layers for the
classification we consider two density
layers with 100 euros each a soft max
displace it at as the output layer
when dropout is considered as a
regularization method we place two
dropout layers in between the dense
layers
the dropout rate is set to 0.5
first i will present framework results
for the case of fixed hyper parameters
as we can see without regularization we
cannot achieve a successful attack for
both data sets after 50 iterations
the y-axis indicates the maximum key
recovery rate or accuracy for a single
scalar multiplication trace
when data augmentation is considered we
can obtain better results for c swap
arith data set the improvement was not
very significant however for the c swap
pointer data set the addition of data
augmentation was enough to make the
attack successful
a significant improvement for syswob
arith dataset is observed when dropout
is considered as a regularization method
in this case we are able to reach a
final and maximum single trace accuracy
of 93 percent
for the other data set dropout also
provided 100 percent of accuracy
now the combination of dropout and data
augmentation delivers the best results
so far for the c swap arith data set we
reach a successful attack that was not
possible before with only dropout or
only data augmentation for cs5 pointer
data set the combination of both
regularization allows us to achieve 100
after only three framework iterations
to define random neural networks we vary
the number of filters kernel size and
strides in convolution layers the number
of density layers and the number of
neurons in density layers we also vary
the activation function that is equal
for all hidden layers
now let's move to the results with
random either parameters without any
regularization we already obtained very
high final single trace accuracy for
both data sets
adding data augmentation is enough to
achieve 100 percent of single trace
accuracy for both data sets
in this case dropout regularization
combination with random hyper parameters
also deliver good results a higher
improvement can be seen for c swap
pointer dataset
finally the combination of dropout and
data augmentation again delivers to
sexual results in this case the
combination of two regularization
methods did not improve results in
comparison to dropout only
here i want to show a final comparison
between the framework executions for
fixed and random hyper parameters
clearly random hyper parameters
increases the chance to succeed
for each regularization scenario we run
10 framework executions
for fixed hyper parameters only one case
return 100 of key recovery for the
random case we achieve 100 percent of
key recovery for 12 out of 40 executions
note also how the case without
regularization provides better results
when random hybrid parameters are
considered in this case we obtain a
final single trace accuracy of 86
percent and for fixed hyper parameters
we were able to reach only 76 percent
for the c-swap pointer data set the
overall results show some differences
between fixed and random hyper
parameters indeed fixed hyper-parameter
delivered better results
in total we were able to succeed in 25
percent of cases for fixed hyper
parameters when random parameters are
considered during framework executions
we recover the full key in 17 out of 40
cases
we also investigated the possibility of
improving the results by trimming the
attacked trace interval we we do that by
obtaining input gradient visualization
which indicate what what samples are
more important for the neural network
decisions it is important to mention
that calculation of input gradients is
totally independent of labels
as you can see the larger input
gradients coincide with many
signal-to-noise radio peaks obtained
with two labels indicating that our
trimmed interval based on gradients is
aligned with the leakage location
these are the best results obtaining
with fixed ip parameters for both data
sets after using gradient visualization
for c swap arit
a data set all regularization cases
provided successful results for c swap
pointer data set dropout only case did
not provided hundred percent of accuracy
after 50 iteration
gradient visualization usage also
affects the results for random hybrid
parameters for c swap arith data set all
scenarios including no regularization
succeed for cs4 pointer data set we can
see a very early convergence with the
regularization cases
here we can see how selecting a trimmed
interval improves the results for c swap
arid data set in the particular case of
fixed hyper parameters we were able to
succeed only one time before after
gradient visualization we obtain 19 out
of 40 successful attacks a significant
improvement is also verified for the
random case
on the other hand for cs5 pointer
dataset trimming the attack interval
does not improve the results this is
mainly because the attacked interval for
1000 samples was already short enough
as conclusions we demonstrated that db
learning approaches can improve attack
success rate due to its capacity of
dealing with noise or wrong labels
for that we proposed an iterative
framework with regularized models that
can achieve successful attack results
the framework should be applicable to
other targets including rsa
implementations
as a future work we would like to
investigate how the framework behaves in
the presence of trace misalignment and
other label initialization methods
thank you very much for watching this
presentation
you