hello i want to present low latency
keychaik at any arbitrary order which is
joint work with iron rezaisha mirzadi
hadi suleimani razia salary fired and
ami moradi
before getting into details i would like
to give an outlook of what low latency
check at any arbitrary order is
in fact this is a realization of
keycheck that is immune to side channel
analysis and has three main
qualities it is low latency meaning that
it has only one registered stage per
round it is compact meaning that
compared to the state of the art it
attains low area consumption and it is a
stretch for widely extendable to higher
order securities by the means of an
algorithm that we have provided for it
first we will have an introduction
including a brief review of masking
schemes and mass implementations of
keychain then repair to the audio low
latency
implementation of ketchup which is the
first order on raw threshold
implementation and finally we go through
the generic single register program
realization followed by its evaluation
results
masking schemes are probably secure
counter measures and case power analysis
they are based on multi-party
computation and secret sharing two of
the most famous hardware masking schemes
are threshold implementation and domain
oriented masking
the threshold implementation scheme was
firstly introduced for first order
security and then it was extended to
higher orders however later it was shown
that the proposed extension only
provides univariate security and fails
to provide multivariate security due to
the lack of fresh random bits however
the key property of this order threshold
implementation is this order
non-completeness which necessitates td
plus 1 as the minimum number of input
shares where t is the algebraic degree
of the shared function
here we have an example which is first
order implement threshold implementation
of an and gate according to the above
formula for the minimum boundary of the
input shares each input has been split
into three shares
the main challenge of threshold
implementation is achieving uniformity
of a shared function a simple example
would be the direct sharing of dimension
and gate which successfully attains
non-completeness property but fails to
achieve uniform output bits
domain oriented masking is the other
well-known hardware masking scheme which
is configurable to any arbitrary order
according to dummy scheme input shares
are divided into independent sets called
domains and this independence is
maintained throughout the whole design
it includes a refreshing layer that adds
fresh random bits to intermediate
variables before compressing them to
reduce the number of output shares the
application of refreshing layer followed
by compression layer necessities hiring
of a register layer at the middle to
avoid glitch propagation
and this refreshing layer
as well as the independent property
leads into g plus one as the minimum
number of input shares rather than td
plus one
an example would be the first order
domain
oriented masking implementation
of and gate in which all aipj
multiplication terms are called
component functions this is important
since later in our design we will refer
to component functions frequently
the other topic that would like to go
over is a brief history of the mass
implementations of kichat that are
proposed up to the present time
majority of these percentage these
implementations are first order ones the
first mass implementation of keychain
was introduced by its designers it was a
three-shared threshold implementation
however later it was discovered that it
suffers from non-uniform output shares
the second third and fourth proposed
designs aimed to fix this non-uniformity
the second one
employed a plenty of randomness to
achieve the goal the third one increase
the number of input shares to sure and
led into an area increase
the fourth one followed a different
technique
and proposed the so-called
changing of the guard methodology which
constructs uniform non-linear layers
instead of
uniform individual aspects
there is only a disorder tone
implementation of keychain in high order
group
compared to the td plus one scheme this
design is
compact however it requires a notable
number of first random bits per chain
stance let's say for second order
implementation this amount equals to 15
bits per chain stands
we have dedicated
low latency implementations to the third
group
where there is only a two round on rule
threshold implementation
this design successfully achieves
half number of clock cycles while
requiring six input shares at its first
order
this is
theoretically extendable to high orders
however in practice in conference
significant
challenges
let us say what happens when we want to
extend it to higher order
implementations
this is the round
the design of the two round on draw
threshold implementation of ketchup
if the entire design is supposed to have
a security order d according to
designers the first round should have
security order of 2d
this is this duplication is a necessary
rule which ensures
non-completeness however it implies two
dt plus one as the minimum number of
input shares
two implementations are proposed for
first order realization by the designers
one with five input shares and the other
with six input checks the results show
that the second one leads to a more
compact implementation
now suppose for second and third order
securities according to the mentioned
duplication rule
the minimum number of input shares in
each of these cases would be 9 and 13
accordingly
this is not a trivial task at all to
find
efficient and non-complex sharings for
5-bit cheap permutation with 9 and 13
input shares
and this is just in case that we do not
consider uniformity challenge if we
consider uniform implementations the
problem
even gets worse
furthermore even if we suppose that
there are implementations which map 9
and 13 input shares to 9 and 13 output
shares such implementations would pose
significant cost
which is not of interest especially when
considering the real world gadgets
so if we take another look
to the map of existing implemented mass
implementations of keycheck now we can
feel the need for a compact low latency
implementation of keycheck which is
feasibly extendable to higher orders
to
satisfy this need we propose or single
register per run dom implementation of
kichat our designer stays with the
latency of an unprotected implementation
at its
higher at
any arbitrary order
to this end we revise the round function
of the dom implementation of keycheck
we relocate the compression layer in
such a way that the wrong function needs
only one register stage per round in
fact we move the compression layer after
the linear layer theta
which results in d plus one to the power
of two instances of theta rather than
d plus one instances of course we will
take this note into account when
evaluating our design
but more importantly we are interested
in investigating what happens in the
lack of register layer after the
non-linear layer g
and before linear layer theta as its
subsequent operation
here we have a simple outlook of how g
function operates on its 5 input bits it
replaces each bit with the result of its
xor with a multiplication
term
the multiplication term is produced by
the complement of the next bit and its
adjacent bit
the outputs of that are then delivered
the outputs of g are then delivered to
tether and theta also
replaces each beat
with the result of its xor with a parity
bit the parity is made up of 10
different bits where one of these 10
bits is exactly the one previous to the
bit being processed
to keep it simple and easy to follow
april with a prime will be added to b y
b prime to c primes and so on
let's check what happens for first order
implementation where we have two share
input bits and four share output bits
the tether is applied to the output
stuff g function and if you keep an eye
on output share one for example we can
see that exploring a prime and b prime
these two
leakage on
all shares of c input bit the same
leakage exists when we export the second
the third shares of c prime and d prime
and speaking more generally exploring
every two adjacent bits of output shares
one and two results in a dangerous
non-completeness failure
how can we fix this issue that is the
result of register emission at the
middle of g and theta
our further investigations show that
the leakage originates from the fact
that the alignment of the component
function in dumb scheme is in such a way
that
every output share contains more than
one share of each input
you say the same holds for output share
two so our solution
would be introducing a new alignment
that is compatible with the lack of in
between register
the realign component function or
proposed real line component function
for first order is shown here it can be
checked that at most one share of each
input variable shows up in each of the
output shares this is true for output
share 1 and the rest of the outputs
a good question would be what about
extension to higher orders we are glad
to announce that our proposed
realignment is not just a heuristic one
working for first order
in fact the show in excess of input
variables are given to the component
functions according to a transparent
rule which is extendable to any
arbitrary order
once again we refer to the first order
solution to describe the
algorithm the sharing nexus
are given to component functions
according to a table called index
configuration table
this table can be generated for any
arbitrary order according to it to an
algorithm that we have provided in
detail in our paper
the structure of this ad grid is based
on three steps first is to give each
output share only one share of each
input variable
then is to check for correctness of the
masking meaning that the
alignment should assure that
every two adjacent columns cover all
combinations of the share indexes
and finally is to placing linear
monomials
there is a freedom to place them in
output shares with the same show index
of that variable
here is our final design architecture
for low latency dom implementation of
ketchup we've instantiated another
multiplexer identified
as multiplexer 2
which bypasses theta step and allows us
to take the outputs of the last round
directly from the compression layer
which turns the number of output shares
uh
back to d plus 1 instead of 2 plus
instead of d plus 1 to the power of 2
which is produced by g function
there are some further notes that we
would like to discuss about our design
first is about to use refreshing layer
our design follows the same refreshing
rule as the dummy scan presents
according to this rule all aipj
component functions where i is not equal
to j are blinded with fresh random bits
in fact the realignment does not change
the refreshing layer and our design
requires the same number of
fresh randomness as the original dom
skin
however the compression layer differs in
some detail
let's suppose that we have the first
order realization into which the random
bits are applied
according to the
rule of compression in doma scheme
output shares 0 and 1 and output shares
2 and 3 are allowed to be summed up this
instruction works for all output base
except for d prime
that results in a
dangerous and invalid compression
so we have to rearrange the outputs of
shares
the output shares of two prime right
before the compression layer and of
course after the application of the top
and after that we can perform an
ordinary dom compression safely
in order to assess the performance of
our design and to compare it with the
state of the art we have used synopsis
design compiler and focused on the
implementation of one of the small-sized
keycheck permutations with the state
size equal to 200. the results show that
compared to the equivalent original dom
implementation our implementation
achieves around 26 and 31
lesser delay in first and second order
securities respectively
our design has almost constant delay in
its higher orders
compared to the first order low latency
ti implementation of keychain
our design had a
74.5 percent lesser area consumption
where they had while they have almost
equal delays
here we have reflected the detailed
results of implementing our design with
security orders one to five and the
results of the related works
we've also performed some experimental
analysis including the verification of
the security of our constructed mask g
function using silver verification tool
and fpga based evaluation using software
g platform
we have used 100 million traces to
perform
fixed vs random t tests
for first second and third order
implementations
for first order implementation
we observe no leakage at first order t
test however
univariate bivariate and multivariate
second and third order t test
show leakage which is the approval of
the
validation of our setup
for second and third order securities no
detectable leakage is observed
since
to the
since there is a high noise caused by
the high number of fresh random bits
updated at every clock cycle in this
design
in summary about low latency check at
any arbitrary order first note is that
this is a design with implementation
costs that are within the feasibility
bonds from a latency point of view
it has a single register per round
regardless of its security order and
from area point of view
it has a lower area overhead compared to
the state of the art the second note is
that the challenge raised by registered
mission in this design is addressed with
the help of kichaki specifications
and there are some closing points about
the design
first is that our solution
is not only working for theta but also
it works for any linear function that is
applied right after the g function the
second is that our solution is dedicated
to g function and this is not extendable
it's right verbally extendable to any
other function
and last but not least is that we make
no claim that the proposed index
configuration is unique maybe there are
some solutions which
can distribute the sharing access to
component functions and achieve the same
code