hello and welcome to my presentation
about our contribution machine learning
of physical unclonable functions using
hyperdata revealing a pitfall in the
fuzzy commitment scheme
this is joint work of christopher
michelle pill and myself emmanuel
schrider
christoph and michel are affiliated with
the technical university of munich
myself is associated with the fraunhof
institute for applied and integrated
security in gaijin nearby munich
the outline of this talk is as follows
i will give a short recap of the
principles of physical unclonable
functions
afterwards i will explain the fuzzy
commitment scheme which is a core part
of the attack
this is followed by the actual attack
sketch and few results of our work
finally some concluding words and
possible mitigations
let's get started with the recap of
puffs
puffs are security primitives which are
based on manufacturing variations
introduced for example during the doping
process
the manufacturing variations are
different for each device
therefore these variations can be used
to extract device-specific randomness
with simple circuits
there are a broad variety of proposed
puff circuits like arbiter puffs ring
oscillator puffs sram puffs and many to
come because of ongoing research
it is an often disputed topic how to
classify puffs
however the only relevant classification
for our contribution is the difference
between single challenge paths and
multi-challenge puffs
only multi-challenged paths are relevant
for this talk
multi-challenge paths allow the
configuration of the internal building
blocks by applying a challenge
we only consider multi-challenge paths
with a binary output
so for each challenge either 0 or 1 is
returned
another assumption is that the
multi-challenge path can be modeled as a
linear combination of its building
blocks
in our contribution we only consider
ring oscillator sump puffs and armata
puffs
however we think that the attack should
also be possible for all other paths
which were successfully attacked by a
machine learning model
all known multi-challenge paths have
been successfully modeled by machine
learning attacks if the attacker has
unrestricted access to the challenge
response pairs
because puffs use physical device
variations their responses are noisy
one way to mitigate the noise is the
fuzzy commitment scheme which contains
error correction capabilities
there is the idea that if one uses the
fuzzy commitment scheme the puff
responses are not accessible by an
attacker
therefore it seems as if the fuzzy
commitment scheme could be a
countermeasure against machine learning
attacks of multi-challenge puffs
in our contribution we show that this
idea has to be refuted
so let's take a closer look at the fuzzy
commitment scheme
the fuzzy commitment scheme has two
phases
the rollout phase is performed once in a
secure environment
the second phase the reconstruction
phase is performed in field
in the left bottom corner we see the
secret s which is fed through the error
correction
encoder the error correction codes add
redundancy to the secret
the resulting code words c are then
masked by the multi-challenge path
we consider the resulting helper data as
well as the challenged storage as
publicly accessible
to achieve a reasonable trade-off
between code rate and implementation
costs
error correction codes are often split
into an outer and an inner code
in the reconstruction phase the helper
data is unmasked by applying the same
challenges to the multi-challenge path
as in the rollout phase
since we are now in the reconstruction
phase the puff responses are potentially
noisy
therefore the code word contains also
noisy bits
the code words are then corrected by the
error correction code and the secret is
returned
how can we extract machine learning
inputs and labels while having access to
the challenges and the helper data
let's take a closer look at the rollout
phase
to sketch our attack i have exchanged
the ecc encoder which contains multiple
codes with the repetition code
we know that the challenge storage and
the helper data storage are publicly
accessible
so the basic idea is to train a machine
learning model which takes the
challenges and the helper data bits
however that's not possible because the
path masks the code word
but we know one additional thing
we know how the fuzzy commitment scheme
generates the helper data bits
this only depends on the generator
matrix of the used error correction code
we now rewrite this generator matrix
this is the rewritten matrix
representation of the fuzzy commitment
scheme
at the top i have exchanged the generic
generator matrix of the error correction
code with the generator matrix of a
repetition code
in general a repetition code repeats the
input bits a number of times to add
redundancy
for the sake of simplicity in this
example i have used the repetition code
which repeats each bit three times
at the bottom we see the identity matrix
we conclude that each helper data bit is
a combination
of the same secret bit and an individual
path response
since we know the helper data bits we
can xor them
we rewrite this and see
that the secret which is unknown cancels
out
so the responses are in a direct
connection with the challenges
by xoring the helper data bits such that
the secret cancels out we learn a
comparison between two path challenges
for more complex codes the search for
all these xo equations is np-hard
since we want very small xor equations
of same length we can use brute force
let's take a look at a little example
how to derive these xor equations
we have a secret which has in this
example only two bits
one and zero
the secret is fed bitwise into the error
correction code
in this example a repetition code which
repeats every bit three times
each codeword has to be masked by the
path
therefore we need six challenges which
are applied to the multiple challenge
path to receive six response bits
with these responses the two code words
are masked and stored as helper data
please note that the repetition code
returns only two possible code words the
all zero or the all one code word
let's take a look at the first code word
and how this knowledge helps
based on the helper data word and the
knowledge that the repetition code only
returns two code words
we can guess two possible path response
strings for this code word
the puff responses have both the same
transition pattern between the bits
therefore we can formulate xor equations
which account for both possibilities
these labels are independent of the two
possible puff response strings
note
that the training inputs and labels can
only be created within the borders of
the helper data words
the more redundancy the code word has
the more xor equations can be created
the next step is to find an approximator
which in fears by examples a mapping
between challenge pairs
and the result of our xo equations
since in the fuzzy commitment scheme
both challenges are fed into the same
puff instance
we can specify the approximator further
in the presented case of the repetition
code the approximator has to approximate
the same puff instance twice
this construction of an internally
cloned approximator instance can be
modeled by a cmes neural network
a zmes neural network has multiple
copies of the same neural network which
share their trainable weights
all neural networks get one challenge
the label with which the neural network
is trained is the xord helper data bit
with this neural network we were able to
derive a comparison between challenges
instead of speaking that we do not claim
that this approximator is the best or
the only possible one
we trained this network by applying many
challenge pairs
so we have this neural network but yet
not the correct key
to derive the key we have to perform the
attack phase
let's get back to our example
our machine learning model can
approximate the response difference
between two challenges
additionally the approximator does not
depend on any unknown secret anymore
to exploit the machine learning model we
have to fix one challenge as a
hypothesis
in this example i have fixed challenged
zero
however we could use any challenge in
the challenge storage
we then build challenge pairs with all
other challenges
these pairs represent a comparison
between each challenge of the storage
with the fixed challenge
we feed the challenge pairs into our
trained siamese neural network
the noisy response difference string is
either the original or the inverse of
the original response string of the
multi-challenge path
this depends on the challenge we fixed
if the original response of the fixed
challenge was 0 we would receive the
original response string of the path
otherwise the inverse
at this point in our attack we can
exploit the fuzzy commitment scheme
again by using the reconstruction phase
to correct erroneous bits in our noisy
response
since the repetition code in our example
can correct one error per code word
let's assume the noisy response string
looks like this
the false bit is marked in orange
as in the fuzzy commitment scheme we xor
the path response with the helper data
set of speaking that the code word has
the wrong bit too
however after the repetition code the
false bit is corrected and the secret is
derived
that is the end of our attack sketch
as already mentioned for more complex
codes the xor equations are more
difficult to derive
and more xors are involved
let's take a look at some results
here we see results of an attack using
the repetition code and a simulated 128
ring oscillator sump off
on the x-axis of all plots we see the
number of used challenge response pairs
all four plots show different steps in
the attack
the top two plots show the accuracy and
the validation accuracy of our machine
learning model during training
these information would also be
available for an attacker
on the bottom left we see the success
rate after using the trained machine
learning model to decode all challenges
on the bottom right we see the success
rate after having corrected the noisy
response string of our machine learning
model with the fuzzy commitment
scheme when comparing the top right and
the bottom left plot we can clearly see
that the validation accuracy is a good
indicator of the success of our attack
additionally if we compare the bottom
two plots we can see that the fuzzy
commitment scheme itself is reliably
correcting
erroneous bits of the noisy response
string of the machine learning model
with only 800 challenge response pairs
we were able to break this simulated
ring oscillator sump off
we wanted to substantiate the notion
that the redundancy per code word of the
used error correction code has a big
impact on our attack
on the left side we see the growth rate
of the number of xor equations for three
different repetition codes given the
challenge response number
can be seen that the number of derivable
xor equations grows faster for codes
with more redundancy
on the right side we see the mean puff's
success rate of our attack
you can see a clear connection between
the number of derivable xor equations
and the learnability of the machine
learning model
the more exo equations the faster the
learning rate and the better the
generalization of the machine learning
model
another question is the influence of the
choice of the fixed challenge in this
plot we see the median puff success rate
of our attack given the challenge
response number for three different
choices of the fixed challenge
all fixed challenges were evaluated
against the same machine learning model
all three fixed challenges saturate at
around 89 percent
however the slope is different for each
reference challenge
we conclude that there could be
potential to choose a good or a bad
fixed challenge
yet we could not explain this behavior
and consider this task as an unsolved
problem
using publicly accessible ring
oscillator measurements
we built
128 ring oscillator sump puffs
for every of these 1 300 puffs and every
challenge response number we trained 10
machine learning models and evaluated
the attack
we see that also with real ring
oscillator measurements it is possible
to conduct this attack
also with 800 challenge response pairs
it is very likely to find the original
or the inverse of the puff key
we repeated this experiment with the
simulated arbiter puff
the results show more variance but in at
least 1 out of 10 tries we could break
the puff with 800 challenge response
pairs
interestingly due to more variants in
some instances even with 400 challenge
response pairs a high percentage of the
secret bits could be decoded correctly
however
this information is not available for an
attacker
let us summarize
in case of a repetition code with seven
bits only a single key is necessary to
learn a simple ring oscillator sumpuf
and arbiter puff
we have tested our attack with different
and more complex codes however i leave
that for the interested reader of our
paper
we conclude
that the fuzzy commitment scheme or any
fuzzy extractor scheme does not counter
the entropy loss of the underlying path
given that the path is not perfect we
think that the only way to counter such
machine learning attacks is the
limitation of the number of challenge
response pairs
another approach to mitigate this attack
could be the usage of more complex and
monolithic error correction codes
these codes lead to more xors in the xor
equations
and therefore more non-linearity which
is harder to learn for a machine
learning model
[Music]
i thank for your attention and interest
in this topic