bonjour i'm gabrielle i'm a phd student
from the revolution laboratory in the
teres itself and today i will propose
you a new loss function that maximizes
the success rate of a neural network
trained to perform sidechain attacks
this work is a joint work with lady
auburn america from the revoking
laboratory and alexandre nelly and
francoise sons from many specimen
conductors but first what's the point
with psychiatric attacks
so to understand this concept let's take
a look at an example
so let's assume that an adversary has
access to a physical device in which a
cryptographic algorithm like for example
ies is implemented and such that she can
configure the secret key and the plain
text to perform an encryption such that
obviously the goal of the advertory is
to recover the sensitive information
manipulated during its operation
so to perform a sidechaining attack she
needs one probe here an om probe and one
oscilloscope at least such that
during the encryption she can capture a
physical trust that directly depends on
the sensitive information manipulated by
the cryptographic module
and because she can perform as many
encryption she wants the other authority
can generate them plenty of physical
trust and thus find some equalities
related to the secret she wants to
retrieve
in the deep learning based side
challenge attacks the adversary
generates a nerve network to
automatically match a physical trap with
the correct target sensitive value such
that this attack can be decomposed into
two parts a profiling phase and an
attack phase
so first in the profiling phase the
adversary trains a neural network to
predict the correct sensitive
information she knows based on the
physical traces generated in the
previous slide
so when this phase is performed the
adversary can predict the intermediate
variable on a target device containing a
secret she wants to retrieve so during
the attack phase by using a new set of
physical trusses she can compute the
probability of observing each key
protesis but unfortunately one physical
truss is not enough to retrieve the
correct targeted value
hence the adversary has to predict the
score related
to each key partici multiple times
to finally aggregate all the predictions
and recover the secret key value
so one way to evaluate the efficiency of
a neural network is to assess the
benefits of the applied loss function to
optimize the attack performance
but
what is the classical learning metric
used in deep learning-based side-channel
attacks
so the most widely used loss function is
called cross-entropy and its function is
reminded here
so that to get a clear overview of its
impact during the training process let's
back to our previous example
so here the adversary generates a set of
physical trusses such that she knows the
target its value manipulated by the
device under test
so during the profiling phase the neural
network output a set of score related to
each hypothetical value such that the i
test its core the item the probability
of observing the related value but
however to fit with the maximum
likelihood distinguisher the scores has
to be converted to a probability
distribution
thus an additional function called
softmax function is applied in order to
convert the scores to a normalized
probability distribution
so through the minimization of the
cross-entropy loss function the
adversary asks the neural network to
maximize the probability of observing
the correct output with respect to each
hypothetical values
thus minimizing the ranking loss
functions seems treated to conduct
sidechain attacks but concretely
how should the loss function be
minimized so to perform such
minimization the adversary employs some
optimization algorithm based on the
gradient descent principle
this technique consists in iteratively
updating the trainable parameters theta
of the neural network based on the
gradient of the loss function
so concretely given a neural network
with two parameters theta 0 and theta 1
we can plot the evolution of the cross
entropy as function depending on the
value of both stringable parameters so
through this plot we can see that
depending on the initialization of zero
and theta one the optimization algorithm
can reach
local minimum
or in the best case scenario it can
reach a global minimum
so to obtain the most efficient
parametric model f theta the adversary
expect the gradient descent algorithm to
converse throughout the global minimum
but unfortunately this solution cannot
beat ensure and in this talk the
resulting error is called optimization
error
more formally it characterizes all the
errors induced by the learning process
from the selection of definite model
space to the error induced by the
optimization algorithm
so to obtain the most efficient model
the goal of the adversary is to find the
solution that maximizes the success rate
metric for a minimum number of attack
traces thus the gradient descent
algorithm should update the trainable
parameter theta in order to penalize the
errors provided on the success rate so
let's see if the penalization term
induced by the cross entropy less
function perfectly fits with this
maximization problem
so here two scenarios can be observed
first if the derivative is completed
with respect to the targeted class then
the penalization term should reflect the
impact of each irrelevant score on the
correct output and this is exactly what
the cross-entropy does at it penalize
the related output with respect to the
probability r then if the derivative is
computed with respect to the untargeted
class the penalization should be only
dependent on the score's distance
between j and k stars such that indeed
following the success rate matrix the
adversary aims at maximizing the score
of k-stars with respect to each wrong
hypothetical values but unfortunately as
illustrated in this slide the derivative
considered by the cross-entropy loss
function does not perfectly reflect the
relative order of the untargeted class
with respect to the targeted one
indeed the cross entropy combined with
the softmax function carries more about
the absolute value of a class with
respect to each other which can induce
blurred results regarding the
optimization of the success rate and
because the wrong penalization of the
class j impacts the probability of the
targeted output we suggest that the
cross entropy does not totally reflect
the probability distribution the
adversary wants to optimize during the
training process in the following this
error they are induced by the
probability distribution is called
approximation errors and it highlights
the deviation of the predicted
distribution from the real unknown one
but however the cross entropy loss
function states beneficial as majority
suggests at just 2020. indeed material
demonstrates the benefits of the
cross-entropy loss function as it
maximizes the perceived information
introduced by ronno and al at error clip
2011. so more concretely three sources
of errors can be alighted
so first the optimization error already
defined characterizes the error induced
by the learning process as well as the
selection of a finite model space in
order to obtain the optimal parametric
model
then
how the adversary maximizes an
estimation of the perfect information
instead of the true personal information
she needs an infinite number of traffic
in order to converge throughout this
solution and add in practice she can
only deal with infinite number of traces
the estimation error characterize the
gap between the empirical and the true
pro-third information and finally the
approximation error defines the
deviation between the birth of
information estimated with the
cross-entropy function and the mutual
information this error is negligible if
and only if the probability distribution
associated with the optimal model
minimizing the cross-entropy function is
similar to the true unknown probability
distribution so in our work we propose a
new loss function which derived from the
success rate metric and prevent the
approximational effect
so when an adversary performs a
sidechain attack she aims at optimizing
the success rate matrix for a given
number of trusses such that this metric
is defined as follows
so in other words the adversary wants to
optimize this probability such that the
score related to the secret key is
always higher than any other key
potential so what the advertory wants in
this scenario is to approximate the
indicator function to make it easy to
understand and following the work
provided by king lew and lee we know
that a natural fashion consists in
taking the sigmoid function in order to
approximate the indicator function such
that on the right side on this slide we
can see that depending on the value of
alpha we can monitor the approximation
of the indicator function so to optimize
the turnable parameters that maximize
the success rate the adversary has to
apply the binary crash entropy in order
to penalize the deviation of the model
probabilities from the desired
predictions
so in other words we want to penalize
the loss function when this expected
relation is not observed
thus when the binary cross entropy is
applied the adversary obtains the
following partial ranking loss function
so this result gives us an insight into
how the cut function penalized the
training process
when this relation is not respected for
therefore maximizing the success rate
tends to minimize the ranking error
between the secret key k stars and any
key potential k
but in order to efficiently find the
model that maximizes the ranking r we
have to apply this partial cost function
on each key protesis in order to
maximize the rank of the secret key
one interesting property with the
ranking function that we demonstrate in
our paper is that this new loss function
can be considered as an upper bound of
the attack success rate thus minimizing
the ranking loss directly optimize the
performance metric the adversary wants
to maximize
but however what are the benefits of
considering the ranking loss instead of
the cross-entropy loss function so first
let's back to the penalization process
so as a reminder the adversary's goal is
to find a model that maximize the attack
success rate such that during the
profiling phase the turnable parameters
are updated in order to maximize this
performance metric so if the derivative
is computed over k stars the ranking
loss pushes the score of the secret key
up via gradient ascent
on the other hand if the derivative is
computed over an irrelevant output the
ranking loss pushes the score of each
key process down via gradient descent so
that dispensation only depends on the
distance between k stars and j so death
in opposition to the cross entropy last
function the score related to each of
the key potentials do not blur the
polarization term indeed for each player
k star k there are two forces at the
play such that the four that each player
exerts is proportionate to the
difference of the scores so def the
penalization process induces by the
ranking loss maximizes the success rate
such that the approximation error
induced by the cross-entropy loss
function is prevented but from an
optimal model perspective what does this
result mean so if we did not the other
rule allowing the extraction of the
targeted sensitive variable from a
parametric model we know that maximizing
the success rate is equivalent to find
an estimation of the optimal model such
that finding the parameters theta that
minimize this term is equivalent to the
optimal distinguisher and this process
describes exactly what the ranking was
done during the training process
so while the ranking loss aims at
finding the parameters theta that
maximizes these functions we can define
a parametric model considering the
ranking loss as a lower bound of the
mutual information such that if the
adversary has an infinite number of
profiling traces and optimal parameter
theta she retrieves the related mutual
information which is highly beneficial
from an attack perspective as it
reflects the minimum number of attack
traces needed to retrieve the frequency
so from an error analysis perspective
we observe that the minimization error
as well as the estimation error still
affect a model train with a ranking loss
but the latter solution is beneficial to
prevent the approximation error so to
verify all these theoretical
observations through different scenarios
we decide to perform it on the most
common database used in deep learning
based section analysis
for the ranking loss what performed on
two public data set and other data sets
are studied in our paper
so first the cheap resper data set is an
unprotected emulation of aes 128
implemented in software on a cheap
whisperer board which is composed by an
8-bit microcontroller
so due to the lack of control r0s the
adversary can recover the secret key
directly and in this experiment we
attack the first xbox operation then the
ascot dataset is the first open database
that has been specified to serve as
common basis for further work in deep
learning based saturn attacks
so the targeted platform is also an
8-bit microcontroller where the first
order masking is implemented with
different level of the synchronization
so to accurately define the performance
of a neural network we introduce
symmetrical ntge that defines the number
of trusses that are needed for reaching
a constant guessing or trophy of one
for being confident in our experiment we
perform 100 attacks and define ntge bar
at our future metric from a practical
perspective the generation of suitable
architectures is known as a difficult
task
hence two kinds of models can be
considered
so first let's take a look at an example
where the parametric model f theta
exploits a partial set of points of
interest on the gps per data set so once
we capture the physical trusses we
design a neural network such that first
we consider the cross-entropy loss
function as learning matrix
what the profiling model was trained
we used some visualization tools in
order to assess the ability of the model
to correctly retrieve the point of
interest
so here we use a weight visualization
introduced by zayden al at just 2020.
once this fade was performed with the
quest entropy loss function we applied
exactly the same process with the
ranking loss in order to compare the
features retrieved by each model with
the snr computation
so our first observation suggests that
both models successfully retrieve the
point of interest located in the first
200 time samples
indeed this result considered with the
peaks returned by the snr computation
but unfortunately if we look more
carefully at the model train with the
crosshand plus function an unexpected
peak appears and this peak is not
detected by the snr computation as well
as the model train with the ranking loss
so while the model train with the quater
entropy loss function considers this
peak as relevant for its making decision
due to approximation error its impact
can be non-negligible during the
expectation phase
indeed on this slide we affect the
ability of each model to retrieve the
secret key when additional gaussian
noise is applied so through this slide
we can notice that the performance gap
between both model inquiries with the
level of the noise thus
if the optimization or inducing each
model is similar considering the ranking
loss is beneficial as it directly
optimizes the expected probability what
the cross-entropy last function doesn't
the second scenario consider in this
talk is the following so if the
adversary constructs models that exploit
all the relevant information in the
leakage classes then she can ask which
function is beneficial to convert faster
towards the best attack performance so
have the models perfectly retrieve the
point of interest it can be assumed that
the approximation error is negligible
thus in such context only the
optimization error and the estimation
error hold so by performing the attack
on the scat data set we plot the
following graph such that you can
visualize the performance evolution of
both model depending on the number of
profiling traces used during the
training process
thus in the y axis you can notice the
ntge bar value previously introduced so
when the ascad data set is considered we
observed that the model train with the
ranking loss always converged faster
toward the best attack performance
solution whatever the desynchronization
level applied thus given a fixed ntg bar
value a model train with a ranking loss
always needs less profiling trusses than
a model train with the quest
entrepreneur's function such that in
this example using the ranking glass is
beneficial to reduce the estimation
error
to conclude about our work we first
linked the learning touring paradigm
with the site channel approach so that
it helps us to develop a new loss
function that maximize the attack
success rate through this new
proposition we are more concerned with
the relative order between the secret
key and each key protege such that it is
beneficial to prevent the impact induced
by the thought max function which we
called the approximation error and
obviously this work is the starting
point of assessing the benefits of the
learning touring approach inside china
attacks and further investigations
should be made on all the learning to
rank approaches as this right approach
for example finally all of our results
can be reproduced through a github
repository and if you have any question
do not hesitate to contact me over email
thank you very much