first session of the third day of chess
2021 the session uh title it's let's get
physical
and the session chess will be alif bilge
carbon and miss japan pizzag there will
be in total one two three four five six
vehicle papers that
we will see some uh first video of those
papers and then there will be time for q
a
uh for questions there are a couple of
options so please you can either use
zulip or you can use a check here to ask
questions and then once we are done with
the presentation video uh the one of the
authors of the paper will answer the
questions
that being said
uh ellie can you introduce this paper
so our first paper uh will be from run
off for institutional isaac and
technical university of munich
the paper is called machine learning of
physical unclonable functions using
calculator building a pitfall in the
fuzzy commitment screen
and the speaker is a manual trader
stage is yours
ah your audio is quite garbled um
it's very bad quality but now it was bit
better but still very bad quality
can you say something again
yes hello are you hearing me better
hello better yeah that's better it's
better yeah
i think i have to talk in the right
direction
so okay
hello and welcome i will give a little
wrap up of our paper machine learning of
physical unclonable functions using
helper data revealing a pitfall in the
fuzzy commitment scheme
[Music]
what's the setting of our proposed
detect
we
attack a multi-challenged path and we
think that the puff shouldn't have full
entropy
the helper data has to be generated by a
fuzzy commitment scheme and the attacker
has to know which linear block code has
been used
an
attacker should have control over the
challenges and the helper data of course
we explain our attack by using the often
used
repetition code the included redundancy
of the linear block code allows the
creation of so-called xo equations
these xor equations are nothing else
than xor helper data bits such that the
secret cancels out
these xor equations can be viewed as a
comparison
of the same path instant with different
challenges
so we see here at the bottom such uh xor
equation
we use these challenges and the results
of the xor equations to train a ziramese
neural network
the specialty about this neural network
is nothing that the
the internal neural networks here in the
middle of the
picture are sharing their weights so
they can be viewed as one instance of
the same neural network and during
training only one one set of weights are
trained
but the specifics are also discussed
very very
thoroughly in the paper if someone has
question with that
so if we have trained this neural
network
we use this network to decode all other
challenges in this in the challenge
storage
the resulting noisy response string
is either the original or the inverse of
the original multi-challenge puff
response string
so after derivation of this noisy string
the fuzzy commitment scheme is again
used to correct errors which have been
made by the machine learning model
it depends
what output the challenge the reference
challenge had in the original path if
whether you get the original or the
inverse of the response string of the
path
so
the
redundancy of the fuzzy commitment
scheme and the internal linear block
code
is used twice in our attack
once during the training to generate
these xor equations
and once during the attack because the
fuzzy commitment scheme again corrects
error of our maybe noisy output of the
machine learning model
so here we see one result
we see
in the right bottom corner
the success rate of our attack and we
see that already with 800 challenge
response pairs
we could
train a neural network with which we
could decode the original key
the original or the inverse of course as
i said previously
we see
also at the top the accuracy and the
validation accuracy during training
and the important thing here is that the
validation accuracy
is a good indicator of how good our
attack is working
but that's
th this this uh
thing is also discussed in our paper
more thoroughly
yes what are the take away messages of
our
of our contribution
in case of a repetition code with seven
bits only a single key is necessary to
learn the multi-challenge path
given that the key is 128 bit
the fuzzy commitment scheme does not
counter the entropy loss of the
underlying path so the linear block
codes can be used to
derive some
some
form of comparison and we can also train
a machine learning model
so we don't need the responses in in
plain form
we think that the only way to counter
this machine learning model attacks um
is the limitation of the number of
challenge response pairs
and one
maybe way of mitigating our attack is
the usage of more complex or monolithic
error correction codes because
then the
creation of these xor equations get very
difficult and there are more xor
xors involved and it gets harder to
train the machine learning model at that
point
okay that's it from me
hope you
are thrilled to read my paper
thank you very much
[Music]
uh are there any questions from the
audience
i do not see any questions in zoom
exactly and i don't see any questions
yet on the lip jets
okay can i start with a question i'm
very interested because you used siamese
neural network so
you uh can you explain a bit more the
motivation why sam means did you use
that uh triplet loss or how did it go
what kind of loss function you used with
sami's network
uh we used the softmax loss function
okay yeah but um
the the the the
thing is with this neural network so our
xo equations are nothing else then um we
for for each part of the xor equations
the path was was used with a different
challenge
and the we thought okay
why to train
multiple neural networks for each of
these
parts of the equation
if the the instance is the same so
and and the zmes neural network does
exactly that that
internally there are
copies of the same neural network but
they share all their weights so if you
train this neural network
um every copy has the same same weights
and that that's exactly what's what's um
what our xo equation is representing so
it's always the same path that we are
training
or wants to model yeah
thanks
thank you
i still don't see any other questions
but feel free to ask in zelda chat if
you have time left you can come back to
that or you can discuss offline
um so i've switched to the next paper
thank you manuel
yeah thank you very much
so our second paper is
inconsistency of simulation and practice
in delay based from puffs this is a from
a ru university boohom and any tag i
will be presenting this paper
stage is yours
hi thanks for your introduction
can you see my screen
yes we can yes
hi everyone welcome to my short talk
which is a joint work uh with uh amir
omradi
uh at first i would like to give you a
very brief introduction about half uh
which are known as fingerprints in
embedded systems these one-way functions
are based on challenge
response mechanism so i should highlight
that
our main focus here is a strong delay
based pops
in the path area we have several
challenges that we will talk just about
well the first one is a machine learning
attire which are the most common one
these type of attacks can be performed
with different classifier or learner
algorithms with game of generating a
proper model for the path afterwards we
would like to focus on the next uh
challenging point uh which is a puffs
hardware implementation especially
the delay-based one
since creating the same delay lines
depending only on physical
characteristic is a difficult uh is
quite difficult
the main question here is that if all ml
attacks are in the simulation domain
consistent with the same accuracy and
success rate in the real world
um to answer this question we observe
the pulse robots against uh modeling
attacks in the most common delay base of
architecture like arbiter base paths and
their evaluation matrix like uniformity
or the opposite bias
to be precise we investigate um
our result on the cases study which is
ipof and its relevant classical attack
like a splitting bypass where we have
collected our real data set
from more than one thousand various ipof
implementation on 100 fpga cluster
as i mentioned uh our cases in this work
is a composite puff architecture which
has more complex model compared to
arbitrary as illustrated here the eye
puff
architecture has two x or arbiter path
layers uh top and the bottom layer the
one with the response uh interpol speed
of the top layer in one bit response uh
from the top layer
uh goes uh um to the challenge of the
bottom layer as the interface fit
since uh the classical lr for the whole
architecture of ipob was a successful
with the 75 percent prediction accuracy
then divide and conquer method of
splitting attack comes to the scene to
be sure this attack applies an artic but
for each layer separately in which the
prediction accuracy improves uh in this
uh several iterations
then let's be a bit physical
to achieve our main goal we need to
implement ipad variants and analyze the
effect of bios on the
applicable attacks
as the cases study we focus on 64 bit
one five ipath as a target of primitive
we have applied more than one thousand
designs in
two different uh placement patterns in
which we can choose the best one to
apply on all of our fpga
cluster
but
um afterward
but before we want to explain uh which
design and why
that has been chosen for the rest of our
observation we should briefly recall
about puff matrix
that are effective in puffs
functionality for the sake of gravity i
focus here on uniformity which is our
main criteria in this world
this parameter estimates a proportion of
once in a puff response
and the ideal value is
68 percent
here in nutshell you can see the result
of the evaluation of our chosen one five
ipof design in terms of different ipof
metrics as you can see the design enjoys
a high reliability but not very idle
uniqueness due to fpga implementation as
we can see here an almost normal
distribution for the uniformity of
each arbitrary puff instances being in a
reasonable range especially the final
response of
ipath
afterwards we investigate our real data
sets uh with the existing exploiting lr
attack based on the simulation results
uh the um this splitting attack should
be
able to successfully break one five ipod
using 500 000
crps either noisy or noise free we
conducted this attack on our 100 fpga
devices for the same ipod variant and
with the best chosen design as you can
see here it's leading to the lower
accuracy of at most 72 percent
in order to enhance the prediction
accuracy of the attack we have tried uh
considering a bias parameter in the
underlying and our learner
but it has not that much improvement in
the prediction accuracy
uh since this splitting ipof attack does
not achieve an adequate prediction
accuracy when the target puff is biased
our attention goes to other learners
like a n which is almost emitted in the
type of library as well
at first we applied the naive
as the black box attack which achieves
higher prediction accuracy compared to
splitting lr
but uh with the substituting uh the lr
learner as um of the splitting ipof
attack within an a n which is the here
called a m splitting we achieve a more
stable learner's behavior leading to a
higher narrow prediction accuracy of at
most 93 percent
to be more concrete it can be seen that
our proposed a n splitting attack uh not
uh only leads to a high prediction
accuracy but also runs considerably
faster compared to naive and l
in order to verify our result in the
simulation domain and finding out uh the
reason behind such an accuracy loss we
repeat the same attack on the same uh
one five and the other one k and kk
ipath design using uh simulated crp sets
for various amount of non uniformity in
the apa for instance for bottom and top
layer both
in the simulation domain uh ideal well
either point of uniformity which is
85 which is a 50 percent are mostly uh
considered
at the end i would like to summarize our
important points that
it means that the high prediction
accuracy of these type of crops in
simulation are mostly considered in idle
or close to idle conditions however
we show that we should verify this
result in practice as well
then the next point is that
non-uniformity in the output of other
powerful complex architecture can affect
uh successful ml attacks in terms of
accuracy or success rate and the last
but not the least point is that an
accurate model of the uplift but besides
of course the ml expert you can fill
this gap between these two domains
thanks for your say
thank you
thank you very much
um
we may have a quick question i guess i'm
checking the lip chat i don't see any
questions there is something in chat
from zoom
from from nikki what's the difference
between a naive a n n and n applied
um actually it's the same uh that naive
a m or a and apply uh because we have
here the approach of a and splitting it
means that we split the ipod to the two
extra arbitrary buff we use this uh
naive a and n to just show that we use a
m for whole of as a black box attack for
whole of ipob architecture
thank you
okay i do not see any more questions so
maybe in the interest of time we can
continue and if there is questions we
can return in the end
exactly so uh thank you once again
we are switching to next paper which is
combining optimization objectives new
modeling attacks on strong puffs this is
a
joint work of mpi security and privacy
bohom for university of august gi
and the
berlin and the speaker is johannes
turbish so the state of your jonas thank
you
uh how do you own videos good
yes yes all right all right thank you a
little bit of a research uh yeah uh
thank you very much um
so anita already talked about strong
puffs and in this work we had a look at
that uh another look at the internet at
the inter-post path
um so you already know a strong puff is
a physical security primitive and it can
be used in this very simple change
response for the coil
and if you care about the security um
you mostly care about whether the
attacker can build a mathematical clone
so if you can build a mechanical clone
you can impersonate a puff and break the
security of the protocol
and the most well-known candidate for a
strong path is the arbiter puff
but it has been well known for a long
time that this can be modeled with a
simple linear model and this means you
need very little data
in your modeling attack to build a clone
so you cannot use this directly
so what people have been doing is they
built composite designs they uh for
example the xor path is also well known
and here you just use multiple arbiter
puffs and
[Music]
in together
but still this suffers also from attacks
um so two years ago the intercost path
for short ipath was presented
and here you again stack two
alternatives together two exops um you
have one the upper one um
which creates an additional challenge
bit and then the lower one is evaluated
on this longer challenge
and
this is hoped to be a more secure design
from a very high level perspective
what you you do with modeling attacks
there are two broad categories you have
these classic attacks and here you just
use challenge response pairs
and you try to learn the whole model at
once basically like your classic
classification setting in machine
learning
um and this works but the
observation is that the
training data that you need is
exponential in size uh in the number of
arbitrary parts of your design
but for most uh common or for most
feasible puff instant sizes you can
still use this attack
however even more devastating are
so-called reliability attacks and here
you take additional information into
account you not only look at the
response but you look at how reliable a
response is
you can do this you can take a path and
query it multiple times for a single
challenge and you can check how likely
it is that the response between flip
and this gives you an optimization
problem basically
and whenever you solve this problem when
you minimize it um you get a candidate
for one of these one of the arbiter
paths in your design so you need to
solve this problem multiple times and
explore all the minima to learn your
whole model
um
the advantage of this attack is that it
only needs a linear training set size so
it's it's you need much less data to
break the path now the eye path it was
thought that was secure against both of
these attacks
last year chest was already shown that
classic attacks can be improved and what
we do in our paper is we show that
reliability attacks can be applied to
this path
i already said that
for the
reliability attack you need to solve an
optimization problem and you need to
explore oil minima
and
the security argument for the ipa was
that they built it in a way that some of
the minima are really unlikely to be
found
so you cannot
build a model of your whole path and
then you cannot predict response as well
and now the core idea of our attack
really is that we say okay you can
modify your optimization target so once
you have found one of the minimap you
can say i don't want to go here again so
you add an additional term it basically
removes that minimum for your um from
your target function and this enables
you to explore other minima as well
this is basically in one slightly decor
idea
um and what's the takeaway result
um based on with our attack here shown
in blue you are already back again in
this regime of linear scaling so if you
increase the the security parameter that
is the number of arbiter paths in your
design
of the ipaf
the training set size only goes somewhat
linearly
and you can break even really large
instances like the 110 112 14 high above
and this is in contrast to the other
texts are shown here which are in the
classical regime and here it's not
feasible to feasible to break this
really large puffs
so what would you find in the paper
actually what we did is we created a
tech framework we combined the classic
and the reliability approach so we
use all the information at hand to uh
conduct the modeling attack
and uh actually there are quite some
details on constraints and how we did
the optimization because even with these
ideas at hand it's not so
straightforward to break the eye path
and there are
some technical challenges there
and maybe looking at
further future work um
one idea would be to check uh can we
can we use some of the benefits of the
ipad can we can we find a generalization
maybe better design
um or
are all designs broken
so this would be another way to look at
it can we maybe get an
impossibility result can we prove that
all out above base designs necessarily
fall addicting to this
kind of reliability text
but that's just a guess at this point
just the hypothesis
that's already everything i've got
thank you
questions from for your harness
no questions yet on the webchat yeah
benedict has a question sure benedict
hey good morning thanks for the talk
you hear me yes yes yes we can see you
can you one slide back please i think it
was slide number six
yes yes this one so um
you said the uh to the attack complexity
now kind of just gets linear in the
number of the architects and i was
wondering um so how does the number of
losses
that you would try in your attack how
does that scale
with the number of the arbitrage like is
that exploding
no and on one side earlier you showed
that you have yes you try these
different losses right and yes um
does this depend at all on the number of
the arbitrators
yes uh this is a really good question um
so
this this is basically our core idea
here uh but we we actually didn't use
this in practice because exactly as you
say we we have to add losses again and
again and again and we found that this
was not uh not the best way to go at it
so what we actually do is
um we learn the whole model at once
and we um so we have multiple articles
that we learn in parallel
and we force them to not become similar
so we force each of our candidates to go
into into a different direction
and that way you don't have this problem
of adding losses again and again again
we found this to be a more
a better solution basically
okay the core ideas
okay thanks
there's a question i guess
there is a question from wei cheng so
the dataset is from real device or from
simulation yes this is from simulation
um because the simulation allows us to
to do this this scaling um to look have
a look at the scaling
and
we also use simulations because i mean
in the original eye ipath um
the original ipaf
arguments were basically on simulated
data and this is kind of the the ideal
setting because the weights are not
correlated and
yeah this is kind of the state of the
art thank you
okay
let's continue with the with the next
talk thank you johannes
thank you thank you very much once again
so the next talk will be probably secure
hardware masking in the transition and
glitch robust probing model better safe
than sorry
this is work from uc level and the
speaker is gatan cassia
the stage is yours
if you're speaking we don't hear you at
the moment
so you'll just need to unmute
seems unmuted but
maybe there's a problem with the
sounds
uh if you're using uh headphones um that
have a microphone attached you may try
unplugging those if you can
[Music]
so
it doesn't seem
to work
shall we maybe continue with the next
talk and then after the next one return
to this one to give
guytan a couple of minutes to
to resolve the issue
yes i think that's yeah probably it's
better to do so okay okay can you take
the speaker into a breakout room that
they can try it there
uh yes
yes
so i'm going to open a breakout room uh
to give this speaker some technical help
um and so nobody else go into it
okay thank you very much
and then we
skipped the next one
it's
exploring crypto physical dark matter
and learning with physical rounding
towards secure and efficient fresh gain
so this is also work from uc leuven and
the speaker is char mumma
all right i'll just share a slide
okay you should see the slide
yes
okay perfect
okay so thanks for the introduction
so uh to
start to motivate a bit of work we'll
start with the with the well-known
symmetry cryptographic setup where alice
wants to speak with bob in a secure
manner
so for that they both know a strict a
secret key value k
that they both use either to encrypt
some data in the case of alice or to
decrypt some data in case of bob
and
such a configuration has been and is
still
analyzed
often
and it has been proved in fact that
there is in fact a lot of solution where
an adversary that has access to this
encrypted data
cannot recover information about the
protected information or the key
but uh starting two decades ago
approximately
uh it has been shown that such a black
box consideration is not really uh
useful because there are different
effects
that can be
involved in the in the settings
and
this effect comes from a flowing
implementation of physical effects that
can leak information about the data that
are manipulated
and
this in fact leads to
attacks that are known as side channel
attacks
and in the context of
power such analytics or physical sight
channel attacks in a more broad sense
a popular quantum measure has been
introduced which is the masking
but
this contour measure appears to be
costly and especially in the context of
block cipher implementation
because of the the non-linear operation
that are inherent to this block cipher
um there is a cost producing alternative
that has been proposed uh the locking
and this tracking mechanism can be
uh
sum up as follows so the basic is the
idea is that instead of directly using
the secret value key
as a as the
circuit value k as the key sorry
we will instead derive a new fresh and
temporary key k star
using
easy to protect hacking function so the
easy to protect a king function is
denoted here in the figure as fk and
this is the the blocks that are in dark
gray in the figure
so put in another way uh the main idea
is there is a separation of duties
between an easy to protect cracking
function that is used only to derive
this new fresh key
and this
is then used by a cryptographically
strong function that is used to process
the data
however uh specifying unified prop
properties for this tracking function
appears to be challenging
and
it turns out in fact that
from the solution that can be found in
the literature for the moment
uh
this solution
try in fact to manage a bit the
trade-off between the efficiency of the
rocking function and the physical
assumptions that are made
to design the security of of their uh
the hurricane function
and among all the different treat models
that have been already considered in in
literature we are placing our work in
the middle of these
by exploring in fact the treat model
where an adversary is able to obtain the
leakage value of this new fresh key that
has been generated by the by the
recruiting function
for our work we took inspiration of the
the
prf proposal of bonnetetal in their work
exploring crypto dark matter
and in fact they propose an instead of
weak paragraph that can be summed uh sum
up sorry as follows so
first we have a dot product between a
binary matrix k
and a binary vector of r the error is a
random binary vector in fact and
once we have done this dot product we
output the value z by assuming in fact
all the the result of the the
vector obtained by the dot product
and we sum all of this value modulo 3.
and this two operation can be in fact
abstracted as a combination between two
main operations so first there is the
dot product k times r
and there is also a mapping that comes
in top of it
and why we took inspiration of such a
weak pair f because in fact
there is
kind of interest for a wreaking uh based
on this sweet perf proposal because we
can see uh that's the the dot product k
times r can be seen as the operation
that should be computed in order to
obtain
this fresh
new key k-star and this operation is in
fact easy to mask additively
and the mapping function
here
can be instead of being
explicitly computed
been
implementation
so here we will consider that
instead of having an explicit
computation of this map operation we
will
use in fact the physics of the
implementation to perform this map
operation
so what are the contributions that we
have made in our paper
we have first proposed in fact a new
ranking scheme so which is defined as
follow we obtain the new fresh k
key sorry k star
by performing a dot product between
a
matrix k
times concatenation between a vector a
and the value 1
where all the values are not binary
anymore but are in a prime field
uh we consider more particularly an
instance where the parameter defined
here m n are equal to four and the prime
that we consider is the mersenne prime 2
to the power 31-1
we did a security and performance
analysis uh for this working scheme
considering that the leakage function is
the the well-known hamming weight
as a first exploration exploration case
study
and
for the security of the
regarding site channel text we did in
fact proof of concept implementation on
fpga
and we consider in the whole paper
two main attack path for the security
analysis a first one which is more a
crypt analysis um a mathematical
mathematical cryptanalysis path which is
defined here as the attack path one in
red so mainly we have to to check if the
leakage value of the the k star key
uh cannot provide any information on the
long secret key uh k
and we define the second attack pad the
attack path 2 which is more related to
side channel attacks
and related in fact to the computation
of this dot product
for a masked implementation of the of
the dot product
to sum up uh a bit the results uh we we
showed in fact that uh such a solution
uh can provide equipped uh cryptographic
properties and uh more uh importantly
this is really more efficient that's
what can be currently found in the
literature and this new figure in fact
sum up a bit this result uh to the left
you can find a randomness requirement
uh of or
masked implementation for the dot
product and we can see that the cost is
linear
regarding the amount of share that we
use
and
to the right you can find the some
results about our security analysis for
the for the physical security and we can
find that the data complexity uh used a
liquid in fact sorry to perform a
dpa
increase
exponentially with the amount of share
and these two figures combined show that
we can have an exponential security
using a linear cost which is in fact
cool for a masked implementation
so what's next
we defined three next uh
research path that we can follow the
first one is the general
generalization to a broader
class of leakage because here we
consider only the amino case
so we can just look for more general
leakage function a second one
is to evaluate a bit the impact of
parallelism uh of the other
implementation that we consider because
here we consider a rather
parallel implementation that we're
performing five multiple multiplication
in parallel so we can see a bit what's
the impact of serialization for example
that
socialization can be in fact found
in software implementation
and we can look also for practical
integration of this working scheme in a
leakage resilient mode so that's it for
me i'm glad to answer any question
thank you
are there any questions
seems like there are no questions on the
lips yet
okay also no questions in
zone chat
so maybe i can ask a very quick small
question
so you you say what's next and you uh
you have couple of
so part one part two and then practical
integration but what would you consider
to be
uh the the the best direction really to
follow so
really uh
going for the generalization or uh
evaluating the impact because both sound
very
very relevant but what which one
do you consider to have the more impact
potentially
that's quite a hard question because i
would say it really depends on the on
the
the constraint that you have for your
application
but
for me
for me in fact both are really important
but i would say that for a more generic
point of view the generalization to
broader class of leakage is really
really important
but
on the other hand uh the fact that you
can have if you want software
implementation for example
uh
even if you have the generalization for
to a broader card to a broader case of
leakage uh you cannot have in fact for
analysis you cannot have a
good security
if you serialize really a lot your
computation
because in this case you can break your
max implementation quite easily so
really you have to do both in parallel
oh okay cool thank you
thank you charles uh let's continue with
the next talk
uh so i'll ask qaton first if uh
everything is ready does the mic work
now
yeah so we can hear now
okay
okay so let's switch back to previous
talk and uh let me introduce once again
so this is about probably secure
hardware masking in transition and
glitch robust probing model better safe
dance story and the speaker is getting
casia
okay thank you for the introduction and
sorry for the technical issue
so the starting point is uh masking as
we all know if you want to mask this
small circuit on the right we have just
a single xor gate to register so in
practice flip flops and then an iron
gate what we will do is replace each
wire with the sharing of the wires that
are taken independently uh here we can
see a1 a2 then we replace each uh gate
with a so-called gadget that implements
the gate but in the mask domain on the
shares so here we have a gadget foxx or
a gadget for register and a big gadget
for the and gate
so that's the starting point and this
works very well we can have security
asymptotic security even noisy gauge but
assuming that we have leakage that this
kind of arithmetic that is each wire
leaks independently
however
yes so that's the deprobing model
basically
when you do here one observation it
should be independent of the secrets
[Music]
in practice however
we do not we have cmos circuits and
those are if leakage characteristic
which are not just really one value at
once but we can have um
other characteristics such that uh for
instance when you have glitches in your
circuit that propagates through the
combinational gates and this makes your
leakage depend possibly on all of the
inputs of a combinational circuit so if
you want to model this in the t probing
model you will extend this model
to the
glitch robust t probing model where
instead of having just one wire when the
adversary puts one probe he will get all
the inputs
of the related combination of circuits
so that's a first kind of physical
effect we want to consider here
another can would be the transition so
here if i take the two circuits one that
would be a first cycle of execution and
the second one would be a second cycle
of execution the adversary that puts a
probe on circuit can and
can detect uh the the transition between
the two values because the cmos gate
will depend
the consumption in current of the cmos
gate will depend on both the initial
value and the final value
of this wire so if we model this we have
the transition robust uh probing model
where basically one probe of the
adversary will give him the value of
those two wires for two different for
two consequential
execution
cycles
and then um if you look at it actually
we can have both glitches and
transitions at the same time and take 18
iron combine
that is
when we have uh this clock cycle that
leads us to this state uh we will have a
lot of glitches and this settling in the
state of the city of this wire will
depend both on its previous state
and on the glitch that you have on all
these previous wires so if you want to
model this with our glitch plus
transition robust probing model where
the adversary using only one probe will
get access to all the the
wires that are input to the
combinational circuit but for two
clock cycles
so that's the model and if you want to
be um like usually in the literature we
are considering more glitch for hardware
implementation and transition for
software implementation but
there's a kind of simplified economy
because it's like where we should we we
see issue in practice that they come
from but in principle you could have
both issue for instance in other
implementations and actually this has
been shown uh recently in some papers
so
yeah
we want to prove security in all those
models so if we look first only to
glitch us that's one of our previous
work and we have been able to prove a
composition term that says if you have
one gadget that is secure uh without
glitches or a lot of gadgets that are
secure without glitches you compose them
so that in the case where no glitches
you have you can still have security for
instance using strategy based on sni ni
pionee and so on
so that's a ditchless composition
you can have
from there direct glitch robust
composition if all of your gadgets are
glitched themselves which is a quite
weak condition um
usually like all hardware gadgets are
ugly robust and of course if they're
still satisfied the same properties in
terms of for example being sni
so now if you want um to look at
transition which is uh the work of this
paper you have been able to prove a
similar composition term
that is we can compose a gadget in the
glitch and transition robust probing
model but here we need a stronger uh
hypothesis or it's a more particular
term we need all the gadget to be open
and open is a new definition we
introduce here
that's a bit stronger than binary
definition
but that's still uh nice because all
linear gadgets are trivially piney so
they are not costly and really uh
provide new construction for opening
multiplication gadgets which are not too
expensive compared to um
to the state-of-the-art uh let's say the
pioneer one so the hover it quite it's
quite small as you can see if we do uh
hpc so pioneer implementation versus
this open implementation the overhead is
not that huge
um
so that's one solution for solving um
the the case
of transitions and then in the paper we
analyze another transition another
solution which is quite
intuitive let's see in this example we
want to evaluate an spn
we'll use
bubbles in our pipeline to avoid
transitions
the idea being that here
every time we switch
off state or to the next cycle every
other cycle with a cycle where the data
would be non-sensitive for instance zero
therefore the um the transitions that
you can have the
adversary can transition between those
two states
he will not learn anything interesting
more than just probing this value so the
transition doesn't learn more and so if
you want to evaluate this spn at the
first cycle we evaluate the first xbox
of the first round
then you leave one cycle empty and here
if we if our s box is two stage then you
have the this state is in the second
stage and then the third cycle you can
evaluate the seconds box and so on you
have the third box and finally if you're
on the trace box at the final round we
can go at the final cycle we can go to
the next round to the first box and so
on so on the main drawback of this um
is that it increases um
it actually reduces the throughput
because every other cycle is just lost
but the nice part of it is that we don't
need any extra constraint on how we
build our gadgets so we can only be
glitch robust
from the gadgets and then from the
structure the way we use them we can
transition from business uh as a bonus
so that's quite um
trivial actually as observation and the
nice part of it is that we have been
able to prove that if you have
a composition strategy that's spiny for
those gadgets
then you can do something a bit better
it is that is is to avoid those bubbles
if you are uh gadgets that are in
parallel so for instance uh s boxes in
the same round of a block cipher and so
this would give this result
which is actually much nicer in terms of
throughput because the only pipeline
bubble you have here is actually
needed for the architecture because if
you want to go to the second round you
will need to have finished this last
round so this is kind of mandatory you
you can never skip it as long as your
xbox is more than one
cycle
latency
you will need
to uh this bubble so actually this comes
from free for example
in our previous hpc paper uh the present
architecture we presented was our aes
architecture to add this property um
so you
you don't need to change anything to the
implementation and in the end you get uh
in addition to this robustness you get
transition robustness for free at no
change in the architecture not even for
the latency or throughput
which is quite nice
so
this contribution is uh
as far as we know the first proverbial
security and transition robustness
circuit and we can prove it for existing
masking here so at no extra overhead and
for a new one where we have generic
composition term i would say if we want
to continue this line a natural future
step as we have seen for many works in
masking is to have automated
verification and maybe one day automated
generation of this quantum module based
on the abstract description of cipher so
thank you for your attention i'll be
glad to answer any question
thank you for your talk
questions
uh there's a question in the libchat uh
for from jurgen focus
uh for glitch robust finally the input
output latency of one response two of
hbc2 seems to be optimal if you want to
have glitch robust opening with trivial
composition then the latency of your
constructions goes up up to two response
recycles do you think you can get
constructions with lower latency keeping
triple composition without bubbles
um
i would say i'm not convinced that the
glitch will be spiny
one versus two is optimal
i believe it should be possible to do
one and one latency
less than that seems to be impossible
[Music]
and then
if we add that for
a piney ugly trophy spiny we would have
then i believe for opini
quite simply two and and two latency
then going back to one and one i'm not
sure if possible but
i wouldn't say it's impossible
it would probably like increase strongly
the cost in randomness
thank you very much there is one more
question i guess um
yes yes
uh provo build security sounds a bit
strong what is the reduction problem in
disprovable security
okay so this is provable security
in the glitch and transition robust
probing model
assuming that we have perfect randomness
so i would say
the first one is this uh
probing model where we assume the
adversary is still probes uh this is not
the practice like practice is noisy
leakage and the traditional reduction
from one to the other is quite loose and
requires many shares
and as you have seen
a previous day
having probably secured in the region
probing model would already be better
and of course in practice you had the
question of how to generate perfect
randomness
thank you
okay in the interest of time let's go
for the last talk exactly so our last
talk will be learning parity with
physical noise
imperfections reductions and fpga
prototype
so this is a joint work of uc leuven and
shanghai jiatong university and our
speaker will be david belicia
no it will be kim off man
can you hear me properly
yes
there is
there's a change
hoffman i guess sorry for that yep no
problem let me show my screen
[Music]
okay
so
i will talk to you about learning parity
with physical noise
so first quick step on learning with
parity noise which is a learning problem
so computationally have problems that
can be used for cryptography
learning problems
have been used widely in the last
decades
mostly learning with errors and focus
quantum schemes and all its variants
but learning with parity noise is a more
minimalist one
basically as in any learning problems an
adversary is given public vectors and
noisy scalar products between the secret
key and these public vectors
and
all the operation occurs of f2
so the error is binary and generated
with a bernoulli
this
problem seems simple so we may think
that its implementation will be true
however sadly it is not the case
mainly because we need a secure engine
to to generate or
if the parent is not secured an
adversary will be able to predict here
therefore remove it and solve the linear
system we would use the key
so this png proves to be
expensive in time and the weak thing you
can say channel attacks
our idea in order to get rid of it is to
use inexact computing
the idea of an exact computing is to use
a processor in a controlled environment
in our case voltage overscaling and
clock manipulation
so that
it will
not perform correctly
and we will end up with 40 outputs
but with a control lever so basically
instead of
correctly computing an inner product and
adding a generated error
we directly compute energy scalar
product in a product
sadly we do not manage to perfectly
control the error
mainly we see output dependencies which
means that the probability of error
depends of the correct output value of
the inner product which is not a
property we want for cryptography use
because
the correct output of the inner product
is linked to the key
so we did not buy delta
the distance
between source probability of errors we
want to mitigate this as much as
possible if we reach a delta of zero
it means that our error is perfectly
balanced and we are
in the lpn case everything is secure
it's great
so we consider different
hardware architectures
to compute our physical inner product
and the best one
we ended up with
is a barrel architecture so one layer of
end gates
send parallel layers of circuits
with a gt3 clock
so
to explain it shortly uh
it's a clock manipulation that allows us
to induce
data independent errors
and
we we end up with a simulated delta of
less than one percent which is small but
sadly not negligible
so it means that a
cryptographic primitive build and
physical in a product
cannot rely directly on the security of
lpn
which leads us to our next contribution
a security reduction of our problem to
appear
so first we define we define our problem
as learning with parity noise with
output dependencies
lpn d is a theoretical problem
whereas the physical inner product is a
physical problem
so lcd is just a modalization of a
problem
based on our observation it's basically
the same as learning with parity noise
certainly differences are two noise
parameters
one is the correct opportunity zero one
if it's one
so the idea for reduction is we see that
npn is a particular case of npn odish
it's a balanced case
and we managed to build an algorithm
that allowed us to transform lpnd
samples into neither ones so that means
that an adversary which has access to
lpn oracle solver
and a batch of lpnwt samples can use
algorithm
to transform them into noise lpn samples
then use its solver to retrieve the key
so that means that with some assumptions
on the parameters
lpn with output dependency is at least
as hard as lpm
and
amusingly
this prediction works the other way
around because we can also transform lpn
into lpnod so the other reduction is
less interesting but still pretty cool
at the end we managed to quantify
the loss in parameters in order to
reduce from lpnod to lpm
and we will be able to use this formula
for concrete implementation because we
built an fpga prototype
board
that
implemented the
physical inner product
this physically this physical product
reached a delta
of 5.8
using a dummy circuit that induced data
independent error
and using our reduction the formula from
our reduction
we can claim 80 bits of security
with a cryptographic scheme relying on
this physical inner product
so to put it in a nutshell
in exact computing applied to lpn allows
us to get rid of the secure png which
means improved performances and
better design against such general
attacks
so circums are that
a problem no relies on a physical
assumption rather than a theoretical one
and it induces data dependent error but
they can be handled at a small cost with
a prediction theorem
the next step will be to try to reach
more complex primitives such as
cross-control movements with
learning with physical errors for
instance
thank you for your attention do you have
any question
thank you uh
i see no questions
also nothing on zulip and
we would advise people to go to
zulipchat for any questions because we
are way out of time
um
so probably
indeed people
people if you have questions please use
uh zulip i i hope clement will be
available for answering as soon as it's
already nine
i think the new session is already
starting so thank you all for your
attention and see you in a new session
in a couple