streaming up
and you're ready to go have a good
session
thank you
okay so this is the session um post
quantum crypto part two so it's a
continuation of the first part from from
monday there's going to be a third part
as well
we are going to have six talks presented
in this session
my name is robin and i'm sharing
together with tony who's also taking
questions and stuff like that
i guess if there's no advanced questions
already in advance then i guess we can
jump invite with the first talk
that would be by christine on rapidly
verifiable xms signatures
yeah thanks robin
so the motivation for this work is the
following use case namely that of um
having one signature being signed and
not verified once but many times and
this is actually
we don't have excuse me i'm sorry sorry
please excuse me for interrupting uh
you'll need to share your screen
that's quite all right there's no nice
way to interrupt people in zooms
let me see is it no sharing again
it is not
interesting
how about now
ah yes
very good
okay
then i continue with the use case namely
that of one signature and many
verifications
this is actually
a pretty common use case namely
for instance in secure boot you have the
situation where one firmware signature
is verified many times
as well as in the case of firmware where
updates where one-sided firmware can be
verified by many devices
and in this use case designer actually
usually has access to many significant
to many computational resources where
the verify might not and this is the
case we looked at specifically for xmss
and asked ourselves the question can
tradeoffs be made to put more
computational load on the
signer
while reducing it on verifier
so i don't have time to go into the
details of of xmss fully um but i will
just mention that the underlying idea of
xmss is that there's a one-time
signature scheme underlying it
specifically volts plus which has one
secret key one public key and can sign
one message clearly
and stateful hash based signature
schemes like xmss combine these one-time
signatures multiple one-time signatures
in a larger scheme using merkle trees
and now again i i don't have time to
explain what's plus in in accurate
complete details but just a very very
simplified look at it is that it has a
public parameter a winternet
constant w and a hash function h
and the secret key consists of chunks
that you see on the left hand chat side
that are linked to the public key by
applying the hash function in the chain
w minus one times
and then a signature in the scheme looks
like
elements on these chains which depend on
the value of
of
the message digest and the checksum
then in this same picture the
computational load for a
consists of taking the signature and
completing these chains so a verifier
has to start from the signature compute
all these blue bubbles by computing hash
functions and verify the right most
right bubble against the public key
and then the the vital observation is
that the cost of verification for such a
signature is mostly determined by where
this signature is on the chain
and that's the result of a hash so it's
rather on the random side
but really for a verifier it would be
much more advantageous if these values
were more on the right of the chain so
for instance if the new signature was
there
and this was an observation that was
also made in pcmcm18
and their idea was to create multiple
hash message digests by looping over t
counters appending all these counters to
the message and hashing each
individually and should
choose the counter that minifimizes the
verification hashes for the verifying
so this was previous work and then onto
our rapidly verifiable xmss
so in black you see the the sort of
traditional xmss signing algorithm and
in blue you see where we apply the core
idea of pcmcm18
to xmss by appending these counters and
in a loop
determining which which is the most
positive for a verifier verification
and also nice to observe is that we show
in the paper that this can be done
effectively for large messages as well
so the initial paper
for large messages would need to hash
the whole message every time well we
observed that if we append the counter
last
we only have to iterate over the last
last hash block every time
and thereby can greatly reduce the speed
or increase the speed of this technique
we also verified our results by making
an implementation on a cortex-m4 board
and we showed that using this technique
with other xmss
optimizations
allows as an example a signature
generation time of about a minute and
already expected speed up on the
verifier side so the constraint device
of over 2.11 and other traders are of
course possible and can be found in the
paper but this is an example of what it
can do
and then lastly about the paper so what
else is in there we discuss
compatibility with rc so whether our
technique is still compatible which can
be achieved with a wrapper function
we show it still secure
by doing a thorough security proof of
the resulting scheme
as well as give some performance
guidance by by doing a thorough
mathematical and experimental analysis
of what effect parameter choices have on
the performance
and if there are any questions now i'll
happily take them
otherwise on later on zulip or
through this contact
thanks
yeah thanks a lot also for keeping in
the five minutes time slot
um other questions now um on the lip in
in the zoom chat
uh i haven't seen any
okay then maybe i have one brief
question um what is the context with
multi-three xmss did you also look into
how that behaves in the multi-scenarios
um we did not look at it in the paper
but thinking about it later
it gets a little bit more complicated
because the connection between the trees
behaves differently than the signing of
the message which you can just iterate
um so we have thought about it
but
let's call it future
all right okay
then if there are no more questions
right now i'm of course feel free to ask
more further questions in the later then
approach the speaker or the co-authors
at any time
write emails all the stuff you can do
and then we would switch over to the
next presentation
and if i can just make a quick
announcement actually my apologies um
but if any of the co-hosts are uh
accidentally hitting the recording
button just do be careful with that uh
because it does announce to everybody
um that recording is stopped and i do
apologize to the speakers who have been
interrupted by that so that's all carry
on
okay
my fault
okay then um the next talk is going to
be about escapart
um what uh
suit for efficient learning with running
key examination mechanisms
and the presenters jose if you're not
mistaken
yeah thank you i'm going to share now um
okay so you can see it right yeah okay i
did not do the check screen before
okay uh yeah so
uh hello everyone good morning or good
afternoon uh
i'm going to try to convince you to
watch our longer video or read
excuse me for interrupting can you move
the uh
the list of people on the side off the
screen
oh yeah
yeah thank you
is it right like now
as long as yeah as long as you don't
have any text at the very top of your
slides
perfect okay yeah
okay thank you so yeah i was going to
say yeah i'm going to try to convince
you to read our paper discovered a suite
of efficient learning with random key
encapsulation mechanism
which is a joint work with hanshuman
supernan english
so
the context of
the content software paper are
we first start with a background lattice
based cryptography
for
those who are not familiar uh
we introduce the basic concepts that are
needed to understand the rest of the
paper
and then we
focus on the design of the schemes uh so
in in scavenger suite there are three
schemes floreta espadagle
and
in this presentation i will talk briefly
about their characteristics but not
their design and parameters but in the
paper you can check more in detail
and then in the paper you can check also
the security analysis of each of these
three schemes and also the parameter
sources
uh we also include uh software results
in
both high-end platforms such as intel
avx processors and embedded platforms
such as cortex and for processors and we
also have a section in which we discuss
on hardware acceleration and in
particular on the acceleration of the
polynomial multiplication there is
nothing which together with hashing is
one of the two
bottlenecks
uh we plan to extend our work
with full hour implementations
and
we have also our conclusion so
yeah for
um as for the paper what was your
motivation so as you all know uh nist is
going to release initial standard for
post quantum cryptography in the coming
year
and
we can see if we look at the finalists
that for both
key encapsulation mechanisms and digital
signatures lattice-based schemes seem to
be the the preferred solutions or
because of their efficiency
and uh basically
they criteria that nist used for
selecting these candidates was uh of
course the security analysis but mainly
implementation aspects i mean in uh
efficiency uh and maybe for for choosing
the standard they will take
into account also a site channel
security
so
for now it was security and efficiency
uh what we did in our paper was to take
advantage of the last advancements in
lattice-based cryptography to
tune uh
existing schemes in the state-of-the-art
or to create new schemes
that will adjust
[Music]
the security while achieving um
some characteristics we we wanted to
achieve so these are for florete we
wanted a scheme that was faster so we
use our ring learning with only
construction
for spider we wanted a scheme that was
very compact
so we use a model learning with running
construction where
the module is smaller than usual and
then for example we just did an
alternate version of saver choosing
different parameters
and
and then of course we we provided
optimize implementations on on software
as i said we discuss a bit on how to
accelerate the non hardware
so
how would these three schemes in this
cover compare to saver
we take saber as as a benchmark because
he's also a learning with running model
learning with running
king capsulation mechanism and if we
compare them we have a floret which is
kind of a ring version let's say as new
hope can be for kyber
but in florida we achieve a higher
performance
of course at the cost of a higher memory
footprint
then in spara
we have
the smallest memory footprint
uh
at the expense of having a worse
performance and then for sable we have a
better trade-off between memory and
performance the ensemble
but the difference between cyber and
sable is that
cyber
was built
being conservative
from the point of view of security while
in some way would try to stretch
to limits while still maintaining
of course the the
security level required
as for the standards
so
yeah the the conclusions of our work is
is that
we
we managed to improve the practical
aspects of the state of the art in in
learning with rounding games
and we explored the same decisions um
yeah as for for the case of saver there
was no ring version let's say
like there is no hope for kyber so we
have now florete and also uh
the design of espada is is nobody in the
sense that uh
all a module learning
with errors or learning running schemes
they use polynomials of 256 coefficients
while here we use a smaller polynomials
so we have a
less
structure and then
our future work or how we plan to
continue our work is to provide
security parameters for target other
security levels because for florida and
spalla we only provide parameters
targeting the security level three
and we also would like to explore our
architectures for acceleration because
in this paper we we could only uh
explore a bit on the acceleration of the
planet multiplication but uh what we
know nowadays is that
lattice-based schemes in hardware they
benefit a lot for from from having also
a hashing processor
because that's the other one to me
so
that's all thank you for your attention
and uh
yeah i can answer your questions now or
or in
in the chat
yeah thank you for the presentation um i
don't see messages right on the zoom
chat tony do you have anything on zulip
uh yeah so there's a question from
pauline pong
and he asked i noticed that your
invention of power accelerator on that
board
is with the frequency
125 or 150 megahertz i guess it is due
to the power software interface limit on
that board so do you have the idea uh
how fast
uh your implantations and self can run
uh
yeah well actually i wouldn't say it
depends on the hardware software
interface but i would say it depends
more on the technology of the fpga
because we know for instance for saber
we use
the rtx 7 fpa but if you move to ultra
scale which has a
better technology
just
while having the same rtl we were having
the same digital design
of the processor but just having a
better physical technology you can
achieve higher
frequency
so
i i think that that's limiting more than
the hardware software interface
all right um
any more questions tony do you ever use
anything
uh
no i don't see more questions from the
web
yeah because also in terms of time it
makes sense to then move on to the next
speaker so thanks a lot
again thank you
and then the next presentation is going
to be well let me guess the name c type
faster constant time c side i would
assume by fabio yeah that's right
so let me share my screen
so
presentation mode
can you see it yep
so yeah
um so hello um hello tony nice to see
you guys
and hello everyone and welcome scene to
seaside faster constant time seaside
implementation
sea tide is a
joint work with gustavo banegas dan
bernstein tongshu tanya langer michel
meyer ben smith and
jana
i would like to start by giving you
um a very short short very very short
introduction to suicide
in order to give you um a briefly
overview suicide is a post quantum
isotony
key exchange
proposed in 2018
which compared to for instance um
lettuce-based schemes is
still relatively slow
but on the other hand offers very small
keys and known interactive not
interactive um different helmet key
exchange
in c side we first choose a bunch of
small odd primes and make sure that that
b is prime as shown in the slide
then we fix a super singular elliptic
curve over the field fp
which means that we
got
p plus one points
then we can use the points of order li
um
so we have the the corresponding
subgroup to compute the lie esogenie
um one can think of this as started from
one curve and by acting being
transported to second curve
the private key in c side consists of a
vector of length n
where the absolute values of each entry
represents the number of isogenes or
the steps to go
within
this
the resulting esogenic graph
and the sine
of these values represents
the direction going
the positive on the negative and
going over there
so to say the quadratic twist for the
negative values
in all the previous implementation these
ci's
of the private key were sampled from a
small range which may vary
based on the point rejection or and the
effort for
calculating the misogyny
for a certain prime degree and the
chosen strategy
in contrast to the previous works in c
type we define a new key space and the
corresponding algorithm to evaluate the
group action in constant time
in this new key space we group the
primes
in batches
in and for each batch we fixed an upper
bound
for
bi
um
in this example this would mean that um
we require that the absolute value of
the sum of the absolute values in a
given batch
is smaller than the corresponding upper
bound when sampling a key
the some setup allows us to achieve the
same key space size with fewer isotonies
um in
comparison you can see that in the setup
of seaside 512
we need
fewer isogenes
in order to achieve the same security
the main question is how to implement
a constant time algorithm or group
reaction
for
for this new key space
and um
um there are a few problems that we have
to solve in order to achieve constant
time with using this this new key space
the first one
have to make sure that all esogenies for
a given batch have the same running time
in
independent of the isogeny degrees we
achieved these by using the
matrashka doll property of the bellow
style formulas
for instance when given two different
prime degrees
evaluating the the required polynomial
for the larger prime
already contains all the operations
necessary for computing also the smaller
one
thus um using this this this approach we
can compute each zoning
of a batch at the cost of the maximal
degree within this this giving batch
so we don't don't leak any information
about the private key
further in order to avoid leaking
information
during the computation of a potential
kernel generation point
we compete with the scala
multiplications based on batches
such that the point
uh only depends on the batches and not
on the
individual degrees within the batch
and finally
we have to care about point rejection
probability
since the point rejection for a given
point
depends strongly depends on on on the
degree and this again depends on the
secret choice of a certain ally
within a batch
we have somehow to make sure that
the rejection probability is the same
for all degrees within a batch
and we do this by performing an
additional
coin toss for the given ally
ensuring that for degrees within a batch
the rejection probability 3 is the same
so we then only continue
um
the calculation of the
the isogeny if the respective point
the
respective point is not infinity and
this
new defined
coin toss also succeeds
so let's
finally talk about the achieved speed up
and compare those two
to previous works
we provide different results
on a skylake in order to compare to all
available previous works
since few of the
of the previous works only presents
results for group action
without public evaluation and some
others
because of being implemented in python
doesn't provide clock cycles
and
summarizing you can see that
c-tide
achieves overall
nearly
speed up at two times speed up
in both number of cycles and also in the
number of multiplications
and um
yeah it's
maybe important to know that the clock
cycles results that we present
are achieved were achieved without any
optimization of the underlying
arithmetic
so
to sum up oh sorry
sorry for that so
to sum up um c tides um defines a new
key space for seaside based on on
batching
city
also um
is also a new constant time algorithm
for evaluating the group action using
the
matriarch id and some other ideas
in our work we also formalize the
definition of atomic blocks
we verify the constant time claims using
wall grind and finally we achieve um
significant speed ups compared to
previous works
so
thank you for your attention and
for further information check our code
and our paper
and yeah all right okay thank you very
much thank you um are there questions i
don't see any questions on the zoom tony
do you have anything on the lip
i don't see any questions on the lips
but maybe i can ask one question
so
yes
also
it's like yeah
so fabio you mentioned that
there hasn't been any uh optimization
work
at the lower level and well
how much to expect
a week again if we really do low-level
optimization seriously
um yeah we are working on a project
which is related to this topic and i
think
there is
a lot of things to to do
and considering the fact that we in
terms of seaside we also look for larger
primes
um it may be
[Music]
becomes quite interesting to use
vectorization in the x2 and things like
that
so i think that is
in terms of clock cycles
there is
enough to do in order to speed up this
this
yeah the field may take so so to say
all right
then thanks again and again if there are
more questions coming up then please
feel free to use
thank you guys
okay
so
we can go to the next talk
so the next dog is going to be a compact
power implementation of cca security
exchange mechanism
crystals kyber on fpga
i'm not sure who will be giving a talk
is it effecting
yes
i'm efficient i'll present our work
okay please start yeah oh okay is my
voice clear
yes it's clear
okay
uh dro i'm you fishing the corresponding
author of the paper this work was done
in 2020 when i was pursuing a doctoral
degree in qinghai university china and
suguri was my supervisor
this work is mainly about a hardware
implementation of kyber aiming at a
compact design
using limited number of butterfly units
the background of our work is a crucial
threat from quantum computers to public
key crypto systems currently used in our
daily life
as a result nist launched the pqc
contest in december 2016 and there are
seven finalists and eight candidates
remained in the third round
in this current view these structured
lattice schemes appear to be the most
promising ones
the motivation of our work is the urgent
need for full hardware reference
implementation of finalists
to demonstrate their
potential strengths strengthens and
intrinsic property
there are many hardware software code
designs they are flexible but relatively
they are
with low performance
we select hyper as our research target
it is a mlw based key exchange mechanism
proposed by crystal's team and is one of
the seven finalists in pqc contest
here is the
algorithm description of key generation
phase of a kyber
as we can see the main procedures
include sampling
and entity related calculations in
polynomial multiplications
the entity in hyper is special as there
is no point primitive root of unity in
field zq and the two facts follow the
first the first is
the evaluation process actually divides
into two parts the path with even
indexed coefficients and the part with
all the index coefficients these two
parts share the same
twitter factors and they can be done it
can be conducted concurrently
the second fact is the pointwise
multiplication actually involves five
five multiplications in fields eq
and in our design we adopt corrupt spa
method
and uh in that in such way one
multiplication in fields eq can be
eliminated
from the two facts about a natural idea
is to adopt two cells or butterfly units
each responsible for even or odd part of
polynomial in entity or inttt
while in polynomial well in point wise
multiplication they cooperate with each
other
such that four multiplications involved
can be done in two cycles
denoted as pwm zero phase and pwm one
phase
besides compress and decompress function
in the protocol
can be supported by this unified
butterfly structure as well
several procedures can be rearranged and
merged
for example the addition with e prime
prime
in calculation of v can be deferred into
calculation of c2
in such a way both calculations can be
supported by the unified butterfly
structure saving cycles potentially
we arrange execution order manually the
main principle is to generate necessary
data before they are required by the
entity core
as the sampling order is irregular
conventional state machine would involve
complex control logic and a pre-defined
other table with more suitable here
within the table there are four kinds of
sampling
and the table is sparse
so it costs several luts to store it
this is the top layer architecture of
our design
compared with related hardware designs
the working dfa 20 is more than two
times faster mainly because
they exploit more computation units the
lut-ff eram dsp usage is 1.5 times 2
times 5 times and 4 times larger than
ours
compared with hhlw 20
our design is more than 10 times faster
while the ltff consumption is more than
is 10 times
40 times less than theirs
compared with
hardware software code designs
or design hundreds of times faster
these code designs are all based on risk
5 soft core
and their resource consumption varies in
a large range from only a quarter of
hours
to 3 times more than hours
and the silver is another finalist in
the pqc contest
compared with the working rp-20
timing performance of ours is pretty
close to that in rb20 while the lt and
ff consumption is three times two times
less than they work in rb20
the compactness of our work mainly comes
from three aspects
storage reuse in fujisaki or commodore
transform multi-purpose butterfly units
and the third is
the input output process of catch our
core
is conducted
uh through the shift of inner state cube
result converts to a dedicated long
shift register
the decent performance of our design
comes mainly from two aspects the first
is we arrange execution order property
and the second is several procedures are
rearranged merged and located in
butterfly units same in total cycles
our design has been verified against
kyber's known answer test files and the
whole design has been uploaded to github
to ease comparison and verification from
other research groups
thank you for your attention that's all
my presentation
yeah thank you very much
other questions and i don't see anything
in zoom about this lip
i also don't see any questions from the
look
maybe just one brief question um could
you comment briefly on side channel
security msca false is there anything
special in your design
uh
uh sorry i can't quite hear you
yesterday
comment on side channel security
uh security of our design
side channel security yes
uh
what's security
site channel
okay if
it takes a long time then maybe you can
just move on
uh
so
why is it not clear maybe maybe you can
type in the chat chat chat
then we'll just suggest that we remove
any questions further questions and too
later on via youtube or by continuing
contacting the authors thank you again
very much
oh thank you
okay then we can continue with the next
talk
there will be side channel protections
for picnic signatures
and the talk is going to give them to be
given by
okan seeker
[Music]
um hello everyone um i hope you can hear
me and um
see the slides also yes we can okay okay
that's great um so hello everyone and i
would like to thank you for the
introduction again so this target is
based on on a joint work with diego
harana kira takaishi from arose
university and sebastian bird thomas is
from university of quebec and greg
savarucha from microsoft research i'm a
consecutive and fro and and i will be
talking about an overview of our main
results
so i would like to jump directly into
the into our contribution uh firstly we
identify two types of sites and
vulnerabilities of picnic tree which is
an alternate candidate in the next
post quantum project so while the first
one is a direct adaptation of the
previous attack on the picnic one the
the second attack is is is is novel and
exploits the specific properties of mpc
indeed with purposes pre-processing
predicate as a counter measure we
suggest a generic approach to mask zero
proof using using this
is using mpc indeed
with pre-processing in the paper we
prove uh that our masking
mask sign in sign operation satisfies
masking circuit notions called t-second
necessity security probing security
and we further support our claim using
formal verification tool uh by mass
curve um so then we apply uh our generic
so then we then we apply our generic
masking counter measure to picnic tree
so that we can achieve a first order
mask implementation as a site
contribution we also publicly release
mask charter implementation and
used as a building block for our for our
scheme and we finally conclude with with
practical uh electromagnetic such a
leakage analysis
so let's jump into into interpreting
through with pro processing so in this
extended
particular mpc
mpc protocol is divided into two phases
the first one is offline fees meaning
that it can be executed independently of
any input values and parties use their
random seeds to
pre-process the state information so
then the online phase then in the online
phase the parties can efficiently
perform the actual competition by making
use of the pro pre-processed states
once mpc is is done the approver
approve prover commit spot on manual
flying phases
now the challenges has two dimensions
the first part b indicates whether
offline or online phase is is is to be
revealed and in the former case the the
prover simply opens all the random seats
and use
uh the offline computation uh and which
contains no sensitive information
so if the online feed is available the
prover essentially opens all but one
views uh
as usual and
and and verify um and verify verifier
checks the either the on offline or
online phase is executed correctly
however you can notice that the the this
online offline product is actually
produce a another attack surface that
can be exploited by such an adversaries
as it has been shown that the open
values act as free props for an
adversary
so on a high level our country
countermeasure
the prover essentially shares the share
concretely each party shares is split
into again shares and every party
internally does does the competition in
ms way accordingly all the views are
maintained in a secret shared form until
the prover learns the challenge
once you obtain the challenge either she
can keep them
keep them in a secret shared form when
offline phase is revealed or
she can only reconstruct the leaves of
the open parties when the online phase
is revealed
this way even if the adversary gets an
information
of some share there is always at least
one share of the vf that remains
completely hidden so with this approach
we don't need to change the number of
parties so it neither breaks the inter
interoperability with existing
verification algorithm nor introduces
any overhead in signature size due to
the masking
while we can prove it amidst the
standard
masking circuit noise so let me start
with some performance of our
implementation so in this table you can
see the benchmark results
and the interesting column is overhead
the highlighted row corresponds to the
unproctered unprotected picnic
implementation and hashing you can see
covers 70 of the operations
so by adapting the masking technique
of shatri we managed to reduce the
overhead from 1.8 from 5.4 we provide
some heuristic options to partially
unmask some
non-sensitive hash computations by
regarding sha-3 as a random oracle here
you can use fuller probable secure
masking and mask every hashing or you
can selectively choose hash function and
mask only the sensing ones
although we are losing the tt probing
security guarantee we are able to
experimentally confirm that no leakage
occurs from this heuristic version of
the implementation so i would like to
continue with the practical setup in
this picture you can see an overview
overview of our setup as our target
device we have used stm32 discovery
board which is suggested by the pkm4
project with an arm cortex m4
and for our side channel source we have
chosen a blocking capacitor as seen in
the picture and placed our
electromagnetic prop close that point
and our goal in this analysis is is to
first show that
the describe attacks in in the earlier
parts of our presentation are indeed
possible and of course show that our
mask picnic the implementation is
leakage-free so in in so in the novel
offline phase attack we implement random
versus driving test to see and actually
verify the leakages inside the unprotect
unprotected picnic tree implementation
here you can see the highlighted values
are opened
we have measured a single online
simulation and using the highlighted
values we managed to see the leakage and
verify the attack the attack on an open
phase moreover we can see that the
leakage is is actually clear with less
than 3000 traces
next we proceed with the with the
leakage analysis of mask chatri so in
this case we use a fixed versus random
setting and hash a random value or a
fixed value
first of all
as a cylinder check uh we we we disable
the masking by forcing mask value to
zero you can see that the leakage is
everywhere and on top of the
implementation and becomes a skyrocket
even with 2000 traces and when we enable
the massing again
we see that the liquids are gone uh gone
even with one million traces and there
is no leakage and finally of course we
would like to do the in uh leakage
analysis of whole picnic tree
implementation and we measured from the
beginning until the end of us
until the end of the first mpc instance
this includes an offline online phase
so we work with fixed versus random step
we have observed that the test results
below the threshold will be for all
eight
million um eight billion sample points
and moreover
you observe that the the t test value
has a stable pattern and remark that
from the previous example uh we know
that a real leakage has a clear
increasing uh pattern with a small
number of traces
um so this is the summary of our
contribution again uh so i would like to
thank you again for your for your
attention if you have any questions or
comments we can glad to answer them and
you can find our our implementation in
in
github or in our artifact page and you
can easily implement those in using the
pkm4 project thank you very much
okay i see one question from the zulic
chat
the question is regarding the next
uh chart3 was it hardened and evaluated
by pvla
if yes for which platform
this would be an interesting component
for fair comparison between post content
crypto schemes
yes so uh for for our setup we use
uh stm32 discovery board and
we use the tvla and this is the results
for the tv lay so this is the t-test
results values we use a fixed versus red
setup for it and so here we can see that
it's it's leakage because mask is the
mask is disabled and the left-hand side
is tvla results
for the shot tree using
regular masking basically and this is
for one million twists
and for our uh for our test for our
target devices as i said stm32 with arm
cortex m4
and you can find the details on on in
the pqm4 project
okay and i guess there's no question
from them also
no i don't see any questions
all right
okay thank you very much
thank you
then let's continue with the last talk
of this session
and it will be
batching seaside group actions using avx
and the speaker is going to be
your home
sorry i cannot pronounce your surname so
yeah
so thank you
for the introduction i will now share my
screen
okay i suppose you can see my slides now
okay
so we have already heard earlier in this
session that c-size has a number of
interesting
properties for example it can serve as a
drop-in replacement for pre-quantum
elliptic curve defailing exchange
but there are also some downsides of
seaside and the main disadvantage is the
high computational cost of the group
action
so as you can see here on the slide
a typical implementation that was state
of the art
when we wrote the paper so a typical
implementation of the seaside 512 group
action evaluation uh takes around 240
million cycles on a skylake processor
which is uh more than 2000 times more
than for example a variable variable
base scalar multiplication on x 2 255.19
and this high computational cost of
seaside
causes a lot of problems when we then
really start to replace pre-quantum ecth
by seaside for example in security
protocols like tls
so we will
we will see problems um on both the
client side on the server side of tls
so one problem that we will see on the
client side is that the key exchange
will cause significantly increased delay
especially when you when your client
runs on a device where you don't have a
super super powerful processor
and on the other hand what the problem
that we will see on the server side is
that the throughput of the server goes
down significantly
which means we can
process fewer key exchanges per second
so when
well um i mean since fabio earlier
already gave a nice overview of
of of seaside i think i can safely skip
these slides
so when we started our work on seaside
uh we first had a look at all the
existing papers that existed and that
were even at that time quite a lot of
papers already and we also looked at the
implementations
that were available at that time and we
found that one implementation is
particularly relevant for our work and
that is the implementation of cervantes
vasquez
from a paper that was presented at latin
crypt 2019
and we used the source code of this of
this implementation as a starting point
for our work
so basically what we did is
that we
tried to continue the line of research
that you saw in the previous slide which
means we tried to improve the efficiency
of seaside 512 group action evaluations
and we we try to do this with the help
of of avx 512 vector instructions
so in what we describe in the paper is
is a number of implementations of of the
group action so we have a high
throughput implementation um that
processes a batch of eight instances of
seaside group action
uh in in in a vector parallel fashion
so this is this implementation
tries to maximize the throughput
and
such an implementation can be useful for
example for server-side tls processing
when you integrate
c site in the tls server or it can also
be useful for
signature schemes that have to evaluate
several group actions
furthermore we have a low latency
implementation and this latency
implementation tries to minimize the
execution time of one instance of a
seaside 512 group action and this could
be useful for
for
client-side tls processing
and we implemented both are using
standard abx 512 instructions and also
the afm a ifma extensions to avx-512
so
abx-512
gives you
or extends the intel architecture by 512
12-bit vector instructions
so this
follows the single instruction multiple
data principle
and when you use avx 512 for prime field
arithmetic what you usually do is that
you represent your operands in an area
of limbs
and usually these limbs are less than 32
bits long similar as in avx2 and in our
case we used 29 bit limbs
on the other hand if if your target
device your target processor also
supports these ifma instructions you can
increase the limb size to up to 52-bit
up to 52 bits
so ifma stands for integer fused
multiply and add
and
this this ifma extensions which is
basically the extension of avx-512
it comes with a couple of instructions
that are very useful for field
arithmetic
because it it comes with instructions
that allow you to multiply 52-bit limbs
and add either the higher part or the
lower part of the product to a 64-bit
value
so when you can use 52-bit limbs of
course that means that the number of
limbs will be much smaller so in our
case we would need only 10 limbs instead
of 18 limbs when we only use standard
abx 512 instructions
so
what you will see here on the right side
is is a very high level algorithmic
description of the group action
evaluation and much simplified of course
and
what makes problems when you want to
implement that
is
certain conditional statements like as
you can see here one example of such a
statement this is this if then if then
statement that is printed here in red
so basically uh this checks whether the
kernel point is is the identity element
um
and we use twisted edwards curves so we
we check here whether it is the neutral
point and
if it is not then we perform a certain
number of operations
and these conditional statements here
are a big problem not only
regarding
timing attacks but they are also a
problem for our throughput optimized
implementation where we
execute a batch of eight instances of
seaside
and and since we
execute these eight instances in a
vector parallel fashion
it is required that each instance always
executes exactly the same operations as
the other seven instances and this is of
course a problem when you have
conditional statements like this
and in order to overcome this problem we
developed
three batching strategies
with which we try to get rid of these
conditional statements
up here and we are getting towards the
end of the session and two into the next
session
yes so so we developed three batching
strategies that we call the extra dummy
batching method extra infinity patching
method and the combined method
um just a few more words about the high
throughput implementation so we
implemented these three patching methods
and at the lower level at the feed
arithmetic level
we do it in eight times one way parallel
fashion which means we always execute
eight field multiplication and then each
multiplication uses a single 64-bit
element of a 5-12-bit vector
the low-latency implementation at the
lower level at the field arithmetic
level uses a 2 times 4-way parallel
implementation which means we execute
two field multiplications and each
multiplication uses four 64-bit elements
of the drive twelve bit vector
so then let's have a look finally at the
results
so what you see
i think the most interesting results are
at the bottom
the last five rows where you can see the
results for our implementation when we
use the ifma instructions
and as you can see here we can
we can compute a batch of eight seaside
group action evaluations in about
447 million clock cycles
um on an iceland cpu which is around
3.64 times faster than than state of the
art non-vectorized implementations and
our low latency our
implementation also achieves an ice
speed up by a factor of around 1.54 to
non-vectorized implementations
so that's it thank you
all right thank you very much sorry for
speeding you up in the end um since we
are really out of time for this session
i would suggest to maybe move any
questions and to zulip and preemie
yeah great okay and then i would um yeah
i guess that concludes this session
sorry for for taking extra time and then
writing up some minutes from the next
session and yeah i hope to see you all
again for the third part of postman
crypto on friday goodbye