okay go ahead
basically i just unmuted myself to say
that it's the general chairs who will
close the conference and not the program
chips
uh okay uh ben do you want to say
something
no go ahead bro it's yours
okay um so let me also share in the
screen
children
i think that's this one
um
oops oops sorry
can you see my slides yes yes that's
good
okay
so
sorry this i didn't change this to this
should be closing remarks
so um before
before we
get close i want to also share with you
some fun facts so
when we started this conference uh on
monday we got 450 participants
and these are the graphs
up to now we have
533 registrations
so we got uh 83 more registrations
during this conference
um
17 students registrations also so
this is good we are very happy that we
reached 533 registrations
uh but this is a good part of uh you
know having a virtual conference
so next year
um let me go to this one so next year we
will be welcoming you uh in beijing also
in september um so 11th is sunday so if
you arrive on sunday we have receptions
real receptions not virtual reception
and you know everything we hope to you
know to get um
everything physical right so
um
and also for uh for registrations uh
next year please do register before the
conference so that we can make sure we
have enough drinks and food for you
um with that said uh i want to thank
everybody again uh so i won't repeat but
you know what uh what i mean i want to
thank everybody for making this event
possible and i think we had a great
event next year i will see you in
beijing thank you very
much i think we have um
i think we still have some slots in the
in the social rooms for the final social
hour right
yes
the idea was to go to the social rooms
at this point
to have a final wrap-up and maybe a
final drink i feel now i'm quite relaxed
i don't know about you guys
i think this is a good time to thank our
general chairs and program chairs and
everything because for two times in a
row we tried to go to beijing now and it
was kind of complicated but maybe
yeah next year it will work yeah it's
very sad for them i mean we all wanted
to go and and see it but uh
hopefully next year thank you for being
so patient
we keep trying
it will happen yeah
and i hope that uh bart can come with
the big band we can find
that's pretty complicated
[Music]
okay
so we are joining the
the social room again right yep i'm
going back there see you later everyone
all right bye everyone here the social
room