ready to go have a good session
okay
um well i'm happy to announce our first
um invited speaker for chess 2021
um cabela trokoso
will give a talk um she's an assistant
professor at epfl
where she heads the spring lab
her research covers a wide range of
topics that are essential to enable the
development of technology that can be
used to build socially responsible
systems
most of our work focuses on analyzing
building and deploying secure and
privacy
uh
preserving systems
she has been named 40 under 40 in
technology by 42 by fortune in 2020 for
her work on contact tracing apps i think
that's where most of us know her from
um and she will give a talk about
hardware for privacy engineering so with
that carella the floor is yours
thank you very much elkin thank you
peter for this uh invitation that made
me very nervous because as elka said i'm
a very privacy person i'm an ordinal
hardwood person
uh when they wrote to me i i said you
got the wrong address um like why were
you inviting me to give the talk at
chess
and they said well i would really like
to have a talk in which somebody brings
a new topic and the needs of this new
topic from the hardware side
so here is my attempt to reduce that and
i hope
i have fulfilled
uh what they asked me to do and i really
hope that you find this interesting and
it actually inspired you to
to open your horizons about what kind of
of how would you design and decide more
things that that us from the privacy
engineering domain can take
as i have to say i'm very sad that the
you know chess always happens in very
exotic places like japan and things like
this and these guys just invited me
today that we're talking but uh we'll
talk about it some of that
so why do we do privacy
well what is this privacy thing all
about right we live in this digital
world in which more and more all of our
interactions are just dealt by digital
things well this conference is one
example right but we do music
not anymore on cities but on spotify we
talk with our oven to ask the oven to
hit before we're going home
uh we don't ask for a taxi with hand in
the street you ask for an uber and so
forth and so forth
and all of these technologies we know
that you know how they get all of this
data but what we do when we do it and we
start to feel like we live
under the big eye of sorrow
and this is uncomfortable but what we
really fear like in the movie it's not
the eye nobody was trying to destroy the
eye we were trying to destroy the ring
because the ring the thing that gives
the power to dominate it all and that is
data that's what happens when we put our
lives on someone and someone can read
our souls when someone with what we like
what we do the next thing we're going to
do and they can predict it and not only
predict it but then also
influence it and i'm
thinking for instance about the
cambridge analytica facebook scandal
where it was like the first time that
all of the fears that privacy advocates
had said like when someone has a lot of
your data they can start
controlling and manipulating you came
the place and well it happened after
that is history
and in the words of salaf right
parts of what makes society a good place
in which to leave is the extent to which
uh it allows people freedom from
interception orders as i said from
manipulation for implications right
whenever we want privacy we don't say we
want privacy because we don't want
people to know our secrets or we don't
want people to know we just don't want
to hear what they have to say we don't
want them to judge us we don't want them
to change us
because they know privacy information so
what we really want is to not have the
consequences of losing our privacy
and indeed a society without privacy in
which everything would be known and we
would be judged all the time and we
could be manipulated all the time
because everybody knows our deepest
wishes could be suffocation it's not a
place where we want to live so
once we all agree we don't want the ring
to be built
um we have a goal the goal is privacy by
design
and a while ago
a lot of people back in the in the sense
this is the hype start everybody was
like we want privacy and policymakers
started to push this very hard right we
have here some quotes from the uh data
protection office in ontario in canada
which was one of the first strong
proponents of this privacy the design
concept of here record from the gdpr
about how you know from the start of the
system we need to implement appropriate
technical organizational measures have
the ftc saying that we should
incorporate substantial privacy
protection on the practices
and all of those things all of these
things are great and we all love them
but you know as a privacy engineer and
especially when i was working for
industry and i had a team and people
were reading all of these things they
were looking at me and it was really
like okay this really feels like this
uh you know
he just assists them now with the
freaking privacy on it
and
so with with them with my colleagues
claudia and said a while ago we started
to think about how can we help engineers
to move from the
circles to the o
and in the beginning uh we published a
paper that says that it was all about
data minimization what we do is to build
systems without data because the least
data that is in the system the more
privacy preserving it is and this was
very celebrated and people like it very
much especially on the on the policy
side because it was clearly related to
data protection regulation principle the
principle of data minimization
and everybody could understand this but
when we're working a bit further on on
how to articulate what we do to build
systems we discover that really data is
not minimized in the system as a whole
because whenever we build a privacy
preserving system data still exists it
may exist only in the user device it may
exist encrypted to the server where only
the client has the key or where we
encrypt it with some
advanced cryptography so that we can
make operations with it we can
distribute it over multiple servers but
at the end of the day
data still exists so just talking about
minimizing data it's really not a good
metaphor to just explain to your
engineers how they have to think to
actually fulfill this idea of privacy by
design
so we went back to the drawing board and
to think about more
what what is it that people that work in
academia and privacy
do when they design this wonderful
privacy preserving system
and we came to the realization that what
we actually do is to minimize the
privacy risks and we do that by
minimizing the trust assumptions on
others
in many places trust is considered a
good thing in the sense that you know if
i can trust you that's good but from a
privacy perspective the least i need to
trust you the more sure i am that you're
not going to violate my privacy
and kind of the key here is this on
other entities and this is what kind of
differentiates a little bit the the the
kind of things
that uh privacy engineers do more here
on divide on the privacy enhancing
technology side from maybe euros like in
the sense of who are we trying to
protect
from in general we're used to this kind
of third-party privacy that's what we
have in social networks where we trust
um
when we trust the provider but then we
don't trust other users or the third
parties and we have all this access
control right right now we're having
this uh there was this conversation
about zoom how we don't trust zoom but
well i mean we need to trust it and then
we trust that zoom is not gonna
broadcast everything we said to others
and because we may don't trust very much
so came the regulatory approaches to try
to put some
pressure on the provider from the legal
side they would have fines if they end
up leaking something and things like
this but actually from a privacy
perspective we would like to live here
the place in which we don't trust anyone
and now the question is how we do this
thing how we
how we move this trust we also
discovered that when we just say this
thing to people it doesn't really uh
doesn't really hit
the way in which they think like they
are still kind of a bit lost engineers
about how to how to reason about this
so um
what we with we discovered is that
actually what we do
as as private engineers is a lot
uh about another actually regulatory
principle the principle of purpose
limitation so when i write here the
usual approach is that the kind of
approach that we we have to build the
system and we mean like
the uh
broad computer science community
and you can see this already if many of
you are actually professors of computer
science or of similar discipline at the
university where you teach your students
the first times they program right when
they think about the program they think
okay i'm going to collect everything
everything i have
and then i'll do operations with
and that's also how people want to build
systems normally think about something
okay let's just collect all of the
things that are possible we don't care
and then it turns out it comes data
protection and you know the tribulation
minimization principle and you know
you cannot collect everything you want
because it has to be kind of associated
with your purpose so you end up
collecting leslie and that's most of the
systems that we have actually anything
that passes through the data protection
fund
but the privacy engineers think in a
very different way what we think is
about first what is the purpose of the
application
then we think exactly about what is the
data that i need for the purpose
and then um because there are other
operational purposes like you cannot
build systems without you know linking
things together and
creating servers and maybe there are
other legal requirements for
accountability and things like that and
you end up needing to to collect other
things the social security by the way we
need to fulfill so sometimes you may
need to collect a bit more data than
what is needed for the purpose you so
you will collect a bit more and to avoid
that the data that you
have to collect more for this
operational core process is where we put
privacy enhancing technologies to ensure
that the purpose is still fulfilled and
as one example
uh back in the two tens we built this
private csg drive uh scheme
in which we thought like if you have to
pay for how much you drive what is the
exact data that you need
and actually the only data that you need
to pay is to know the final amount of
the bill
the rest of the things that appear on a
bill are in general actually kind of
accountability and checks but it's not
the information that you need
and then that would be kind of the
minimal amount and to really build the
system and ensure that people could not
cheat and all of those things we
actually had to create a log the lock
had to be privacy preserving so we had
to encrypt it and that's how we ended up
with a system that had a bit more data
than the amount to build but it's still
much less data than any system that you
could collect that would actually gather
all of the gps data for the vehicles and
then maybe reduce it somewhere but it
could always be less than
so in this sense the idea of
limited purpose from a technological
perspective
limits actually the need of trust
because if all the data i give you
you cannot use it for anything else than
exactly the purpose i said to you i
don't need to trust you for that you're
not going to misuse it it's just going
to happen so this is kind of a good
metaphor to explain to people how to
think about privacy services
and that made me very happy right
because now i have a way to teach my
students about how to think uh in this
complex way that took me like
almost 20 years now of being working on
this topic to really understand uh what
is it that am i doing
and this is great we have now something
we have a tool to reason about these
systems and this is actually what you
see in
most of the academic literature but
people at the end of the day the
introduction of the paper says this is
the problem i have this is the only data
i need and then they spend all of the
rest of the section putting a lot of
technical details to just convince you
that they actually have fulfilled their
purpose with very little amount of data
by means of super cool crypto and other
stuff
and this actually
is very similar to to what would be a
waterfall software development where you
establish the requirements and then you
design the system to develop verify it
deploy it and maintain and you can read
these as you know
intro of the paper section one
um
system model
uh implementation of the system like an
instantiation evaluation and well we
don't deployment
but but you see how this goes but it
turns out that in the world we live
today this is called the past
nobody anymore actually uses this kind
of a waterfall right we now live in an
ideal world in which this idea that the
requirement phase happens at the very
beginning and then you just you know
waterfall design and deploy does not
happen sign is agile the requirements
change over time
and also we don't live in in a in a
system that where we control everything
as we do on the papers where we just
control the full stack you know i think
we now people deploy in this thing as a
service deploys over services in which
your design is not only constrained uh
with what you know what you can do and
your requirements but it's also
constrained by with these little blocks
that you're going to use as a service
whatever is an app
it is a service an authentication
service it is um
the cloud that is going to give you an
api and you are constrained by all of
those and those also affect your privacy
capabilities because if the api does not
offer what you want i mean you may want
to have
excellent crypto but if the api does not
offer it
it doesn't matter that you know all
about privacy preserving protocols you
just cannot build it and underline all
of these here infrastructure as a
service there is actually hardware it is
actually the chip
that uh infrastructure builds on that
the platform builds on software builds
on and that also constrains what each of
these elements can do
and just to show a little bit um how the
difference between having the freedom
like to be here as a privacy engineer or
not having so much freedom let me talk
about two projects that my lab developed
in the last two years uh on the left we
have a data share this is a
decentralized search engine
for investigative journalists we had a
two-year collaboration with the
international consumption of
investigative journalists the guys of
the luxembourg leagues the guys of the
panama papers
and they came to us and they say we have
a ton of electronic documents and we
would like to be able to search on each
other's collection because we find it
very useful but we're very scared of
putting them out there because they
actually can get us killed right these
guys have all of these leaks like
imagine snowden had just gone with the
pile of documents and just put it it on
the search engine for everybody to look
uh for things
for
uh before he left right
and and we built for them a system that
is uh currently being implemented
hopefully deployed by early next year
uh covet pandemic always the latest
things
and here what we had it was a complete
blank slate for design right this guy
said you can build anything we don't
have an infrastructure we don't have
anything so just you guys which are the
the privacy expert that what would you
do and in the sense we had a total
control of this tag i hear for total
quote unquote because we still have to
use the internet which is not something
that we can completely redesign
from scratch and also the journalists
don't have their own clouds and their
own things they still use
amazon web services so there are some
things that we will limit
but because we have this total control
and freedom we had space to deploy any
crypto we wanted and in fact we deployed
very novel protocols for them and
a new way of combining privacy
preserving protocols to solving their
problems
like because we also had a space to
design a whole system had a space to put
anonymous communications their anonymous
authentication all of it was great
on the other side like for the last year
and a half by spending this frantic
design of context raising up
and here we had to design very fast and
we had to design for something people
already had on their pockets
and that meant that our design was based
on existing components right an existing
on the phone the operative system had to
be existing on uh
on existing communications so we had to
use ble it tessa that ble has a payload
of 16 bytes well off you go like all
your crypto is actually limited to
having 16 bytes of payload believe me
that limits a lot of the kind of fancy
things we can do and the level of
security we can get we had to rely on
the services that the mobile and the
cloud gave us at the moment that google
and apple decided we're gonna implement
the protocol insight and give you an api
that's completely limited like there was
little space for our own crypto we
designed the protocol they took it they
put it down and that's the limit of our
of our power and also meant that the
end-to-end design space was completely
limited with what they said because if
this api gets a signature and the
signature is in the format that they
want you cannot now go fancy and use
group signatures or anonymous signatures
you have to use whatever they tell you
right and all of these things actually
completely change so this is to say that
whatever you put at the end of the day
and the lowest level in the hard work is
going to have an implication on what how
and how much we can build at the top
so with this
i'm started my
wish list
of things that would be great to have
and it would be great to start having
hardware that supports it because that
will also push
up up the stack like in the platform as
a service in the absence service more
and more libraries and capabilities to
use the things that we want to use as
privacy engineers and the first thing um
is well i really would like to have a
hardware crypto swiss knife that is
actually tailored to the needs of
privacy preserving protocols
and let me present you a couple of
cryptographic tools that we that we use
very much to use privacy preserving
systems and because i'm not a
photographer i'm not going to embarrass
myself going in the details of the
crypto and but i'm not just going to
give you pointers to what are the names
of these technologies which are these
key key keywords that if you're
interested in building technologies for
this you can go
and and google and find it in in
different uh
general
neural security conference or privacy
conferences and then you will find the
details of the crypto and i trust you
guys that you are the best that's
actually taking any crypto and put it
on a hardware implementation
so the first one i want to talk about is
private intersection which allows us to
to actually learn about the intersection
of two sets
without learning about anything else
that is not in the intersection we can
even go further and just learn some the
cardinality of the intersection even
without knowing what are the elements in
the intersection let alone elements that
are not in the intersection
and this has a lot of applications for
private content discovery like for
instance whatsapp contacts like who are
my contacts and what are the numbers uh
in the big database of whatsapp private
search this is actually what is
underlined apple see some very
controversial detection happy to talk
about it on the q a if you are
into that uh it is actually what is
behind our designing data share it can
be used for intrusion detection so the
two companies can compare an intrusion
logs without and unlearn
what are the common attacks within
knowing anything else about the rest of
the logs and has many more applications
and this kind of private set
intersections they are either based on
modulus pronunciation vcc which is a lot
of hashing
not necessarily
the the most common hashes that depends
on how exactly you want to build some of
them uh build a multi-party computation
uh mostly two-party computation because
in general these are thought about two
parties building an intersection
uh some of them are based on oblivious
pref which of course built on hashes and
cc but built in particular ways
and
because when we built these protocols we
not only think about about the hardcore
crypto but also that we need to put them
on a system and on a system we need to
make sure
that all of this is efficient and works
and a bunch of these things are not
efficient at all and because we don't
have a hardware acceleration or anything
they're just not efficient and we need
to use other tricks so one trick and
very common the private sector
intersection protocols is the use of
cuckoo filters which are the um clever
brother of the bloom filters if you want
to see them like that and we use those
for efficiency communication and speed
um
now maybe uh if
we're going to have more acceleration
hardware we don't need the trick anymore
but maybe you do so actually the input
to the protocol
at the hardware level is not going to be
messages as you think it's actually come
in a different format
and also um we do these operations but
running the whole protocol uh it doesn't
require one exponentiation it requires
one per element in the data set so we
need to run this
little
primitives here but we need to run them
many many many many times in order for
this uh to actually
and these are the kind of things that
when we just think about uh
the primitives we may think about okay
i'm gonna make this faster but sometimes
it's not only about making them faster
it's also about thinking what is going
to come surrounding and kind of code
assign those in a way that the whole
protocol is actually efficient and fast
which is actually what we need to be
able to put them in our systems
then we also have private information
retrieval which allows us to retrieve an
element from a database without telling
the database which element we retrieve
and this can be used for private
messaging so that you can retrieve
messages from
from a mailbox without telling
the
the mailbox which message you're
interested on or certificate
transparency so that you can retrieve
which certificates you want to check
without telling database of certificates
which thing you're browsing for private
media browsing for many of these things
and there are two flavors of private
information retrieval computational
which is actually securities based on
computational assumptions or information
theoretical which is about distributed
sets and
distributing the data on several servers
and then do some operations information
theoretically it's more secure it's just
information theoretically secure but you
know what um
i love all of these multi-party
computation things but when you want to
deploy in reality there are so very few
moments where you actually do have
uh non-colluding servers i'm sorry guys
i'm sorry to break this to you but in
practice this disappears really happens
uh for instance in the project with the
journalist right where people were like
oh why don't you do super fancy npc like
because these guys don't have two
servers like when we
talk about this possibility they said oh
yeah we can spin two instances on amazon
i was like ah it's not gonna cut it
right but you cannot expect that
different journalists in the world they
actually have one server one in each
jurisdiction right one in brazil one in
the uk
and i was going to say one in canada
it's kind of the same
one in china they don't have that they
only have one instance in amazon web
service so when you go for
deploying these things you mostly go for
the kind of one server thing even though
there's a lot of literature on the rest
but you know
that is the one that actually can hit
reality
and protocols of this sense are based
mainly on morphic encryption there's
some fancy that use something else and
that means that we mostly need lattice
that's right that's how morphic
decryption is built nowadays and um it's
better very little support for uh
lattices on hardware
and again here to make all of this
efficient uh we see how people use again
a lot of strategies to a lot of
strategies to represent data in a
different way like spacking and batching
so that they can compute
many things at the same time because it
will require
many operations on the server side
remember that you don't want to tell the
server what message you have touched and
this already gives you an idea that
you're going to have to touch a bunch of
them
if you really don't want to reveal which
one is the one of your interest
so you're going to have to do many
operations and these operations are
expensive so either due to this packing
invention or people nowadays are moving
to offline phases of pre-processing um
and this is actually also very
interesting right because you tell us
that that we have in many privacy
perspective protocols kind of two phases
one phase where maybe we don't care if
it's so energy efficient or so slow
because it's gonna be offline right so
we can actually spend uh maybe
more time doing it maybe we want to be
very energy efficient but we don't mind
if it is for one day you have to go
pre-processing all of these things
because it's a one-time cost but then
you need something very fast online and
this kind of two separate things may
actually result on very different
hardware designs but both of them are
going to help when combined to actually
uh allows us to use this kind of
primitives
very well in the wild
another one that we use a lot a lot
a lot is attributes based potential
because it allows us to do anonymous
authentication
look we can build end-to-end privacy
preserving systems without having a way
to authenticate without having a way of
actually preventing
and malicious users from uh coming into
the system
and a way of doing this is using this
kind of technology that is mainly based
on zero knowledge proofs and
green signatures sometimes it's an or
sometimes we can get away with just
doing the blind signatures and this
allows to prove in zero knowledge that
you're actually an authorized member
and to do these proofs we need to do a
lot of operations again by the moderate
explanations of the curves we're going
to use a lot of hash functions and
recently with a ton of bilinear pairings
by
are starting to be the kind of of the
core of most privacy preserving
protocols they have very nice properties
that allow them to be very flexible and
we can construct a very nice kind of
proofs with them
ah but they are also very expensive and
very hard to program and it would be
great to have an extractions and when we
have attributes with credentials kind of
the very basic is to just prove one
attribute i'm a member of this thing i'm
older than 18.
but actually there are very fancy
protocols that achieve
cooler things like the capability to
revoke
again you think about building
end-to-end systems and deploying them in
reality revocation is a must
um
limited usage so i'm going to give you
an anonymous credential that you can
only use one time or two times and again
each of these things kind of come with a
little bit more crypto and each step is
great it allows more functionality but
also makes them more prohibitive
and here we have something that as
opposed to before we don't require many
operations
only one operation on the client you
construct the proof only one operation
on the server to verify the proof but
both of these are expensive depending on
the anonymous credential and the serial
knowledge proof it may be that you put
more weight on the client on the server
or you distribute but at the end of the
day one of them is going to be expensive
and therefore this kind of technology is
kind of hard many times to put out there
especially if we are going to put them
in smart cards that really don't have
much but
and there are many more of these of this
crypto that we use i just gave some
examples of the ones that are
very much used and that if you see
systems kind of all of them peak that's
many of these but all of the other all
of the other fancy protocols at the end
of the day the underlying building
blocks like the primitives you saw that
in my three examples i've studied
studied i already started to repeat what
are the needs are mostly common at the
end of the day all of them have the same
structure but the same primitives they
are used in slightly different ways it
is not that we have infinite of them
and that also means that the bottlenecks
are common and if you want to know more
about how this is used uh go to the
procedures of pets usenix ccs uh smp and
i encourage you to not to look at the
crypto papers there but actually look at
the privacy preserving systems in those
in those
papers and see how they use these
protocols how they combine them to
really understand the needs beyond
the crypto itself
so okay we have to these things so why
there is no privacy right they have said
before it's because it is very hard to
deport them in privacy they are based
typically in non-standard
use of cryptographic primitives
like i have mentioned is not that that
other people don't use ecc's the other
people or other schemes that use
moderate pronunciation but this is an
understanded use and therefore we cannot
use the implementation that out there so
they end up uh uh
you know there are mainly academic
primitives that nobody really works on
in the real world so there are very few
software libraries and the ones that
exist they need to build from scratch
because there is no hardware support
there is nothing underlying them they
have to implement all of the little
things and there but being a slow and
also
this library is sadly enough they have
subordinate support because they are
they are not built really by by
companies they are mostly built by
academia
and either they are very slow
because there is no hardware
acceleration we need to do everything in
software and these operations are very
very expensive because hardware
acceleration um
mainly focus on the mainstream
as rsa
also ecc but on these particular use
cases that i'm sorry it's not what we
need it's not how we use those
primitives and actually if you look in
the literature having people actually uh
read
uh kind of misusing sometimes these apis
so you can actually take
an rsa accelerator and misuse it
quote-unquote the api to actually build
a fast anonymous anonymous
authentication
but you know we wouldn't like to have to
go and reverse engineer how these things
work and find a way of misusing the apis
it could be great if we have apis that
actually allow us to build privacy
preserving systems
and many of these primitives are also
very energy consuming and there is no
efficient implementation because there
is no way we can do this uh only
software and that means that they become
absolutely prohibitive to do uh to put
anywhere that you actually don't have a
a power cord on it like the internet of
things
so what can you do for us one what would
be great
uh build hardware support
right build accelerators for for this
kind of uses uh of primitives for the
primitives that so far don't exist like
the linear pairings would be great right
if we could have some of those
and when you think about building this
hardware think both about putting it on
the normal processors that we have in
commodity devices because we want to
build these things
on the phone and on the laptop but also
think about how can we put it in
independent devices because as i said
very early in the talk right one of the
things that um
we don't want
where we want privacy is to about avoid
the power power that others can accept
and would you only put all of these
primitives on the mainstream uh devices
it actually means that privacy engineers
is still
under the control of the operative
service provider and this is the example
of the contact tracing apps
right even if you put there at the end
of the day they are going to be the one
that showed the
api to us and we're still going to be
limited so it's great if we can start to
separate and build independent devices
that allow us to actually escape from
the control of the googles and the
apples and the microsofts of the world
and then
let's build some energy efficient
implementations so that we can put this
even for phones right as you will know
everybody hates when the battery is
trained uh
very fast and some of them we're going
to need them fast because some of the
protocols we do
actually are for real kind of real-time
implementations or rather have speed
constraints again concentration up is an
example
some of them we want them small and very
efficient
for this iot of online phases or we just
want them to be
to be not consuming very much battery
but we don't really care about speed
like when we built this thing for the
for the journalists
uh
as opposed to other uh
psi protocols like the main thing for
contact discovery for instance what's up
is how fast you can go through this huge
list on the server of contacts
the journalists done this fast right
they want something to search and you
know waiting for one day to be able to
search on all of the journalists
collections of the world
that
if you don't wait you just can't get
zero capability to do that it's
perfectly fine for many privacy
preserving applications speed is not
actually a constraint
and it's again i think a a way of going
back and thinking about what is the
purpose of my application and what are
the
and what are the requirements because
we're many times nowadays very very um
very oriented by the goals of the
googles and the apples of the big tech
that tells us you know what are the
needs and they actually want to do real
time and and everything for them is kind
of large scale
but many people that actually need
privacy at a much smaller scale and they
are not always in a hurry so actually
building for different trade-offs can be
extremely useful when you talk with
privacy engineers and for some we're not
i'm here with my wish list we went both
fast small and very efficient off you go
and please please please when you you're
going to do all of these things ensure
that you talk with developers and sure
that we talk with the people that are
going to use it when deciding what kind
of attraction you're going to offer the
exterior how are we going to be able to
use it because i'm sorry if we cannot
program it does not exist right we
cannot use it it's just useless but
there are many people that are really
looking forward to these technologies
and we would love to spend a lot of time
with you actually learning about your
discipline and finding how to code
assign to actually really bring these
things to the market because that's the
only way in which we can really have a
privacy at the broad scope
okay so do imagine that you gave me this
thing and
i now have my swiss knife of uh hardware
crypto cool stuff
are we done like no i'm sorry
not done
crypto is not the only thing encryption
and confidentiality is not the same
thing but now at least we can start to
build systems we're going to start have
these primitives that allow me to
compute it in the crypto domain and
build systems with them and that means
that we're going to use these primitives
in different ways and we already talked
a lot about batch operations
and
why this much operations happen let me
remind you is because it is private so
many times we either don't know which
record we're interested in when we do
something like in private settings
section or we don't want to show which
record we're interested in as in pir
and that means that we need to repeat uh
our operations many times that means
that when you're thinking about hardwood
about this maybe you just don't think
about the entrance that only gets you uh
one message maybe think about something
that allows me to compute in batches
that already gets that embedded into the
hardware design that could actually
allow to accelerate a lot uh the kind of
things that we do and may actually
if you do this kind of in in uh
co-design with the people that do the
protocols it may really really make the
use of this primitive so much easier
because we can abstract on some of the
things that right now we actually need
to program and so forth and it could be
great if we could forget about
but
also we not only have these places we
just need to compute on a full database
a very much use a trick that we have on
privacy preserver design is that we use
a lot of trial decrypt
and it is because the fact that it is
private not only means that we don't
know what message or what record we want
to touch it also means that we don't
know what key to use
so we kind of need to try all of them
and to give an example of this in
concert tracing apps so first we have
but we now have an extension that allows
us to do what we call presence tracing
and this is to kind of be able to
um alert people that have been sharing
in space like arrested at the bar a room
a meeting and for this what we do is we
put a qr code
on the venue that these people are going
to be in this qr code essentially
contains a public key um
it's a fancy privacy seven public key
kind of thing but for all intents and
purposes this talk is a public key and
then when users come they scan they have
the key with the
phone of the cameras
and then when eventually it is
discovered that this restaurant had a
positive and we want to launch an alarm
to everyone and the doctors contact the
restaurant give them an access code and
then they can upload the secret key of
this qr code to the server
all phones
go and collect all of these secret keys
of all services
and now they have a list of public keys
they have scanned and a list of secret
keys that some of them
are uh
that denote that
there was an infection so now we need to
go and try all of the keys in all of our
uh public key scans to see if one of
them actually decrypts if you decrypt
you actually have been there but the
only way we have is to actually try this
right so that means that we not only
batch cipher this we also batch keys and
believe me this is a thing that we have
to do many times when we design and we
get to this quadratic explosion that
actually again
uh bombs our energy efficiency works our
fastest
time in this case for the phone right
mostly we're carrying about energy
efficiency
uh the fact that we don't drain the
battery of the phone and this is kind of
problematic so if you can find us
another way of building hardware that
actually also thinks about the moment
where we're going to receive many keys
and be cool the good news is that the
restraint the constraints here are also
kind of a little more flexible it can be
probabilistic
this this uh
decryption failure right you can you can
and early if you're kind of almost very
sure that this is not going to happen
uh that means you can abort early to be
fair we are not really sure but the
timing attacks uh how much they would
affect here
but i've heard that the people in the
chess community are actually experts on
timing attacks so i hope that
um and you guys can work a little bit on
it and and give us like what is the good
trade of here for the risk they have in
the drivers and the timing attack but
the advantages that it gives me on
implementation side
we could also use some plain text
that depends on on the privacy situation
you can have a trade-off but we could
also imagine situations in which we can
give some hints so that you don't need
to test all the keys on all the cycles
we can talk about all of those things
but at the end of the day we're still
going to do trial decrypt where we're
still going to need to repeat this
operation gazillion times with different
keys
so that's another thing we use a lot and
another main difference that they think
that sometimes is uh
is it's not really seen about how
different it is when you design the
hardware and when you design the whole
system in particular from a privacy
certain way
is that
a chairs like most of the things are
really uh on this chip like the
adversary is looking here very close to
the chip and can't can talk to it but
when we design a privacy persuasion
system like chips or part of devices and
we actually assume that the adversary is
kind of everywhere right against liquid
devices you can also look at the chip
it's not that we forget about this thing
it can look at the cloud it can look
essentially you can look
and what that means is that maybe the
adversary cannot do the attack here and
you they think well that was my job
but
uh diversity may do the attack here
right and
and that means that what i said before
like encryption is only the first step
to achieve privacy and you're not done
we are not done when we encrypt things
and this starts to be very very relevant
in the world of the internet of things
and here is a paper from from my
colleagues at epfl where they started
studying bluetooth wearable devices and
particularly kind of fancy apple phones
and
things where you can install apps that
interact with your phone and do a bunch
of stuff and a lot of these apps are
actually very sensitive because they
have to go with health or they have to
uh with a church like there are apps
that remind you when to pray their apps
forever
um so
what they show here right is that when
you have that thing that adversary may
not be actually on the phone may
actually just be at the network looking
at the cryptic communication
and then like
a good adversary will just look at this
look how the packets look like and then
it is able to identify sensitive actions
and it is able to identify actions like
to a very large extent here we have a
application matrix this is where the
vessel is predicted excuse the true
label and we see that the adversary
makes very good errors right the
probability of having the predicted
equal to the true is very high the rest
is fundamentally white only when there
are very low volume applications when
there is not enough traffic that person
is not able to do this distinction
and the things that they show extremely
practically invasive like yeah you can
decide whether there is a measurement
you can see for applications that are
about when you eat whether there is food
intake when you send messages receive
messages and and i just took another
example from there
on the paper to show that you even like
this is a an application
to for diabetic people to actually kind
of take notes of how they're doing
and the application
says everything right when you when
you're eating food what kind of food
you're eating how you're doing and then
they say when you add glucose and with
your insulin just kind of keep you on
track and this guy showed that you can
essentially distinguish everything
everything that happened just by the
traffic
and how we typically solve this from a
privacy perspective perspective is to
use dummy traffic that you may also have
heard about as tough
and the goal is to hide information from
this network observer to hide these
patterns because otherwise i'm sorry the
internet of things is never going to be
private because we're going to have
we're going to be leaking a lot on what
these things are sending uh the router
to the phone
to whomever they ascend
and the signs that work on damage
traffic they do one or more of things
either they add packets at
random intervals and
how what is the distribution of this
randomness actually matters a lot happy
to have a whole discussion about how
hard it is to get it right
or you can add packets not kind of from
a random distribution but actually to
mimic other applications other actions
right you just try to mimic you start to
to to hide in the crowd
and the thing about all of these is that
it has high cost because you need to
compute more things you need to compute
when to put
these things out you're going to consume
bandwidth because you need to put and it
can sound that bandwidth
consumes energy
you're also going to have to wake up at
moments that typically you don't have to
wake up so you're going to augment the
number of times that the phone or the
device the iot device has to spend
battery it has to actually pull you know
i can come on and take the big
energy energy spike from the back and
that means that the ndf will be deployed
but as i said without them we're not
going to have end-to-end privacy
preserving systems
so what can you do and and this may be
one of my wildest dreams if these are
possible can we reduce the energy
consumption if you guys think about the
fact that this is gonna happen the fact
that
there are gonna be more messages than
what you think the fact that uh we're
gonna have to combine network privacy
with computation privacy when we do
something that allows these devices to
be more energy efficient
can we maybe just create the damage at
the hardware level
they just need to be random i mean with
some particular randomness but maybe we
can configure that
and also
the timing their timing is kind of
independent of real traffic i mean
that's the whole point right if you make
the time independent of the real traffic
that means that also the damage traffic
is going to leak information about the
real one so maybe we can actually just
create chips that do that for us
and maybe those are much more efficient
that actually the kind of things that we
have nowadays we're going to do have to
do with the application layer and then
we have to
well reduce a lot of things that are
very non-efficient and again i would
like to remind you that sometimes the
speed is not a requirement we can't
afford very slow efficient computation
maybe
over time we can sometimes even afford
very slow transmission over the network
because you know we're not in a hiring
so maybe we can find ways in which um
and actually the network interface is
used by the hardware in a way that
allows us to put more traffic on the
line in a slower way but actually gets
us to have a very high priority at a low
cost so that you can actually convince
vendors vendors of these um
small devices or vendors or phones that
actually we need to protect the traffic
because otherwise we're lost
and by now you're thinking well why does
this person come to ask me for basic
things that we cannot do
the good thing is that negative results
are also great okay if you cannot do if
you tell me that there are limits on the
harvard state that we are never going to
get
visit that shows the limit of privacy
are as important as solutions we move
forward in this digital world on the
assumption that we will fix it later
right you can see this with machine
learning fairness or with
optimization or in general with privacy
right it will come later on we'll build
it and then later on we'll plug
something in
it is very important to inform policy
discussions about the snake oil that
they are being sold when people tell
them that this will be solved that we
will solve the ethics of ai you just
need to wait like for a couple of years
until someone in eurips comes up with
the algorithm no we start starting to
have more and more uh negative results
there that show that
robustness cannot coexist with fairness
or that privacy cannot coexist with
robustness and these things are so
important because otherwise policymakers
that are you know love it all the time
they will believe that the holy grail
will appear and it will solve all of
their problems and by the time they
realize this is not the case we will
have a world in which privacy is not
possible anymore so you have negative
results bring them to the table i would
also be happy to take them on and to and
to also write on our papers like well
this is the limit of what we can do and
now we have to choose in which kind of
society we want to live a society which
maybe has an application but we'll never
have privacy or the society would you
know maybe we're a little bit less
digital but we do have privacy that's
kind of
nice so with this i would like to to end
my talk and to
just kind of reverse the key points
what we do when we do privacy is to
actually limit the purpose of systems
that we create so that we don't need to
trust anyone to use the data under
purpose and for doing that we need to
use a bunch of non-standard
cryptographic and non-cryptographic
solutions like the dummy traffic
and these are constrained by the
infrastructure and infrastructure
includes hardware and sometimes help
starts from the bottom and if you can
kind of help from this bottom by
producing more and more efficient things
it will be easier that actually those
improvements get to the software layer
and we're actually able to deploy this
thing so we need better support and if
you cannot build it let's
find the limits and this is equally
important uh for the for the actual
discussion at the broader level
and with this i'd like to stop and take
questions which i hope to have many and
learn more from you than maybe what you
have learned from me today thank you
very much
thank you so much carmilla was a great
talk
so we have so far one question in the
zulub chat and i have a few more
questions so one question is about um
homomorphic encryption versus
multi-party computation
where the question says that the
confidential computing consortium claims
that there is an ambiguity in the
definitions of homomorphic encryption
and multi-party computation that leads
to gray areas between the two concepts
and the question is if you have any
thoughts on this
i think that that can be probably
correct right then
sometimes multi-party computations you
could really call it homomorphic
encryption in a way because you're doing
uh
you're doing like the kind of techniques
you use they are so close to each other
that that probably they are the same
now
uh from my perspective or maybe in the
context of this talk this is even better
news because it means you guys may only
need to do
one of these to actually you know
two birds with one stone
you can help us do multi-party
computation and homomorphic encryption
with the same piece of hardware uh
it's much important
thank you there's a another question
to what extent does privacy require
secure hardware or a secure system
ultimately you don't have a security on
a compromised system but perhaps
state-of-the-art systems
sufficiently minimize data stored on the
user's device to for example survive
later a temporary compromise
that's a very good question uh no in
many ways many many many cases i don't
think we really need a
secure hardware like anti-tampering
hardware like the adversary model i said
that
in my in my picture about the two
adversaries i said the privacy also
cares about the tags that you can have
on the chip it does it does in the sense
that uh especially when we outsource to
the cloud and we don't trust the cloud
at all we also don't trust that the
cloud
just very powerful adversary like the
cloud provider cannot maybe do a
hardware attack there but as this person
says uh maybe on the phone physical
security is not uh it's not the
the priority
but again like the fact that the
hardware is not secure doesn't mean that
the hardware cannot help securing the
network
you see what i mean
thank you um
another question a hardware-based
trusted execution environments are also
emerging as a solution for
privacy-preserving scenarios you did not
talk about those did you imply that tes
are not important or will not be
dominant in the future
ah
crystal bowling is not my fourth day um
so i think the teas are interesting uh
they are very useful they sometimes
enable to
to even kind of
offload some of the heavy computations
of all of these protocols kind of the
tea and you can make hybrid approaches
so there are two things one is that yeti
is maybe but you know not all phones
have t's and in general these are also
very restricted in access again as we
were we were talking about that before
right
phones have tes nowadays do you know how
many can i use to build my privacy
serving applications zero so that is not
going to be kind of of the solution that
that brings privacy and privacy in
europe i think the broader scale it kind
of actually still leaves the privacy
engineer in the hands of the powerful
the google and the apples they're going
to decide who why and when can use the
teas
um it also is still
a kind of technology that depends on
maybe the hardware manufacturers and how
they do these things
so i don't know i think that we need
both both at the same time but in
particular um
yeah what i don't believe is that
everybody's going to have access to
a te
and so we need other ways to get access
to the privacy that the teu could give
and this is actually
okay
i have one question actually which is
so you're saying that privacy is about
minimizing trust and i think as
when looking at cryptographic protocols
whenever we
eliminate more trusted parties to
ideally have none left at the end
we get a problem with usability so
usually systems where we trust some some
parties are much easier to use
like one trusted central party
already simplifies a lot of
authentication issues um key management
and all of these things so how much do
you think this is an issue
that if we're building more and more
privacy preserving and trust minimizing
systems
that the average user isn't using them
anymore or can't be using them anymore
okay i don't think
that the usability uh when you were
saying that i was thinking that you were
thinking about the usability for the
developer
which indeed is a freaking nightmare
right every time we decentralize we need
to go around doing a lot of stuff
and uh and it is hard it's hard to get
it right but for the user it's not that
these things uh
really kind of make a big difference
right now the question is can
can can we abstract this away from the
user like i don't understand why having
a decentralized system essentially makes
it different from the point of view
of of the user uh for example in the
contact racing apps users have no idea
whether the thing is decentralized or
not in fact they could not distinguish
or decentralize from a centralized thing
but because for them there is a phone
doing bluetooth and sending stuff to
places
so i think you're very right that
privacy preserving technologies make
developers life much much harder i'm not
so sure that that necessarily goes to
making the user life so hard
and
also
i mean thankfully enough there is a lot
of research that goes actually on
usability of privacy technologies and we
probably would need we did more but i
don't think that those things are kind
of
fundamentally impossible to put together
okay
that's great um
one more question
uh can you maybe elaborate a bit on when
you meant uh when you mentioned in one
of the slides you can't build end-to-end
without authentication
so we want to use this privacy
preserving uh schemes uh
and we have a lot of the for instance
privacy preserving search right and
privacy preserving search it's um
at the end of the day a leaky primitive
because you are going to leak one thing
what you search for right if you search
for something and you and you find it
you can receive it
now
the only way we have to avoid that is to
avoid that somebody can come and make
infinite queries
and for that we need to know that people
that came uh but that the people cannot
do infinite ones and the ways we have to
solve those things are then to bring uh
authentication now when we have
authentication we're losing a lot of the
privacy
on the privacy problems we had before
privacy properties we had before so we
want to do anonymous identification that
is one case uh in other cases for
for uh abusive systems like many times
people like wikipedia for instance would
like to
to be able to actually limit how much
abuse there is and they do this by doing
a straightforward authentication
and if you move to the privacy
preserving world then you would like to
have some kind of anonymous
authentication that allows you to say
i'm a legitimate user right that is not
doing bad things and that's the kind of
things you need to prove
but uh why we need all of those is
because if we ask wikipedia to go
anonymous then they ask us give us an
abuse
an abuse prevention system uh in the
case of the search is the same kind of
thing so maybe what i'm saying is that
we need authentication for prevention
and then we need
to bring that again take a step back and
put that prevention in the privacy for
certain way i think that's what i meant
i don't know if i make a better word
i think you made it better
um okay also i think we have two more
minutes until the next session starts so
i'm afraid we have to stop here so thank
you again very much for this for this
great talk
um i don't know if you can join zulip to
maybe answer some more questions that
are popping up
then maybe we can continue the
discussion there and move over to the
next session great thank you again so
much thank you