hello and welcome to our presentation
about security and trust of open source
security tokens my name is mark shinke
and i did this research together with
alexander wagner floren understand and
duon heisen
let us start with a short motivation why
passwords are bad and why we need
additional security measures passwords
are the most common means of
authentication but they come with a lot
of problems and so it's not surprising
that most hacking related data breaches
are the result of weak or stolen
passwords to illustrate only a few
problems of using passwords let us use
the twitter account of this guy as a
case example the twitter account of the
former president donald trump was hacked
at least twice in 2016 his account was
hacked by a dutch group of hackers they
found his password in a database that
was part of a data breach on linkedin in
trump used the same password for
linkedin and twitter his password back
then was you are fired which is
obviously a weak password then in 2020
his account was hacked again by one of
the dutch hackers this time he spotted a
twitter post that shows the guest wifi
password used on the 2020 election rally
for donald trump
after trying some variations of this
password he got access to trump's
twitter account this time trump's
password was maga 2020 exclamation mark
not as bad as the first one but still
easy to guess but maybe trump was
relying on the expertise of kaspersky
according to their password checker this
password is nice and tag resistant but
seriously this shows another problem
with passwords in some cases the context
so who uses a password influences the
security level to ids and a bunch of
other password related problems you
should use hardware security tokens
hardware security tokens are dedicated
devices that you usually plug into the
usb port of your computer
instead of guessable passwords or
passwords with questionable entropy
security tokens use strong cryptographic
algorithms for the authentication the
downside is however that end users have
no control and inside what's happening
you have to fully trust the heart and
software of the token
to gain the user's trust some
manufacturers make their products open
source this gives insight and detailed
information about how these devices work
and allows security audits by
independent researchers and other third
parties nevertheless potential physical
attacks for example during the whole
supply chain until the device reaches
the customer still remain
so our research question was how secure
and trustworthy are these devices
is it possible to manipulate or clone
these devices without being noticed by
the user
before we answer this question and move
on to the results of our security
analysis it is important to specify an
adversary model that is suitable for
hardware security tokens once we are
able to reach the goal within the rules
of this framework our attack is
considered to be successful
our goal is always to gain unrestricted
access to all the services a token is
used for for example a service like
google or github we can achieve this
goal in two ways
first we can extract the cryptographic
keys directly from the token to clone it
second we can manipulate the tokens
firmware such that for example the
generated keys used for the
authentication are weak and brute
forceable
since we are interested in unrestricted
access to the services we are not
allowed to leave any evidence of our
attack for example a longer
disappearance or even permanent theft of
the token would alert the user
the user could revoke the token from all
registered services which would make the
attack pointless
the attack equipment is restricted to
low-cost devices that sum up to an
amount of a few thousand us dollars the
equipment should also be portable such
that it can be used in an evil-made
scenario for example
for this adversarial model we consider
two attack scenarios evil mate and
supply chain attacks
for example an evil mate attack is when
the room service compromises your token
while it is unattended in your hotel
room this is far from being a
theoretical threat we have seen similar
cases where attackers broke into a hotel
room and compromised a laptop of a
professional online poker player
the supply chain scenario covers all
attacks that can be carried out in the
way from the producer to the end
customer this also covers scenarios
where an attacker offers fake tokens
with manipulated firmware we have
already seen such attacks in the past
for example network devices have been
intercepted and manipulated on the way
to the customers there are also cases
where manipulated network devices were
sold directly
in both scenarios an attacker has
physical access to the token but is
limited in time for example a few
minutes in hotel room or maybe half an
hour during an attack somewhere in the
supply chain
in our research we evaluated all
commercially available open source
security tokens in total we analyzed
seven security tokens and identified
several vulnerabilities that can all be
carried out in a supply chain or evil
made scenario our methods range from
simple bus probing to more sophisticated
fault injection attacks
in this presentation i will show you
three different attacks one bus probing
attack on the nitro key fido u2f and a
side channel and fault injection attack
against the zolo from zolokis this
selection is intended to illustrate you
the different types of attacks that can
be carried out on hardware security
tokens in the supply chain or evil mate
attack scenario for all other attacks
and vulnerabilities we identified i
would like to refer you to our paper
let's start with the first device the
nitro key fighter u2f this device
consists of a microcontroller and the
secure element is highlighted on the
right hand side the secure element is
used as key storage and to perform the
cryptographic algorithms the
microcontroller on the other hand
implements the authentication protocol
and usb communication it is important to
note that the secure element contains
the hardware attestation key this is
specified by the fido standard and can
be used to verify the authenticity of
the device to prevent an attacker from
simply exchanging the secure element or
manipulate the firmware of the
microcontroller both chips contain
shared secrets
however we identified a flaw that allows
us to recover the shared secrets we are
probing the i square c bus between
microcontroller and secure element with
that we are able to manipulate the
firmware on the microcontroller and
implement malicious features like a
backdoor or key generator with low
entropy
let's take a look at what happens on the
i-square c-bus when we register the
nitro key fighter u2f on an arbitrary
service like google or github the
protocol consists of multiple steps but
only the first two are important for
this attack
in the first step our nuns and the
application id are concatenated and then
transferred from the microcontroller to
the secure element the app id identifies
the service for example google and the
nonsense generated on the
microcontroller both variables are not
important to understand this attack on
the secure element an hmac is generated
and the result is then transferred back
to the microcontroller afterwards the
hmeg is used to derive the service key
for that one of the two shared secrets
the r key is used in this figure the
shared secrets we are interested in are
highlighted in boldface in the next step
the service key is concatenated with the
second shared secret dw key and then
transferred to the cq element both are
fed into a hash function and the result
is then transferred back to the
microcontroller the mac is then used in
a later protocol step which is not
important for this attack the problem of
the protocol is now quite obvious the
service key and the second shared secret
w key are transferred in plane on the
bus together with the hmac from the
previous step we can easily infer the r
key
now we have the secrets shared between
the secure element and the
microcontroller for that we only had to
capture two messages on the i square c
bus here highlighted in red
with the two secrets we are now able to
replace the firmware on the
microcontroller and implement malicious
features this attack can be mounted in a
supply chain and even made scenario for
example a key generator that produces
guessable service keys what makes this
attack so malicious is that it scales
well in the supply chain scenario and
the device remains authentic the user is
not able to identify the manipulation
which fully undermines the trust
riffiness of these devices the reason is
that with both shared secrets our
malicious firmware can still use the
secure element with the original
hardware the station key this would not
be possible by simply exchanging the
microcontroller
this vulnerability can easily be fixed
by moving the mac calculation to the
microcontroller instead of outsourcing
it to the secure element and thereby
expose sensitive information on the i
square c bus
unfortunately the manufacturer did not
provide a patch for the firmware so far
however since the firmware is open
source our results enable third parties
to fix the vulnerability
the next attack i'm going to present you
is a side channel attack that affects
the zola from solo keys and all devices
that are based on it
the solo consists only for
microcontroller the stm32l4 this
microcontroller contains all the
cryptographic credentials for the
authentication on the service the
elliptic curve algorithms are
implemented in software using the micro
ecc library
we identified a timing side channel in
the ecdsa implementation of the micro
ecc library
to be precise the scalar multiplication
of the random number k and the base
point g
in the following i'm going to show you
an oracle-based single trace attack on
this easy dsa implementation the oracle
device is just another stm32l4
microcontroller with a modified version
of the micro ecc library for this attack
a large em probe with a diameter of
about one centimeter placed directly on
the top of the microcontroller is
sufficient you can see the placement on
the right hand side actually it's not
even necessary to remove the tokens
casing in the following example we are
going to extract the hardware the
station key from a solar security token
all other credentials like service keys
can be extracted in the same way
the attack works as follows once we have
physical access to the token for example
when the token is left unattended in a
hotel room we trigger a registration on
an arbitrary service this starts the
ecdsa operation with the hardware the
station key during this process we
capture the electromagnetic emission of
the microcontroller after that the
attack phase is already over and we do
not need physical access to the token
any longer the figure shows the
electromagnetic emission of the attack
token while processing the first bit of
the unknown random number k
now we use our oracle device where we
have full control over the variable k to
recover the first bit of k from the
capture dm trace we capture two em
traces of our oracle device with the
first bit of case set to 0 and 1. you
can see these traces on the top and
bottom of the figure
finally we visually compare the m trace
of the attack token with the traces of
our oracle device when we highlight
certain parts of the m traces you can
see that the m trace of the oracle with
k equals 1 matches the token cm trace on
the other hand the m trace of the oracle
with k equals 0 shows clear differences
this means that the first bit of k of
the attack token is 1. to recover the
second bit we set the first bit of k of
the oracle to 1 and repeat the procedure
this approach can be repeated until
every bit of k is recovered
ok how does this side channel attack
affect the security and trust roughness
of the solo key security token this
attack allows to extract the hardware
the station key as well as all other
service keys from the security token
with the hard restation key it is
possible to distribute authentic but
malicious token user customer cannot
distinguish this token from the original
one the token's manipulated firmware
could for example generate guessable
service keys that can be brought first
later this attack allows also to fully
clone a token and gives an adversary
unlimited access to all services for
which the token is used even though the
key recovery phase takes some time this
attack can be easily mounted in a supply
chain and even made scenario the attack
phase is very short only a single em
trace per key needs to be captured which
can be done in a few minutes fortunately
the side channel leakage can easily be
mitigated by randomizing the basepoint
key in the ecdsa implementation
we reported the vulnerability in the
most recent version of the micro ecc
library is already fixed
the side channel attack i showed you has
one major drawback it allows us to
extract only keys that are already
registered on a service at the time of
the attack to circumvent this limitation
we need access to the service root key
with this key we can derive the keys for
all services even though they are not
used at the time of our attack this
brings us to the last and my favorite
attack of this presentation
this time we target the token's hardware
more precisely the readout protection of
the stm32l4 microcontroller once this
protection is broken we have access to
the rootkey via the microcontroller's
debug interface
to achieve this we use a side channel
assisted fault injection attack we
choose electromagnetic fault injection
to leave no traces on the device on the
right hand side you can see the position
we used for the em side channel probe
and the emfi injection coil
before i show you how the attack works
let's start with a brief overview of the
stm32l4 readout protection
the readout protection is responsible to
prevent malicious readouts via the debug
interface
the readout protection has three
different levels in level 0 used for
firmware development there is no
protection and all components of the
microcontroller are accessible via the
debug interface
in level 1 access to the flash memory is
restricted but the srom remains
accessible
the highest level level 2 fully disables
the debug interface according to the
manufacturer this level is irreversible
in a few minutes you will see that this
is not quite right
to understand how the attack works we
first need to understand how the rdp
level is implemented the rdp level is
part of the option bytes which are
permanently stored in flash memory
during the boot phase the option bytes
are transferred from flash memory into
shadow registers to detect errors during
this transfer the actual option bytes
and their complementary values are
transferred
the important point here is that once an
error is detected fallback values are
used for the option wise interestingly
the fallback state for the rdp level is
not too the most secure one but level
one where the sram is accessible
okay so our attack idea is to disrupt
the memory transfer of the option bytes
to bring the device into rdp level 1.
the problem however is that there are
many unknowns for example we do not know
the right position for the mfi coil and
other glitch parameters also and most
important we do not know the point in
time at which we need to inject the
glitch the precise timing is of utmost
importance because otherwise it is
almost infeasible to find out the other
unknown parameters
to determine the exact point in time for
a successful glitch we analyze the
electromagnetic emission of the
microcontroller's boot phase
this figure shows the electromagnetic
emission of a small part of the boot
face of the microcontroller to identify
the point in time of the memory transfer
that contains the rdp level we use a
correlation based leakage test
with help of this leakage test we
successfully determined the exact timing
by injecting a fault into the peak
highlighted in red we are able to bring
the device back into rdp level 1.
now we are able to connect this via the
debug interface to the microcontroller
and read out the root key directly from
the internal srom
for the detailed steps setup parameters
and the result of the leakage test i
would like to refer you to our paper
the impact of this attack is the same as
for the side channel attack but with the
advantage that we can also extract the
root service key a clone token
containing this key can be used to
authenticate against all currently used
services and most important against all
services that will be used in the future
with a properly built and configured
setup we only need a few minutes of
physical access to the token to carry
out this attack the root cause of the
vulnerability is to read out protection
of the token's microcontroller instead
of using the most secure rdp level in
case of a faulty memory transfer the rdp
fallback value enables access to the
internal srom
fortunately there are different
software-based counter measures that can
be implemented one counter measure that
we proposed and that is already
implemented enforces the rdp level
during the startup process of the
firmware this basically puts a token
always into rdp level 2 and thereby
counteracts our downgrade attack
in this presentation i showed you
different attacks to raise awareness for
evil mate and supply chain attacks on
hardware security tokens my take home
message for you is that evil made and
supply chain attacks are realistic
threats for hardware security tokens it
should be considered more in future
products we showed the token
manipulation and even cloning is
possible with a few minutes of physical
access this undermines the
trustworthiness of these products even
though the firm is open source the open
source nature of these products enables
independent security audits and thereby
increase their trust and security
instead of wasting valuable time for
reverse engineering open source allows
us directly to analyze the important
parts of a design where we encountered
closed source components such as the
microcontrollers we had to spend some
time for reverse engineering but
achieved our goal anyway
unfortunately at the moment you have to
choose between security and trust on the
one side you have certified high
security smart cards which require ndas
and prevent open source firmware for
various reasons on the other side you
have general purpose microcontrollers
with closed source hardware but they
allow you at least to open source your
entire firmware and therefore are
trustworthier
the hardware is in fact the only
remaining black box in the last missing
piece towards a fully open and
trustworthy security token so what we
need is not certification of closed
source microcontrollers but open source
microcontrollers with suitable
protection against physical attacks and
fortunately there will be soon open
source microcontrollers like the open
titan that consider hardware security
and physical attacks right from the
design phase until that time comes you
should continue to use hardware security
tokens despite our research findings
they still can protect you against a
bunch of password-related issues and
remote attacks also our proposed
countermeasures mitigate all of our
identified vulnerabilities if in doubt
compile and deploy your firmware
on-premise that's one major advantage of
open source security tokens
if you have any further questions please
do not hesitate to contact us thank you
for listening