hello my name is kim irvine and i will
present our work speed reading in the
dark accelerating functional encryption
for quadratic functions with
reprogrammable hardware
this is a joint work between binary and
myself from university of helsinki and
dylan mark and michael stoppard from
xlab
the work was done in the eu project
pentek
we will go through this
architecture for the first hardware
accelerator for functional encryption
for quadratic functions it is a hardware
software co-design
designed particularly for xilinx zinc
ultra scale and piezo
but it's also
usable
for other
such
socs
the
accelerator is optimized particularly
for the decryptions of this functional
encryption scheme
and this
decryption operation requires pairings
and discrete logarithmic computations
one of the central contributions of our
work is this
parallel version of zhang's famous baby
step science the discrete logarithm
algorithm
and
we utilize pre-computations and parallel
processing in that
that algorithm
what we saw is that
our implementation provides large
speedups compared to software-only
implementations
we get several tens or even hundreds of
times faster
results than
a software library called covay
designed for the same same operation
we also showcased two
practical use cases
in the domain of machine learning
particular image classification and so
that these
speed ups translate also to practical
use cases
so what is functional encryption
if you think about traditional
encryption it's all or nothing in the
sense that
whoever has the decryption key dk here
gets access to the full plaintext and
sees it entirely
after decrypting the cipher text then
again if you don't have this decryption
key you get nothing at all
or maybe you know something something
about the length of the message or
something but actually the contents are
completely hidden from you
functional encryption
then again provides more fine-grained
control
so
it's possible to hand out a decryption
keys that allow to compute a specific
function
from the cipher text so the function of
the plain text when given this side
vertex
and this decryption key allows to
compute this function but doesn't give
any other information about the x
every time that some somebody talks
about computations with ciphertext one
of course
thinks about homomorphic encryption
but
in this sense homomorphic encryption is
more like traditional encryption
that uh
when whenever you decrypt you get the
entire plaintext and if you cannot
decrypt then you get nothing at all but
the functional encryption
actually lets you compute something but
that doesn't
reveal the entire
contents of the message
so then the question is of course
how uh
or what kind of functions can we compute
and in general
general functions are possible in theory
but not in practice
so in
in practical sense we are limited to
very
basic functions so there is
functional encryption for inner products
that
and those schemes allow you to compute
inner products
and like you can compute means or
weighted averages or these kind of very
basic
basic statistics over our vector of data
functional encryption for quadratic
functions lets you compute already
quadratic functions and
can lead to much
much more powerful for practical
applications and uh the focus of this
work is is that is uh
qf
and as we will show we can actually do
some simple machine learning tasks even
with this this kind of
schemes
so here is a small example of what what
kind of
problems or practical problems could be
solved with functional encryption
so we have a setup where we have a
patient
and then
[Music]
in this case two different doctors
they might be for example from different
specialties so it might be a cardio
cardiologist and an oncologist for
example
and now
keys are given for the for the patient
to encrypt data and
two different keys are are given to the
doctors so
the cardiologist can compute the
function f and
the angle of this
function g
and now the patient may uh
encrypt her her data like genomic data
as an example and send it to a server
then
the cardiologist can can query this
genomic data
with uh for and see for example if there
is some
some
hard condition
based on the
patient's
genetic data
and
the oncologist can
search similar things but for other
diseases so in this case
for example some cancer
and
nobody not the doctor and not even even
the server has full access to the
patient's genomic data
and
the central computation in this kind of
a setup is the
decryption function of this functional
encryption scheme
and that's the motivation why this work
also focuses
mostly on the on the decryption
operation or
uh
because it's it's quite
seldom when these keys needs to be
generated so so there
is probably quite little need for
accelerating the key generation function
and then a patient
encrypts her data maybe
once or very seldom in any case and it's
also very likely that that the patients
can't have access to hardware
accelerators
so so this decryption operation that is
both frequent and and done in a
centralized server
is is a
very good candidate for hardware
acceleration
okay so let's take a look on the
actual decryption algorithm that we
focus on in this work
so this is uh
from a scheme uh
described in in a in a paper titled
reading in the dark and that's also
the origin of the title of our paper
speed reading in the dark because we we
do that faster with our hardware
acceleration
and
if we look at this decryption algorithm
it takes as an input the
specific format
ciphertext and then
a decryption key for specific quadratic
function f
and then it computes a number of of
pairing computations
actually the number of
pairings that are required in the
decryption depends on the length of the
ciphertext
vector
to how many many uh
values are encrypted in the in the
ciphertext vector
uh then uh there are some finite
arithmetic operations required uh also
but those are rather insignificant if
you look at the big picture
and actually the the performance of this
algorithm is mostly determined by by the
pairings
and importantly the final discrete
logarithm that needs to be computed in
the end
so this discrete logarithm returns
an integer value as a as an output and
that's the
the output of the quadratic function
that we want from
to compute with this uh algorithm
and uh our work
has focused
on the novelties in our work are are
concentrated on this discrete logarithm
computation so in this presentation i
will
focus mostly on that but the details
about how we compute the pairings are
are available in the in the paper
so a discrete logarithm is the problem
of finding x
when given
alpha and beta in some cyclic group
and beta is such that it's alpha 2x
a famous way to solve this problem is
the thanks baby step giant step
algorithm which is based on this
equality here
so once a match is found for
where
some power of alpha equals
this right hand side
then we know what the x is
and the uh algorithm splits into two
phases so there is this baby step base
which uh computes uh powers of alpha and
stores them in a in a table
and then the actual giant step base is
is the one where we try to find the
matches
okay and
the
discrete logarithms that need to be
computed in this decryption algorithm
are actually quite special in the in the
sense that
that
we know that the x is in a specific
bound which is
very small compared to the the size of
the cyclic group
and
so so in most cases we know that the
the function that we evaluate can return
output values in the interval
from minus
b
to positive b
and uh it's also the case that this uh
alpha value
is is fixed in this it's a domain
parameter so so uh we can pre-compute
this baby step
the table t
and although this
size of the cyclic group is is huge
and and that would prevent us from
computing the whole thing we can can
still
compute the t up to some predefined
bound
and in this uh
where we didn't work we denote that by b
and then it allows to
allows us to evaluate all functions that
satisfy this inequality
it's also uh
noticeable that
we don't have to actually store the
entire
of the j but it's stuff is to to
only store some some bits of that
that
value
as long as all the entries in in t are
unique
and and this helps us to save a lot of
uh space
which is very very central in this
network because we are actually
computing huge tables
then our architecture that i will
present in the following slides is a
parallel with architecture so so it is
of interest to to paralyze this
algorithm
and actually this both of the steps are
are
can be fully paralyzed in the sense that
if we have n cores we get almost n times
speed up
and the the resulting algorithm that
takes these
this
list into account is actually quite
complex it's about one-page algorithm so
i spare you from that and you can take a
look
in the paper if you are interested
okay so so here is the high-level
architecture of our
our accelerator so as i mentioned it's a
hardware software co-design so that
there is a short software side so you
can see this arm core here
and then there's a hardware side which
is implemented
on an fpga
fabric
um
the
most important components in the in the
hardware domain are these in parallel
processing cores
so n is 16 in our implementations case
but but we basically it could be
another another value for n could be
used as as well but we filled the fpga
and that meant that we could fit in 16
16 panel cores
these cores are are optimized
for speed and area which allows us to
optimally use the
resources that we have
available
the actual architecture of the of this
course is based on a bearing
co-processor architecture
designed by mila and myself and
published in fpl last year
so it's optimized for pairing
computations
but
as it ultimately relies on the efficient
financial arithmetic it can be also used
to efficiently compute
the other parts of the
decryption algorithm including the
discrete logarithm computation
here on the hardware side we also have
a hierarchy of local memory so there is
there are
there are local memories in the in the
cp course
but there is also shared memory which
allows the cp cores to exchange data
with each other
the main purpose of this memory
hierarchy is to reduce the amount of
data that needs to be transferred
between the software and hardware
domains because that
communication would easily become
a bottleneck
if not
not implemented with a smart
uh
hierarch local memory in the hardware
side
uh in the software side there's this arm
core that takes care of general control
and flow management but also certain
what i call auxiliary processing meaning
operations small operations that need to
be computed
but
which are either not supported by the
hardware domain or that doesn't pay off
to be
to be uh delegated to the hardware at
that point
uh an important
component here is also this ddr memory
which is actually not part of the
designing chip but it's it's on the
on the same board
and this uh large ddr memory is used for
storing the pre-computed key and
actually we used almost two gigabytes of
that memory so that's that's a very
central component in this computation
okay so let's uh take a look on the
results next so we compare this uh
the results of our work
against the gopher library also a result
of the fentech project
that implements the same
feqf
scheme
but in in addition to the original
coffee we also
compare against optimal go fa sorry
optimized coffee
which is uh
the same cofa library but where we have
implemented discrete logarithms with our
discrete logarithmic computation
with pre-computations
and we can see from here that actually
this
this algorithm has a
very significant impact also in the
software performance
so you can see that that
with the normal original coffee
the discrete logarithms quickly start
start
to dominate here and and the
decryption times grow
to impractical
levels quite quickly because all of
these samples here are actually
rather small in practical sense so so in
some cases there is only one value
the largest 20
but
but as soon as the the the size of the
result grows the
coffee library gets slow
with the
new biscuit look at the algorithm we get
significant speed ups but but by using
the hardware accelerator
we get
[Music]
even much better better results so so we
get
get the speed ups of over a thousand
times compared to original coffee but
almost 20 times even even against the
optimized one
and it's uh so that the
the bigger the functions are the more
the more benefit you get from the
hardware accelerator
and that's you know a
good showcase of the importance of
hardware acceleration for practical
use cases because in those cases the
functions usually are on the larger end
at the beginning i said that we also
tested our system with uh practical or
practical
like scenarios or use cases
and we tested them with two different
image classification use cases
so so the the setup is such that for
example
in the first case we use this mnist
famous mnist database of
images of written digits
and the task there is to normally to to
give this image to a computer and and it
should then say which which digit is is
there in the image
in this case that we have the the
task is much
[Music]
more difficult because we actually
encrypt the image so it's not not
possible to visually even even look at
that and tell which
which image there is and but with the
functional encryption it's still
possible to do this machine learning
computation by
by giving out 10 different
different
decryption keys
one that that
gives the the
likelihood that the
this is the zero the one that it's one
and so on all the way up to nine
and in this example for example we see
that the
the decryption with the key that they
gives the likelihood with
for the digits eight gives the largest
output and then that means that the
the image in that encrypted image
is likely to be eighth
the fashion mnist databases is similar
but instead of hundred and digits it
contains images of different kind of
clothes like t-shirts browsers and so on
and the task is to
is to find out which one that is there
there are also 10 different classes in
that case
so in both cases actually the images are
28 times 28 pixels
and
contain different 10 different classes
but because the
task of
of
classifying these 100 digits is much
much easier actually uh the computation
or the
that is required there is is much
simpler so we we can use in
is 40 as a parameter in that case and we
get
on average 29 bit outputs from the from
the computation
and actually this this kind of a model
gives a 97 percent accuracy
in the case of eminis we have to use
bigger
parameters so we have n is 128
on average 37 bit outputs and still we
get less than 90 accuracy
so if we look at the uh literature so
original gopher was reported to to
have this mnist case done in less than
20 seconds
um
when we do that with optimized coffee
we get
on average 1.3 seconds for that
computation for the mnist
and uh passionate is
done in
5.2 seconds
with our accelerator we are
0.09 seconds for the mnist case and
about 0.4 seconds for the
fashion name list so we get
15 times speed up
which is
something that already has a lot of
practical significance
so as a conclusion
what we showed was that the functional
encryption for quadratic functions
benefits difficulty from hardware
acceleration
although we focused on on us one
specific scheme in this
work
also the other fbq schemes that have
been proposed are actually very similar
in structure so they use pairings and
discrete logarithms
so we expect that our results can be
used or our results generalize
to them also rather
rather easily and
our accelerator can be used
for for different fpqf
schemes with only very minor
modifications
if you are interested in in the paper
or or the the details about the
architecture
algorithms and for your discussion on
site channel attacks please please see
the
see the paper
okay thank you very much and
questions can be
asked
either during the online session or
mailed directly to me this
email address schema dot u dot yeah i
remember not helping you fine
thank you very much for your attention