hello all welcome to our talk on the
design of the new aes instruction set
extensions for risk five uh the aim of
this talk is basically to give you an
overview of what risk five is and our
role within it um talk a little bit
about instruction set extensions for
cryptography generally and then the
specific ones that we've built for risk
five um so we'll talk you through our
design process explain how these new
instructions work because i hope a lot
of you will be using them
and then explain sort of our next steps
as a group
as a group of people who are developing
instructions for risk five um we're
going to keep the talk as technical as
possible within the time so most of the
details will still be in the paper
and if you're watching this through on
youtube i will not blame you if you
watch this back at half speed because it
is quite dense so moving on to exactly
what risk five is
so in their own words it's a free and
open iso that lets anyone
pick up the specification and build a
cpu or software to execute on that
as opposed to someone like arm or risk
five where either cost you a lot of
money to buy the chip or simply license
the design
this means anyone can use risk five for
free so it's very popular in research
and industry
particularly in industry for niche
applications like security
and the main principles of risk five are
that it's a very small base instruction
set architecture and then you have
domain specific extensions for
particular things
so this
incomplete map sort of shows this so the
bottom you've got the base instruction
set and then each of the little bricks
represents sort of an extension on top
um the blue ones are ratified so that
means they're frozen and won't change
the bright yellow ones are sort of being
developed currently and then
slightly the paler yellow ones are on
the road map
and some of these are extensions are
being ratified this year including the
scalar cryptography instruction set that
we have been working to extend with
these aes instructions
so that's the focus of this talk it's
not so much the scalar cryptography
instruction set extension specifically
but the design process that we went
through to build the aes accelerator
instructions for risk five
so just to introduce instruction set
extensions for cryptography more
generally so these screenshots are from
the arm manual on the left and the intel
uh blog on the right introducing their
aes acceleration instructions um we're
also on some level familiar with these
the idea being that if you add an
instruction to your architecture that
performs the very specific operation
that aes does or indeed any other piece
of cryptography or the particular
specific operation that your cpu needs
to do you can get an enormous uh power
performance
improvement
um so you know the the more and
cryptography is a really good example of
sort of domain specific instruction set
extensions because you get such an
enormous performance increase you can
very often get a security benefit as
well by removing timing attack vectors
so for aes this means that you're no
longer computing your s boxes and your
mixed columns operations through t
tables
um and you
uh also get us something of a
portability benefit so for uh
sort of smaller embedded applications
where everyone's using a slightly
different dedicated aes sort of
accelerator engine um you have to
interact with via the fire some sort of
hardware abstraction layer that's a bit
of a faff and it's quite difficult to do
for portable software whereas if you've
got them built into the instruction set
software can always rely on them being
there
um the flip side of this is that
particularly for aes
um most of the way that these
instruction set extensions have been
defined and if i flick back to the
previous slide you sort of see this is
that they build on top of the existing
uh cmd or vector registers in the cpu
and that's great because uh
aes cryptography generally tends to have
quite large inputs to its operations so
if you've already got these big
registers in your cpus it makes perfect
sense to reuse them you can see here on
the bottom left here that you know it's
128 bits going in 128 bits coming out
and that's great if you've already got
these big registers in your cpu but for
a large class of cpu that's just not
feasible they are designed to be area
optimized and very very small
um
and of course lots of you have written
software for sort of embedded
microcontroller platforms like arm
cortex m something um and you know that
you know writing cryptography for those
can be a right pain um it can really
benefit from having sort of some level
of accelerated cryptography both in
terms of performance but for smaller
devices in particular uh it's more about
power efficiency as well
um so that's the good and the bad of
sort of instruction set extensions for
cryptography the ugly until recently was
that risk life didn't have any
cryptography acceleration um and they've
been papers pointing out that actually
risk five struggles in a lot of regard
when it comes to sort of certain
cryptographic primitives
so that was our job so the authors of
this paper and a whole bunch of other
people
are members of the risk five
cryptography extension task group and
it's our job to make risk five the best
architecture out there for doing
cryptography and that's hopefully what
we've uh somewhat achieved um and again
this presentation will take you through
the aes versions
um
so the first
question we started with when building
these extensions was do we go down the
traditional route of accelerating air
yes do we reuse the
sort of forthcoming risk five vector
registers um or do we take do something
a bit different that's not actually been
done before do we look at the scalar
approach which is to only use existing
general purpose registers
um
in true risk five fashion we actually
decided to do both but we're focusing on
the scalar
instructions first because they're ready
whereas the risk flight vector extension
is still being defined so you probably
guessed from the title of this
presentation we're looking at scalar
stuff now and what makes scalar
different is that your input and opera
input
registers are maybe only 32 bit or 64
bits wide as opposed to 128 bits
um and this means that inevitably your
implementation is going to be a little
bit slower but it's going to be
available to a much much larger set of
cpu types
and that was the really interesting
thing from a five perspective because
that's
currently it's most popular in the sort
of embedded compute space
um so
in terms of what we actually did to
define these instructions um and our
sort of approach we basically went
looking through the literature we had a
really positive experience going through
um existing stuff uh chairs and various
other venues going back years for how
people thought about adding
uh instruction set extensions to 32-bit
processors in order to speed up aes
um so we find sort of three distinct
pre-existing works that you can see sort
of snapshotted here and we also invented
a couple of our own two our own designs
one of which was for the 64-bit
architecture because we didn't actually
find any
uh sort of 64-bit only work in the
literature for
accelerating aes and then we went
through a fairly standard process of
benchmarking their software performance
looking at static and dynamic
instruction counts how much they cost to
implement in hardware and the sort of
funny complexity like what does this
mean if you want to actually integrate
this into a cpu does it make it
make the rest of the design
disproportionately complex how would we
verify the functionality all these other
sorts of things that don't necessarily
um
aren't immediately apparent if you just
look at the sort of academic designs
um and once we benchmarked all of these
luckily we thought they were two ver
very clear winners um
so we picked one for the 32-bit bass
risk five architecture and one for the
64-bit and the rest of this uh
presentation will give you a sort of
whistle-stop tour of exactly how those
two different instruction set extensions
work
so for 32-bit design uh we basically um
the way we like to explain this is it's
based on t tables in hardware so if you
imagine you've implemented aes and
you've done it in software with a
t-total style you've got essentially a
one byte input producing a 32-bit output
but normally you would do this by
looking up into memory um but in this
case we roll up that entire operation
into a single instruction
so each instruction does one byte of
s-box
does
some of the shift rows and the one bytes
worth of mixed columns and then you
excel that result back into the state
just like you would with a normal
t-table operation
the advantage for this in particularly
for a 32-bit design is that you only
need to instance one s box in hardware
and the area for these instructions is
always dominated by the s box despite
years of research on efficient xbox s
boxes they're still the sort of um
they're the bottleneck basically
um so this is so on the right there you
can see the actual iso specification for
these instructions um i won't dwell on
those too much i'll give you a link to
the spec later on
um but you get
using these instructions you get a
pretty big speed up for a relatively
small cost so there's only about one
cane and two gates
um for both encrypt and decrypt which is
amazing um and you end up with about 20
instructions per encrypted decrypt round
um so in terms of what a round actually
looks like at this point please do pause
on youtube just to take in this
extremely busy slide so pause
and back so
the actual round loop itself
um so you start with four load word
instructions so that's your next round
key essentially and then you've got 16
of these
aes 32 esmi so aes 32 bits encrypt sub
bytes mix
i with an immediate
and what each of the each four
instructions process is one row and each
instruction within a row selects the ith
byte of an of uh one of the input
registers
applies the s box says what's going on
over here
then if it's a middle round it applies
the
mix makes columns and if it's not a
middle round then it doesn't
and then you rotate the result and xor
it back into rs1 i do not expect this to
be completely understood on a first
reading here but this is essentially how
the whole operation breaks down for one
round of aes on a 32-bit risk five
um
so if you want to pause and just take
take all that in i will not blame you
um
for the 32 for the 64-bit design rather
our key realization that if you take two
64-bit registers you can fit an entire
128-bit state and this is an absolute
revelation to us
and that means that we can fit an entire
aes state input into one instruction so
over two instructions which can only
produce a 64-bit result each we can
compute the entire aes next round state
so two instructions an entire round
um
we have
these instructions are
designed because they're for 64-bit
processors which are naturally a little
bit bigger we opted to make them
somewhat more higher performance
so that means you can do them in do an
entire aes encrypt or decrypt operation
in six instructions per round as opposed
to 20 in the previous so you imagine
already there that's quite a big
difference um in terms of how that
stacks up against sort of um arm and
intel's version well they can do an
entire round in one instruction so
although we're not as fast as them in
terms of like cost per performance
increase we're actually extremely
efficient
and this particular instruction has uh
some trade-offs there where you uh can
implement it with one s box over eight
cycles so you make a multi-cycle
operation that's a bit smaller and a bit
slower or you can do eight x boxes in
effectively one cycle of pipeline as
necessary
um so again you've got snapshot from the
spec there
um let's give you a concrete example a
little bit less busy this time
so this is uh the recommended way that
we we think you should implement uh aes
round on a 64-bit risk five
um first of all load in two sets of
round keys so we do double rounds and we
do this because we want to pipeline all
the loads in one go
we use a normal xor instructions two of
them to do the ad round key step
and then the aes 64 encrypt sub pipes
makes columns instruction does the rest
so it does shift rows sub bytes and
mixed columns
um the actual steps involved so you take
128 bits of input from rs1 and rs2
and then you do shift rows
and you only take the low 64 bits of the
result of the shift rows
to which you then apply sub bytes and
mixed columns and output those 64 bits
so that gives you half of a round and
then to compute the other half you just
swap the order of your input registers
and because of the way shift rows works
that means you naturally get the other
half of the output
um if that isn't immediately apparent
just trust me but it's a nice little
trick that meant we only needed half as
many instructions as we thought we did
that's the 64-bit design um
in terms of our evaluation again i
apologize it's a bit of a busy slide but
these are all the numbers that you
really want to see from the paper
the headlines being that we're between
five and ten times faster than software
t tables
um
we get rid of all of the data
data requirements because there are no
more tables um the hardware cost is very
modest um and we're a fair bit faster so
uh yeah this is the headline numbers if
you want to pause again and just take
all of this in please do
um
we did have an anticipated question
because these are obviously instructions
that are intended to go in
smaller machines smaller cpus that
possibly have side channel concerns
um
so
how did we how do we consider this in
our design process so for timing it's
pretty easy you're no longer doing
memory lookups because well you
shouldn't have been doing memory lookups
anyway but if you were there's no need
to anymore because
the actual sbox operation is wrapped up
in the instruction so timing we actually
found fairly simple
um for em and power side channels
however that's a very different question
and i would love to talk to you all
about this
in extreme depth so please come and come
find me about this because there's a lot
to talk about
um but basically we excluded these from
scope pretty early on in the design of
these instructions because at the time
there wasn't much research on how to add
side channel guarantees to instruction
set architectures and whether or not the
instruction set definition is actually
the right place to do that because the
moment you add it to that point in the
abstraction stack you have to be able to
verify it and verifying the absence of
powerside channels is quite difficult at
the moment you can make all kinds of
claims about uh sort of formal proofs of
uh
powerslide channel security but in
reality those rely on a certain set of
assumptions that we couldn't guarantee
would hold for everyone who was going to
implement these instructions
um
so we actually excluded them from scope
however hopefully we're going to put out
an eprint soon that explains how you
might add side channel protections to
these instructions um but generally we
need more research on this so please do
come and talk to us because it's
something that um the the risk five sort
of security and cryptography community
is really interested in
um so that was more of it so i
anticipate your question please do keep
asking about it but
just to
tell you we've we've have done some
thinking about it
um so in terms of what's actually
happening now because of our work
um the risk five scalar cryptography ise
is out for public review and it includes
these instructions
so the the actual instruction set
extension includes not just instructions
for aes but also sm3 sm4
sha2 and a bunch of other sort of more
generic instructions for accelerating
cryptography and you can go and find it
at these various links
um
but we hope the the chess community will
find this very interesting because it's
uh risk five is the first instruction
set
um sort of that's been widely adopted
that's going to have a
dedicated extension for
small cpus to accelerate cryptography
um this hasn't really happened before
and we really want to sort of get it out
into the community so
tell us what you think basically
um and in terms of what's next on our
horizon so the the cryptography task
group within risk five we're going to
start looking at vector instructions for
aes these are the really high
performance versions much more similar
to what x86 and arm have done in the
past uh we also want to look at post
quantum cryptography how are we going to
support the primitives necessary for
that
on on a risk live based system we also
want to look more at side channel
security uh specifically for these aes
instructions because they're very common
target but also more generally how can
we add constraints to the risk five
um sort of design process that makes it
easier to support
power or em side channels
uh security um we've got some ideas
about this but we wanna talk to you
about it because you're all the experts
um because overall our goal is to make
risk five the best iso for cryptography
in the world and we've already used a
lot of work that's appeared at ches in
hopefully uh getting closer to that goal
but we know there's a way to go
so thank you for listening to my
presentation that i realized was a
little bit all over the place but i hope
you've learned a little bit about
not only the aes instructions that we've
designed but also where they're going to
go how they're going to be used
so yeah thank you very much for
listening