hi i'm yuji koike in this video i'm
gonna talk about youroi updatable
whitebox cryptography
this is a joint work with takanori
subway
now before i talk about the main point
of our work let me get started with some
background
white box cryptography is cryptography
which ensures security of the
cryptographic keys in the white box
setting
in this setting the adversary is assumed
to have control over the execution
environment
so the adversary is allowed to observe
not only inputs and outputs of the
cryptographic algorithm but also its
internal
what's more the adversary can even
modify the internal states
this white box setting is quite
different from the standard model called
black box setting where the adversary is
allowed to observe only inputs and
outputs of the algorithm
to be more specific what can the white
box adversary do
well since white box adversary has the
control over the execution environment
she can do anything possible to come up
with
for example the adversary can observe
and modify all the states of the
algorithm like i said
and she can do memory inspection
reverse engineering of implementation
code and code tempering and so on
under such assumption there are two
requirements to design a new white box
cipher
first of all white box cipher is
required to provide key extraction
security
this security ensures that it is secure
against key extraction attack where the
adversary tries to extract the secret
key from the implementation code
in addition white box cipher has to
provide code lifting security
this security ensures that it is secure
against code lifting attack where
instead of extracting the key the lfc
tries to steal implementation code for
the cryptographic function and use it as
a large effective key in a standalone
manner
these are the two
security requirements to meet when
designing a new white box cipher
now let me show you an existing white
box cipher and how it meets these
security requirements
the basic idea for the recent ciphers is
to generate the table which comprises
the inputs for a certain cryptographic
operation and their outputs to hide the
process of cryptographic operations
for instance a white box cipher spn box
which was proposed by bogdanov at all
is based on table lookup whose table is
composed of inputs and outputs for block
cipher
it uses the table as a secret key and
looks up
values in the table for encryption and
decryption
so because of using a block cipher as an
underlying cipher for table generation
even if the adversary can see the
contents of the table what she can see
is just a set of inputs and outputs for
the cipher
as a result if the underlying block
cipher is secure in the standard black
box setting it is computationally
difficult to extract the key from the
table
therefore spn box can successfully
ensure the key extraction security by
reducing the key extraction security in
the white box setting to the key
recovery problem for the underlying
block cipher in the standard black box
setting
when it comes to code lifting security
bogdanov at all proposed a security
notion called space hardness
to quantify the security level against
the code lifting attack
space hardness shows the relationship
between the amount of stolen data and
the corresponding security level
for instance t over 4 128 spaced
hardness means that the adversary has to
steal at least one fourth of the table
to compute the input with the
probability of more than two to the
power of minus 128.
spn box 16 provides this security level
in terms of called lifting security
in other words spin box 16 whose total
table size t is
128 kilobytes ensures sufficient
security even if one fourth table data
is linked to the adversary
however space hardness is just
mitigation of code lifting attack
why because this security notion cannot
deal with continuous leakage
even if t over 4 128 space hardness
ensures some security level in the
situation where one force of the table
is leaked by continuously stealing the
table data the amount of stolen dollar
will be more than t over 4
and eventually that amount will reach t
which means
the adversary will succeed in
cold lifting attack in the end
this figure shows relationship between
time and corresponding security level z
when considering the leakage of a
certain amount on a daily basis
it shows that security level drops
constantly to zero
so what can we do about it
well as a countermeasure it is natural
to think that we update the secret key
or the table in this context
however this counter measure would come
with two disadvantages
first this counter measure will need a
lot of computational cost
and second it will increase security
risk
in the following slides i will talk
about these disadvantages in more detail
by taking mobile payment application as
an example
so mobile payment application is a
typical application in which whitebox
cryptography is applicable
in this context whitebox cipher is used
to protect payment credentials to
encrypting them
in this example let's say spin box 16
whose table size is 128 kilobytes is
used to protect them
and the adversary is insidiously staying
in the system and continuously steals
the terrible data for spn box 16 little
by little
in this case spin box 16 has the
property of t over 4 128 space hardness
so even if the top table data of 32
gigabytes is stolen by the adversaries
spin box 16 can ensure sufficient
security
however the problem is after the leakage
amount reached t over 4.
if we do nothing then the security level
drops as shown in the upper right figure
so in order to ensure constant security
it is necessary to update the table
before the leakage amount reached d over
4.
however this causes us two problems
which are computational cost and
security risk
first of all regarding the computational
cost
updating the table means it requires
re-encryption of payment credentials
when updating the table first it is
necessary to decrypt the encrypted
credentials with the old table
and then encrypt the credentials again
with a new table
this encryption is a additional cost to
avoid if possible
second when it comes to security risk
re-encryption gives more chance for the
adversary to see the payment credentials
in the plain text form
right after the decryption of the
encrypted credentials with the old table
they are in the plaintext form
so if the adversary stays in the system
it is possible to see them
so in order to solve these problems we
believe white box ciphers would need a
new property
which ensures constant security while
maintaining the same functionality under
the continuous leakage
because a cipher with this property
would provide constant security even in
the situation of continuous leakage
what's more since a cipher with this
property can maintain the same
functionality
it wouldn't need a re-encryption
and we define this new property as the
longevity
the formal definition is in our paper so
if i talk about the definition of the
longevity in more casual way then
i would say a cipher with the longevity
ensures that even in the situation of
continuous leakage
the upper bounds of success probability
for called lifting attack is less than 2
power by minus
z while keeping the same functionality
at every single point
this property deals with continuous
leakage and as a result the g longevity
can enhance
cold lifting security
in order to ensure the longevity
we designed a new cryptographic scheme
which can maintain the same
functionality even after table updates
by table updates this scheme aims to
ensure constant security
and by keeping the same functionality it
can get rid of
re-encryption in the following slides i
will discuss our approach for the design
in more detail step by step
so white box ciphers are basically table
based ciphers
which means they simply look up in the
tables repeatedly for encryption and
decryption just like the figure on the
left
in order to keep the same functionality
even after table update
we put another encryption algorithm eki
and the corresponding decryption
algorithm dki between tables just like
the figure on the right
and then we combine one table and eki to
create ti1
and combine one table and dki to create
ti2
with this approach the functionality of
the algorithm on the right and
the one on the left are equivalent
because eki and the dki on the right are
cancelled out
also by updating the key ki for eki and
dki and creating different tables the
algorithm on the right can keep the same
functionality even after the table
updates
however in reality white box ciphers are
much more complicated
for instance there might be mds linear
layer between table lookups in the
algorithm so that it can ensure
diffusion
in this case putting ek and dk between
tables cannot
keep same functionality
because once
output of ek goes through mds linear
layer
the value of output will be changed and
the changed output cannot be decrypted
by decay successfully
in other words this mds linear layer
prevents ek and dk from being cancelled
out
so in order to solve this problem
we split the output of table lookup into
two parts
in this approach one part skips mds
layer and the other part goes through it
with this approach eki and edki are
successfully cancelled out
and we can ensure that the functionality
on the left and the one on the right are
equivalent
also even after updating the key ki for
eki and dki
the functionality remains equivalent
so the essential approach is to update
key ki for eki and dki
so that it can update table ti-1 and ti2
and keep the same functionality
in addition in order to maintain the
same functionality we split the output
into two parts
one part goes through eki and then
directory goes to dki
and the other part goes through mds
layer and goes to another table lookup
now what's important is that the key of
the underlying cipher for s remains
unchanged
these approaches helps to keep the same
functionality
so based on the approaches we
constructed uri which is composed of
five elements
first of table si which is based on the
dedicated block cipher for sbn box
with different key for s1 s2 and s3
second ek and dk
in our construction small scale aes or
small scale present are
suitable and then after layer and mds
matrix layer
it is important to note that the output
of eki never goes through these layers
so that it can keep the same
functionality even after the table
updates
and finally can round a s in the last
round
the reason why we put this aes layer is
that this simplifies the security
evaluation in the black box setting
based on these elements we constructed
two variants which are euro 32 and euro
16.
they both take 128 bits data as an input
when it comes to euro 32 each table
takes 32 bits input
and the output of table lookup is
splitted into two parts
one is 28 bits long and the other is
four bits long
total runs are for euro 32 is 16.
and regarding the mds layer we used
cyclic matrix which is used in picorl
now let me discuss security in the
standard blackbox setting
in this setting the adversary is allowed
to observe inputs and outputs of the
cryptographic algorithm
in this case security of uri in the
black box setting
is reduced to security of aes
because euro has 10 round as in the last
round
when it comes to security in the white
box setting
where the adversary is allowed to
observe inputs outputs and their
internal states of the cryptographic
algorithm
there are two requirements
first regarding key extraction security
of euro e
at least it is reduced to the key
recovery problem for the underlying
cipher of spin box in the black box
setting
this is because even if the adversary
can see the internal states
what she can see is inputs and outputs
of table
which are inputs and outputs of the
underlying ciphers
moreover
partial output is also encrypted by
another encryption algorithm
so at least key extraction security in
the white box setting is reduced to the
underlying block cipher for the table
also regarding the code lifting security
in order to ensure t over for 128 space
hardness
which the existing ciphers provides
8 and 16 rounds should be enough for uri
16 and euro 32 respectively
please refer to our paper for how to
actually evaluate the code lifting
security if you are interested
now let me talk about what's missing in
the existing ciphers
in other words longevity
when we consider the continuous leakage
the longevity is useful
let me take uroy32 as an example
and let's say 24 megabytes of the table
data is leaked on a daily basis
then as shown in figure the security
level drops to 2 powered by -120
in
512 days
at this point by updating tables it can
keep this security level for longer
so by repeating the table updates at
proper timings
euros32 can maintain these security
levels
which means euro e32 can ensure 128
longevity
finally let me talk a little bit about
performance of uri
we measured a single encryption
performance and parallel encryption
performance of uri
and compared with those of the existing
ciphers
the base of our comparison is table
input space
in other words we compared euro 32 with
spn box 32 white block 32 space 32 and
galaxy 32
and compared euro 16
with espn box 16 white block 16 space 16
and galaxy 16 and wem
from the perspective of encryption
performance
for the detail of measurement
environment please refer to our paper
now what the performance results shows
as a whole is that uri is competitive
with other existing ciphers
while it can ensure the new property
called longevity
for instance compression of euro 16 with
the other ciphers tells us that even
though galaxy 16 is the fastest uri 16
is competitive with it
in conclusion in this work we proposed
and defined a new property called
longevity for white box ciphers and we
proposed a new design of white box
cipher called uroi
which ensures longevity and
is as fast as the existing ciphers in
terms of encryption performance
thank you
you