under hey hi everyone I will talk about
abusing bash on Windows the idea of the
presentation is you've got some code
execution on a Windows box there is some
bash on it's like cygwin or WSL and what
can you do with that in order to do some
post exploitation I'm a pen tester
identity security firms and though I
will talk about
Bashan window the facts is interesting
for an attacker auto backdoor its and
some other stuff about a broker in
forensics or the script of the
presentation are available on github the
aim is to be reproducible by you and if
you need to do the stuff you can do it
just by copy pasting my scripts so
Marshall on Windows knows we have to to
software there is sigmund since 2001
it's not distributed by Microsoft's it's
even worse in 6p that's it's working on
older version and since two years since
two years we have WSL windows subsystem
for linux it's it's Myra plus cygwin in
the time it's not installed by default
on Windows that's it edited by Microsoft
and for now it's only for Windows 10 and
Windows Server 2000 online team I looked
for some previous research on these
tools I didn't find anything on cygwin
only some CD and as wsl is very young
there is some there are some research
@rickeon or blue hats so how can you
install it cygwin it sabbatic
installation file for wsl it's little
more complicated you need to enable
developer mods reboots at the windows
subsystem for linux reboots and then you
will have on the Microsoft Store some
different subsystem and you can
understand all the subsystem on the same
computer you can have Debian on curry
and open SUSE and so on for cygwin it's
just a classical installation file you
just have to choose your package at the
installation and the main difference
between this both system is that cygwin
is running some P file
it's bash but it's executable file from
the windows world in WS l you are
running real
elf file and you can compete compiled a
file on you
classical Linux put it on Windows and
execute seeds cygwin is on the C folder
and for for the fun facts everyone can
read every file in cygwin so if you have
two users in the cygwin walls the first
user can read the fight from the second
user so if you stored you SSH key on
cygwin everyone can read every one of
the system can read them without being
system for W said it's a little small
but it's more complicated because at the
beginning there were only open two on
Windows so there were only one pass for
the file of the Linux file system and
since there is a lot of vision they did
stuff with some package and you can have
many folders and many file system and if
you install Kali on debian on your
windows you will have two Linux file
system
two Linux kernel and so on at the first
run when you run cygwin it just created
some classical window a linux file like
bash RC and so on on oh it's small when
you run a wsl system at the first time
it asks you for a password for your
pseudo icons because you have sudo on on
wsl and the fun fact with that is a very
studio and you run bash on the very cell
you will not be able to run at the
shadow because you are not fruits but
the filesystem is stored in your own app
data file so you can read it from
windows so you've got a password that
you cannot read from bash but you can
read from simply dot eggsy they are
stored here this is the old version at
the top at at the bottom it's the newer
version the package name depends on the
sub system you used and the version I
did a Metasploit post module that will
try to find every shadow file and
download its if you already have got
execution and if your system you can
read every with a Linux file system of
every user you can easily called your
cygwin or your Bosch system from windows
for cygwin you have to use the full path
of the scripts and for W cell there is a
variable in the past that can you can
allow you to use bash or Debian and so
on there is they're out there and you
can do the other way you can call some
Windows command from the Linux system by
using the full pass or just running
simply that's easy so you can run bad
for energy simply from bash or even back
from CMD and so on it's like an
inception it's kind beyond a normal
thing that's you can think it's a normal
thing you can create a file from windows
and read it's in your Linux file system
here I'm creating the file from the
Linux file system from windows and I can
read it the same thing for cygwin but on
the first version on wsl if you create C
created a file from windows the fight
didn't exist in the Linux file system
and this created the first program of
wsl it's the AV wasn't able to monitor
what's was happening in this system so
at the at the beginning of WL you had a
lot of malware that cannot be seen in
the subsystem nor they are seen but the
fun fact is if you created a metal
Porter for Windows most of the AV will
know it's as malicious file and if you
created a metal plate or for Linux it
will not be seen by so many AV so after
you have your Linux file system
WS save that can run elf file you can
run Linux malicious file and evade some
AV on the system so why I've been
interested in in bath for Windows the
user or thus that tools are developers
and means incident response team and
everything and I can do on the Linux box
I cannot do it on a on our we are on the
windows box and I can also try to use
malware from the Linux world everything
next is assume that you already have
occurred
education on the machine it's not a ving
code execution it just post exploitation
some example it's you've got a remote
code execution on a computer on or to
either reverse shell into WSL process
because it's less money told or you want
to you have a remote code execution
there is wsl you read the it's shadow
file you're able to crack the rush
maybe this password is used somewhere
else though for the remote shell parts
are there is two point there is the
one-liner remerge tell you can have from
Linux systems and the Met reporter one
so I just look for a cheat sheet from
pen test monkey a list of unlike
one-liner reverse shell I just don't use
Java because I had to compile some stuff
and I look into every system which one
is using by defaults a bash / and so on
and you've got a lots of remote shell by
defaults there's just some Ruby or nut
cut which is not working that cut is
because you don't have the - each option
and for Ruby it's because I'm pen test
on kids for Ruby 1:9 and know you have
Ruby 2 to 1 to 2 so on so you can easily
change the line and it's still working
if you really want to use a reverse
shell from a tube that is not in style
you might be able to install it on W
said it's like on your classic clinics
you just need to be routes on the Linux
and for cygwin you need to have look at
a new sort of period so it can be odd
and for the meat of metal perturb parts
as I told before sequin is not able to
run elf so it's not working but WL can
run elf so the I don't know why stage
payload not working and wsl but stage
late stage less payload dude so you can
easily having a metal praetor ear it's a
Linux meterpreter run on WL and then you
can call your Cindy that's easy in a
view CMD from Linux rivers shell and
there is no screen in the evaluation
it's not working even if you install
it's it will not work but you have
timers which is working so you can
your rivers shell in WSL and the user
will only see a Bosch process running
and without know what is running in is
the other stuff is oh can we steal
passwords ashore elevates using bash the
first case is I had a small scripted
bash startup it's very classic on the
Linux world and back doing Linux and
it's performing a simple request to my
computer so ID is to coach to call the
SMB request with responder I can do that
from the windows world I have got
execution I can already do that that's
if a back door if I backdoor bash every
time the guy will you run bash and I
will have the ash and if he changes
password because you have to change
password every I don't know 60 day I
will have the new ash every 60 day or if
I can execute code on a computer which
is of the network for the Opera analog
computers I can do that and when you go
back on the network I can get the ash so
it's pretty small scripts anyone you can
use responder to catch the ash or use a
relay attached and it's it's pretty easy
to you just the iron here it's cygwin i
back no cygwin I quit and when the user
will run cygwin again it will perform
SMB request so there is no request here
the user is running cygwin that's the
little Bistro I don't know because it's
signal and I have got my SMB requests on
the network okay so I can cause it
after that it's although some classical
stuff like get the bash sudo password so
it's not working on Sivan because there
is no sudo the IDS to created a fake
sudo spritz we asked the password to the
user and then we ran the real sudo
scripts sudo binaries pretty easy you
can either pass on a file system or
sauna terminal network it's it's nothing
really new then
it's just that you can steal a password
and maybe it will be reused somewhere
else so it's you can see it a lot so we
can see the ribs to the one when the
user rerun again it has for his password
so every time you run sudo the first
time it failed so it may give him a hint
that there is something wrong and it can
fade four times that it's this is not
normal on Linux so it will other ins of
that but you already have the passwords
yeah we can do that but we can also ask
for the Windows password from bash every
time you run WSL if there is updates
needed it will told you a guy you need
to update double yourself so you just
add to that a small script asking for
his password and you can get it it's oh
it's this it's really the same idea it's
just about having the windows part and
you can do that because you can interact
between Windows and Linux and you can
get is windows username from the Linux
system very easily it's here it's a
domain account already you can see
actually the actual service on our crew
domain so you can get this password and
you can do stuff really realistic but it
will run every time so it can give in
students2 okay and the force ID I add it
was about asking admin privilege you may
just want to ask the user to run
privilege software like Metro pitcher or
mimikatz
so that's I found three of shell they
run us from the command line to run us
from portion and she'll run us from
system Turner's for the runners from the
CLI it's not working because it's you
run the windows binary it's asking for
you is it's asking you to type the
passwords in
windows Cindy you are not in the windows
team diesel is crushing on PowerShell
stuff that's what is really nice it's
the user must elevate if you use a known
privilege icons it will not work it will
ask him the to retype password and if
you run the scripts it will told you
that you are running Windows come on
processor so if you put meta meta
sprites on mini cats in CMD fire a bad
file if we told you our it's signed by
Microsoft's but it's not and if you are
using sysinternals there is some stuff
like saying sysinternals but it's pretty
weird so as the user must elevate with
PowerShell I should that and it's okay
the next one right is the same is will
just ask for the password of the user
but you are not stealing the password
you are just getting privileged icon so
I try with the non privileged accounts
he will told me this request an
elevation and then I will get my it's
not a script I just run assembly for the
demo and I am looking at min with that
so that's just basic Linux stuff on
Windows but what about up Locker I'm not
sure to tell you all to implement up
lockers there is a lot of stuff on the
internet
- well implement a broker's there is
some default route default rules from
Makeup Microsoft's which are some time
runs because you can execute everything
from the windows folder and there isn't
on folder termed folder in it's my idea
was to say okay your restricts at the
user with a broker and you allow him to
run cygwin all bash and what can be done
now here i cannot run scripts from the
cygwin pass because i forgot i forbid
the scripts but I can read I can run
sorry I can run bash scripts from
sigmund it's normal and if I try to do
that I'll WI said it's the same thing
that's if I try to call some same GGG on
some and I is forbidden I
not be able to do this now I try to
compile a hello world file on cygwin I
try to execute it and it failed because
as I told you before it's a P file and
the P file is forbidden but if you do
that w cell you will be able to run you
your Linux file so you can even if there
is a poker if W said is authorized you
can compile everything you want and do
what she wants
this only stuff is that GCC is only
enabled with less other punches for
Windows I also asked myself if I can
bypass my screen but in fact small
screen ism can be bypassed only by
running your binary from just come
online so and that's point some question
about forensics because now you have to
look into the system for forensic the
bash history the path and so on and for
example if you run cygwin and another
user is running cygwin and you do PS you
will see this process but as every users
own wsl you won't see this process and
if you try to dump memory from a task
manager from elf which is running you
won't be able to do that because windows
don't know to do it so I can windows our
windows can handle the WCA memory on you
can or can you investigate wsl sub
process such as will not run by you and
so on ok and the end is just someone who
sits I don't know if some of you
remember new win32 is just some shell
escape from mostly CTF and how to do
them on a new wind 32 ok is there any
question any questions in the room and
well Tony you'll be around outside if
anybody wants to speak so thank you very
much
you