go for it all right hi everyone
the start is too condensed version of an
earlier talks that's why there's like
slides and stuff basically the idea here
is don't leave parts unknown it's a
recipe for ethical documentation Who am
I I'm this guy back in engineer and also
I do a lot of security things for a
company called wetransfer in the
Netherlands it's not very interesting
what is interesting is good
documentation you may think oh no that's
not interesting but trust me it does our
jobs as developers and people who are
interested in making things better for
our co-workers and our users are easier
and more interesting if people are able
to do security things for themselves or
anything for themselves really but
because this is a security conference
who the more people get security the
more people are able to pick up things
that were working on projects that we're
making tutorials that we write the more
people are able to implement things and
it becomes less and less of our job to
say oh no there's a header missing
whatever it's and we the the things we
get to tackle become more interesting
and the things that other people get to
deal with to come at us are also more
interesting and more difficult so net
profit right so how do we do that so I
think I don't know this guy Anthony
Bourdain sadly died earlier this year
but he really had kind of this over the
years of his growth as a person he
became well known for meeting people
where they were he started off as kind
of like yeah it's crazy there's drugs
and I'm gonna eat some weird meat and
yeah but then eventually it turned into
he would use that as an opportunity to
really get to meet people and talk and
work with them kind of in the spaces
where they lived and worked and I think
we can apply these rules to
documentation so five rules rules zero
have documentation yes good okay thank
you no rule to you want to have friendly
documentation I think you should avoid
where it was a really good tweet and I
can't find it anymore and it's killing
me but the idea was you shouldn't in
your Docs for your projects and your
things you should try to avoid words
like easily your obvious or as you can
see
see that thing with the last night
anyway the you can use this and just
login it's great but there isn't that
for people's brains
you should be as explicit as possible
consider your naming the AWS
documentation sorry if anyone who works
on that is here but it is a great
example of how not to do that they have
like 15 different things that all have
exactly the same name ok 3 in this
example but really like and that are
interchangeable and but are all actually
the same thing anyway so if you want
people to use your stuff don't do that 3
you don't have 3 the text it's just an
example of what not to do you want to
have reliable useful error messages we
get a lot of things like in our in our
disclosure program that are like hey
your websites on the internet and
there's like 800 paragraphs of text
about why that's bad but know it's
supposed to be there so you have to
think about kind of the the balance
between when you when you send things
back to users like is it understandable
and does it tell them enough but does
not tell them too much that's really
hard number 4 don't assume a particular
level of skill we like that someone
brought up earlier and I yesterday the
Mossad or not Mossad distinction a lot
most users I would say are not Mossad no
matter their level of skill right we're
not all of us worked for intelligence
agencies I don't know exactly exactly
well that's your own problem I guess but
what this just means those that when
you're or can't documentation and
writing things you you don't want to
assume that people who are really
skilled are gonna pick up your stuff
immediately but you also don't want to
assume the same thing of people who
aren't so yeah it's tough yep so as for
things and also have documentation I
think he's you know he said once you
have to be a romantic to invest yourself
your money and your time and cheese I
think the same thing is true of really
good project and system documentation I
think that's me
the end
you