okay so hi everyone and thank you for
joining me for this talk
my name is Mathieu tall I'm real excited
to be here today and I got you and I
both shrubs intention today about how to
debug a process from the hypervisor so
the agenda for today is that we are
going to review what are the concrete
benefits of having hypervisor level
debuggers they're going to quickly
review the existing projects and I'm
going to explain why I decided to start
my own implementation of this tool first
Who am I I'm currently a researcher at
f-secure well I'm focusing on building
Sun box solutions and mainly stealth Sun
boxes so my main focus is on the other
machine introspection VMI is let's say a
way to analyze the contents of a virtual
machine from the outside from the
hypervisor level and I did that
expression especially on on a VM so the
k vm VMI project is what I've started to
let's say a common effort to bring an
official VMI API on KVM that's me to my
background so now it's not why why
hypervisor level debuggers are relevant
the first problem I can think of is my
own arises it's because the burgers are
noisy the debugger will always modify
let's say the execution environments of
a debug II it's kind of this observer
effect that you cannot avoid and usually
it's not a problem until you have to
deal with a malware but the core problem
of that is that our debugging API our
operating system debugging FBI I've
never been designed to deal with my rels
in the first place and we are still
trying to a nice memory of that so we
are building workarounds and and it's
not really working so and we need to
find more permanent solution to this
problem the second Primerica I can think
of is that sometime this observer effect
is intentional sometimes you have some
closed source operating systems out
there which are just trying to protect
their features if you enable the debug
debugging on on windows it will disable
first patch guard
and then disable the protected media
pass the protect media buff is a
requirement to analyze - let's say it
starts with protected environment to
allow the execution of a drm so if you
want to analyze drm execution you know
let's use a debugger for that because
it's protected and the third program I
can think of is that what you see here
is the virtualization based modsecurity
model of Windows 10 you have the normal
kernel supported from the secure kernel
and you have hyper-v managing all of
that you can analyze and debug the
normal cone on there is an extension to
debug the hyper-v kernel drop hyper-v
sorry but there is so far not an easy
way to debug the secure kernel so we may
need to find a solution for that also
so the solution I would like to use is
to stop hacking around in the kernel and
rebase our entire debugging platforms on
the hypervisor itself to gain more
privileges first what we're gain is
stealth
the stealth we need to analyze my rails
first because we are not using the
operating system debug API of course so
we don't leave any traces and the second
thing is that we can use invisible debug
break points thanks to EPT violations
and the second advantage is that we'll
have the full system analyzes the
hypervisor has a full view of a system
of the guest state at any time so you
have the entire control and on top of
that you can debug good loaders because
your debugger is available from the time
your protein system is booting but more
than that you have some benefits
depending how you implement Sharper by
the liver debugger you can have
unmodified guest you can use your raw
veteran machine right away
so no serial cable no specific hardware
and the specific guest configuration to
enable the debugging and plus you have
this on the flight debugging so
debugging a virtual machine without
having to reboot it I'll change the
configuration and the last benefit I can
think of is that what we want we can aim
for is the cross-platform debugging
infrastructure
where my hypervisor is able to debug the
kernel of Windows Linux and Mac OS with
the same tool think about it we can have
an ice agnostic debugger which on top of
which you are building your knowledge
and your scripts so it's quite
convenient so now it's reviewed existing
projects that we have and the video
history are they used are remain
contained I fitted this into two
categories the first one is bare metal
debuggers this kind of debuggers are in
are being used to a debug real hardware
so the first one I can think of is
hybrid EBG hybrid EBG what they wanted
to do is to see if it was possible to
take the full control our production
system for forensic purposes and how did
they do that is by using a term called
hyper jackin hyper jackin is that I'm
going to take my hosts and viateur eyes
it on the fly so dynamically I'm going
to insert a hypervisor on the fly so
beforehand they are they've been
building a driver and in studying it on
the on the host and this is this rising
the host using the driver so everything
happens on the same machine and if you
press the key f12 you have this
graphical interface which is appearing
and which is the debugger itself now the
problem with that is that hypervisor is
writing directly to the video card frame
buffer so it's hardly maintainable let's
move to the next project without DB g
VAR DB g what i wanted to do is to
analyze password and patrick rod
specifically the obfuscation behind
patch guard so the same idea using hyper
jackin but this time it's a bit better
because well they used a DMA attack to
have a read and write access to the
physical memory and inject their own
driver into into Windows
so it's bit better because the guest
doesn't know that's what's happening and
you don't have to install a driver
beforehand
everything happens dynamically and the
driver is injected into the guest so
it's better than hyper hyper gene in
this way and there's a DVD protocol
because if there is a client and a
server but you can do better and first
dbg is doing better than that
what he wanted to do first was to have a
better windbg UI that's what's the main
reason why I started this project so I
started reversing the windbg protocol
and at the same time he realized he was
also writing a hypervisor so he said
okay I can merge both of this project in
the same tool that's what he did and
with proxy BG you have to okay change
your boot sequence because the
hypervisor is written inside an EFI
module so when you put your pansy
protein system you're going to boot on
either a USB key or a TV FTP server
which is going to provide you this EFI
audio and then it's going to be able to
get your eyes any operating system
behind it so first DVD is better than
the previous one because there's no
driver
it's an ef5 module and then there is
another category which I would call
theater machine debuggers on this
category Rob what we want to debug
virtual address and we take an existing
hypervisor and we are trying to build
our debugging API inside it the first
one in particular can think of is pirate
box maybe I've heard of it what I wanted
to have is let's say a diamond dynamic
instrumentation system a high-level
we've a lot of callbacks
so instrumented the whole Kim Kim you as
an emulator they added plenty of
callbacks inside it and it's great
because you can have even callbacks on
instruction level or when a block starts
of end and on top of that you have
high-level scripts in Python to
introspect the guest so it's really
great for my mind Maran arises and it's
maintained at the same time and the
second project I have is our VM I so I
VMI what he wanted to do is to see why a
marathon Paul didn't run in their
sandbox and analyze it understand it
so they took free call as the eventual
record the memory forensic framework
throttle volatility and the I did a
debugger on top of it and at the added
the instrumented KVM hypervisor to add
breakpoints inside it so it's also
maintained and it's really a great tool
so that's a bit what what we have in
terms of hypervisor level debuggers
project as of today but now we're
we move from here should I use one of
these projects or no well what I want to
do is my analysis that's my first goal
the premise that I don't want to use
Pyrrha box because it's emulation based
and I would like to keep the speed of
hardware virtualization and I'm very
interested in our EMI it looks really
great and I'm going to have to let's say
some issue of the design of our VMI I'd
like to improve it
so our keep our EMI as a focus and
improve improve it what we what you're
seeing is that say a somatic version of
the design of our VMI we take Rico as
the main tool and then we are going to
add a debugger on top of it which is
communicating with communicating with
Kim UK via on top of this what I would
like to do is to first add vmi
introspection that you're out like a
hypervisor via my layer so I don't want
to be tied to one specific hypervisor
like the hypervisor independence and the
second modification is that I would like
to take a good reverse engineering tool
of the burger as my main tool and add
the spore introspection layer on top of
it the goal is to be more maintainable
in the future that's my design how do
you how can you be hypervisor agnostic
where we have a library for that it's go
live VM I leave VMI is a very VMI
abstraction layer it will take care of
for you of low-level details like
parsing the page tables or intercepting
hardware events and if you also offer
you some basic introspection like
translating a kernel symbol to other
advice but the more important thing to
remember about the VMI in that it
defines you and unified it's a VMI
interface across all hypervisors
so if you want to be live in my
application you use VMI as as the first
library so what does the hypervisor
support for IBM I exam is fully
supported at this moment they have a
registered memory and hardware events
and KVM is on its way
thanks to be defender who have been
writing awesome patches for that
so this is my final architecture I will
use rod re as well as the main tool for
debugging because it's really flexible
and it allows me to write a debugger
back back-end and implement my own
debugger with plugins I will I write an
i origin which will deal with English
icing leave Vienna in accessing the
memory and a debug plug-in which will
deal with all the hardware events and
the debugging events so as the status of
this project as of today well what I can
do today is to intercept a process in
the guests using intercepting the CR
free single step in the execution and
setting some memory breakpoints or
software breakpoints or so I can load
the symbols thanks to the recall profile
and have the whole rather to interface
on top of that so I've I've I've graphed
scripts structures and every and it's or
everything that rather to can basically
provide so now maybe let's have a demo
DT yes okay can see so I'm starting
here my debugger we've Rada this is my
VM and I'm starting by debugger and I
would like to intercept explore that exe
as you can see i intercepted CR three
loads until the schedule of schedules
has been has been scheduling extra dot
exe then after that I would like to load
my symbols so that means command that
Baxter symbols to load the kernel
symbols then I would like to add the
breakpoints so I have all the kernel
symbols loaded into radar too and I
would like to I the breakpoints on NT
Open File like this and then I'm going
to continue the execution and I will
trigger an T opens file by opening its
product exe right like this and as you
can see if i disassemble
we are at ng open file the beginning of
the Cisco also I can single step
execution like this yes and if I analyze
this Cisco I can have the graph view or
productive ok so now we have to grab the
graph view a frittata - I can single
step inside this graph view and you can
have the disassembly of IOP create file
dynamically on the fly in the guest but
I would like to go a bit further than
that I would like to have more
introspection so I developed on top of
recall a plug-in that allows me to
access live via my and access the
physical memory of the guest immediately
I don't want to make memory terms I want
to recall to work on top of the physical
memory of the guest that's what this
plug-in does so I can run PS list
directly it's going to check the
physical memory and I can also run the
other list or every any record plug-in
that you want and I can use this
introspection to like these addresses
inside rather - of course here I'm going
to take the base address of a DLL I'm
going to stick to it inside the physical
memory and if I print I have the
beginning of a PE either so now it's q2
the next demo you can script with Radha
- you have read - pipe first I'm using
here this R I recall vmi address space
to get the address of a Cisco and I
added or at breakpoint on top of it and
opening Libra to pipe a python binding -
rather - and continue execution
so here are the Python script which
rerun the SS DT plug-in retrieve recall
to extract the Cisco's and/or of that I
was going to set a breakpoint on ng open
file everything happens in Python here
so it's a script Python script okay now
if I love my prec point which is set and
I can intercept any open file and print
out the object name associated so now
what is the future of this project I
have some challenges of course because I
would like not to intercept you see are
free but to attach to a fred's context
and r.i.p i would like to break on be
able to break on and map addresses by
injecting page faults i would like to
improve the introspection layer and
there's many challenges interesting
challenges to be to resolved on top of
this but the important thing is that my
goal is to do more analysis now like to
invent is this kind of a framework while
you have this via my sandbox which Zelda
link this is dealing with extracting all
the basic information that you can have
combined with this vmi debugger which is
giving you a fine grain control over the
malware execution and you can also think
of use over this case as phasing or
maybe try to debug the Windows 10 secure
kernel the important thing to remember
is that right to VMI is a multi-purpose
respect from for system debugger and by
design its peel built for the long-term
reusing a maximum of components and also
is hypervisor agnostic by design I would
like to thank all of these people for
helping me especially the people from
radar - well me all a lot and ties for
pushing me to submit even though I just
ideas in my mind for this project and
I'm available for questions thank you
for attention
[Applause]
hey thank you so any questions in the in
the room in questions okay as we short
for time we'll move on you're gonna be
around so people have I'll be around
thank you oh there's a question over
there just a quick one can you put the
github address back up after that all
right maybe I was a bit quick because of
the time but here you go
sure any more questions or requests for
other slides am I getting in the way
okay well thank you again Matthew thank
you everyone
[Applause]