good morning everybody thank you very
much for coming to this early thought my
name is tight Mui my colleague sit Rao
was supposed to give this talk with me
but uh unfortunately he's gonna come
today we are both doctoral student from
alcone University in Finland and our
research focuses on analysis and design
of Plato's acute that level protocols as
well application security in this talk
have we thought about security of
inter-process communication or I can see
in this talk I will show that
application developer usually think that
IPC is inherently secure and don't pay
much attention in securing it I will
show that this is a huge misconception
as the data transfer over IPC you should
be protected in the same way as always
the internet so the structure of the
Tory has followed I first discuss the
threat model that we call bans abortion
or Midna and then I will warm up with
some basic about IPC and its attack
vectors which make many software
vulnerabilities meet my threat model we
can go through some case studies of
real-world software applications that
are vulnerable to the Midna attack model
and finally I will sum up with some
mitigation mechanism all right so let us
get started first let us understand or
the man is a machine threat model so we
see software with client-server
architecture everywhere
let's take the browser and web server
for example in the traditional network
threat model the user device and the
server are typically trusted with a
network in hostile so tackler can do
various type attack such a man in the
middle to steal the data that exchange
over the Internet and since we are aware
of such attacks we use crypto solutions
such a PKI such as TOS and replica I to
protect the communication however in
three
be not all the communication goes over
the network certain violence
communications that happen within the
computer for example software often
comprised of the funnel that provided
GUI and the back end Samaras data
there's separate processes and they use
a mechanism called inter-process
communications or I pcs to access data
this communications stay within the
computer and Emily outside however they
can be adjust the component inside the
computer and protecting the user
information exchange of IPC is equally
important as always the network so for
these reasons in this work we try to
understand the security of the
communication inside a computer with
focus on IPC security this is a bit mad
threat model we consider the threat from
malicious processes inside the computer
however we are not interested in manual
because we think that if the computer is
infected with malware
everything will be compromised so
instead we're interested in legitimate
processes run by other users and this
process are supposed to be on the
computer in our trap model the attacker
can be any unprivileged user that tried
to steal sensitive information from
other users on a same computer the
example of potential bit metals our
colleague or you know family members and
the toilet system here is any multi-user
computer you know computers that can be
accessed by multiple users are very
common think of enterprises and
university for example well centralized
access control used to allow an employee
or student to login to any computer and
in some environment everyone have their
own credentials have their own personal
computer but this computer can be
accessed by any domain users with their
own credentials
and we found that we also found that a
typo cami and they guess you were too
many operating system such as you would
do the enable just access by default so
the title could be anyone not as
insiders so how does a meet my attacker
to attack other users on the same
computer the attack method here is to
run malicious process from attackers or
locking sessions and they say by taxi
attack scenario is as follows so take a
science to the victims computer with his
own credentials and run the evil process
he uses fast user switching on Windows
to leave the login session in the
background so this way the evil process
will continue running in the background
and try to exploit the IPC of the victim
where the victim is using the computer
or malice analytics is even easier
because a process can be kept running in
the background without leaving the lucky
assassin in the background and things
could even be worse if they remote
access such an SSH or windows remote
desktop enabled computer with these the
attacker could run the evil process from
remotely so before talking about how
sweet the attacker their exploit IVC use
in security critical applications let us
now look deeper into IPC and its
appetite better there are many types of
IPC's and not all the vulnerable to the
Midna attack model it's a common feature
of vulnerable IPC's is that the server
process buys to a name or an identifier
and wasteful combination from client
processes and in this work we focus on
three IPC metals which are going to
socket
name pipe and USB human interface device
strictly speaking USB is not IPC however
USB communication also happen inside a
computer
and shared common feature of the as ad
the vulnerable IPC made hood so it
leaves the mid-market eager to exploit
it
there are also IPC method that are
secured against our attacker model such
as socket pairs or vampire so do you see
that both the communication and poise of
this communication channel
I created by the same process at the
same time so this way but untrusted
process cannot get in this middle and
explore the channel and now let us take
a look at each observe unibrow by throat
one by one let's begin with general
socket so even though they will suck it
usually used over the network in
computer network it can also be used as
AI BC and in fact one of the most widely
used IP see here the server listens are
also the Luba interface on a specific
port number and wait for client
relations as long as the port number is
higher than what how they actually form
and it process regardless of its pruner
owner can listen on support and with
channel socket only single process can
listen to a port at the time but
multiple client can connect to a server
and there's no beauty in access control
to restrict who can bees and power cable
socket communications so this leaves
local Tigers like meat man to exploit it
and one of the obvious things that a bid
man a title can do is client
impersonation
the title can fry the port number from
documentation source code or simply by
running Nestor and connect to the server
as a client so there could be cases
where the local server accepts only one
clinicians so it's a our cycle comes
later
it's request will be discarded by a
server in such cases the attacker just
need to connect to a server before the
legitimate client does
so the question here it's quiet
impersonation can be done that is it
also possible to do server impersonation
well yes so the attacker just had to
start a local server
before the midnight server does and
that's nothing that can stop this attack
so client would not notice that it
connect without notice this is not the
right server and simply connect to
support and start HS information so at
this point cells you might have noticed
that legitimate and malicious servers
can not by the same point at the same
time so can meet molecular Duhamel's me
to attack although that was Saki
communications well it's still possible
so here I take the first needs to
perform serving personation
that is it runs a local server on the
legitimate server ports and on this
primary port he can receive condition
from the client many software while
running local server they feel overall
to ascend in the report when the primary
point is already taken this one agility
makes sense from a software point of
view because this software they don't
use standard port number so some as a
legitimate process on the computer my
already hectic in the pot so switching
to another pot last make sense here but
this however keep antibodies to the
attacker because after doing the server
impersonation it's a meat mallet I just
need to connect to the realized server
on the side of the report and that to
perform the clients of to to perform the
client personalized attack and then so
and that we have the man's middle then
of course the cases where such facility
is not implemented in such scenario so
attacker can switch his role between
impersonating impersonating a server and
client he can time it well and exchange
information with
the midnight client and the midnight
server similar to that of man's middle
however this will be slower so now that
we know that was socket on localhost and
wouldn't wrote a bitmap what about the
Empire so net parts are available on
most operating system however they
differ in the implementation here we are
interested only in windows in Windows
named pipe windows name by have a
similar client-server architecture like
metal socket but instead of localhost
with an empire instance are placed in
sepsis versa path where everyone can
access including guest users and instead
of the pod number this name pipe has a
specific name we die without socket
there's always one server and multiple
client can connect to it but here with
them path they can be multiple instances
of a named pipe and all this instance II
share the same name there is exactly one
PI server and one PI client that can be
connected to each instance and when the
PI server process runs it wait for the
PI clients to connect to it and once
client process join a pipe instance the
PI server process or even another
process can create a new instance and
wait for a new client there's a bunch of
difference between vampire I will socket
that is their part have beauty in access
control so nap I basically windows
object so they have this could this
Quisenberry access console is associated
with them and their two cases here where
the PI doesn't exist anyone and the user
including guests can create a new pipe
and set as I such concern list of all
the future PI instances however if the
PI does exist
only those either with five create my
instance provision can create a new one
and they cannot change the ISIS control
list of the pie anymore
so that's having access control stop
meant by from being vulnerable to meet
magnetics unfortunately no so similar to
that of metal socket the mid my attacker
can perform client impersonation by
simply connect to any open PI instance
even though they are subjected to access
control we will learn for the best like
that this I sequential doesn't matter at
all just like port hijacking or are
taking over support before the
legitimate server does in a new socket
submit Massacre can perform so
impersonation simply by hijacking the
name of the pipe he can either the nails
a pile just by creating the first
instant of the pipe and since Isis
console of the pipe so that anyone can
create or connect to any new instances
and this way the be Knight PI server
just create a second instance without
knowing that there's already an existing
one thus abstract which can be used to
detect whether the pipe instant is a
first one or not however we found that
many software developers missed such
options leaving the lamp a communication
of Allah reward to the bitmap effects
similarly the B'nai client process can
connect to an open fire instance without
noticing that the owner is not an
illicit email owner but the attacker
Somen the middle attack is pretty
straight for what we named pipe and so
attacker just need to perform client and
server impersonation at the same time
and forward messages between the five
instances so now that we know about
socket and the Empire let's not talk
about
if the last eyepieces that we consider
the USB HID so what is common to leather
socket lamp I and USPS any
communications so even though USB is
strictly not an IPC method USBs IDs by
step I do an identifier and with
connection as well so it leaves them
vulnerable to our tech model we are
interested in these devices because
hardware security tokens such a luma key
that we use for second factor you're
also USB HID so Linux and the master web
implementation is different from data
windows allele is another West the USB
HID devices can only be accessed from
only the current interactive user login
sentence but however in Windows no such
a sequential minute mechanism exists so
more than one user at the tab can access
a USB HID even though even the one in
the background so it means that the
security of this USB HID depends on the
application layer security mechanism
implemented in the software or in the
hardware devices themselves so now I
will show how we can exploit the
vulnerable IPC method in fashion manager
and security tokens our primary case
study is standalone passive managers so
they're different from Clio parts of
medicine like LastPass in terms they
provide a native desktop app that allow
user to manage the password this
password manager are often integrated
into web browser with browser extensions
this path extensions assist users in
storing password and entering the
password interlocking pieces and
surprise extensions app communicates the
password over IPC and in this world we
analyze various functions managers to
see how it protects the channel
the first case study I would like to
talk about Strobel form the Robottom abs
run is PPP server on port five four five
one two and rest for client commissions
the robot web browser is kanzen connect
as a client to a server in order to
query the paschal forms an app it's a
problem with RoboForm is that there's no
authentication in the IPC on this IPC
channel the app will respond to any
client without verifying that is
actually it's a legitimate RoboForm
proud extension so it's quite easy for
the meatman psycho to exploit RoboForm
so that go here is an unprivileged user
that running malicious process in the
background so he can easily perform try
impersonation just by connecting as a
client to the app and query the whole
password database thumbs up so second
case study is one password
another popular Pospisil medicine this
is more interesting because one part
should try to keep some security on the
IPC channel but it's not good enough to
be fair again the meet my attacker
here's a branch a WebSocket server on
for C 2 C 3 and well for collision from
the Prowler extension by the server
aquatic relations
it's verify the client very carefully it
says the browser extended ID is HTTP
header in terms of cost silence in
nature of the client process to make
sure that it is an old browser and most
importantly the solar check whether the
server and the client process are owned
by the same user so we see checks we
couldn't perform client personation
on one password however it's quiet here
does not verify the server actually can
order because the projects canceled is
sent both by the browser and it has
access to very limited api so this
allows a bit my attacker to perform
server impersonation even though the
client server
the random
go in the first communications to a
chance and M tsuki but the desire of the
protocol is secure enough to prevent the
server impersonating attack so let us
take a look at the protocol this is how
the protocol looks like and the client
here the browser extension and the
server is a desktop app there are
several problem with this protocol so we
can see here first all the material of
the final key you don't see it so each
pad key and the nonsense so send out in
the messages and second we can see our
staff profile that users has become it's
a code that user has to compare this as
a random string we has nothing to do
with the protocol values and also on
step 5 the user only confirm on the
upside it means that a malicious server
can skip this confirmation so this is
secure protocol together with the fact
that there's no server authentication no
server verifications allow the meadmaker
to perform server impersonation so now I
will walk us through how to perform
server impersonation on the one password
so attack oh it's just little runs on
WebSocket server on port 606 3 before
the death of a sub AB bass and read up
twice to run a server and see the port
has probably been taken this fail
silently without informing the user but
like a server god connection from the
products standard it does it's a key
derivation protocol so as I described
before but schemes use the confirmations
so here unlike verbal form the meatman
attacker cannot have cannot access a
password database because it's
performing server impersonation but we
found that the attacker can send a
command called collect documents to the
paradise chasm to collect all the data
that the victim enters on web forms and
this data include rocking credentials
so we have seen two person barriers at
your socket as I proceed channel many
are the boss of managers use native
messaging instead this is standard
browsers beauty method that desire to
provide a more secure alternative
to netwo socket for communicating
between browser extension and native
code
so how lytic messaging works we pass
magazine the password manager first it's
a visitor with a browser on a secure
double coordinated messaging host and
allow only is browser extension to
access this may be messaging host and
well it proud extends of the one to
communicate with lady messaging host
it's a browser which runs a native
messaging host in a child process and
communicate with it using standard input
and output so this way submit my
attacker cannot get at this middle and
intercept the clinician so the question
here is native messaging a perfect
solution for password manager well
emotionally no reason the reason is that
as a native messaging host and password
manager app are still two separate
processes and they need to exchange data
open IPC so the oil difference here is
at the native messaging host is not
sandbox by the browser so it has more
options on how to communicate with a
password manager app so let's take a
look at an example here
passive boss in example a password
manager set News lady messaging host
lady messaging on Windows this native
messaging host used name pipe to
communicate with a native app and when
the app starts it creates a named pipe
and wealth proclamation for the native
messaging host so native messaging host
simply connects to the damn pipe as a
client and forward messages between so
proudly stencil and the app
however it is a app as a native
messaging host here they don't
authenticate each other and all messages
are sent a plain text so because of
these issues we were able to perform man
in the middle impassive boss and we
could do it not only from an
authenticated user but also from guest
users so let me first show how the
demands of media type could be done from
an authenticated user as I mentioned
when sap start it creates an empire and
with convention from the native
messaging host
so first the attacker just need to
connect as a client to the apps v
instance and then the attacker create
another instance of the pipe and with
the condition from the native messaging
host and well the native messaging host
communic try to communicate with the app
we correlate to the attacker instance
because it is only open instance of the
name pipe and after that the attacker
simply forward messages between the two
pi assistants and we have made as a
middle attack this it a little bit more
tricky to perform a typewriter guest
user because as I mentioned before so
Isis control list of pipe Allah only
access from authenticated user so you
mean that a process running from a guest
user cannot connect as a client or
create a new instance of the pipe so the
solution here is pile a project in the
guest user could create the first
instance as a pipe and set full access
to all users so this way when through
app quiesce instance he doesn't even
notice that another users have created a
first pipe because the first instance
apart and Isis control the pipe is not
as expect and the rest of the attack is
exactly the same as I typed my
authenticated user so last case study I
would like to talk about in the Phaedo
you to app security Sophie do you to app
your standard for the second fight
authentication is supported by many
popular services such as Facebook Google
and github and most security key
implemented standard equalling you wiki
and the new Google tightened security
keys you can see on the right that we
see a simplified protocol up house.you
chip security protocol works
so first the use of most the rest of the
device with the authorized service that
he wants to enable second factor so
basically here to Device Center it and
authenticate generate and public key
pair and the service link the public key
to the user after that when the user one
to login to the service the service
center challenge to the browser and
expect to see the response containing
the signature the device engage on the
challenge to get a response is a browser
will repeatedly send a challenge to the
device until received response so device
here doesn't automatically sigh and it
requests which receives and it needs to
be activated by touching a button of the
device and it only responds to the first
request a pizza pouch so now I will show
how speed my attacker could exploit the
YouTube security key since security Keys
is supposed to prevent malicious rockin
even when the user password has been
compromised we assume here that attacker
has already obtained the victim password
and that's why the correct the second
factor so attacker will exploit the fact
that on window and user even though one
running in the background can access USB
HID devices at any time so attack yes
follow but I'll take her first run a
malicious browser process in the lock in
his promise essence and size into a
service using the password that he has
obtained so Melissa's browser will
receive a challenge from the service
after that I'd like keep selling the
challenge from the service to the device
that high grip that illegitimate trouser
would do to solve this way it will
increase the chance of getting the
challenge side this is pretty easy
because hope for example send a
challenge to the device every 300
milliseconds
and where the victim size into any
Soviet using the same security key the
victim would touch the button of the
device and there is high probability
that like this request would be side
because it being sent as a device at
high grade the user might notice does
the first button has no effect because
it is used by the attacker
but such pilotless are typically ignore
so we tested Czar type on popular
services including Facebook and github
and 100% are separate so we have seen
how we exploit the trouble for one
password massive boss and here on
YouTube Keys but those are not all the
applications that we found from the
robot to meet my attacker and this is
the list of absent we analyzed and their
cool abilities
bunch of managers and other login
credentials are our focus here we also
found with ability in other apps that
follow client-server architecture my
idea for example on Windows client and
server I wanna sing computer and the
client camp so it's not exactly is the
client can connect to the server using
name path we were able to perform an in
the middle on this channel and we
optically could obtain all queries and
results of this channel so how can meet
mallet I can be mitigated
since attack I performed by leaving a
malicious process running in the
background it's the most straightforward
solutions would be to limit the number
of users that have access to a computer
so ideally which computer should be
personal to a single computer artists or
single user people I said to also be
disabled or limited only one
user and submit palette I can also be
easily depicted so application level of
process need to compare owner of a
server at the client process but it's a
little bit more difficult for JavaScript
client running in the web browser
because such client say help you don't
have access through the OS API and they
cannot perform the owner type so in that
case you could graphic solution can be
used such as TRS at the PGI so inclusion
so main takeaway message from this talk
is that a software developer should be
aware that IPC security IPC is not
inherently secure there has been a
common belief that nothing can do to
defend against local attacker
it may be true if the user device is
infected with malware however as we have
seen there are many other potential
attackers and any user regardless of its
privileged can attack the IPC by the
user on a same computer and alive and
well so the application developer can
totally be found again this attacker so
this is anime con thank you
[Applause]