thank you very much for joining this
session I know it's a hard time you know
we all had lunch you know we're kind of
getting sleepy
hopefully this talk is not gonna be
boring for you and my name is Dan
Demeter I'd like to start with a quote
that I think defines the essence of our
cybersecurity industry and this quote
says if you're not the enemy and you
know yourself you shouldn't fear
anything and I think this is quite good
and we'll discuss about this a little
bit later so my name is Dan Demeter I
graduated University if almost four
years ago it's been a long time since
then I've been I joined Kaspersky Lab
global research and analysis team and I
mostly do threat intelligence and big
data so I'm writing tools for threat
intelligence that is helping my that are
helping my team further research and
discover new stuff and I'm also
interested in big data correlating stuff
and getting meaningful results also if
you don't know about my team it's called
global research and analysis team it was
founded almost 10 years ago this year we
celebrated our 10th 10th anniversary and
we are highly specialized in finding
analyzing and protecting against a PT's
advanced threats or highly own attacks
against banks governments power plants
you name it
so a little history in our 10 10 years
of existence we managed to find a lot of
interesting stuff you might have heard
about oops
pointer is not working you might have
heard about do Q goes flame we might
have heard about epic turtle arm you
might have heard about carbon arc who
heard about carbon arc here perfect so
the leader got caught it's a bit was a
big win for us and you know you might
ask yourself hey Dan why
why do you only show 2010 17 like sorry
doesn't in 16 well the answer is because
2017 wouldn't fit in the slide like we
managed to uncover more than 100 apt
groups different abt groups and it
couldn't fit on the screen so yes it's
there those are though that it's that
many if you want to catch up with our
latest research feel free to check our
secure is calm it's our blog post where
we post our newest research newest
findings but it's not totally new mostly
because or we don't publish most of all
over all our stuff on this website
mostly because we have our private
reports and actually we are publishing
new research every week so our private
reports they don't go here but we also
published our latest sounds latest stuff
on this website
what doing our security analyst
conference which happened this year to
gentleman way smarter than I am
they presented their idea of the
information war and this information
were they said has three parts it has
the it says the mass subpoena
manipulation which were not going to
talk about today and he has two other
components the cyber cyber espionage and
cyber sabotage those two components they
both use only one and a specific
specific code and they use malware well
they were small where in order to gain
persistence in order to gain to able to
enter new networks or to exfiltrate data
and today we're going to talk about
malware and more most importantly we're
going to talk about finding malware thus
this piece of code look familiar to you
it's kind of like C code type
nobody and okay we have someone somebody
here okay so this is this piece of like
looking sea type code is called Yarra
with Europe basically it's an
open-source tool its creator ones calls
it the Swiss Army knife
for pattern matching and it basically
allows you to write comp specific and
advanced rules
to match files so let's say you have one
binary you have on a sample and then you
can write specific specific rules in
order to try to find similar similar
samples that are kind of identical with
the same sample that you're analyzing
and basically you can use Yaron you can
download you compile it and then you can
run your ax over a collection of files
which are not let's say are not
clustered or are you don't know what
they are and then you can try to see if
those files match your URLs and then you
can find similarities code similarities
between those two samples and basically
you can say those samples are from the
same family are from the same apt group
or not well there's a problem with this
it's the problem that you need to hunt
in the wild you you can write the best
general rule but if you don't know where
to run the yarn rule or in or you don't
know where to search for what you don't
have don't have where to search her URL
or rule then it's kind of useless so
most of you might be using virustotal
I'm using it a lot in virustotal there's
an option there's a there's a button
called virustotal intelligence and in
that intelligence you can run your yarn
rules over their collection is called
retro hunt and basically a virustotal
allows you to run your yarn rules over
the entire collection which is huge it
takes some time to scan it entirely but
you get your results you can get your
matched files by your URL well
that's pretty good that's pretty good
about this but there are some issues
first of all you have to upload your
Yara rule on virustotal
what happens if you have a TLP read-only
for your team you are our world well you
can't you can't actually upload it on
virustotal secondly their collection of
files it's theirs what if you have your
own collection and you don't want to
upload them on virustotal
but you want to scan them in a
distributed dynamic way like they do
with retro hunt well because because of
these issues we decided to create our
own our own scanner and it's not called
Deloris although I wished because it's
my favorite character it's called Clara
so Clara
basically what it does is a distributed
DRS scanner it allows you to submit your
submit your URLs on a web interface you
submit them you click run and then they
get they get distributed to multiple
servers servers start scanning the file
repositories they have with your yards
and you get back your results
furthermore you have the option of
implementing groups such that you can
have a group for your team you can have
a group for your customers you can have
a group for whatever you before and in
those groups people are allowed to scan
different different files and basically
it's a neat way to just fire us the our
rule upload it on the web interface and
get the results back you don't have to
run it on your computer you don't have
to execute any command like comments
from your terminal although I'm a fan of
terminal like running commands in
terminal but some people they just
before - and it's easier to just upload
them on the web interface so you might
say ok then but you know like why should
I use Clara well if you have your error
rules and you want to check against if
they're correct if they match some files
they don't fire false positives you'd
might want to do it because the cycle of
creating guy on our wall is quite
complicated because you first need to
create a URL then you have to test for
false positives then you have to tweak
it again make it better I know
use some more relaxed options or add
some more conditions and then write
again right again and then when you're
happy with your rule you have to run it
over your collection of samples unknown
samples or markers or whatever then
another reason is that you have you
might face some problems if you're
running locally on your laptop
especially with with collections that
are higher than like big data big in
size like 1 terabyte 2 terabytes 5
terabytes you can't actually run this
one on your laptop mostly because it
takes a lot of time and secondly because
you can't you don't have a lot of
storage available for you so the
solution will be to actually run it in
the cloud as I said like retro hunt then
you want we have another option where
you can you your your rule which is
amazing it's like best year ever did
I'll hit on any files does it mean it's
a bad Yara rule no it means that right
now you didn't match anything but you
might match something next tomorrow you
might match it in one year so basically
what you want to do is and one possible
scenario would be to have all your files
suspicious files from your your
organization your your Sauk center will
collect them you dump them in your one
of your servers and then you
periodically scan those files with your
URLs and let's say it might not match
today but in next year your honor that
you created two years ago might match
and you'll see oh this is a sample we
got hit by this apt and now they're
trying to hit us again so that's
that's like pretty cool furthermore you
can have your results shared in the in a
nice way on the web interface so instead
of like sharing results here are results
by email which is like so 1990s you can
just send them send vlink
on slack and then like your colleague
from the same team can just like click
on the link and get the results and
lastly you can also run your trainings
like we do basically with people they
check they don't have to install yotta
on their laptop they can just upload the
rules on there on the web interface this
is also useful for people who don't know
how to compile yara and you might end up
like with issues like dotnet is missing
or like some library didn't compile
correctly so basically you can have like
a clean web interface where they just
fire their words so okay let's talk
about like the project itself how does
it look like briefly basically Speight
turn on SQL database and of course is
using the ARA your binary we didn't
modify the our binary basically you can
just download it from github and you can
run in terms of the architecture it's
not super complicated basically we have
like a dispatcher and multiple workers
they connect to the dispatcher
dispatcher gets the job from the
database and users can submit jobs and
you can create groups and jobs and
whatever you can create them on the web
interface which then changes the
database and whenever an user submits a
new job the job gets inserted into the
database and then the workers will ping
dispatcher and dispatcher will say ok
let me check the database check the
database and says ok I have a new job
for you here it is I have assigned this
job for you when a worker finishes
finishes the scan returns the results
back to dispatcher dispatch our notifies
by email the user and you have your
results on the web interface so it's
pretty simple the idea is that you can
add as many workers as you want you can
have unlimited workers and nowadays with
the increasing cost of super computers
like it's better to have like 100 100
like not
powerful computers rather than just one
powerful computer so that's pretty
pretty neat about this so I wouldn't be
telling you this if and I wouldn't be I
wouldn't be presenting you this project
if it you wouldn't have the chance to
play with it so basically this year we
open source the project you can check it
on github and you can install it in your
infrastructure and run distributed URLs
so I think this is pretty good in terms
of installing it we run it on a bun - we
ran it when I'm going to it also works
on Debian Ubuntu 16 or 18 LTS basically
need you need Python you need supervisor
and Python to a virtual environment you
have you need the same you need to have
the same setup for for the worker or
plus the yarra binary and an SQL
database we recommend Mario DB but you
can also use MySQL up to you doesn't
matter so as I said it's a worker
dispatcher worker dispatcher
parodying and it has a web interface
which looks like this so whenever you
log in first for the for the first time
you have a like you have a dashboard and
in the dashboard you have like
unfortunately I can't pull icon point I
don't know why it doesn't work but yes
it works this so we have the dashboard
they have like create jobs and new job
and whenever you go like on your job you
can just space your role here and you
have those repositories to scan which
are those things here and just a little
info body-positive each server can have
multiple repositories
when I say repository I am actually
referring to a folder that sits on the
data story data storage for one servers
and basically you can have multiple
folder folders with different names and
you can see like one one of our workers
we have this clean folder and we have
this sis folder so basically it is these
are the repositories whenever you press
submit like you press commit here
basically those rules are being fired
they will be picked up by the workers
and then when they finish they just tell
you like it was scanned in 8 seconds
this is our easier
this is a repository and those are the
results in this case we didn't have any
results but basically if we met matched
any files we would have their MD files
in here and you have the error results
in here okay cool
so I about the depositories one
important thing if you want to install
this one in your infrastructure is that
you have to make to be careful when
you're using when you're setting up your
repositories because you need to set up
a repository control file so you have
please check out check the instructure
instructions because you need to set up
a repository control file and this
repository control file has also some
other features which we're gonna be
discussing next it has some advanced
features and some of them are here and
basically I'll go through them really
fast so the redirect pads feature allows
you to have a repository in one
directory but rather scan another
directory so think of it like a like on
a symbolic link in Linux you know like
this is the repository like mount
storage virustotal samples and then
basically I say no I'd like to redirect
the scan to Mount Nass Clara bigger
collection so basically from this or the
worker will scan this one it's like a
symbolic link exactly like a symbolic
link then you can have you can search
for hashes so basically each rule might
hit on different files and then you can
search the same search for this md5 or
sha-1 hash how many rules did match this
file and then basically you can search
for multiple hashes and you can see
multiple rules that match those files
this is useful when you want to see if
to yarrow rules generate the same
results and you can compare and do
whatever you want with them then you can
have shareable links shareable links are
useful if you want to share your rules
with somebody else and basically you can
see here you have like a link and then
you can copy this link and you can
provide it to other users of the
platform and they can see your role
regardless of if they're in the same
group with you
if they same if they have the same
access as you have so participative this
is pretty cool if you share rules
between you so basically this was it
Clara
in a nutshell but it wouldn't be useful
if we don't try to optimize it pretty
like as much as possible so basically I
try to we try to get the most out of it
so of course the first optimization will
be the server performance if and I think
the most important one are discs if
you're running with spinning spinning
discs you won't get a lot of performance
out of it so instead we decided of
running with SSDs we have them like in a
server we have like 80 SSDs in a raid 5
configuration and on top of that
configure all on top of that raid we
decided to use an x FS file system
because x FS is pretty fast
with reading also with writing but it's
not a lot of wear and tear on the SSDs
itself mostly because if you're doing a
lot of scans you're not writing a lot
you're reading 90% of our operations are
read operations so that's pretty cool so
these are the servers you this is this
is the this is the SSDs server this is
the database server like SSDs on top
database on the back below they are
super micro servers I know crazy stuff
we checked them nothing suspicious but
you know you never know
and we got three gigabytes per second
three gigabytes scanning speed which is
pretty impressive we hit the raid read
speed so unfortunately we can't get more
out of that raid but basically we
managed to scan 10 terabytes in 30
minutes which is pretty impressive of
course with caching and other techniques
but mostly with that set up with the
server setup I think 30 minutes is
pretty ok in order to find for new
samples we have over 30 since we
deployed we have over 30,000 jobs and
they all worked okay we distributed with
multiple servers as you saw in the
picture but we also have multiple
servers the more all of them are SSDs
and I think it's very important when
you're setting up the server no matter
if it's like SSDs or spinning disks to
have the file system and the file system
properly configured and this implies
that we need to set up the stripe
correction the stripe rate red stripe
correctly and the number of disks so
basically in our C in our example in our
situation we have like a 256 kilo
stripes and we have like 7 data disks
and what one part it is parity disk
sorry which is right grade 5 and of
course the mounting options in order to
try to get out of more the most speed
out of it okay so basically the future
plans and I'm the main developer of
Clara or future future plans are to set
up to set up the web interface sorry to
set up the Web API basically the API
allowing you to execute the same to run
the same commands and to do everything
as you do as a like a web user you can
do it using an API and this means that
you can set up tasks that you fire your
hours over your collection and you have
another robot that feeds new files into
your servers and then you can scan the
files you can check new URLs that you
receive from your local certs you can
check them against your files and you
can do other cool stuff so this week I'm
gonna be releasing the API
specifications and the API code and as a
gift for you as a gift because you
attended our session if you want come
come talk to me or send them contact me
I'm gonna be around here like you can
also contact me on Twitter I can create
an account for you on our Clara server
with our virus collection well don't
think that is Kaspersky's huge virus
collection because I can't provide
mostly because it's like super huge but
we have a smaller collection of 10
terabytes with most of our interesting
files and like interesting the tags that
you can scan the Ori are our rules
against so please come by if you want to
test it out also there's a web interface
basically you can see it in action
without installing it yourself so going
back to my quote originally quote I
think that it should be slightly changed
to this one and I would say that Yara is
the future and if you didn't start
already writing Garrels
you should if you want to search for the
project you can find search on your
favorite on DuckDuckGo or your favorite
search engine search for Kaspersky Clara
great
you can join you can follow my Twitter
or you can join our chat on telegram
where we discuss about like updates or
improvements to Clara and which is being
said I'd like to thank you for watching
my presentation and I hope it was
interesting
[Applause]
hello nice talk thank you may I ask Cara
is scanning just files or you plan to
scan also some metadata in some DB like
sequences or ngrams okay um so basically
we are using Clara is using Yara and
basically what Clara does it feeds a
file like physical file to Yara
if Yara can do what you're saying then
Clara can also be implemented to do that
now Engram we are actually using an
graham but we have like modified system
which is not available for it is not
open sourced
so whatever Yara can do Clara can also
be programmed to do that thank you in
the second question I saw that the most
of the code bases in PHP why have you
chosen this most of the code base is
actually Python but the web interface is
PHP this is because of legacy reasons
mostly because we had an older system
web interface that it was written in PHP
and for another project and basically I
just use that for the web interface but
dispatcher and workers are in Python so
basically you can just install them on
any operating system and it yeah I want
to rewrite the web page in PHP but I
just wanted to have it something useful
that people can use anymore what should
I do you have something to manage the
similar rule in case some of your
colleague create a new rule that is
similar to you that you created
previously let's say a it's matching
something so there are other projects
that are actually meant to organize the
era rules currently in Klara there is no
option to have like similar yarra rules
or to see if others wrote the same stuff
mostly because we decided to just have
this
like you fire a rule on the web
interface you get the results back and
that's it yeah but there are other
projects that are actually used to
cluster to organize yours what the
answer is no okay any further questions
we have another question there if I
understand correctly the workers need to
have local access to to the collection
to the mobile collection of course yes
so there's no pool mechanism to fetch a
gyre rule and then a file and then from
the from the dispatcher so wait so
workers have the local files physically
in the data store workers they connect
to the dispatcher and dispatcher gives
them the yarra rule that they have to
scan the dispatch it does not provide
the file dispatcher does not provide any
files of our management you need to set
up separately the files you can have
your robots up feed the files to the
workers directly so there are no files
being sent over the network you have the
local connect collection of files in
your workers you feed them as you want
you can have like a distributed file
system on the workers up to you then
what the worker what dispatcher does it
only feeds the yarra role and it feeds
on ID so basically the worker comes back
and says hey I di I finished the work
with this yours these are the results
this is the idea of the job okay so so
it's up to the worker to decide which
fastest scan now it's up to the user to
decide which files to scan because in
the user you select those repositories
if you remember or you select which
repositories you want to scan right and
those repositories are locally present
on the workers yes yeah and multiple
workers can have the same repositories
this is what we're doing we have like
five workers and all of them have slash
clean repository which you
so file management is a separate process
outside of the Clara's so file
management so distributing the malware
among your workers is up to you of
course and we design it like this
basically it's up to you to distribute
the malware that the collection the
samples on each workers up to you how
much like however you want there are
some plans on trying to get the option
off because you might run run into some
issues like you have a hit yeah how do
you get the file and basically we have a
different system that we can fetch the
file by its end by its md5 or sha-1 have
that system it might be a feature of
Clara to just say hey I want this file
with this hash and then the world
basically dispatcher goes to the worker
and says give me this file and worker it
is back and then you but it's not
implemented all right okay okay thank
you any other questions I think there
are none okay thanks thank you very much
[Applause]