Oh so hello everybody the this
presentation is called modifying data on
a read-only mounted device so this is an
exercise out of our forensic training
out of the circle forensic training and
once in the morning I read in the book
that nothing prevent the PC to modify
the data on a read-only device that
makes me letting thought about it and
back in the office already I had a proof
of concept so and that's what I like to
share with you today so we have this USB
stick
I will now connect it to my PC okay it
is now connected now I check with a
small program you message how it is
connected to my PC and we see easily it
is connected as SDB with one partition
as db1 I check how this mounted and we
see that stb-1 is mounted on my media
folders so all is good but it is still
mounted in read write mode so I have to
remount it now I will remount it in
read-only mode and just verify if
everything works wrong good and now we
see that the device is mounted read-only
it's a V fat filesystem and it's mounted
read-only okay now some small tests if I
can modify the data
so I changed the dock
I cannot save it you see the safe is not
enabled because it devices read-only I
have no option to save it and I can only
save it on a different location or close
without saving so ok what I do next now
is a kind of forensic search string
search for the strings I'd like to
modify so I like to modify the hello
world stuff so I search for the stuff on
my partition and I give the options TD
which bring me the results in bytes
the offset where the string will be
found in offsets in bytes and it's email
notation so now I have the offsets
rather file where the data are stored
now I can calculate the Zach door
so it's stored at by 299,000 at sector
at sector five eight four so I copied
the sector onto my local drive I copied
the sector of five eight for my local
drive just the one sector and now I can
open this data with a hex editor so here
we are now modify the data on my hard
drive
one minute Michael so the data are now
locally modified and I just use DD to
write them back on my USB stick so
that's all now the data should be
modified on the USB stick I will verify
and or they are not modified what a pair
what a mess but wait 30 seconds but wait
we will eject the USB stick and
reconnect it and let's give it a try
where's my mouse pointer here well uh
the data are really modified it's just
it was not seen in the first test
because it was somewhere in the cache so
it's cached and it was not shown up
thank you thank you
[Applause]