good morning all genders good morning
heckler you all look I was gonna say
bright-eyed and bushy-tailed but you
look like maybe you haven't had enough
coffee you're awake
you ready we have a lot of slides to get
through it's gonna be very dense this
talk is it's a mixture it's a mixture of
economics a little bit of reverse
engineering blockchain chasing payments
analyzing payments and insurance and I
know insurance gets you all awake right
you're all like super excited about
insurance doing cyber insurance puts you
in a special status somewhere between
like rock star and fighter pilot right
no okay you don't even want to laugh
early in the morning it's too early okay
we'll just do the dry academic version
of the presentation and that's I guess
that's what they want so we'll see so
I'm Aaron Leverett I'm at the Cambridge
judge Business School and I also run a
company called consider risks it's my
first time so if I make a blunder please
pardon my monkey done while I'm a PhD
student at the University of Padua
I am the finally I mean in my final year
hopefully I will graduate this year and
let's see where we take you through I
hope you will like the presentation so
this is the overall introduction to the
presentation we are going to do these
points and we have couple of slides here
first we are going to introduce ya they
don't want to see the table okay just
one more thing I would like to say about
myself is that I do research in I
started with my network security but
right now I'm focusing on crypto
currency and crypto mining both legal
and illegal crypto mining and apart from
this I believe in the reproducible
research so if you want to if you go to
my web page you will find source code
and it is it whatever you would like to
reproduce my results I want to reiterate
that like I contacted on kid because of
a chance miss correlations so like I was
doing a bunch of research and my
research correlated with his research
and then I contacted him and some of you
will know you contact an academic
researcher and go can I see some of your
data and they're like oh maybe I'll get
around to it later but he genuinely gave
me access to the data and was
really open about his research and he'd
done better research than I did so if
you can beat them join them right so
here we are okay so I'm gonna I'm gonna
give you a weird little introduction to
insurance because I know it's super
boring but I want to use it as a
framework for this talk so I was in
Norway a few years ago I'm a huge fan of
a hackerspace in Norway called hat Korea
so it greets to them and when I was
there there was a talk from some people
from Sweden and they came in and they
basically said we believe that transport
should be free you should be able to
ride the subway in Sweden for free and
the state doesn't agree with this right
so they have these little barriers and
they have little cops that go around
checking to see whether or not you have
a ticket on the subway and this
organization came in and said okay it's
like a hundred SEK to buy a day ticket
these prices aren't right but I'll just
give them as a rough example and it's
like a thousand SEK if you get fined
right okay these barriers aren't so
effective we can just walk past them and
we can hope that we don't get caught
what is the ratio at which the police
actually catch people with tickets
because if we sit down and we do the
math maybe we could pay 50 SEK per day
and then anyone who gets caught will pay
their fines right and then a few of the
people who are doing this we're kind of
you know making fun of the cops as they
went past and so they got caught more
frequently and this scheme didn't work
so well so they introduced what the
insurance would call it deductible so
you paid like the first 50 of the
thousand fine but they paid the rest
right and this scheme is still going and
the goal is to show people that you
could have transport for free like you
actually spend more money and forcing
tickets being used on the on the subway
than you do then you would pay if you
wanted everyone to have free access to
the subway right now obviously these
kinds of schemes work in places where
they don't shoot people for getting on
the subway I say that as someone from
Britain it doesn't happen very often but
occasionally so you know this might not
work for you in different countries
depending on whether or not it's legal
but I think I think it's a very
interesting example of what insurance is
like right most people think insurance
and they think huge
you know big companies blah blah blah I
love this these people sat down and did
the mathematics of how likely they were
to get caught on the subway to give
people free rides on the subway and
that's the kind of math that I think is
really cool so I want you to keep this
in mind as we go through the rest of the
presentation
essentially this presentation is about
I'm a huge fan of socialized medicine
and I wonder if it's possible for around
somewhere to be treated in this way
could we pay for this to be treated
anyone who comes to us with a ransomware
infection is it possible what would the
mathematics look like can we afford it
so a little bit more about insurance
if you don't insure yourself insurer
right so lots of people hate the idea of
paying a big insurance company that's
fine but that means you put aside some
money for a rainy day by yourself and if
not money then you put aside some grain
or you put aside some electricity or you
put aside something right so we're going
to talk about risk models and the other
complaint I hear mostly about insurance
is that it would eat into my security
budget that's true if your security
budget only involves prevention and
response then fine
let's just compare with what they'll
offer us with what with what we do for
ourselves right that's the the basic
idea all right we'll skip this this is
the boring stuff this is boring too does
anyone in the room not know what
ransomware is we're happy to answer for
you if you'd know okay good we'll move
on we have good slides so everyone
understands the basic premise of
ransomware and the infection lifecycle
we're going to use this as a you know we
know that you know this stuff we're just
using it as a sort of definition for the
purposes of this talk we're not going to
get into massive discussions about the
difference between a locker and a wiper
and a krypter right like that's not the
purpose of this discussion it's a little
bit more about economics and so on and
so forth all right so ransomware life
cycle okay so the first phase is the
infection and how that's over spreads so
I'm gonna go very quickly from this for
these lines it's like first thing they
send spam emails some drive-by downloads
or software updates
Emme means they generally say okay this
is the customer complain for your
company and they're gonna put some links
there and if someone one of the employee
hits the button then probably it's going
to enter in the company drive-by
downloads for example encrypt of all
they send mixed fax decoy and they
probably the the link the link was to
download the the malicious payload and
for not pay Tia was distributed as an
update to Ukrainian software colony dog
so these are some of the things that we
discovered when we were researching
about these things another thing that
they do is the backdoors like wanna cry
did to use the Pulsar backdoor and some
installers in bad habit interestingly
they also offer you affiliate program so
if you help us a spreading ransomware we
are gonna pay you like five percent ten
percent fifty percent depending upon how
much you spread our and somewhere which
was specially with the this guy Janos if
you know if you work in ransomware you
know who John says so alright so
everyone knows that ransomware I first
started in nineteen eighty nine right no
you really don't to interact this
morning okay alright so yeah there was a
hiv/aids researcher who was trying to
get across the point that you get this
disease and then big companies charge
you a ransom to get yourself as healthy
as possible and to live as long as
possible and that's kind of crazy so
here's this stunt I'm gonna infect your
computer with like I'm gonna offer some
software that helps you do some risk
assessment of HIV patients or potential
HIV patients and then when your computer
reboots ninety times you're going to get
this message saying that you need to
send a banker's check to Ecuador Panama
or something some tax haven and you know
this was a stun I believe the researcher
served time for it because it was a
virus and it's illegal but that was 1989
before the blockchain really existed the
thing that we think is really funny as
we're going through this is that we
found a cache are from cryptolocker from
1972 so the QR code there takes you to
the blockchain example if you want to go
and have a look we were surprised we
know that the 1972 timestamp is false
like it must be false why would it be in
there
it's the received time for blockchain
enthusiasts amongst you but we still
think it's pretty cool and it's
interesting so if some people have some
ideas
about why their blockchain received
times in the 70s I mean some of our
ideas are anti forensics right you might
do this on purpose because when someone
goes to look through a bunch of
transactions and they're not going to
look at that far back in time that might
be one reason it could be a parsing
error on behalf of blockchain info or
comm that was suggested by a few other
people that missed and circle ooh you
had some other ideas too about why might
be there probably it's a time warp
attack yes I mean we were looking at
time warp attacks I think yeah good so
time warp attack is like you make
transaction on purpose and you play with
the play with that times time which is
in epic and try to insert it inside the
blockchain with the with the falls with
a false epoch this is about this is a
new type of attack which we think is
attack and it's possible and we are we
are trying to work out and put some
proofs here we are trying to we are
trying to make some experiments and if
we are successful probably we will
release it as as well and we will
discuss more maybe next year yeah that's
about the time warp attack in block
change I mean the the basic point here
is that in the real world things are
weird like you start doing research into
malware it doesn't always make sense
there's always something really bizarre
in there that you're not expecting and
that's that's why I love doing hacker
research in general either because we
find the weird stuff ourselves or
because we find it in other people's
work so sometimes I get bored in the
evenings and I make up data
visualizations so we went through a
bunch of ransomware and we decided you
know when I was at Cambridge they talked
a lot about the crypto Wars right Ross
Anderson and those people were involved
in lots of arguments about the crypto
Wars about which ciphers might be
backdoored and which ones weren't and
whether or not we should have a clipper
chip and all that sort of stuff and I
thought this was like a cute little
example of a cipher war like inside
ransomware they're fighting over which
cipher is the best for encrypting stuff
right and they actually have incentives
for getting their encryption right
unlike the embedded firmware industry
for example sorry that was unfair but uh
but it's also true so I wanted to know
which of these different ciphers showed
up the most and you can see some of them
aren't even ciphers right there's like
7-zip in here are c4
I guess our c4 is technically a cipher
but not anymore so one of the most one
it was used a yes which is a symmetric
encryption the property with the
symmetric encryption is that you have
same keys as so the encryption is faster
and you have less computation but the
problem is this number of keys because
it's it spans like n square because you
need one key pair for each encryption so
the next thing that comes up is RSA
which is public key but the problem with
RSA is that you need more computation
and it takes a bit more time as compared
to a yes encryption however on this
slide what we want to point out is that
from 2016 we see a spike in how many
people search for RSA on Wikipedia so
which indicates like okay for us it's
it's okay when we speak about encryption
and things like this but back there in
my family let's say my cousin brothers
they don't know what encryption is what
ransomware is or something like this
they are not so technical as we as
probably we are but if for for common
people something like a ransomware hits
they give you for your convenience a
link on Wikipedia and say ok look this
is a ransomware and this is RSA
technique people start to click there
show search it ok what's what's RSA is
so this is what we took from Wikipedia
we cannot go back beyond 2006 actually
actually we can it's just harder work we
haven't done yeah so at 2016 we saw that
ok people are searching for RSA so this
is an indicator that from 2016 there was
a rise in RSVP in in the search for RSA
which probably indicated that Alice is
being used and we suspect that it is
being used in an server so we haven't
done mathematical correlation of this
data to infections and payments yet but
that's one of the things we want to do
but a lot of times in our research we
run into these anomalies right and so
we're also asking you the audience does
anybody know why this spike in 2016
occurred in RSA on Wikipedia of course
Arina can you shout it out
the della acquisition of RSA okay okay
all right fantastic so we'll look into
that and see if that correlates much
better than with samples which I suspect
it will right that's why we asked the
question but it's also interesting that
this is the time frame in which our RSA
declines on Wikipedia searches and AES
Rises so we're not just talking about
this in a ransomware context we're also
talking about it in encrypted wars
context so like that seems to be a
transition period where afterwards
people are more interested everyday
people are more interested in AES so
symmetric versus asymmetric inside
ransomware one of the key elements if
you'll forgive the pun of the ransomware
research that we were doing is the
theory that ransomware actually keys
matter right if you screw up the keys
someone can steal the ransoms from you
another rival gang can steal your money
right or the money you're about to steal
from someone else that's not true so
like we talked a lot about incentives in
the Cambridge Lab and like I was saying
before embedded firmwares if I screw up
your router firmware and I don't get the
keys right you guys suffer the costs I
don't as a business right whereas in
this case they actually have the
incentives the right way round if they
screw up they don't get their money and
that's that so we think in some cases
you see some ransomware where the
encryption is very good and those are
the ones that continue to make money and
don't get stolen from other people so
with that as a inspiration our kids been
looking at symmetric and asymmetric
inside these things started to use a
combination of symmetric and asymmetric
because symmetric gives you the speed
and asymmetric gives you the more strand
to encrypt the encrypted files so most
of the ransomware we analyzed they were
using a combination of this where
symmetric keys were generated locally
while asymmetric keys were downloaded
from the server so it gives them a speed
as well as the power to encrypt power to
encrypt e files more strongly okay so
now coming to the extortion when
ransomware started they give you
multiple options to pay from
it included cash you money parklet coin
bit coin and one of the most important
criteria characteristics of all these
payments is the is the anonymity offered
by these by these payments however we
can say these are not completely
anonymous but they are at least pseudo
anonymous by a pseudo anonymous what I
mean is that they are not the identity
of the parent pay is not visible however
you can see from which address let's say
the pseudonym a the payment is made from
and the payment is made to so these
payments were our Sudha Sudha or none of
us and we try to see in a blockchain to
to relay these pseudo anonymous names we
our target was not to identify the
identity of the of the guys but the only
target was - at the time of the research
was to identify the payments made to at
the total cost these hands were made to
us me to the society so the on the
screen you see the price of Bitcoin
since it was started from mt.gox
exchange and with the increasing the
price you see the number of families
surfacing on the Internet
so number of families ransom our number
of families of ransomware increasing on
the internet with the price increasing
there we saw more and more ransomware
rising here the idea here is that okay
when the price was increasing everybody
was talking about Bitcoin and people
also started to copy-paste the
ransomware for example jigsaw has like
thousands of versions because everybody
was taking a binary and start just
putting his all ransomware bitcoin
address and started to publish his own
jigsaw version under the name jigsaw
again for the deadlines the payments are
generally few days lights like three
days or something at max weeks but they
allow you to have some extension at some
extra price and the payment addresses
are generally single address hard-coded
or generated on the fly single address
means for example not wait not petia
only use one address to receive payments
and the the the relation here from
binary to address could be one to one or
many to one all the binaries of not
petia
has one address for example
in case of wanna cry it was hard-coded
there were some three addresses it was
supposed to do on the fly generation but
because of some bug in the code
generation it was talked to three
addresses and only three addresses were
used to make payments to wanna cry so
here the relation would go to one-to-one
one-to-many and many-to-many and why
does that matter to us right the answer
is misma correlations basically so if
you've got a one-to-one binary to
address correlation then that will give
you a different correlation structure
than if you've got many two one
so like jigsaw with the reuse of
addresses it's very easy to see that
across multiple binaries which also
makes it easy to classify right but
where you do it on the fly it's much
harder to get a correlation between a
Bitcoin address and binary to a family
from another sample because polymorphism
right so that's why we're interested in
that property and one of the things that
it's fascinating is that with Bitcoin
there's often generated new addresses
because it's known to be not very
anonymous
whereas Manero for example is still
perceived to be very anonymous so people
have a tendency not to regenerate Manero
addresses in crypto miners and things
like this which makes it easier right as
you wish okay so another thing that we
discovered during while we were
searching about this that the people
were targeting everywhere and CPB Locker
targeted web sites which is I think in
my opinion is not so intelligent because
you take regular backups of your website
so if some day someone hits my website I
have my backup I will wipe out my server
and just put up the back I mean I will
restore my web site from the backup in
this case we didn't saw many payments
and interestingly ransomware has become
a full-fledged business model which is
offering you discounts if you write to
them sometimes they offer you better
customer support as compared to known
companies for their customer support
another thing that they are using is the
pressure tactics which is called daxing
so they say okay if you don't pay to us
we are going to release your personal
photos and videos online so better pay
us and there
something that Aaron would like to say
about it it's related to GDP are I think
yes so I think some of the the student
amongst you have been worried for a
little while that ransomware using this
daxing tactic could be leveraging GDP
our fines right because you can be fined
up to four percent of your business for
breaches that release all of this data
and so a lot of us have been worried in
this community that this ransomware
would use that as a threat and if they
charge slightly less than four percent
then you're more likely to pay that than
worried about going to the regulator but
through some conversations we've had
with a couple regulators in Europe it's
become clear that they would take that
into account so if you are in a position
where you have a ransom and the threat
is that they will publish the data you
can go to the regulator and tell them
that this is the threat and they will
take that into account at the time at
the point in time that you are
potentially fine and reduce any fines or
remove them because you were brave
enough to come forward under these
circumstances so I think that's really
important I wanted you all to know about
it and you can ask clever questions of
the regulators about it so the final
stage is the decryption and hopefully
they will decrypt your file if you pay
them but there's no guarantee for
example for for the case mentioned in
the reference six that is Kansas Heart
Hospital the ransomware guys decrypted
everything however in case of power warm
the due to the mistake in the codes the
ransomware eventually destroyed all the
files so if you pay to pay to this
ransomware there's no guarantee if your
file would be decrypted or not coming to
this point so ransomware guy started to
prove their authenticity and saying okay
pay us some amount let's say five
dollars and we will decrypt five files
for you just to prove that they are
authentic and their ransomware works
sometimes they even release your master
master keys off of the ransomware
campaign after the campaign is over
and even rivals release your pub you're
the rival release a private key of the
ransomware just to prove that ok the
other guy's not doing good the funny
thing is that with the Thunder crypt
I think the the screenshot is visible
yeah the Thunder crypt was a campaign
launched
Pilon I guess yes
no Taiwan it was in Taiwan and the
campaign was launched and a guy wrote to
this the sign somewhere guy okay my
salary is not even $400 so do you expect
me to pay you $400 to decrypt my system
and as a good guy he said okay really
please pay me a coffee and I will
decrypt it so these are some fun things
that we discovered in fact that gets a
lot deeper and is really fascinating to
economists any economists in the room
raise your hand no one okay fantastic
so I'm excited we get excited about this
stuff and we're probably the only ones
but they we find examples like I used to
think like many of the hackers in the
room geography doesn't matter right
ransomware can happen anywhere in the
globe it doesn't matter but it does
matter in terms of prices because you
can't charge people more than their
average wage or they're not gonna pay
you right so there's a differential and
geographical pricing for ransomware
there's also a few types of ransomware
that do like a B testing so they'll
throw out like three prices in a region
and then based on which people will pay
more often they'll adjust their pricing
scheme right so it's just like Google or
Amazon right they're doing some
differential pricing so there's some
clever economics going on and ransomware
if you can get to this data and I get
excited about that stuff as much as I
get excited about the the reverse
engineering part as well it's probably
worth saying this is from a sample set
of thirty one thousand one hundred and
eighty one samples which is remarkably
precise but it's because it shows up
every time I run the code across in so
do we want to say something about OSS we
all know that ransomware affects every
OS right okay that's it we're done with
the boring stuff let's get to the cool
stuff so Bitcoin ransomware is different
than Manero ransomware for example
electron Yom is a new currency that I
had run into recently on a minor anyone
heard of electron ium no same as me so I
was looking at a minor not very exciting
that was mining from Manero and then one
of its alternate configurations was to
mine for electron ium which is a variant
of Manero so like those of us doing
ransomware research we've got to up our
game in terms of what coins we're
looking for right because it's
constantly changing and it's
frustrating and it's fun to write regex
is for those coins top tip from our
research because they have validation
and verification you can do it much
faster like looking for URLs and
binaries you never know you get a lot of
false positives but if you code in the
you know the verification of Bitcoin
addresses or Manero addresses it speeds
up your code and you can work through
lots of samples very very quickly in
fact I'll give you an example some of
the code were releasing as part of this
work is up on github and I got sent a
disk image Hakeem you an image of a
miner like the entire disk image right
and they said that there was a crypto
miner on it and I didn't know where
inside the disk image to look for the
binary you know buying a binary
orienteering problem like which ones the
malicious one right so I run this code
across the entire thing and I find
Foreman arrow addresses two of them are
legit addresses that are donation
addresses for github project code so
it's basically the miner itself but the
other two were the sort of malicious
accounts if you like where they were
trying to send the money but that meant
that when I mounted the image later I
was able to find the binaries that I
wanted because I knew where the where
the accounts were if you understand what
I mean and that's where I discovered
this electron ium stuff but you're gonna
say more about the proliferation of
different families talk about things we
did in the research and I'm going to
give you details how we did our research
so when we started we wanted to cover
all the runs over but the problem is
that how do we prove in academia that
our research is legit so what we decided
to do is that we took all the ransomware
which asked for money in bitcoins and at
least one payment was publicly available
because we cannot say ok we find this
address and there is no proof on the
internet so we get a hit by the reviewer
so we only took all those all those
ransomware which asked bitcoins and one
public address available somewhere we
started with and we analyze all these
ransomware which is which are shown by
red flags and yellow flags and in this
presentation I'm going to give you we
are going to give you the details of the
payments to the ransomware which are
flagged as yellow so there will be total
six runs over we are going to talk about
I just want to interject briefly and say
when he says we in this context I didn't
do this research this is the research he
did with
D Mia and that's how I discovered what
he was doing and it's super cool so
enjoy so the payment analysis framework
was we had has three modules first one
is to identify the ransomware addresses
my version was different and Aaron came
up with a better version after we met
each other and the code is available
here on github maybe if someone wants to
take it can go as hard I was just
talking about yeah and the second module
was to collect the data and generate the
database locally because we want to
analyze things and that's why we
downloaded everything on the local PC
and then finally how do we classify
because not all payments to Bitcoin
addresses our ransom payments so we came
up with with a mathematical function to
classify payments as ransom supercool so
how do how did we collect initial
addresses what we did was like we
collected ransomware binaries whenever
it was available we searched through
knowledge basis we read the reports from
CPU and incident response team
we searched over online forums where
victims say is okay I'm hit by this and
this is the address which is asking me
ransom and the final thing which might
be not so convincing but we believe
people put their screenshot on image
searching and on YouTube because people
doing how to YouTube videos on
everything and there are how-to videos
to show how to remove blah blah blah
ransomware so we also try to search
every possible video and we basically
saw every video so for you image
processing folks there's a significant
opportunity here to classify cowan
accounts and addresses in images as
opposed to in text non-trivial
yeah that's that's one thing that I mean
we were thinking to do this idle way of
doing image processing but this was out
of my capability let's say so we did it
manually now once you find the initial
addresses the point is what if you have
initial addresses that does not reveal a
lot about these addresses because not
everyone is going to take a screenshot
put it online or going to share these
share their ransomware addresses by
which they are hit so how can we
defy the real depth of these addresses
so I'm gonna we we have two things which
is called multi input transaction and
shadow addresses on the screen you can
see the left side part which is multi
input transactions so you have multiple
inputs and on the right hand side you
have some output I am sure that this
video that this that this image is not
so clear so I'm gonna take it I'm a bear
of little brain so like you've got a
bunch of accounts so not every payment
into the account is a ransom and so what
you're trying to do is classify which
ones are ransoms and which ones are not
and how the cash outs are working so
okay I'm gonna put this first that let's
say Heron every time he goes to a
conference and you ask for honorarium
and just to keep a track of how much is
being paid how much is being paid from
conference a and conference B so he
gives out one Bitcoin address to one
conference another Bitcoin address to
another conference just to keep a track
of it and just because generating
addresses is free so you can generate as
many addresses as you want so Island has
let's say three addresses and each
address has 500 euros or pounds whatever
you prefer and when it goes back home he
has to pay a bill of 450 let's say so he
says okay I have five 500 into three I
can pay 450 from one of the address so
he takes one address and it pays from
one of the address and 50 changes given
back to him we will come back to this 50
change and at the same time I call
Ireland and say ok you you remember me
I'm a poor guy from Italy I'm doing my
PhD and I need money to travel and he
can you please give me 900 pounds and he
says ok I I have a lot of money so I can
give you back give you this so what he
does is like ok I have two more
addresses with 500 each so he clubs this
amount which is one thousand and gives
and pays me 900 so the point is the
moment he clubs these two addresses it
is assured that these two addresses
belong to iearn if i see one of the
address in the blockchain i can retrieve
the history of this this known address
and i will see this address with this
address where he paid me 900 the point
is when you do multi input transaction
it is guaranteed that all the addresses
on the left-hand side of the
of the screen are yours so when we had
initial and some addresses we we fetch
thee we fetch the data from blockchain
and we did like a recursive recursive
how to say in miss terminology they
didn't Richmond on the payments to fire
new accounts and new payments so this
was one of the strategy to expand our
address address set the second thing
which we left before is like the shadow
addresses whenever you make a payment
and there is a change it's not returned
to you on the same address from which
you made the payment it is given to you
in a new address so the time he paid 450
for his bills he was given back 50 in a
new address so if in a blockchain if I
see a new address which was which was
not occurring any time before let's say
it's a new address and no payment has
been done before so I can say ok this is
a shadow address so on the right hand
side of the transaction I see some
shadow address which belongs to him
so this way we took like one or two
addresses and expanded our data set to
thousands of addresses for each family
exactly so you know if you haven't had
enough caffeine they have a cool
technique for finding more Bitcoin
addresses from the other Bitcoin
addresses and chasing these transactions
so we have about 10 more minutes to get
through a lot of slides ok so the second
thing was to download entire blockchain
which is like over 500,000 blocks and I
was afraid because my server machine
does not have enough space so what I did
is like I used blockchain API from
blockchain data blockchain calm now
before it was blocked in info and we
crawl all the transaction which were
which which was related to the address
of interest now how did we classify a
payment as ransom so the ransom is
asking BTC in Bitcoin or some time in
u.s. dollars they can ask pay me 300 US
dollars or pay me 1 Bitcoin but the
point here is that sometimes people
don't know how to pay 300 US dollars in
bitcoins because there is a fees
associated with it so when you when I
want to make a super fast transaction I
need to pay extra money over it so I
will pay 310 rather 300 in this
situation if I if I just consider 300
u.s. dollars my
my results from from for enzyme payments
would not be correct so what we decided
to do is that to take into consideration
the fees associated with every Bitcoin
transaction and for Bitcoin and both US
dollars we did the conversion and using
this for me using this mathematical
formula formula we we drive the results
for for our payment another key point
here is that I was really impressed with
on Kidd and the rest of his team's
economic analysis right because you
could analyze all the payments that were
made to ransomware over time and you
could decide that they all cashed out at
the peak of Bitcoin and you would get a
different number than if you decided
they cashed out every day so this team
did some analysis of max min and median
or was it mean price an average price
for those mathematically inclined so and
then they used that to assume that they
cashed out on the same day of the
payment or they look to see when the
payments were made later on and then
they could make an estimate of how much
money ransomware had made and I found
that to be a better estimate than any of
the other estimates that I read before
so kudos to you and your team things
so these are some payments I'm going to
show here so then we will conclude our
presentation IFS column it's a line
column wise so crypto wall you see on
the blue is a day to day payments or in
orange you see day to day BTC payments
and in green you see D day to day USD
payments so these are the some payments
that we discovered while we were while
we were doing this research for an
interval for cryptolocker yeah and we'll
look at a few slides in a moment of this
kind of data but the key concept I want
to get across to you here is every other
presentation you've ever seen of this
type has been obsessed with how much
money the criminals made it's the wrong
approach like yes if you work for
Europol or the police or something then
this is important because it goes into
your case for the rest of us we just
have to pay cleanup costs so we're not
interested in how much the criminals
made like in economic terms the economy
the criminals behave in is asymmetric to
ours they make a certain amount of money
it's different than the cost of
infection to the rest of us so we have
to pay the cost of cleanup whether we
pay the ransom or not so we should be
obsessed with the blue graph not the
orange or the green graph
the number of payments that were made
why because if we knew the average
number of people who paid a ransom per
ransomware family then we could multiply
up and know the scale of and face of
infection based off of the ransoms right
and then if we knew the cost of cleanup
then we could multiply that and we'd
have the total cost to society and we
can start talking about having the NHS
of ransomware and might governments
clean up ransomware right so similarly
for DMA and what I cry I think the same
crypto defense are not paid here the
same this is more important actually
just before this one just very briefly
so these blue graphs I also think
there's a really exciting thing here
different ransomware has different
spread strategies so some of it is a
worm some of it's a virus some of its
affiliate could we buy the ratio of
payments and the delta of change of
payments start to make an estimate of
what their infection strategies are
interesting idea for future we're
researching so just to sum up the
payments we see the here like almost
hundred and three thousand number of
payments and almost eighty eight point
four million u.s. dollar values paid to
these to these six families but the
point which Aaron was making is coming
in the next slide I think just keep the
number eighty eight point four million
in your mind and yeah because I want to
compare this actually before we get to
the comparison you had you at this point
which I think is funny and cool so also
this thing what we discovered is like
how many payments were made on weekdays
and weekends
so what we discovered was like more
payments were made on weekdays as
compared to weekends we speculate the
idea is people who are in personal
capacity like in my in my personal
laptop I refrained to pay I would like
to wipe out my system because I take
regular backups
however for organization who work for
Monday to Friday they make payments on
Monday to Friday so when we saw these
payments we did an analysis considering
the time shift of time zones and this is
the graph which we saw so 80% of the
payments were made on weekdays we do not
claim any I mean we do not have any
solid proof for this but we suspect that
most of the companies tend to pay for 4d
ransoms yeah it's correlation not
causation okay
so getting back to my basic point
there's a fantastic paper that inspired
me when I was a researcher and when the
first time I was invited to hack how you
by Alexander it was because I was put in
touch by a researcher called Richard
Clayton who's well known in the incident
response community and a generally
fantastic guide to speak to and he wrote
this paper that's kind of under cited it
only has like 23 citations which i think
is disappointing and it's called might
government's clean up malware so go and
read the paper and in the paper he talks
about the strategy of how companies and
governments might collaborate so let's
say the government funds it to some
degree and a local computer emergency
response team is willing to clean up the
the malware of some kind they might sell
other services such as a new antivirus
product or a new computer or
exfiltration detection service right so
they could make a little extra money off
of this as piglia scheme while they're
cleaning up the government or cleaning
up the malware on a kind of government
you know fee right and it's a great idea
so it shows like the average cost of
clean up could be like 90 US dollars for
regular malware this is you know before
we were really talking about ransomware
so the cost might be different but they
can bring the price down by offering
these extra services and making a little
bit of extra money on the side and he
eventually comes to the conclusion that
it could be done
the government's payment subsidy into
the system might be 66 cents per
computer right which is an extraordinary
sum so go and read the paper and decide
for yourself maybe you don't agree with
the numbers but that's the point maybe
the numbers work in some way differently
right so let's say he's crazy and it
costs sixty six dollars per computer
just to do the calculation right we know
this calculation is wrong but we want to
talk about it so we have the number of
payments and infections multiplied by
what we think the ratio of people who
actually pay is and then we have the
cost of payment so this is you know if
one in 20 people pay all of the ransoms
that we saw what is the cost to society
and this comes out at like a hundred and
thirtysomething million so you compare
that to what the criminals are making
they're making less money then they're
causing us as damage in society
which is no surprise it's classic
externality in the economic sense right
so the economists are excited but I'm
also interested in whether or not we
could create Mutual's to handle this so
I go back to the insurance industry and
I start to ask them and I start to find
these numbers we're not Pecha is
supposedly not pat you alone one
ransomware family is supposed to have
costs the insurance industry maybe three
billion right now those numbers don't
seem to make sense to me right why well
because people might be ineffectual at
cleaning up around somewhere or the
corporate level fees are much higher
than the ones that we're seeing here we
know that to be true when they charge a
corporation a ransom they charge a
higher amount than some of the
transactions we've seen here the point
is that there's a big differential here
and the insurance industry is still
profitable after paying out three
billion in losses which tells you
something about the profitability of
malware versus insurance so wrapping it
up get me to the final slides so people
can have more coffee yes what we
discovered was like ransomware campaigns
were just increasing day by day and even
novice users can launch these campaigns
just by copy-paste simple copy paste and
for the insurance part do we need a do
we need their insurance or not it's up
to you if you would like to do an
insurance or would you like to take a
hit by runs over yeah I mean keep in
mind again I'm not talking about
corporate insurance like you could
approach this as a socialized medicine
problem you could approach this as a
mutual you could find five other
organizations that have a similar risk
profile and put aside a little money for
yourself for a rainy day when you get
hit with a breach or ransom and that's
called creating a mutual and I'm
interested in those kind of not for
profit insurance Mutual's or risk
captives as well where you create a
company to hold the money for your
company in case of a rainy day does
anyone actually realistically believe we
can ban encryption on machines good just
checking okay and I have a book out in
December so if you want to buy a book
that buys me a coffee and I'd appreciate
that
on kitte needs lots of applause and
support because he worked very hard on
this and I think did some great work and
I also want to give a shout out to DJ
Jackalope whose shirt I'm wearing
because most of the research in this
project
was done listening to our music so
greets to her and applause for honking
hello well that's great you are on time
it's brilliant
you haven't had coffee he's standing
between you and coffee but are there any
questions in the room
yes sorry I had the question like the
the amount that undamaged cause to
insurance the 303 billion that site was
that mask
no that wasn't just like when you say
was that that's all payments across the
industry it's an estimate okay from a
company and like the estimate is better
than some but not as good as it could be
but I think the deeper question you're
asking is what's the largest driver
amongst that number yeah it's Merck not
murska interesting Maersk was something
like a 200 to 300 million payout we
think that mark like we're getting deep
into some insurance stuff that I don't
think everything everyone else cares
about but basically there's a difference
between affirmative insurance where I
sell you cyber insurance and then you
have losses and it's within the policy
and then there's stuff where you have a
regular policy that happens to have a
cyber and they call that silent exposure
so it's an exposure you didn't think you
had asbestos is a good example of it so
this is silent exposure three billion
this is property and casualty that got
charged with ransomware when they didn't
think they were insuring against
ransomware