hello good morning welcome I apologize
that I'm probably going to cut at least
a little bit into everyone's lunch
thanks to Linux on desktop but I will
try to get through this as quickly as
possible and still leave room for
questions that anybody may have at the
end so welcome to real world threat
intelligence and where we're going to
take a look at some of the threats that
users sometimes face in the wild so
before I get into some of the threats
that I've kind of gotten to see out in
the real world I want to tell you a
little bit about my background because
it is really non-traditional and that's
actually been quite an asset for me I
don't come from a traditional computer
science background at all I actually got
into security through teaching workshops
to activists and I got into that through
emergency medical response so it's been
quite an interesting path to kind of
wind up here on this stage in front of
you and there are a few takeaways that I
have from both of these backgrounds that
I want to share so activism is where I
learned a significant portion of my
threat modeling both how to do it and
also how to talk to people when
sometimes they think that their threat
is one thing but their threat is
actually something else I work in the
United States mostly and a lot of the
activists there have a tendency to think
that their greatest threat is the FBI
the FBI probably does not care about
their bike-powered kale farm but local
law enforcement might and the way that
you address both of these threats is
going to be a little bit different so
figuring out how to get other people at
threat model appropriately is also one
of the things that I've gotten from my
activism background I've also developed
a really good understanding of
operational security and tradecraft
through both my own activism and helping
teach other activists how to do things
ideally without landing in prison and
yeah that's not something that
a lot of people who are coming from CS
backgrounds generally really get to
develop an understanding of especially
tradecraft so I also confirm Emergency
Medical Response and this has been
really really really useful to me
because I already have a really great
understanding of triage if it's not
bleeding out then it can probably be
managed and if somebody is bleeding out
then it can still be managed it just
needs to be done a little more quickly
this is translated to a background in
incident management as well and it's
given me the additional perspective of
the fact that I'm used to people who may
or may not die if they're not treated
correctly computers seldom have outcomes
that severe even when they're
malfunctioning horribly so it makes it
really really easy to maintain
perspective and keep calm and then the
last thing that I've really taken away
from my medical background is learning
how to develop a diagnosis before giving
treatment so that I can be sure that the
treatment that I'm suggesting actually
fixes the problem and I'm actually going
to keep going back to that point quite a
bit this afternoon or this morning so
diagnosing the problem in medicine the
first rule of diagnosing a problem is
talk to your patient your patient
probably knows things that you don't
know you might be looking at somebody
with a dislocated shoulder going oh my
god that's not supposed to be like that
and your patient may turn to you and go
oh no that happens every Thursday and
sometimes if I look the wrong direction
so sometimes your patient actually has a
much better idea of the failure modes
that they're experiencing in their
bodies and it turns out that users are
also going to have a pretty good idea of
failure modes that they experience in
their everyday lives we we also want to
kind of figure out whether they're a
pre-existing condition
that we should know about for example I
warned Raphael that probably it was
going to take a little bit of extra work
to set up my slide deck to display
correctly because I'm a Debian user and
audio-visual issues and Linux are one of
the things that are as persistent as
death and taxes
so are there any pre-existing conditions
we should know about is one of the
things that we kind of factor in when
we're starting to try to diagnose people
and then one of the other things is have
we seen something like this before have
we
in our experience seen circumstances
similar to the ones that our patient is
presenting with and does that inform our
treatment of them it might it might not
so the first rule of medicine is do no
harm and that means a whole bunch of
different things but it mostly means we
don't want to prescribe treatments
without having a really good
understanding of what the actual problem
is we don't just want to treat surface
level symptoms we want to actually fix
the problem at its cause and again that
means also talking to your patient it
means letting them know if there are
potential problems that they may face in
pursuing the treatment path that you're
recommending to them and it means
talking them through their options and
helping them decide what works best for
them because your patients care and your
patients quality of life are the most
important things in medicine so when
we're developing a treatment plan there
are a couple questions that we want to
ask one is are there a bunch of symptoms
to address and do we want to prioritize
treating some of them over others
next is are there potential
contraindications for the treatments
that we are recommending so if we're
thinking of pursuing medication as a
treatment for a problem that a patient
is experiencing does that medication
interact with other things that that
person is already taking is it going to
cause side of
facts in them that may be worse than the
condition that we're actually trying to
fix these are these are all questions
that we kind of want to ask if if we're
trying to figure out how to treat a
problem so another thing that we want to
kind of figure out is do some of the
recommendations that we're making need
to be prioritized over others
if we're looking at somebody who has
multiple issues going on we want to make
sure that we're treating the most
critical ones and that sometimes means
leaving the less critical issues
untreated and it also sometimes means
revoking treatments that were previously
in use so that we can treat the more
severe issues one of the things that
comes to mind is that same situation
where we're potentially prescribing
medication to somebody but it interacts
poorly with a medication that they're
already taking at that point in time
we're going to want to kind of look at
the the problem that the medication
they're already taking is treating the
immediate problem that we're trying to
solve by prescribing additional
medication and figure out which of those
is more important to fix because maybe
we can't fix them both and then the most
the two most important points are here
at the bottom chemist plan actually be
carried out if we're prescribing
solutions for our patients that they
can't actually implement then we're not
really helping we're just kind of adding
to the problem a little bit because
we're giving them hope and then not
giving them the support that they need
to act on it and then also will this
plan result in a net improvement to
their quality of life this one's huge
and it translates almost one-to-one into
security practice as well so
understanding threats we want to talk to
targets we want to know what they think
their threat model is sometimes they're
wrong but more often than not they have
a really really good understanding of
what they're afraid of and what they
want to protect and from who
they probably have a much better
understanding of that than we do because
we've just met them and they've been
living in their bodies their whole lives
we want to understand how the threat
that they're under is impacting them
that doesn't just mean how it could
potentially harm them in the future that
doesn't mean what attack surface is open
we also want to know how the threat is
impacting their mental health their
daily life because a lot of the threats
that normal users face cause them to
feel like they can't live their lives
the way that they want to and because we
are prioritizing their quality of life
and that's the question we want to
figure out we also want to know if there
are other immediate threats that we need
to take into account so if somebody is
coming to us about one problem we want
to get a good idea of their total threat
landscape not just a good idea of the
circumstances around that one problem so
that we can factor that into our
decision making process and again have
we seen anything like this before this
particular question has come up really
really really often in my own practice
as an independent consultant and it's
actually helped quite a bit because I
have a tendency to get people who come
to me panicked because their phone is
doing something really really weird they
think that it might be malware and even
in cases where it is being able to say
hey this probably actually is malware
but I've seen malware just like this
before this is behaving erratically in a
predictable way and in ways that other
people have also experienced you're not
alone you're not crazy and you're not
imagining this so have we seen anything
like this before helps quite a lot when
dealing with users in the wild use
signal use torque raise your hand if
you've ever given this advice to
somebody who was asking you for security
advice nobody in this nobody in this
room has said you signal you store
does anybody know why I'm asking OPSEC
because of OPSEC let's actually let's
explore that a little bit when you say
because of OPSEC what do you mean okay
this person over here in the front said
that there may be more important
problems to address before suggesting
signal on tour and that's sometimes true
this phrase comes up a lot in in the
United States I've also seen people
outside of the US recommending these two
tools it's not inherently bad advice
recommending signal and tour in most
cases won't pot or won't cause
additional threat to your user or the
person that you're trying to help but
it's important to think a little bit
before you recommend tools we don't want
to recommend the security tools to
anybody if we don't know how those tools
are going to impact their lives some of
the cases that we're going to kind of
think about in a couple moments here are
actually some cases where this might be
actively dangerous advice because while
using signal and using tor under normal
circumstances is probably benign at
least and may actually help there are a
lot of use cases where advocating the
use of specific security tools may be
enough of a red flag to the threat
actors that people are dealing with to
actively endanger them so we just want
to make sure that we're not recommending
tools without really really
understanding the circumstances of the
people we're recommending them to so
securing targets this slide looks really
familiar because it's really really
similar to our treatment plans for for
medical patients so how big is the
attack surface right we want to know the
landscape of what they're facing not
just the one issue that they maybe have
come and presented us with we also want
to know they might think that their
phone is vulnerable but we also want to
kind of get an idea of how vulnerable
their everyday life is maybe other
devices that are in their possession
there are a bunch of things that we want
to take into account here we also want
to know whether addressing some threats
is going to make the target more
vulnerable to others so if we're
recommending that somebody start using
signal and tor for example but they're
living somewhere so if let's say we're
recommending somebody to use signal and
tor to help them fly under the radar of
surveillance state surveillance if that
person is also in an abusive
relationship that advice might actually
be endangering them because if you're
dealing with intimate partner violence
in your everyday life the appearance of
security tools on your device may
actually trigger your abuser to become
violent so that's one of the things that
we want to consider we also want to
think about whether some recommendations
need to be prioritized over others so
whether some threats are posing a more
clear and present danger to our users we
want to ask if the target can actually
carry out this plan telling our users
that they'll be totally secure if they
just use tails might sound like really
good advice except that they're probably
not going to actually do that which
makes it potentially less than useful
and finally will this solution result in
a net improvement to their quality of
life the idea is not to make them jump
through a whole bunch of hoops for like
a marginal increase in quality of life
we want to make sure that we're actually
improving their day to day experience so
let's talk about threats these are a few
of the threats that I have
in the wild stalkers they tend to be
fairly persistent but are usually
relatively low skill level overbearing
relatives snooping bosses other
generally creepy people who are kind of
in your everyday life and maybe want to
know a little bit more than you want
them to know or maybe want to know
things that they have no business
knowing my dating life is definitely not
my boss's business intimate partner
violence I have had the opportunity to
work with a lot of people who are facing
this particular threat it is a really
scary one and there is no one single
solution to that problem so every time I
work with somebody I have to actually
kind of figure out a and targeted
solution for them and their
circumstances state repression I have
had the I guess I want to say privilege
but I shouldn't have to work with
activists from all over the world
because people should be free to express
dissidents but I have gotten to work
with activists from all over the world
and I've learned a lot of really
valuable lessons again this is another
threat model that requires plans be
tailored pretty specifically to each
individual targets path of life but it's
a really interesting problem to solve
and then finally actual freaking Nazis
and other non-state political
adversaries and this one's kind of
important for a couple of different
reasons because these adversaries do go
after political activists but in a lot
of places they also go after people who
are just normal human beings whose
lifestyles they maybe don't agree with
so a lot of people who are not even
necessarily terribly politically engaged
but happen to be people of color or
transgender people or queer people or
disabled people actively face threat
from a lot of these far right-wing
zealots who just don't
that they deserve the right to live and
if they happen to be outspoken that
threat is increased so what all of these
threats have in common is actually quite
a lot a lot of the tactics that they use
are fairly similar they all use open
source information on their targets or
open source intelligence on their
targets to kind of build a profile of
that targets path of life so that they
can figure out how best to mess with it
they all use fear as a means of control
they all really really negatively impact
the quality of life of their targets
just being targeted in this way is
enough to make people think that maybe
they can't or don't deserve to live the
life the way that they have been and
that's a really really detrimental
effect that is often overlooked another
of the things that all of these problems
have in common is they can't be
technology dawei these problems are
going to persist because they're human
problems and we can't actually solve
them with computers we can use computers
to help in some cases and we can
certainly use computers to reduce attack
surface for these people but we can't
computer the problems away we have to
actually solve them in human ways and
finally all of these problems result
require dynamic solutions tailored to
the individual targets needs because
again we want to make sure that we're
recommending strategies that people can
actually implement and incorporate into
their lives so that they use them and so
that they get the security benefit from
them so let's talk a little bit about
stalkers creepy bosses overbearing
parents just general snoops right they
are usually pretty unsophisticated there
are a few exceptions to that rule we've
certainly seen a rise of stalker where
in the last five years or so can you
raise your hand if you've heard the term
stalker where and know what I'm talking
about
okay so awareness is also spreading
that's really exciting for those of you
who don't know what I'm talking about
stalker wear is a class of remote access
tool that is usually deployed to a
device via either physical access to
that device or a phishing attack
typically it comes from somebody that
the owner of the device knows and trusts
so it might be a significant other it
might be a parent it's frequently sold
as tools to monitor your children's
device usage but by allowing that to
kind of persist we're also allowing
these tools to be used in other
potentially even more nefarious ways and
I say potentially because even using
these tools to monitor your kids devices
teaches your kids that surveillance is
okay and good and that they should
accept it and that's definitely not a
message we want to be sending but so
we're seeing a rise of stalker where and
that is one of the technical advantages
that some of these particular threat
actors actually do have access to a lot
of these particular threats have direct
physical access to their targets whether
because it's a stalker who has
established this person's pattern of
life and is starting to show up places
where they think that person may be or
an abusive spouse who lives with this
person or a parent who you know maybe
only sees their kid a couple times a
year but asks them to bring their
computer because they've you know bought
them a new hard drive or something they
they frequently have physical access to
both the target and their devices and
that can be a real problem they also
will all have the potential to pose
significant risk to the targets physical
safety so with all of these threats
we're looking at a potential risk of
bodily harm to our target if they're
handled incorrectly
and that's something that's really
important to keep in mind when we're
making recommendations these particular
threats probably can't be eliminated but
in a lot of cases they can be mitigated
so that at least our targets have a
chance at living a happy fulfilling life
and that's gonna be our goal here right
we can't make somebody stop obsessing
over someone but we can make it a lot
harder for them to impact that person's
day-to-day life so a few of the things
that I would recommend actually you know
what let's let's not look at that yet um
I want to know what you would recommend
if a friend came to you and said that
they had a stalker what's the first
thing you might suggest set your
accounts to private yeah that's a really
really good place to start making it
harder to track you on social media is a
really really great place to start what
else would you recommend
that's a really really good suggestion
and I'm gonna go ahead and repeat it so
who to talk to in case you're having
trouble and organizing spaces for you to
be in to talk about problems spaces that
are safe for you anything else
keep records yeah that's actually a
really good idea too and I like that you
phrased it that way and so keeping
records is really useful because it
allows us to consider how we might want
to use documentation later but it
doesn't necessarily imply or require our
getting the state involved in our
problem because in a lot of cases that's
not necessarily useful anything else
okay so one of the things that we are
gonna do is like this gentleman over
here suggested make sure that our target
has a support system we want to make
sure that they have friends who are
checking in on them we want to make sure
that they have friends who are going to
notice if something goes wrong we want
to make sure that they have people that
they can rely on for support because all
of these threat actors use isolation to
increase attack surface we also want to
make sure that they establish escape
routes and have safe spaces set up for
themselves we want to make sure that
they have contingency plans and duress
phrases that they can use with their
trusted parties with their support
systems so that if you have a weekly
check-in setup where you say hey are you
gonna be a yoga class on Wednesday and
the person who's being targeted says no
I have a scheduling conflict maybe
that's a good clue to you that they're
not actually doing okay and that
immediate action needs to be taken it's
a totally benign message but it's one
that you can kind of establish
beforehand and using the event of an
emergency that won't trigger violence
hopefully from from the person that
they're facing threat from so that's a
way that we mitigate throughout without
causing suspicion
other ways that we might want to think
about mitigating threat without causing
suspicion or maybe instead of
recommending that they use signal and
use tor we want to start getting them to
use Facebook secret messages which is a
weird thing for a privacy advocate to
stand up here and suggest but Facebook
is a messenger that millions and
millions and millions of people around
the world use every freaking day it's
not a security tool and it actually has
an end-to-end encrypted messaging option
built into it with ephemeral messaging
so that those messages can be deleted so
it's it's not actually a bad suggestion
to make in this particular use case and
that's one of the reasons that I say
that we should start thinking about all
of the problems that somebody is facing
before we recommend tools because
sometimes the problems that they're
dealing with in their lives call for
really unconventional security or
privacy tools and then as the gentleman
in the back suggested we also want to
help them reduce their open-source
intelligence footprint so locking down
social media accounts may be developing
pseudonyms for using social media
there's there's a whole bunch of
different things that we can do we can
also teach them some basic
compartmentalization so that they can
kind of control which bits of
information are linked to which other
bits to help kind of carve out some
privacy for them so that they can help
or they can start making plans to to
take care of themselves
state repression so the first thing I
want to say about this is not all state
actors are created equally there is a
huge difference between local law
enforcement in the United States and the
NSA and which of these particular actors
we're dealing with is going to pretty
drastically influence the suggestions
that we make their objective is
generally to alter the targets behavior
so whether we're talking about state
repression in a country where it's
illegal to be gay or state repression
against dissident
or state repression against women all of
these things are are done to people
because the government wants them to
stop being a problem they want their
behaviors to alter and so our objective
when we're dealing with this is to
prevent our users from having to alter
their lifestyles because we want to
protect that we want to preserve that if
we keep our users safe but they have to
change to their lives in order to do it
the government has won and they didn't
even have to do anything
state Rep repression may also threaten
the physical safety of targets it can
this can happen in a whole bunch of
different ways it might mean
incarceration incarceration is a threat
to the physical safety of any human
being if you are in prison you are being
harmed it doesn't matter if you're
getting three square meals a day if you
don't get to do the things that you want
to do and have the life that you want to
live
that's harm that that's not something
that is OK it may also include black
bagging meetings sometimes dissidents
are killed so there are a whole bunch of
different levels where state repression
actually does threaten the physical
safety of targets all of them are valid
things that we want to avoid all of them
are things that we really want to
prevent state repression can also
threaten targets loved ones and that's
something that there may not be a
perfect solution for but that we want to
take into account when we're starting to
make recommendations and when we're
working with our targets to help them
build their safety plans and then
finally they can also threaten the
targets livelihood it's not uncommon for
people who are facing state repression
to also be blacklisted in their
profession harassed coming to and from
work so that's something that's
important to keep in mind as well so the
first question that we're going to ask
when we're dealing with somebody who is
facing
state repression is an essay or not NSA
these are the two threat models right if
it's the NSA the other way that I've
heard this phrased is Mossad or not
Mossad which is accurate if it's NSA or
Mossad there's probably not a whole lot
that we can do to help that person we
might be able to help them protect their
families a little bit better we might be
able to help them come up with an exit
strategy but there's probably not a lot
that we can do to secure our users
against those particular targets the
good news is most of the threats that
people are facing are not NSA and if
it's not NSA there's a good chance that
we can help those folks at least reduce
their attack surface cool so again the
objective our primary objective is to
prevent or to protect our user and
protect their lifestyle since them doing
the things that they do in their
everyday lives
is what is causing them to face state
repression in the first place we want to
make sure they get to keep doing that
thing we also want to make sure that
they're do using basic hardening methods
on their devices their communications
depending on where they're living using
signal and tor might actually be a great
way to help with that using signal and
tor can certainly help people slip
through the surveillance dragnet in the
United States in other parts of the
world we're using security tools is a
red flag that kind of draws the eye of
Sauron on to you it might be a better
idea to recommend things like whatsapp
because it's widely used and isn't
actually a security tool we also want to
you know like I said tools are gonna
depend on a lot of factors another the
factor is that our tool recommendation
is going to depend on is the technical
capability of the user we're working
with if we're working with a normal
human
we probably don't want to recommend that
they switch to running Linux on desktop
which I say like that because I've been
doing it for a really long time it's
fine we also want to start talking to
our target about how to protect their
loved ones and this can mean a whole
bunch of different things this can mean
getting them to talk to their loved ones
about the threat that they're facing and
the threat that their loved ones may be
facing and it also might mean creating
distance between themselves and their
loved ones for their protection it's got
to protect it's going to depend pretty
widely based on circumstances but it's a
conversation that we should be having
with people that we're trying to protect
so that they can decide what's going to
work best for them again we're gonna try
to reduce their open-source intelligence
footprint this is more because we want
to protect their non relation loved ones
so we don't want to make a really really
clear map of what their social network
looks like so we're gonna go ahead and
help teach them how to compartmentalize
and and reduce their social media
presence so that it's not evident from
looking at their Facebook who their
three best friends are and who matters
most of them outside of their immediate
family so that's something that we're
gonna go ahead and do miscellaneous
political adversaries which are people
like actual heck and Nazis and other
people who hate fun they probably don't
have the same resources as state actors
but sometimes they will actively attempt
to leverage some of the state resources
we've seen a lot of daxing in the United
States where people have taken gone to
great lengths to D anonymize individuals
captured in photos at various
demonstrations and then pass that
information on to law enforcement in
hopes of law enforcement seeking
prosecution against them so while a lot
of these miscellaneous threats don't
necessarily have state-level resources
there is a lot of collaboration between
the two
at least in the United States the
government frequently does very very
eagerly accept that help that they're
receiving and does go after left-wing
activists so that's something to keep in
mind we also see a lot of miscellaneous
political adversaries targeting people's
livelihoods targeting their families
it's usually done a little bit
differently so where state actors may
threaten incarceration or other physical
harm to someone's loved ones usually the
kind of random people who hate fun and
political speech will do things like
send harassing mail and phone calls to
people's families which is still really
scary for the people on the receiving
end of that and still something that we
want to help them avoid and we also see
them doing the same with people's
employers calling their bosses and
trying to get them fired which has
happened to me and it's really not fun
to deal with so they use general
bullying tactics so the first thing
we're gonna do here is try to help them
reduce their open-source intelligence
footprint because this is the primary
attack vector that a lot of these people
have this might mean removing pictures
of their face from any public social
media sites as best they can
it's definitely going to include locking
down their social media profiles it may
involve choosing to use a different name
so that their legal name is not
associated with their political activity
in ways that these particular threat
actors can find and again
compartmentalization like we were
talking about before is gonna be really
useful in this situation perhaps even
more so because the government probably
knows who you are and who you're related
to
but randoms on the internet might not
and again we want to make sure that
we're supporting targets and maintaining
their lifestyle these folks come after
all sorts of different human beings and
we want to make sure that people who are
being
because of the circumstances of their
birth have the right to continue being
exactly who they are without harassment
so what can we do I'm really lucky
because I get to work with a lot of the
people facing these threats directly and
that means that I can help them figure
out plans to secure their lives and go
about their business but that's not true
for everybody in this room and that
doesn't mean that there aren't things
that every single person in this room
can do to help so one of the things that
we can do is we can start thinking about
security like health care and when I say
that I don't mean like American health
care right security is for everyone it's
not just for people who can afford it
and are gainfully employed so we can
start taking preventative measures to
help minimize the frequency of
emergencies that means making sure that
the code we're pushing is actually
secure and not full of thugs which can
be you later exploited it also means
listening to our users about their needs
and their concerns I'm gonna say that
again it means listening to users about
their needs and their concerns it means
actually believing people when they say
that the product that you're developing
and dangers them in some way they might
not have a solution for how to fix that
problem but they might have ideas on how
to mitigate it and it's worth hearing
them out and the only way to do this is
through robust testing and actually
engaging with users on a regular basis
we can also get details before
recommending strategies and tools so
that we're making the best
recommendations and the recommendations
people can actually implement and we can
be good stewards of user data the EU is
definitely taking a wonderful step in
that direction with gdpr but we all have
the ability to kind of push for better
regulations around user data all over
the world and we certainly have the
ability to push internally within our
own organizations for better security
for user data and the last thing
here is treat your users with respect
and dignity users are not the weakest
link in insecurity users are actually
part of the security solution because
again they know what their threat
vectors are they know what their attack
surfaces and they know how you can help
them reduce that so the last thing that
I want to ask is because I'm a person
who's coming from a non-traditional
background and because I spent all of
this time telling you that you need to
talk to users and you need to listen to
users I want you to remember that every
single person that you meet every single
day of your life
is somebody that you can learn something
from and somebody that you can teach
something to that doesn't mean every
single person necessarily wants to have
that interaction with you and that's
okay but I think that if we start
treating each other this way we're gonna
see a lot of the social problems that
we're facing in technologies start to
melt away so please if you take nothing
else from this take this home with you
and finally if you want to get in touch
with me here is Twitter email my blog
the blog is not in fact malware it's
right there in the name I'm super
trustworthy if anybody has any questions
now is a great time thank you so much
[Music]
[Applause]
hi how questions since you're somewhat
of an expert in something happened in an
embassy in Turkey would you have been
able to tell that person not to enter
this embassy oh man I have so many
thoughts on that and is a really
complicated question I would say that
probably if you're facing that level of
threat from a state adversary going into
their house is maybe not the best idea
that said I don't think anyone thought
that they would do that there in the
embassy because as a state actor being
like oh yes this person that we didn't
particularly like wandered into our
embassy and didn't walk out is not
exactly subtle so I I would definitely
recommend that you not just walk into
your adversaries house but also I
understand why that person did anyone
else no questions yes I I was wondering
the advice that you gave in the last
slide all right I'm aware this could be
a whole separate talking of itself but
how would any advice for convincing like
product organizations to take that
advice if that makes sense um it's hard
one of the things that I can recommend
doing is the thing that I'm doing right
now I actually hate giving talks and I'm
terrified of being up on stage but I'm
doing it because I think that pushing
the narrative that we need to start
listening to users is really important
so I would definitely suggest that
that's one way to to do that but also
just kind of like presenting it in a way
that makes them think that they've come
up with that idea themselves is another
great way to kind of help get better
adoption of that strategy so that might
be another way to think about
approaching it very cool thank you
you're welcome
anybody else more questions in the room
let's say people want to do more work
like you do and they come from a
traditional security background how do
they find their space to participate to
help out how do they participate take it
from theoretical to practical work yeah
that's a really great question and I'm
really glad you asked I'm one of the
recommendations that I would probably
make is to start looking for
organizations who are working on
projects you really really care about
and offer to plug in with them a lot of
nonprofits don't really have great
security teams working with them so that
might be a really good first step and
usually if you can kind of get a foot in
the door helping out in these spaces in
that way you can kind of figure out
where your next steps might be any more
questions and I have a question you
talked about the people you work with
how do they find you out of people that
are in these situations how do they find
somebody like you to help them so a
bunch of different ways I am a really
public person I have made it really
really easy to contact me my Twitter DMS
are always open my email address is
published on my Twitter profile and then
I do a lot of writing as well so I've
written for publications that have
fairly wide readership on some of these
issues and made sure that anyone reading
it kind of had a way of contacting me
just from the article that they read as
well and I've also done some work with a
couple of different NGOs to get put in
touch with people so a whole bunch of
different things I work I'm specifically
thinking about people you're saying that
can't contact how do you know how do
people have a really in a difficult
situation that anything is flagging
something up have it how do they find
help I think that's where building those
support systems comes in really
so making sure that people aren't cut
off from their support systems is
something that we want to push so that
we can just be there even for our
friends who are facing some of these
issues and if somebody who's directly
under threat isn't able to reach out to
me themselves maybe somebody who's in
their support network can kind of give
me or someone like me an idea of what
their threat landscape looks like and we
can kind of work to help develop a plan
for them without ever directly
communicating with that person who might
be put at risk by talking to me right
any more questions or comments okay I'm
sure you'll be happy to talk to people
outside it's lunch time thank you
[Applause]