hello everybody so it's really great to
be back
I guess hacking is one of my favorites
conference ever I will be talking about
rape exploitation but don't be really
happy about that because it's not sort
of proper towards it I will be talking
mostly about the things that are not
working at all and that's why it makes
it really important to talk to tell that
this is thing something that I'm doing
my free time and my free time I really
mean like after work weekends as some of
you know doing slides around the world
and um so don't be into Demento it's
really free time stuff and another thing
is I'm not of an ability research that
means that everything that I'm doing
here is like experimental and mostly
theoretical because for those that know
me knows that I do a lot of mess so
about me
I like binaries so it doesn't really
matter which kind of binaries as long as
they are compiled and I really like
assembly I work mostly with x86 but I
also try to do stuff in MIPS and other
kind of stuff
I am also korra member and board member
of black hoodie that's a reverse
engineering boot camp just for women
that we organized it wants to know in a
year plus some spin-offs like we had
this Monday here trakula I am also in
the program committee but I cannot vote
for my talk so don't worry about it I'm
also working for disobey as a
technicality of content there I give
lots of workshops on assembly reverse
engineering and other stuff and I'm
trying to get really good at karaoke so
that's the most important thing that you
should know about me
I'm terrible but I'm working on that so
what I'm going to talk about today here
is about constraint logic programming
solvers static analysis and all the
problems that you have with that about
memory of course and heap or kind of so
the first question that I have is always
like such as empty what are you talking
about so it's just a sober it's
something that it's going to solve our
problems sounds good right and the
problem is so birds are that like the
such problem is unknown at your ethical
problem is np-complete problem that
means you cannot solve it without
Garifuna it easily not in a way that we
know how to do it and everything needs
to be written in boolean functions and
that's pretty complex so you cannot
easily describe the whole words just
with logic right so that's the reason
people are working on SMT solvers that's
like a front-end not like web
applications fronting a bit dirtier but
it's just you a front-end that makes it
easier to write real word problems in a
way that it's translated to boolean
logic so how this day's work is mostly
like you have something like this
picture and the server's are going to
try to reason about questions that you
make about it so you have the situation
that you are seeing here and the
question is can I go outside without
getting wet so the server is going to
look at it and you'll see okay there is
a lot of tough water on the street it
looks like rain so oh wait I see people
with umbrellas and they are not wet so
it will give yes there is a possibility
this is getting an umbrella and then you
say no that is not going to work with me
I don't have an umbrella what else and
then it will check again and say yeah so
nope
you don't have a chance to get outside
without getting wet
and so I'm talking about about call
strings and I realized that the easiest
way to explain what constraints are is
like looking at a maze the constraints
would be like walls inside this maze so
at first you don't have so many walls so
you can find more ways to go from the
beginning to the end and every time that
you wear the constraint yeah it's like
you are adding out whoa
India maze so it's getting harder and
harder and the paths towards the
beginning to the end are less and less
ER and this is the coat that you were
always going to see in my talks because
that's the guy that like mostly inspired
me to change from other styles so
computer science and that's it he told
me that tastes something that can solve
my problems without me having to do that
so why not and what I use to solve my
problems is something that it's using
constraint programming and also solvers
that's they automate Siri improvement so
if you want to know how the essence of
is self work or like internals of the
logic inside we can talk about that
later offline because that's just 45
minutes but you can assume that's a
black box you put a problem inside our
feet like we did before which the ring
and if I can get outside and everything
and that is over will analyze all the
constraints that you have of the
situation and limitations and then it's
a is it feasible or not to do what you
want and the good part of it is like
it's not just saying to you yeah you can
do that but also how how you can achieve
with all your constraints to solve your
problem the way you want and why is it
interesting is like people were using it
before in the mess
the mathematicians wanted to take small
little pieces of problems put them
together to solve bigger ones so you had
like these problems that are worth
millions on the list like big equals NP
right so you can model small parts of
this problem put inside an SMT solver
and try to solve and infer that the
bigger one is also feasible why do we
want to do that in computer science you
can think about code verification right
you have like hardware and software and
you want to verify that it's actually
working the way it's supposed to do
so you can have like little asserts
really small piece of code asserting
that it's doing this right the thing
that you want to do and then you can
escape it and then you have light scalar
verification people that are also using
SMT solvers in logic for computer
science at the lung sack pickup they are
actually implementing the logic inside
the parses so that the language itself
is safe so you cannot do much wrong if
you are using the right parts and how I
use it also in other people it's for
symbolic engines symbolic execution
engines so symbolically the question is
just like exploring the code with
symbolic values in that so you don't
have like concrete input you have like
symbolic input and you go through the
whole code like that and combine with
SMT solvers like I am using and other
engines to it will reason about if if a
path is doable or not if you I want to
explore the path or not if it makes
sense if it's unreachable anyway and so
on so it looks like this one you know if
you look at the code it's easier to
understand but in a theoretical approach
that I mostly talk about here is your
extender language that you're having are
turning machine with symbolic values so
then you can explore your whole code
without using like concrete values and
then you can find bugs in your code
without even as accusing it without
needing to further you first-first it
because you have the domains that are
possible and you find something that
it's not
I really is the algorithmic like just to
get an idea how it works would be like
this so we create processes every time
that you reach a state and then you have
the process known by United State and
you edit this process so for to the
domain of your whole system or whole
program and then you just iterate it
every time that you reach a branching
point in your code that it's visible you
had all both of the paths inside your
domain and if it's not then you just
negate the one that it's not possible
and put in your domain and then you
continue exploring your content you
didn't you understand how I was trying
to use this concept for automating the
exploitation of heaps
you need to understand how the memory
works because it's a bit different order
other stuff so memory is just that
you're storing information right and in
a hardware level it looks really simple
it's to select so if you have like and
or letters everywhere
if you just look like that it's really
really super me I'm not asking artists
and I can even make that so it's not
hard but in your processors it gets a
bit you bit harder because you have more
complexity so you need to imagine that
you just you don't have just one of it
because this one can you store just one
guy but one bit and if you think about
how many bits you have in your rest room
right now it's a bit more than that and
this one is also independent of the
whole context right now you have like
metrics of this kind of stuff inside of
of your processor communicating with
each other to have like a bunch of
information that belongs together but if
the hardware is the same what's the
difference in the difference in the
memory and any way that we know we have
more right yeah we don't have 50 shades
we have just like two or three depends
who you're talking with but we are going
to talk about the heap not about the
stack for the stack we already have like
bunch of work done
automated exploit for stack but not for
the heap and the funny thing is like why
I guess you know how this type looks
like it's mostly like that it's easy to
understand it's just put stuff together
and then you'll have the heap that looks
like this so the thing is if you think
about you have a stack of books and you
are just taking one from above it's easy
you know which book to get the next with
the heap is completely different if I
want if I say to you yeah I want that
book and you'll have this it's a mess so
it's pretty hard to find the right
position on your memory to actually
exploit a heap with under flows or
overflows because you don't even know
exactly where it is and the heap is also
a managed memory so you have regionals
for everything somewhere and even in the
Intel books they are defining like that
the heap is in a specified place so you
cannot know anyway so how can I put that
all together before I use it - oh sorry
before I was using a some cheese over
symbolic execution all these things to
make my job easier
that was my way on others but that work
is done and I remember that before I use
it to say like I know that people are
using it for posing code verification
binary analysis and also for PLC's and
exploit generation right and I was like
ok people are doing it but why is not
going further what's the problem there
what are people doing wrong and the
thing is I started to write some simple
proof of concepts using all this
theoretical approach
I like it because I see a lot of PLC's
out there from bugs and most of the
people I publish a PLC for something and
then two weeks later or maybe one week
later I see a bunch of malware using
this same really same code from github
and infecting a lot of machines and
that's not fair right it makes my job
harder so what I started to do is like
okay you can write PLC's using logic so
I can infer that the code is broken
without actually giving a working code
for it I don't need to exploit it to
prove that it's buggy and then I cited
okay so maybe I saw something there and
I started looking for stuff and I
decided to start with code verification
and that's a really broad field and then
I look at like okay if I'm looking for
all the bugs it's nothing not really
going to work right because I mean it's
my free time I need to do I also have a
life as a as you know what I really want
to be a karaoke singer so yeah so I
decided to make the my problem is Mahler
like the mathematicians make so if I
cannot prove like everything at once
maybe if I break a tree to pieces like
check the deeper it will work so that's
what I did I broke my problems of code
verification into smaller pieces and
then I decided to do like okay let's
just find bugs but not all the bugs but
exploit robots because they have
something else and maybe someone wants
to pay for it because if it's buggy but
no one can exploit this it's just a red
code then it's just bad code but if you
can exploit this then it you have a
value of it
and it makes more sense to fix something
that it's exploitable then she just fix
buggy code right so my problem was a bit
smaller now but it wasn't enough because
decided to check how to crash a code and
it's easy you can just write everywhere
and then de marisco to go hooked I
didn't scratched right but what does
that mean and then I decided okay that's
not enough I'm I will make even a
smaller I don't want to just crash
something I want to have control of the
code and then I started to check all the
techniques that are already there
the research haven't been done so I saw
that people were using exploratory
testing for finding the bugs that's not
my field it's fun tried it once but not
mine
I saw people using dynamic tainted
analysis yeah more interesting still not
mines because I cannot really do it good
with Prolog and that's my free time so I
choose what I want to do right and then
they people have like abstract
interpretation and excited to learn
about it and read a lot of papers in it
sounds super interesting so I was like
okay that could be Wiccans and and then
I saw click that's open source and
symbolic execution engine whatever it
runs on top at LLL VM super cool the
problem is it's not scalable you can use
like key for small pieces of source code
but not for my binaries and lot of other
stuff so I saw a Manticore it's working
on binary it's also symbolic execution
engine it's also doing tainted analysis
and it has binary instrumentation the
problem is you can use multi core for a
crack mix and you can use a multi core
for small binaries but I don't want to
start a bunch of binaries on my on my
computer just to play around all the
weekends so what I am doing is I'm using
just the B folder of my of my computer
and like pink poking everywhere and that
doesn't work with much core it crashes
all the time there is also another
engine that I found out like last week
so I didn't have time to put everything
here but the name is man hi
and it's pretty cool but I didn't test
it to the end
I cannot say much about them but it
sounds interesting what I choose to do
is like always it's three times so I
decided to implement my own and I'm
using forward symbolic execution that's
a symbolic execution but I'm using the
same key service in the branching points
to decide if it makes sense or not to go
to the end and I try to not have the
100% code coverage because my computer
cannot do that so the first thing was
find a bug that was easy it was really
easy you just need the symbolic
education there it's filtering the
domains and then you have the bugs but
for that I needed to define because I
like definitions and math so I defined
what is that does that mean that if
there is a bug there so I defined this
when I hope F is this you can see and
then I had a plan but for that I also
need a theorem right so I wanted to
define what kind of stuff I want to
prove in the end of my research so my
idea was that given a program I can
automatically find the vulnerabilities
and generate exploits for them sounds
normal science sounds ok yeah and then I
started to check which kind of
vulnerabilities I'm looking for the
thing is I also needed to define a
really small scope for it because you
cannot check everything the second
problem was that you have a lot of
techniques to finding bugs but not for
the checking if they exploit the words
so I started like ok I will check for
directing friends of the user every time
that user has the power giving some kind
of important and this input is change in
control flow of the program that's
directing when so it's like when you
define my lock with a size you are
defined directly stopping in the control
flow of your program right and then you
have the indirect that it's something
like that where the
user has the power of change selfie but
not directly so if you want to change
something that you need to know how your
input is influencing the whole hood in
in a way that it makes sense to exploit
it so the second step was to check if
the vulnerability that we found in the
first one is exploitable because I
didn't want to find all of them just the
one that makes sense right and for that
I was thinking okay let's use
concretization but it wasn't that easy
anymore because then I had like this
huge amount of possible inputs that you
have in your domain and if you put all
of them and test all of them then it's
just fuzzing it that's not really
automating the way I was thinking about
and I need a definition so there is I
wanted to find the paths that are
vulnerable and at the same time you with
the same input you need to find a
function that it makes it exploitable
and both of them needs to be true if one
of them are not true
that's not what I'm looking for I hope
that's clear
the third step was implement the
function that makes both sides true yeah
and then I implemented something the
problem was that it was working just for
a video a special case so for it was not
genetic or enough in my opinion so it
was working for some kind of malach like
I had a code for each kind of a bug code
access so I had like a piece of a
function that was working just for free
right opposite of free and then I had
one that it was just working for under
flows
that's just working for a special case
not always
and then I I noticed that it's just
working most of the time so every time
why if it the bug is the same right and
I'm there and even doing it manually is
was it still not working all the time
and then I was thinking okay if it does
this is the case is it Nvidia automation
if not even like doing my hand is
working anymore
so I added an extra step that was the
evaluation of the whole project and then
all the problems that I had along the
way the first one was like finding the
hip that was a challenge by itself I am
really happy that I had people talking
to me and explained to me and writing
amazing papers I'm going to list them on
the end that's a real complex problem
how to find the hip in the memory itself
and then they expert verification and I
thought before you have like this huge
amount of possible inputs that makes the
more files decoder than a video tomato
and exploit and then you had the 31 that
taste tastes a little explosion I don't
know if you know but I'm doing
everything on this is morphing here it
doesn't work like that you are doing
like a symbolic education you have like
a huge amount of memory being used all
the time and then I had the problem with
environmental definition and that is
what I did not expect and I I guess it's
a flower because I am not having ability
research so I was not thinking about
that but every time when I was checking
my the first time my memory was clean
because it was just booting my computer
the second time I was doing again and I
had something in my memory already and
in the third time I was just over
writing my memory and that's every time
that I was running the code without
rebooting it I had stuff there so you
really need to define which kind of
environment who you are using before
starting the first place so the
limitations that I had
at the first one they are always the
same when talking about symbolic
execution and code verification or any
kind of binary analysis it's basically
the halting problem because if you have
a code to verify another code it's
theoretically impossible to assume that
every time that you are verifying a
program with another program that it
will be hold for the property that you
are testing for so that means that you
cannot write a code to verify another
code and be sure that you can do that
every single time and the second one is
that if you define that your program
doesn't depend of the user input you are
still inside to this decidable languages
the problem was that when I was a cuting
the code multiple times in your memory
and had like garbage is still on my
memory I run into the underside
languages and if I don't take care of it
I can even go further to the
non-throwing asset where language is
because there are estates in my memory
that I don't want to go there
but we are talking about quantum physics
I cannot know what it's inside every
single thing on my processor right it's
impossible to know the state of it and
then we have the practical thing we are
still running normal processors they are
not a quantum computers right now so the
problem is that the normal processes
that everyone has everywhere in the
phones in a computer or whatever they
have in each state machine that means
they have to be machines and they are
disabled so I cannot write a code that
it's running in the another bubble in
there under desirable languages in a
desirable product because that's
uncomfortable right so after oh this
theoretical approach that I had my first
idea was that I could do something like
your case symbolic execution super cool
for when ability research right but then
I needed to change that can be
and I really believe that it can be
because the mothers ico pretty hard to
write and define and everything so the
main takeaway for myself was that I I
need to understand better how can I
build she research work because what I
did before were mostly related to my job
so I knew how things work manually so I
could automate it faster right if you
know how to do it yourself you see the
patterns you know how it works you can
automate and I'm probably I'm pretty
sure that if I've one ability research
sit in front of the code and define the
models it will work way better and way
faster they need to work at it for me
that's the reason that right now I
decided to write kind of assistant to
write these constraints for security
problems that are going into the SMGs
over so instead of modeling just for
malware and then modeling it just from
hip exploitation and then modeling it
again for its type of flows or whatever
what I can do is just create a framework
that will assist security researchers
that have the knowledge already from the
other side like I had from the malware
side to write these models by themselves
and then just use it the engine in the
back end because they don't need to know
how SMT solvers work but they know how
to model things in a way that it's
logical to check and the people that I
wanted to think about all this viscera
today it's like my list at least eight
months are Jean and Mario Sheryl publish
a paper it's it's already published it's
not anywhere to appear about hippie
layout manipulation so he was kind of
solving the problem that I had about
finding the hip and it was really
inspiring to talk with him like he she
was helping me all the time
and every time that I thought about like
giving up because it wasn't working the
way I I was thinking it was supposed to
work he would just say no you riding a
good path just keep doing it and my own
because she was the one that first show
me binaries another paper that helped me
a lot was the models that vinegar
presented in the SEC conference he was
modeling the the heap for the first time
in a theoretical approach that I could
use to model the exploits after the
Intel documentation kind of help
movement not really it depends the way
you look at it and that's it
[Applause]