so hello everyone I will show you some
stuff with phone from pasties using the
air framework which is another analysis
information leak software so basically
is a modular framework to analyze
potential information leaks from
unstructured data sources like pace from
Pez beam those operators available on
github and it is fully open source so
recently we included a new model which
is a built-in hidden services scroller
and I'll show you some result we we get
from it
so on average with this new new tool we
have around 7g bit of screenshot per day
only from onion we can phone on pasties
and we are only crawling it with the DEF
of one meaning that if we increase the
depth we will have way more data so for
example just below this is an example of
onion list that we can find on PES bin
so let's go with a slideshow so for
example on this kind of weather we can
see this kind of thing worried the guy
the webmaster is asking for money where
he pretend to be the father and know the
truth and so on what you can have also
it's basic country fates and replicas of
memory also Visa American Express cards
different type of services like IKEA
social media tread background checks
computer security training and so on
let's happy thing assassination murder
services
yeah it's pretend buy expensive and it
depends on the target also
this is really really interesting so
this is website which provide a way to
have a coach to lose weight and it's
only available in the hidden services so
it's not public on the index well and
they only accept Bitcoin and not trade
money
I don't know who would use that also
what you also what you have is some
classical illegal stuff like drugs
different type of drugs weapons of
course that you can found and this kind
of thing so precious material like
diamond where it provides interesting
information and even data sheet of the
product and of course I promise are
unique on there you are
this is interesting website called
mystery box so basically you just buy a
box and you don't know what is inside so
you have to pay sub in count they said
it's worth a hundred or thousands of
dollars but you don't know what is
inside and it's under the website you
have multiple 100 for example this is
another one where I pretend that you can
buy a mystery box that cost and
apparently there were hacked some times
ago but now they are back so all fine
you can only find fine schemers like
this or an improved version like this
and well it's not that expensive for
this kind of product as I would say also
you have things that can look like
really real the storage Jenica one where
they have some interesting features like
building languages a lot of them give
also the customer receive of the
transaction and and so on so you have a
lot of thing yes so we have a lot of
this kind of thing where they kind of
expect you to be a human to enter it
or even more interesting they require
you to disable JavaScript so it's kind
of the opposites in some cell some words
I want you to have the transcript
enabled but they want to that you have
this javascript disabled and this kind
of waiver visually or this kind of thing
were well that's not good
GL but and charge sexual abuse material
I suppose the protector I would say the
user to be detected with the turkey but
I don't know why they were doing it this
is very powerful so a guy just posted a
blog of recipes on the hidden services
not available on the index web and it's
full of recipes perhaps there is
something behind this but well who who
knows and last more edgy stuff so kind
of thing where journalists can post
their article and so on and that's it
for the quick slideshow because I don't
have much time so thank you very much if
you want to learn more about the a
framework it is essentially bird to
analyzing but you want to learn more or
soon learned about the new feature we
developed with basics which is really
interesting a lot of also fun I would
say content there is a workshop tomorrow
at 1:30 which is replacing the as
menacing so thank you very much
you