hi and welcome back to the studio track
it is time for a wrap-up session where i
am joined by my co-his co-host samuel
and the top dog of hacking the box lead
dog
thank you so much for joining us for a
wrap-up session oh my pleasure man you
guys have been running an awesome studio
for the last few days
thank you for the first time doing it i
i think i think we made it work in true
hack in the box spirit you know
definitely i mean there's a reason why
we chose you to be the pastor
because you've known us for the longest
time
from 2003 practically right or even
maybe earlier 2003 is when we started
discussing and then
i think my first was 2005 back in the
box
really yes
we were definitely in touch during that
yeah and i used to come to malaysia for
doing other instructional stuff for
for the malaysian powers that that were
yeah that was the powers that were
and we used to always bump into each
other it was great times goes to show
how long it's been right it's been a
while and it's been a it's been a great
ride
so um
this is one of the reasons why i wanted
you in the in the studio
we spent two days talking to friends old
and new
we've had some great memories great
thoughts shared
and we wanted to wrap it up in style
with the man himself thanks thanks um
let's have you just uh take us down hack
in the box lane oh man like how much
time
it's your show all the time
of money to travel there
it was just too expensive i thought
how hard can it be
[Music]
and here we are many many years later
and it turns out it's not that easy
but not that hard not that impossible
either exactly but the main thing that
i've always said is that as long as it's
still fun you keep doing it exactly and
it feels like what we've been doing over
the last couple of years
uh the consistency of that that energy
right that we get from the volunteers
and from the crew and from the folks
that come and we see the the looks on
their faces with the hacking stuff and
getting excited about it we were once
those guys right yeah we're looking on
the internet and like oh check it out
it's like dark song stuff you know i
want you to be like be able to meet them
yeah and now we see these younger guys
coming it's like oh man it's almost ah
you know it's over hurricane rice game
this is all just really cool guys that
we
that make up the security industry and
so that's really what pushes me to
continue to do it is because i still see
that a lot of people actually appreciate
it right and they they kind of like
understand what we're trying to do is
it's not easy but
it makes you worth it when you see the
reactions
indeed indeed
um
i have great memories of hacking the box
so let's do this right let's just start
from some of the earliest aha moments
you and i
and uh okay
in no particular order probably things
that work spectacularly well and then
things where things went spectacularly
haywire well i can probably remember
about the haywire ones that i cannot
feel like spectacularly well because
whenever anything goes mediumly well
without thank god everything worked out
fine right because uh yeah there's
always been times when we were like
will we make it through this you know
what i mean even in the first year i
think uh when we were with dr d you know
denis nyer back in the day right now
exactly right i mean we
we had somewhere he wasn't dr d then
he was always dr d but he never really
used that handle he was always like i'm
not sure i should say but his handle is
like alpha or something
right so the necklace that comes when it
comes yeah exactly
so yeah i mean uh we've had some really
awesome adventures man i think like the
first time we went to bahrain in 2004 or
was that 2005 and then you know a year
or two after we were in dubai
uh so many good memories man so many
good memories trekking into the desert
remember that time we went into the
desert they were like the desert where
the grug nearly passed out yeah yes i
think there's many conferences where
he's nearly passed out so you know i
kind of lost track which they said was
without consuming anything
yeah it's probably due to the heat right
like it's desert right what do you think
yeah yeah yeah remember that we were
thinking like why is he not making a
single sound normally it is impossible
for the drug to stay silent like it's
been 30 minutes since he spoke and he's
like oh oh oh oh i see
let's go home
here it's time to call this
yeah
what i took away from that was that hitb
stands for hospitality
you saw everything through it did not
matter that there were just eight people
out there yeah you had the parties you
treated everybody the way they should
have been no cutting corners you lost a
metric ton of money oh my god but
that's the spirit that i took away with
and i was like telling my friends like
this is this is what commitment means
this is what it uh means to take care of
your own thank you
thanks i mean the way i look at it is
that folks have taken time energy to
make the trip over right very similar to
this year as well i mean it searched
uncertain times that we are in right now
who knows what's gonna happen tomorrow
right like a week ago amsterdam was all
fine and well yeah now it looks like it
might go back to lockdown right so
things changed but people actually made
the effort to come and i remember lauren
odor he drove like from france to golo
knows where to make the trip over
because flights were cancelled yeah but
he did it and we owe it to him to give
him that hacking box experience man i
mean people took their time to come
right to deliver a talk like even if
it's just an hour
it takes effort energy to prepare it
right at least the least you can do is
host them as if it was if it was you how
would you like to be treated right and
that's what i always say is if you try
to make it that it's family we always
call it the hagerbox family right that's
that's what brings me back all the time
and the family grows larger every time
i'm every time i'm here it is it is
growing slightly larger yes
i mean i remember i'll rock off the
plane jack lagged
before i even come and put the baggage
in the room first stop is the secretary
yeah it may be 1am there's always
somebody there there's always everywhere
until four or five when you walk in it's
not like oh at the end of the day
like please can you leave me alone it's
like hi welcome bright smiles you sit
for a while you talk
have a coke or something
then
you may or may not log on to the hotel
network you'll never know but then you
kind of go back to the room and uh
you know sleep happy and then the next
day begins
so this type of hospitality i have not
seen
in other events through all these years
it's always been
seamless you're part of the crew part of
the ship
everything because it takes all of us to
make it happen right i mean let's be
honest right it's not just like yeah
we're the organizers so you know answer
to us but
if a speaker doesn't show up it's not
feeling well the speaker is not
at his best it doesn't make us look good
either right yeah so we're all in it
together as in every single person that
showed up here played a role played a
part no matter how small even if they're
a volunteer that just i used to say like
you know if you're the guy that's just
pulling the network cables you might
feel like that's like an inconsequential
job but somebody's got to do it right
and without that cable
exactly you know so everybody who is
who's played a part in hanging the box
no matter big or small
deserves to be to be to be treated right
and that's that's it it's just plain and
simple but maybe it could be a malaysian
hospitality thing i don't know
and that have been of course yeah
wonderfully yeah my first experience
like that amsterdam was
because i'd been to blackhead europe
before
and
say okay great it's also the
krasnopolski again and those are those
were old memories but a very very
different vibe came out it was like okay
this is malaysia once again and then and
then holland goes to malaysia malaysia
goes to holland and this was
like it became a part of my life my
annual life twice a year
a hack in the box was feature you know i
had forgotten about it in these
times but yeah it's all coming back so
coming back let's uh
make sure it stays this way yeah fingers
crossed
uh
well uh dylan would you want to give a
shout out to um
to anyone
well i would say i don't want to give
out i want to give a shout out to the
crew as always i always say like you
know i'm the guy who just answers the
emails right when whenever people email
us i'm the guy who understands but the
folks that actually produce the show and
make it what it is it's not me man it's
like usually i always say when it comes
close to the conference i'm quite free
stressed but quite free and it's all the
rest of the guys that actually deserve
the credit right so it's the dutch crew
the malaysian crew like liang wang daryl
amy
sherry i'm going to remember forget some
names obviously jaco
direct all the ctf guys from russia like
hackerdom everybody who has come those
are the guys that need the credit so
obviously if you see them at another
conference buy them a beer because you
know they're the guys man like without
them none of this would be possible i'll
just be answering emails and nothing
would have happened
so
[Laughter]
it's cool uh
thanks again cherry thank you so much
for
doing this together i
first accepted
villains requests like hey would you
want to be the host
and my idea was like yeah we're going to
walk over and you know take the camera
here and then
throw the thing around
we quickly had to improvise and it was
awesome to improvise and
you know i think we just made the whole
program up from from thin air so i want
to do it again
i would love to thank you so much
with me
i remember when when amy told me like
hey jerry can you do a host for studio
with sawmill and i practically jumped a
home in the air as we say in netherlands
just because i was so happy to do this
with you because it gets knowing better
so thank you so much for going on this
studio journey with thank you again
thank you very much i think we're coming
to the wrap of the studio for uh
heck of the box abugabe 2021 dylan one
last request
i know a lot of our folks have been
joining in remotely
the show is wrapping up but where can
they find the talks recordings oh yeah
sure
i'm i'll let you do that and then sherry
and i are going to wrap up and cool we
will let you uh i gotta get to the other
stage over
there lose do a little bit of a closing
note there so yeah but uh so where to
find the materials yeah so basically in
usual hacking about style uh all the
videos we uploaded to youtube
traditionally around a week to two weeks
after we finish
but it also depends on you know whether
cooper's feeling up to it i mean he's
the guy who records all the videos and
does all the post-production and it's a
lot of work to make it look right uh and
the material so each presentation uh
that's on the cyber website if you click
on it maybe not today but tomorrow or
day after you'll find that the
presentation slides are there um and of
course we'll be tweeting it out as well
so if you're not following us on twitter
why not you should be and that's where
you find the links and for the youtube
channel
smash that like button yes
they say right
all right guys all right it's been
awesome thank you yeah for being here
thank you for supporting us taking us on
this awesome journey in the studio event
i really appreciate it sherry as well
pleasure
all right see you guys