hi and welcome back to the studio track
we are joined right now by our very own
cooper
who is our local video god he has been
doing the videos of hakuna books for
many many years we're here to talk about
all of his experience in past years
hi hi
welcome cooper um
i've known you for several years now
you're uh nothing short of a legend
so uh
you're the guy who makes me look good in
all the talks that i give at hack in the
box and several other conferences
um we would like to talk to you about
how you pull off all the magic okay and
what's all the wiring that goes on
behind the scenes
and
everything you do
to overcome all the adversities as well
sure can you tell us a bit more about
how you first started attacking the boss
or by or first started by typing videos
for conferences in general so
hack in the box was
i think the
second conference i no actually it was
the first conference i ever volunteered
for
um just as like i was the guy standing
at the door helping people get in making
sure that if you didn't have a badge you
got sent back
um
this had everything to do with um
me trying to get
trying to understand conferences better
because um
i was
i was i was viewing a lot of conferences
conference talks online on youtube at
the time they were mostly american so
the defcon talks and that sort of thing
stuff that iron geek was doing
and
the
um
it it looked it looked appealing so i
asked my employer to send me to a
conference so they sent me ton of
conference uh the abstract eu
for reference i am a software developer
so doing going to an overwatch
conference makes a lot of sense
um
and i
went hey this is fun i want to do this
more
so um i walked up to my boss and was
like hey um that was a fun conference
now i would like to also go to that that
that i know like
that is way too expensive we can't do
that
um
so i looked into it and going to a lot
of conferences certainly is expensive
like doing one or two a year i'm sure
for like big ones like this
wouldn't need to break the bank but um
yeah if you want to do more than that
then it becomes quite cost innovative
so the solution i found was to just
volunteer for conferences so you'd be
able to at least pick up
some of it yeah um
and
i talked to a friend of mine
digininja
on twitter who uh i asked him like what
would be like a really good conference
for someone like me to go to
and he mentioned a few blue con
heck in the box got mentioned because it
would be local to me in the netherlands
and he off the cuff mentioned that he
was organizing his own conference in
sheffield england oh which
was of course
that just blew my mind it was like i
know somebody who organizes a conference
what
so i told him well i'm gonna come and
volunteer for your conference
and i'm sure he thought i was completely
nuts because who travels from the
netherlands all the way to england to go
to his 100 person last time at least um
but um sure enough there i was
and as i stood there going hey i'm here
i'm volunteering what do i do
the person who was doing the camera
duties for um for steelcon uh walked
through the door going sorry i'm super
late but um we have an hour and a half
to set up two tracks
who can help me
so i i was already interested somewhat
in conference videoing as a thing
so i said sure let's help
um i spent the rest of the day helping
this individual
filming
steelcon best be good but in the end i
think about 60
of the talks that we tried to film could
be put online and the rest had to be
discarded due to the various problems
that we had it was cameras out of focus
sd cards that filled up
the light balance was such that you just
could not see what was going on
and yeah all sorts of
nitty little problems that just
completely ruined
the video
so i after the conference was over it
also took many months before the talks
would even become available
so i talked to the individual
who was doing the videoing and asked him
like how could we do better
and he had a few suggestions but he
wasn't really willing to follow through
on it but i was inspired so i started
collecting hardware
putting together what would become my
first video rig
and at the same conference i
met
aaron finnen phoenix
who turned out to be organizing besides
hamburg opposite ccc
when was all this like what this was
2015 2015. yes
so seven years and counting yes
i mean i keep counting
um
he he organized uh visa hamburg opposite
ccc and um before uh before the event he
put out a tweet saying
there's not gonna be any camera there's
not going to be any photography we
haven't arranged any of that so if you
want to see something of this conference
just show up
which was my cue to go hey since there
is no video are you willing to take a
chance
and have me come in with this alpha as
can be set up
to see if i could maybe film your
conference
and he was game
i actually ended up borrowing my
mother's camera to do the other track
okay
and
filmed it
um
in the end everything that i filmed
there was at least i'm good enough to be
put online
i learned a heck of a lot
um
but that was what started it off so i
didn't i did one conference in 2015
from the from just that conference alone
i got leads to two other conferences
that would be interested in getting
films if i wanted to
and um yeah in 2019 the
last year full year before corona i had
over 40 conferences in a single year
that is nothing short of being
impressive
and i mean i know that people ask for
people ask for his services by example
like if cooper is going to do it it'll
be awesome i know i'm i'm one of the
guys who requested to do exactly that
and uh i mean it's
been a pleasure working with you
very much likewise
you've uh
you've been pretty much all over the
world
how do you manage to
get things set up
with perfection
in record time
um
the setting up bit i am still trying to
make easier still
um but i've had it's it's
you do something you figure out that you
have a problem and you you fix it and so
for the next time you're better one good
example with heck in the box is i
initially on my cameras i would have
near the camera i would have a power
outlet
that would power all the bits near the
camera and i would have a power outlet
on the stage to power all the things on
the lectern um
until for one two for one talk at hack
in the box some person decided that
their phone needed charging
and
so thankfully by then i was already
showing people what i got because well
i'm i'm i'm not shy to admit i'm well
proud of what i've done here um
show them like this this is what you're
supposed to see and when it's wrong you
see that
that person happened to just be walking
by the room where this had just happened
and
went and fetched me and it was like oh
yeah this is definitely a problem that
we quickly need to fix
and i've since addressed it by
um no longer relying on power sockets
anywhere other than where the main pc is
so
for for most video you have sdi it's
digital coax i run along with my sdi
cable
literally speaker cable
that
takes 12 volts off of the pc power
supply
at camera site or on the lectern i take
a converter box
schematics are on my
on my website you can 3d print the box
and i put in a cheap 70 cent at
aliexpress or whatever
down converted go from 12 volt or
whatever is left of it after a huge
length of cable
um take that down to 5 volts which is
then again reliable yeah and from there
i feed my camera i feed converter boxes
on the lectern i feed all the converters
that people use and
i only rely on power at the pc i have no
external dependencies on the outer parts
where i also have hardware
so
this is this is something that you reach
after trying a few things and then
discovering that things are not reliable
i can tell you
billions of things about the different
kinds of plugs i've used before i
settled on the ones that i'm now using
simply because they have to be reliable
you don't know if the when you pull a
cable if somebody's going to put a mat
over there and subsequently a drinks car
is going to come out and come by and go
go over over your cable if you've got a
flimsy connector there that means no
power or something and stuff breaks
so
that sort of thing
so uh i've i've seen you
also
tackle design level issues right
one of the things before you started
doing the conference videos
whenever i would see conference talks
being recorded
it's
some sort of an ugly combination of
slides being projected half of them
projected on the speaker's face and that
whole thing being recorded
you can barely make out either the
person's face or you can make out the
slides but not both at the same time and
somehow you bumble through it the
recording exists just for the sake of
recording
what i've seen you do
is you've created this beautiful layout
right you have figured out through i
think design thinking
that speakers are standing up so you
give them the left column for the
speaker they have the logo then you have
the slides and everything is so crisp
clear balanced
audio is good
how do you make that whole thing happen
what's the what's your rig and thought
process magic i i got when i was doing
so for the first
videos that i made i was filming in a
landscape for the camera and you get
landscape from the slides and then i had
the trouble of how do you now combine
that in yet another landscape thing so
you end up with doing things like the
text on the slide is here so i put the
camera the the image from the camera
over there next slide the text is now on
the bottom so you put the image and you
practically get c6 from watching it and
it is a heck of a lot of work for you in
editing after you've recorded something
to get this right
so
the end result was just that the method
whilst it looked good enough
the main reason for doing it differently
was that this method didn't scale
yeah so i focused on saying i want the
slide to be visible throughout because
the one thing that absolutely annoyed me
about watching conference videos is that
you would have the speaker
somebody would decide that they wanted
the speaker full frame yeah um so no
slide visible at all and the speaker is
at that point describing something on
the slide
where you're going like that would be
nice to have seen yeah
so um i switched to our switch i went
for a format where you would just
see the slide throughout the slide is
also the bulk of the visual
um and the
the camera is actually not really that
important it helps to get a bit of feel
about
what the person's about and what they're
doing it just makes for a more pleasant
viewing experience but for actually
giving the meat of the talk the content
you don't necessarily need the camera
it's just pleasant
it's a huge improvement over just uh
slides with voice coming in versus
slides with
a person
that you see speaking it it actually
makes the presentation alive
it doesn't look like just a voiceover
and a
and a narration yes it's it's certainly
lie we had a lot of that with the um
live streams where
people would go um yeah i just i just
i'm i'm so filled up with being on
camera for work and whatnot i'm just
gonna do my recording for my talk with
the camera off
and
if you then look at that you genuinely
go why
yes because it's so much easier to
follow a presentation when you have
someone sending it to you when you see
their face
yeah
you get some more you get some emotion
from that and you can see that the
person presenting this is like really
excited about the thing and yeah and and
it's it's intoxicating to see somebody
give like an inspired talk um yeah
level up yes and
i don't see how you could possibly do
that
without having a camera on this person
even like some suppressed nuances like a
little smile or
an expression like this you you catch
your mind as a viewer catches everything
that's what you go to an event for like
you want in the real thing this this
gives as close to the real thing as
possible yeah yes and if you if you're
not actually looking at percentage you
might as well just be reading a book or
an art school explaining it in paper
you just desync you end up you end up
de-syncing it just becomes background
background noise and then like the slide
plays and you're off doing something
else you hear from from people that that
are after the conference very loudly
going i want the slide deck because i
don't want to see the video for
reasons such as i for me it's just more
efficient to just see the slide that i
can from the slide deck i can pretty
much
think what the entire talk is going to
be i find it impressive but some people
can do that
um
hack in the box is one of the few places
that actually collects the slide deck of
everybody and publishes them
it's not something i see with most
conferences
and you just you're gonna have to rely
on the video and if the video is then
dull or boring
then it just becomes difficult
my first experience
of you know seeing your output was at
hackaloo
i don't know when
many heckles ago is all i'm going to say
but
once i finished my talk
by the time i got coffee and i got back
into the track
you'd publish the talk on youtube yep i
believe it was 13 minutes
i know it was less than 15 so i'm just
going to go with 13 good prime number
but how the heck did you pull that off
within 13 minutes
from me
rocking off the stage
and being up on youtube
i've made a very big point of
streamlining the process
so that
because
nobody wants to work on a conference
once the conference is over
once the conference is over it's time
for after party it's time for beers it's
time to hang out with your friends and
so
nobody wants to spend a lot of time
doing things afterwards and for my first
two conferences where i was filming
things
the um
the time i spent editing things
afterwards was several weeks i was
spending my entire evening every single
day working on trying to make it
look presentable
and like i said that just does not scale
so i've looked at pipelining and i've
looked at
just
really thinking about the workflow
and making sure that whatever
goes into a step is already in the exact
format i need it to be so that i can
immediately move on to the next step the
most notable thing you might notice with
my setup is that um
i am i'm i'm with the hackerspace hack
42 and there are some really nice crafty
people there who uh one of them
made me a 90 degree bracket for the
camera
so that i can still use standard tripods
but due to the bracket i am able to
mount my camera not in
landscape or in portraits
and the reasoning here is that by
putting the camera in portrait mode i'm
still getting a full hd image
but this full hd image is getting shrunk
it gets cleans it gets cleaned up and
then it gets shrunk to uh to like a
fourth
probably even less of its original size
which sharpens it immensely and gives
the equivalent of having like a really
really good sensor even though my camera
isn't that good
but just just that little thing alone
meant that i get better quality camera
because it looks sharp as it can be and
the processing of taking the image from
that to this and smaller
i've completely put that i've made that
like part of the pipeline so that the
video that emerges is already in the
exact size that i need it to be
and that is what i save as like a backup
because also on the rig
i've got backups for everything because
the the the point also with pipelining
is that
the people who help me on the day
they don't know anything about video
hell i don't know and i i don't know
anything about the theory behind video
but i can i can understand if i aim the
camera that way then what i see is what
i get right
so if you wanted to have like a vertical
sliver and you're filming in landscape
that means you have to know that there's
a line here cropping it yeah yes
and if you don't know where that line is
it's impossible to properly film right
so instead i just rotate the camera you
know i have the entire screen and the
only thing i have to tell you is if you
see the speaker you're golden exactly so
keep them new
that's
so yeah and you look at pipelining so
i've got i've made a few scripts that
automate the process of
um
a video file comes out of obs by the way
the best software ever
open broadcast system broadcasters
project system yeah open broadcasting
system or something sting yeah i never
know if it broadcast
or broadcaster
obs obs project on twitter yeah exactly
um
best project ever they
the video that comes out of that
i've made scripts that take this
assembled version of the various inputs
that i have
and
that i can just say i'm at frame there
until frame there
that is the bit that i want to keep
um which is where the other bit of
magical open source software comes along
ffmpeg yes where
with when you have um
an mp4 file or it's actually more the
codec so um
libx 264
the concept is you have a full frame and
then you have a number of frames where
it just changes if you tell ffmpeg i
want from this frame to that frame it
can either re-encode which takes forever
or it can do the smart thing which is
just backtrack until we get the full
frame and from there moment on we just
copy right and because it's just a copy
you're just waiting for io
okay so if you do a one hour talk
i basically have to search back for
maybe 30 seconds in the video for the
point where
from where you actually start to where i
have a full frame
and then just copy everything
put a little intro in front a little
outer at the end so people know the talk
is now over
and
i can start uploading
obviously i also clean up the audio
because that is
that varies from place to place that was
actually what i was going to ask you
about and this is a pet peeve of mine if
the audio is messed up it's it's it's
pretty horrible it's difficult to listen
to video is in a way
correct me if i'm wrong slightly
predictable because the screen is a
screen and screen output is screen
output either it works or it doesn't
work
the speaker
is like either there or invisible so you
know
not too many variations about that but
audio can be all over the place and
recording equipment
ambient noise
levels
all your videos are perfectly clean when
it comes to audio so
well
let's let's uh educate us on how what
those secrets are um i've used
professional you could say
devices for this
i use a shure x2u
which is a usb sound card that takes xlr
in
and xlr is like the sound cable for
those who don't know is like the sound
cable for professional audio
and if you have any decent microphone
you will find that it has an xlr output
somewhere
so my sound card can use that directly
the other benefit is that that
particular soundbar sound card is the
size of a cigar so it's really portable
and really easy to take anywhere
in most places where i film there is at
least something like a mixer table and
you can just directly connect to the
mixer table
some places because
as you mentioned i do do conferences
that are um very small i don't really
care how big it is if you're doing
something interesting that is worthy
worthy is like worth of my time and
other people's time to see this again
then um i think it should be filmed so
that people can see it again
and
so i've done like my hackerspace has
done events where there were like
30 people there
but
you put a camera there and people can
watch it and all of a sudden it's as if
there were more people there
but there was no mixer so i also have in
every single one of my rigs i have a
condenser microphone
which you can just put anywhere in the
room my personal favorite is to uh tape
it to the ceiling uh because then it's
out of the way and it's got like a clear
direction an an an unobstructed
direction a line of sight if you will to
the speaker so sound is easy enough you
can easily travel there and you get
really great audio despite there not
being a really good microphone there
so
that's impressive and then yeah the the
only step after that is to use audacity
to take the audio from the video
make it look nice you use ffmpeg again
to replace the audio track with the one
you just cleaned up
and you're done and the the the the
magic if you will for
this step is that with ffmpeg
the replacing of the audio track is
no more effort than encoding an mp3
it doesn't touch the video at all also
means that there's no loss in quality
right it just like slices it in yes
literally which i i don't understand the
magic about that that is going on there
but i love it the bits
so cooper you have been doing all kinds
of conferences for many many years now
you must have some
great stories to tell by now
well i do have um this is this is a
thing that i am contemplating doing i
haven't yet
really
put like proper thoughts into it i've
put the paper
things that have gone wrong i once saw a
tweet from somebody who was a confidence
organizer and um
the the phrase he was using pardon my
french was a umbrella
that's the that a
conference organizer is a umbrella
whenever they're shipped they
make sure that it doesn't hit the people
below but that causes massive burnout
under the conference organizer because
you're trying to do something nice and
everybody just complains
so
that got me thinking like
how many things are going wrong
during a conference just any conference
and that we are somehow able to hide
from people such that they don't realize
that something wrong something wrong
something went wrong
just because um yeah we are able to
cover for it
um one of the examples i like to cite is
where
i've set up for multiple or multiple
tracks in a venue
this was a school
um it was a three-track event
and
i am in one of the tracks and one of the
volunteers approaches me and says hey um
we have a problem with the track in
floor seven
um
floor seven we don't have a track in
floor seven turns out that the entire
sea wing of the building had lost power
that wasn't going to come back anymore
and somebody just made the executive
decision to just lift my entire rig up
and plunk it in a different room in a
different building in a different size
of the side of the building and they got
almost all the connections right
almost
so i show up there it's like okay run
the cable this one's wrong this one's
wrong right you're good to go
and we had the track in there for the
rest of the day
nobody noticed the thing i don't well
there was an announcement that track got
moved
but nobody knows the complexity of what
you just saw
and i wasn't even there that's that's
the thing that i love the most like i
wasn't even there just some volunteers
looked at it somebody made a few
photographs of certain bits like okay
this looks a bit complex let's make a
picture of it so we know how to connect
it afterwards and then it just literally
just lifted it up alt took it all out
there and plunked it in a different room
and
that was it and i did it perfectly
that is brilliant
what next
what's your next uh i mean you've taken
something which
you know pretty much was
a very uh
what shall we say a subset of a
conference
videos
you brought it to the main stage instead
yes
videos are like flowers the best when
they're fresh you publish them fresh
they get consumed on time they clean
they're beautiful they've got life in it
you've perfected the format perfected
the audio the layout
you perfected your rigs you've created
your own tooling
you've scaled this you can do 40
conferences a year
probably 80 if you could do that
but if i need to convince my employer
but yeah exactly it's just a matter of
you know permissions and not that not
the tools and the process
but what's next
what do you want what do you want to do
before corona
i was
i did a
i basically passed the hat around asking
people to
put donate some money so that i would be
able to
make
more of these rigs at the time i had
seven of them
um
three of them were fit for
taking uh taking in the air so i had a
pelican with two rigs in it required
that the organizer provided a few of the
bulkier bits
i had one in a suitcase whereas where
where i would go to an event that would
just have a single track and i would be
able to film that
but i would bring everything and there
were the four
golden standard rigs that i would just
throw in my car and drive to places with
but that is a lot of transport and a lot
of logistics
that
i honestly could do without so and the
other problem was that brexit was coming
along
and
a fair few of my conferences i'm saying
my conferences that i film
are in england and customs was going to
become an issue if that went through
well it did went through
and
thankfully before then i had already
left
four full rigs in england
there are two
at two different universities with the
hope they have an ethical hacking
they each have an ethical hacking
society
they do a lot of talks for like their
own group
um i would really like it to see you
like to see them film that
they haven't done so probably has a lot
to do with rona
then another two i left with a friend
who does look picking villages
throughout the uk so that means he's
already going somewhere with something
heavy so that typically means that he's
driving so he might as well take my rigs
with it that was at least theory
um
similar process
when i thought of doing something like
that i went okay and now i want to do it
proper big
um so like i said pass the head around
and um in the end
i was able to
get the money to do
i think it is 21 rigs at the moment that
i have under my call it my supervision
there's four in india two in singapore
uh
there's going to be two in ireland due
to conan i haven't been able to bring
them there yet there is two in germany
and i still have i think seven or eight
of mine
um
but what i would really like to see
is that people who are
doing an event anything i've learned
that
libraries do conferences yes
it blew my mind when i heard that but
awesome
there is interest here clearly these
conferences get well visited so
film the things
and if you find it inhibitive or
whatever
have a chat with somebody who knows
where my rigs are
could be me could be someone else
doesn't have to be me um
we find a way via back channels and
whatnot to get the rigs towards your
event
and there are explanations on my website
on how you put the thing together give
it a try at home preferably before the
thing starts
put the wigs in there show people how to
operate them i can do i can do that here
in under 15 minutes i can teach somebody
how to operate everything and it is not
a difficult thing to do
um
and in the end you have your conference
filmed or your event filled
so if i could find people who are
willing to
do the logistics as in i'm going to this
event i'm going to collect the rigs
before i go and make sure that they show
up there on time and possibly other
people or even the same people
willing to take these bits and take them
into a space
and build it up
if we can find those people that would
that would really be amazing
i'm going to make that my personal
target for the next event that i'm
either
part of the organization or have any any
say formally or informally in committee
we're going to make that a priority
i would personally love to see a
three-hour cooper workshop
let's get
pardon the word mini cooper's trained
shakira they actually had a mini cooper
like like everybody called him mini
cooper
let's get folks trained in this art and
craft
and
you're right like this this must go out
to
way more events i think you've got
something also i know you as a fantastic
human being you volunteer your efforts
for free in several several cases so um
it's if this this thing must scale this
thing must grow this thing must expand
yes
um cooper thank you so much
for
sharing your time
and uh
keep us looking good
i will
thank you