we
have
a very special guest with us today
we have with us muza al-ramaithi she is
the director of cyber security at adq
and she's uh
joining us in the studio for a fireside
chat with cherry and myself
welcome to the studio moosa thank you
very much and thank you for sparing your
time this morning thank you to join us
for the talk we had a conversation as we
had a conversation earlier about just
getting to know each other and
what i found is there's so many points
of resonance
i personally am a cybersecurity
researcher and an entrepreneur and a pen
tester and i just got to know
that you're also very passionate about
cyber security passionate about pen
testing
so we just like to have an informal
conversation with you
about your journey
your passion
your thoughts and the type of messages
that you would wish to convey to those
who you mentor currently and those who
would like you you those who you would
like to mentor in the future
uh welcome once again and
would you uh would you introduce
yourself and your current role to the
audience please of course thank you very
much
for uh for this warm welcome
um thank you for uh hosting me here
today my name is mozar methi i'm
director of cyber security i've been in
this role fairly recently actually i've
joined adq in in may
uh prior to that i've worked in the
cyber security realm for over 13 years
a mix actually between it and cyber
security so i started my career actually
in the it field and then moved to
specialize in cyber security especially
after i got my master's degree okay and
from there i did not
did not change the the field that i'm in
um
i enjoy it i have so much passion for
that and i mean it when i say i have so
much passion in such a way that um
i i don't only say that you need we need
to practice uh cybersecurity i also
practice it myself
and try to get my hands on experience on
a lot of areas so i mean the realm of
cyber security is is huge right yes and
it's not about just well compliance is
one part of it but then there are there
are fun aspects of part of it i'm not
saying compliance is not but i'm saying
that there are also other aspects of it
like
penetration testing you know malware
analysis if you're into that uh
you know working with the different
security solutions there's tons of
things that you really can there's a
huge opportunity to learn and grow in
that area yes indeed
what got you excited about cyber
security
in your career right so um
i think the
shift happened when i entered the master
program of cyber security that's when i
discovered that
yes this is what i want to do okay and
uh i'm glad i was in certain an
organization so at that point i was in
emirates identity authority
and at that point uh the the
organization actually supported me and
moved me from
i.t
job and moved me to the cyber security
role right and from there i was like yes
this is where i'm supposed to be and
this is where i've been ever since
so initially when i we started we
started with the iso 27000
implementation so i went into the
compliance training i went into the
audit part of it
uh and uh we
we pretty much uh we're focusing on risk
management that sort of thing
later on in in my career i shifted more
into the technical aspect of it
uh and that's where i found out that i
really enjoy uh
conducting penetration testing and i
would in my own time practice it at home
not a lab but a mini lab that i i have
at home that where i can
you know practice and uh try out
different tools there there's tons of
open source solutions that you can try
and you know play around with and it's
an excellent learning opportunity and
that's how i how that helped build up my
skill set that area
you're true you're a true hacker at
heart actually
and the uh the term hacker somehow took
a very wrong turn in mainstream media
but it's it's not about you know doing
bad things it's about essentially
thinking out of the box right and
making things do stuff that they were
not supposed to do
like
i'll give an example in rural india
there's one region of rural india which
purchases the most number of washing
machines this is farmland
so the the whirlpool decided like hey
why are these guys buying the most
number of washing machines and they're
not selling in cities
turns out that they're using washing
machines to make lusty the buttermilk
drink because it can churn 40 liters of
lassi in one go yeah they give you lussy
throw a washing made that's a hack
and that is the smartest hack of them
all that's very interesting and you know
that's what draws me into the field and
i i i can see that that's what draws you
into
into the field as well because
you're not satisfied with what's given
to you you want to play with it on your
own
see where you can push it to the next
level
in terms of both threats and uh threats
and defense
um
i also
there's also two types of personalities
i've seen in cyber security
and two very sharp types of personality
those who do not wish to own it
like oh this is given to me but i'd
rather it just goes away
and there are folks like you
who own it
so what uh what makes you own this as i
heard you say earlier that you do not
wish to
move out of cybersecurity what keeps you
in
daily uh what keeps me in actually is
so
with cyber security the one aspect that
or one of the many aspects actually that
really attracts me is
you know there's
something new every day and there's a
new challenge we need to tackle every
day
this is what keeps it it's not a routine
job
if if the person that thinks it's a
routine job then they're probably not
practicing it as they should because
there's tons to do there's tons of
opportunity for learning
and i would encourage especially people
that think it's more of a routine job is
to try different aspects of it and they
would come to discover know that it's
not as routine as they think it is and
in fact
if we don't really hone our skills
that's a very good
way of putting it
then we then attackers will always stay
ahead of us and this is what we see
packers always stay ahead of us because
we're just playing cattle
yes
and uh
how do you hone your skills yourself
like what what keeps you updated
personally
right um so other than
what i do personally um
i i i really like to
take you know different security courses
that's important
um
but if that opportunity is not there so
what i do is i
i go for the free learning
resources that are out there there are
tons out there that you can just need to
sit there are many videos on youtube you
can come and you know try uh different
aspects of security
build your own lab i wouldn't call it a
lab really just spin up some virtual
machines install some things on it and
play around with it that that helps
really yes uh and it doesn't need that
much to to set up something
to to work on so that's what i did so um
i have my mini lab right
uh and um i try different uh techniques
so i played around with metalsploit a
lot nice i played around with uh packet
crafting a lot i played around with um
the defensive side so it's not only
about the attack side but i played
around with the defensive side set up
the firewall make it harder for
um attackers to to break in uh so that
gave me that helped me you know build a
perspective of how we should secure our
infrastructure and i take all these
lessons learned by myself i take that
all these lessons learned
and take them forward in the
organization i work for i say okay we
need to do things differently because
you know attackers can come this way
i've tried it i know how attackers can
can bypass security controls
um
this this helped me personally and i
really encourage people to really try
and work uh on their own as much as
possible be self-driven you need to be
subdriven
that's a very important point you
mentioned is you have to be self-driven
because nobody's going to be able to do
it for you
and
in terms of the landscape as you
mentioned right things are changing so
fast we're always trying to play catch
up
i
am an entrepreneur
you are a leader a practitioner of cyber
security in a large organization
um but both of us see two areas of
challenges
there's a technical challenges that we
face on a daily basis
and there's the non-technical or the
human challenges
technologies keep upgrading but but
humans are humans right as a leader
how do you
tackle both these challenges
on on a daily basis
what are your tips for
mastering these challenges of course
so yes the human aspect is there but it
the way i would approach especially the
human aspect
i mean having that security awareness
program is important
but designing it in such a way that
the message actually reaches the
audience is even more important
so um yes it's
we can have you know that one hour
session beeping just telling our you
know our employees that okay you need to
follow the security practice these these
are the password policies you need to do
one two three
but then after one hour people or maybe
even after the first 10 minutes yes this
is concentration right
so
this is where i think it's important to
team up especially with your
communication team how we can you know
design the method
in such a way that people will follow it
it's easy to understand people will
follow and they understand the
importance of it
uh
you can address the human aspect that
way and
it's important also to have that
leadership buy-in and the management
support
if we have that then
it will cascade down if we push it
bottom up it might not work
so that's a key aspect and the
technology aspect of it
the technology aspect of it i see that
it's still driven by people right yes we
need to train those people that are uh
working on those technology that
to make sure that they have the right
skills
to configure um or
to set up our infrastructure in such a
way that
where
the cyber resilience is uh
improved you know we continuously review
our uh firewall rules we can just
improve our you know our signature we
continuously improve what our settings
our hardening controls all those sort of
things but it's important even from that
idiot focus on the people aspect
that's uh that's an excellent point that
you make
are there any uh i'm sure you've had
many
like any specific aha moments that you
wish to call out in your own career
in terms of both discovery of of new
stuff
as well as
tackling a very complex challenge in in
a successful way look um
initially what i would
i would not so when i first
started in this leadership role
[Music]
how i would approach cyber security i
would say we need to do one two three
four
that i saw that was not the right of
course because that got a lot of
resistance because here i am
as a team telling the business how they
should do their business without
actually involving them in the decision
of why we should do security in this
right in this way right
so
i changed my approach in the last few
years
drastically in such a way that
these decisions shouldn't come from
security these are these decisions
should come in line with business we
agree with business yes this is how we
should uh approach things
and i i found out that this approach got
more agreements right
there might be some resistance but
that's fine i mean i expect that to
happen but at the end of the day as long
as i get or we reach to a certain
understanding and a certain buy-in
comes easier to implement the program
going forward
that's uh let's i've heard this theme
that you mentioned
is a very common theme amongst all
successful cyber security leaders is
that if the alignment doesn't happen
none of you succeed neither the business
succeeds not the cyber security
so i'm very glad you you've synthesized
that and
brought that into the into the picture i
wouldn't say i learned the hard way but
while i learned so here's the secret
everybody learns the hard way
it's uh there is no easy way in cyber
security it's uh
personally never happened for me i mean
every gray hair on my head is the hard
way story at some point or the other and
there are many um
in terms of changes
what have you seen change across the
landscape
and what has changed but not really
changed
if you wish to highlight that
for the audience from a landscape i mean
uh might sound cliche but i mean
the
pandemic
caused a lot of changes in the landscape
so
today the perimeter is no longer the
perimeter right initially people come to
work and you know we have that perimeter
firewall that protect us so on
today we don't have that right i mean
where is the perimeter anymore people
working from home and how do we
expand and people not only work from
home but they work from different
geographical locations not necessarily
in uae but maybe outside
so
how do we make sure we we cover that how
do we make sure we secure all these uh
areas so that presented a new challenge
for us we need to rethink security that
okay maybe um you know our perimeter
firewall is not what we should focus on
anymore we should focus on the actual
perimeter today so that's uh one of the
main things that uh
we're focusing on and the second thing
how do we ensure still with people
working in the different geographical
locations we ensure that they still get
that awareness they still get that
knowledge uh
aspect of it so so that is uh key i
think uh yeah tackle those two uh two
only two but one of those those two uh
aspects then
you know uh
we understand we can re-prioritize uh
where we should focus on
that's uh actually you're right the the
pandemic has
blown apart the concept of the perimeter
there is there is no perimeter there are
just people
and there are assets
and people can be anywhere
and assets can be anywhere too it's it's
entirely true
i am actually
pleasantly surprised that
the world continued working through the
pandemic it uh in a way
did not disrupt
it it brought a few bumps into the
picture but
somehow we we as a world overcame it and
we we continued um
going ahead right we're kind of seeing
the tail end of the pandemic i hope i i
pray
um
what would uh
what kind of positive changes has the
pandemic caused in your workforce
that you would wish to continue and you
you'd wish that is also adopted by other
organizations worldwide
that's that's a good point um
honestly when the pandemic
happened so the change and the shift to
work from home happened uh
pretty quickly
and
i wouldn't say we had no say in it but
that we had to support it
and perhaps maybe we were not ready to
to shift that into that
but we had to
at some point look back
and and work on it and i found out that
because still you know the organization
wants to monitor what employees were
doing because at the end of the day
that has been right at this moment
distributed in different locations how
do we protect that data so uh
when we came up with a model on how to
secure this information
you know with people working remotely
that got uh acceptance so
i feel like that
the changes the suggestions we made got
more
listened to because at the end of the
day you know what are we trying to do
trying to prevent a breach right yeah so
uh i feel like this is positive uh and i
feel like
organizations really starting to listen
to security and embedding it in that
business decision that's that's a very
good point you make
you mentioned
about the human aspect a number of times
during the during our discussion
and
working i mean i personally believe
spending
any time in helping
our team members grow their skills is
always time well invested and what would
your uh what would your thoughts
mentorship messages be
to
everyone that you mentor and would
mentor in the future right
i have one
message never stop
keep learning that's
key
and we're happy to support
personally i'm happy to support
passionate people self-driven people
if we find that caliber we're more than
happy to
push them challenge them to to grow in
that in that area key thing is never
stop
that's that's most important the other
key thing is you've you've been a
practitioner by example
you've done it by getting your hands
dirty
you've not waited on
you know
things being delivered to you
and i see
this
a number of youngsters coming into the
cyber security landscape
they're starting out their careers
like when folks like me started out
there were very few resources like we we
didn't even have
a broadband internet it came a little
later in my career
if we wanted to find how to do things
we have to search through some papers
articles and try it ourselves you can't
google it i'm sorry you can't google it
we cannot google it we cannot google it
there's no youtube walkthrough of it uh
there's there's nothing right
but today there's everything aplenty so
a kid walks into the cyber security a
student walks in
everything around how would you help the
students pick and choose their battles
and what would your message be for them
to
like what is it that's going to drive
them to excellence and not just
mediocrity okay i'll start first of all
by saying
know why you picked cybersecurity yes
if you know why you picked it
it's a challenging it's a very
challenging
field and if you do not challenge
yourself every day to learn something
new
maybe this field is not for you
that's one so understand why you want to
go into cyber city not just because it's
required in the market there's a gap yes
of course
we need more people in cyber security
we need the right people so
know why
they want you want to go into cyber
security that's number one secondly
uh
as i mentioned have have uh you know
people to uh
self-learn that's that's key and never
stop and and pick the right
pick the right organizations to to work
for so there might be certain
organizations that really focus on cyber
security and help you and certain
organization where the
attackers focus on uh maybe financial
those sectors those are the kind of uh
sectors that you might be interested in
working for and help
hone your skills
uh i would say
work on everything start work on
penetration tests look uh
try to understand
download wireshark and look at the
packets trying to understand each and
every packet what it does i know it
sounds very tough and very challenging
but why not yeah that's how you learn
right yeah that's the only way you learn
by actually doing it it's a hard work
exactly might sound cumbersome my at
it might be challenging you have tons of
free resources
use them so
uh
that's that's the message i really want
to give and uh look there a lot of
programs i've seen i mean we have these
for example cyber security council
they've signed an agreement you know to
bring an intern so
there is a huge emphasis on focusing on
the sector we want to bring more
professionals into the market
so
if you're the right person if you like
this uh field you know there's tons of
support and i'm sure you know with time
you'll be situated in the right
you know
in the right position and you'll be able
to lead cyber security going forward
pick your battles wisely
know what you're getting into and do it
yourself that's uh that's that's that's
fantastic um
you reminded me i need to go and pick up
wireshark once again and play with
packets
it's been a long time since i do it
makes me feel so comfortable now you
know
you're probably very one of the very few
security leaders who who still plays
around with packets that i've seen it
gladdens me that there are people out
there i'd like to do it more often uh
but you know if we had even one hour
extra in the day i would be
it would be a blessing you know probably
we can make it happen at heck in the box
next time maybe yeah you should just
have you know like
an invite only chatter mouse rules
we put ourselves in and
just
just have an unfiltered time focused
time absolutely break a few things and
then we learn that's how we'll learn as
well and look you know these
opportunities like hack in the box i
mean
going back to the you know
student aspect
really they
i would encourage them to take advantage
of of such events uh
they come maybe every now and then but
take advantage really there's a lot of
professionals that we you know we can
talk uh to we can learn a lot from them
talk to different people really uh
expand your horizon maybe you know even
in cyber maybe you're you're comfortable
with princess maybe you like something
else later on
why not explore what's what you like and
go for it yeah always push your
boundaries
it's just pushing all these
nothing
right uh
muza
thank you so much for your time
are there any closing comments that
you'd like to share with the audience um
about uh about your thoughts or
what hack in the box especially
i would say maybe the the main message
really is
continue learning uh continue
interacting three talking to security
professionals
you know you learn things something
every day i i would say
continue keep on continuing i'm learning
something every day uh i'm happy i'm
blessed that i'm in such an opportunity
that i can
learn and i can't take part in certain
such conferences so i'm glad i'm here
thank you so much for for your time
today uh
appreciate it and i hope i was able to
you know share some of my experience
share
inspire some people hopefully
to pursue cyber security
thank you very much um thanks for
leading by example
thanks for telling our audience what it
takes to be a cyber security leader my
pleasure thank you so much for your time