uh welcome to my talk it's called
malicious contracts
and it's uh towards the development of a
fully auto anonymous
smart contract powered rootkit
i'll give a little
so today we'll be talking about
ethereum what are smart contracts
what is a rootkit
the problems with traditional
the problems in attribution with
traditional rootkit approaches
how using a smart contract for rootkit
c2
is a much better way to do that
and provides full anonymity for an
attacker
i'll be giving a little demo and then
we'll be talking a bit about
countermeasures
so about us
um
i'm chris i used to be the uh former cso
of dark matter uh
then i was the cease of karim
and most recently i'm working on a
fintech startup
which is trying to create the citibank
of d5
long story short we're creating a durham
stablecoin
and a merchant acceptance layer around
that
i've been doing a lot of research over
the years in rootkits and rookie
technology
and
many many years ago 2010
just the last time i spoke at a
conference
at defcon 18 i talked about an android
colonel rookit
i was supposed to be joined by
kipriyanova
today
uh unfortunately his pcr expired before
he could board his flights uh and he
won't be able to join us
but he's the chief hacking officer of
panthera labs and a great friend for
many many years now and he was basically
the guy who helped secure
multiple olympic games over over the
years that they were happening
so how many of you here and i i can't
see who's virtually but how many of you
here know what ethereum is maybe show
hands
yeah
awesome
so
it's considered the world's biggest
distributed computer
and
when you run an ethereum client on your
compute on your
ethereum wallet or client on your on
your computer
basically you can access this whole
massive network and
um it's it's a blockchain uh and
unlike prior blockchains like bitcoin
um what made ethereum special is this
this functionality of smart contracts
eth is the native cryptocurrency of the
platform
and if you can if you if you've been
following the markets it's gained quite
some momentum
and is quite valuable these days
so
a smart contract how many of you guys
know what a smart contract is
yeah awesome
so smart contracts run on the ethereum
blockchain and basically it's a program
that
[Music]
just like you have on your normal
computer and you install programs
that those programs only run on your
computer they don't run on other
people's computers they only run on your
computer
in ethereum
uh by deploying a smart contract every
single
node or computer that's connected to the
blockchain suddenly has access to the
same computer or same same sorry same uh
smart contract same program that you
created
um and what's the what's the use of the
smart contract well kind of like the
name kind of gives it away it's a
contract but it's a it's a contract
that's that's
codified by code
so
if we were to take an example of a real
estate transaction where one party wants
to sell a house once a party wants to
buy the house
and there's usually a real estate broker
involved in that transaction and then
there's the land registry who just
swaps the names on the title deed
that's the traditional way of of doing a
contractual
collection
exchange
of course there's lots of inefficiencies
in that process as we all know and are
all aware of
in a smart contract
we basically put the rules of that deal
in code
uh in that case let's say the smart
contract would own the title dude it
would currently be in the owner of the
buyer of the seller sorry
and as soon as the
buyer
sends money to the smart contract the
smart contract will change name on title
d and send it to the buyer
no third parties involved it's all done
autonomously seamlessly
and and very swiftly
so smart contracts that's just one
example of like a transaction that can
be done on smart contract but there's
many other types of transactions that
can be done on smart contracts so you
can create smart contracts that
basically
send value from one person to another
a lot of the cryptocurrency tokens that
you hear about
are running on smart contracts um
so so there's different types of smart
contracts and they
and they're created for different types
of use cases
how many of you guys are familiar with
the rootkit what that is yeah seems like
a few hands here awesome
so
if i'm an attacker and i hack into a box
and i want to stay hidden
then what i'm going to do is i'm going
to install some software on that box it
doesn't matter how i got in but let's
assume i've already got in
i'm going to install some software on
that box that what that what that
software does is it basically has the
attacker's presence on that machine
and there's various ways that attackers
do that one way is they um
let's say you type
you type a directory listing on your
machine
and you see all the good files and all
the bad files that are there
uh if there was no wiki you would see
all the all the good files and all the
bad files but a rootkit can modify the
system so that
you're when you type a directory listing
on your machine you only see the good
files and it hides all the attackers bad
files
and there's different types of rootkits
there's user land root kits that run in
the user land there's kernel level
rookies that run in the kernel
kernel is better because it can be
bypassed very easily
and can be detected very easily
long story shore
a
is basically a malicious program that
runs on a computer that has an
attacker's presence
now
what's the traditional approach
of an attacker accessing the root kit
the machine you see over here
is the target machine the one with the
the virus installed the look it
installed so usually
um
an attacker what they do
is they install a rocket on the machine
and then
it sends commands
back to this to the attacker's jump box
and
and the attacker is able to
control the target machine that they've
compromised
through that intermittent jump box
they've done the reason why an attacker
does not want the root kick connecting
directly back to them to their home ip
address
is is because of attribution
because if somebody knew
that the attackers that the the the
compromise machine is directly attacked
connecting to the attacker they'd be
able to go to the isp and so on and so
forth and basically put the attacker in
jail or get him in trouble
so what attackers do is they
they use
an intermittent jump box to prevent a
direct attribution back to them
now
there's a drawback for the for an
attacker in this approach and the
the drawback is that
the rootkit that you install on the
machine
it needs to know
what what that what that jump box is it
needs to know the ip address of that
jump box it needs to know where to send
that callback connection to
and
our whole industries in cyber security a
lot of the forensics works that we do
when a company calls us and says hey
we've been compromised what we do
is we go to the company we find out that
the server has been compromised we take
out the hard drive we perform a forensic
image
and we try to identify
malicious software on the drive
once we found the malicious software on
the drive it could be a driver it could
be a kernel module it could be a
modified binary that doesn't match the
distributions md5 or sha sums
we then start to look at that specific
binary and we try to reverse engineer it
and the whole point is we try to find
that thing in the middle the jump box
because that's
what tells us where the attacker came
from and based on where the attacker
came from
we can tell
maybe you know which country they're
coming from
what other people or companies have they
attacked
so on and so forth
so
what attackers try to do to prevent that
kind of like
direct attribution back is they add more
intermittent servers so here there's
like two hops between the target server
but it could be ten it could be twenty
could be a hundred
but
that increases the the cost for an
attacker they basically have to go
hack into more servers buy more
vps with bitcoin or whatever they use
and and buy a lot more throwaway servers
in order for them to put in line
between themselves and the target server
to make attribution more difficult
and
attackers get lazy because it's a high
cost for them to replicate and send up
all this infrastructure they tend to
reuse it so they'll use the same
infrastructure to attack
to attack me to attack company a to
attack company b
and a lot of
attribution these days is looking at
shared infrastructure used across
various attacker groups
there's a case here with microsoft
they're saying uh what tracking attacker
email infrastructure tells us about
persistent criminal operations for
example this is a well-defined thing in
forensics and incident response
whereby you look at the shared
infrastructure that attackers use across
campaigns
you look at the md5 hashes the binaries
and so on and so forth and see where
these things have been shared
and used in other attacks
so
these are the drawbacks this is this is
how attackers currently try to solve the
problem
but what if there was a better solution
and
this is where we start talking about
blockchain and you know you're going to
say this is a really weird thing to do
how does blockchain help us with c2
infrastructure well i'll kind of tell
you how
well
when when we create a transaction on a
blockchain doesn't matter which
blockchain you use when you communicate
with a blockchain or a smart contract
all your communication with that smart
contract and that blockchain is
completely anonymous
nobody logs your ip address nobody logs
your
your username nobody logs uh
your browser identity and every blogs
logs absolutely anything when you
interact with a smart contract
there's nothing there that anybody can
tell that is directly related to you and
nobody knows who created a specific
smart contract who who sent
who what's the real identity between
person a and person b
this is what you see
when you interact with a smart contract
or you send value from one person to
another person over in a third network
or any other network what you see is
from
this address
to this address these are public key
wallets these are
ethereum addresses in this case we're
using another protocol called matic
polygon
but that's literally all you see and
that doesn't tell you much
you can't geo-locate that you don't know
where it's coming from
and you can't really tell um what's
happened there well you can't tell that
value went from person a to person b but
you can't really tell
who's behind it
and
now
there's
there's ways you can actually and what
i'm saying is not entirely correct
so there's ways you can you can't find
who's behind it and that's only if the
attacker is not very smart
but i'll tell you how they can be a bit
smarter
and the way you can tell is by using uh
what are called on-chain tools
like chain analysis so because
everything on the blockchain is recorded
you could basically start from the
origin
and work your way through the previous
transactions
eventually figuring out where this guy
got his original bitcoin from or his
original ethereum from and that's
usually
on exchange
and there's a lot of blockchain forensic
firms
spacing up these days that make a huge
business out of tracing transactions
like this
and one of the key use cases is for
track uh tracking uh elict money flows
uh
for example when there was the case was
silk road many many years ago ago which
was a narcotics marketplace a lot of the
floors the elite flows that and where
these funds eventually ended up to and
who was behind secret
this type of analysis was used
however
there's ways you can
obfuscate your your traces
and so long as you don't buy your
bitcoin from an exchange which allow
which asks you to provide your kyc
documents
and one is using mixers which confuse
the transactions and shuffle them across
many others
it's very akin to money laundering
something like that
another
use case is where you can use
testnet coins
you can still interact with a blockchain
on a different network uh testnet
network and a test net network is
basically the exact same it's think
about it as a
as a uat testing network it's not the
production network because the uat
testing network
so you can use like the uat testing
network with testnet coins
and they're services that give you free
test net coins in order to deploy
contracts with and because you're not
getting them from any exchange you're
not getting them for any public sources
and it's all in single use specifically
for this pursuit of creating this
anonymous infrastructure
you can remain undetected
so
what you see here is a little smart
contract i created
are any of you guys familiar smart
contract programming
yeah cool
there's a few smart contract programming
languages there's something called
solidity which is the normal one there's
something called uh
viper which is what i've used here viper
is pythonic it uses like a python type
like syntax it's not really python but
it kind of looks like python
what this smart contract does is
absolutely looks very innocent like if
anybody's if like a cyber security guy
saw this they'd be like
well what does it do it sets a it has an
admin function
or it takes a takes somebody's address
and just sets sets it as an admin
and then it has a reporter function
and all that reporter function does is
it says log fx
whatever address you give it and
whatever stream you supply
so literally all it does
is if the buyer is an authorized user of
this smart contract if he's an admin
then
if i call the reporter function then all
it's going to do
is it's going to log if you see on the
very top there it says event
sender string it's just going to send an
event on the blockchain and an event on
a blockchain is like a log it's like a
system log
so sending an event on the blockchain
that um
that our rootkit will be tuned to listen
to and then act on and do certain
instructions on
now this is one way we're sending an
event we're sending a a transaction to
our smart contract the smart contract is
sending an event on the blockchain our
rook is going to listen to that but we
have no way of hearing back from the
rootkit and knowing what it's with the
responses
of that transaction are
there's ways you can do it i won't get
into it in this talk it's a bit more
complicated and very involved the long
story short you use the same methodology
but in reverse
your root kit would instead
back
have some value attached to it would
have its own public private key it would
be set as an admin on this contract and
itself would send the contra transaction
back to this event with a response of
whatever transaction sent to it and your
client side
command controller whatever you want to
call it will pick up that and get the
responses back from the rootkit
so
how it works
is the attacker executes the smart
contract
the
smart contract emits this fx event
and
through this effects event uh it
contains very strings
these various strings could be
download a command
run
run a command it could be
uh
now run this executable on the on the
on the
on the compromise machine that's
basically ransomware or it could be shut
down the machine it could be r minus rf
delete everything on the machine it
could be whatever
whatever you want it to
be so
that's
high level the logic and because it's a
smart contract that's giving the
commands the rookit that rookie is
listening for
uh there's no attribution right there's
no ip addresses logged if anybody
if as a cyber security person
if i find this rootkit on
on my box on my server and i look at it
all i see is that it's accepting
commands from a blockchain i'll be like
okay that's great
um kind of cool but
how do i find out who sent those
commands
all i'll be able to see
i'll then go to this to the smart
contract address and i'll see which
address was sending commands to that
smart contract and i'll just see it's a
dummy address with more value or
whatever
and because it's come from webster or
some other test net coins
i can't back pedal and find out who
if it came from an exchange or not
because it didn't
so this creates a completely
anonymous
c2 infrastructure for rootkits
and reduces the complexity in the cost
for an attacker to almost nothing they
don't have to set up shared
infrastructure they don't have to do any
of that stuff anymore
all they have to do
is is connect the existing roof kits to
this c2 infrastructure
so
demo time
um
i hope the demo gods are kind to us
and wi-fi being fidgety and stuff so i'm
going to try and give a live demo
if it doesn't work for whatever reason i
have a backup video that i can show you
as well
so i've already deployed the smart
contract
sorry guys
how can i get my screen up here
it's all good
sorry guys
so as i was saying um
this is something called ethereum remix
it's basically a smart contract
deployment platform
um i've already deployed the smart
contract
it's running over here
and it's the exact same one i showed you
guys
what i'm also going to do
oops
i'll make that smaller because it's made
it massive
is i'll run
the rootkit
okay yep
let me just check something sorry about
that
what i have here
before i get into running the route is
the rookit itself
and what the rookie does
is
long story short it connects the
contract to the events
that affects thing
and it listens for events that come from
that fx
on the blockchain so it's long story
short it's monitoring that contract and
the effects events that are sent to it
and then as soon as
uh
an event is detected on that fx log
then it comes to this
method that's called handle event
it extracts some parameters and checks
if
if we center the hello message if we did
it executes an operating system command
called ls which shows my files
but that operating system file could be
that operating system command can be any
command we choose it could be
delete the whole box
remove all the files it could be shut
down it could be absolutely anything you
wanted to be there
so cool
that's running and listening for events
what we're going to do now is we're
going to
invoke the reporter function with a
message hello that if you remember
my smart contract was listening for
what's popped up over here
is uh my ethereum wallet it's we're
running on a different network called
polygon it's faster and cheaper but bear
with me
um and what we're going to do right now
is we're basically uh sending
we're sending um
we're basically what you see here is
contract interaction we're interacting
with this contract we're calling this
reporter method
with a hello message
and what's happening in this black
screen is it's listening for on that
contract for the hello message to come
through and what we hope to achieve is
as soon as the contract successfully
executes as you'll see on the left black
thing here
a directory listing of my files
cool
hey
it worked
so
uh yeah
now
that's basically ran
everything
you got a directory listing of my files
but this could be i don't know whatever
you want it to be it could be you know
what let's create a file let's create a
file on the system
uh it could be
create an account
roger you're giving me a tough job man
but let's do it
delete everything how about i make it
shut down
i'll shut it down but then i'll have to
do the presentation solo
yeah
okay uh
oh
the screen you know like as soon as this
executes it's gonna shut down my
computer so i won't have a presentation
anymore but then we can just take take
it a bit offline
maybe what i do
before i execute it is i actually talk
to you a bit about counter measures and
then i'll go back
um
so
counter measures like
what i've talked about today is like
some pretty scary stuff it sounds very
scary and all that stuff but
how do you prevent this from the
from the get-go how do you prevent this
from happening right
the usual advice applies you know run a
hardened network everything that
cybersecurity people we know we preach
about always applies
but in addition in this use case
you need to monitor
outbound connections on your network for
blockchain
uh
networks
so if you have a sock or something or
some sort of outbound monitoring make
sure that that's block monitoring for
blockchain transactions
uh now that's becomes a bit of a mouse
game because there's a hyper
proliferation of blockchain networks out
there there's one coming up every single
day
and it's further compounded by
there's various sas based not rpc based
uh ways to interact with with blockchain
networks
like infuror if you guys are familiar
with that it's like basically interact
with blockchain over http and because
http is very is like
ubiquitous in a corporate network it's
very hard for you to block it
but there's ways you know
chain analysis if you're lucky and they
came through
went through an exchange and they're not
very intelligent
but now
let's go back to the cool stuff
and shut down my machine
with a rookie
ah i can't see my screen
okay
i might need your help again
oh okay
that kind of sucks
because now i can't see my screen
but i'll try and do it over here
[Music]
oops
wait
wait wait let's do it properly
yeah cool
let's do it properly
and let's go here again
what i'm doing here is just making it go
faster
paying more for the transaction but
don't worry about that
so yeah that's it
thank you
do we have any questions from the
audience
are there any open source root rootkits
or
exploitation tools or anything that is
currently using blockchain
non to my knowledge to my knowledge and
i did a lot of open source investigation
around this i think this is
the first time documented time this has
been used
um
and because it has the potential of
massive abuse i don't intend to make
this public
so it's it's just showing the
methodology behind something like this
at present
i do expect it to be used though
it's quite a effective way to stay
hidden