welcome to
our talk name the rage against the
machine clear
systematic analysis of machine clears
and their implications for transcendent
execution attacks
this was a joint work with me enrico
barbaris and henry raghav
and our professors herbert bose and
christina giufrida and all of us are
coming from the rusec security group in
amsterdam
today we are going to
[Music]
present in
this slots we start with some background
later we are going to focus on the main
topic of the presentation that is
machine clears and later we are showing
a full end and exploit on
on firefox with uh with a demo and
finally we conclude with some results
before deep diving into
washing clears let's have a small
background section
and all this work is based on site
channel
so what is a channel
in a nutshell
an attacker by observing side effects of
a system can infer some secret
data for example here
with a stethoscope an attacker can hear
the
safe and
discover the secret combination to open
the safe
again this is not an intended the
communication channel is a side effect
but still we can use this
leakage or information to
obtain
information but
all these apply to modern processor so
um
before we saw a time
sound say channel sorry on processor
usually we use timings a channel it is
way more reliable
and the most common way to observe this
kind of leakage information is through
flush and reload attack
so let's have a very simple example to
explain it
we have the data cache that is in
on the bottom
where we have some entries of an array
stored in this cache so the green one
will be cached and the gray one will not
be cached at the beginning some entries
will be cached some other entries will
not
the first step is to bring this cache to
a known state
by for example flashing the entire cache
then
the victim will execute a snippet of
code for example like this one that
depending of a secret value so a bit of
a crypto key will either access r80 or
ra1 for example
and let's say that in our example we are
accessing the first entry of the array
so array one
and this will bring array1 into the
cache
later the attacker by performing the
reload step
will measure the timing for every
access time for each entry of the array
so the first one that was never accessed
will be quite slow
the second one instead since was loaded
by the victim will be much faster and
just by measuring this delta time
between slow and fast
an attacker can observe what the victim
executed does leaking the key
but all these actually
become
very interesting
is with transient execution or
speculative execution
so let's combine these uh cache side
channel with specular execution
let's look at this uh simple snippet of
code a very
common piece of code so bounded array
access so before accessing an array
you're checking it is in the bounded
size
and let's suppose that the array size
for some reason for example is a
coming from a long memory operation is
not available uh immediately
the processor must
well you would prefer to speculatively
execute the
the inner branch of the linear code of
the branch
to optimize the speed execution so the
pressure is betting that the branch will
be taken and the memory access will be
executed
but this is indeed a speculation what
happens if this is
a wrong one
well the processor must revert the
execution
and roll back to the other branch
to execute
but still as you can see in this slide
the
array at position x is still in the
cache so
this trace is still there an attacker
can still
discover this
liquid like this
observe inside channel sorry
and
as you can see combining these two
primitives so speculative execution and
say channel an attacker is not only
capable of observing what the victim is
executing but also
to observe what the processor is
executing in a speculative path so wrong
path it is never committed
and again we can recover what the person
did again using the timings each other
just with these two primitives in the
last years many attacks were discovered
let's start by late 2017 we told you
know the most famous spectra in meldon
that probably all of you know
and after that month after month new
attacks variant popped up
for example in 2018
micro tutorial sampling brought a lot of
variants as you can see
where basically an attacker can
basically can break every barrier in the
single physical core
for example we have the riddle load
value injection and many other attacks
then after 2020
we even
crossed this border by leaking across
multiple cores on the same cpu die
and now
we are presenting two new complete
attack primitives that are named the
floating point wheel injection and the
speculative store bypass that we're
going to present today
all right
so
let's look first at the main class of of
these
of all these trans execution attacks so
here
uh intel defines bad speculation as the
root cause of discarding
issued micro creations on x86 processors
and it defines this bad speculation in
two main subclasses the first one is
branches prediction which we just
saw and it's basically when a branch
predictor mispredicts either the
direction or a target of a branch and
the second class is machine clear where
a machine clear condition when it occurs
it flushes the entire pipeline and
resumes the execution from the last
retail instruction so it's not waiting
to mispredict the branch it's a
deterministic condition that once it
occurs it flushes the entire pipeline
and resumes from less retired
instruction
well branch misprediction have been
widely explored on for example spectre
and along with different types of faults
and different ways of aborting an insult
tsx transaction all these three methods
have been widely explained on all in all
previous trans execution attacks
uh the class of machine clear
remains widely unexplored until now so
everyone that wanted to create a transit
execution path it had either to create a
fault or aborted intel tsx transaction
or mistrain branch predictor and
mispredict but no one explored the other
ways of creating these execution paths
that fall under the class of machine
clear and this is what we did in this
work
so in this work we performed the reverse
engineering the the security analysis of
the four main types of machine clear
which are self-modifying code floating
point
memory ordering and
memory examination machine player
two of these four types of machine clear
led us to obtain a completely new
transit execution attack based attack
primitive the first one is called
speculative code store bypass which is
based on a self-modifying code machine
player and the second one is called
floating point value injection which is
based on top of a floating point machine
clear
furthermore uh the floating point value
injection attack primitive led us to
mount an end-to-end exploit uh leaking
advertising memory addresses inside the
firefox web browser with the leakage
rate that can reach up to 30 kilobytes
per second
so in order to understand uh all these
types of fusion clear and how a machine
clear i can actually work we first try
to understand what is the architectural
environment upon which machine clear is
based
how this invariant can be violated and
therefore triggering a machine clear or
a pipeline flush
how this environment violation
what is the security implication of this
violation
and finally how this violation can be
exploited
so the first type of fashion clear that
we are going to look at is software
defined code machine player and a
self-modifying code is a program storing
instructions as data modifying its own
execution
modifying its own code while it's being
executed
let's take a look at this example the
snippet of code where we have two
instructions the first instruction is
modifying the following instruction
modifying it from changing it from a
load secret to a new operation
modern front end of my cpus
try to in order to maximize the
execution throughput will fetch the code
and execute speculatively well ahead of
retirement well ahead of the
architectural retirement point
and whenever a front end of motor cpu
will detect
a store instruction trying to modify
code that has been already fetched
decoded alex you executed so it's
already residing in the in the pipeline
it will have to flush its pipeline from
the previously uh and speculatively
executed instruction in this case the no
the no operation sorry in this case the
load secret that was already in the
pipeline and fetch the code and execute
the new code that has been uh that is
being stored in this case the no
operation because this is what the
program is doing it needs to modify uh
the code and therefore the the
instruction stream inside the front end
but since this detection of a
self-modifying code is not immediate
this creates a transient window or
some uh
time window where the cpu has already
fetched decoded and executed the state
codes which was already in the pipeline
in this case the load secret and as we
saw earlier through a cover channel
we can leak uh the side effects of this
stale execution of the load secret
and therefore
and therefore it will uh try to flash
its pipeline from the cell code and uh
try to
execute the new code
so the architectural environment here is
that store
store instructions always target
data memory addresses
this
architectural environment is violated in
the case of self-modifying code which
does
exactly the opposite where it targets
code memory addresses instead
this invariant validation allows an
attacker to transiently execute state
code which is in this case the load
secret
and in order to understand what how we
can exploit such uh
such behavior we needna said what is the
attack primitive that this type of
machine layer provides us with
so a speculative code store bypass is an
attack primitive that is built on top of
a transit execution window created by a
software code machine clear which allows
an attacker to execute state code under
its control
uh let's take
let's take a look at the three main
steps of this uh attack parameter but
first keep in mind that codes and data
views are always uh coherent between
between each other and there are two
different views of the same memory the
same addresses
so in the first step of
a csb we
did uh the code of function f to perform
the store step of a self-modifying code
where we need to store code and then
execute it in this case to store codes
under attacker control we did a function
f
and we did it in at the same address
where the code of function g is already
residing in in memory
in this case we do it through data
because this is how self-referent code
works it tries to store code as data
the second step as we see here we are
creating a temporary synchronization
between code view and data view where
the code view will contain will continue
to contain the previously fetched
decoded and executed
code which is function g but the data
view will contain the freshly stored
code which is in this case function f
creating this temporary synchronization
between code and data
eventually the cpu will detect that
there has been a soft modifying code and
will issue a machine clear flushing its
own pipeline from the previous and sale
code which in this case function g
so yeah at this step um
even before like flushing the the
pipeline if we get to the point that we
have actually to call
the function that we just stored
the processor will take the code
residing at that address from the code
view it will not take the one that we
just wrote in
because it has no no notion at this
point at this point of
a software front code so it needs to
fetch whatever was in the code view
executed transiently then trigger
machine clear then as a last step we
re-synchronize code and data to resume
the coherency that was uh that was there
before
before the software encode program
so during our reverse engineering of
this behavior uh we looked at the
developer manuals of intel to see how
they suggest to handle self-motion code
and cross modifying codes on their
processors and we see that there are two
basically two options uh to handle this
and interestingly option one uh that
intel is suggesting to users in order to
handle self-referent code and custom
reference code is describing the exact
steps of our attack primitive
which means that any program or any
software uh relying on adopting option
one to handle software defined code is
uh speculatively performing a
speculative code store bypass attack
without knowing this
because again
option one is relying on the fact that
uh code and data are coherent all the
time
this is true on the architectural side
but but on the microcontextual side this
can be violated this coherence can be
broken
in the case of a self-refined code
in fact the two main web browsers used
by millions of users
are basically
not performing any
any operation whatsoever when they try
to store new code which is the exact use
case of our attack primitive where an
attacker control code can be used so an
attacker
can get whatever javascript code they
want
which will be stored so creating and
performing the store step of a
self-modifying code and later at some
point this jitted code will be executed
and therefore execute instead of code
and as we can see here both chrome and
firefox are not doing anything to avoid
this behavior because they are relying
on option one that intel is suggesting
in the uh in the developer manual
so for exploiting uh smc we have
speculative code survey pass which
allows an attacker to execute state code
which is somehow similar to its
architecture counterpart uses the free
attack primitive where an attack
is accessing a memory that is not
referenced anymore
the second type of machine cloud that
we're looking at today is called memory
ordering machine clear which is based on
a total
order model memory model which is the
one adapted by and implemented by intel
in their cpus
which is a memory model that guarantees
that all cpu cores see all memory
operations
as the program order except one case
a story where source instruction
followed by a load instruction um
operating on different addresses these
two may be reordered so violating the
the program order
let's take a look at this example where
we have processor a performing two load
instructions and then a function call on
the resulting
loaded value and processor b is
performing two store instructions on the
same addresses that processor a is
loading
so let's assume that for some reason the
first load of processor a is slow
because for example it has a cache miss
so it needs to fetch the data from main
memory that will take time processor a
will not wait internally for the data to
come from
memory and will execute out of order the
second load and all subsequent dependent
operations so in this case the second
load on address y and all subsequent
operations will be executed out of order
and will be kept in a ready-to-commit
state internally uh
internally of in processor a waiting for
the data of the first load to be fetched
and then commit everything in program
order to uh
to follow the memory model of the cpu
let's assume that at this point
processor b performs its corresponding
store instructions modifying the value
of x address x and other address y which
uh processor a have already loaded out
of order
at this point processor a1 cannot commit
previously and the speculatively loaded
value of address y and it needs to
flush its line from the
speculatively loaded value
take into account the new value of y
that stored by processor b
re-executes the second load and all
subsequent uh dependent operations so as
we can see here we've loaded a cell
value from memory by violating the
memory uh
order model
so the architectural environment of this
type of machine clear is that out of
order execution always complies with the
total store order memory model
this architectural variant is violated
in the case of a memory ordering machine
clear where two processors can violate
each other's
program order
this violation allows
an attacker to transiently leak state
data in this case the old value of a
memory address
and uh
this type of machine clear is
non-trivial all to to exploit we tried
many times but it's not easy due to the
strict synchronization between the two
cores that need to be so precise
even more on the microtexture level to
violate the memory
order model
now we'll hand over to enrique we'll
tell you more about this third type of
machine cloud representing play
okay thank you
yeah now we're going to talk about
floating point machine clear this one is
the one that led us to find a full
length and exploit on
firefox
and
is completely based on a special
representation of floating point numbers
that are named subnormal
and usually they are very small numbers
for example for the double
floating point representation
every number below 2 to the power of
minus one thousand to teacher will be a
sub normal number
but to keep it simple
let's say in the i3 police standard
floating point they decided to
create a very let's say specialist and
complicated representation of small
numbers
and
there will be a machine clearer on this
again let's use a snippet of code to
explain this more easily
let's suppose we have some floating
point operations so a division followed
by an addition very common
snippet of code
and
basically every time the following is
happening so the processor sorry the
14-point unit
is performing a division
but cc the 14-point unit must be fast
he's always operating
on normal numbers only let's say
standard floating point numbers he's
always betting that this special
presentation never
kicks in basically so it quickly
performs
the floating point division result and
you will forward this value to the
subsequent instruction for example the
addition
but let's suppose that actually this
division generate a very small number
that is in the subnormal range
later the 14 point unit will detect this
and basically it needs to stop the
entire processor because he generated a
completely wrong result
and
it will basically trigger a machine
clear by flashing all the subsequent
instruction
and again to compute the
correct result
the processor actually relies on
software there will be a microcode
assist
and this division will be actually very
slow compared to a normal division
so the processor again we compute this
division in software generate the
current result and give it back to the
cpu with the
intended operation result
so here we see that basically the
floating point you need to be fast is
optimized for normal uh
floating point representation and it's
abnormally stated as a special case that
you need to handle
uh separately
to violate this it's super simple you
just need to make a 14-point operation
to generate a very small
number
and this good implication here is that
the wrongly computed result
the one that is using the red
instruction
is almost completely under attack
control so an attacker by choosing the
operands in a specific way
you can transiently inject some
arbitrary values to the subsequent
instruction
and for exploitation
we are going to show you now the
full exploit that we made to firefox and
we named it floating point value
injection
okay this is a firefox eight version 83
firmware correctly
on the left you have a an origin that is
different from the iframe to the right
so the victim is on the left the
attacker on the right
completely separated
and the goal here is from the attackery
frame let's suppose there's another
advertisement
of our webpage is to link the entire
content of the other page
now let's go back for a moment to this
arbitrary value
injection so we develop a tool that is
available on github
where you just provide the value that
you want to see transiently on the
floating point division in this case and
this two will give you the x and y
operand of the division
that transiently as you can see
will give you the that b for example
here the transient result as you as you
want as you wish
um
[Music]
again please notice that the real result
the architectural result here is minus
infinity
but actually the processor and computes
this wrong result will obtain the
results on the under bottom that you can
see
now if you notice we also have ffb on
the top of the
floating point number
why is the case well
on firefox browser
specifically in the javascript engine
every object variable is represented
with a floating point numbers and this
technique is named non-boxing
and it's quite simple so
in the unused space of
floating point numbers or none numbers
the top bits ffb
this is the encoding for the type of the
variable so in this case this means that
these are string objects
while the bottom that b400 is the
payload basically the pointer to the
string
so let's suppose that we use the x and y
operands that we found before
we perform the division and then we ask
the javascript engine hey
is the type of the division
string
obviously the answer is always no i mean
if you operate on numbers the type of
the variable should be integer
and indeed architecturally the processor
executes the blue branch taking the else
case
however speculatively
we injected this ffb
deadbeat result again a string where we
control the pointer
and the jasket engine at the beginning
we say well of course the division of
these numbers is a string
and we control the pointer of the string
so by accessing for example the length
parameter
we are forcing the javascript engine to
read whatever we want
and then using the flash node attack
that we explained before
we can then recover this data later with
our state channel
so
again here if you think about is pretty
crazy that we managed to type confuse
javascript that a division result is of
type string and on top of this we
control the pointer
bits
so we managed to build a
read primitive you can read any address
in the firefox process
just starting by a division
and yeah usually we're used to that at
least the cpu on mathematical operation
is uh is perfect but here is making a
huge mistake basically
to conclude the primitive of the attack
now we have a red primitive we can read
any address that we want
so we just need to break a clr because
we don't know where the process of
firefox is located and it's quite simple
now you just need to for example locate
one gigabyte of known
text let's say all a's
and then we start
reading in a course grain way i don't
know gigabyte after gigabyte in the
memory
and eventually we'll find that we licked
the intended straight memory
once we have this course course grade
you just need to
go page by page until we find
the start of the spray
and after that we break slr we can
and we know that for example the firefox
memory will be on top of our sprayed
memory
we're going to also to show a full video
of the attack
again this is the same setup of before
the victim page on the left the attacker
frame on the right
exactly we start by
again this
spraying of memory so we have one
gigabyte of
known text and now using fpvi again a
division that type confuse firefox
to read arbitrary memory
we are reading in a course green way
until we find our
spread memory
and after
a while i mean take a few seconds
exactly now is uh
almost finished
we broke slr of uh of firefox and now we
are already leaking the entire firefox
process memory now we are just printing
a useful text but in reality in the
background is
reading a lot of memory of the firefox
process and eventually you see exactly
we are linking the secret
page of the victim
again just by using
a floating point division it is uh quite
pleased in our opinion
and if we let the attack runs for a bit
we also start leaking uh other stuff
after the the page that is for example
javascript probably of
i don't we still don't know this is the
javascript code
because again we completely
broke the barrier so now we can read the
entire firefox process memory
now you may ask
what is the leakage rate well is quite
high for this kind of attack is 13
kilobytes per second
and how can we defend against it well
there are multiple choice the first one
is to disable entirely these special
floating point numbers there are some
registers in the floating point you need
to to do that
but it's not a viable solution because
many programs actually
works based on this representation
so we try to implement a compiler pass
to
basically serialize the processor
pipeline to avoid this
speculative execution
however the overhead is quite
significant is at least 53 percent on
the
of on a floating heavy 14 point uh
suite
exactly
so at the end
firefox implemented a custom defense it
is basically a conditional mask of 14
point results so
whenever you do a floating point
division firefox before actually
getting the results there is like an if
condition checking it actually is not
a non-result so you're sure that uh
even transiently this cannot be abused
or simply as chrome is doing set
isolation every tab is a separate
process and you cannot
cross this this border
now we present the last type of machine
clear that is uh memories ambiguation
and
basically
when a lot instruction is following a
story instruction
which the destination of these addresses
are not ready yet
this is there's a specific predictor in
the cpu name the memory is aggregation
unit
that tries to predict if either this
operation will operate on the same
address or not so aliasing to the same
address or not
again let's use a very simple example to
explain this
a store followed by a load
let's say again the store address is not
available yet maybe it's coming from a
long
operation in the pipeline
so at this point the processor
asked the predictor
look i know i should wait the store to
complete before doing the load but
can you predict for me if they are
operating some others so i can
parallelize and go faster
let's say that the predictor will say
yes they are not the same you can do
them
in parallel
or out of order
well
obviously a predator can can be wrong
and
if actually the address of the store and
the load is the same
well you need to execute before the
store and then loading the newly stored
values in this case hello
so the load lighted in red
will be executed firstly with a steel
data and later will be re-executed with
the current data
so here the invariant is that the
processor really trusts this predictor
and uh
basically
the predictor will never make a mistake
and to violate this again you need a
misprediction so bring the processor or
the predictor in a state that is going
to make a mistake
and secure the implication is that
it will translate stale data
reagan exploitation this was already
known in the past was named spectre v4
we presented also in this paper because
we believe was
kinda
mistaken for a spectre variant where is
only branch misprediction
here actually
if you think about is a data
misprediction so you are
mispredicting the data the processor is
operating on
now
yes on our paper i know four is already
a lot but in our paper there are even
more so if you want to to know about
them there are other uh strange
condition the processor must
stop flush the entire pulpit and
recontinue from the correct path
for example uh exception we have
interrupts
there are other many type of microcode
assist but for that please have a look
at our paper
and now
back to 20.
all right so uh now that we we've seen
uh four types of machine clear let's uh
look at the big pictures of what we
presented so far we've seen uh a
software phone code machine clear where
a store instruction uh causes a machine
clear trigging uh the pipeline flash of
previously executed instructions
we've seen the memory ordering machine
clear where a processor validates the
memory ordering model of another
processor flashing its pipeline again
the floating point machine clear where
we perform any floating point division
with controlled operands uh causing the
the processor to flush his pipeline
again and we execute the instructions
and the last one is the mermaid's
immigration
machine clear where we flush the
pipeline from one uh
one load instruction that had loaded
sale data
so how these types of machine clearance
perform
uh compared to all previously known
trans execution
mechanisms so here on the x-axis you
have the different types the different
mechanisms that can trigger transit
execution so speculative execution paths
in the processor
and on the y-axis we have two criteria
the top plot is representing the number
of transient loads that fit within a
single transient window created by a
corresponding machine corresponding
transit execution mechanism and the
bottom plot representing the leakage
rate how a specific trans execution
mechanism performs in terms of leaking
data
here we have the uh the flushing reload
uh bars representing the architectural
upper limit in terms of leakage rate
uh that we can try to compare our
leakage rate against
and then we have intel tsx bsd and folds
which are the three uh
ways the three mechanisms that all
previous strength extreme attacks were
relying on to create uh transient uh
paths
where intel tsx is obviously available
only on intel and is not supported
anymore on recent cpu so
before this uh our work an attacker
would have been left only with a bhd so
mistraining uh branch predictor or
causing a fault to create a trending
path but after our work we're basically
providing five new ways to create
transit execution attacks which are also
available on md which is quite powerful
in terms of
tools to reverse engineer the internal
behavior of a cpu
when it comes to the number of transit
loads we can see that we measured more
than 160 transient loads that can fit
inside one single window of a self
modifying code machine clear
160 loads that will never be committed
architecturally and can leave a micro
extension trace leaking memory
and that this is with only one single
somewhat code machine clear which is
really powerful
another interesting number is that with
a floating point machine clear
uh we can leak more than four megabits
per second
four megabits with performing flooring
point operations and this again will be
transiently executed will never be
observed on the micro macro and
architectural uh
execution but on the micro architectural
level it will leave
an observable trace and we can reach
more than 4 megabits per second thanks
to the determinism of a flowing point
operation we are not mistraining we are
not wasting execution cycles on trying
to bring the micro actual trace
microarchitecture of a modern cpu to a
known or a specific state is
deterministic we perform flowing point
operation and we have a transit
execution path
so now that we have a clear image of all
different trans execution mechanisms we
try to classify these to have a more a
more systematic understanding of these
uh uh of this of trans execution and we
start from two main uh subclasses of bad
speculation bespeculation is the let's
say the top class representing this
behavior on modern cpus and we have two
main subclasses the first one is control
performance prediction and the second
one is database protection so
counterflow is speculating on the next
instruction to execute data prediction
is
speculating on the data not uh
not code
each subclass has its own
predictive subclass
while controlling protection are failed
attempts to speculate on the next
instructions to execute data
inspirations are failed attempts to
operate on data that has been not
validated yet
then we have the exceptions of flash
subclass of
database protection which represents all
the architectural
exceptions that have been widely
explored in previous attacks
and then we created this new subclass of
data inspiration which is called likely
in variance violations which represents
all the architectural environments that
usually hold but occasionally fail like
for example in the case of a floating
point
machine clear where it assumes to be
working on normal numbers and that's
correct because it works everything
everything works fine in that case but
whenever a subnormal number uh occurs
then this
invariant is violated
another class of data inspection that we
observed creating strategic execution
path is interrupts and more specifically
hardware interrupts you can need this
you can read more about this in our
our paper
so we disclosed floating point value
injection and uh speculative code server
pass to all major cpu browser operating
system hypervisors vendors earlier this
year and uh we uh also observed that
when it comes to
store code bypass specifically difficult
code store bypass all intel cpus are
affected all amd cpus are affected and
regarding arm cpus they are not affected
because the coherency between data and
code is explicitly left to the user so
it's not a vulnerability in that case
regarding floating point value injection
again all intel cpus are affected by
this all mdcpus are affected by this and
also arm cpus we were informed after our
disclosure that some floating point of
implementations on arm processor are uh
are affected by floating point value
injection
mozilla confirmed the vulnerability and
deploy the mitigation based on
conditionally masking malicious numb box
floating point results starting from
firefox 87 and on
and also the zen hypervisor mitigated
speculative code survey pass and release
the security advisory following our
proposed mitigation which is basically
issuing a serializing instruction after
we store the new code in the case of snc
so we make sure that code and data are
coherent and then when we try to call
the new code we're actually also uh
executing it on the microsoft level
and therefore avoiding a software called
machine clear
to include uh bad speculation is not
caused only by classic mispredictions
but also by architectural invariance
violation like the different types of
machine clay that we presented today
these architectural invariants can be
exploited creating a new security new
security threats like flowing point
value injection and speculative code
survey paths and we think that defenses
from now on uh must focus on the wider
meaning and the wider class of the root
causes of bad speculation which are not
only avoiding mistraining the predictor
as we saw here we can deterministically
perform
these type of attacks and therefore the
defenses must
be take this into account too
here you can find different links to our
paper the code and the exploit
and yeah thanks for your attention now
we can take any questions you might have
thanks
[Applause]