hello everyone my name is martin dorinal
i'm a security researcher at the ramses
labs and today i'm going to present a
new set of techniques that can be used
to obtain control of the response queue
in a persistent connection by exploiting
http the synchronization vulnerabilities
so the agenda for today
first i'm going to start introducing the
concept of request smuggling and what is
httpd synchronization and even though i
expect that most of you already know
what atp smart
request marketing is and the
synchronization i'm still going to make
a quick recap and i'm also going to talk
about the synchronization variants in
particular one that was found and
reported to many vendors that will be
used in following demos and examples
then i'm going to start talking about
response modeling and how to the
synchronized responses and the response
queue and how to also
obtain response concatenation to create
new payloads and to cause what i call
response scripting which will allow me
to exploit the
the browser of the victims and also to
cause arbitrary proximate poisoning
which will allow me to also persist the
attacks which in the past was impossible
and finally i will present some demos in
in some labs and also in one of the most
or the most used erp in the world
so what is request smuggling
the idea behind request magazine is to
exploit http synchronization
vulnerabilities and this kind of monavie
was
introduced or discovered in 2005 by
watchfire and reborn in 2019 by james
kettle who presented a set of
methodologies that could be used to
exploit in a much more reliable way this
kind of attack this kind of
vulnerabilities
so
the idea behind again discussing the
synchronization is to abuse the
discrepancies or the differences that
a power surge in the front end and the
back-end server has
and in particular this these differences
are related to the way that the parsers
can find the or can calculate the length
of the http message and the body of the
of the request
so
if i'm able to
cause this difference or cause these
discrepancies then i will be able to
split a single message that will be
forward by the proxy into the back end
and the back-end will consider this as
two different parts and will allow me to
cause
affect the the victim's
request and to place a prefix that will
maybe execute something in the backend
or cause some execution also in the
browser
so a simple example let's consider we
have a proxy and a backend server the
proxy will only
take into take into consideration the
the first content length if i send
multiple content length headers and the
backend will only take into
consideration the last content length
this is something rather common in many
email servers and in many proxies
because they have to choose
in some cases they will not allow this
but in many cases they will choose one
of the content lengths and will use it
to calculate the length
so in this example i send the the
following payload containing two content
lengths the first one
it will be used by the proxy so the
proxy will forward the entire message to
the back end considering that it's only
a
one single message
but when this when this payload reaches
the back end it will be split in two
because the content length the second
container length will be used so it will
consider that only five bytes are in the
in the body
so only the first five a's will be used
as part of the body
and then the rest of the of the body
will be used as an entire new http
request which in this case will be a
prefix because it's not completed
so when uh when a new request reaches
the proxy which in this case could be a
victims request it will be also
forwarded to the back end which will be
concatenated with the previous um
the previous prefix that i injected and
therefore
where will be executed instead of get to
my my account that the victim issued
the the backend will think that the
request is i get to delete my account
and in this case we can see that it will
use the cookies and the session id
and so probably the account of the big
thing will be deleted
but also the
also the
the response of this request will be
sent back to the victim so if the if the
response contains any malicious payload
such as a javascript this will be
executed in the victim's browser
so we will see many of these diagrams
because it's easier to explain many
concepts
and the idea again is the attacker will
send a single a single request
that will be forwarded entirely by the
proxy the proxy will think that there's
only one request
the backend then will be splitting this
request into
it will create a response for the first
part and it will be sent back to the
attacker
but then when when the victim or the
client sends a new request
this will be forwarded again by the
proxy
and the back-end will concatenate it
with the previous injected prefix
it will create a response
and the response will again be sent back
by to the client
so that's the main idea of http request
modeling or the synchronization we will
see later how to exploit this or how to
exploit using request smuggling
but
as i said we can use
two for example two content lengths but
also there are many ways of creating
this synchronization
one of the most interesting
variants that are called
that i found and i was able to report
this new variant to many vendors was to
use
some new connections some new connection
headers that will allow me to exploit
this this kind of vulnerabilities
so the idea is in many in many previous
examples we were using uh an issue or we
are exploiting an issue that exists
because of the implementation of the rfc
or of the parser but there is also
another way of exploiting this and it's
to
use the rfc and to use some concept that
when the when the http rfc was written
they were not considered
and to understand this we first need to
understand what is a end-to-end and a
whole by-hop header so an entrance here
is one is those headers that are
intended to go from the client to the
back end and forwarded by any proxy in
the middle
the other way is the hope i hope header
which is not intended to be forwarded by
all the all the process and instead
when the proxy receives a hope i hope
header it should process it and delete
it and then forward the request without
this header okay so
we can declare this using the connection
header
most of you already know the connection
here and it's used to
establish direct directives such as
close or keep alive to say how the
connection should be should be
established
but
it's a more general purpose a kind of
header because we can use it to
establish to set any other custom custom
value and then this value will be
searched in the headers and delete it
when when the request is forwarded
so as an example if we send a
a request saying we have the connection
keep alive and the option value then we
can set a keep a live header to say how
many how many time or how many requests
should be
should be used in the same persistent
connection but also we can set an option
header which is the value we set in the
connection
and
what will cause this is that the proxy
before forwarding this request
we delete the option header
and we'll delete the keep a live header
as well as of course the connection
so
it's not interesting as us using with a
keep alive or a close but what if we
instead of setting uh a keep a live or a
value that is expected we set some value
that is expected to be an end-to-end
header for example the content length
so if i send this request to a proxy the
proxy will think that the content length
is 13 bytes
it will forward the entire request but
before it does it will remove the
content length header
and the connection header because it
thinks it's a hobbyhole header
so when this reaches the backend the
smuggled data will be will be considered
to be another request because the
content length is not there anymore so
it will consider it to be zero
this vulnerability was reported to
google
and to many other vendors and in this
case google was vulnerable in all their
domains and i was able to prove that we
could hijack any any user account or any
session
a cookie using this kind of attacks
okay so how we can exploit this kind of
vulnerabilities we said we can modify
the request of a victim so that it cause
some different effect for the using the
cookies but there are also other kind of
attacks
like for example bypass a front-end
control
this is we can bypass some authorization
controls in the proxies because we can
hide some we can hit some request fro
from the control because it will not
consider the
the smuggler request to be another
request so it will not
uh it would not verify that for example
if we could if we try to access to our
url that it should be forbidden
this won't be
verified by the proxy
also we can upgrade existing
vulnerabilities such as xss open
redirects another kind of
vulnerabilities that require for user
interaction
and that is because we can hide our our
injection our xss in the in the
smackdown request and this will cause
that the response is the response for
the victim is modified and then the
browser gets exploited using this kind
of attacks
we can also hijack request a victim's
request where if we are able to store
the the request using some kind of
storing and retrieving features such as
an email we could use
um the prefix to be a request to one
place that we can later retrieve the
information
and we can also cause some other kind of
attacks such as uh server-side request
forgery for if there is an internal
rejection supported or other kind of
more interesting attacks but are much
more complex
so this is all
uh request magazine and why do we need
more research about it it's it seems
like we can exploit everything just with
this
but the truth is that there are some
issues with the with the way that james
kettle presented to exploit these
vulnerabilities and there were presented
in the past and this is
bypass front-end controls means that we
only can bypass controls that are in the
proxy not in the back end and that's
rather uncommon in many applications
we can also upgrade the existing
vulnerabilities yes but there are we
need for we need to have extra bubbling
this before so if we look for an
application and we find a http
synchronization but we don't have any
other vulnerability then this won't work
we can also hijack requests yes but only
if the data if we can store data and we
can then retrieve this data and this
feature is not
so much so common in many applications
and also in many in many cases we will
need to be authenticated
and again we need many preconditions and
it's not so reliable the attack so the
attack complexity is quite high
and finally it's not persistent we need
to keep attacking the system to to get
the
to exploit victims and to get their
responses so to get there to get the
requests
so
i started looking for other kind of
attack vectors and then i start thinking
well if i'm able to smuggle a request in
the risk in the request queue then i am
able to smuggle a message in the
response queue
and the answer was yes
but to do so instead of injecting a
prefix i will have to inject a comp an
entire request that is completed by by
itself okay it won't need another
request from a victim or from
the attacker again
so in this case as i said i will use the
same kind of ideas but i won't inject
the prefix i will inject our entire
request which is completed
and in this case
we can see that if i send this to
request or this smart request then this
will cause that the
that the backend recreate two responses
okay so one request was issued by the
attacker and two responses were created
and what's interesting about this
well
if then
a victim issues a new request the proxy
will also forward it but it will think
that there are two only two requests
issued
so
the first response
will be sent back to sorry the first
response will be sent back to the
attacker
the second response will be sent back to
the victim
and if the attacker sends a new request
he will receive the response that was
intended to go to the victim so that way
i'm able to hijack different responses
that are not intended for me but for
other victims these responses in this
case if i if i hijack a response to a
login i will probably hijack the cookies
of the session cookies that will allow
me to obtain control of the victims
accounts
again using this diagram
we see that the attacker and the client
sends both requests
the proxy thinks that there are two
requests only so it will issue them to
it will forward them to the back end
but the back end will split them and
create three different responses
so when these three responses go back to
the proxy the proxy will send the first
one to the attacker
the second one which was injected by the
attacker it will be sent to the client
and then when the attacker sends a new
request he will obtain as i said the
victim's response
but if we try this attack
we will see that it fails and this is
because the connection keeps get close
keeps closing it and
we can understand why if we consider how
pipelining works
so when a proxy receives these two
requests
it will set it will send the first one
through one
connection but instead of sending the
clients or the victim's request if it
was received at the same time through
the same connection
it will establish a new connection
and therefore the the pro the message
will be sent through this connection and
it won't be affected by the attackers by
the attacker's request
so
again the three responses will be
created
but in this case the client is as i said
is not affected so we cannot get the
client's response in order to modify the
client the client's request
what's more when the proxy receives an
extra an extra response
it will it will think that this is a
connection error because he only issued
one request so
for each request the proxy issues it
should receive one response not two
so this will cause that the connection
gets closed
and the attacker's
injection gets lost
so how can we solve this problem so the
real issue here is that the condition is
being closed because if not a following
client's request will also be
be forwarded through the same connection
and it will work
so the idea is
the attacker will send a request
that will be splitted in the back end
but in this case the second rig the
second request will take some time we
will call it a sleeping request now this
time doesn't need to be a long time he
just need to allow the attacker to
receive his response
and the proxy to receive a new a new
request from a client or from a victim
which will be again issued to the or
forward to the back end
and now the response that was injected
can be forwarded back to the back for
the proxy
this will cause that decline received
this
this injected response
and when the attacker sends his new
request he will in this case receive the
victim's
response
if we use
another kind of injection which is what
i said a sleepy request we see that this
attack gets successful we are able to
hijack a lot of responses
and so we have fulfilled to the the we
have
bypassed this issue and we are able to
hijack responses
so this is not quite interesting it was
not known but it's still hard to exploit
so
what i wanted is another way to actually
create new payloads because i still have
the same issues i will i am able to
hijack responses but i have the same
issues as not being able to create a
attacks with with like xss if i don't
have an xss
so now
if i can smuggle one request one entire
request inside my my carrying my
carrying message i can also smuggle two
requests
so in this case i will show how to use
the same the same ideas or the same
attack to hijack a request from a victim
and this is without any storage
feature or without having to retrieve
any data
so the idea is we will use a reflection
and then add a synchronization to obtain
the victim's response
in this example we send one request
sorry we send one request that will be
forwarded by the proxy
the proxy the sorry the backend will
receive this and split them into three
different requests
the first request will create a response
that will go back to the attacker
and now the proxy will be able to
receive another another request from for
example a victim and we'll forward it
back to the to the back end
when the back-end receives this it will
concatenate it with a with the last
request
and now the sleepy request
create a response this will go back to
the big team as we already saw
but now the the extra the extra request
that was injected in the backend
will use the
the request that was issued by the
attacker sorry by the victim
to to reflect it and to reflect the
content
if you see i use a content length a big
content length here and that is to allow
the attacker to send extra data that
will be also considered concatenated and
to avoid that the the back end creates
the response before the new data is
arrived is retrieved
so what this will create is a new
response containing the
the request of the victim
but as i'm able to synchronize this the
attacker will then receive this response
so again not so much interesting i want
to do something more i want to create
new payloads
so this is when
i started looking for concatenation and
to
desynchronize something else so until
now we are able to desynchronize the
the request queue okay by using
different content lengths or by using a
transfer encoding but
is it possible to desynchronize the
response queue
i know that i cannot control the content
length because well the content length
is created by the backend so it's
impossible for me to actually
modify the content so that this gets the
synchronized
but
are there any kind of
request or maybe responses that
use a different way of
of calculating the length
and
this is
this is true for head responses
so on for health requests so if i issue
a head request the proxy will know that
the the response should only should not
contain anybody
but the rfc allows the the both the rig
the back end and the proxy to establish
a content length that will not be used
so for example this is a get request to
google to uh not found to any any place
in google and if we set a get to
let's say aaa we will see that we
receive a response with a content length
of 100 157
but
if we issue the same request with a head
we are head um
sorry ahead request
we will be able to receive the same
response only the headers but the
content length is still used
so
the idea is the proxy knows that he
should a hit request so it won't
consider the content length and this is
there is no problem using this
but what if we are able to
cause that the proxy phase to match
responses and requests so are we able to
cause that the proxy believe that it
issued a a get request when he actually
issued a head request
and the answer is yes we are and we are
because we are using this the
synchronization attack
so
if i send a get a get request containing
two smart requests
the first one using a head and the
second one using a gate
this will cause that the back end split
them into three now the proxy remember
the proxy only sees one request so it
thinks that it issue a a get request to
the back end
so
the backend will respond the first one
and this will be sent back to the
attacker
but when another
another request reaches the the proxy it
will forward it and in this case it's a
get request so again the the proxy
thinks that he had issued a get request
when
the back end will respond to a head
request
so when the proxy receives this request
it will consider the content length to
be valid
and it will wait for 50 bytes extra for
frequently
so when the next response is generated
and is obtained by the proxy it will use
the first 15 bytes
as the body of the of the first
response
and this will be sent back to the victim
for his get request now the extra bytes
will be used as another response which
in this case is a notable response
because it's not using
the http
beginning bytes
so this will be discarded and the
connection will be closed
again let's see this in a
in an example
we have an attacker who sends his get
request containing his two smart
requests the red one remember is a head
this will be issued or sent back to the
backend
the backend will then create three
responses the first one will go back to
the attacker
there's no problem here
now when the client sends his get
request
the proxy will forward this and think
that there is a get request in the
in the request and response queue
so when the response is reached back the
proxy
the first the first one saying that the
content length is different from zero
will use the next part of the of the
response as the body
and therefore this will be forwarded
back to the victim
now as i said the
the extra bytes will cause that the
proxy cost close the connection but we
don't care about this because we already
achieved that the client received this
new kind of payload
now
what can we do with this well we can set
we can build new payloads using heaters
and bodies
so the heaters will be set using the
head request
and the body will be set using the
the next request the sorry the next
response which in this case will also
use the the headers of this response as
part of the body
so we can modify the content type for
example by saying if we have a response
that contains
a reflection or something that we can
use as an attack but it's a plane type
then we can modify this by setting a new
a new header to this response which sets
the
the content type to be text html for
example
and also we can use headers as body so
if we have a reflection in the headers
such as an xss
then which wouldn't be abundant in other
case then in this case we are able to
use it as a as a script
so again
if we are able to set to use a head
request
that
generates a content type text html and a
content length of 100 and then we
generate another response that
using for example in the location uh
a reflection which is a script which is
a javascript this will be used as an
actual javascript instead of headers
and we will be able to exploit the
victim browser using this attack
so
i will show a demo using this
and the idea is we are going to have a
varnish proxy an engine an ng x right
back in
okay
so
yeah so here
um
so i created this
small
example
we have
this page this hello smuggler page we
also have a redirect a
url which is if we send anything
this can fail
it will also send back to the home
so let's see this in board
so again i have my get hello world to
hello smuggler it's just a static
response
nothing interesting here
i got my
get with with which will generate a
array direction but here if i use
for example
some one thing that is pretty common
i can reflect data here
what excesses should be
i can reflect data here so
i could set for example a script
and this will cause
that the
that the application returns a a
redirect with the location uh
reflecting what what i injected with
jesus creep now this is not a
vulnerability by itself because i cannot
do anything with this but remember
we have the get hello smuggler
which
can be converted into a head response to
a head request
and as in many cases the content the
content length will indicate that there
is there should be body but any proxy in
the middle will say okay this is a head
request so i'm not expecting anybody
but then
if we send this request this is the
carrying request this is the head that
will produce what i what i said this
will produce that our response
containing a content length different
from zero to be set
and
then this will be concatenated
so i can send this request
and the next request i i send
will contain instead of what is expected
will contain
the
the payload it will also contain part of
the rig of the response of the of the
victim
and it contains the head with the head
response which indicates that it should
use the first 383 bytes as part of the
body
so
i can
sorry
i can use this
to
keep modifying the the responses here
i'm not throwing the attack
but if i go in burp and use the troop
intruder
which i already said
okay here i will keep sending the attack
i i
set a timeslip so that my own attacks
don't
affect the attacker so the attacker
doesn't want to receive the the
malicious responses
so if i start throwing the attack
next time i go here and i said
hello smuggler
i get the crosstalk scripting
okay
this will work for anybo any url
or should work for anywhere likes i hope
yeah
and we can see that we will keep
receiving this kind of responses these
payloads
until
i stop the attack
so this is not a persistent attack
if i then send the request when the
attack is
stopped
i will receive what i expected
okay
i'm having some issues here
the internet
okay
eh
sounds some issues
okay so as i said this is not a
persistent attack i'm able to modify the
responses but only if i keep sending
these attacks
so is there any way to actually
send one request and
modify the responses for all the victims
in the future
and this is possible by using the cachet
control header so remember
what i'm doing here is to build a new
payload by using headers and body i can
choose any any response or any headers
response and then i can set any body i
want with other responses
so
instead of looking for some some
response that contains a content length
and a content type html i will also look
for a response that contains a cache
control header this will cause that the
proxy believe that the the response
should be stored in the cache for the
request that
the last request that
was issued by the proxy
so again
if i send this kind of attack
where i'm doing exactly the same thing
but in this case
okay the attacker will receive his
response and in this case
the risk the first response or the
heater response will also contain
akashic control
so
when the
when the next request is
forwarded by to the backend
this will again
produce the the payload
but this case in this case will be
stored in the last request
so this is to redirect so the next time
a victim issue a request to a request to
redirect
he will receive the same store payload
okay so
and again the same
diagram
an attacker in this case the attacker
will send two two concatenated requests
or two pipeline requests that the proxy
will recognize as two different ones and
that's that this is because we want to
set the
the
the target url that will be poisoned
uh
for for the one that the attacker choose
not the victims one
so now the back end receives these three
these two requests
it will split them into four the first
three that were smuggled and the the
last one that will be used as the target
this will create four responses
that will be sent back to the proxy
the first response
will be sent again to the attacker
now the second response which contains
the payload will be sent to the to the
next request which is a get request
again to the attack from from the
attacker but in this case
the request will the the proxy will see
that the response contain the cache
control header so it will store this in
the in the cache
and then for the rest of the of the
message it will be discarded because
it's not a valid
http message
or http response now when the client
sends a new request containing the same
url
the proxy instead of forwarding this to
the backend we look in this in its cache
in its cache
and
it will look for the response that it
was stored so
the the client will receive this payload
anytime the
the request is issued
so we are able to poison the webcast of
any proxy and we are able to poison the
webcast of any of any url that we get
regularly choose
and also the as i said the response can
contain any payload we want
so again
i have a demo
i will use the same system
but in this case instead of sending many
requests i will see i will only send one
so
i also set a new
a new endpoint which is this a cachable
endpoint
if we see this in board
we see that we have almost the same the
same response that are in the hellos
model
but
in this case we have the cache control
header okay so the cache control header
will cause that as i said the proxy
thinks that it should store this in the
web cache
okay we see if we send this
we will be storing this
so
now if i send the same the same kind of
attack but instead of using the hello
smuggler i use the cachable the cachable
head request
this will cause that the response gets
stored
let me check this and
if you see i'm actually sending this
request is not a smuggle okay so the
the two smart requests are this
we have 138 bytes which is the content
length
and the last one will be used as a
pipeline request
so i can set any url i want
let's say i said
this url
this will poison
the the index that's called the starting
point url
so now if i go here
i will receive the
the payload anytime i send a request
i can also poison any other url and i
can even poison urls that does not exist
that should give me a 404 so for example
let's say i said
af
acsd
then
when i make a request to
asd
again
i will receive again the payload
okay so finally i want to show that this
is possible in real systems so i
establish a small lab but you might say
okay
you are doing some tricks and this is
not possible to do it in real in real
cases i was able to do it in google but
i'm not able to show it
but i am able to show sap because i do
have a as an old version of sap
so the 188 in sap was kind of different
it was that
when first the sap have two two
important components which is the web
dispatcher the web dispatcher is a load
balancer or a webcaster proxy can be
used also
and the thing is when i send a request
to the web cache to the web dispatcher
containing a transfer encoding and the
transfer encoding is not just chunk is
an invalid transfer encoding the
the web dispatcher will convert this to
a chunk
to a chunk message to a professional
coding chunk but this is not true or it
will not convert it it will not forward
it like this but it will consider that
the transfer encoding is chunked
but the back end which is a
an sap
for s4hana
which is the new
flagship erp solution of sap and it's an
http server this also works for other
sap http
server versions uh in this case the
transfer encoding will not be converted
to chunk but instead it will be
considered to be identity which is the
same as saying hey let's go let's only
use the content length
so
i can build a new a new payload using as
i said
response block which is the headers in
this case i will use the hit to reset
password
which will return me a response
containing the content type text html
a content length which is different from
zero
and a cache control header which says
that the response should be stored for a
week
and then at the body i will use a
similar example that i use in in my in
my own lab which is a gate
containing the the parameter x sub
origin location that will also create a
response containing the
the payload that i can that i can
provide which is a reflective parameter
and will be will be reflected actually
in the
in the headers so this is not a
vulnerability by itself but i will
become i will turn it to abnormality by
combining this with the heaters
so again i send a carrier a carrier
request which is the the attacker's
request that will be sent to him
and i also i will send the transfer
encoding
using the the attack that i just
described
this will cause that the
the proxy forwards the first part
to the to the back end as an entire
request and then the next the next
request which is the pipeline request
will also be forwarded
but that's a different request
when the back-end received this request
it will split them into four
the first one the first response will be
sent to the big to the attacker
the second response will contain the
content length different from 0 and it
will not be recognized as a hit response
because it matched the get
and it will match the gate to the target
url so this is going to modify the
target url in the cache
the body
is generated using these get requests
that produce an xss
and finally the last response is the one
to the target url which in this case
will be discarded
now as i said this this response the
first response is going to be back to
the attacker and the second response is
going to be storing the cache for the
target url
so we will see a
video demo
again
we can see that if we go to sap we have
everything as expected
we can send this head request to
a recent password
which will generate this response
containing a content length a content
type which is html
a content length which is different from
zero which is something that the rfc
allows
and a cache control saying that the
response should be stored for a week in
the cache
then i will also show how the how to
generate the payload
the payload is again stored in the in
the headers of the response which is not
a vulnerability
in this case i'm using
an alert to cache xss
and the content length or the length of
the of the body of this entire response
corresponds to the same length of the
of the content length that was in the
head response
now again i use the attack using the
invalid transfer encoding
i use the content length to be five
bytes so that the first only the first
five bytes are used as part of the first
request
next the head
request will create the the headers
the payload will be created with the red
with the
get to the redirect response
and finally the target url
will be the one that will be poison
okay this is the first request that will
be forwarded the second request that
will be forwarded by the proxy
and now when i send this request the
proxy or the web dispatcher will modify
the cache for this same page
for this url so when i say it again i
get
the payload
this way i can modify the response for
any victim and i don't need to keep
sending the attack i only need to send
one one request that will modify the the
responses for a week
i can do the same with the login page
remember i can't set any kind of payload
i could also set
something different such as a a fake
login so that the victim sent me sends
him sends me his
his credentials
in this case i will inject a javascript
amazing javascript in the in the login
page
okay
and again now if i
if i request the login page
i will receive the
the payload which executes this alert
message
okay
i have time to show this
so to solve this sub releases released
two security nodes and it
marked this as a cbe 2021
or this number
so
i'm also able to
do something else with their with the
rest of the of the response that was
being discarded remember that when i was
using the only the first part of the of
the second request as as the body i had
some extra bytes that will be discarded
but what if instead of using this byte
to to close the connection i use them to
create a new a new response
so again
let's say that i send this request to
the to the backend server which will
it's it will be for white as one but
will be split into
into three different requests by the
by the backend
the first response will be sent back to
the attacker
the second response will be used as
headers
and now this response let's say i'm able
to inject this in the or to reflect this
in the response this response will be
used as part of the body so the first
100 bytes will be used as part of the
body of this hit request
this will be forwarded back to the
to the attacker
but now the extra the extra bytes which
were reflecting the the parameter that
the attacker sent
will create a new response in the past
we would have a response that wasn't
invalid so this would create a closed
connection but in this case
this response is a valid is a valid
response or valid http message so it
will be also delivered back to the to
the victim or to the attacker and this
will allow me to actually create any any
kind of response not not using blocks
like before but to actually write
anything i want so this in this case i
will use a response that contains a
cache control a content length and an
arbitrary body response
and this will be sent
to the example and will be stored in the
cache for the example url
okay so some final conclusions
the idea of response snaggling is that
we don't need to rely on any extra
vulnerability and this is true for all
systems that we
i had looped
because i'm not looking for
vulnerabilities i'm looking for things
that are not considered to be invalid
are and i rely on the rfc i use for
example the content length to be to be
something different
and that is valid by the rfc
also
in this case i will analyze the
how how the scoring should be for this
kind of vulnerabilities and
if i'm able this response mapping will
be able to i will be able to perform
response modeling anytime i have an http
synchronization vulnerability okay so i
don't need as i said any extra
preconditions and using respawn and rico
smuggling i am able to hijack
two hijacked messages so the
confidentiality is completely
compromised
i'm also able to poison the red cache or
to inject nested
responses that are invalid so i'm able
to compromise the ability the
availability by setting for example
responses that says 404
i'm also able to compromise the
integrity because i'm able to modify
persistently modify the the responses
that a server or a proxy will
will give to clients
and as i said
using the cache technique i'm able to
persist this attack and to compromise
any any client that will use this
application
and finally of course the
to hijack different requests and
responses
using the sleepy sleeping request
technique i'm able to increase the
the reliability not only for response
marketing but also for request smuggling
so
in the future this this kind of
vulnerabilities should be considered as
critical and not
as medium as many back bounty programs
would say they are or as many other
vendors would consider to be
okay questions
um first of all thank you for that it
was really really interesting
can you hear me
it was really really interesting and uh
thank you for that
i just want to ask uh a couple of
questions so
uh when you send the ad request it it
has to be
when you send the ad request yeah it has
to be the response has to be 200 okay or
it can be no different it can be
anything
the only important thing is that the
connection is not being closed so for
example if the response is a 404 in some
cases that will close the connection but
in most cases no that's not true only
for for example in sap it would close
the connection
for example uh like a phone and one or
you can you can set anything you want
and this will work and it will even be
exploitable because the browsers will
will just check that it's a 401 but it
will still display the
all the payload and so the browser will
execute the javascript
cool um yeah and
did you try this attack with uh web
application firewall on the on the on
the web
method does it make a change it doesn't
matter because it actually helps me
there are some
i tested with one firewall actually and
it helps because firewalls are still hp
proxies and they follow the same rules
and they don't verify this because they
are they cannot look for energies that
are not gonna raise this because even
yeah but sometimes they see the string
like like you did script a little script
within the body or and and they block it
even with to see the start of script or
scrap it's a standard escape of them yes
but in many cases
so the examples i showed was using
the attack in the healers but you can
also use this in the plane in plain text
so many many responses that said plain
text as the content type
you can you can use this to
to create new payloads that will change
the the content type and the firewalls
won't verify this because they think
that this is safe i mean there are many
ways of bypassing firewalls because
there are safe ways or they would think
this is safe when this is not safe
actually
i can also bypass the firewalls
by smuggling
twice the the request oh nice so that
the firewall will not recognize this
because it will it will not see a
request actually yeah yeah so and the
last last question is
did you find it on different uh besides
like google as you said and the sap and
varnish did you find it on
other
yes you can say yeah
some of them are still
working on it because they first
so the problem here and why i said this
conclusion is because many of the
vendors would say okay http the
synchronization is not a big deal for us
so i had to prove them that
with just one request because even when
i said okay
here one request will modify your your
your entire application and they will
say no it's impossible so
you have to prove it and sometimes in in
web applications that are
public it's hard to prove it without
modifying and having some issues yeah
okay thank you very much thank you thank
you
and there was another question
hello
okay thank you for presentation um i
have only one question uh what was in a
skip it slide and why you skip it
you hear me
[Applause]
okay thank you for presentation again so
i have only one question about uh what
was in skipped slide and why you skip it
no i thought that
i wouldn't get with the time so the skip
the skipper try was the the arbitrary
diabetes injection which allows me to
create new kind of responses actually to
write the response in the entire
by by using the last part that is
so remember when i use a head
a response it will take the first x
bytes
that is set in the content length okay
of the next response but then
the extra bytes that are not used as the
body
are in many cases discarded but if i'm
able to reflect something there so for
example a a response which would say
http
1.1 anything else 200 let's say i'm able
to write a new response and use this to
actually
create responses
by scratch not using
not using blocks but
by writing it by myself so this would
allow me to create even better payloads
and even when
i have i was able to prove this in one
vendor
and this was pros this allowed me to
create a payload that
that contained a javascript and in any
other way it was impossible because they
had like almost nothing almost nothing
reflected almost no way of you of
creating a new payload but this way i
was able to create a payload from
scratch and inject it in the in the
cashier
okay thank
you i think we're running out of time
there so thank you very much martin for
your talk thank you