all right
so good morning everyone and
welcome to
uh my talk on software analysis
from security perspective and
what we are doing and what we would like
to do
in the near
future so about me
so i joined uh technology uh innovation
institute very recently
uh and before that and there i lead a
group
uh called software
security analysis
and this is a very generic group which
focuses on typical
software
programming a program analysis
techniques and we kept it
kind of like little bit generic on
purpose because we would like to
you know poke our nose everywhere
all the project that we want to do
because as i will try to convey that
software program analysis remains a
basis for most of the typical soft
software security tasks that you see
and before joining uh tii i was a
professor at the university of bristol
uk
and there i was also part of a cyber
security group and also
conducted several few workshops at
various levels there
and before joining uh bristol i was part
of
susek freya university amsterdam and in
fact currently as we i'm speaking my
ex-colleagues are speaking on your left
there about some work okay so i was also
there at the the same group here which
they are presenting
and i also spent uh some time
at very mac france uh which is a very
good lab for program verification where
basically i started doing a lot of uh
program analysis from binary core
perspective
and so on
so about the talk
so as uh as i joined uh tii very
recently and overseas center is a very
new research center so we don't have
actually a finished product to talk
about
but we all we have blueprints
so
most of the time in this talk i would i
would be just talking about what we
can't do here
and
basically i will be talking about some
of the dimensions
that allow us to to really
build a secure software okay and i call
them as automated star properties and
then star means several things like
vulnerability uh detection
some mitigations
and
and i will discuss some of those
divisions and during this talk i would
i would like to uh i would like to
emphasize or will write to convince you
that there has to be a balance in all of
these dimensions in order to really have
a secure software focusing on just one
may not
yield a very fruitful result and i would
also like to convince
or would like to let's say
give some ideas about how we should go
about it and
as a security community
this is my experience also that we have
to look at the neighboring research
community also in order to take ideas
and i have seen because i have worked in
different communities focusing on the
very very fundamental work theoretical
work verification system communities and
and i felt that sometimes they live in
in isolation means the island the system
community works its own way uh
verification community works in own way
but they are trying to achieve things
which may help each other and sometimes
that the dialogue is missing and that
that that ends up and this result that i
that we see that we tend to sometimes
repeat research or sometimes we are not
able to do things properly if you talk
to each other things become pretty good
this has been so i would like to also
emphasize on this part
okay
so last year
i happened to
watch a keynote
talk by alex
and i think if you are working in
security then you must be knowing this
uh alex because he's also by the way
author of
fifth and fifth to seventh edition of
windows internal he's a kind of like you
know a kind of pillars of you know that
generation of hackers who did a lot of
fundamental work
and
and he presented a keynote at woot usnix
which is offensive
technology based
conference
and that was a very strong
and very different keynote for me also
and thanks to you know lockdown that
that the talk was uh you know online so
i could also attend otherwise it would
have been difficult for me to to attend
that talk
and then what
and what he mentioned there is
basically that
we are spending
too much
money
and efforts
on
bug detection
and he and he made this point that okay
when he saw some of the
thing coming up in bug detection for
example you know uh fuzzing also and
then people also working in bug bounties
earning a lot of money he said that i
have been seeing that for the last
several years
at that time also you were finding lot
of bugs and today also we are finding
lot of bugs
but thing is that bug finding getting
better but
it's not that we do are not seeing bug
you are still keep seeing
vulnerabilities
and this point was that okay because you
have lot of incentives and you have to
do something about it and then he went
on seeing lot of things and basically he
is trying to say that okay we have to
change everything we have to start
building software
secure since you know when we start from
the beginning itself that's the
solution otherwise we are never going to
end this this
this dirty state of software development
okay this resonates very well with what
i was trying to uh you know do in my
research career
so i took
some of the take away from this so he
said that yes finding box automatic for
me finding bus automatically is really
important and it's played a very
significant role so far because that's
why we see now many many uh you know
serious
is coming up quickly and people are
trying to do something about it okay but
then the problem is as he said also that
if you are just focusing on one side
this is a imbalance means you just can't
handle because you are getting too many
bugs but you have no way of really
fixing them quickly
and that becomes imbalance
so
so then the point is here we have lot of
incentives for finding bugs but we do
not have equivalent for fixing bug for
example
okay
shift left is techno i mean nowadays
this is what people have proposed that
okay bring
everything
uh related to security testing in your
development itself yeah it works but the
problem is that because you still it is
still in the hand or the team who is
developing that it's fine okay the
problem is post release bug fixing is
still a man versus machine effort you
are you have a lot of lot of automated
tool for finding but you can't do
anything to fix them
so we need more automation beyond the
full pipeline of sdl okay so that's the
one takeaway for me
from the task
so then
what i i categorize as vulnerability
research with everything that revolves
around vulnerability finding
vulnerability fixing vulnerability doing
somehow mitigating the effect of
vulnerability in all those things
and
so we need have some sort of balance
there in all those aspects here okay so
so at ti
we are trying to do something in this
direction
okay and so so for example a program
comprehension from a security property
stand point of view this is exactly i
was mentioning about our group because
we really want to develop skills that
allows us to to have a fantastic
understanding of program whatever it is
it may be source code it may be binary
code small large we would like to have
fundamental techniques inbuilt so that
we can really understand what first of
all what program is and i will show you
tell you that okay this is fundamental
for whatever task you want to achieve
later on
then in that we have vulnerability
discovery and these are the kind of a
blue area where you will see that okay
we are focusing on a lot uh at cii
and then attack mitigation this is i
will go through one of the each of them
in my subsequent slide
and then you have
attack patching automatic patching
because as i said in the beginning if
you are discovering too many bugs
but you are not trying to do anything
about them you are not going anywhere
the program the software will remain
insecure for decades to come unless
until we do something fundamental about
it
then automatic spoil generation this
seems kind of odd here because we are
talking about building
software secure software but certainly
why the exploit generation i will touch
something about it
so vulnerability discovery part here
so far we are mainly focusing on memory
corruption bugs that are coming from
memory and safe languages because we
know there are there will be memory and
safe languages
i hope that after some time when we when
we have more memory safe languages like
rest go this thing will be
uh better
but it will take time a lot of time
because
i don't see that in the coming
five years or more than five between
five ten years we will replace
memory and safe languages with memory
safe languages it's gonna take time
and then we have actually in this
how we do vulnerability discovery
automatically then we have static and
dynamic program analysis techniques that
we use
fuzzing is one of such dynamic analysis
technique but the problem here because
it's a dynamic analysis it's precise
it's fine but it's not complete
okay and that is why you keep seeing
many
uh bugs being discovered now also
because peop even though you rely on
fuzzing which is effective but
after all it's a dynamic analysis
technique you are not sure how much
coverage
how much complete it is okay
then you we can use static analysis okay
but it's not precise and scalability is
problematic
so these are the fundamental problems in
both of these techniques and if you use
either of them you know fundamentally
that okay there is a gap
you just can't be sure about it
so and then comes the part analyzing
binding poses another
problem whatever it is
okay and there we see a lot of
opportunity because
we cannot avoid binary code analysis at
all we have to we have to analyze binary
code what even though we are
working
as a coder writing our own code and i
will i will tell you a little bit more
about it once we start this
go in detail
and we have definitely lot of lot of
opportunities if we if
if you look at this
area of program analysis okay
and then attack mitigation
part as i talked about
so
we know that software will have bugs
that's it a period we can we can't do
anything about it and if there are bugs
there will be exploit that that will you
know exploit those vulnerabilities
so there has to be some mechanism
that allow us
to
mitigate those
uh attacks exploits
you can't avoid them
okay then so last decade
i would say sorry in my uh experience
was dominated by control flow integrity
solutions a lot people worked on control
for integrity solution a lot
and
the effect was very good and you can see
that now
even the hardware or intel they have
come up with their hardware
feature that allows you to
uh
embed control for integrity in your
software with the help of
hardware
earlier the problem was it's expensive
if you want to have control to integrity
directly in your software your software
runs slower because of the performance
overhead incurred by uh cfi control for
integrity but now you see that the
impact is super high it is like your
hardware our vendors are thinking about
oh no we should be we should do
something about it
okay and then source base control flow
graph uh integ control uh flow integrity
is definitely better than binary uh
control for integrating for obvious
reason because soft software has more i
mean your source code has more
information for you to analyze than the
binary code but again if you just focus
on software then it's not gonna help you
much because
at runtime your software depends on many
libraries runtime libraries whose source
code is not available to you so they are
not enabled with cfi okay then again you
are not going to win the price there
so that is again a lot of uh opportunity
uh to explore there in that particular
part
and then of course binary rewriting is
fundamental for all these things because
remember you are trying to
change something in your in your
application if it is binary that means
you have to have way of changing your
binary effectively so that's a one
requirement if you want to go in this
in this direction and we will see that
what's happening in this
so automatic exploit generation as i
said that did this looks like a kind of
odd uh
member of this but all these dimensions
but it is not actually in my opinion
normally exploit generation is a really
complex task because if you want to do
automated exploit generation you have to
consider several things including the
environment of a particular victim
machine
there you may have lot of mitigation
bringing brought up by your operating
system
okay you really do not know about that
but you want to do everything
automatically it's a super super complex
task whatever we see currently is not
like i mean it's really very trivial so
it is very very complex first of all so
if you really want to have a automatic
generation which is full which is
arbitrary for i mean it can take any any
target and give you a new uh automatic
exploit it's really not gonna happen in
my opinion now okay
so
but then
that's good actually
because
if we are
trying to generate automatic
exploits and we know that for many
complex scenarios it will not be able to
do so
but however
if it could
then we know that definitely smart
people out there
will definitely write an exploit for
that that's for sure because there are
people who are super smart than the
current state of automatics by
generation so if your algorithm could do
this
definitely is going to be exploited in
the wild so for you it's a good
measurement of how to fix this bug
quickly so you have a prioritization
based on that so for me it's more of a
prioritization you still get lot of bug
but you really do not know which book to
fix
is fix first
this gives you some sort of ranking and
then you can prioritize your efforts
accordingly so for me it's still a kind
of a good member even though it looks
like it's a function part why we are
talking about but it's important for me
and then automatic exploit generation
i say that it's a it it's kind of like a
rigorous testing software rigorous
software testing so if you bring in this
kind of
uh
feature or dimension in your in your
overall secure development it becomes i
think more rigorous than just relying on
you know some uh
static or dynamic analysis
and then auto patching i said that
this is relatively a new area now
okay and then initially like
in 90s people came up with the idea of
autonomic computing there they were
talking about lot of self properties of
the software of course that was ahead of
time proposal
but now i think things are pretty good
and we can really go forward in the
direction
uh of uh autonomic computing
so basically what it says that okay
you you once a bug is found or maybe
perhaps exploited also patch can take
time still right you you will you will
file the bug and then depending on the
availability people will try to patch it
and
also if the bug is in is in is in some
third party library it is really out of
your hand you can't do anything about it
you have to just wait for that okay
so so that's why now i feel that
lot of emphasis is being given to this
aspect and especially if you see there
is a dharpa
grand challenge also now for the same
purpose and darpa keeps encouraging
people while
with coming up with uh
coming up with new grand challenges
so this is one of those run challenges
there
so now
program comprehension i come back to now
so whatever we saw earlier all these
dimensions if you look at
them
closely
then you will find that all of them
involves
a better analysis of the system
if you do not have better analysis
techniques for your system
you cannot automate that that part and
that's the main thing because you as an
individual may look at a particular
software
you can analyze it
with your own understanding you can do
something about it but you cannot
automate it
in order to do automatic automated way
of analysis you have to go back to
program analysis part of program
comprehension so that's why i said it's
a it's a it's a fundamental for all
these dimensions that we talked about
and then from the security perspective
we also have a kind of whole system
whole program analysis
and to make thing worse you have to
sometimes deal with multi language
analysis because nowadays your your
programs are so so complex they are not
written in one language only you can you
know mix languages you can use c you can
use c plus plus you can use rust with
calling c function even other other
combinations are possible in such
scenarios
you are talking about program analysis
in a proper way it's really really hard
now so we really require a lot of lot of
you know effort new efforts in this
direction
then this is the part i already touched
upon that what even though you are the
owner of a particular project you have
full access to source code you may still
be using third party libraries whose
source code is not i mean they are
commercial so you only use them in
binary form but your software depends on
those libraries how you are sure that
your everything is all right because
there may be problem in those libraries
so you have to have a way of you know
mixing these two
sources and mine binary base analysis
so this is again a
good part that
nowadays actually
you also have a
hardware support that i talked about
little bit and also some of the machine
learning and artificial intelligence
maybe i think it's a it's a good time to
to try that reason is not that they are
really magic it's not about this for me
it's about like complex the softwares
are very large
very complex
perhaps you may miss many things
as a systematic analysis
so
bring in little bit of
ai or ml to help you in order to get rid
of all those complexities and let let
let the ml analyze little bit for you
and then you move forward okay
so now we go little bit of ah in detail
about like what i see
what is happening and how we can do
little bit more there so basically for
me the program analysis means it is like
is still assisting humans i think it's
not about totally replacing human it's
like it gives some more idea about the
properties of the program in more
automated way to human and then let
human decide certain aspects very very
difficult to take out human fully i
think at this stage
okay so question to ponder upon for me
is like that what security aspects are
important to address for example so what
kind of
security property we are interested in
for example insecure
information flow this is how your
information leak happens if you really
you are looking for those kind of
vulnerabilities you have to think about
okay what can i do about it okay some of
the things are for example here in the
second point like initialize read null
pointer dereferencing use after free
these are typical memory corruption
books
typical but little bit you know harder
than the more known form of like stack
overflow this kind of thing they are
little bit more complex
when
but the point here is
some of them
can be detected
by using just a classical classical
program analysis or compiler back-end
analysis
if you are aware of some of them for
example even the reaching definition
can
very easily
uh detect
oh it's been back here yes
uninitialized read
just you adopt classical
compiler backhand technique and you can
do
uh some of the you can analyze some of
these vulnerabilities very well the all
we need is some sort of you know
creative thinking
all right
so this is what i was talking about that
compiler and so compiler backend they
are working on very interesting
techniques if you are really doing a
software analysis but still just not
software analysis the same techniques
can be adopted to binary code also as
well
and then you have verification
communities they are working on
verification techniques but some of
those techniques you can adopt we can
adopt for our program and security
program analysis and the venue to look
for is like pldi purpose these are the
top venues where you have fantastic work
coming up okay
i will give some examples of that
the scalability that's uh i think
main hurdle
the security analysis often require
whole program analysis that's a one
thing so if you really want to do
something meaningful you have to have
really a hopeful
uh program analysis
and that is not that easy yet
especially given the fact that we saw
that okay environment is very very you
know
uh hit a heterogeneous
so there are some very interesting
things happening for example in abstract
interpretation it's a very very and it's
a it's a a static analysis but does a
lot of runtime
ah kind of infer
infer of runtime inference of prop uh
dynamic properties of your a program
okay so it's a very powerful technique
people are i will give you some
reference at the in the next slide
okay
and this is something i put it green
because this is very to me it's very
very important area which is like teen
flow analysis it's it's like
it's it's it's very useful for
several security related tasks
unfortunately
we are still uh we do not have
very very you know interesting or good
solution for it i mean there are dynamic
inflow analysis techniques but they do
have lot of lot of overhead
now there is a possibility of maybe ah
combining some of the recent development
in in hardware also to come up with a
very uh
good info analysis technique you can
combine static analysis
kind of thing and then
symbolic and concolic execution okay
this is also a very good uh
candidate that we should be exploring
more i guess and it has got
it has got application in almost every
dimension that we talked about
vulnerability detection
mitigation part okay and automatic
exploit generation it's it's kind of
like a fundamental there i would say
fundamental means it's so so important
that
if you if you do it properly i think you
are good
so there are some recent advancements in
in this area for example sims easy if
you are in this you might have seen that
it changed
the whole whole dialogue there okay
because by nature symbolic execution is
symbolically you are trying to
understand interpreting and simply
change that narrative at all it says
that okay fine we can even do something
with the compile time and then it gets
you all the information that you want
and then chop symbolic execution q sim
okay there are many thing
and
so for example so this is the so this is
the work that i did uh before joining
tii so i will not talk about
in this work here but
this is also one attempt towards making
symbolic or concolic education a little
bit more usable okay
and basically what it does is like again
i am using 10 flow analysis to do some
optimization
to make it better and this is my
main point here that we do have
techniques now all we have to do use
them creatively and then they can work
in a better way for the given task
so this is
source and binary i touched upon it
so you have to choose whether you want
to do source code analysis source based
analysis or binary base analysis fine
but
the point here is
if you do
binary based and program analysis it is
still fun i mean we say that okay we
have to get our hand dirty normally when
you are talking about low level bind
playing with assembly code this is
people typically say that well we have
to get our hand dirty but is this still
fun like okay it's nice like you like it
the problem comes that when we talk
about
real large complex applications then
it's not always
a fun i mean it's really really hard it
is like okay
i don't see that okay that is really
really fun i am enjoying it no no after
some time you really get frustrated
because it's really really tough
especially when you talk about binary
code analysis and in order to make
things even worse multi-language and now
you have c
c plus plus
if you look at c plus plus code at
binary level a it is like it's totally
mess
and it becomes really difficult to to
analyze it so that's what i'm talking
about here it's really really super
challenging but
lot of opportunities that's why
right so and binary code unless
basically a security community thing i
would say because it's it's it's
normally security community who is
trying to work on it and this is my
point i was trying to make because it's
security community they are trying to
work on a binary code analysis but on
the same time
it is only security committee but they
are not trying to talk to other
communities like verification people or
some other people because they have nice
techniques may be classical and you can
adopt them but that communication is not
happening much
and if we have that communication i
think this this is fantastic
all right so i will move forward exploit
mitigation
so understanding holders in developing
this is my objective like why i want to
uh currently what what is what i want to
study here first of all to understand
that what are the hurdles in developing
attack mitigation techniques
so question to ponder upon is are we
discovering new attack surfaces
okay because automated exploit automatic
exploit mitigation
we need to understand what are the
what are the new surfaces
that we have to deal with
that means new technologies for example
nowadays you have like iots right lot of
iit devices definitely they have lot of
new attack surfaces coming up and now
your
attack mitigation you have to consider
those things so that means of course if
you just consider a typical desktop
server kind of application it takes some
input either from the network or your
file and then does maybe you have to
adopt
in iot
are there newer attack techniques which
are fundamentally different that is also
one important part that we have to
understand other that's why you can do
some mitigation
if
the attacks
are fundamentally different your
mitigation
definitely may not work there and this
is what we see a lot in the previous
decade like we came up with
new kind of attacks like for example
coupe which is like counter feed object
oriented
programming okay and then people come up
with
print only programming data oriented
attacks okay
these are fundamentally different
attacks
and you really need to have a new way of
i mean coming up a new way of uh
defending against them okay
so we saw already
some of the techniques i talked about
that source of binary code uh binary
level control for integrity yes that's
that's there and
we we have lot of opportunities in
binary uh cfi then code diversification
that is a one more another technique but
very very
not much investigated so far there
because it is it is it is also a little
bit difficult because the idea about the
idea behind code diversification is
that each binary that you compile looks
different each binary okay and still the
functionality is same
so it is it is not that easy
but if you are able to do it pretty nice
okay and then other thing is which is
which i i am
hoping a lot
uh on this aspect like hardware support
that's very very important here
because
attack mitigation means that you are
changing your binary
your program
you are bringing in some new
thing in your program which will look
for something and react on something
which means there are overhead
involved with mitigation
if you are going for only software only
solution this overhead tends to be high
that's why we do not see such uh
mitigations in your
in your
typical application but now
hardware people vendors are giving you
interfaces that okay you you you
implement your
attack mitigation and we have
specialized instructions in order to do
some common tasks and then it becomes
super super fast because your hardware
is supporting you
and i have a lot of hope uh from that
perspective that
with more hardware support we can do
fantastic job i think
they are
mainly they they may be very specific
for a particular task but we can we can
be very creative and we can use the same
facility
to do something else
and then the other part that i think is
needs lot of lot of improvement is data
flow integrity this is a very very
strong property data flow if you are
able to do it
that is something like okay it's very
very difficult to attack
your application very very difficult
but it's very very expensive also but
because it has to do lot of lot of check
lot of check at runtime
and those checks with those checks in
place i don't think your you would like
to you would like to run your
application with all those checks but
then again the same thing my savior is
this
hardware
because if we have better hardware
support
i think the next
big
change that we'll see will come from dfi
and i'm pretty sure that in the next
coming up in the coming years it will be
dfi that is going to go into you know be
a hot topic among
mitigation
all right
so this is what i was talking about that
so research and programming language
community
they are working
separately
not necessarily with the security
community but they are coming off pretty
nice techniques okay for example
they these are the some of the paper
that i saw in in programming language
community
okay
complete formula semantics of x86
instruction set
it is really really very good because it
allows you now to do a lot of thing
automatically because you have formal
semantics of each instruction you can do
lot of analysis
you know that what this instruction does
you can understand this is this
implication and all automatic
so this is really nice similarly
abstract into sorry
similarly abstract integration under
speculative execution fantastic because
as i said that abstract interpretation
is a is a technique
which allows you to
to to to reason about your runtime
behavior of your program but statically
very very very very powerful
now what they have done they have done
that okay we can even reason about
speculative execution
which you do not observe actually as a
user level program but it happens
internally and i think what they did is
because of last year last to last year
meltdown spectre
uh attack if you might have heard about
them they were based on speculative
execution the the problem
and now you have a way of you know even
reasoning your program with speculative
execution and this is coming from not
from security community pldi purple
community okay so that's what my
ah effort was in the beginning that we
need to connect
if you are if you think that we can work
iso in isolation as a island it's not
gonna work
okay so so research in software
engineering and verification community
definitely doing some work which we can
definitely borrow ideas for
all right
so
right automatic exploit generation
why it is important how to do it this is
what i think
when i start looking at automatic
exploit generation
so
one i already told that my views on
automatic supply generation is not about
okay we can generate uh exploit
automatically because this is not what i
i'm not a offensive uh researcher as
such uh security researcher so that's
not my research agenda so for me
automatic generation is more like a
little bit more rigorous rigorous
testing but then what's happening in
this space
so if you look at
that
you you had some work initially in 2005
some work
after that
cmu group did some work you see that but
that is very very you know sparse 2008
then 2011 12
after that you don't see much coming out
from there and then from
uh
sean helen from the oxford university he
did some work in 2009 and after that
2017 he did some interesting work on he
uh he based expert generation okay
automatic heavy uh heap
overflow for generation
and then i saw
some one or two papers recently
so
it tells
that
we are really not progressing very well
in automated exploit generation
and that also gives you an idea or some
hint that it is complex it is very very
complex
because as i said that you have to
understand the environment of the victim
machine properly in order to really
generate automatics for generation which
is not easy okay
and nowadays
and also pain flow analysis that plays
major role is not still
there means it it is like it takes time
and it's a very heavy computation
symbolic execution controlling execution
which are fundamental they are still a
little bit heavy for people to apply
okay
so and then i am coming to my
last part here
as far as those main dimensions are
concerned
so
automated patching
right so we saw in the beginning in fact
this is this is where all started like
okay you are finding bugs too quickly
but you are not fixing them at the same
rate and that's why things are not
moving you know smoothly you do not have
you you just keep discovering new
attacks but you do not fix them so
nothing changes nothing much changes
actually okay but
so there is a community separate
community working for decades called
program synthesis
automated program synthesis so the
community basically is a branch of
software engineering
what they try to what they have been
trying to do is given some
specifications can we really
generate
computer programs
so this is a very very challenging task
of course nowadays it's becoming reality
some of them
might seem already co-pilot okay which
is uh integrated in in in
github it allows you to to to do
lot of lot of you know program automated
program uh rewrite not rewriting but
synthesis but in a limited way still but
this community has been working for
decades
okay and then
a lighter form of program synthesis is
called automated program repair
this is also active community
and i s so for example you can see one
paper concolic program repair in pldi 21
again
i am i am pointing out pldi
not specifically a security community
but they are working on this also
they were not
focusing on as such
patching a security bug
but they are focusing on okay we can
generate some program given something we
can and repairs some program because
there was some mistake or some feature
was missing kind of thing right so they
are doing totally a kind of complete
software engineering perspective they
were developing techniques but now we
can take ideas from them because after
all patch is again a piece of code that
you want to fix and replace with
something
okay so whole program synthesis is not
easy so sure that's why you do not see
much
much coming out from there i mean you do
not i mean until recently you did not
see much coming out from that community
but then the good part is in my opinion
that security bugs especially bugs which
are memo which are related to memory
corruption perhaps not they are not very
huge patches huge piece of code
because that is small then we do have
actually a good
uh friends
because
they are what they they
the technique is working may not go in
very large code but then maybe we also
do not require a large code okay my just
idea i mean i'm thinking maybe
so this is what i so we have been
working on some research project so i we
were where we were trying to analyze
some of the patches
and in most of the time we found that
your patches in some of the open sources
are not really really
very big so this is your original
program
and the patch was because you bring in
some new condition here and that
condition does something and then carry
on here or it goes somewhere else so
most of the time these memory
related corruption memory corruption
related bugs they have this kind of fix
because out of outer bound access they
want to stop that so this these are not
very big in my opinion
okay so and things to solve for patching
that but these are the thing that we
have to really really think about so
first of all
we have to have some automated way of
knowing the root cause of a particular
bug okay if you do not know the root
cause of any bug then you are not going
to do anything but if you are and also
the sorry
and also this root cause analysis is
also useful for crash triaging and
yesterday night when i was fixing my
slide i just looked for some new uh i
research were coming up in this
direction
just one week ago in ccs
which is a prime premier security
conference
a team from epfl presented igor
and what they are doing root cause
analysis for christianity in ccs one
week ago
so people are really working and i was
super happy about it that okay yes
that's that's exactly the thing that we
need to do
and then of course because this is the
patching of binary code definitely you
you have we have to take care of binary
code analysis that we talked about
earlier
binary rewriting is the fundamental
because you are changing the binary okay
but but luckily we have nice candidates
nowadays so it is the right time to do
this kind of thing we can do it i think
and there is another community which is
riso venetian
so binary resume nation is a different
community which what they are trying to
do that given a binary
legacy binary it was written
in late 70s perhaps with some computer
compiler
now you want to rejuvenate that with the
modern features of that particular
language at binary level so this is
super hard but they are working we can
take some ideas perhaps
so i am going to just
finish in
five minutes or so
so so now so hybrid approaches of
vulnerability discovery so we have
already seen this kind of
some separate thing like i talked about
you have static analysis you have
dynamic analysis
and then you also have hardware assisted
features and perhaps some other machine
learning kind of thing but how we we can
combine them
okay
so one thing is that what type of
vulnerability again i am thinking about
so memory corruption
vulnerabilities are there for the last
several years but still you see that
okay new cve is for a typical
vulnerability memory corruption
vulnerability is assigned
so they are not going here
ah they are still there okay
now the co and even we are not even
talking about this logic box forget
about because what we are talking about
memory corruption work because we can
observe them clearly
logic bugs are even people not talking
about
so perhaps what it gives us that
maybe we definitely need some sort of
combination of several type of analysis
to to solve this problem because
individually
we are i think
not doing uh we are not yet there okay
so this is what i was talking about
application of
ai and machine learning so large complex
application
so it means that
difficult to comprehend so then we can
maybe perhaps take the help of some
machine learning or
artificial intelligence but in
a more creative way rather than like
okay just take whatever comes to your
mind
and just give it to machine learning it
will do some magic and you will get some
answer no i don't think that that's
approach we have to have a very
meaningful
way of combining them
but
and you see what's happening
first of all yes people did some work
to to use artificial ml to find binary
level function recognition
those who are working on binary label
you may be knowing that this
is not that easy all the time
okay sometimes highly optimized code or
handwritten code may not have the proper
signature for the functions at binary
level if you are not able to find
functions you can't do things actually
okay
and this is you see the use in
they are doing value set analysis with
deep learning this is one of the
fundamental thing in program in program
analysis community and they did nice
work
with deep learning
and then they did assisted alias
analysis so these are the very some of
the fundamental problems of program
analysis
people have been trying to do that
correctly
but
given the size and complexity of the of
the software
classical technique if you want to apply
them as it is
is not they are not scalable sometimes
they give up
but here people are
doing a kind of very creative use of
machine learning and this is exactly
what i was talking about the some
creative uh application the way you
combine these two different communities
it's it's i think if you can able to if
you are able to do it
we can do a very very interesting work
so
i am summing up so in nutshell for me
the secure software that i said that is
definitely you have to have a balance in
all these aspects
okay
and
so i say the balance across various
steps that we talked about if you are
just focusing only on one we are not
still we are not going to have that
really the secure software that we are
talking about just focusing on one is
not going to help
and we need to look at communities
for
recent advancement and then try to adopt
and adapt
solutions from them and then we can
maybe do some better job i guess
and then
as i said that i'm really really looking
forward for this that there is a very
interesting development in hardware
software interfaces and this may be a
game changer for all this classical but
heavy technique
to be
usable in your large complex
environment
all right so with that i finish my talk
thank you very much
and if you have any
questions you can ask