hi this class is non-standard like me
let me tell you the seven reasons why
you should take this osd2 all you can
learn buffet class instead of a normal
one one in this class the instructor's
whole job is to answer your questions in
a normal class the instructor spends a
lot of their time just talking
in this class you watch the talking in
cyberspace not meat space this leaves
the instructor with way way more time in
order to answer your questions work with
you on labs and just talk with you just
like with red hat linux you're not
paying for the content you're paying for
the support and if you're the kind of
student who in a normal meat space class
isn't exactly inclined to ask a question
for whatever reason well there's no fear
here two everyone learns at their own
pace everyone's coming into this class
with a different background one size
does not fit all why should everyone go
through the class in lockstep in this
class you can speed up or slow
down the lectures as much as you want
three
three three
this class isn't just one class it's all
the classes from this particular
instructor if you finish the class early
you can move on to the next class in the
learning tree if you don't finish the
class in a given time you can still move
on to the next class after class because
we want you to take all the classes from
ost2 remember you're still going to have
support from the instructor after the
in-person class you'll get an instructor
who will answer up to 20 more questions
after the class because that's what
you're paying for support
it's literally like a cheat code for
getting unstuck in the game of life four
unlike a live lecture here you get
captions so if english isn't your first
language it makes it that much easier to
understand what the instructor just said
five unlike a live lecture where the
instructor might make a mistake and take
a while wasting your time as they try to
figure it out here through the magic of
video editing the mistakes are beaten
out of it quickly six
in a normal class you gotta wait for the
instructor's permission to get up and
take a break in this class it's after
lunch if you're feeling sleepy just get
up stretch your legs have some coffee
walk around give yourself the old
and no one's gonna bat an eye
seven as someone who's taught a lot of
live lecture classes i really do think
this hybrid format is going to lead to
the best student outcomes but if you
need one more reason to take a class
like this it's this by taking this class
you're directly supporting ost2
instructors who can then go off and make
more classes on more material so you can
just keep skilling up it's win win win
where the other winner is everyone
so don't delay sign up today and gorge
yourself at the ost2 all you can learn
buffet
you