[Music]
[Applause]
welcome to linux heap exploitation by
infosect
why do a course on linux heap
exploitation and one of the reasons that
we want to do this course is that
classic stack overflows have been
largely mitigated against
in server and desktop operating systems
now in the embedded space in iot space
classic stack overflows are probably
still exploitable but on server systems
and desktop systems they're very they're
reasonably mitigated again now heap
allocators have some mitigations and
more are introduced regularly in linux
but even with that modern exploit
primitives and many exploit privileges
can be gained on modern linux systems
and heap exploitation is still possible
on many allocators
with appropriate heat grooming
mostly these give us arbitrary read
write primitives and maybe an
information disclosure which in this
course will lead to control flow
hijacking and code execution this course
is an advanced course but it's
definitely achievable
a little bit about myself i'm the
managing director here at infosec i'm
also a conference organizer of b-sides
camera and the c-size monthly link that
we run in australia but before i was at
infosec full-time i was the director of
education and training at unsw canberra
which is university of new south wales
canberra at the australian defense force
academy overseeing the content and
ensuring that we had quality delivery
and quality content and training
i've also worked in industry on the blue
side i was the director of anti-malware
engineering at wallace effectively
commercializing my work on malware
variant detection
many years ago as also the scanner
architect wallace uh and wrote or
rewrote much of their core engine police
guard wrote about 50 000 lines of c code
for them and that's pretty much the
industry standard for vulnerability
assessment today
i've also worked on the red side i was a
senior software specialist at azimuth
security doing vulnerability research
online training at infosec has been very
well received we've been doing it for
more than a year now we have
a good lab environment using amazon
instances you basically get a desktop
environment through the browser
we have good lectures we have high
quality av to provide this as well in
face-to-face training using a whiteboard
is a very important process of showing
how certain things are laid out in
memory we replicate that experience
using
you know a tablet to
that we can interactively draw on
we have lab exercises that cover
all of the techniques and attacks that
we're working on the labs are running on
ubuntu 20.04 the latest version of that
which is the lts release of ubuntu
the most recent lt lts release as well i
was very nice that rgr security did
quote one of our uh one of our bits of
research at infosec where we attack
the linux kernel heap allocator from a
year or two ago and we'll talk about
some of the weaknesses in that linux
penalty validator implementation and how
it was fixed and it's very nice to do
our security to talk about that in one
of their recent blog posts
if
modern exploitation against linux
systems interests you
register for the training and i'll see
you on the course