hi my name is monapa i'm the author of
the book learning malware analysis i
specialize in malware analysis memory
forensics and threat hunting
i have trained security professionals
from government and private sectors in
various conferences like black hat blue
corn and hitb this year i am really
excited to teach our course on malware
analysis and memory forensics at hitb
cyber week
in this training you will learn the
concept tools and techniques to analyze
investigate and partner and also you
will be learning
some of the analysis techniques like
static analysis dynamic analysis i'll be
introducing you to the concept of
reverse engineering and also we will
look at some of the windows internal
concepts and the techniques to hunt for
malware using memory forensics
this is a completely hands-on training
where you will be analyzing real malware
samples and you will be hunting for
threads from the malware infected memory
images
whether you are a beginner who want to
learn malware analysis from scratch or
an experienced professional who want to
take your skills to the next level then
this course is for you i promise this
course will be fun
and if this sounds interesting please
take a moment to visit the course page
and sign up for the training
and also if you have any questions
please don't hesitate to reach out to me
or hitb organizers and will be happy to
answer all your questions
thank you for watching have a nice day