hello everybody this is
from defensive security hope you are
doing well
i would like to invite you for the
upcoming cyber week conference which is
the largest cyber security event in the
middle east organized by the greatest
hike in the box crew cheers guys
so this year i will have a pleasure to
run a technical in and out attack
detection and hunting with purple ops
training and i believe it's gonna be
awesome
so expect very challenging time brain
overflow eventually with a ton of
different
hands-on labs in the formula of attack
versus detection
uh during the last year i have trained
over 100 people from the largest
companies over the world
threat hunter security engineers sock
analysts penetration testers red and
blue team members and everyone were
extremely happy and impressed because of
the content the new skills they gained
and overall training environment not to
mention the atmosphere of course so
if you would like to learn more about
how to run
adversary simulations effectively
including the development of attack
paths and chain attack scenarios if you
would like to know more about how to get
sufficient network and os visibility how
the sigma detection rules work and how
to use them to know more about the apt
and the malware behavior
if you are interested in detection
methods and capabilities of well or
recognized hunting and detection tools
including hunting elk systems plank
elastiflow moloch osquery was a great
look just to name a few
then this training is just for you so
really
this is a big content combo based on my
almost 20 years of experience in the
cyber security market so
i can't wait for it
once again join me in face to face in
abu dhabi on november 21 for just attend
online and yeah let's meet and learn
something new all together
thank you very much and see you there
you