[Music]
see how order in the future yes well
thank you so much to you and Phoebe and
everyone who is here and sharing this
morning with us and in this case with so
interesting subject of cybersecurity and
I think cybersecurity has to be aimed at
all types of audiences when I came in I
said people you're dancing and doing
different kinds of sports and I asked my
age I'm not even ex generation my baby
boomer I would recommend a sea bear to
have maybe yoga or pilot session more
we're here there you know and we could
learn the vocabulary linked to
cybersecurity and and do something which
is more adapted to us because we have
two options from my generation my say oh
this is awful
I've gotten off with my whatsapp and it
does what I need to do and then be happy
and then find that the digital gap
becomes bigger and bigger every day
because we are surrounded by technology
everywhere because our fridge has this
and that and things call you and Madonna
and then the supermarket comes he M
brings coffee to your home oh you have
another option your and you can say no
I'm going to Train but first of all we
need to raise awareness and secondly we
need to off the training so add in
Phoebe in lea in Leon I did tell the
former manager and I would like to tell
the new director we need a cyber camp
for seniors so having said that let's
start and see why we need that sort of
cyber camp
ah sorry could you tell me what I have
to press sir the flight change could you
tell me how this works please oh there
we go thank you so much it was just an
excuse to getting closer to me oh well
well as I was saying I'm going to talk
about benefits prejudices and many other
things that we usually think we know but
which are surrounding us and the people
from a generation needs to get to know
at some point you won't even realize
that you're not getting your money into
the bank because there are banks which
are telling you that you cannot check
anything if you didn't download the app
and well I'll show you what it means for
us to download an app so first of all so
we're saying are we do we have enough
knowledge does this affect society in
the same way all of society what do you
think yes no does it affect all of us
Yeah right then get a move on and so
we'll see that there are tools because
we've been talking about many tools
during these days and these are very
specialized tools but I go piano Keller
and I will tell you it once I think I
should be telling you oh ma roughly
around 1945 he was the last US general
in the Second World War and said if we
keep developing our technology without
knowledge and without prudence our
server could have become our key lasting
and I think that is exactly what's
happening right now what can I tell you
about the benefits of communication and
IT interconnection flexibility
convergence you can get surgery heart
surgery but does someone tell you about
the
it means the amount of a almonds it's so
numerous superficiality social isolation
to to know by the way that every 2.5
hours commit suicide in Spain I'm not
saying the business because of
communication technology but social
isolation is very important cyber
harassment digital gap not only people
my age but also people who do not have
access to technologies I am part of an
association Confederation in Malaga and
people from sources who make who produce
raining racing's communicate with very
very rudimentary ways and now Montero is
saying our Minister for taxes that we
need a digital signature for everything
so what happens with people who use very
rudimentary ways of communication what
can we do because your fridge and your
car and you washing machine and all the
things that you multiplying the amount
of solution that we have in our world
we're going to have the climate
conference in in Madrid and well we are
going to keep using energy in the same
way only because we fail well because we
have that conference taking place here
and then they were saying that there
were girls who would get one kilo of
food social project every hour that they
want without their phone and the one who
spent the most hours without their phone
spend 23 hours although they did manage
to get 400 kilos anyway there are many
many things I haven't really talked
about the digital gap and I think we
have to overcome that
do you know what social engineering is
because at they don't tell us the truth
because if they say when they say social
I think about solidarity but something
good but do you know what social
engineering is yes tell us exactly
everything people use to make us believe
the things which you know not I've
already talked to all the actors consent
on this to change the name because when
I think so sure I think of something
good the social engineering is obtaining
confidential information by manipulating
the legitimate uses and they say that
and that's it right no this is a scam
this is social scam not social
engineering
well the users are the weakest link and
that is why I think how about Fiona
Institute who's already checking now
where are you going where you're not
going this is a study that took place
last week in the plains Baba it doesn't
matter they can follow what you do
because you're not going to say who you
are and they're selling our data yeah
for that study and are we ready for
what's coming or what's already going on
how about fishing oh you already know
someone calls you someone says you're an
email or just change your bank's
password in my time this was always in
good faith all the director of the bank
has called me I am very proud and now
you give them their password and they
take all the money from your account and
how about social media oh yeah I've got
Facebook oh oh yeah I use Instagram I
didn't use Facebook anymore
Oh uses Instagram but did you know that
the picture of your grants and the you
just uploaded is being sold by a man in
Australia no no but it's fine because I
upload it well no actually it isn't
because you upload it onto the Internet
anyway if I came across all those people
from Facebook does anyone know what the
cloud is
I have no idea whatsoever route route
cloud is a trend isn't it we're all
going towards the cloud cloud computing
that sounds so smart and then they say
we're going to give you computing
services through the cloud that you're
not going to have to buy anything
anymore because Amazon has everything
Google has everything all that stuff all
I can say is be very careful with this
famous cloud because there are 50,000
Chinese people getting ready to get
everything you have loading reading
everything and spreading it amongst
themselves so be careful with the cloud
it's true we're not going to do a lot of
fear now at my age but just be careful
with the cloud because and the cloud
they want to get everything connected
all those things your fridge and
everything else and the more things you
open the more doors
you open you know that if you have two
daughters very difficult to monitor
who's coming in and out your home so
that you've got your doors your tablet
your phone your your car your fridge
everything is connected in the cloud
well this is really pulling your leg the
famous cookie has it not happen to you
but you say oh I'm going with my friends
to Lisbon just in the weekend
and you go on the site and you see that
the flight costs a hundred euros and you
say whoa I found a ticket for 100 euros
you can find it in this in that way you
go on again it's 150 but why it was a
hundred only half an hour ago oh you
know so foreign demand no it's because
they give you a number there on your
phone and it's tracking you number seven
where is where is she now it's got an
iPhone it's got money she's in Madrid
his price goes up
oh she's swarthy - but she doesn't have
money anymore so we'll put the price
down so that she or she doesn't have
battery I meant so they put the price
down so you male then they register your
behavior but game information about your
behaviour whatever you download you've
got it there oh how about apps I've
already mentioned that when talking
about banks it's another way of being
spied upon remotely you download to get
a torch and that torch has access to
your son's phone how why we really need
to know how to stop where we have to set
boundaries and we just want a torch to
light up that's all we want because then
they have the nerve to say well the
services for free so who is the product
it will be you right why are you
complaining I'm giving you things for
free I was saying to some friends the
other day but this reminds me of when I
used to go and buy some because when you
bought Simon they gave you the Simon and
then a piece of the hair can I throw out
on the head please you just won the
salmon everyone takes a piece of the
head I don't mind I don't mind paying
more but I don't want the head so to all
these engineers and people I would say
well make me pay more but stop spying on
me because I think technology is all
very good but I don't want you to spy on
me now so this is just a short
introduction about salad and now
let's get into it because we have virus
that attack worms Trojans mutants
mmm blah blah whatever there's a new one
every day this is like olive oil isn't
it in my time olive oil was awful really
bad for you and now it's really good
well in my time hackers were really bad
people and now the really good people so
those bad people are the crackers so
hacker is good cracker is bad see I'm
starting to get but this is really
difficult
now how about is cyber harassment this
is quite serious actually this is one of
the biggest and according to the wuh-oh
Spain is one of the countries where this
means cyber harassment actually 70% of
girls suffer it and boys only 30% but
this is something that we really really
need to stop including cyber bullying
which is I think young people we've got
different times
grooming which is pretending that
sexting that affects both children and
teenagers you take a picture for your
boyfriend you censor and you know how
this works
extortion well there are many many many
sites so if it's granny doesn't know
about this and then the granny cannot
help their grandchildren and and help
them and show them the way now we're
getting to the worst part access to
pornography that young people now have
and this means that women can be
harassed relationship in Spain have
increased incredibly and 43% with
regards to
- last year in terms of group group rape
in Spain with so there's sexual abuse
and Agri civet II and this is being
transmitted as if it were normal not
love and passion so I think engineers
need to find a way of ensuring that
pornography does not reach young people
so easily so what about artificial
intelligence do you think this is male
chauvinist or not so many engineers hear
so much silence here we have Khan she
she's an expert what about Eddie what do
you think yes or no what do you think
out there
I think artificial intelligence if it
learns from the information that it
receives it depends what the world
itself is like you're absolutely right
absolutely right you hit the nail on the
head I went back for a moment let me
just say so if you learn a language and
if you learn language that has been
distorted then that is what you in you
you believe in there are sexist
translation systems such as the Google
translation system we're talking about
Turkish where there is no
differentiation between gender and there
are cases of when it says doctor when
somebody is actually an nurse only 15%
in face book of artificial intelligence
and 10% in Google and a 18% of people
going online are actually women in terms
of artificial intelligence so we need to
do things to correct this situation
because it will be increasingly male
chauvinist at what the police release is
Biogen regarding violence against women
saying that there will be activities to
avoid gender violence which is
increasing and that the will increased
prediction of reoccurring offenders so
this is why it's very very important
that we increasingly have young women
who study stem degrees and I would like
to say something I would like to say
that there was gentle
who was talking earlier don't if he's
here now
but I'd like to point out that apart
from the fact that you do a wonderful
job here but we need to do a job we need
to work with the mathematicians and the
teachers of maths in Spain if teachers
are bad in Spain what you're going to
achieve if teachers say to you if you're
this is awful if you're going to be
studying this you're going to spend your
whole life studying and they oriented
towards young men and we have to work
with maths teachers in this country in
this sense I think maths is on the
increase now and there's been an
increase of women in maths degrees now
because it deals a lot with artificial
intelligence and I think this is a point
that is growing and we have big innocent
representatives of the women and
mathematicians and maths in Spain what
I'm saying is that teachers need to be
good teachers that's what I'm trying to
say because according to a study one of
the big issues that we have in terms of
engineering and men and women this was
one of the big issues that came out in a
recent study so if they say so it must
be true I'm not going to go against that
so we need to help young women in STEM
degrees but we'll see to have good
teachers 50 or 80% of professions
depending on who you listen to in the
future we are unaware of currently but
they will all be related to technology
so it's very very important that we help
those algorithms to come out if you want
to
study philosophy you always you also
need to have people with ethics within
that field I need to have people with
ethics within cybersecurity and in
artificial intelligence and what about
fake news I'm a journalist so who's
behind this political parties
corporations great companies and you're
being told lies or they change
presidents or they talk about the Amazon
or different situations in countries
brexit the Russians and so on and so on
this is all around us in our day today
so it's very important to point this out
there are businesses one a particular
maldita dot yes that deals specifically
with this and it's being attacked
continually we are not machines are we
happy with everything that we have
around us an expert in positive
psychology who said that quantitative
measures make sense to machines but
human lives were not created like that
do we need to earn more money do we need
to be more famous do we need more light
this is what what it creates is stress
we're surrounded about all the things
that we could enjoy but actually what we
do and what we end up having is
depression and stress and so on and so
on I would suggest that engineers should
try and create a less stressful and
- TIF world a bit more quality I don't
know if that's possible but I think we
would be happier so a few pieces of
advice from my humble opinion get in
touch with the OSI the office for
security for uses of the internet their
tools to help you and they encourage you
you need to learn the necessary things
about this field and it's also helpful
if somebody is harassing you because if
somebody is harassing you in a normal
world in my opinion the normal thing to
do would be to call the police I've been
I'm being harassed they're not going to
pay you any attention we're going to
explain that many many people make these
same calls every day is there a
telephone number or an email address
that can write to to talk about this
no there is no no there really isn't if
you pull that number then what they tell
you is that you have to go and make a
report so it's not as easy it looks so
let's avoid this
let's have prevention tools and in in
fever itself you can get some formation
about this and then you can move forward
and talk to the police
so using webcams and covering webcams I
should do this every day because I
always walk around at home perhaps with
my clothes on and I forget about things
and I'm walking around happy so why
should I cover my webcam spying through
a mobile what are we talking about here
oh they're encouraging you to buy and
buy and buy now I've already mentioned
this house words everybody here will
know here but other people may
you need to have at least eight
characters capital letters and numbers
and different characters once you've
done it one time then somebody else
comes along says something different and
changes the idea so do what you think is
best I've got a list of all my passwords
and so on got them in a given place and
sometimes they say oh it's got to be
encrypted and then you encrypt it and
then you forget it okay so do whatever
you can you got to concentrate on being
happy so remove all your applications or
the tools that you're not using because
they're the door of entry and they also
use up your battery so maybe you need
somebody to help you to do this because
you might end up with no my book mobile
at all disconnect your Wi-Fi when you
leave home and remove all the data I
don't know if I'm capable of doing this
and sometimes I ended up I tried doing
it and ended up with no data at all who
can I call now use your common sense
of course you have to try encourage
people and these are my conclusions
cyber security might say see sim seems
something that that doesn't affect you
but it does affect us in our day-to-day
we need to get trained and we need to be
aware of what is going on and we need to
teach people about digital devices we
have to integrate and try to progress
and of course we have to close that
gender gap because as I was saying cyber
security is for everyone thank you very
much
[Applause]
if you have any questions we've got
about three minutes I believe now you
know nobody you already know a lot about
all of this it's been a pleasure to be
here
I would love our associate of women for
dialogue and education to offer their
support if you are interested in taking
the first steps because we do workshops
on emotional intelligence because we say
well if we're going to do talks about
business let's talk about cyber security
as well so that's all just be happy
[Applause]
you