[Music]
right good morning everyone thank you
very much for being here at this early
hour as we have been introduced and as
it has been said we're going to talk
about professional opportunities and
cyber security currently as they set
during the inauguration our general
manager as well as the secretary of
state cyber security is an industry
which is growing thus loads of
professional opportunities and today
we're going to have very important
speakers to give us a very holistic
vision of the professional opportunities
and the studies that we can undergo in
order to end up working in cyber
security we're going to have the
presentation here at the background slow
issue with the presentation but whilst
we get that sorted I'm going to
introduce the rest of the guests we have
Alejandro Velasco from the official
engineering Association in the Valencian
community thank you for being here
also Ramona Nubia which is part of the
Association of computing professors in
the Valencian community also Santiago
Escobar from the Polytechnic University
and finally Emilio Soria from the
University of Valencia what they're
going to do is introduce briefly how
they see from the point of view of every
different institution what the
professional opportunities are
cybersecurity what studies will lead you
to a career in cybersecurity and when we
finish we'll have an open question and
answer session for those of you who
don't know what they should do now or
what they should do once they finish
this to you this can ask any questions
they have and and we have a few
questions if you didn't have any that
have
asked before and we can use them later
it looks like the presentations not
working right now so we're going to
start talking about cybersecurity which
is an environment which is currently
growing it's an industry that is growing
and there's a lack of experts and
professionals whilst we have everyone's
presentation I'm going to ask the first
question what is the future of
cybersecurity what does it look like why
is it so important right now
why cybersecurity sirki alejandro well
good morning everyone
I think for all of you who are here is
going to be very obvious why
cybersecurity is important companies
more and more consent every day towards
the risks that they facing every day and
because of new technologies companies
are being targeted every day and they
need mechanisms tools systems and
professionals who help them to face
these risks they also need to find
balance between the budget that goes
toward cybersecurity and to compensate
it with the risks that they might face
they have to assess which risks may
affect their branding the brand image
and their business and that is why
cybersecurity right now is one of and we
were going to talk about this a lot this
morning but it's one of the main niche
for professionals from the point of view
of academia maybe Ramon can tell us
something about education well as
Alejandro was saying cybersecurity is
growing continuously and from the point
of view of vocational training them
I'm pleased that we are surrounded with
and with whom we have internship
agreements demanding more technicians
especially when it comes from operations
security operations or network
operations these are positions that
usually engineer's do not do because
they usually manage at a higher level
different operations so there are a lot
of opportunities with the Internet of
Things victims especially in industry in
general companies facing new risks every
day because we have new possibilities
new sales channels ways of doing
business online so we we face new risks
every day is that handle we're saying so
there's there's a very high demand which
is also increasing in cyber security and
for students to train in this area is
very important because they have many
opportunities to find a job now from the
point of view of universities we have
the to many universities in Valente how
do you see the situation well from the
point of view of the Polytechnic
University I agree completely with what
has been said because we also have not
only to train but also to research and
and then obviously the opportunities
because right now there are many people
who graduated by in in different
universities and but are not specialized
in cyber security but do end up from
different degrees working in cyber
security so I do agree that in many
industries what they're asking right now
and this is not only for companies it's
it's for also higher positions when it
comes to innovation to research to
development to thinking about what will
happen with big data in a few years or
with the with industry with a different
attacks that they are facing and being
the target off so this is a critical
point in
many opportunities well I think some
years ago we were on the mobility decade
with mobile phones and communication
devices between people and this decade
is the decade of security we've got
numerous days they're going between
companies we have many devices that can
be targeted by hackers and so we have to
keep the integrity of that data and of
that information so we're going towards
a century where everything is going to
be around data about information and we
definitely have to protect the integrity
of that data and that information so if
I have to study again I would definitely
do a master's in cybersecurity
now along these lines especially when it
comes to the it work to education we
know that this is a very young industry
that there are many people who work
already in cybersecurity but who are
self-taught so I would like especially
from the point of view of universities
and education and also from the
professional point of view what added
value to someone bring who has trained
in cybersecurity versus someone who has
trained themselves well I think the main
difference is that in this kind of
issues practice and experience has just
make a big difference because at home
you can watch videos you can see things
and but I think the way you're quiet
knowledge is when someone tells you
about the problems that they've had and
the issues that they've had to face
there are many online causes nowadays
but they will never give you the
experience that someone has if they have
been working for years in this area and
what I would add is that cybersecurity
is
very mmm multi-faceted and I think if
you have that kind of training you can
definitely do that
from home you can see many things but it
is precisely from universities will be
fostering multifaceted
the education and although there aren't
that many specific training programs or
the masses and everything I think we do
provide a very rich education that can
then be applied to industry and the
people who train with us then in high
demand for companies because companies
do look for that kind of profile and how
about vocational training well we think
that being self-taught is definitely key
and actually companies do tell us that
they prefect someone who has the will
and the attitude towards learning and
having also a professional certificate
but at the end of the day companies what
they want to know is what you can do so
I think it's definitely key that if
someone who is passionate about what
they do if they like cybersecurity if
they work in many different fields they
work at home they do they try different
things they have little shock at home
they fiddle a little bit around with
their ruse so what the actual definition
of geek that we've always had I don't
like the word eek but it's it's the
picture that we always get so that for
companies the fact that you have your
own blog that you can share your
knowledge so you come to conferences and
you do speeches so companies do value
the fact that you have formal training
but I think that increasingly looking
for people who can do a bit more than
that and how about from the professional
point of view well I understand what the
people from universities have
set I think formal training the way we
know it nowadays both from public and
private institutions is very important
in order to have a certain skills that
will allow you to develop your
profession later on it is also true than
nowadays we have multiple channels where
we can train ourselves be it with open
massive open and courses you've got
YouTube I don't think there's a great
source of knowledge but I'm sure that
there will be people who know how to
pass on that knowledge and you can
actually internalize some of their
knowledge but I think there are many
many different ways of complementing
your formal training I think it's
actually key and I think we will all
agree the nowadays no one who has had
has just obtained their degree can stop
learning because this is a changing
market especially cybersecurity
everything is changing the attacks
changing the fields are changing you
have to be doing continuous professional
development CPD all the time companies
do look for someone who is curious who
want to keep training who wants to keep
learning and that is very important
specialization is key especially for
certain positions especially technical
positions but you have to have a very
broad vision of business of what risks
businesses face and all in all what can
help you have an advantage in the
professional market especially for
people who were looking for jobs which
in this case will be saying well it's
not easy but easier than in other
industries so just to summarize what
we've been saying we could say that
whilst it is true that training both
University and vocational training gives
us some fundamental some basis and some
knowledge it is in high demand also a
profit
someone who goes a bit further who wants
to try new things so we are looking for
a bit of everything boys and girls so
we're looking for people who do formal
training but also people who go a bit
further and want to make a difference
compared to the other people who are
applying for a job well now that we have
the presentation I'm going to let
Alejandra tell us a little bit what how
they see it from his institution good
morning everyone
I've already said good morning because
we've been talking a bit but I would
like to take this opportunity to think
in theory for organizing this event also
because they've decided to do it in
Valencia although it looks like we are
becoming a bit trendy in the last few
months and actually I've been here for
the third time today in in two weeks
also thank you to all those who are
showing my round to the round table with
me today and without further ado because
we've changed a little bit the pace of
the conference today I wanted to show
you a little bit Dyanne news headings or
media headings both from digital and
paper media and general and special
media and this gives us a very clear
vision of what that situation looks like
nowadays when it comes to employment in
the cybersecurity industry as you can
see very clearly we are expecting this
industry to grow dramatically that
employment will hence increase that it
is very difficult to find talent
nowadays that is a highly profitable
niche as I was saying and far a few more
data
concerning the industry as we can see
here as well there's a big gender gap
because a few women who work in
cybersecurity actually well in in
general there's very few women who work
in computing the night ear in general so
cybercrime is profitable and is still
profitable so we're going to be
suffering attacks in general in
companies and most companies are
understanding that the area's the
cybersecurity
areas too small they need more
professionals but at the same time they
cannot feel and fulfill all their needs
they also intend to increase their
spending on this over the coming years
this perception that we have based on
some articles and headlines in
newspapers it's also backed up by other
day turned reports from international
sources such as I sac and they have the
different areas of knowledge regarding
how cyber security is evolving and this
is also relevant the vacancies are not
being covered and the candidates
themselves don't believe that they have
sufficient expertise in order to be able
to opt for those positions knowledge of
the profession has been identified as a
gap gap of knowledge amongst the
candidates we were mentioning that you
need to have a good white knowledge
broad knowledge of the business all
candidates according to businesses are
not prepared to face the challenges and
there is
in the business and also another point
which i think is very interesting and
I'd like to highlight this today almost
80% of men of men it's understood that
men and women have the same
opportunities in businesses but in fact
49% of women only share that opinion
this can be resolved through diversity
programs in businesses what do we do in
order to contribute to resolving this in
Tallinn to try and fit the correct
profiles with the the available offers
and the the needs we are public entity
and we represent a number of
professionals in the field we do is
almost a outside of working hours and we
try to collaborate with universities we
collaborate with the two universities in
Berlin in Valencia particularly in the
forest stem project which is promoted by
the College of the scientists and this
is basically a project 30 aims to raise
awareness about stem and who promotes
the vocation of women within the field
of technology also participate in a
competition which is stem for teens
and it's for fourth and fifth year
secondary education students and it's
trying to get them closer to the world
of technology and bring young people
closer to projects that I'm talking
about new projects they haven't been
running for long the Employment
Authority for example we received
information to think a little bit more
about the competencies that are
currently existing and we are working on
that with them we're trying to work out
a better profile of the people who'll be
working today and tomorrow and I can
tell you that we have made a suggestion
that cybersecurity should be covered
across the board in all areas of
Education and this was delivered this
report was delivered last we have the
employment authority service so that
offers can be published the office
that's been provided by universities and
companies that is our employment service
that we have been running we have issued
a number of opportunities this year and
with a volume of 644 professional
opportunities and with a success rate of
around 10 percent we tried to give ad
hoc training courses these two proposals
for training for the coming months
related to different areas of technology
and another one regarding cyber security
it's called experts in cyber security
and this will be done over a number
for events and so that people can get
the sufficient training under to move
and to manage the world of cybersecurity
we have some activities going on in the
professional world we have public and
private services that are based on
demand we can carry out audits and this
is we cover issues that are currently
very on invoke such as what's up and
taking people's identity of course we
have to have ethics within our field and
this is also something that we cover the
definition of the the professionals in
the field we are working that on that
air with a European participation and
national committees to divine define the
roles in IT for professionals
what is the market actually looking for
in our opinion the market is looking for
all kinds of profiles more some to do
with more with cyber security more to do
with networks and systems you need
knowledge of methodology and good
practices professional vocational
training or as also has an added value
and there is also a little bit of
resistance in terms of the knowledge of
language we need to go beyond just
knowing Spanish you have a bit of
information something that you can turn
to which I think is very interesting
it's information that was released
weeks ago and its analysis of the
digital and not digital professional
opportunities linked to the professional
opportunities it's divided up by
provinces so depending on where you are
from you can look at the opportunities
that you have and the knowledge that you
will need in order to be able to opt for
those opportunities this information has
been taken from various sources from
different companies that publish their
offers including input jobs I think it's
worth spending a few minutes there is
one section that says expert in cyber
security and it indicates the
requirements in order to opt for that
role
so in terms of the opportunities in the
professional world what can we use our
knowledge for there are different roles
and professional functions we can manage
security within businesses we can also
work in sales and pre-sales audits
consultancy developing software and
there's also a systems technicians
opportunities and this is related with
privacy gen managing data and privacy
and this is across all sectors of
Industry all companies need to have
people who are looking after their area
cybersecurity you can work in a company
you work as a freelance self-employed
person or based on projects there are
more and more people who are
specializing and working in this way
application here something that came up
recently it was on our web page and it's
an opportunity for a pen tester this is
a Valencian company that deals with
consultancy and audits and it works on
regional and national level it leaves
this opportunity on our web page and I
thought it would give you an idea of the
kind of profile that companies are
looking for this gives you a general
idea of the things that we have been
working on and it could give you a
general idea of what the market is like
what the market is looking for what the
opportunities
you don't forget it's a little bit over
this hose you know get ourselves so
thank you very much
Thank You alejandro so now will allow
Ramon to take the floor also like to say
thank you to the organization for
inviting us to be here this morning and
for representing the teachers for
vocational training for computer science
I'd like to talk a little bit about the
profit vocational training the current
status of vocational training training
is currently grouped in two different
families and we're in telecommunications
and could be decides we have a basic
vocational training and mid level
training and superior level training the
subjects are modules in vocational
training and there are two modules that
are verticals we say the rest are
transversal there are techniques of how
to protect applications and so on there
are nice they're only two modules that
are called
computer security these modules just
cover two terms so there's a very little
time there's only year five hours of
training a week they reach around a
hundred hundred and ten hours and they
give a general overview of what of these
subjects I'll give you a general idea
but we are not able to get into these
skills and competencies that companies
are actually looking for so you have the
content of the mid-level and super level
vocational training courses and in the
mid-level would be a technician more
into towards small and medium sized
companies and the superior level is a
technician who has the mid-level
training but also has little extra and
can work in perhaps larger companies
larger corporations in s Sox and NOx
[Music]
linphea we have a the entity for
response to emergencies and we had a
speech about that from Laura this
perhaps more advanced areas in the
superior level training Alejandro said
in cybersecurity we also have some data
here to to share I won't cover it in
detail because Alejandro already
mentioned this but from our point of
view and our experience what I can tell
you is that companies are looking for
different profiles and they have up to
six months of positions that not being
covered so we can say there is maybe a
niche where somebody who has vocational
training can cover people who have a
higher level training or knowledge of
autism so on can't cover and these
positions can be complementary now
they're looking for many people with
vocational training level two level one
and two for operations and so on okay so
slappy CV
[Music]
and whatever they what are they
suggesting as you listen come a little
bit late but since June of this year
there is a specialist course in
cybersecurity for IT companies and this
is part of our family and there is
another field that's also growing and
cybersecurity in industrial environments
these work in parallel so in order to be
able to walk work in industrial sectors
but I'm going to be talking this morning
about the one that we are dealing with
currently the course is only in draft
version so hopefully for the next school
year we'll be able to put it into
practice so this would be provided by
centers that provide for vacation or
training this is for people who have
vocational training qualifications on
the superior level in app development
web development and it's for them in
order to get training so that gets more
specific training on security this gives
us access to the system settler
communications and computer science
scientists superior courts it's all
available in FPS on the webpage if you
look in there you'll see it on there and
you can access the content of the
modules I'd like to point out that we do
have modules or subjects as we call them
specific in terms of management of
incidents and cybersecurity how to
manage them how to deal with
how to copy all the proof and data there
is also computer forensic analysis there
is another module
regarding networks and systems it deals
with servers routers firewalls and so on
the one regarding is safe production
that's developing web applications
covering the requirements for in terms
of security another one on ethical
hacking as we call it and this is more
and towards pentesting and the red teams
which many organisms called them and of
course there is a module on
cybersecurity itself it's important in
terms of protecting cell systems and but
also dealing with complying with
regulations and so on there is currently
more and more legislation that we have
to comply with so it's important that
technicians are familiar with this and
they understand the expectations that
are coming from a European level
so what do we have in this draft
document it says that the profiles for
this course have the options later and a
professional level consultants in
cybersecurity order dissing
cybersecurity and experts in
cybersecurity I have added operations
technicians on level one and level two
usually they are in engineers level one
and level two technicians can work in
safety operations in companies many of
these are out sourced by different
companies because they don't have
resources within the company at all to
do themselves
also possible to work in a NOC
management of incidents and so on and
racing away there is also opportunities
as an analyst and Auditor there are also
options in order to VM job to work as a
civil guard or the central Brigade for
investigation in technology for the
National Police Force in cyber security
it's also possible in order to be Auto
opt for these opportunities within these
fields I have mentioned this is an
alternative option is not only the
opportunities are not only in companies
and businesses these are alternative
options just too and I'll tell you a
little bit about the companies with whom
we have some contacts and I've mentioned
some of them here just because they
collaborate with us and what they're
looking for now they have told me is
pentesters opportunities in what they
call the red team with regarding
technical reports penetration of systems
and improving their security in the
organization's security auditors also
what I was mentioning before level 1 and
level 2 operators and remote monitoring
these people work in shifts let's need
to be checked continually so these
people work in shifts and as I was
saying before most in most companies
have instance almost every week so this
is on the up they have also
that vocational people the vacation or
training can also help in terms of her
consultancies in terms of sales they can
help to write offers and reports and we
have students who have worked in
awareness training in awareness these
people give talks about cybersecurity
grooming sexting and so on these are
transversal subjects and we should all
be aware of them whether or not we're
technicians so some of our students have
have also done work of this kind and
with this and we'll pass over to our
colleague first of all I would like to
think in fever for inviting me to take
part in this roundtable I've got a
little technical problem and I haven't
been able to bring all the slides that I
have and I wanted to use my browser but
I'm not sure that I can use it
Hey
right sorry about that
we've had a little technical problem and
I don't have my slides here but I've
really liked the presentations given by
my other colleagues I think you have
covered most of everything to do with
cybersecurity and what companies are
looking for so I think what we can add
up on from universities is regarding
degrees and masters and cybersecurity so
this is our official website for the
Apollo Technical University
you've got the link here to studies so
we have many different degrees amongst
those related to cybersecurity which
could be related to cybersecurity and
you can see I come from the computer
science schools we've got a degree in
computing the computer science and we
look into cyber security in many many
subjects so this is one of the degrees
that would be an entry point for many
companies who are looking for computer
engineers we also have a new data
science degree and within that data
science degree we've talked a lot about
big data and many other related issues
we also have subjects in cybersecurity
sorry I'm a bit tall for this table
well sorry anyway would you have several
degrees which are related to
telecommunications to industrial
engineering that could also be relevant
to many other aspects of cybersecurity
indeed many people who have degrees in
telecommunications do access the work
market and it has been one of the main
areas for cybersecurity in the last few
years and now currently because of
cybersecurity and industrial
environments there are many people from
industrial engineering or civil
engineering who are in high demand
because of the particular knowledge that
they have so other than this just add I
want to be brief
so other than bachelor degrees we also
have master's degrees and I'm going to
I'm really sorry because this is this
table is really low and I cannot see it
well as I was saying the Polytechnic
universities and really have a master's
which is specifically on cyber security
but we work in on one which will start
will be launched in September next year
we've got many companies which are
interested among them
the lawyer and many others in this
master's this is specialized in cyber
security and cyber intelligence and as
you can see we have many other masters
on offer right now we've got software
engineering when we talk about secure
development and we also have master's in
civil engineering that complements the
training that has been given in
The Bachelor degree and also touch upon
cybersecurity
I don't know all the masses but I think
we also I'm sure we also have some
masses related with cyber intelligence
which are also specialized in cyber
security so we have many different
trainings that do touch upon cyber
security this is all thank you very much
[Applause]
and finally Emilio Surya from University
of Berlin yeah yeah if I could just have
the remote so that we can have a mr.
sensation here on the background
well Emilio is going to tell us a little
bit about the vision or the point of
view of the University of Valencia
first of all I would like to think in
thievery form inviting me to be here I
think everyone has already almost
touches upon everything already from the
from our point of view we also have
different bachelor degrees will we train
about cyber security we actually do you
have the masters now inside a security
and I wanted to think a little bit about
cyber security for the future of cyber
security we've been looking at data and
numbers about the present and because I
am the last one I'm going to talk a
little bit about its future so when we
talk about security we talk about
integrity and security of information so
one a few years ago we had the first
computers were started talking about
viruses those of us who already have a
few white hairs in my case I don't have
any hair at all well for eyes there was
a big thing then we had mobile phones
which at the beginning were only used to
speak but when they started having
applications instead of being attacked
as well so that was the next stage then
it went on to industrial devices and
program programmable automatons and then
we moved on to intensive care units in
hospitals and many other applications in
medicine and I think in the future the
next device there's going to be attacked
and they will give a lot of work it's
going to be us
said I was talking about fake news a lot
lately and yes yesterday there was a
video of Nixon the former president well
he was sending a message completely
different to the message that he would
have sent so I think the next devices
are going to be attacked as us are us um
artificial intelligence systems can
generate videos and texts that seem to
have been generated by human beings and
whenever I go to companies I mentioned
this if you
a video of your boss saying you have to
delete your hard drive from your
computer don't do it because you never
know if it's really your boss saying
that because right now with three
pictures we can have a full video of
someone saying whatever you want them to
say so this is concerning devices
everything to do with fake news bots all
that is going to give a lot of work in
this field and now concerning techniques
I've been looking into the different
speeches about IOT big tater and
artificial intelligence shows the fact
of working in this industries means that
you going to have surely a job because
for example in cybersecurity one of the
techniques that and it's being most used
is anomaly detection which is almost
like looking for something which is
really difficult to find so for example
predictive maintenance for machines or
fraud detection for credit cards so
studying cybersecurity will open up many
opportunities in other applications than
that said laughs I've got one minute
left thank you now we would like to give
the floor to all of you who are here
today in case you have any questions
either for all of our guests or all of
us all for someone in particular I don't
know if anyone would like to ask a
question yeah we have a question over
there hello good morning we are
currently studying a multi-platform
application development
[Music]
until we have this one-year
specialization in vocational training
for cybersecurity what do you recommend
we do can we do any of them training any
anything else well I'm going to answer
because there you were asking about
vocational training but I think anyone
else can answer I think other than what
you could do yourself and train and
teach yourself if you're talking about
formal education or certifications I
would recommend if you would like to
invest in certifications if you like
security for example because when it
comes to vocational training unless you
want to do an engineering degree if you
have time and if you like it and you can
even do a online or distance learning
but you can also train from
certification certified ethical hacker
is one I recommend very highly it's
something that you can study full it has
a very high level of technicality but it
can open many doors or just be
self-taught you know that's why I say
very often though most of the things
that I'm teaching right now I've learned
myself if you undergo formal training
that helps you structure your mind and
having some discipline but most of the
things that you learn are going to be
obsolete very quickly so you have to be
continuously training thank you very
much I don't know if we have another
question there's another one over here
hey good morning my question deals with
we've been hearing a lot of information
about technical requirements especially
concerning the different educational
paths but how about law communication
other areas which are actually linked to
this industry and how how is that going
to be looked into for education we're
very happy you asked that because that
was one of the things that we wanted to
talk about and something they had been
asked before I don't know if you know
would like to say something about how it
is true that security affects many
different disciplines and Alejandro I
think was saying that cyber crime is
very very profitable so we're finding
many different cases which are not just
physical but digital and we need lawyers
when in jurists in general who know
about this so what are we doing from the
point of view of a formal training to
complement those aspects have you
studying law congratulations because
with the new Data Protection Directive
and everything and everything that we've
been talking about at the end of day it
is data that we're talking about all the
time and there's many professional
opportunities and in our research group
there's a worldwide renowned specialist
in a behavioral economy because the
weakest link on the chain is always the
user you can have the highest security
from a technological point of view but
if that if the user doesn't know how to
do things if they didn't abide by all
the rules then you have prepared for
them then you have a really big issue so
out what this expert was analyzing its
what incentives you would have to give
the final user so that they don't decide
to just not abide by those security
rules I would like to also add I also
congratulate you if you're studying law
and if you want to specialize in cyber
security you're going to have a lot of
work because you can see there are loads
of regulations as many people who have
studied computer science and
telecommunications who do not know about
laws and
cannot deal with them you will probably
know that legislation in Spanish called
the same as in Italy France Japan United
States or India so there are many
companies who are facing many issues
when they try to export a product abroad
and the cyber security requirements are
completely different to the ones that we
have here so it's that easy so if you
study law and for example Polytechnical
University we have many postgraduate
studies of which lasts about six months
one year that would help you specialize
in cybersecurity if you wanted to so if
you do law you speak English and you
have a specialization in cybersecurity
then you will definitely find a job and
from in theory I would like to also say
that because this is a very
multidisciplinary area when it comes to
law education everything is
interconnected we need psychologists we
need trainers who know how to work in
their secure environments and raise
awareness so it is true that we have
more and more training every day not
only technical training but now we have
post graduates and a master's in cyber
security and industrial security law and
we also have vocational training and
university level training which is
focusing on the fact that any discipline
needs a cybersecurity component nowadays
because we do live in a hyper-connected
world for better or for worse and so
this is something that we're working on
and if unfortunately the specialization
the youth fight and at some point they
you if your degree it's not specialized
in cybersecurity it is important to have
some training as a complement both
vocational training or higher education
or certifications well we've run out of
time I would like to thank everyone
who's been here with me in the
roundtable today and finally I just
wanted I don't know if you could show
them
it's light I wanted to show you the
activities that we have in relation with
this roundtable today at cyber camp and
then some activities will continue over
time so you have employment and talent
forum and we will have 52 opportunities
30 companies and over 20 training
institutions so you can get information
and even apply to those job offers we
have over 250 openings in in this forum
you can have access to if those of you
who are lucky enough to be here not
those who are on streaming unfortunately
but add those who are here we have a
coaching corner on the second floor
where they're going to be able to assess
your CV if you have it with you they
will tell you how to make it more
attractive how to change it so that it's
it is attractive from employments we
also have training for job interviews
which my make us very nervous at the
beginning so that we can help you on key
points for those first interviews now
for those of you who are not still
looking for a job we also have some
activities which we have called show
your potential and we can tell you about
the things you can potentiate in for
your future when it comes to soft skills
volunteering sports teamwork which is
something that companies really do value
when looking for candidate we will also
have some practical workshops of
initiation to cyber security who are
interested they will take place in room
in the owl lab and for those of you who
do not find a spot because face is
limited you can also find them in
universities and vocational training
centers all around Spain we have them
all at the time we also have the cyber
Olympics the hackathon loads of activity
so we do invite you to invest
a little bit explore what we have and
for those of you who are interested in
this do take the plunge and if you see a
job offer that you could apply to do it
thank you very much
[Applause]
you