[Music]
video for the EEC cybersecurity
challenge I'm going not to I'm going to
try not to take too much time service to
my colleagues talk as well just want to
explain what the program is about how it
works and how it has evolved ever since
Anisa took over the project already four
years ago and what the future looks like
for this project or with planned and its
development so as you know nowadays we
do need cybersecurity experts there is a
great need
cyber experts not only in technical
areas but also in legal compliance and
many other fields this is a very
transversal area in every company so not
only I'm looking for technical knowledge
but also for knowledge of other fields
and also have different skills such as
public speaking being able to
communicate to manage and to presented
projects so things which are no
necessarily technical so other than
promoting technical knowledge we are
also trying to promote other types of
skills so saying public speaking
teamwork and so on just to give you some
context the ECSC came under the umbrella
of cybersecurity strategy in 2013 and we
got a mandate from the Commission to
organize a competition at a European
level for all countries at the time the
world really seven countries which were
partaking in national level competitions
and aneesa's idea was to give support to
those countries all right so the
competition could grow
aims of this challenge to promote CTF
national competitions in the same way
that we're doing it here in Spain
evidently organises their own national
competitions and from that they select
the people who will compete at European
level and what we're trying to do with
this is to get more and more nations
from the European Union to have training
programs food cams and participate in
this challenge and at the end as AV aim
is to manage to train cyber experts in
cybersecurity experts in every country
we think it's a very interesting project
to promote cybersecurity it's very
exciting it involves young people it
also entails some competition and at the
end of the day it puts the spotlight on
cybersecurity and it can help future
talents to actually work in
cybersecurity so we want to identify and
promote talent we want to develop
contact networks so at the cybersecurity
world is quite small compared to other
areas and fields and everyone knows each
other and so whoever takes part in the
ECSC my actually even come together in
the end and gets up together or be the
future leaders of cybersecurity target
audience is obviously student both high
school and university students
industries so that they can find future
workers for them and the public so then
through security they can see their
these activities are taking place any
contribute to this project basically
three parts I'm just saying that Anisa
does not organize the ec-series like the
Olympic Committee for the Olympics so we
try to give support to you the country
it's being organ
in this year it was in Romania but he
was England next year's going to take
things in Austria and so why Anissa
tries to do is to promote and to find
some continuity in the project starting
with a strategic support we can actually
provide because we can have a role to
bring transparency and equity which
other organizations might not have we
also support development and governance
framework and finally we give technical
support
I think strategic support that Anissa
gives to the project has been very
relevant indeed will see a graph later
on how the project has grown joined but
basically aneesa's content works in
every country through different bodies
as many other groups so through them we
try to get countries to join the
initiative and we try to help them with
any issue that may arise on and say why
are you know taking part can we help you
so that you can actually eventually take
that or would you like to take part as
an observer so that you can enter the
cycle and start seeing how we work so
this approach has been quite successful
as next year we have at least three new
countries which have already taken
places of service and just about to
start a compact activity another one of
legs with which leaders trying to
support is governance framework through
a steering committee and trying to do we
create the government structure which is
the steering committee and this
committee is the one that is going to
design how the project evolves and from
Anisa what we try is to give it cannot
annuity to have a baseline for the
project those decision-making is always
transparent but it is fair
there are two meetings every year we try
to support the steering committee or the
Syrian committee is trying to support
the National Organization we foster
collaboration between different nations
because cybersecurity for example in
Spain is very advanced but there are
other countries which didn't even have a
training structure or challenge
structure or cybersecurity so that
knowledge that we have in Spain in other
countries such as Germany or England
they have very strong structures there's
a very strong foundations they can help
the countries which and also advanced in
this sense and that is one of the things
that the steering committee is trying to
promote when it comes to technical
support we try to do is to help the
organising country challenges we have a
school board which receives for the
first honest yeah and it has been
improved dramatically this year with all
the ideas that we gathered through
Soviet service you feedback but also
with the eighties from the steering
committee we also try to promote
information exchange tours and we are
going to have a new one will be launched
soon guidelines and guides for experts
and for people who need it we promote
the winning team so that they go to
Brussels and present in front of the
Commission similar and we also try to
have coordinating policies our public
affairs team are always there during the
event they try to program and schedule
meetings to share pictures to share
videos to have everyone aligned and send
the same message during the challenge
and now I'm going to show you another
video this is a surprise for the a goal
and I saw can we have the second video
please it's very short it is what the
challenge looks like the team knows
already because they've been there this
is something that was recorded with a
drone
and for all those young people who might
be in the room
I hope this draws your attention and the
you will be with us in one and two years
right to the event in Bucharest took
place in the second biggest building in
the world the Parliament building
Belgian Belgium didn't take part in the
incident we had three new countries and
two observers motor and Finland we had
over 200 participants and sponsors and
team leaders finally the winner was
Romania and Italy runners-up and finally
all children which who are going to be
the organizers here you can see their
impact on social network there isn't a
big difference compared to the previous
year but there are less negative
feedback which is already something good
and this is how the project has evolved
as was mentioning before since - 2016
when Anissa started getting involved in
the project business increased
exponentially and we're hoping as I said
that two three needs teams join next
year and also we need to find financing
for the participating teams so that they
keep on coming because sometimes
depending on the sponsors teams make it
or not so we're trying to create some
sort of financing to obey so that
countries can actually have access to it
and have at least some sort of basic
trainings and boot camps for teams to
train and then take part in the
challenge so we have already agreed on
the next few challenges this is a really
good presentation business start because
when we are trying to find sponsors and
year and we tell someone that you
already have five events scheduled no
one can say that this is going to be a
one-off
so from Anissa we're trying to have an
international competition which means
outside of Europe obviously the
continental intercontinental competition
we have already started making contact
with people from early aid thanks to
Spain we've got contacts with Japan with
Australia and we're going to try and
have an intercontinental competition for
following the years actually we hope
this will take place in Greece which is
where Anisa headquarters at and finally
next year the challenge will take place
in real Vienna between 3rd and 7th
November and we hope to see some of you
and what does the future hold the future
of Annisa with the challenge is to keep
supporting new countries to take part
the challenge try to help logistically
the organising country and everything
they need be it's quarter it's being
happier challenges be it having speakers
unlined with other activities from the
Commission's such as woman for cyber
which is a program that is going to be
launched very soon from any service to
get women involved in cyber security in
general and we hope that the challenge
will be an interesting program to foster
women joining cyber security cyber
security mob as well and cybersecurity
strategy national cybersecurity strategy
as well and as I was saying before
creating European team Team Europe that
can partake in competitions and
intercontinental competitions as we were
saying thank you very much I hope this
gives you a clearer idea now of what's
going on other than what's been done
here in Spain and I think this is very
motivating both from a European and
national point of view even further than
that thank you very much Thank You
Adrian if you'd like to ask him
questions we'll do that at the end so we
can hear everybody first do manrique is
going to talk now he's in the same area
as me and in theory he has experience in
organizing international competitions of
cybersecurity challenges and he's
involved initiative to promote young
talent and to help people have a career
in cyber security
he's our representative in the executive
committee in the ECSC since 2018 Thank
You Tatiana for the presentation and the
introduction it's a pleasure to be here
once again to be here talking about the
ECSC we're in the final phase of the
Year CyberLink fix we've just had that
and I'm going to talk about a move over
to the positive side yeah we've got the
presentation up now I'd like to talk
about four things the role of Antibes
and the competition it's a decisive role
in different areas the journey that
we've had of the last five years for
ECSC
and the recent competition in October
and probably the most interesting part
is how to participate in in this and be
part of the selected team I've been
working hard on this since
Monday people have been asking me when
the selection will begin and what the
requirements are and I don't want it to
be have any doubts about that
I hope it's interesting for you and
Alejandro and Adrian are the present
part of the selection that but you are
the future because the fact that you're
in cyber camp that you've been in the
cyber Olympics or in the final of the
competition tomorrow
means that you're in a good position to
be part of that pre selection of
candidates to be part of the national
team and the next next year they will
participate in Vienna in Austria in the
European challenge for cyber security so
I will begin by explaining a sea-based
role its role is to create the national
team the people in the European
competition that is so how did that they
do it through national competitions and
once the team has been selected then in
theory has to train the team we'll talk
about this a little bit later on and the
purpose is to prepare the team the
national team for the competition we
also accompany the national team as
tatiana was saying we've been in it for
a few years and last year was in london
this year in bucharest and it's a very
positive experience we'll talk a bit
more about this later on we're also
members of the steering committee there
in committee and I'll talk about that in
a bit and in 2017 we had a dual
challenge
it was participating in the competition
and organizing it organizing the
European cyber suit key challenge in
Malaga so what's the steering committee
it's not a very visible work
it's back-office work but it's a group
that
made up of all the countries
participating in the competition but we
do have every decisive role it's a great
commitment because we are very aligned
with the objectives of the competition
we have been working over the last few
years in on a number of initiatives
events and support programs to identify
talented cybersecurity and we have a
number of shared objectives with Anissa
and in terms of this competition we add
value I think to the steering committee
because where we have experience in
organizing events on a national event
and all particularly competitions many
of the countries that are thinking about
organizing the challenge do not have
this experience and they ask us for
advice
for exampie for example the Italians
were thinking about whether or not to
event to participate in the event and be
organisers and they were asking us about
logistical matters and matters of budget
and that's a very valuable advice that
we can give them this it's also a very
important room in in theory there's a
team working there we have a technical
office for European projects an office
for proposals for finance and in the
instance we are leaders for other
companies there's a European Director
for cybersecurity and we participate on
the legal side of that and so we have a
solvent we're a solvent in entity and
greatly committed to the competition we
also have the role of selecting the team
as I was saying so how do we do this we
do this through national competitions
that happen in cyber camp cyber Olympics
hackathon and the individual
competitions we also have grants through
different conferences in Spain and the
winners of their CTF company
I have the right to go into the final
phase of the CTF individual phase in
cyber camp then the other thing is the
training we've been working on this for
the last few years it goes over a
two-week period and it deals with
technique and soft skills we prepare the
team when the technique to go into the
competition there are different
categories of challenges so we try and
find their strengths and weaknesses in
the team with the aim of getting a
balanced team that can have good results
in competitions then we have the soft
skills which make you a better
professional should we say it's working
in team managing stress conflicts and
number of skills that are required by
companies also in cybersecurity and this
makes a quite a difference in the
selection processes so to get an idea of
what this training is like I'm going to
show you this which is the training
session that we have this year
[Music]
it just wasn't just the training it was
the presentation video for that sir me
that opens the competition in Bucharest
and I'd like to go over the journey for
Spain in this competition it all began
in 2015 in Switzerland when a teen team
of young people that came from cyber
camp 2014 a long time ago it was first
one in Madrid and they went to
Switzerland to compete as Adrian was
saying it was a kind of a European Cup
for young talents in cybersecurity and
they were more and more national
competitions in different countries and
aneisa decided to arrange a competition
and to bring together all the talent in
Europe we did fairly well we were in
fourth position I think there were six
countries at the time in 2015 in 2016 we
had learnt a lot and we were able to win
we had a ray decisive technique right
from the start and people like or her
join the team people like a colossal
maria marcos and it truly was a very
satisfying year in 2017 we were the
winners from the previous year and we
took the double win home with us we had
a double challenge there to compete and
to arrange and also organized the cyber
gap tatiana will say it was a very
difficult in busy year in 2018 last year
it was my first year and we were in 11th
position
you might not see that because
originally we were in third position but
on the second day a number of situations
came across and that left us in 11th
position but I don't think it was a
reflection of the team role Resco is
here with us today in the front row
actually I've got all my bosses here in
the front row so this is like an exam
for me but he's the person who in a FIBA
has most believed in this project he had
to go early last time but this is a
little bit of a summary of our
participation in the European
competitions we have to tell you about
what happened this year just a few
months ago we were in Bucharest
competing and as the brand was saying it
was in the palace for the Parliament in
Bucharest it was a great place to be the
second largest government building after
their Pentagon and people who say that
you could see the building from the moon
but it's really quite amazing it's huge
and impressive there were some political
issues there specifically at the time so
it was a rather delicate and we were
there competing at the time so the
competition this year was a capture the
Jeopardy and exploiting and so on and
there were new categories like machine
learning probability mathematics and
radio honking this is an important part
of the competition last year we it is an
escape room and this is kind of
different everything else and it changes
every year there's flexibility for the
organising country
and it's really very interesting we had
dynamic scoring this year the number of
results depending on the participation
of each team and also the presentation
had to go in front of the jury and talk
to the jury and talk about one of the
challenge that they had resolved during
the competition there were 35 challenges
over two days some for the first day and
some for the second so this stops them
competing overnight and have some time
off the team members and I wanted to
show you a summary using a video and I
think this will show you exactly what
happened there in Bucharest
[Music]
[Applause]
so this is a summary video of this year
and how the screens gone I'd like to say
hello to one friend of mine who is on
the steering committee in Bucharest she
was in the video so anything else I need
to tell you about my home this image
says a lot they often say that an image
is better than words
and this image is a summary of what
happened in the competition and we ended
up in 13th position at the back this man
well Blanco and one of the coaches San
Diego my colleague and I'm there on the
left
this was midway through the competition
and we were out of the possibility of
winning but we you also learn from all
of this and that's what we have to take
away from this I'm sure that MTB we did
things wrong the model that we have
currently needs to evolve so that
spanking get back up there at the top in
the position that it deserves and I'd
like to reflect on this a little bit and
talk about how the competition has
evolved over the last few years there
has been a change in the quality of it
significantly there are lots of company
countries supporting their teams
training them the people from Poland
last year were six and now they were
fourth this year and other countries are
giving their team special training and
coaching a qur'anic from italy have not
done many CTF but they
did qualify for their for the
competition and they were seven they had
a lot of people supporting them so the
commitment of each team and each country
is increasing every year there are
creasing lis more resources and each
country tries to take their best people
because this competition which began as
a bit of fun should we say and to
promote talent has become a little bit
more professional now and countries
taking things very seriously very often
and this in particular I heard something
that this is like Eurovision Spain is
not what it used to be in fact behind
the competition there is a lot of
dedication a lot of efforts people take
this very seriously and we don't like
losing we are also competitive in this
field we've learnt a lot from this we're
going to try and improve and take Spain
back up to the place where they this
maybe we could talk about in the
question around but I'm just going to
make it short but how do you get into
these Spanish national team you have to
be under 25 you have to have taken
national a part in national particular
composite competitions being tribal
Impex yeah
cyber careful hackathon some
requirements we need to have five good
news and five senior pre selection we
have to have this into account as well
Junius is 18 to 20 and seniors is 20 to
25 there's a pre selection stage like to
have more people pre-selected so
everyone has assessment for every pan
stick and once we
have a profile every candidate then we
choose the final team they come to in
FIBA and they train for G so what
benefits can you get out of this it's a
unique opportunity
you can share experiences with over 200
young fans from over 20 countries
European countries you will also have a
chance to complete part of the national
team and you will be able to train many
opportunities in gue German abroad you
can even compete in one the I'm going to
now give the floor to of today thank you
[Applause]
thank you very well no one could talk
more than me in Phoebus but he talks
more than me and faster to my right we
have Spanish national team 15 people in
that team and here at the Prado Malini
is senior in 2017 so he has been a
winner of the European 2018-2019 as well
and then we have an economy title who is
new to the team I would like to ask you
a few questions that you were not
expecting Diego prepared them so if he
hasn't told you about it it's his fault
I would like you to be an inspiration to
all those who would like to get into
this field of cybersecurity and I can
little tell us what did you stacking
interesting about this well since I was
very young I was always interested in
that
and computer science and it's true that
I've always liked gaming I was the
proper game I was always in denial
service attacks that I really liked
seeing and I was always curious about
how these things happened why they
happened and then I started hearing
about Wi-Fi Wi-Fi asshats web so you
start seeing a bit of everything really
because you don't know how things work
and you eventually find yourself doing
something that really draws your
attention and buys the category I am in
right now you start doing challenges
taking part in challenges you learn
little by little because obviously you
are not born knowing everything and you
learn something new in every competition
and that's how it works
other than you are also a professional
so when did you hobby become a
profession how did you manage in great
part thanks to this because this
experience is not only important and
it's not only satisfying on a personal
level but it gives you high visibility
as well it gives you also a contact
network you start going into the world
of cyber security which is we were
saying it's not very big and so it gives
you a chance to get people to know you
and to show your work so I think in a
way my current situation is due to
thanks to this and I am currently
working in blue live and I am in the red
team department that so what would you
recommend to a young person who wants to
specialize in cyber security doesn't
know how to go about it I would
recommend obviously poppy
studied the underwent training they
found a technical area they're
interested in and that they devote a lot
of time to that area because I was at
the end of the day where you won't make
a difference where you can start making
a difference and getting visibility
because if even if you cannot do
classroom courses you can do it online
because when you to know how to do
something but you devote time to it
until you manage to do it I think that
is very important you have that kind of
mindset yeah I think we're here saying
at the end of the day these competitions
do serve the purpose of helping you to
get acquainted with this kind of
learning if you someone who's
competitive who likes to win challenges
then this really helps and in my case
it's easier to learn like this because
you see a challenge you want to make
care you don't know how to do where you
find your documentation
you either work it out so you have to
wait for solutions to be polished and
that's where you really really learn and
obviously afterwards you have to learn
you have to do your formal training to
learn new techniques find documentation
but if we need to help you learn because
it makes it easier and it makes it more
fun and also to find what do you like
best because yeah you studying
engineering yeah I am doing engineering
right now a university also huge
mentioned that I'm you know before and
there is a nickname which cheese think
the main technical skills we have talked
about soft skills we've talked about
teamwork team building public speaking
speaking English but how about technical
skills what is the key to have good
performance for two dates in the
competition because
we have to bear in mind that when the
competition lasted one day we were doing
better but with two days it's becoming
more difficult for us well when it comes
to technical skills it really depends on
which category you are focusing on
because it isn't it is impossible to do
everything I'm not even talking about
cybersecurity I'm talking about CTS only
I think such skills is really really
important especially stress management
and also how you work with the rest of
the team what kind of relationship you
establish what communication policies
you establish what mechanism you have to
say listen I really cannot do this so
I'm going to move on to the next thing
that I think is what really determines
your act from in longer competitions
yeah I also think in order to be able to
do 16 hours in two days of competition
eight hours a day that you spend almost
completely in front of a screen I think
as I was saying other than technical
skills which we understand everyone
asked what advanced technical skills if
they are on the team also has a big role
to play the way someone is the character
because when people are focused or doing
something it is really difficult or
people didn't like to therefore their
attention to be drawn to something else
I face bit with Adrian is saying it's
how you work with the team
[Music]
patience with the you are persistent
because if you want someone who gets
frustrated at the moment something
doesn't work out then you will end up
not really getting any challenge because
you something that you will never be
able to solve the first time you attempt
it you have to try and try on it so I
think the people who do Bessa challenges
of those who like challenges who patient
and never stop trying until they make it
or even have the ability of say okay I'm
going to put this two aside and I'm
going to try and do another one and once
I've done that one I'll get back to this
one but yeah it's it's something about
soft skills is what su was saying no
Diego mentioned that really other teams
are improving that the level is higher
how do you think in the BB can help you
because we are the ones who are going to
select teams how can we help you improve
how have the other teams improved and we
have not I would imagine that training
is very important how we organize
training and for training to be more
constant rather than for it to be all
condensed in two weeks I think we should
have continuous challenges not only
because we would practice more but also
because we would practice practice more
as a team because at the other day this
is a team challenge everyone is focused
on their own computer but you are
playing as a team and I think that is
key and is something that should be
worked on a bit more
yeah I agree with with again because
it's not just two weeks or two days it
is something that has to be continuous
when whenever there's a CTF wish you'd
take part as a team if next week there's
another one then we'll shoot again take
part as a team if there's no continuity
then in two weeks is really
really difficult to proper training for
the challenge unless you have a method
background so you need constant work
some people might not be have much
practice or have not taken part in that
many challenges so they probably would
need to have more challenges to take
part in more challenges will do a CTF
this week then the next week we have
tests or you have to read this documents
we have to process these techniques I
think yeah continuity definitely improve
everyone's abilities and I think it
would improve our overall results the
other has to take have you taken down
yet that is what one of the first
lessons learned and we spoke to the
Germans who are very very
straightforward they invest a lot in
preselection but then during the year we
train constantly on their own they said
that most of them didn't even meet until
the first day of the competition but I
am certain that what they say about
constant work is definitely necessarily
necessary we need to find signs of ways
of taking part in CDF's every week so
the team members get to know each other
and start working in an efficient manner
right so now they're all were saying
what we how we see it from the inside
but now tell us why were you 13 what did
you end up 13 in these challenge well
about I mean
saying that there is change in
generations there were many good teams
before but how do you see that but it is
true that the team members are changing
oh it is his last year
in the competition by the way from my
point of view the teams that take part
in CTF in Spain it's true that they the
older teams play less and there are not
many new players in for example we've
seen the case of the Italians with
macaroni and their philosophy of who is
part of the team is very different here
it's just people who are passionate
about a cybersecurity and they chose on
their own decide to form a team whereas
at hockey Ronnie for example they have a
team of teams from university so
universities create CTF teams that
aren't already very advanced and then
that gives you a mechanism of natural
handover from generation to generation
because everyone starts in the
university teams and then they have a
really really good team of teams and I
think that is something that we should
really think about and incentivize as a
country now about what happened this
year in the competition I think it was
mostly to do with the fact that
specifically this year the my half in a
category where we would have needed to
have someone who knew more about but
also training it really has nothing to
do with the competition looks like three
four years ago and what it is like now
because it's a much more professional
continuous training is very important
many other countries are doing it and
we're not and that makes a big
difference because they are much better
prepared for the challenge than we are
maybe in the past when they were leave
less countries and they were not taking
it so seriously maybe the innate
challenge and challenge wasn't off but I
don't think it's the case nowadays well
I can tell that from here and fever is
really committed you will see tomorrow
it'd be individual city a final we have
had many new things that you will see
tomorrow I'm not going to give them away
but we are really trying to get onto
these new tendencies categories
challenges well you'll see tomorrow I
don't know if the audience has any
questions before we open the question
round at these two people just a small
part of the team but I would like for
the rest of the team to come on the
stage because they have been listening
and they have they had to come today
although they're competing tomorrow and
they should be training by the year
today so please run round of applause
for our national team here we stand up
would you like to name the people
introduce them from here from curry as
well you can use the nicknames if you
want to local from Cordova avidin
via the Leeds family from Toledo
I'll go from Alicante I'm from Madrid
Yolanda from Cordova and Pablo from
Salamanca and you're thee from Valencia
[Music]
Danielle who is from Asturias believes
in Valencia people have not been able to
make it today some members of the team
these are our year's national team we
have many people behind them last year
we had 10 people and I would like to say
there's these future professionals when
you may leave the national team they
start becoming they become mentors or
will take them to different competitions
so and then you know going away from us
so didn't try to run away any questions
now make the most of it because that
they are the future protectors of our
cyberspace no questions
can I have my professor I can just ask a
question to a member of the national
team thank you thank you and like I'm
here here's the first girl in the
national team we've had others in the
post-election stage she is the only girl
that has in class that has classified
this year and I would just wanted her to
say hello I'm not going to ask anything
and she has to compete tomorrow so just
tell us your experience well my name is
Yolanda my experience has been
absolutely wonderful and I encourage
women to do this because this is a
unique experience and I think we have
exactly the same abilities as men to do
this and I will do this again any time
thank you
[Applause]
I'll village boy stur he is also quite
shy so let's see what he says I think
this is really a very good opportunity
because you get to know people who share
your passions and it's a way of finding
emerging talent in Europe so I was
encourage anyone who's interested in
cybersecurity to enroll to show their
potential and the talent and become part
of the national team thank you very much
and you've got the floor say where you
come from where you're going and what
you're going to do tomorrow well I come
from Cadiz and as my team members were
saying I would encourage anyone to take
part in the CTF and we need
professionals in cyber security what
have you been doing today with cyber
Olympics I've been accompanying the
teams that have won the cyber Olympics
he's been one of the mentees of the team
so as you see we keep promoting talent
from a fee-based anyone else who would
like to say something
ah we're being kicked out and we've run
out of time thank you very much
congratulations mr. Birnam indras so
whilst they're having their photo taken
we're going to continue the program the
schedule for today we've got one last
talk to end the day today day three
we're going to tell you all about it in
just a few moments please don't go away
[Music]
[Applause]