[Music]
thank you for being here we're going to
start with workshop for those who have
sides of the auditorium with her father
I am known security I've been working on
this bill for several years I'm open we
almost everything security exploiting
we're going to start with a very easy
exploit in order for you to understand
how exploit work because on many
occasions we take some code from our
repository and we start combining it we
don't even know how it works
since nobody checks the code and we just
simply want to obtain the code it
doesn't work so what do we do let's
start then with the from the beginning
will speak first about vertical and then
about a spectral and melt down which are
very similar inspector I'm sure you have
with it it has been useful it has
affected their CPU it has a slowly down
and it has regardless of the operating
system that we use whether it is Linux
Windows or any other because the problem
is in the microprocessor so people in
the end end up buying any laptop and I'm
going to talk about it and I'm going to
mention new things on the field so that
somehow we can use the hardware in a
secure way so without further ado let's
start with their to go who are familiar
with their to come it is one of the rare
occasions when I see so many just a few
ok is a privilege escalation we are a
user in a system I do not have any
permissions so I am like an intern at a
company but I want to become the
administrator the administrator user so
we need to do some magic in order to
obtain more privileges this is a very
old ability because it started in 2016
and it affected all kernel in Linux
based
systems including Android things these
we convert our device even if it that's
the objective we're going to see all
these steps you know the to understand
why and how it works as you see on the
screen problem ahead of us
Co Co W is a copy and right there for
Nevada
Apple they're in there so we need to
understand the vulnerability in all the
20 standard steps that we're going to
use the ball for Specter and full
meltdown as consequences we could modify
any kind of protected files just et Cie
password any kind of file as if we were
a user or root user
we have several POCs you can download
them from GD hi usually people are
familiar with this but they need a
workshop in order to understand all
these steps usually manufacturers launch
some patches and the vulnerability
disappears let's start with memory
mapping of file usually typically go we
are going to do it with C language in a
very easy way and we all already have
their code written for you not to have a
typo error so let's see how to map Linux
bases
file innovate remapped the memory we're
going to use the system called memory
map we can call the system in order to
map device let's say memory device maybe
to write an a to read it it is just
opening it and instead of working
directly on the device I use it in the
memory very simple piece of code wavelet
and then we go to the standard system
called I guess you are familiar with
obscene language it is basically like we
do not see you at home in one of the
lines you see the number let's imagine
we open HTC host fire we have the
possibility to open it in read-only mode
or in writing mode I think nothing I
haven't said nothing so far we know that
when opening a file there is a system of
permission if the while only has a
read-only mode for the user for example
the ETP password even if I try to make
it you have to open it if I want to open
it from right in a street world the
system is going to tell me that I can't
because this subsystem of permissions is
going to prevail however I could create
memory in line to zero
okay memory map
we have I could remember these
operations we have the print limpiar we
want we can clean the code back it was
if we hadn't declared the emails we take
you back to the operating system to boil
in their regimental Lopez la function ma
map electro defeated hola Dora
we're trying to understand little
function ma map memory map not what are
we going to do the beginning who is then
the kind of protection it must match
with the permission of the file device
if I'm an user and I'm trying to open
PTC because WT with read mode I should
use the read protection because of the Y
Z operating system that will tell me hey
what are you doing you're trying to ride
on this file he were override
name in the Memorial okay da ba ba la
memoria compartir de rien and they may
have both memory modules either shared
memory or private memory this kind of
memory yes I wanna say Savannah's a pool
IGAs will be carved on the last names
Pericles slides are going to be
published I will tell you after the
workshop where to download this
PowerPoint but how does a mapped memory
word a shared much memory we have
several processes we are using multitask
operating systems and we need to map the
memory somehow but what happens with the
physical memory for each one of the
processes it is thought that the
physical memory it's theirs that's why
we have the describers on the tables
within the operating system which make
the process thing to be it is unique but
what happens in the operating system
let's imagine you have a first process
with a virtual memory on the second on
the right part we have a second process
with a virtual memory we have a file
descriptor and we open the same file
both pointers will point to the same
place word file is in the physical
memory logically the operating system
wouldn't open a limited physical memory
and feudin wouldn't be logical to open
to different this script describers when
we're not going to do a lot we just want
to read the data in that bias what
francium in classes the case of the LTC
passwd so what's different map una
memoria Mia
privada I tell the operating system I
want to use my private memory so the
file is going to be assigned to private
memory just using mat provide private
the changes are not going to be visible
for all the processes but the content of
the original memory is going to be
copied and the private memory where I
will be able to do whatever I want so
not here's how the physical memory works
between process 1 & 4 & process 2
there's going to be a copy of that
memory of the people so that with my
profit memory I can work on whatever I
want if I want to modify something I
will be able to do so but if I'm going
to discard or if I'm going to discard
the changes in the file it should be
copied on the original memory and then
permissions are going to tell me you can
do whatever you to do in your private
memory but obviously those changes those
modifications in the original file are
not going to be copied into the original
file because the operating system is
going to prevent it from happening this
is the theoretical part for you to
understand the magic we're going to use
and then
getting working you know that you have a
so we're going to try to do a small
exercise first of all we're going to
take a code we're going to try to mock
up a file to do if you have the virtual
machine it has the port 22 open so that
you can use any laptop because if we had
it with say 12 books he would have been
more complicated to use these consoles
I'm using DLL in here you have all the
microcode and in the first one we find
dear to go demos which look what we have
here we have the a map that C
corresponds to the file that I have
mentioned earlier
super easy let's see what do we have
I'm going to open the TC has W beans we
are root user we open this file with the
read/write in mode the operating system
is going to check out for the root user
is that correct but I do it mini
straighter user then I could read those
ten bytes I could write on the memory
and I could community modifications so
see oh I'm sorry
that's wrong that's
so rude can you say it properly
do you need a bigger fund okay mucho
porque una empresa there is a user which
I am going to use which is overcome
cyber camp with nothing not to open
several terminals prepare these user
reveal could open anyone let's see I'm
going to open another console it's this
age come on up nothing I told him up at
the console is ready to work on an 80
mode so that you don't have any problem
to access it I meant each other nobody I
was that pale I was told not to turn
around but I think I need it
[Music]
hey are you okay so I don't know if you
can see it right I D it is an user
without any privilege but if I want to
see the content of the file et Cie
passwd we see everything but we cannot
do anything else obviously I'm not
allowed to write
okay yes so I just have one split and
let's do one thing the code that I have
here the M the M map is going to be
copied off Cybercom amberle elessedil
appears l provid are you say welcome
then this is the owner yes I've come
home so I become plaintiff I'll come
they know me mmm up he comment a
logically I have my Cybercom my em up I
look at the code again I am going to try
to open it as read and write e mode and
I'm going to try to change it let's say
GCC - Oh name mmm out and let's compile
the source do you think it is going to
work it shouldn't because if it does
work then it's like winning the lottery
this is segment breach it's telling me
hey you have tried to do
something which is not logical according
to your permissions so I'm not allowed
to do so this is the normal behavior of
the operating system however let's see
these technique of copy-on-write they
see o w we have the same physical memory
page two pointers which point at the
same card if they have identical content
but if I want to map to map it into my
private memory it involves they see owt
copy so I take it I will have another
pointer below which is pointed to
another part of the physical memory
which has nothing to do with the
original one it is way below so let's
see how we can do it this is the whole
process we're going let's see how we can
map it with many problems I'm going to
open this file
okey and notice something here mr.
Latura
yeah CUDA did I write I said read and
write mode and I think that's what going
to be the mistake I think that was a
mistake we could assign the modifier R
or we could change it for the brief
change it to our read-only mode we could
just write that let's follow these steps
that the operating system is given us we
can write whatever one
what did we say what we're going to do
what would I need to change you know
that for me to allow me to write allow
me to write or to allow me to read
are you familiar with this okay I like
the other way but just okay that's gonna
enable us to open it we said these had
to my with the previous step right okay
I'm going to leave broad right in order
for me to be able to write but look at
here map shared what are the two
pointers in the physical memory they are
pointing at the same point and I'm going
do something instead of writing map
shared I can say mobile private do you
think I can do it we have seen
definition of the function I can write
this and what is happening here one
there will be coping I will be able to
do whatever I want with my coping but
when two the two pointers go back to the
same place I want to be able to do what
I wanted but while I have this copy I
can use it as I want you can see there
is a warning that we don't care we if
it's if we are compiling it is the K for
us to ignore that warning are you
following me okay
this is a bridge a second membrane so
this is not working demo Bharati
we're trying to do something that the
operating system don't like because
there are some privilege systems he's
there identification systems and the
operating system doesn't like what we're
doing
okay let's see if now we can advance a
little bit let's imagine I have read
only mode file he waives permissions for
everything to match correctly and then
I'm going to open it with the indicator
read-only and I'm going to use the
option prod renoise the operating system
is going to allow me to do so because
both match it is not what I did
previously in this case the operating
system sees that both of them match and
they match with the permissions within
the file now I shouldn't be able to
write on a read-only mode memory but if
I'm up in the private memory I could
write on the file copied and I could use
any function the road map open any file
both permissions I have my private and I
see the process memory with India from
and with el-sheikh I could go to a
certain position I could write I could
do whatever I wanted
what's the limit to what extent when I
tell the operating system to discard the
memory and pointers a point at the same
card it's going to say that permissions
do not allow me to do so how are you
ok I'm going to copy these to the home
of the users have become a copyright
owner cyber come if you want you can
copy the whole folder you can I change
them up a meal okay this is a room map
file it is mine I'm no one according to
my idea and I'm going to date these
files if you realize it is exactly the
same but instead of having this file I'm
going to instead of adding a file that I
created I'm going to open directly the
phi e TC has WD it is a system file but
it works in the same way this is in
read-only mode
I have the pro-trade but not his this is
the difference from before because
both matches and I have a private memory
and the rest I don't care it is a still
advanced in the file and to show it on
screen then we need to clean here when
we compile let's see what what happens
when we compile the same everything is
compiled and now okay I maybe I'm going
too fast but I would like for those who
have a laptop you know to do it
sometimes a whole workshop that's five
or six hours if we describe properly all
their steps but let's try raise your
hand if it is working okay one person
good the operating system has underlying
information it has open the file
et Cie pass WD it has copied copied it
in my route private memory where I come
in Lane five and then here I have
managed to change in the root part SEO
is bad Oh meeting your mother I have
imagined wise advice a system call in
all then to leave the pointer in the
block of physical memory corresponding
to the original file
system has realized okay you do not have
any right information so the root is
going to stay this way okay if we can
address it at least we can play on a
private memory but what is it what can I
use it for for nothing but actually
there is an operation called my vise we
have copied the mapped memory the page
table has been updated we have written
on the memory but not taste is how
important it is it says that the steps
are not do not have an atomic nature
which means that they can be interrupted
we do not need to follow a b3 in order
at a certain point I can interrupt this
process and do whatever I want I could
do a C and then B and then D and this is
precisely what is going to create a
potential race condition which will
enable me to exploit I have a my device
function it is going to indicate that
you need to leave the pointer where it
was in the beginning by half but I have
another function that is enabling me to
write on my part of my private memory
so if steps are not atomic I could be
writing changes on the one side and on
the other side I could be calling the
mud
system and maybe at a certain point that
is race condition at a certain point the
operating system is not following and we
can commit to the original point we
could commit those changes to the
original pointers those changes that I
have written on my private memory and
that's what data collection so here I
can say I am NOT going to need that
memory we are going to be able to invoke
it little by little so this step is not
atomic
it may be called the first step but I
can call it after the second one after
the fourth one whenever I want to and I
know they succeed what could we do well
so the idea would be to have a first
thread in which we would write and we
would have a second thread ruling out
the previous mapped memory and if we are
lucky in a race condition in which there
are so many cycles we will reach a point
in which the changes that I've done in
my private art will remain in my
original file and in order to do so well
we've created the user already so let's
imagine that here for example in this
case I'm a normal user
I'm Cybercom I have user ID Abel I'm
able to move in a normal file and I can
look for things in a normal file I'm
going to have our normal ID that will be
one thousand ten thousand I don't know
what's going to be and I don't know even
what group I am but I can look for aid
if I start changing this in the threat
in which I can write within the memory
in my private part
if I can change zeros if I can change
1,000 by zero zero zero zero and at some
point Matt Weiss commits the change in
this race condition what's going to be
the result in their file come on
the room is almost fooled it will be
kept it will be kept let's see if that
happens for real
well basically this is just a small
exploit in which here for example you
can see the threat what's interesting to
us so in order to create their race
conditions I'm going to create a thread
the mat bite and the right here I'm
going to have two threads
my vise and right what I'm going to do
next in one thread I'm going to look for
my user for example it would work just
by changing the user ID that I have but
I can also change the group the
description anything I wanted and that
just involves writing in that thread in
the other thread the only thing that I
have to do is saying this memory is
ruled out commit this memory and leave
the pointer where it is so the race
condition is executed and then
automatically we are going to use what
we've written so let's see if that's so
we are user without privileges I have
here an exploit we also can see their
code in the root e so if I'm a user that
downloads an exploit execute C it is
execute is
composites I'm not going to easily come
because I have to truly find out who I
am say for example here this is looking
for a user that's not me that ISA is not
me that user is the last user I sent for
the last person that did an exploit it's
not always going so much to what you
want to but if you really understand the
code of what you're handling you're
going to be able to do anything you want
to so what are we going to do I have a
user ID a certain user ID for example
here I'm the user Cybercom I have four
servers because I'm the user number 1000
1001 1004 with four digits I can even be
more specific
when I'm within their files but here I'm
just opening the file for the mapped
memory as we've seen it before and this
is the threat that I've mentioned before
so here in order to find Who I am
I'm going to search within the file even
though I meet with inside the memory I'm
going to look for this hyper camp you
say I'm going to see that I have an ID
number of 1000 was it the same one as
before yes it was so I think so so this
is right so let's shake example here I
can see that I'm used to number 1000
maybe in a real system I can be there
user number 3000 or maybe it can have
just three digits instead of four but
this is just for you to understand
with moral code that's behind all of
these don't give up here so again these
are the changes so this is going to look
for cyber command is going to r02 is
going to search within the map of the
private memory the part of cyber county
with related to the number of 1000 and
in the other thread that i've mentioned
before that memory is going to be ruled
out let's see if that's true
now we're going to compile it before
compiling it we have to use the library
because as I'm working with threads I
need to work through the library of the
threads so let's compile let's create
the exploit and now we're going to
combine with f3 so now this is compile
before executing I mean ID mine I'm the
intern I'm the intern and now I'm going
to execute the exploit
I didn't write any duration in the
thread they are executing themselves I
have a lot of race conditions so we
don't need to keep it for a long time
it's running so maybe it could happen
very fast just in the first or second
execution I'm going to click on ctrl C
for mine now
the route and I so now when I'm right
when I write I attack the ID number one
of cyber can exploit has failed are you
sure the exploit has failed are you
wandering through an El Sistema
mountain go away when we are inside the
system I'm going to keep the original
the original mission but if I exit exist
the system and then I enter again in the
system as Cybercom without changing the
password when I write the password you
know it is something we are here do you
think there is something weird is
something here which is not for the
cyber camp you sir what can we see here
the mighty we've done now I'm a Rooter
turn into a group to change the group or
to change the description do you want me
to do in the system
something evil maybe this is not
something that we would do all real
conditions if the system would be part
this shouldn't work if the system was
positive should shouldn't work so what
can we do with this well in the end this
is just about having some basic
some basic knowledge and understanding
what there is within this code to start
playing of example so let's live to
Timothy to another game it's exercise
let's do an exercise so I have the
exploit so imagine that no I can write I
want to change the password of the files
CTC shadow two one two three four five
six so let's make it be let's try the
newspapers to write about us and now I'm
joking this is for educational purposes
just educational purposes of course so
let's do this exercise could we do it we
change all the users with credentials in
the file
ATC shadow to have to change the
password and to write one two three well
in this case I'm already route if I'm
rude of course I will be able to do so
to change this password about that guten
bees that would be too easy
so well let's look for a an atc shadow
right and let's see the type of
parameter it has and for whom a normal
system permits if I'm not using an
operating system I mean if my operating
system is saying that I'm going to be
able to open this even in read-only mode
I'm not going to be able to open that
file so I don't have that possibility
but this is going to work in any file in
which at least I have that read-only per
me so these meter is 32 bytes what
happens with 64 bytes how am I going to
exploit that
what should i do what should i click on
but if can see some more route okay
you're not even a member we are
complicated well we are have to exploit
a user are you sir so what what this
person said is just go and executed but
then I could just go and edit it and I
mean to do it without any privilege so
what's the difference between 30 and 30
and 64 bytes regarding they exploit
Munna come on if you find it out I will
pay you a beer afterwards there is no
difference what there's no difference at
all their work exactly the same way
because I'm basing this on a C's system
call which is native of the computer
maybe I can do a cross compilation I
could add minus M 64 and in order to
generate an exploit for 64 bytes well
the next exercise is to analyze they
exploit available in these treasures
because sometimes what really works is a
part that we want people to see but
behind that we may find many more things
let's move to we have here all over
take this spectrum Spectre is a
vulnerability of the kernel of kernel
that happens in modern cycles and that
happens to my microphones better Intel
for this 32 up here in the Intel system
and everybody started saying that the
engineers of Intel Hutton something
wrong but afterwards this also affected
while AMD a empower PowerPC and there's
any mic micro processors that execute
the speculative execution in a branch
predictions have you heard of these
speculative execution in writes
prediction one two three people but
you've heard about this right what we
will see what this is about but well
basically this some CV is for a site and
it is affected barely all of the
operating systems because this is not
something is Pacific to operating system
at this is in the hardware and because
of the way their Hardware works no
matter the operating system that you put
on top this problem is going to be on
the base of everything as we really like
this type of vulnerabilities with a logo
a nice logo because every time I've
owner ability is going to be published
people look for a nice logo
and someone writes an article that
nobody understands and that's so well
part of our real work is to try to
understand how these vulnerabilities
work you know that to reply them and to
solve them but this can also be loaded
remote remotely GI t motors that work
for JavaScript who's not using
javascript nowadays when navigating I do
so but in the end I cannot see the
functionalities of any website I can do
anything with that
so normally a and W enabling and there
are a lot of challenges regarding these
probability and there are a lot of many
things that could be done and I think
many things have been done I don't want
to boil fingers but I think that many
things have been done but well you know
there for you to understand the context
keep some slides and I want to explain
this clearly this is related to the
meltdown art but I'm executing these as
user lamp because of the failure of the
CPV the failure is the same I'm sure you
are going to understand this and I'm in
using userland mode I'm going to be a
process and I'm going to have access to
everything which is related to my part
of the process isn't it right for
example if I'm a browser I will have
access to my whole Krauser but if the
browser if I'm navigating with different
screens if the browser imposes a
restriction or a sandbox in a scream
I'm not going to be able to read the
data that I have in the other screen or
top for example if I'm using Gmail in a
top Facebook another top etc it's normal
that I cannot access from the top from
the Facebook top to the data or the
Gmail top because that could be a
problem we would blame the browser that
I'm using for that and this is what we
are going to spray it with inspector
within the user lam if I have a sandbox
I'm going to be able to want to keep the
sandbox based on a failure of the CP but
what is difference with the meltdown
well the Midtown is the same thing but
if I had the user line here now I have
here the kernel mode and I'm going to do
the same thing the same exploitation but
at the kernel model but kernel can
access all of the processes right so if
I'm a browser and I'm being exploited
and I have text processor or a keypad or
and something like that this is going to
have access to everything and any
password that we may have in the memory
and any key secret that we may have
hidden in the memory is going to be so
let's see what happens and why we have
these failures so I have different steps
after thinking about it for a long time
well we're going to see how these attack
works but by thinking about the
letter-size channel we're going to talk
about the cpu out of order execution in
the micro architecture of the CPU
process memory protection of the
operating system and if we're lucky if
we compile everything right until
probably something wrong work on yes
this worksheet by the way is just for
CPUs in turn this is one of the jokes I
always make I was saying before that it
was for a AMD IRM etc just to show you
that all of the manufacturers make the
same mistakes
get a get him so as we have certain
instructions I let's see what we have to
do I'm not going to computer compiled
from up down there are specific
instructions that I have to execute in
the CPU and we need to do a native
compilation so in the movie we are going
to the computer
Martin 80 now let's see this side
channel I'm going to based on the cached
memory of the CPUs and I'm going to use
this as a side channel
this technique is cement Dale called as
flash blast reload but I is a hardware
I'm going to know what a cachet memory
is going to do if I have data in the
cache a memory and I try to access that
data this is going to be faster than
going to the memory bring in today to
maintain the data in the crochet and
give it back to the user right this is
something that we've learned since the
beginning so logically I'm going to have
I'm going to play with that area you
know that see if data can be accessed
faster than our data that is not cash in
cachet and I have and that I have to do
for in the memory so but with which
manufacturer doesn't ease
I share do you know any that is not
using cachet no right but this is why
caches there in order to access fast I
think it's true that there are
manufacturers that have said well the
speculative execution let's try to do
let's try to remove the that the
speculative execution and now we're
going to try to remove the cachet from
that point all when people are trying to
to mean like a share they are doing it
wrong in the end the solution is to is
to launch new operating systems and new
computers in order to solve these
problems
well let's move to the code basically
I'm going to write here so here we have
this picture and in order not to make
any mistake I'm going to show you the
code I'm going to write it down here and
I'm going to skip this life I mean this
lights are for you to be at home late
later so here I'm going to explain very
briefly what this is so I'm going to
define a vector that's going to allow me
to introduced an element and this is not
a random value we will see this later
and then I will have to measure
different timings and you know this
sometimes these arguments here and what
really is too
restart the arrived at a house I'm going
to take these ten elements and I'm going
to say their value is one for all of
them for each one of them and logically
these awry is going to have a value of
one each so elements here is going to be
one element what is going to be one
elements who is going to be one etc and
here I'm going to flush
what's a flash flash means cleaning I'm
going to indicate the microprocessor to
clean the cache a memory this was why
you're seeing here's something weird
which is something with slaw / - a blue
flash this is going to be used to clean
the machine just for there right then
I'm going to introduce some data for
example here in the position number
three I'm going to give a value of 100
in position seven I'm going to give the
value of 200 now logically both 100 and
200 when accessing some data these data
whether it is reading or writing data is
going to be in the cache a memory but
how is the element number one number
serial number their caches are
completely clean they have nothing
inside so in this case as I'm trying in
this is in this loop I'm trying to
access element number one number zero
number two I'm going to be able to clean
make a shake but other elements that are
not there it should be brought from the
cache a memory from from the memory and
if this works and if our microprocessor
is vulnerable was not worried about
vulnerabilities actually a
characteristic of all microprocessors
this is going to allow me to know the
access in time
well now I'm going to first first I'm
going to compile this time I'm going to
write access time and that's now let's
see this is true okay so access time
this requires time I'm just I'm going to
write so this is going to be useful just
for one test so I'm going to write one
here what what are the elements that has
different values before the elements had
different values before remember that in
the code that is there in the element
three I have here
124 cycles of site be CPU which is very
low compared to the other ones what
timings are you going into getting your
computer's they are going to be
completely different in depends on your
computer it depends on many other
processes this is going to change
depending on the computer but probably
when I have like a shared data in
crochet I'm going to be able to see that
leaves are going to reduce to reduce
more or less but the timings are going
to reduce which we read at the element
seven I have one 559 element eight 238
so if I see that I'm not going to be
able to compare because I don't know
what's going to happen but anyway I'm
going to click on execute I'm going to
execute this for 1000 times that it
changed after I 1000 time execution yes
right
which are the elements with less CPU
cycles three and seven right so next
time I'm going to chain six and four is
it working for you music I can see that
it's working for me money saying yes
your microprocessor is vulnerable now it
has the cachet is it working for you all
I'm sure that it's not working for all
of you I say who knows because this is
not very very specific technique in
order to make sure that this is true
because for example there may be data
maybe we're not in cachet so we are
getting closer I don't know yet we
cannot be sure you know that you
continue so this is the next thing that
we have what I'm going to try to do well
I'm going to skip some slides excitable
we don't have a lot of time now we're
going to try to set a threshold value
specific to each computer in order to
find out if these data was in caching or
in memory but this is going to be of
course valley for example we have more
than I don't know how many cycles or if
it lasts more than I don't know how many
seconds I'm going to guess but this is
in cashier if not this is going to be in
memory now we're going to save a secret
or a password
normally we
access secret value from the outside but
I could do some cleaning
I could reload what I wanted and I could
check caches memories you know that you
see if the secret may be in the element
see will I have some value in element
one another one our basic idea over to
recover a bite how many values you have
have 256 right maybe you had written
capital T whatever what's the problem if
I define an array of this kind it won't
work
why because operations in storage cache
a in machine works in blocks not in
bytes it works at the block level not in
the byte level I have a block for this
part not a block for another part so the
idea when using this side channel is
that every element has to fall within a
certain block you know there for me to
be able to check later that bloke and to
be sure that the element with the lowest
time access in each of the blocks is the
element of the secret I was looking for
that's the idea of a specter so what am
I going to do why ami was I using the
value 4096 bytes in order to be sure
that each one of the elements is going
to fall into a different block so I'm
going to create the array of search in
order for them not too much because we
will have some problems with element
cero when I'm looking for that element
zero I have some problems the element
zero is kind of special so I can add a
delta value so if the element zero is
going to be here I am going to send it
to 1024 bytes in order for it to act as
the element one but instead of going
from zero to ten I will go from zero to
knowing that 11 will be the zero element
I don't know if you are following me
that's why we're going to add a delta
value we have another Gold Line which is
a flash reload and basically oops I'm
sorry what we're doing here is to define
the secret value in order to save it
let's for example say the number 13 out
of superstition I'm going to define that
Delta 1024 and randomly because I just
wanted to do so I did find a threshold
you know let's say it is a threshold of
80 I just made it up what do you think
if I write 100 what if I I tie 1,000
what value do we enter that's that's
dangerous if we read all the
documentation on microprocessors there
are thousands and thousands of pages
that in tell us that threshold the
values that we can enter according to
the threshold if I enter a very low
value maybe
want it won't be useful so I am going to
use a statistical technique in order for
that value to be closer so I'm going to
repeat the search for the secret and
with a small counter I can that I can
determine how many cachet hits I I have
I can repeat it 1000 times or 1 million
times and I'm sure that if after 1
million times the value is cachet we
find that the element of the array was
in cachet that's the element we're
looking for so that's why that value
should be around 80 100 here we have the
array you know the to prevent I do not
want to fall it right next to it because
if the element I'm looking for within
the same block
I cannot distinguish it and the rest is
kind of easy so the only thing I'm going
to do is to do a flush reload to God to
call the system function and then I'm
going to do the reload of the flush I'd
channel let's see if we can compile it
the native and the flash reload dot see
let's see what happens let's execute
it's a great Oracle Tracy so secret
recovered the value of 13 is it working
for you I hope somebody tells me no
those okay one over there anyone else
maybe a second person the rest of us may
have more vulnerable micro processors I
need people to tell me hey you recovered
the value 13 because it is your machine
you know the threshold value and so on
once you have compiled it what we're
doing is we're refining a little bit
more the code I am sure that at the end
of the session if I manage to end on
time I am sure that you will recover the
secret value is it working for you that
means your microprocessor is a bit
vulnerable and it is a new laptop I can
see maybe 15 you bought it 15 days ago
really I really need someone to tell me
it is not working for them why did it
work here it was it was luck actually
because if you start doing this maybe
one of them work and some others don't
and maybe after 1 million times you can
recover the secret value of 13 otherwise
maybe I will need to make some efforts
and to improve the code so that it I am
sure this is working universe in a
universal way for every kind of
microprocessor I want environmental
arredondo so let's continue while you're
working on it
you pull up and let's move on okay so we
check at least not I can play with
stressful values or below and we're
getting things a little bit more
complicated you can search for a
threshold value that warrantees ones
100% of hits in cash a okay precisely
why I'm telling you this we cannot be
sure of 100% value when we want to
exploit to it work in an Universal way
so what kind of we do we need to keep
thinking it on it and we have all the
things to think about it is the
execution and the branch prediction this
is our code we learned in our first year
of training write this code beta value
equals zero and it is going to verify if
the value is lower than the side and the
increase of five equals three and size
equals 10 so the code is if 3 is less
than 10 then data equals 5 is that
correct okay good how can we execute
these simple code within the
microprocessor the microprocessor is not
stupid micro processors and engineers
who are very smart decided to execute
the good part of the branch of the jump
at the same time that I execute the evil
the bad part when you
the verification I am going to show you
only the part that you want to see with
data equals five but wait maybe we can
say studied there if at a certain moment
is halted and we were able to open the
microprocessor I would have the
execution of the if function and the
execution of the no function with both
results and this is precisely the
execution out of order and branch
prediction and why have we carried out a
branch prediction in order to obtain
results as soon as possible an inspector
and mulden were based on these kind of
foundations which I mentioned earlier
so what manufacture what microprocessor
manufacturer
didn't think of this speculative
execution
they hadn't thought of that they are
stupid because the faster and the more
optimal the microprocessor works the
better okay condition is true outside
the CPU but an architecture level we
could see if it had been implemented or
not and I could start seeing those
results any microprocessor enable us to
execute these out of all the because
what we want
if the microprocessor some instructions
to be executed at the same time
depending on the functions that we have
but in order to execute an if function
this is enough and now I'm going to
execute
books what is that some books what does
it execute is the if function so if you
are on this tab you cannot access the
data from another tab and if you are in
the other tab you cannot access the
other tabs data a simple sandbox
regarding the code level we can have a
part of password with a secured function
to access it and I'm checking it with an
if if we have access or not in this case
the microarchitecture level it is going
to execute functions as speculatively
the prediction is going to be true or
false
changes are going to be committed and
now we could somehow try to exploit the
code that we had before what was this
execution regarding designed if it had
to process something if function needs
to process something what would didn't
we delete the data from the cache a so
you we should have done a flash but who
was going to access the data from the
cache a who was going to check the
microarchitecture from the CPU in order
to see what was executed or not well
therefore Chinese who launched it the
piper and the for stupid persons who
devoted their time to read those
documents so maybe here we can see how
we can see
that execution in order to CD
microarchitecture so let's go back to
the code here in order for me to explain
it it's better for you notice that it is
still the same but we are adding tweet
complication this is not machine
learning this is not AI this is manually
refining the code i'm keep on doing to
flush reload i hear a victim function
this is a victim function whatever it is
is less than some value let's see if it
executes it or not let's see what
happens this is like pokemons we're
going to train cpus in order for it to
adapt the true function from the victim
function I'm calling from 0 to 10 I am
calling the function vector the victim
function is that right but before
calling the victim function I am
cleaning the cachet be careful because
the victim function let's imagine we set
the threshold the maximum value of the
victim of the victim function to 5 or
lower than 5 higher than 5 when I am
calling the function the function is
going to tell me true true true and then
falls falls falls falls falls and the
victim function is going to process
something right
maybe some destruction but I'm sure it
won't leave any data I'm sorry it will
leave some data in the cachet memory and
if I look it up or if I call the assist
the function correctly I mean a normal
execution maybe not victim function but
any other function when I call it and I
reload the side channel the research is
going to be true but in that out of
order execution probably I would know
what is true what is false and then I
can look up in the cache a their data
that were left here and that's what
these code vests let's compile it and
see if it works correctly so we enter
here native victim
I was colonnades from the valley or 97
okay
let's see if we have the value 97 what
is this what is this maybe I should have
received some results some value right I
mean you have the code right okay so
yeah I was saving it I was reloading at
least I should have received with that
line of code yes or no what do you think
9797 who is if we follow the Killa
pending notice it depends on some values
if it is on cash a memory I was entering
cash a threshold so in this case we can
compile again hacking in reversing and
exploiting in everything you need to be
lazy why to compile again no I'm going
to oh this is working already is always
working and it is going to and when is
it going to stop working I have no idea
I'm clueless I don't know when it is
going to work in a universal way or when
I'm going to have good value but I told
you before that with a threshold of 100
I do not happy what enough warranties to
make it work in every microprocessor so
if it is very precise is going to be
very very difficult this is basically
what we're explaining here ok so here we
have the prediction the speculative
function is executed sometimes it does
work sometimes it doesn't either it
depends on the machine I would like you
to do this afterwards because in the
main let's imagine we remove flesh to
see that maybe we can't never find it
but maybe if we train it and we call
with some set values we can realize it
is more variable
times we will only obtain these three
souls once in every 100 times but at
least I know it is stored in cash a
memory I still have some noise and
that's the reason why it is not working
there is some extra data stored in
cachet so now I can make the code to
execute the true branch even if the
condition is false the CPU won't matter
so if I do not clean the cachet I will
have a vulnerability what does I have
secret data within the same process but
there are some functions within the same
process that do not have access to those
data that we had saved so what happens
here that I have a protection at the
hardware level and this protection since
is from the same process it is what
protection artists and bolus level and
here we have the same problem I am going
to create a sandbox I will have
restrained access here we are and other
with no restraint access I can call the
function with correct values in the
beginning or incorrect values I can
train the CPU T leave some data in
cachet or not can I access no can I
access No so maybe the value is 97 and
cachet is going to say yes or no is it
100 is it 100 and tell is the element 13
and from there I'm going to recover
everything
logic says I'm going to start here a
buffer I'm going to create the sandbox
basically I would have a secret on the
top I would have a very very simple
sandbox but do not think that sandbox
from browser tabs are more complex than
this one and I am going to be able to
access from nine to not from zero to
nine depending on the value if it is
lower or higher there we have the whole
code I am defining here a secret I have
powered I have a sandbox the rest is the
same so when you do this at home use
values from 60 80 100 and 120 you don't
need to enter 5,000 pages of the tech
spec and that would be enough and now
I'm going to try to train my sandbox I'm
going to execute a flourish I'm going to
call the function with whatever I want
finally I'm going to see these if it is
correct
and now I would like you to ID on't know
where you were those who didn't get the
correct value but now I would like to
see if it works or not this is what we
have done well the code I mean the code
I showed you and that's it
will it work this is already a spectrum
this is Specter
if I did the same with lick of device
with a kernel I would have access to all
the memory of all the processes it would
be the same so I'm going to compile it
I'm going to compile negative I'm going
to originate the inspector do we bet
something we bet on a beer if it works
does it work for you 97 was a value
wasn't it but now I want those who
couldn't do it before to speak up ok
let's press ENTER all together let's do
it but didn't we have to obtain the
value 97 what's the value you're
obtaining below it doesn't compile but
you have it on the top they're compiling
button no it's not working for you are
you receiving the value 0 ok let's let's
press ENTER several times because oh
look there are different values here 115
115 see we'll see well I want you to see
by yourself you don't need to compile it
once at times but press it for several
times 115 is the value for non capital S
but sometimes do you get Diwali on
sometimes you don't so it's almost
Spectre but not yet right
[Music]
do you understand are you following me
are you following me
yes okay so this is the code when we
called this is the secret and if we use
a browser and we search who does have
internet access because I do not have
why free access this should work always
but I see that these works randomly so
what to do do you have any ideas because
I have some you let's imagine port
JavaScript you might think if you want
to do it for browsers I could executed
several times I would have some data
from you realize that the value C wave
appears several times not only in my
computer but I'm sure that indoors as
well I distracted with the rickroll with
the video and then we could discard the
serial value and executed several times
right is that correct and then I would
have the value 115 in this case or
whatever value it gives us is that
correct okay so no it's not useful at
all we have a dish
values we can use it later I have caches
working so why not to call a statistical
function I can launch the attack several
times but I can set at a counter with
cachet hits for the element zero one two
three four in order to recover the
secret of the valley and then of a bite
sorry for whatever I want and then
simply with this statistical function
which is a very simple one I can check
the element with the highest number of
hits this is quite complex to add a
counter for those who for those of you
who love games we have a score in
counter and every time our heat is
obtained then the counter will keep on
going up let's see if this is true okay
let's take let's do this directly we can
we have this exploit I have secret
I have sandbox I have everything as it
was before and the only thing that we
did was to one launch it several times
let's compile it
GCC architecture native exploit exploit
that see okay now I have my counter my
score
and I want you to execute it what's the
result do you get the SSO meter those of
you that couldn't get it before this is
not magic we do this had to check the
heap of the elements are you obtaining
the same result well so instead of
paying the beer for you I think that you
will have to invite me for those of you
that are watching a live streaming
let's see if this is true or not
as you've seen it takes longer
I mean we don't have to wait for their
whole great roller but besides the
memory address which I've obtained
because I wanted to some of you would
understand why later
I'm obtaining the 150 value the state
secret value which corresponds to the
letter S if I execute this right now and
I'm I don't know what right the result
is going to be but if you execute this
now you're going to obtain different
result it's working right now I'm able
to access our part two which I couldn't
access before and here I may find a
password that I've kept or anything I
mean this can be data from a picture is
your imagination and now how can I give
back all that secret has even me okay
I'm going to repeat what some what
someone just because we don't have a
microphone there but he just mentioned
please listen to our colleague if you
know where the vibe is with the secret
is kept in the memory you just have to
edit the memory position and process
that's it we you don't have to do
anything else this is why links the
memory address where this was hidden so
yes I will invite you I will be aware
but well i have i've hit counter right
if I show the element with the highest
score which was 115 in the next element
what will I have same thing right I can
access through the memory or through the
heap scatter the element with the
highest number of heat and then the
element with the second highest number
of heat until the final secret picture
that you may have in the key pass well
maybe that's not possible but passwords
or things like that this would be used
in order to recover that information for
example here let's write something
bodies here and a second exploit now we
have more spectral sources if we read
these what it is doing the same thing
that we did before and now I'm going to
be able to understand it better I'm
going to generate a second exploit here
so this is my second exploit but a el
STD exploit to point C dot C so case you
know the promotion naughty if they see
some intimacy mockery so well we have to
delete that native because otherwise
this is not going to work otherwise so
well we have our second our second
exploit here and well here we had secret
meal where was it or is it the picture
secret that we so well this is the
secret with a lot of characters we've
already known find found we've already
discovered how to work with that and
once it's compiled when we execute
exploit to if we go up down we can see
that here we have the address the
scoring so ivory-billed revealed a
secret through inspector this may be a
password or anything
mozzie comment a we can use our
imagination you know there too but
basically in this case and with type of
workshop what I want to do is
in the city for you to understand the
different steps and also to try it to
receive something that it is very
complex to understand I mean this is the
objective purpose my workshop today
these cyber completion I'm talking other
user level of course but now at the
kernel level we also have to do some
things right
can you mind what are we going to be
able to do at the kernel level this is
going to be the same thing basically so
well I'm going to continue we this slide
I'm not going to I'm going to skip the
meltdown slices oh my god I think I'm
going very fast but I'm sure that these
rings avail to all of you doesn't it
this is familiar twelve here for example
we are working with our kernel module
that we are introducing that's
protecting a special driver it's special
process I normally use our couldn't have
access to these in the end if we reduce
lights we're going to realize that the
process is exactly the same we are
information to our counter and that's it
and in order to get everything back we
are going to follow the same process we
still have some time I didn't think we
would make it because I know that this
is very complex and of course I would
like to think there thank you for being
here and think they're gonna organize
ourself cyber camp for doing this but I
think we have time for a couple of
questions so we have a couple of minutes
if you have any question please feel
free to ask them now
but assistant must appear at people's
window silly nooks gets to be a sin and
for windows and linux apprai appraised
in systems that AMD operators does it
work the same same thing this is the
operating system it's not important
because the problem is based on the
design of the cpu there also touches
from melted cetera that it's low the
operating system because what microcode
of the cpu is not doing is now being
done by the operating system so second
return of the flash is really next
cetera this system is going to worry
worse and I'm glad that you that we've
mentioned a RM because this has been in
the end a copy of a copy of copy so
regarding the speculative execution this
is something that must happen that must
be done because we need to be more
efficient and faster than our
competitors
funky the everybody wants to be the best
in their category are there any more
questions
nothing
[Music]