[Music]
good morning everybody
my talk this morning is less technical
than some of the others you'll see we're
going to talk about cybersecurity but
from the point of view of working in
this field how we can start out in this
market and what age we start training
and getting prepared for this field in
terms of computer science but not only
just in cybersecurity it's in general
let's go quickly into the presentation
because I've always been presented this
morning just give me a second because
the slide isn't moving forward
we'll skip over this first bit because
I've already been presented I work in a
field that's not directly related with
cybersecurity but in my specialization
in my area workers come into this field
I am a teacher or lecturer at the
University of castilla-la mancha and on
the master of in cybersecurity and
security information but in computer
safety and I've worked in the
administration but the last few years
I've been working in the field of
computing and cyber security so let's
move on to the next slide and we're
going to talk about several different
things I've got a little bit of an index
here this is the title of the the talk
is about working in the field of cyber
security what do I need to do do I need
a degree a little bit about the
available qualifications that you can
get in the field and so different areas
within cyber security you can work in
what would I like to do is more
specifically we'll talk about
certificates that you can gain in the
field of cyber security and some of
these I think these are both
theoretically and in practice very
positive also the skills that a person
who specialized in cyber security needs
and we'll talk about training and
qualifications and continuous cert
training people involved in this field
are always in different forums were
different congresses and giving talks
and we're continually improving and
learning law what our business is
looking for and what
the salary can we achieve this is one of
the areas that I love it would seem that
there are few people in this field not
enough people and few specialists people
however that it's not really a balance
in what businesses or institutions ask
for what I'm prepared to give for some
institution we're doing a comparison
also with the US and the UK and we'll
talk about if there's a future in this
field I think the future is closer than
we think in terms of the professionals
that we need in this field start with
the definition of cybersecurity this is
taken from a sack I'm sure you're
familiar with it they establish
regulations on a global scale and
perhaps for me this is the best
definition and it's a protection of
information assets in short what we're
talking about here is if it can get the
information up we're talking about
assets and information which could be
anything anything can be a value for an
organization that can be systems and can
be people can be computers of any kind
and assets and information come is very
general but at the end of the day what
we do is to protect digital information
information they can find reasons why
I'm talking maybe not
we have training training training in
terms of gang hired by companies basic
location
all ready to do the things that they
want to do and not necessarily undergo
studies that then they my actually at
some point if they didn't go we have
different professional families is basic
location on a painting that is composed
reset globe RC apprenticeship you can
imagine well obviously here the salaries
are very very you can actually access to
the higher level many people who once
it's really close to the actual work and
[Music]
have been doing
undergoing I might be interested in
having that person maybe I can thing
them maybe I can just give them
professional training so occasional
train
[Music]
together so you get 300 very very
training in four years
[Music]
doing coding and you think the way it
works what happens is many people say
you have to be very sure once you
[Music]
and cybersecurity there are many many
things to do with cybersecurity in
vacation going to now the biggest
question do I really need a degree three
vocational training versus self training
degree versus vocational training out
I'm going to lie I'm going some often
require university different thing would
be
[Music]
google play to sell them and you've
always liked hanging and everything you
are that person you will need 90% to
join a company very professional
training when it comes to salaries is
not as university degree talking from an
economic point of view annual training
training you have the more if you're
going to it you may think well when you
finish a degree you didn't have a
practical training or not as much more
than someone who's been working with
computers since they were 14 yeah
project when they people they ask
company once those people should also
have further certification in CH
certifications they compulsory on the
conditions to take part in the
competition so with degree we have no
training America let's not forget why I
said before people with vocational
training
now how about self
[Music]
now when it comes in on this if you want
I highly recommend this what field
should I choose what can we do in the
field of cyber security there are many
many things that you can you can do
cybersecurity you can work in software
creating
apps to manage security or even Hardware
creating equipment to protect different
areas could work perhaps in the the
legal security terms of regulation soon
on people working in this field don't
tend to have come from an engineering
field but to does happen sometimes in
terms of vulnerabilities or ethical
hacking and so on pen testing these are
quite popular so there's the field of
malware it's very very popular at the
moment so there's a reverse analysis and
so on all of this are very popular areas
but my advice is always to try a little
bit of everything if I don't try
something that I don't know if I'm going
to like it maybe just to do a course for
a few hours give me a general idea and I
might say oh I love for reversing or
it's not my particular case but you
might make ethical hacking or response
to incidents forensics try a little bit
of everything that's the most interest
way interesting way of doing things
there are many different areas different
areas that you work in in cyber security
generally offensive and defensive
security that can relate those two main
branches we're talking about pen testing
but hunting of protecting we're talking
about there's two main definitions and
then we have the rest of the areas that
you can work in here's a list of the
different areas that you can work in a
cybersecurity
malware from digital forensics incident
handling developing tools telefónica
telefónica develops its own tools so we
have ethical hacking management of risks
a cycle hacking is one of the things
that people like most looking systems
and testing and it's also really great
area threat intelligence rat hunting
critical infrastructures critical
infrastructures Tamizh there's a very
very interesting field you can see there
are many many different installations
and not necessarily critical ones but in
different companies they look any
external people for coming in in some
companies look with Windows NT or 3/1
just with a card here you can say wow we
to do this at the beginning of their all
time but it's always worked like this
and if I want to change that then I have
to stop the company's system and they
have to put it on hold and that costs
money and so therefore companies don't
even think about it we have to focus in
a different kind of way you have to go
around the perimeter and get their
different kind of focus on it so it's a
field that I think is very very
interesting and I think it's a field for
the future as well in cyber security
the term of installations so very
interesting so certificates that you can
get the most demanded ones in cyber
security and the ones that companies are
looking for because he can be a computer
engineer but you don't have any
experience when you go out into the
world of work
and so you'll enter into a company as a
junior with no experience sometimes
companies do go after a particular
person because would you say that we
need many many computer professionals
for cybersecurity and that this is
necessary and these people need to go
straight into companies right now but
it's also difficult to find jobs without
any kind of qualification those that are
most abundant in the field are those so
for aisaka such as the systems auditor
and security manager these are the ones
that are most required in the field of
we look at specific something a bit but
you'll see that these are some of the
things that are being required this is
nothing this is a safety governance
however I'm talking about a sake here
but there are some people who do already
have a vocational training and that to
me tells me that that person has gone
through a practical process and tells me
that that person already has some
training and can sit in front of a
computer my practice might be two
different things what about the
ec-council certificate for ethical
hackers it's a test at the end of it all
there's a subject matter that you had to
cover and then a test at the end you can
say I'm a computer scientist this
ethical hacker certificate for me see
Council I know I'd like to work a
business might say that be given three
options
not to select one of those because
that's what I've been trained for and if
I'm not able to do that then what have I
been trained force this is a filter and
certifications are important but we do
need practice
we need practice currently in Spain
there are some qualifications that you
can give that are issued by a company
for one for Red Team one for Blue Team
and qualifications means getting and
training in a specific area and you have
to know what that is going to be useful
for you if somebody comes to me with
practical experience then I believe in
them a little bit more so sometimes what
you get is what you see on this list and
there are other certifications that you
can get but they are very very expensive
very expensive for what they actually
give you so what girls do you need I'm
going to go through this quickly I'll
just talk quickly a little bit about
some of the things I think are a most
important asset e to learn this is
everyday today we are given a problem
but it doesn't exist yesterday so now I
have to resolve it today I have to be
continually learning and Kimpton t
updating myself regarding the technology
I don't know anybody cybersecurity there
isn't constantly going to forums isn't
getting involved in talks I don't know
anybody who really works in the field
who is not involved in these kind of
events there is a lot of sharing of
information between different companies
and this is really important somebody
some
beginning you tend to think oh if I've
got this so knowledge then I'm going to
be better valued in the market know on
the country but if I don't know if
you've got that knowledge if you don't
tell me about that I'm not going to find
you ever it's not just that you're in
your house hidden away but it's just
that you're not exposing yourself to the
opportunities I'm not going to find you
and results these have the big companies
you have to be able to work under
pressure you will be faced with a big
issue you sometimes you just have to to
to resolve that and that might be the
only thing that that employing you who's
been useful for you have to be able to
resolve issues whatever time of day
Saturday it's 12:00 at night if it has
to be team work you have to know how to
work by yourself but you have to know
how to work in a team a lot of work is
done from a whole many of the companies
the big companies have people who work
from home but you have to work in a team
as well you have an issue if you need to
be dynamic can have intuition that's
when you have an issue that comes to
mind are not really sure where it's
coming from anything of that kind that
makes you think and you just can't just
sit back we have to react and act so now
we're talking about ethics this is a
vocational area of employment obviously
when you're 13 14 doing secondary
education
have to feel the vocation at that age
but when during the first few years of
your engineering degree for example then
you do need to have that feel for
vocation and then to know whether it's
the job for you that's irrespective of
whether or not there's a current bubble
of employment in this that's very
well-paid most contracts that are set up
with large companies also have an
attachment to them and it indicates that
you have to you have to respond and you
must not reveal any of the information
and this is what you're sharing with
your colleagues even teamwork is
absolutely essential you have to share
results you have to share experience
share absolutely everything in this
community in the hacker community for
example this is a community in which we
share everything we have a lot of
exchange is the sort of forums there are
a lot of talks never lose that interest
in sharing if you share information that
does mean you're of less value for a
company on the country you're of more
value to a company continuous training
training never ends never ever you have
to be continually learning here we have
a number of blogs of all different kinds
a bit darker than others some are on the
gray area and some of which I can
recommend security for example I like
blight a lot I like the Hispanic there
at the bottom so they can focus on some
of the vulnerabilities that are coming
up so
can continue update one a day you gnarly
at the bottom that you say there is a
Spanish one it's a project by Paco
Gonzalez and it's been on hold for a
while but it's now is up and running
again now and it's very good the in
zebra also has a lot of information
sometimes it can seem a little bit heavy
because there's an institution but they
have a really a load of interesting
information what courses can we do to
complement and add on to what we've
already learned in official education
recommendations here such as offensive
security that I think are essential if
you'd like to work in pen testing or
ethical hacking for example the
pentester academy over the Internet
economy code Academy some of these
courses are free and the other thing you
have to do is to pay if you need to get
the certificate or the Diploma at the
end because well these entities or put a
lot of time into these projects so
that's fine deme also has a number of
different courses of this kind both in
English and in Spanish and there are
very very many interesting things about
technology about programming of course
if you don't know anything about Python
in terms of cybersecurity then you're
nobody so specific academies that I
mentioned many that work in the weekends
that are available in the week they're
different many different ways of
forgetting additional education
different events that you can
participate in such as this one cyber
down the technical talks or educational
talks such as this one or even practical
workshops that you can avail these
events are really worth getting involved
in so SEC admin nopon name honey coin
there are many different ones and John
this is from South America day so the
many places that you can learn new
things it's not just about learning new
things though it's also a little about
networking and getting to know people I
just met somebody in the VIP room
somebody who are used to go to
university with but I didn't actually
personally know that person and it was
really great to meet him also meeting
people on the floor or in the room and
that's also way of making a community so
this is very very recommendable please
go to all the events that you can
hologram is the revolution of many many
different groups and I really recommend
this very highly I recommend you going
into telegram continuously if you just
don't go in one there for one day you'll
only have about 4000 messages the next
day so so you have to discriminate a
little bit the information that you're
going to receive and find out what's
important to you
highly recommendable be info say foreign
informatica forints there was a forensic
computer hack the box they've also got
their own group in telegram talking
about certifications there's a group
which is CIA
espanol
there are specific cybersecurity group
and on the whole there is a lot of
information available to me and my
family
who has all of this a lot hello salaries
never increase because they are now so
expansions vamos let's focus on your
cybersecurity
you see forty five forty seven thousand
statistics 2000
[Music]
here we can see 29,000 we're talking
about 33,000 and 45,000 but hello
hundred through genius someone was just
starting out this garage yes 19500 in
Madrid when we were make ends meet and
jumps here as well because you're
managing and didn't have the patience to
it you salary to your job then oh my now
I'm gonna run
this is closer to Spain we hear about
vocation because otherwise is going 2018
people
is the number one we see fish
for that most boring part of it well at
least you have something easy now
finally the media say beauty will die
it's no longer about big companies run
somewhere
[Music]
if you want to say something just raise
your sorry haven't seen you well first
of all things a lot for your speech and
also from Sarah both eyes been a very
interesting
speech and concerning my experience I
have a degree in engineering I'm looking
for a job and I have been able to
respond when they ask you should fight
[Music]
that's what should be compulsory to
going to n thank you very much hello and
we've talked about doing university
degree or vocational training
[Music]
it was someone who what is true is that
unless you have specific all the things
as I was saying before then it's not
really complete I mean from my point of
view if it's not
by an external company then then maybe
it should be anything else yes over
there I just wanted to say that I've
really liked speech I'd like to add when
it comes to training in cybersecurity
for what I've seen
looking around I've seen masters which
have very very high tuition fees I don't
know about only we see every day
Victoria but there's there's a master's
by one of the one of the big audit
companies sorry change our people is
true that we have the big four or five
are the ones which train people yeah
that's how it works yeah and I also like
to see in your CV the you are a private
detective well imagine how important it
would be when they intercept your mobile
chip they take it to another phone and
they empty your account would you be
able to detect the person who has
started that well actually managed chips
to then have them mounted in other
machine I personally difficult some
people could do it thank you well thank
you very much
[Music]