[Music]
all I want to start this hello good
evening
thank you for the introduction thank you
and fever for inviting me to be here
today and for all those of you who have
stayed for this workshop which I hope is
going to be interesting I don't know if
you are very experienced in answering to
incidents and to detecting issues I'm
going to try to make this as practical
as possible I'm going to show you a few
examples but of course it's going to be
a short introduction well first of all
my name is javier marcos I work in
cybersecurity I've worked in
cybersecurity for the last 1215 days
I am a systems engineer engineer and
security engineer
I love open source software and I have
worked for Facebook Google air B&B and
now I'm working with crypto currencies
and well I have always been really close
to open source community and I have
always tried to contribute with projects
that I thought could be interesting from
the point of view of security but also
because technological companies do
support open source and so there is a
project that I was lucky enough to take
part in I don't know if you've ever
heard of o square e OS query no one well
it's better so because that way I can
introduce it to you well and I'm going
to start talking about how this workshop
is going to be structured first of all
I'm going to tell you about OS query
what the concept behind it is how it
came up it was a tool that was created
at Facebook as around mid 2015 and well
I will tell you about it in a minute but
I'm
just tell the basic concepts how we use
that and then information related
information that were then going to use
in a in order to use ours query in a
scalable environment of hundreds and
even millions of machines because in
these cases what you really want is to
be able to manage hours gathering and
information generation of all the
machines they have in your production
environments and when it comes to
technological companies such as Facebook
or uber or Google the number of
production machines even within the
company is enormous we can even talk
about millions of servers so I'm just
going to explain how the concept of OS
query applies in this kind of
environment how it can be used how it
can be implemented and finally how you
could manage manage those nodes or those
agents that are within your corporate
production system and how you can manage
them with OS control which is the tool
that I have developed myself this is the
third iteration of them to that I
started developing in 2016 it was
successfully deployed in corporate
environment at uber and I think right
now it counts around half a million
machines Windows mark Lynas Linux and
all of that salt and still working and
I'm actually quite proud that although
I'm not working at the company anymore
they're still using my software that was
the first iteration then there was the
second iteration which was what I then
converted to OS control and this is open
source so you can use that at home if
you want to improve your detection
infrastructure or just reflect gather
logs etc so I'm just going to show you
the tools components how the logs are
gathered
and how you can then use it yourself so
always query first of all right now the
companies that use us query to collect
or gather logs is actually quite big you
can see many names here and there are
also other companies that do not want to
be acknowledged publicly but there are
really really big companies and actually
Google has recently done an integration
with ours query and their forensic
artifacts recollection to see our ads
and you can see here an example of all
the companies which are using us query
and who one don't mind knowing people
knowing obviously Facebook uses scream
in all their systems even network
appliances and all the others as well so
you get an idea more or less of what the
impact of a tool that was developed by
three people the engineers in this
project and which is now being used in
very important production systems so the
idea behind ours query is to expose your
operating system using sequel extraction
so the idea behind using this extraction
with SQL was to create a system that
generated abstract data and different
infrastructures and it was able to
detect intrusion or to detect incidents
as well so if you can detect that then
it is very important to have early
detection so that you can then issue and
response really quickly now OS query
uses 100% OS API so all the tables that
I'm going to show you later will be
native code from the operating system of
every platform that supports OS query
for example if you want to know the
amount of processes that are going on on
a Linux system it's going to show you a
list but it's not going to pass those PS
or any other thing that usually takes
place in system administration to see
commands and how machines work and then
you have to pass everything so OS query
wants to bring normalized data that can
be applied to all the platforms that
aren't supported by it so OS query vo is
where you can find information about the
different packages that you can download
and see the different versions the
tables and the github repository on
oversquare foundation used to be under
Facebook's open source account
originally but now a few months ago it
happened to be an organized it changed
to an organization of the Linux
Foundation so that there was no way of
affecting the decisions that could be
made because obviously the project was
at the inception created in on Facebook
but it has a very wide impact in this
industry right now so there's a
committee which is currently making
decisions about where the code is added
to and where attention needs to be drawn
now the motivation behind our query was
other than detecting intruders and
generating logs was basically would you
be able to picture this in your
corporate environment which in this case
we're saying possible Linux or Mac and
Microsoft computers laptops how many of
these have an extension with the
identifier how would you be able to
retrieve that information
how many file descriptors were opened
yesterday in the production environment
every hour all for example if you have
full bridge VPN in your corporate
network is the resistance that is
routing that VPN to your local network
how would you check that you need to
have very high capacity for executing
commands and then parts that those
commands and then know exactly whether
the information that you're gathering
does or not make sense so these are
three examples which are quite visual
easy to visualize and to us and the
motivation behind something like OS
query so the first concept I would like
to introduce within OS query I was query
I which is an interactive shell which is
basically the CLE where you can execute
your queries and the idea behind this
tool is to be able to execute these
commands in a local machine to say for
example you need to know which users or
which processes using UID 0 for example
so you would just try to extract the
query within this system and then you
would be able to see which query you
would need to execute and what outcome
that query is going to give so for
example OS query has very good
documentation you can find almost any
answer you looking for on the wiki and
there's a very complete introduction
because you've got flags and parameters
and everything and I'm just going to
show you a little bit how this works so
that we can keep on going with the
expansion by the way if you have any
questions do not hesitate to interrupt
me if you need
me to explain anything again just let me
know and I will go back and try and
explain it the question is that if there
are consultations that are executed and
os Korea need to have something
installed no you just need oh s query
I'll tell you for each platform how it
works because when we're going on
several different platforms here they
are
if you want to use it for Mac you can
install it with brew or and when did
you've got chuckle you can use apt Linux
or four distributions of the kind you
need an RPM with this command and with
FreeBSD it's also gussets on installer
as well Stacy in Delap this would be the
place to start from if you're using your
computer then you can install OS query
so we have the different packages of the
different architectures around a week
ago we found that if you had a linux 4.1
the 401 came out several months later so
the 401 version got stuck and it became
a stable and has this sir fault so if
you do have been in the the project tree
then you need to go to the 402 version
you can see an example of how to get the
page UID and name the the core concepts
that we have in OS query are I can plus
platform-agnostic we seem to have some
issues with the sound can you hear me
now
yeah so the basic concepts in a SQL are
platform agnostic the PID the name and
the idea from processes are basically
the same in all platforms that use OS
query and the option of using SQL is
technology that has been working for a
long time and most system administrators
are familiar with that so the SQL
concepts tend to be well known and you
will be able to see how to do
consultations using parameters or join
the tables as developers system
developers are familiar with let's take
a look at an example here so the
concepts the main concept is tables and
is they executed in each operating
system and we're going to get the
information here and this is the concept
table in which shoot from which you take
some attributes that is the columns that
you'd like to take from the table you
apply some filters or some constraints
for example I'd like the PID the name
and the UID from the processes
where the UI you ideas different to zero
and furthermore the the power of that is
that you can join different tables and
decorate the table with the different
processes using a join on the UID so you
obtain more information rather than just
showing the processes otherwise you
would have to do several different
commands you'd have to do a pipe from
one command to another grips and other
things that we have to do usually to get
this kind of information the most basic
command is dot help and this will give
you basically the ideas and the dot help
is taken from the SQL motor so SQL elite
it's SQL elite three points something I
don't know which the most recent one is
so it's a SQL elite in this case the dot
table will give you all the information
on the different of machines that are
running at the time if you're using Mac
can use dot tables then you will see
everything that is connected to those
platform but if you bring a Windows it
will show you different tables because
others depend on two different platforms
and others are not so the information
will be different the command pragma
table info in this particular case will
give you the sin taxes or the columns
within the scheme of a table you will
need this in order to joins between
tables or if you needed to use a
parameter within a table and use you to
compare one with another so this is
quite useful it's equivalent to a desk
and then sq
and this comes in the scheme of the
tables the latest version of OS queries
4.0.3 but it's not too stable they load
most recent stable one is point two
there are four different platforms that
can be used at OS X Windows Linux for
different packets and FreeBSD the
information can be easily collected and
it's easy to do joints and so on the
format of the tables in the scheme so
you can take a look at them so these are
some of the tables that generally give
us quite a good deal of information when
you need to respond to incidents or you
need to extract information from a
machine that might have been compromised
you can get a great deal of interesting
information and to check the status of
the machines that you're working with an
interesting point is that when you
select a table the code is executed each
time you do a select so that code is for
each table so it always executes every
time you launch the table there's a
little detail to keep in mind here if
you understand how iOS Curie works then
based on the nature of the data that
you're going to generate all the
complexity or the quantity of
information that is being used then
there are different caches within OS
query within its own process so that you
don't execute tables all the times that
you don't have to execute them all the
time
so if you want to see if the hard disk
on a computer has been encrypted then
that information will be cache
and you see changes in the sim then
there's going to detect that for you so
that's done internally if you need to
get into further detail regarding
whether on - there's cash in the table
then you're probably in an advanced use
of os query and you'll know what you
need in this case the time table if you
select date/time you click on command
and it executes once again we've talked
about simple tables and I will talk
about tables with parameters in SQL this
is a where and you put in a parameter to
compare with in this particular case
it's file so we have the file table to
extract information from files you would
extract the directory of the file where
the path is it's a issue as you can see
on the screen there because this is what
you have selected this is what you've
asked for these are just the parameters
of the consultation another example
which is very useful is this one you can
use the file table to extract
information from a file but in this case
it's doing a join with a hash table so
you can strike the information from the
table that you're pointing towards it
would give you the md5 of that table the
hash table you will see it will have md5
510 and so many different hashes these
are some examples for system
administration could be on Windows or
Linux there are interesting tables and
they might be interesting for our
systems administrator you can look the
status the number of users which are the
kernel modules
and what are these startup items that
have been configured in a Window System
an important point when you begin
OS query is to understand the files once
you've installed this on your machine
you need to know the deef default routes
for OS query so for Linux through a Deb
on rpm here you have a stroke et Cie
stroke OS query and then you have the
configuration that would try to load or
the flash and I'll talk a little bit
more about this in a minute
so we have stroke vard stroke log stroke
OS query this would generate the logs if
you use a local blogger and then we have
the beans and the OS query I of query D
and we'll talk a little bit about the
packs in a moment
they're sets of consultations so that
you can read as if it were an antivirus
it searches for a very interesting
information so as I mentioned before it
would be the same in these Mac systems
it would be installed with a brew it
these are signed packages and the
difference is stroke away query
it's VAR ba stroke aways query at the
same for the logs for the pains and the
packs and so on so these are just the
default routes for the system and last
of all those of you using Windows
there's an interesting point in that the
first C TV that came out
the first CV that came out was for a
range of privileges that in the Ruta
that was previously being used because
this was programmed data since this was
not a system route her if he didn't have
the right permission then you could
inject different extensions and as a
result you would inject the permissions
for OS curry and install it as a system
the first one we had was four and a
window system big offence it affected
the roots so now we have a little quiz
to give you a couple of examples of
consultations that you can use within OS
query and that can give you interesting
information for example how to get the
hosts from the machine that is running
you do select host name from the system
info table
can you see anything make it look a bit
bigger can you see it from the back so I
put in o s query I show the table
command and these are all the tables
that links to this computer which is a
Mac so if you put in this information
then you would get all the information
from the system info table and you'd get
the different content for example we can
do select hostname from system info and
then you have the host that's just one
simple example in this case for the host
who would be these system users it would
be the users table we would do exactly
the same thing
it'll be pragma info from the users
table he have the UID the GID for the
group the cell at the shell and so on
what do I want the UID so we would write
in it select UID name from users rather
user name and then we you would get the
user ID the user in this case of the
Machine and this is the processor table
this last example it's a little bit more
complex
we'd show the processors table and the
scheme of this table is little bit
different because has quite a lot of
information would like information from
the processes I'd like the
PID and the name for example and EU have
their PID and the name so now you might
say how would I knew what the username
and the shell of the user is of the user
that his running processes in the
machine do you have an idea how you
would do that
well you'd use a join from the users
table and the processes table and use
that to extract the user shell and the
user name so what does the user table
show us we've got the shell and we write
in select username since we're going to
do a join we need to put an identifier
in or for the table so it'd be you dot
username you shell from users as you
join processes as P where P dot u ID
equals u u dot u ID and in this case you
would see the users that are running and
the shell this is where the use of the
SQL comes in and the join is done here
you can see how powerful this tool can
be when you want to extract information
from systems
and it can be quite a large quantity of
information especially if you have many
machines and in fact in this case
they're not actually related to the
platform platform it'd be the same in
Linux on Windows and so on it gives you
the information directly related to the
platform that you're using so when
you're getting infrastructure's
information or information that you need
to obtain it's very useful so do you
have any questions so far
either you haven't understood anything
so far or if it's plain things very very
well so let's go on we've talked about
OS query on my computer level and I can
execute consult consultations on my
computer
oona console so how do i execute a query
in 2000 computers and especially if I
want for it to extract the information
continuously and send it somewhere else
so what you would use instead of query
i/o is securi
i yd which is OS q queries daemon and
the difference is how you launch the
queries here you install it as a service
as in as an init system D launch the and
windows service that's how you install
it when you install the O's query
package it executes immediately and
automatically and I'm going to explain
to you how you can configure it once
it's installed and execute it what's
powerful about OS query is that it
executes queries continuously and so the
way the demon works is that you program
your queries to be executed every
specific time frame
and you can configure that by seconds
and then you have the different types of
locks that are generated which are
status and results status are generated
depending on os query status whether
there's been an error or a failure and
results queries are the results of the
queries precisely they have generated
through the programmed or on-demand
queries as query y the flax numerals you
have so many you couldn't even imagine
I'm just going to explain a few of them
the easiest ones but as I was saying
wiki is really good here such as have a
look on your own if you're interested in
in it so the idea behind Aris query
demon is that you have an operating
system when you have processes systems
users within that OS and within this OS
you would have OS query wardie running
and you would configure it with
different flex and remote configurations
then it would extract loss that would
then be sent to a centralized management
and within those boxes where you would
apply the use cases for planned
infrastructure or detection
infrastructure or whatever you want to
use it for so if instead of knowing what
commands uses our executing for example
you just want to monitor your CPU the
CPU of your production machines you can
do it so you can see the flexibility
that this tool gives us not just for
security issues but also for just system
administration so I was saying a loose
query D if you run the help then you
have a lot of flags as you can see
so you have more than enough to
configure it so these are very well
documented on the wiki and the way you
can configure this flax well you have
actually have two options you can either
give the daemon through the flat file
parameter where what you doing is just
adding all the parameters you one line
by line in on a flag file or you can
just have them jason are configuring
file and I'm going to show you both
examples so you can then see them on OS
control and see how this can be
configurated using flags and the
different configurations or centralized
configurations depending on what on what
you want and as I was saying the help
command is the same for OS query in
general is the same command all the time
that we've been seeing includes the flax
that you can see on help but on a file
line-by-line but what if you don't want
to use a flat file and you just want to
configure them through our configuration
configuration file what you would do
would be to take the name of the flag
without the dash dash then you would put
it on Jason within the options and then
you would have the configuration and the
value historically I was query the way
the parser JSON parser was implementing
implemented it didn't matter whether you
were using numbers billions chains
anything because it was going to
interpret it anyway and the 3.01 version
we changed that and so the json parser
changed from the c++ native nation
version to add rapid js
and that works much better because what
we wanted to do was form the types to be
well setted when they were generated and
in the case that they were Jason types
because if you have something waiting
for a stream or a boolean then the
logistics might be a bit complicated if
you want to access them but this is this
is just a little story little anecdote
because I've been well doing this for so
long
anyway in this example you can see here
what we're doing is configuring the API
filesystem and you're taking it from the
file system this is the path which is
not the default path because the default
path is the one I showed you Elian the
different architectures what we have
here is the logger which is where we're
generating locks and we would create log
files locally in the system and here on
the S play field what you are doing is
to avoid CPU surges and what you do is
you apply a percentage of that is play
to the programmed interaction so what
you're doing is saying if you have one a
100 second interval and you using 10
percent of s play then you might in the
best of cases it will be done in 90
seconds and in the worst case scenario
it would be in 110 seconds so you have a
worst-case best-case scenario so if you
didn't configure this you get a 50
percent so some people ask me sometimes
well after on this for 60 seconds and
this is doing it whenever it once it's
not that's not working it's that you
have an S play you could do an S play
zero and then it would execute it when
you want it to be executed but because I
was query was originally thought to
perform more than anything else and to
work in systems were there hundreds of
machines these little details do help
you
escalator services that are running and
have less performance issues and this is
just to have for example everything in
UTC when you have machines and different
regions if you don't want to use local
times everywhere you just use you to see
and it's easier for everyone so here we
have another example we've been talking
about configuration which is options and
now we're going to look into schedule
which is basically the scheduled queries
that OS who is going to execute and the
format in this case what consists in
defining the name of the query you
choose there it has to be unique because
otherwise it would be executing the
first in the configuration and not the
next one if they have the same name so
here you have a chain which is the cute
look the query which is where you
execute in the console then you have the
interval in seconds and in this case
we're using two for example there are
more things that can be configured here
within the within scheduled queries you
can define chain you can define numeric
for the interval in seconds you can
define the platform because you might
have a configuration where you are
distributing information to different
machines some queries are going to be
executed in Linux because they're for
Windows and the other way around because
they don't have a tables so what you can
do really is to limit the queries so
that queries are only executed if they
belong to a certain platform and then we
have sharding for example which is
another configuration parameter say for
example you have to work in a system
with many machines distributed systems
and a bit of them load so what sharding
will do for you is just do
a sampling of the queries that you're
running so it's not going to be
executing them constantly but just
statistically and internally without
really talking to the other machines
it's going to be executed in a
percentage of time say you have a query
with a sharding of 50 percent of hosts
and so what's going to happen is that
50% of the times it's not going to be
executed say I have a query for every 30
seconds if it hasn't happened in these
30 seconds and it doesn't get executed
that's because you have a shot for 50
percent now this is a bit more
complicated but if you're interested in
sharding I think there was an blogspot
the was created where they explain the
concept of sharding and white is useful
when you have very distributed systems
and have many different executions field
we have here is snapshot and this is
quite important because by default with
OS query you are executed when we have
the daemon configurated because when you
are trying on your console all the
queries that are being executed at
snapshot which means they are always
going to be executed but when you have
the daemon configured you you will not
have snapshots unless you can figure
them to be so when you have snapshots
they will there are always going to be
executed whatever it is you will always
get all the data and otherwise when you
have the daemon running and you say well
I want to get processes you generate
those processes and you ask it to give
you the processes again but if the query
is not doing snapshot and no processes
have been added or eliminated then it's
not going to show you anything because
that data has already been generated so
if it hasn't changed then you won't get
data and so people say well I have
configurated it to extract some in
Meishan well and I'm not getting
anything well it's because nothing has
changed because I was clearly can know
internally where the changes have been
made since the last configuration so you
can see it's very powerful but how to
take that into account cuz otherwise we
might drive you crazy because you think
that it's not giving you the uses yeah
but it's only because it hasn't changed
you could also choose to configure to
configure it so that you only get
additions and not when something has
been removed or you can get everything
or you can just get a snapshot and and
then you will see everything now what is
sorry there was a question if you have
yeah it keeps an internal status like a
hash of the result of the execution
because
SQL works with SQL elite as engineering
but it's storing its ephemeral and it
uses rocks DB that's from OS query this
is a fit and the ephemeral database
in-memory developed by Facebook based on
Cassandra and it has several
optimizations and that is what most
query uses in order to keep a register
of queries and configuration and so on
because a risk query is keeping a local
configuration of it's running status and
of the tables that are being executed
and right now the way it works
internally has changed a lot so I'm not
very sure whether that has changed or
not but there is a way it used to work
and the question was how does a square
we know what the outcome is I really
don't know the detail don't know if it
uses hashing or if it uses the outcome
I would need to look into it right
well
anyway so what I was saying is that if
you configure these snapshots to be
queries that generate a lot of
information you have to take into
account are you going to get a lot of
information generated every time this
gets executed so if you want to know the
processes all the time and you're going
to be executing it for a long time
you're going to have a list of processes
all the time so you will have a lot of
information and that is where you where
you need to take into account the
information that is being generated
because this obviously takes up memory
space and when you execute os query D if
you execute the command and you look at
the processes you will see that sim
processes are r-square easy and you have
OS query engine and then the watchdog
which I will mention a bit further in
the presentation I'm going to tell you
how what's dog works so we've talked
about configuration options we've talked
about scheduled for scheduled queries
where they are the intervals and now
we're going to talk about another part
of the configuration which is the
decorators which is basically
information that you add to the results
of the queries that OS query is either
storing or hopefully or sending to a
remote system and basically you can
define decorator can either be used only
when OS query is loading so that every
time it stats you execute that query
because you need that information and
that information would be sent with the
results locks that are being sent to a
remote system or if you want for the
decorator to be
continuously you would configure it as
always now this field is extremely
interesting because when you have a
remote OS query configuration and you
have indexed data in Splunk Kafka
elasticsearch whatever you use to store
your locks this is going to add metadata
to all the information that you're
indexing so you won't need to run
searches or to look for the information
that the host is sending but with a
decorator you can see that this result
comes from this host with a certain ID
and etc and I'm going to show you a few
examples later another interesting
concept about OS query is that when it
was originally created anecdote we
created the the tool we liberated it we
made it open source we wanted the people
to use it because it was very powerful
it did facilitate searches but then
people said what do I do now with it
what queries should I send well I don't
know well what are you looking for if
you doing hunting what do you need what
processes what connections yeah but do
you know have queries for that well I
don't know what you're interested in so
anyway out we have to do is to assess
have like query completion with
information that could potentially be
interesting for different use cases in
this case for example we see that we
have a pack which is the files in the
same format as the schedule fields that
we saw out to configuration so this is
like adding a JSON block so you have one
to monitor the OS query process because
you want to know whether this is
affecting your machines performance for
example all queries which are
interesting to in
didn't respond response such as
compliance my we're at we're known for
Mac we don't really have that much
information about that sort of
compilations but in this way you have a
few the same thing for Windows have run
queries to see if a machine is secure or
not and these are installed by default
when you install OS query in your
machine so if you look for these files
for example always attacks Kampf you
will see if you look for their in the
machine you will see that you've got
different queries and otherwise you can
see it on the repository and github and
the same thing that I have mentioned for
schedule goes for packs format you just
add the name of the pack what you would
have them queries and on the query you
would add the name of the pad will be
interval for the query and the new also
have an additional field which is OS
query version because you might have an
infrastructure which is very fragmented
and you have different versions of OS
query installed you might have a version
which does not have the last or the
latest tables that have been added to
the other versions of OS query but we
have others so for example in this case
the query would say execute this table
only if it is in this OS query version
what I mentioned before about the
watchdog in OS query if you launch this
on OS query ID you will get something on
the watchdog and what it's doing is
looking because necessarily OS query
executes in a given system so it doesn't
request a CPU or groups that's something
you have to look into if you need to
some areas for other functions but by
default the watchdog ensure ensures that
OS query never goes over the CPU or
memory usage it needs to extract
information from the machines without
affecting what is going on in the
machines themselves so if you don't
configure this
the watchdog in OS query will restart
the service if for over nine seconds
air with Korea hell has the the system
at over sixty percent you could - all
the files that I have in my home because
you might find a large file and curry
might start working and this will
increase the CPU above 60% for more than
nine seconds you can set this up
manually I want it to be less
restrictive for example or I want it to
be more restrictive and that's the same
with the allocated memory if you do
queries with a lot of information until
that information is sent then it doesn't
come out of the storage of OS query
there's a query that uses a lot of
memory then the process will do an
analog of more than 100 measures this
will execute if you use advanced OS
query with a table of events for example
you will probably want to move this up
to 300 at least you can get memory very
cheaply so that's fine the shell for OS
query I and ID and I'm going to talk
about the remote IP for OS query to
manage and to work with the tools for OS
control
this is a management service for
therefore the users in this case it's me
because it's an example here we have an
indication of how this would work this
is the architecture and the machines for
OS query we have their status and result
logs that are sent over the Internet if
you choose to do so
it receives the configuration through
the internet if you wish to or not and
you end up with an TLS endpoint which is
the management server and this basically
distributes the OS query configuration
so this is a simplified diagram because
this is the most basic concept of
machines using OS query so this is how
it work with a centralized server so
what can we get out of this you might
say I don't want to set up OS query to
cause me issues using flags and
certificates and so on so that I was
clear he talks to a server so what can I
get out of setting up a wisk URI with a
TLS end point each time OS query talks
to the server and the logs are
automatically sent coming from the
machine and stored then you can use a
concept called distributed queries in
this case it's on demand queries the
same ones that are executed from the
machine itself from the console and the
results are sent directly to the server
it's like having a distributed cell
within the machines that are running
so for investigation forensic
investigation the case investigation of
incidence or internal use and so on it's
very useful it's because it's like
having a cell within that machine
it's a read-only query it's encapsulated
with on the capacities and security and
and performance of OS query so the
solutions that currently exist on the
market for an endpoint TLS some are for
free and some are you have to pay for
them
central is one of the first ones that
came out which is an IT management
system it's not very up-to-date at the
moment and dormand was an interesting
one it was in Python but they haven't
done much maintenance on that for quite
some time now I put a with control in
there several times so you don't miss it
I don't know if you know live ops I
don't if you know carbon black it used
oh s query logs sgt use is in service
server less since restructures from
amazon and some of the most well-known
ones which are commercial solutions like
optics and collide collide also has
another version but it's missing a few
little pieces so to implement an
endpoint TLS it's not very complicated
but you might say oh i'm not convinced
with any of the current situations or
the options that i have and i want to do
during Cobalts then what you've got to
do is to implement a handler so you
implement the handler to
receive the requests the post requests
to have an enroll in the machine it
receives another handler to distribute
the configuration another handler to
receive the logs they can be status
results or query logs and then you also
have to implement some handlers that
I'll show you in a moment
for on-demand queries for file carving
and so on it's not really that
complicated the documentation for OS
query is very well prepared and you have
it here on this URL it can say what the
format will be what to you should expect
it to give you the information you
should expect to receive because it's
very easy to follow because the
documentation is really well prepared
either in flags or air config remote
configuration there are a number of
values that you need to configure so
that OS query can use a remote system if
you have a mutual TLS then you need a
client certificate or a password you'll
have to give the hostname that TLS will
use and these certificates for the
server's if if they are not in their
machine keychain I'd like to point out
that the TLS end point is called that
because OS query can only use Telus
endpoint it was done like that right
from the beginning so that there were no
opportunities for logs that use met a
lot of sensitive information could go
around on the network so you can use os
query to use
HTTP but I don't recommend that because
you have to make a number of
modifications because it always tries to
setup you should always try to set up a
stable configuration that says decision
was taken to ensure that the
configurations were always encrypted and
so on we've spoken about s query I and
you just need to check how much time
I've got left so it 40 minutes yep we've
spoken about os query i/os query d OS
quality with a demon we configure
programs and the remote OS query tool
which is used for programming your own
TLS so now we're going to look at some
of the implementation details and to
present the OS control - it was
liberated in September there is some
documentation available and it isn't
actually complete yet I've got to polish
at it a little bit if there was an
introduction there available but
basically the idea behind it is you if
you have any questions later than I'll
put the information up but you can also
get in touch with me no problem the why
did I write an endpoint TLS endpoint
when I could have used something else
such as doing login within the machine
using the flags or heavy forwarding
[Music]
there were many many different options
for removing the logs from the machines
there's also share for puppet options
for distributing
the different configurations but the
idea of using the TLS end point was the
fact that there are certain things that
the existing solutions I wasn't
convinced about because it would make
you do something in a certain way it
wasn't a modular enough oh it didn't
have the ability to support certain
things and I started writing this in
2016 when optics for example didn't
exist as companies and these companies
were created using the OS query business
model but at the time they didn't exist
so at the time there weren't many
options for a tool of this kind so
writing one of these was because I was
interested in particular in distributing
the configuration I wanted to build a
change in the configuration I wanted it
be as fast as possible and now none of
the solutions that exist are able to
deal with that it's an extraction of
files within the machines and this
concept is called file cards
it's an OS function that's not
documented you can extract files from
document em from documents but you can't
deal with them if you go to those files
you can implement and it works very well
and I'll show you this in a moment and I
really wanted to be able to have
OnDemand her queries I was also
interested in having an open source
solution that I could change as I wished
and at the time there wasn't much else
available it needed to have different
modules and there were things that I
weren't quite convinced with but it
wasn't sufficiently
medulla and I also wanted it to be
scalable and this was particularly
important because when I had the first
version of OS control internally I spent
around maybe 10 Dane's
looking to see if the configuration had
been download and all of a sudden they
had there were 15,000 machines all of a
sudden from 0 to 15,000 I didn't have
enough of capacity in my code it wasn't
a bad experience nothing broke the
service continued and I thought goodness
me that's a good thing that I wrote this
and now when they have issues I know how
to fix them because there are many
machines that have gone down you don't
know what's going wrong with them and
this is when you say oh well I have to
go in there and result that I saw I
wanted it to be modular and scalable and
it was equivalent to the performance of
the TLS that was going to work with so
this is the diagram of the control of
the components there is one thing
missing here that is implemented but
it's not documented but it's in the
repository this diagram looks a little
bit crazy but it's not complicated but
I'd like to point a couple of things out
and I'll probably point out a few more
things as we go along this looks like a
kind of a crazy person diagram but
they're TLS surface is what stores and
receives the logs and distributes
distributes the configuration so that
they had the OS query nodes is
distributed through
Internet is distributed through ng INX
it emits metrics and the information is
stored in the database the main idea of
this direct communication is that it's a
critical point so when you need to make
changes it needs to be balanced the wise
the system will break and stop
generating and you'll lose visibility so
what you want to get from os query you
will lose that so the idea is that the
logs should be sent to servers so
whatever the type they are there could
be Splunk Kafka yella okay whatever so
this is a component of OS control so
this is OS control admin here you can
see I've got internet here but in the
administration console I don't put that
s that in because there one of the
reasons I wanted to get my own solution
was that many of the systems that were
being produced were distributed
geographically and I wanted the solution
to be a one-stop shop solution but
Cornette is basically laptops that
people take around there and there are
thousands of people who have them and so
you can't wait until people are
connected so what I wanted was for the
TL service to receive that and
distribute the configurations
configurations of the Internet meanwhile
the administration servers could be over
the Internet
but in actual fact the operator would
send it over the Internet it could be SS
over sam'l whatever you use for your
internet applications but in actual fact
the access would be through a VPN the
idea is to ensure that the communication
through the administration and the TLS
is done using the backend and that's
internally connected through a network
and it's the same with a net metrics and
so on and you can use this information
for whatever your purpose is and take
into account the critical information
that you're working with you don't want
that to be available on the Internet so
you have this console behind a VPN or at
a similar kind of systems that's a
little bit of a detail Accio so well
Sarah mismo I'm going to show it to you
right now this is taken from OS control
and it's basically a web that shows the
machines then you have configured the
UID unique ID and everything else and
the last component that I would like to
mention is the command line in OS
control usually if you want to see
something that you don't want you don't
want to expose all the metadata but he
have stored in your database and
sometimes you might even want to see it
in bulk or just integrate it with slack
for example or with anything that you
want to do through your are tickets
you're not going to go directly into
your back-end system because you might
make a mistake and instead of writing
system you write delete so really we
don't want to be fiddling with
production systems like that
because em I wake you up on a Monday
morning if you make a little mistake
so in order not to have to do that I
wrote the command console which is
basically an interface with the same
functionality that the packages the
administration packages give you but it
is very configurable and in a very
similar way as I was query so I'm going
to show you a couple of things now but
lastly I would like to mention that it
is highly important to always always
always emit metrics within your system
because usually when you have systems
that are scalable or when you have many
systems it is very important to know
what's going on and to be able to
identify patterns within your graphs
that give you information without having
to go in-depth into all the information
for example here we have a metric graph
that always control deploys by default
and you can figure it so that it's
that's generating it directly and I
think this is a capture of the same data
but for only 12 hours but here you can
see another snapshot for seven days and
here you can see there have been changes
to use that seeing really pattern so
this is just to mention it because
sometimes we didn't realize or because
big data generates a lot of information
stuff but sometimes just looking at this
graph the one at the bottom right you
see that there's a failure but you don't
know what's going on but this is going
to help you to see that on this day
between this and that time something has
happened and then you can locate it and
obviously you can see very interesting
things such as when the employees in
specific time zone go home and they stop
logging because they
shut down their computers and now I'm
going to show you the actual system of
us control which is the same one that
you have on github I still need to add a
couple of things so you have them log in
can you see it at the back yeah I'm
going to zoom in because someone is
saying that they can already see it so
so is it better now right um so
basically I was control and I've been
deploying it whilst we think there was
finishing his speech and I have lunch
there and I'm running it locally on this
machine and I have enrolled the actual
system directly within OS control so you
can see here the metadata that have been
stored in this system you can see the
rolling all the information that has
been sent the decorates is everything
that I have shown you as a fool we are
the status are being sent and the result
locks we are getting are those that
aren't configured here is what we
configure the information these flags
here are the intervals at which the
events for log configuration and queries
are being done queries is on demand and
here we have the configuration as I
showed you before options schedule
decorators it's a very simple
configuration this query is executed
every 60 minutes at 60 seconds and the
locks are sent every 600 seconds so
because I don't have it configured every
two minutes it is being sent now I want
to show you a couple of things now just
a second please see I'm going to put
this on 70 seconds now what happens now
I've saved it and the Machine I have
configured I have configured it through
this one-liner
I'm going to show you this is the script
that is generated dynamically this is
not going to come out because I've done
something for certificates because the
Weiss chrome gives me a lot of pain with
signed certificates now so this is the
local machine what she's seeing right
now just so you see that this script is
generated dynamically with the enrolling
secret which is a URL that you should
not be able to guess and then you can
also configure the system so that this
expires in a few I would say for example
you want to have this expire then it
wouldn't work see so the idea is that
those one-liners that are useful
enrolling machines on demand and I'm
going to show you how to do it I'm going
to lift a couple of virtual machines
with different Linux flavours you can
see everything that I'm getting here
these are be grandma Sheen's by the way
so I'm just going well I'm logged in as
administrators and I have access to
everything to do with administration I'm
going to make a couple of changes here
right I'm going to refresh the
environments to sixty seconds and year
to sixty as well what I'm doing right
now is to be able to show you the back
mode because I have a pseudo cachet
I haven't finished implementing rid is
so I have this right now so I have
changed the flags in this machine but
the flax that I have for this service
that was pre-configured are the flax I
had before but now I want them to be
faster so I have the 360 and 600 here
because this is a local file I will have
to use them one liner to change it so I
activate the command the commander shell
by the way it works on every Linux Mac
and I have another one that is generated
full-powered shell as well to enroll
Windows systems so we execute this here
and now we have an updated configuration
and you can see we have 17 13 and so on
so now the machine has an accelerated
configuration now and we're going to
show you is we're going to enroll more
machines I'm going to enroll a couple
more machines as I was saying so you can
see I am actually creating because I
have a concept within the system that I
call environment so say for example I
have an environment which is the
development environment and you can also
see the notes by platform by the way say
for example you are developing a master
you have a virtual machine there is some
gold in this environment
so how would could I create a new
environment now you would go here to
environment management
and you going to call Yoon environment
cyber camp hostname it's 10.10 tot 10.5
this is my machines IP and this is a
font Eisen
this is from for these CFCs I've chosen
this type because I'm working on an
standard agent which does not make me to
run it as I was query so say for example
in an IOT environment because it's a
smaller architecture or something with
limitations we're always query is not
complete that for one could not run then
I am working on a standard agent that
talks to OS control without needing to
use OS query so this is like an
abstraction of OS query it's a sea to
for production systems so we would do is
create the cyber camp environment and
take into account the way you three and
create your environment if you didn't
create it with the come command console
you would get the flags generated but
you would not get the certificate
generated so what we're going to do is
we're going to copy their certificate
from the one we have already created
which is the auto signed certificate and
what we're going to do is say okay use
the same certificates of Eros query can
talk to the server so I will just copy
right here
upload and there we have the certificate
configured so we've got the flags we're
going to reactivate the enrolling
commands
we've got machines running in the cyber
camp environment and now we're going to
activate these machines so we launch
bears and what's happening right now is
that enrolling has detected that OS
query is not installed it's going to
install it for the platform you
select it now it could be awake so it
could be windows it's lifting the cervix
right now and if you go back to the
environment you can see that this is the
machine that we've just enrolled we've
enrolled it 13 seconds ago it still
doesn't have any status only the
configuration because we had inputted it
at the beginning so you can see how easy
it is to add machines that are running
with OS query and now we're going to do
the same with all these other machines
which is follow the same process yes
there is a question yeah this is
configured so you can use the endpoint
TLS that you're running in this case I
have local machines and what they're
doing is sending loves to oh s control
which is running on my laptop so we're
going in to add here all the others and
basically what we're doing right now
I've got different machines and we're
going to see because I've launched the
service so now we'll see different
machines see a red hat red hat -
Ubuntu's and 2:18 this is a trusting 14
and this is a CentOS I think seven well
so what's happening right now is that
these systems are receiving the
configuration wouldn't have a status log
because the machine has just been
enrolled so it hasn't sent anything yet
so you don't have results yet because
you haven't received these results and
we have the locks configured for every
60 seconds we're going to was still this
is still this has only been there for 45
seconds so we're going to wait a bit
longer to see how this status logs are
going
come in because always query is
gathering them and sending them at the
intervals that we have configured it for
and then you can configure them
scheduled queries that are going to be
sent depending on the interval that you
have chosen for the flags I think the
default configurations that I use are
these values because I have already
tested them and they work well so what
I'm going to do is I'm going to update
sorry I made a little mistake as them
it's going to take a bit longer now but
this is what I'm doing right now which
is basically updating the flash file and
now we should have visit light and we
can have all the locks so you can see we
have a status here so it is sending us
query logs to the distributed system and
the logs are giving you warnings and
everything so you see that there is an
issue and you can detect it so OS
control installs by default the logs
that go to the local database if you
have many machines this is not a good
idea because you would have to contact
all the locks because it would generate
a lot of information so what I would
recommend is well actually something
that I'm working on right now is for
this to show only the last 24 hours or
48 hours depending on what you choose of
the logs that are locally
being stored so that you can have
everything that's been going on this is
only showing the last six hours of logs
but if you need to look at further
information then depending on the log
then you have configured beard gray log
kafka elasticsearch or whatever then you
would get the data now what else can I
show you well if you see here no locks
have been sent because I don't have any
queries configured so I'm going to
configure something I'm just going to
just change something here so I don't
have to write after work
and see that you'd have to check that
JSON is valid because if you make a
mistake here then the configuration is
going it's not going to work
the machine configuration and then you
will have to go back now so we have set
it to 60 seconds if the JSON is not
valid then it tells you that there's a
failure let's ask another query let's
send a system info query so what I want
to do is when I stole this here
this makes the change and because this
sends it to every client next time they
check in which I think it has been
configured to 30 seconds so this is
going to start sending information about
status as you can see publisher etc and
you can start seeing the results this is
going to refresh every 60 seconds by
default so we're going to start getting
the source for the scheduled query which
is every 60 seconds with an S play of
zero and so every 60 seconds we're going
to get that information and otherwise we
could get 60 plus the interval so we're
going to be able to see it in a little
while so this is more or less what I
wanted to show you now for example on
demand queries say you want to check on
Debian nine you want to see CPUs info
either to host select info and in this
way you would have an on-demand query
configured the query is active progress
means that it has been programmed and
hasn't been sent yet
so because it was created 13 seconds ago
as you can see here so the on the query
on demand sends the information every 60
seconds I think is the configuration
that we have so we'll all be able to see
it very shortly we can also have a file
say for example you want to get the /tc
for what slash password for this machine
as you go environment platform ID so I
want to get that information now this
has been completed we can see that the
file has been carved that we can see the
ID the different blocks because you can
configure it according to the size the
for the blocks that you want what kind
of block you one and then you say please
download the file here you go onto the
command
this was can't files theme file here it
is
which is going to move this here so that
it doesn't destroy everything that I've
been doing so now we're they're doing a
tar it's carved files so this is the
machine password so it's very powerful
and all the computers that you have in
the system in two minutes I've shown you
how it works how OS control works maybe
I can show you a couple more things for
advanced users the components they have
a TLS endpoint the metrics the backend
and so on so the next component which is
in the repository and I've tested but I
haven't documented it is the AFI for OS
control it allows you to expose all the
data in the administration controls but
from an API so what I was looking for
with this component you can do it to
integrate it so that you don't have to
do this more than once
so the administration I've got in
westeros I could link it to an interface
or another active component to take the
information from the API and I could
even have communication with a back-end
using WebSocket and this would be even
faster information but one of the reason
for the API is for the relationship that
it has with other projects in this case
it's go query it was liberated a couple
of weeks ago what it does is to
implement a distributed sale using OS
query
through an API it also uses another
couple of things that have not been
documented which is an accelerated
system and so on if you're using an OS
query in a specific way you increase the
interval so instead of it being being
the seconds that you've configured then
it's a shorter interval this hasn't been
documented but it's very good for
research purposes so a couple of things
I wanted to show you one important thing
is that if you're going to use it if
you're going to use query or OS control
feedback test issues what if you're
interested in everything is well we
welcome everything there's one for OS
query one for OS control you can go into
those logs and I write things in there
I've got a couple of friends who use I
was controlling in their businesses and
they add information in there when
things are going well or so on so
feedback is always important and useful
you can use a Twitter and please do get
in touch with me now I've just got a few
minutes left I'd like to show you
advanced across OS query use so if you
now know how to use OS query and you
know how to use your TLS endpoint what's
the next step you could use OS querier
to detect archives perhaps you have
confidential files and you want to know
when somebody is using them you can use
os query for that I can show it to you
quickly I already have a configuration
here for OS query I use file events
through the IP ape API and it returns
the data to you I'm going to configure
this through OS control and you'll see
how powerful it can be for monitoring
purposes I'll show you a case first you
have if you have a docker container for
example in which you have files and
where the database is configured and you
have some credentials that you don't
want to filter so in this particular
case I'm going to show you some queries
so this is the query that I sent to the
machine so in the last ten minutes we're
going to do a little test with the file
interval here we can configure a table
events a table of events is advanced
users because it's very complex but I'm
just going to show you how powerful it
is it takes the information from the
file events and ship it determines the
routes that I want to monitor it can be
binary our files or you or beam or s
been and you want to go in and have a
look what has been going on there for
example you'll be the demo cyber camp in
this particular case because I want to
show you an example in this particular
case we're talking about OS control
because we're talking about machine
development but basics all about looking
at how powerful this function is on OS
control I want s query so this is an OS
query is not sorry
OS control machine
so the configuration was set up eight
seconds so it probably hasn't had a
chance to do anything yet so it probably
has configured for every 30 seconds so
let's just wait a moment until the
configuration has been loaded we'll see
when it is loaded when we see an event
when an event has been activated when
the file events have been activated
and this will give you an alert on the
status logs it will receive the
configuration let's see if the
configuration has actually been sent so
the logs won't be sent until another 60
seconds it's received uptime uptime and
accelerated in 30 seconds and here we
have a little bit of extra information
[Music]
here you have a number of options here
we just have one machine that's being
configurated so it's going to get send
you the alert but when you use events
then you're going to get rid of events
that have expired because events expire
automatically otherwise you'll have many
many events over time so you need to
know when you're extracting those logs
and if you're going to consult do a
query with many different logs you may
get a lot of different events so you
have to keep that in mind let me show
you then how this works in terms of the
events and event files for monitoring
purposes the file we're monitoring is
the file with the credentials for the
database the control database you may
have credentials that nobody can use
because you want a safe storage system
and you want to know if an engineer
accessing that so it's /opt /oc control
splash config slash DB json this is the
configuration of the database and we
need the configuration of the system
there might be system that can only be
accessed by a given machine it depends
on your protocols and your policies in
terms of permission to access the
production systems we have done the C 80
we've accessed the fire and since we
have the events configured so we can
detect accesses to those files the next
time os query sends data if everything
works properly and things go well here
this afternoon then we will see that
access to that file by a user and we can
see how that comes up within the results
so it says he have 15 seconds no it's
not looking good it said last result
three minutes ago
again it says 30 seconds here this is
the trouble with the demos when you're
doing live demos it's executed the file
events just 40 seconds ago let's see if
the expiring is very short
we don't have results but I don't know
why let me have a look I think I know
what has gone on we have a log in the
storage for logs and that was what was
causing us some trouble
so let's cheat here a little bit
one tower we've lifted the service we
should be able to see it here we should
see that has restarted in the status
logs let's have a look at the results we
have the status and the results log we
have the machine that is sending the
logs let me see if I can work out what's
going on
what I'm afraid the demonstration didn't
work as I would have liked it to
I thinks it's doing event expiry and are
going to remove that so that it does not
remove them it's set up for 30 seconds
here that's fine let's let it
configure and I'll continue with the
presentation then we'll come back to
this okay yes now we have it we've sent
it a few times so perhaps actually it
got a bit stuck there so here you can
see the events from the events file with
the category that we put in the TAF the
path that we put in and the a time the C
time and so on so now we have a large
number of events I didn't realize that
they had the event expire one there and
when the event expiry is in one each
time there is a query to the table
events it expires everything that has
been stored so this is why the intervals
are important because if the log hasn't
been sent it's going to go into expiry
and you'll get rid of that so this is
why this part is important so it's
important to see when somebody has
accessed a file that's the point I can't
go into other details of advanced os
query we have file integrity monitoring
writing I've showed you the
configuration I suggest to that you play
with this a little bit using a machine
that you can do that with because it
does generate a lot of information so I
only use the advanced users in
certain situations unless you have a
small tier of machines then actually
before you play around with events you
need to have a lot of agility and doing
configurations and vents but you can as
you can see it's very powerful tool here
we have the query wiki and there's a lot
of documentation there it's very useful
and the same for your rules you can use
os query to do searches in certain paths
for your rules it can be a malicious
binary or indicator that of an attack or
similar you can have her table events
and use them a little bit carefully as I
was saying and os query extensions you
can extend the configuration of OS query
if you just have a information from a
thrift handler then you can access
information from tables that your
interest in it's a very powerful tool
but it needs to have performance as
their priority so you might cause a bit
of a bottleneck depending on the
information that you're dealing with
each extension is executed in a
different process it's simple to create
the extension and you can extend iOS
query for the commands but on the other
hand you do lose a little bit of the
essence of OS query there's a repository
and people who do a lot with s query
port information in there there is
information about analysis of fire where
and a lot of very useful and powerful
information there and that's
advanced users so do we have any
questions no no questions okay so as
query documentation is available on the
wiki it's very well written very well
documented the best thing if you need to
look at is the code the best thing is to
go and look at the code and some of ours
query has not been documented and
obviously there's the website for OS
query we have the repository the scheme
of the tables and so on the OS control
the site for that is where you have the
documentation and the repositories where
you have all the information on what I'm
working on now there are more and more
people using it and so there is more and
more information I do put this
information on Twitter and so on when I
put in new versions so that's all for
today thank you very much for being here
this afternoon especially those who have
waited until the end I understand that
it's not a subject for this late hour
so if you have any questions please get
in touch with me through Twitter or s
Lag you can see me here at cyber camp
thank you for inviting me here today
[Music]
[Applause]