[Music]
one of the other laws beautifuiiy one in
the first place I'd like to think at
Cybercom an exhibit or accepting my
presentation wait it's going to deal
with post exploitation through a
bombshell so we are going to learn how
we are going to execute our post post
exploitation source sins an open source
tool created here in Spain how I like to
talk to developers that may help in a
project in an open source project anyone
may collaborate can modify it can study
the code and add new functionalities and
also this is going to be addressed to
pen testers that may find it is truly
useful this is a description of myself
where I'm working and working in
telefónica in the 11-part laboratory I'm
also a professor in different Spanish
universities and besides talking about
some events such as cyber camp I've
published in C or export publishing so
we're going to learn about ourselves we
are going to talk about different
frameworks that have been used or pen
testing and then we are going to learn
about a bombshell for those programmers
that may know the code they might find
out how to help in this project by
adding new functionalities we are going
to to analyze the architecture its
different ways of working and finally we
are going to execute item shell in real
environments we are going to create a
real scenario real Network and we are
going to use items
so you know they do this presentation
and the later workshop I'm going to use
a Windows 7 computer Windows 10 computer
and Kali Linux computer windows usually
provides 90 days trials these trials can
be activated several times and they are
quite interesting in order to do some
testing especially for those people that
you do not usually is a Windows so if
you want to try this workshop out and do
what I'm going to do you can use this 90
day the trials of Windows the first
question I would like to ask you is can
you do up and testing without tools do
you think that can you do a fan testing
without tools and the second questions I
want to ask is could you do a pen
testing without tools in Windows because
normally we're using different systems
in order to execute these tools so well
reset rate here because it's not that we
are not going to use the tools we are
going to use the most powerful tool of
Windows which is PowerShell so what's
PowerShell when was it created
PowerShell has been installed by default
since Windows Vista and so on so this is
why I was asking if we could do that pen
testing without the tools this is a tool
of course but it's already installed in
the different versions of Windows we are
going to realize that lease a
multi-platform tool windows tool based
on framework and then we will also we
are also going to learn how to execute
power shell in only lineups and other
operating system the first version of
PowerShell was published which launched
in 2006
second version
was modified and was launched in 2009 in
the third version appeared in 2012
confession in 2013 with Windows 8.1 and
November 4.0 and version number 5 in
2006 the sixth version of PowerShell
became open-source so in the 10th
anniversary of Windows 10 they released
the code and this PowerShell code since
then is compatible with all operating
systems and in fact the source code is
found in the repository and this project
that anyone can clone and modify and
adapt to the different environments and
people can even contribute to this
powershell project resource a 7.0
version which is also open open source
is it is d i mean until 6.0 this version
this powershell was not open source
but since 6.0 and 7.0 it is open open
source and 7.0 is under test if we have
a previous version it may not work we
are going to do any we have a very
updated version we may have some
functionalities that are not compatible
with previous versions
so what frameworks are based on
PowerShell there are several interesting
framework searches powershell mafia
frameworks such as powersploit
well the ones that you can see here on
screen there are many functionalities
related to powershell which are related
to pen testing at the same time another
important project that i want to mention
is empire if you work with empire you
may be familiar with
some methods also different framers our
mission our power view and these are
used being used are fantastic tools in
PowerShell as I was saying when we know
these we say that we have 91 modules
currently loaded
we have listeners we have agents as you
can see here so Empire works as follows
is listening server and any one agent is
a machine in which some phone ability
has been exploited and that has been
connected to that listener so post
exploitation has became be done with
Empire and with 91 modules that are
available so let's move to I believe
she'll because we're going to see the
coding don't worry because this is going
to be very basic I just want to show you
to give you an idea of the basics of
item shell and then we're going to move
to real scenarios so where does IBM
she'll come from so the idea of item
shell behind a bombshell is offering a
pen testing tool available at any time
the different steps that we need to take
in order to have a bombshell in our
equipment the following we don't have to
install anything everything is going to
be stored in the memory but we need to
take four steps we have to open the eye
bombshell of Windows we have to download
Chrome to the memory we are working
directly on the memory we are not taught
in the TSP after that we are going to
execute the prompt and we are going to
have any problems that is going to offer
us many functions that are going to be
on the cloud and will be downloaded
whenever we need them when doing pen
testing and you could be able to do
anything you need so the idea is very
simple there regarding architecture
it work first thing I want to mention is
that everything that we are loading is
going to be downloaded and this is great
because we are going to have an updated
prompt at any time if we develop any
functionality and we uploaded it to
their repository when we can load these
items shell to the memory we are going
to have all new functionalities so from
PowerShell we are going to be in sheet
hat and the response is going to be
injected so when we whenever we are
close in the powershell script of the
new console is going to disappear and
everything every time we are going to
need it we are going to download it from
the internet and when we close the
PowerShell session we will lose all
these things in a bombshell in order to
execute memory stuff powershell a
command invoke expression this invoke
expression execute commands and stores
them in its code here you have an
example if i do i'm involved in a
powershell in PowerShell this is going
to download the script and the function
downloaded is going to be stored in the
memory we will be able to use it this is
what we are going to do with a bombshell
in the end a bombshell is a main
function that is going to load in a
dynamic way different functions but we
are just loading a function in the
memory that we are going to execute
later
here well I'm not going into working
wait forever they perform on consoles
now but this is an example this string
is basically a function which is get
processed if we execute that variable
this is going to bring print on this
screen variable here but if we use
invoke expression this command it's
going to be executed in limbo
I mean this is a command that we have
stored an invocation is going to execute
in order to have our repository on the
internet we also have to use well client
downloading download string it's going
to otherwise it will download from the
internet a series of characters that
codifies the function so we are going to
download a stream of Li you have
repository and we can both invoke
expression we are going to execute it so
the idea behind that is quite simple
this is what we are going to see right
now in the coding this is the main
function this is what we are going to
load the rest of the function so
whenever we want to have any
functionality for example let's imagine
that we want we want to have a
understand in order to analyze the poise
when we execute in the prompt of iPhone
shell the function that we want to
download our port scan this is what's
going to you know the function that we
want to download it's going to download
it from the internet and we it's going
to load it and we will be we will be
able to use these are the functions that
we have right now and while I'm going to
start working from here right now can
you see properly I'm going to start
using their visual studio text editor
function here I want to clean this later
but I want okay let's let me see if I
have something here I was going to open
Aidid had
with a story for you to see for you to
try to access the item shell repository
we have a move so that you could see
this it's structured well but the loader
function is here is one of the first
ones but the main thing about the
console is that this is a function it is
a function that inside is loading other
type of functions that are on the cloud
this is the main the main item shell
directory is me here we have written a
license etc license is open your open
source as I've mentioned and it comes so
is what's on the route here on the route
within that we have the rest of modules
that are on the folder that data here we
have the rest of the modules here in the
route we also have function of point
txt where we have all the functions that
we will be able to download the
presentation I also want to mention that
there are two ways of working the system
is we're going to be always the same
my bomb shell is going to execute in the
memory we have working is everywhere
this is a prompt that you don't have you
know you can load it in the memory and
you're going to use it whenever you need
it
Molly whatever so what's the
architecture so we have our computer and
we have the story our computer from a
bombshell it's going to carry the
profitable of a bombshell
this is going to be a more narrative in
the memory and after that we can start
playing with the environment graphically
what would would be that we have a
console that console is going to write
down all the function that it's reading
it's going to write it down in function
point txt so whenever we want to
implement
and we're going to put it there we are
going to keep it within the four data
folder there is a classification pair
folder so we have a section for bypasses
another section or system and then we
have a series of basic functions which
are on the internet so basically we are
going to install them since the
beginning these functions are going to
allow us to see the functions that we
can download that we can load and the
functions that are available right now
for us to execute these two functions
need to be by default these two his
first basic functions need to be
installed by default otherwise I'm not
going to be able to see the functions
that I am so the XE XE XE to function
also may be by default function test
otherwise I won't be able to exceed we
are going to do our first demo first of
all we are going to see how to load this
into our Windows machine Windows 7 then
we will move to Windows 10 and then we
will also see a problem we may find with
Windows 10 because it is true that we
have also witnessed with Windows 10 even
won't be able to use it of their most
interesting part but for both test
accommodation there are also good news
that we will see later story of a
bombshell heart here we are going to see
the string that we have to copy and
paste we see it so I'm more oriented
towards the second of all what is that
we are going to see which is the first
module here is more similarities now you
seen C 2 and we will see that later what
we have to do here you know that to
download iPhone shall you become the
rapist story is pleasing we are going to
do this from the master branch I'm so
I'm going to copy this we're going to
open our PowerShell you have to be
careful here with quotation mark what
marks because in the readme
I think they added extra rotation marks
well before executing these I would like
to show the functions that we have
stored here right now how shall they
don't so in our memory in my memory have
these functions any consoles here as you
can see but now I'm going to download a
bombshell
okay I couldn't copy it oh okay now it
is be careful with quotation marks
because they know there is a mistake
there okay let's see if I have an
internet connection
okay so we've just went to did happen
once you know the to download these into
the memory and now we're going to
execute it eat any more enemies then you
prompted that we are going to have
wanted to show you how to execute very
well this everywhere it is simple as
this and now I'm going to move to
something else so when we go home in one
second in a way of working here we can
make the motion all the functionalities
I mean if we have a function that is in
the memory one and if we can start
interactive interacting in order to
download from windows without having to
install anything however in this case in
the second way of working this is
different and we thought okay if in
PowerShell I can have a console why
shouldn't we try this console to be
controlled remotely and this is how we
this is why we also need to create a C
to accommodate control this was done in
my son and the way it works is also the
right thing oh so on the one side we
have a album self is already part of
some vulnerabilities have been exploited
and it is integrated already and it is
connected to the teacher I'm a new
console and I've been asked to connect
to you and the dc2 is going to race to
the IBM not see it's not going to say
anything
what's going to happen now in East
they machine it even say that has a
bombshell every five seconds is going to
start launching no there to see if it
has to do anything so every time we are
generating a nice function c2 is going
to keep a fire that is going to be
consulting that infected machine that is
called warrior so as part of its own
name for machines here we've called this
computer water is going to be a warrior
the water is going to be asking
continuously do you have to do something
we'll have to do something whenever it
has to do something it's going to
receive that message and it is going to
execute in memory what it has to do and
it's going to give the results back so
the system is quite simple - and what's
the architecture we have their prompt
executed in a memory process we have a
session that has been created that needs
to be monitored because maybe at some
point their machine that's connected
stops working and there may be also
different computers we may have
different computers some of them with
privileges some of them with abilities
and this is divided in different
sessions that we may be able to control
and we may choose to which session we
want to send the command instead of
having the coding in-house shared as
before so we see in Python programming
we have a PowerShell function this power
cell function is a string that stream
it's going to be downloaded into the
memory it's going to inject that inject
in a memory that way so there are two
files which are very important to module
four that that are very important the
first one is that Lisa
we are going to try to break into that
server that is going to send the
connections from remote machines and
then we if we want to we can create new
worlds if we want to inject new warriors
in that machine so how are we going to
connect to that you see here in this
case I'm going to use Kali but you can
use any other system that you may have
but this is the system that I'm going to
use in order to break into that server
that's going to receive the connections
so first I'm going to prepare it so this
has been downloaded from the repository
this is what we're going to see in our
repository well here we have it all then
called a bombshell secure so here we can
see how everything is divided into parts
and how the everywhere module is
different from the rest of the modules
of them work basic memory everywhere
module keeps all functions in the data
folder the more let's see - that is a
aibum she'll see - folder is completely
separate so if I think here on C - I
have like a new different project which
is command and control once their
prerequisites have been installed we can
execute aibum share in order to obtain
their here and I would have to call the
listener we will see this later when we
start creating modules so now that we
have the listener we are going to go to
the Windows computer and what we're
going to do is to execute the console
you know that T
Silas and I are there silently this is a
flood that is going to indicate that we
want to connect remotely well I haven't
configurated the interface ok I love you
and you know they're ready to find it
but yeah if everything Kali 10003 and
Windows machine is co-ceo seven now we
are executing this super power that has
been installed but later in the real
demonstration I will inject this console
with an exploitation process we can
exploit process ok it's not working we
have to with us to define the port which
will have it we've just done a remote
connection we've configured and this is
what we're going to do come on that
you've seen so silently that is related
to an IP is what we are going to inject
the exploit process is the part that we
will inject later so these are the
different ways of working I think that
they are completely really well if we
have the everywhere mode
I mean silently mode we are very
different as you have seen once again
we're going to be able to cooperate with
the project if you're good at writing in
PowerShell or Python
you want to see daddy they code if you
want to modify modified and improved
version you can do it I mean they're
people that have collaborated there at
least I see two right recently I think
in and there was AI someone that did an
graphic interface in order to control t2
for example this is a 14 year all young
neither like programming and decided to
do that so if you also like programming
and you want to extend the functionality
of the project you can do it I mean I
don't she'll is I told that quite under
development
I mean it is like our beta version it's
not a final version but it's true that
with people that used PowerShell in
order to do pentesting we've seen
several presentations about that and I
thought this is great because we are
starting like I mean to develop the tool
and and we want people to use it and we
want of course people to collaborate so
that gross so some of the
characteristics PowerShell the Python
3.6 3.6 then you license docker if you
want to use docker we've done I mean an
image that you can use in order to
download
PowerShell and they Python for you to
play with the two modes
don't become talker and then we also
have their papers and papers in which
there are many more these about my
presentation today if you have any
questions you can go to the papers
section it will of course has evolved
since the papers but the core and the
functionality is well explained there
how we're going to create materials
first of all if we're going to create it
for the everywhere mode or if we create
more deals for PowerShell you're going
to see I'm going to show you some of the
functions we're not still using the
instructor but when you use the help
command lines as a description of what
we're going to do so when executing
their help module we're going to get
this information otherwise if you do
functionality on PowerShell you don't
load it and you don't know how to use it
then here you have a description set up
shares what parameters you need to enter
and when you execute the help command it
will help you to understand what's what
is going on let's see the code of a
certain function this is a function that
I downloaded from the internet it is not
still implemented on PowerShell but we
will see later the function in order to
download external power shell functions
in addition to those which are gathered
at a bombshell repository this functions
name is dead system info which offers
you a brief description of the system
you're executing it is divided into
several functions because when I execute
these in Power Cells it will be executed
at system information even if the name
of the file is get system info the main
functions name is get system information
this one the PS one has several
functions which will be
when the main function is called and all
of them have you know that you have
parameters I not serious description and
so on so we should get system it says
main function it has it sign up sales
description how it is used and then you
will be able to use it if I'm not wrong
I think I had it over here I hurry done
de Cali retool machine I am going to do
in line with the following demonstration
to have a bombshell on your own server
I'm going to download it
Judis let's imagine now we're saying
that this a bombshell is indeed hub and
that's the philosophy the idea is to be
able to download it at any time from
github if you have access to internet
let's imagine we are in an internal
network and there are only a few
computers within that network but we do
not have yet happen that's what I'm
going to do I'm going to use to do my
demonstration you know the tool left to
this server and then we will be able to
play with our own server and I'm going
to download it from github as I did in
my first demonstration what I'm going to
do is to have it on my own server if I
do some if I make some changes
everything will be in my virtual machine
so what are we going to do first of all
we are going to download the iBook
shellcode in the server that was select
I'm going to you
Kalli machine in order to do it here
then we're going to do the invoke
expression to call the part of the
memory and it is going to be mounted
here in our repository so what are we
going to modify if we review the console
code we can take a look at code revision
of no more consult here you have some
parameters it can be used in proxy we
have the assignments lee mode so there
will be a condition which says if this
is here you're going to execute it in
another way here if you have the loader
function through which you are going to
receive the function then you want to
download and this is the one that we
load that fraction you know the to do
cell eight recurs to make request so
there is a function that makes the
request and the request will send us a
string in order to inject it in the
memory here we have several functions
such as the read functions function and
there is another one in order to say if
in do register and here it's the
important part where are we going to
point at where I am going to download it
from we need to do some modifications I
wish that in the future we will be able
to modify it and set it up without
loosing the main nature of a bombshell
I'm not paying for a server I'm done
loaded in directly
we need to reject because everything we
write has to be redirected if we have
the silence li mode it is going to
execute everything here otherwise if
it's not silently mode it will go on the
other side so here it's where we're
going to point that I have modified it
already here let's say if it's over here
yeah here it is
so I am lifting it to my own machine
which is set up with a 1000 3 with the
port number 8,000 yeah
as I was sayin will lift our server on
this machine the East easiest and
fastest way to do it is that I could use
an Apache but there is another easier
way which is Python when I learnt the
Python with the mode simple HTTP server
because it has left it a server and if I
access the direction 1000 3 where the
server has been lifted will see the root
of where I am so I am within I won't
share part ok so here we have our server
everything's right over here Windows
machine the only thing I'm going to do
here this is the listener but I'm going
to point at you need to make a
distinguish between the listener which
is in port 8080 and the repository which
is in port 8000 here I have the
connection notice that we were pointing
at did have to load this memory part it
from our virtual machine from Daisy 1000
three
so that's how you lift a Bible on our
own server you have seen is quite easy
to do do you just have to do three steps
to have our own i bombshell in our cally
machine which is the server that i just
created make some changes on this cally
machine which will be reflected on that
i powershell about modules and ways of
working if we if we have looked at
functions on i bombshell
let's see how those functions work here
I was saying within a bombshell
repository you have I bones shall see
two which is pythons part if you look at
here you have several functions we can
review some of them first of all you
have template dot P I which tells you
how to implement a second module from
the city this is a custom module object
that depends on module and we have all
the information about it in order to
show what that module does we also have
the options we will need we will always
need it to be pointed at where one of
our machines undersea to control is to
know where we're going to send our
functions and then we have the variable
variables that we want to select maybe
we want to execute a command so we would
need a way to reset a code to send a
common and we will do
here we have a list with three values
initial value if we want to give it one
we see it in the listener mode if we
lift the listener mode it says that you
will be redirected to the port 8080
unless it specified the opposite then we
have description and finally you have
the information of whether it is
recovered or not if it is required
you cannot launch this module without
activating this option if you will so
you need this option is required and
then it needs to be activated then you
have the information of the module then
you have the rim method which is
PowerShell function but the project is
from Python and this string is belong
the PowerShell function installed in our
memory the first thing you need to do is
to define the function but you need to
call it and in order to do so this file
is going to look for our where air if
our warrior execute is these function on
the memory you need to execute it and
then you have to execute this boom
function so boom - M because we had a
message that indicated true so at least
we need to add it here this is going to
generate a file which is going to be
called by the warrior and it is going to
be downloaded as you see it is quite
easy to create modules my Python modules
are
right easy the most difficult part is
the eye bombshell part because it is
what's going to be executed this is
quite easy unity for cues mainly on
power cell scripts if for example we
opened a listener a different one
because we're left in a server even if
it is listener were left in a server why
we are going to make consultations on in
order to see if they contain something
so it is a bit different from the others
if we open another one like this one we
see that we also have the function maybe
it is a more it is more complex than the
template but you have the real one we'll
start from the beginning we have the
definition of dimaggio it's requirements
and so on and then we have the real
module with the power shell function
which is verifying some conditions in
order to enter some things or other
things then the power shell function and
to call memory okay now we're going to
see a real scenario now we know the two
we know how to create modules we know
the two ways of working
we have tried them only on the surface
but we're going to try them now in a
real environment this is the scenario
we're going to follow we have the callee
machine where we have the repository
which is going to be pointed there and
we have the listener then we have the
windows 7 machine
the Windows 10 machine the first
demonstrations were going to do are the
following only with Windows 7 machine
and to know the everywhere mode then
we're going to have the 1001 with the
listener and our idea was going to send
it from this machine to the Windows 7
machine and finally to pass it from with
the 7 to Windows 10 everything through I
Borgia so let's go for it and before
this one turns off I'm going to reset it
manually if it allows me to do so they
have 90 days trial they can reset
themselves and I don't want it to happen
in the middle of the demonstration I'm
going to wait a little bit in before
start in Windows 10 ok machines are
connected within an internal network all
of them are connected to each other
Windows 7 Windows 10 and Kali I have in
Kali we have the listener which he was
executing but I'm going to stop it
because the Windows 7 machine if we turn
it on it will have turned this one off
it says is dead detects it's that every
time you leave the C 2 mode the files
dead because in the end it is always
making consultations on whether there
are or not any files and we're going to
lift it on our own repository
okay let's move on to powershell now I
will leave this open for later and we're
going to download the everywhere mode if
we want it if you want to work on
everywhere mode let's see if it allows
me to do so okay let's see since we have
seen everything we're going to focus on
the tool itself what can we do with a
bombshell in everywhere mode let's do a
small demonstration if you don't have
the manual of instructions to read it it
can be actually a bit intuitive it says
you can use show Commerce in order to
see what commands are available to be
downloaded and then you have this show
function in order to see what we can
execute because we have downloaded it
already we have all these available I am
going to start loading basic function
for example the help function how can i
download the functions just clicking on
just copying the name of it in the case
of help it is not in any subfolder in
any category so function loaded so the
following that we can load in order to
scan ports is here in scanner TCPS come
there is a function that analyzes ports
so let's copy it how can i load
functions just type in their name and
how can i execute them now just invoking
that I may not know how to use these
module so then I execute the help
function and here I have the information
of the module this is a beta version so
there are some things that have not been
yet implemented we want instruction
information for people to know how to
use it and here we have the basics
intern syntax of this function as you
can seen I have lifted the 8080 the 8000
port in the callee machine so I am going
to execute TCP scanned from a range only
not too not free to take it long so I'm
going to invoke TCP scanned with IP 1000
3 and let's specify a range seven nine
nine nine two eight zero zero zero one
so these start scanning and there it is
upward scanning in memory you don't need
an nmap in other to scan ports if
everything is destroyed somebody may
think isn't it isn't there any
possibility to be able to save what we
have in the memory for example I do a
lot of audits and I usually start with
theses TCP scan can I already save those
functions you know that not to download
them all the time in memory yes we have
the save function look look at what it's
doing
it is directing to the registry it is
saved
all these scripts that we have
downloaded here in this case only help
function and TCP scam function it has
the current user it has created an entry
line by line to recover it later let's
go to the registry so you see I should
have shown here these earlier but if you
execute this on your computer you won't
have it it has saved their functions I
have downloaded their help on TCP
functions and look at what it does it is
storing the function in register code so
that when we open a bombshell the first
thing we're going to do is to look at
the registry if there is something on
the registry it is going to load that
content so if everything works fine I am
going yeah I am going to live here to
quit and I am going to launch the
console usually this function is not
loaded but when I launch it it is going
to make a consultation on the registry
in order to download our functions
let's see these usually takes longer
because it has to recover from the
registry let's see if it loads the
functions
otherwise I will download it again
yes that's what I'm going to do because
it's made slow
let's see if it loads it yes we see them
here if we didn't have these functions
in the beginning since now I have copied
them I have been available for me to
execute them but maybe we did not have
access to info to internet in agonal
repository there is a part that invokes
PowerShell that needs to load the
console mode from the registry that's
what you will need to do if you don't
have access to the Internet and then you
could keep on working another function I
had mentioned was there a possibility to
download external functions I'm going to
see the commands yeah it is this one the
loader text to load external functions
since I am pointing at the normal server
now this may not work because all the
references are pointing at github let's
see if it works we have a small catalog
as a sample catalog because here we're
pointing at Empire projects we have also
PowerShell Mafia the powers Boy Floyd
that has many functionalities and we
have decided to include some of them
here I can't open any more
let's see if it works
[Music]
every time you have a problem you can
call the help function so it says we
have two possibilities with the loader
loader xed to execute the catalog where
we have included some proposals or the
or they URL which is not finished yet
let's see if I didn't right here we have
it yeah it has loaded it or maybe not I
think I yeah I was executing help
function let's see if to the other
machine
yes it's loaded so here we would cede
the invoke of the DLL injection all the
functions on power said which I oh no
the repository can be loaded so we can
provide support to people who have their
own functions in order to use them let's
move on to X the x post exploitation
part we're going to start a meta exploit
console and what we're going to do is
the machine the Windows 7 machine has a
vulnerable application
let's imagine we have already done
search for vulnerabilities so in that
exploitation process I'm going to inject
DLL from the remote i/o bombshell so
first thing to do you may be wondering
how can I create DLL from a bombshell
let's launch again the panel this is the
commands that we can execute with load
we're going to load modules with show
we're going to see the information the
description the author shape and the
fields at some points you will see which
of them are required and they have to be
activated as you see this is the setting
it has with room we launch it so the
listener module is ready the 8080 port
the next module I'm going to launch here
you can see the c2 sections so there is
one module for bypass another one for
credentials execution files so modules
for OS X persistence we're going to see
some of them here is the generate module
within these module we have all these so
we could generate in a very easy way for
a macro for the CVD for rubber ducky so
for example if I execute the rubber
ducky in this case this is a required
field so I have to set IP and write the
direction 1000 3 in the port we have a
default value
and here we can decide whether we want
to save the code in a file if we want to
generate the file and save it into the
rubber ducky and here with room it is
offering me the information that I just
sent it so we are going to use the one
that says generate DLL in this case we
want to I'd be to connect to us and we
are going to keep it somewhere in our
system let's keep it here for example
fruit Cybercom dot dll so here I should
be able to see and I'm going to execute
it because I'm if I don't execute it I'm
just going to be establishing the
variables I have to execute now we have
generated our DLL and we are going to
use it so as I was saying we're going to
lunch may exploit and as we already know
that this machine has already vulnerable
we're going to exploit it and we are
going to connect to our listener through
the DLL the Windows 7 machine what I'm
going to exceed this
so that Windows 7 machine has been
prepared with a couple of
vulnerabilities in this case this
application okay this is open right now
I'm going to launch it again okay so
this trial version just lasts for 30
minutes which is enough for these
examples so well they said we're server
this is an application without web
server that once had a vulnerability and
I'm going to use that vulnerability well
I'm not going to explain Matt exploit
because this is the tool that we are
going to use to explode their their
vulnerability but you can use to draw a
turkey wherever you want to this is just
an example that we are doing through DLL
all these tools all these pen testing
tools and vulnerable exploits tools
usually have their own strong and with
item shell it works similarly so this is
their way of setting firewalls well I
don't know if you can see it very well
but one of the requirements here is the
machine that we are going to attack or
where we won't exploit that
vulnerability
only a fella will achieve it in this
case windows 7 so 0:07
so what are we going to do once this
vulnerability is expertise we want if we
can use a metal cutter if we want to get
a meterpreter console but in this case
we're going to use our DLL so DLL inject
if we show the options right now we're
going to see that the payload options
are defining our DLL as we've created
one we are going to write it down set
DLL fruit cyber camp dot DL n so let's
see if I've said it
each right ok I'm going to launch it to
see if it works the listener is
somewhere here
and while I'm going to punch it again
okay let's try again some something
failed okay let's wait because if the
exploit is working fine and the model is
working fine it should work okay it
closed list let's try again
0:07
okay I think now it should work okay I'm
going to try something else
okay forgot to do something which is
generating the DLN is that my system is
32 bits the requirements is 64 bits but
I have a deal and that I've generated
and I'm going to change it I'm going to
replace it this one is for 32 bits
what about our sister okay let's see now
it works with this one I can't see if
not only now it's working it was a
problem with yet any question so now I
have our variable available well I'm
going to launch it manually I think this
symbol here in a problem I mean I don't
want to connect with privileges because
later we are going to do a bypass in
order to obtain privileges from aibum
shell but I already have some privileges
because I've launched the the process
that way knowing to try to do it with
Khan Academy no of them okay now that
sees a different one okay so this is
another application which is vulnerable
well I almost appear to me hello I'm
going to set the payload of Windows DLL
what animal you live in either okay so
we've already defined the host the DLL
this is the one that may work let's see
if they Konica Minolta which is
somewhere here is going to send us to
give us a shell without privileges okay
we have the listener here we have the
DLL let's see if this program okay now
before this is you know the to identify
that we have privileges but in order to
work in a more real environment we want
to start exploiting a vulnerability in a
system that doesn't have privileges
because we have to forget that
privileges afterwards I want to do any
process that requires admin privileges
such as achieving passwords I cannot do
it so this is why I want to go from here
to a machine with privileges there if we
are lucky enough to find a process with
privileges and we get back these
privileges then part of the world would
have been done already it would be more
simple so the warrior command allows us
to do different things with warrior such
as killing listing or renaming so as it
may be a little bit confusing where I'm
going to change names and this one is
going to be called for example Windows 7
Italy almost 80 bypass where was it so
then we're going to bypass UAC bypass
what's that exactly when we try to
launch an application or when we are
launching an application that needs
abilities these windows pops up anyway
that if you AC bypass we can execute our
process with privileges without having
this window popping up so this is what
we want to get these that's our
objective we want to execute privileges
skipping the UAC this is a control
measure is it means either account
control of Windows and it's been working
for a long time when we were having
Windows Vista Windows Vista this was
popping up every now and then and it was
quite tiring for the users having this
window all the time but in Windows 7
they decreased a little bit their level
of intrusion when is UAC
Viper's going to work it's not always
going to work we need to meet certain
requirements for example the user that's
executing the processes in the machine
she'd belong to their admin team it
doesn't have to be the main admin but it
should be part of the admin team and
also the UAC configuration must be by
default because this has certain levels
if we want to to be to have this window
popping up all the time we have me set
things up in order to have this so
certain requirements must be met because
I in the end this is their window that
we want to screen we want to scream when
this house had many UAC bypasses
throughout his its history and Windows
doesn't even considered it as a
vulnerability sometimes it's a
use characteristic there are many ways
of skipping that screen that window
sometimes there is a process that may
look for a dll in order to execute it
and if it doesn't exist it's going to
use their DNA library the main deal and
library people that found this out for
example there some processes of Windows
that are executed with abilities all the
time so the bypass tries to get in the
middle of these processes that is
privileges in order to target the code
that we want to address so this looks a
DLL in the registry and it would help us
do the bypass so we're going to execute
this in a process with privileges for
example if we have here here we have the
I am a bombshell connection process this
machine will have privileges who needs
to replicate the UAC bypass in order to
get our warrior back when we do our USC
bypass we are going to execute coding it
maybe just writing a unit C but if we
don't have the permit to write in C we
are not going to be able to do so but
what we are going to do is inject in a
command that gives our spark directly
are another warrior and in order to do
so I'm going to use their bypasses UAC
bypass here we have several bypasses and
the one that is working in my
environment is this one so what do I
need to do I need to introduce the
warrior that's going to execute this and
then optionally I can give an
instruction if we don't give an
instruction it's not going to do
anything so Windows 7 plus the
instruction I think it is somewhere here
we can see it's kind of long I'm going
to explain to you what it does
well Louie up under our Laura let me
take one Olivia very much so when we say
we want to execute an instruction I mean
we normally say I wanted you to give but
another eye bombshell with PowerShell I
mean I'm going to bring up a PowerShell
process you know they're to inject if we
use PowerShell next thing it's not going
to be found so we need to write down the
pathway exactly one way Windows
PowerShell the pathway man we are going
to execute a command this white we have
here minus CN minus C involves
downloading what we've seen in this
workshop it's going to go to github or
our normal repository is going to
download and it's going to be to execute
return in a silently mode so let's see
if this works when this machine is not
noticing these because there are no
alerts popping out so here we see that
we have another warrior which has
privileges this is what we are looking
for before we got the privileges because
their process was being executed you
know from high level so here we can see
the start so the start means that that
you know session has privileged easy if
not it doesn't have privileges and now
we're going to rename these two I'm
going to rename all these things so that
we can identify them better this is
going to be Windows 7 so ok I've changed
the names here I'm going to start
bringing up all the machines now we are
playing with Kali with Windows 7
let's introduce another agent in the
game we're going to tradition that uses
Windows 10 what we bring data
we're going to do something else okay
let's see in which part of the
demonstration we are okay that's the
scenario we've done a finger printing to
live into medicine okay let's play a
little bit with this we're going to do a
lateral movement in order to get to the
Windows 10 watching we need to know the
admin password you know that to do so so
the admin password normally is the same
for all the computers in the same
network you know that to be able to
being able to we may use that in order
to achieve the credential that's right
this is what we're going to do now
however we can do something else which
seems silly but visually I'm sure that
you're going to like if I have here a
machine with Windows 7 we have a module
here that has been called phishing I'm
not going to explain what phishing is
but it's like faking something so let's
see we have who's going to bring this
our ok we're going to bring it up with
our normal Windows 7 system here it says
title name and domain we have some
information by default but can you
imagine what I'm going to do ok let's
set title here
what is it if you cannot be the
passwords friendly user for them what
would you do if you see the odd screen
okay you start right in this is my
username and this is my password this is
that screen is going to Philly and
that's it if I don't have their
credentials I'm going to try to ask take
credentials to the machine now we're
going to get the hashes from that
machines I have privileges and now I
want to get the credentials here we are
going to lose their power time function
and that's going to allow okay the
hashes everything is quite well
developed we just have to generate
modules configure ate them and launching
them and launch them if I decide to
launch those windows 7 normal warrior
it's going to say that it doesn't have
the privileges to do what that function
doesn't have admin privileges but this
is why don't bypassed update in order to
get these type of abilities and here we
can see all the passwords all the hashes
as I've said before in an organization
we all have the same acne with a
password so that the general admin can
manage administrate all the machines
remotely this is going to be very soda
machines are managed in the same network
variable to use their ID mimic as well
in order to move from a Windows 7
machine to the Windows 7 machine let's
see if we had it here very if the
Windows 10 machine has been already
brought up well giving it
I'll get them into anymore okay so here
we have you are Windows 10 machine Jamal
Khalifa released maybe a safe and we are
going to use SMB T so what's here so
here we are going to decide it's going
to initiate but not really movement the
warrior that's going in to execute that
in this case those have been my son's
going to use that the target is their
remote IP the Windows 10 machine tours
we want to move to and then we have the
admin hash that we need in order for
these unnatural movement to happen so
the target is 1000 10 this is my Windows
10 machine or at least it should be
I'm going to check it ok so yes it is
1000 10 I'm going to get the heist from
up here and here is very important we
just want to check that we've done there
we can do a write it 1 C and in order to
show that but we want to agree another
bombshell another Windows 10 that we
want to include here so we're going to
launch again what we've what we had
before so here you have set command
we're doing the same thing as we execute
how
we're going to execute it like that and
if it works let's see if it works if it
works we're going to launch it when we
know seven machine is going to receive
an instruction is going to execute it
and that we newsstand machine I mean
we'll be able to break into there I mean
there's ten machine from the Windows 7
machine
so we've achieved I witness this to a
term to get into our Windows 10 session
and with privileges and we have plenty
of time and went to the same thing but
doing a UAC write husband Windows 10
first I will have to bring up a normal
session but what let's finish with this
process first because we can do more
things here three machines here they're
all alive one of them is kind of week we
will see graphically I'm only I'm going
to rename these two this is Windows 10
with privileges okay so we inside the
windows 10 machine so what else can we
do now that we Windows 10 now has am
sayin I told you that there is something
good about Windows 10 and I bombshell
because currently Windows is already
detecting a bombshell as a malware and
it doesn't let you store it in the
memory with Windows 7 it works fine but
Microsoft is now aware of a bombshell
and he's protecting memory from that and
how does it know how malicious process
is being stored in the memory because I
mean with an anti-virus you can analyze
the disk in order to see what's going on
but when we are working at the moment at
the memory level a that option didn't
exist
so this wife is working what we are
doing right now
we understand is verifying the memory -
and what does it mean so nowadays it
realizes that bombshell is there and
alerts you if we are using that all the
windows fashion we could disable the
malware for example the power more than
my mate I've already detected that and
but this is a new tool this is not going
to be detected in this case with a
bombshell we can bypass C of Windows so
when MC is trying to check if there is
something we are in the memory Windows
Defender is going to be alerted but with
the part what we are going to do is
watching it so that it is not executed
so we are going to move to there MC
bypass and okay the worry it's going to
be requested this is Windows 10 case we
are not going to be able to see anything
I mean we're going to now we are going
to clean it up in order to see what
happens if ourself so that you can see
that this is executed in PowerShell and
it includes so that the unsafe is not
executed and if we disable I mean when
we do our Nancy bypass now it is party
the last thing that we can do here with
with a bombshell is disabling the wind
the windows are the virus so here we
have monitor we are going to write down
the end of your time here we just have
to to type the warrior
wait where it is located and we want to
say we want these to be enabled or
disabled we are going to say that we
want the antivirus to be disabled
and from now I mean with the Alsea of
the Windows 10 we've don't Lee I'm
survivors and we've disable the
antivirus so now we can do whatever we
want to so we're going to look the MC
into detail let's kill warriors now
maybe it's not necessary unless final
parties do a bypass to Windows 10
because now winters dear 10 was used as
an administrator but let's try to do a
bypass no I'm gonna do it directly here
so first thing to do is to download it
so for that I have to copy and then
going to connect manually so everything
that I execute will appear here on the
console manually and remember the
parameters silently silently and Yuri
console in their 10003 port 8080 see
here we have one of them for machine
ones went at seven with our privileges
windows have been with privileges window
10 with privileges until new one I'm
going to rename it and call it wind 10
to know which one it is the first thing
we're going to do our bypass from UAC
and when we apply and see if we want to
do a bypass that we want to
we would have to need to patch the MC in
order to execute the UAC
so let's load the module of bypasses
from the MC in this case it would be
Windows 10 first scan from MC has been
part but and now we're going to do a
bypass UAC
this is going to do this is the K I was
mentioning earlier it is consulting with
in the registry if it it's pointing a
DLL and we need to come in first we need
to inject DLL in Windows environment
requires warrior IP import so warrior is
normal Windows 10 and we want to connect
two 1000 three that's the IP address we
want the port 8080 so let's see because
it is short lunch a new PowerShell
Windows 10 process with elevated
privileges as you see the list is
extending now we have Windows 7 and
Windows 7 with privileges window 10 and
window 10 with privileges and a new one
that was generated through the bypass
and I'm going to rename it window 10
[Music]
privileges in the same way we could what
we have already done as earlier we did
the lateral movement from windows 7 to
Windows 10 it was generated with
privileges but if the if we didn't have
privileges we would start with the
Machine Windows 10 so our process
without privileges that we need to
upgrade and from there to patch and so
on finally the last demonstration was to
pass the harsh through lateral movement
here's the end of my workshop I think we
have some time for questions so please
feel free to to ask
thank you for your presentation a lot oh
I wanted to ask you if you're going to
introduce an association method between
the infected client and the UC are you
going to implementation method to
analyze communications yeah that would
be quite interesting actually requests
are made through HTTP the connection
could be made through HTTP but now it is
done through HTTP but with encrypted
content the project is open source so
anyone who dares and who understands
about this I encourage you to do it in
order to make the project improve any
other questions good morning
congratulations on your presentation why
do you use don't care what is hideous do
you know how docker
works right yes but I don't know why the
tool has docker what we took image of
docker in case you want to lift the c2
from docker or if you want to launch the
everywhere mode from docker just in case
you have that image any other questions
okay no further questions then in that
case let's leave it here and thank you
very much for your attention
[Applause]
you