[Music]
thank you this is a good morning to
everyone my presentation is called The
Adventures of an expert on computing and
I want my presentation to be fun I want
to drop draft-dodger attention I want
you to ask me questions and of course I
want you to for you to know the
difficult tasks that involves that have
been computing expert it is a very
interesting job it is very well paid and
it is it also has a great potential for
technical and legal and technical people
I think that it is a career which is
becoming more and more important well
I'm a professor in the Polytechnic
College School of the University of
Cassidy's and my estate number is 103
you know that we are computing expert
you need to be part of the computing
experts association I would like to also
introduce two people that have been
referenced for me in the field of
computing expertise these people are and
risk Adam he's my teacher he's taught me
everything I know and Jose Rodela
Garcia who's also very important
reference and we have half the chance to
create
degree in the university of Extremadura
of computing expertise and also I would
like to introduce to you my assistant
today this is the person that's going to
help me in this presentation he's going
to be asking some questions during my
presentation and
also terrifying some concepts I would
like to think of course in fever for
organizing cyber camp this is actually
my fourth or fifth cyber camp I
participated in Madurai 2015 I did a
presentation on forensic analysis of
this I started working on this bill in
2015 this picture was taken by one year
together with Ayane
and yen when other colleagues are in
charge of doing an investigation tasks
or in the event in 2016
I brought some students from the
University of leh of Extremadura to
participate in the hackathon of Leontes
not 16 I think this is very important
and in Mullica 2018 I gave a
presentation which was kind of
controversial because it was about
authentication systems of university and
what was my presentation about today
well my presentation is about four cases
well three real cases of on computing
expertise and also some problems and
recommendations about these professions
these cases are completely real these
are my so-called
adventures the first case is about an
information leak leakage of information
the second case is about an
investigation you know that you
invalidate some digital evidence for a
trial the third case is about taking
some payments between a company and the
administration's and finally I'm going
to talk about these difficulties and
recommendations but my objective in the
end of this presentation is to explain
real concepts applied to these real
cases concepts related to computing
expertise that may not sound very
important but that in the end are
significant and I want you to be aware
that this is important and that we need
more computing experts
first of all I want to ask this question
what forensic analysis we all know some
foreign forensic experts but we all
think about doctors right but forensic
analysis is Ana specialized technique
that allow allows us to identify
preserve and I will explain this later
and analyze digital evidence that are
going to be presented in a legal
procedure with the maximum technical and
preservation guarantees we will also
talk about the custody chain and in one
of the cases I will explain this chain
was completely broken doing these
forensic analysis is a methodological
process we need to be very
methodological we need to know
legislation in depth not to break off or
violate the basic rights of people and
we need to also pay attention you know
that not to invalidate digital evidence
we will see also how to do that and also
we need to be experts we need to have
expertise knowledge because afterwards
we will have faced a lot of we will have
to face judges and lawyers and we will
have to talk to them and answer the
questions so let's start with the
interesting things the first case was a
case related to an information leakage
this is these are real cases that happen
on daily basis in this case we had an
information leakage and this the
investigation needed to find out if an
employee of a company with a parent with
stealing information and I'm going to
give you more details what's what was
the context the background when we do an
expertise report we need to explain the
purpose of the report this was a company
without
that was in charge was devoted to
manufacturing manufacturing doors so
what is an computing expert doing in a
doorman factoring company well it's a
good question but I was working there in
that case so then we have the employee
that we need to investigate this was an
investigation job and when the company
contacted us at first they said that the
employee was stealing information from
the company the holidays in August they
saw the employee putting a USB in a
computer of their of the company and
after holidays when they starting they
started manufacturing new designs the
employee was not working there anymore
and they couldn't keep on working on the
new designs so they had a problem with
the new designs and this is when they
decided to let us know about this
problem one of the biggest problems when
you are working as a computing expert in
a situation like this one is
understanding the context the scope and
the limitations this is why my assistant
is saying here you must think before
acting this is an important thing an
important idea to keep in mind you need
to know the system very well before
doing anything in this case the employee
was working in a manufacturing chain in
a production chain there were like eight
nine processes involved from the cut of
the materials they're designed
assembling testing etc the employee was
working specifically in the design area
so first the material of the door was
cut and then the design process to play
in which more accurate cuts were done in
the door etc and the important thing to
take into account is that the company
had a patent they had an assembling
system that made them very competitive
and the employee as I was saying was in
working in the second process of the
production chain he was working in a
machine that was connected to our
computer and that was in charge of of
performing the design so okay this is
the context we are understanding it as
we can see the employee had to type or
do to work on the computers in order to
generate the designs and the designs
were generated with some coordinates
this machine would interpret the
coordinates from the computer later and
apply them second thing that we need to
do is to establish the facts so we said
that in our report we need to say the
purpose the scope and now the we need to
establish the facts the first thing that
we started thinking as experts and
investigators was that we needed to
study the information that existed in
that USP so before acting before doing
anything we needed to analyze the
information existing in that USP then we
had to compare that information and to
see if it was related with the
production information of the company
which is logical and then we have we had
to look for possible evidence is that
show that there has been an information
leakage from the company we need to look
for the evidence that showed that there
was a leakage of information well in
also in all reports we are going to say
that the expert
not going to assess the content on the
digital evidence the expert is just
going to use the information in order to
establish that possible leakage of
information so starting point so to
speak and this is how or when we can
start working with our digital evidence
our digital evidence was once so far
which was the USB USB that the company
gave us and that the police had taken
from the from the employee so the police
force was involved I was saying before
that it is very important to preserve
the evidence this means not we don't
have to alter or manipulate the evidence
because otherwise we are going to
invalidate the evidence so here we are
we are in a position of advantage
compared to doctors forensic doctors
because we can take the digital evidence
and we can do an identical copy and and
that's exactly the same as the real
evidence as you may imagine forensic
doctors cannot clone cannot duplicate
people so this is an advantage that
without that we have this preservation
of the evidence is done through
different coding software's we can do an
image of the pendrive a USB and clone
that image and we have to also show that
the evidence is preserved and that a day
and when if we calculate their hands
code which I will explain later we can
guarantee that we have an exact copy of
the evidence in this case
ah so si la policía de hecho I didn't
know if that police forces had done
duplication of the USB before so we
duplicated these USB before an artery
and we left a copy also on that notary
obviously know that to preserve these
costly change next thing that we have to
do is analyzing the information on that
USB so once we have the copy the
truthful copy of the USB they the real
USB is not being used was not being used
we are working all the time with a copy
with a replica replicate because if when
working with the USB we make a mistake
we delete something we changed something
we can clone again we can duplicate
again the original USB and restarts you
the process so this is why working with
a duplicate is important so once we
started analyzing the USB we realized
that there were files sequential namings
from 1 to 512 and these files contained
the design and the recycling the design
of the machine used in the design
process
so what what's next I want to ask you
that question once we've analyzed that
information what should we do so our
next step is starting the investigation
we have to go beyond we need to look for
things that may not be visible and this
implies looking for information
information exhaustively you know you
speak we can look for the hidden in
when we put information in a USB we put
music etc and afterwards we delete that
music physically physically you are not
deleting that information I mean
something physical physically deleting
something is something when you delete
with an eraser on a paper but when we
are talking about the computing field
there is a logical erasing you are going
to delete something in order to have
space to put more things but the
information is still there and that's
what the forensic analysis implies we
are going to recover this deleted
information once we've deleted that
information we can study the metadata
which is something very important when
drafting an expert an expertise report
and then we have to order to organize
that information do you know what we
found out well when we did that
information analysis we realized that we
had files from one to five hundred and
twenty but we were deleted files from
121 to 867 and there was other type of
information - such as index that
indicated to which part corresponding
age design and also there were images
with work with word commands so first
evidence is that we that there was
information deleted from that USB so now
what what's next so once we found that
we had we needed to count on other
digital evidence which is the computer
of the company we went
to the company we got the hard disk and
we did a copy of the hardest and gave
the original hardest back to the company
what for well in order to establish if
in the computer of the company they only
had files from one to five hundred and
twenty one or and if the rest of files
had been deleted - as in the USB when we
lead that process we realized that in
the computer of the company there were
only files from one to five hundred
nineteen and they were all visible but
in the USB we had files from one to
eight hundred and sixteen as we've said
before so you can start guessing what's
happening here what where our
conclusions which is the most important
part because of course we can draft a
report which may be very technical but
in the end conclusions need to be clear
so that adjust or anyone else can
understand what's happening so we showed
that the USB was connected to the
computer that that's the first thing we
could show we can get to know which
devices have been connected to our
computer and we can also check the
serial number and what else could we
show on the 13th of August showed that
the file but the files had information
related to their productive productivity
of the company also we could prove that
depend that the USB had deleted files
that were related to the signs of the
activity of the company and finally we
need to to be
in our conclusions and we said that
there were deleted files that which is
stored in the USB of the employee and
not in the computer of the company so
this explains a little bit more of the
situation what happened then the court
statements in courts this is image or of
a court of the disposition of chairs and
tables in a court normally experts
intervene at the end so at first the
defense witnesses intervene and at the
end there is a intervention of the
expert
it's what usually happens when I went to
the to the court I was there in the door
waiting to be called and they call me
the first to declare which was quite
weird and they just asked me good we can
see that they device as a security copy
no because in order for an L and a
device to be consider as a security copy
it must be stored in two devices not
just in one half had the files being
created in working during working hours
this is something that I didn't
understand at first but they just asked
me that question yes the files had been
created in during the working hours this
was written on the report I started I
didn't know why this metadata were
useful but sometimes you have questions
such as these ones and you can answer
because of that information and also
hard files being erased after the
employee went on holidays and I said yes
and can you know what's the date of ha
file once it it has been erased no but
when you recover it you can get to know
that information so the judge asked me
if files had been erased after the 13th
of August after the employee went on
holidays and yes it was true because
there were files from 14 15 of August or
even from September that had been erased
so if they were created after the 13th
of August and then they had been deleted
it means that that some files were
erased that with a date later than May
13th of August the employee said that he
needed that those files because he
needed to work at home he didn't have
enough enough time to finish during the
working hours
however the files had been created
during the working hours and well in the
end the employee anyway was saying that
he was taking work um so well as a
summary and regarding the resolution to
summary here is that first of all we
need to understand the context the
background we need to preserve the USB
this means we need to replicate to clone
a USB we did this before in our train we
left a copy there too
also we must have you must want an
information analysis then we need to
start doing the investigation and we
need to start recovering the information
of the USB these deleted files also as
we've when we saw that they were eyes
that had been deleted we decided to
duplicate the hard drive the hard disk
of the company of the computer of the
company then we also recover the
information of the computer of the
company compare the results and deliver
an expertise report of course after that
the employee decided to report the calm
and the conclusion of the sentence the
conclusions of the sentence were similar
to the conclusions that we have dropped
across it in their reports of it just
completely trusted our report in the
expertise information that we gave him
now we are going to move to the second
case case which was the invalidation of
digital evidence this was a shocking
case for me and I'm sure it will be a
shocking case for you too
means that in a court sometimes there in
this case in a court some these are
evidence were presented but I'm going to
give you more context so there there was
a building company that was in charge of
building houses and buildings in general
second trucks a construction company in
general and well the bank can provide
loans to the companies so the company
and the body were fighting for loan of
more than 20 euros 20 million euros very
bit it's important to say that and
experts computing experts do not have a
salary based on Commission's which would
have been been very interesting for us
in this case with a 20 million euros so
we'll scope and limitations we know that
there were three detailed evidence that
could be used as contracts so the
problem started here because it was said
that this loan granted in 2008 toxic
interest with all
we've all heard about these toxic
interest of sunken entities but the
digital evidence that the banking
presented in the court we're not
presented on the right terms and we will
see what what happened later have you
seen what happened to my assistant he's
turning around because he couldn't
believe what he was seeing seriously are
these the evidence so there was just a
CD with our own conversation from 2008
that at first was not cutter as an
evidence but that that never was never
sent to the construction company so at
first two cities were delivered one for
the jury and word for one for the
construction company and also all the
other evidence were two emails and that
were provided us screenshots that's not
mean that's not being very serious right
so this is a very serious case we said
20 million euro loan involved and these
are the digital evidence provided by the
banking entity the conversation was
seven minutes long and we try to
establish if the conversation had been
cut at some points and if the
conversation had been manipulated then
we move to the establishing the facts we
studied the audio CDs provided
corresponding to that conversation of
2008 and also we studied if we analyzed
if the emails were valid or not the
expert again is not going to assess the
content of the digital evidence we are
just going to treat these as technical
evidence from the technical point of
view and I need to make a comment here
law says that a electronic document is
the information in electronic format in
an electronic support which can be
identified and treated in a different
way we are used to print in emails but
that's not the format you need to hand
them in with the integrity and
authentication principle how can you get
that integrity you need to extract the
ID card we all have our own
identification number which is the hash
which is going to warranty that the
copies that we can make from me they are
exactly the same as me so you need to
have an identical copy of the original
okay
so far so good add an authentication it
is important that professionals are
following the professional code are in
charge of drafting these experts report
because they have proven their
qualification some recent sentences are
required are discarding experts report
because they didn't have these required
qualification it is important that the
evidence has not been tampered with
through documentation of the access
process tension transference and storage
we also need to follow those rules we
have to follow those principles which
are essential authenticity and integrity
ok do you remember where we were at we
were saying that
we have three digital evidences CDs two
males but the CD never reached the
construction company so we requested a
copy from the cold but the current had
lost the evidence yes as you hear it
the cord had lost that evidence and
that's when you start to be angry
well the deed was to talk to the
construction company and they said I
have a copy and I can send it to you so
here I just analyzed a generation and
modification dates from this file from
CD one but some days before the hearing
by turns
they found the evidence because we had
requested them to look for it and they
found this tell this phone call this
phone conversation which was the only
evidence between that conversation
between the bank and the construction
company but this even if they hadn't
sent anything conversation can be
considered as an agreement so when we
analyzed the CD from the court what do
you think that happened the conversation
was made in 2008 here we have a copy of
the one instructed in 2018 by the other
part by the bank part do you know what
happened we got the CD and when we
analyzed it they lost CD their creation
the date was January the first in 1995
and I'm not kidding you this is not a
joke I guess you're as shocked as I was
when I saw it I thought okay this is
wrong it's something that it is
that cannot be possible but it was true
I mean these was a falsified evidence it
had been tampered with we cannot see the
name the kind of the format the date
didn't match there were two completely
different evidences and then we have
email one an email to which were in PDF
format when you print email it doesn't
warranty it's legal validity because you
can scan them and tamper them with and
we can make Batman to speak with
spider-man if we want in an email
the mail is a file in our gmail account
we can push a button to show the
original you know that you downloaded
and there are different files in
different formats but it is necessary to
identify the header of the Gmail with
the person who sends a email the person
who receives it and so on conclusion we
started several conclusions the main one
is that these expert affirms that from
the expert point of view the digital
evidences are invalid CD 1 CD to email
one an email to why because they these
evidences were not presented
according to adequate computing experts
procedures and the custody chain was
lost and then we couldn't know what the
where the origin of had had been created
imagine myself going to trial
invalidating
the digital evidences can you imagine
what happened in the court in the
beginning the church
didn't want to accept the experts report
first of all because she wanted to
assess the whole case as if evidence
were true reasons for that opaque
obviously because those evidence hadn't
been presented in the appropriate way
and then questions by trade by the judge
but I would have loved to ask the judge
who extracted that conversation in the
back was it tempered tempered with
because I saw there were some cuts in
that conversation is the experts report
invalid I mean I think judges need to
trust technical teams and at least
accept and assess what's going on even
if it's not nice I told you dad I was
going to share my opinion and I'm doing
it this case one-day trial they didn't
want to record to all the higher digital
evidence should be presented CD one and
CD 2 the name of the file the size of
the file extension the day of
modification the time and hashes md5 on
any other hash because you can use
different hash which are encryption
algorithms you have the file you use
this algorithm and then you have
alphanumeric code that identifies
uniquely that file you can tell me
encryption algorithms are broken yes
they are all broken that means there
have been issues which means that two
different files had the same hash but it
has never been proven that two hashes to
different hashes for the same file that
has never been proven in da
documentation index which is available
for different lawyers and the judge they
have the hash that identifies every file
whether it is electronics or not case 3
I know that the two first case is where
high level and this one is software okay
this is the check in next start an
investigation process looking for
evidences secondly we can check the
validity of those evidence and in this
third case we're going to compare some
data with all the data especially with
economic issues in between I'm going to
speak about bus company I'm yes I am a
computer expert but I am working this
bus company and then on the other hand
we have a public administration so you
might think what is the relationship
between them well geez bus company is
offering a public service because
transport in regions are funded by by
general funds and this is what links
they
services that these this company
provides and then the funds that the
public administration gave them and then
the problem comes when these numbers do
not match we need to compare the
services from the company with the with
the funds by the other public
administration if if a bus provides the
service every Monday Wednesday and
Friday obviously every all those days
have proven to offer a service and then
if the days do not match between both
parts then you need to hire an expert a
computing expert
every service which means every time a
bus starts a route the was a line
created in a txt in a text file and
every ticket but also generated another
line in a text file eventually those
lines in the txt files
well they output that the company sends
to the public administration in all then
carry out the payoffs every six months
to come the company sends these
documents and the public administration
pays every six months a little comment
txt files of two meters or three meters
so you can imagine how much information
there was according to services and
wicked antion tickets and the payoff was
made in an Excel and we need to we
needed to compare both both excels to
see the difference so I had to wait I
still have to wait to go to
the current but the first thing is that
it is impossible for the public
administration do you have had to be
reliable control on the services
provided by the company because the
company is the one that sends that
information and every month this report
is sent to the public administration
that system is not well designed for a
public trans trans port service the bus
should send directly to the company and
to the public administration that
information which is generated and it
shouldn't go first by the company that
information should be sent at the same
time to the company and to the public
administration which requires a change
in design logically both files do not
match public administration information
doesn't match with the best company's
information and there are quite a few
differences between them and something
like that is quite weird but as I said
we have to we still have to wait but I
wanted to explain to you this procedure
of analyzing and comparing different
files there it's been eight months of
hard work and in the end we have ripped
some fruits and we have extracted some
conclusions and we'll see how it ends
I'm going to move on to the last part
which is difficulties and
recommendations what are difficulties
that an expert faces well you can I then
you may already know them I worked for a
company that manufactures door bus
company
an agricultural company a real estate
company so those are the cases that I
have been in charge of in the last
year's and the difficult part is to get
you know in depth the contact the
context and how you can isolate all the
evidence so that everyone can understand
it that's the most difficult part of the
expert because as for the technical part
once you start working with evidence is
no longer interesting what is difficult
is the new challenge of faith in
different procedures and processes
within companies you don't know those
processes you need to learn I have
learned a lot about buses I didn't learn
that much of a doors but about buses I
did and you need to isolate all the case
and to build the case that's the most
difficult part as for recommendations an
expert needs to be unbiased objective
and needs to know the responsibility
because it is not only about telling the
truth when the expert gets to know the
faults there is no other option than
telling the truth being responsible and
objective and act as an expert should
act and this is the last thing which is
the professional code of ethical code
all computing professionals and in the
field of communications also doctors
every professional group has an ethical
code which is designed to comply with
several aspects which cannot question
our value we need to be objective we
need to keep confession via
confidentiality integrity
do you have skills I mean you need to
have enough skills and knowledge in
order to face different cases with
warranties and if you are not an expert
in some fields do not worry you can
discard that case you can reject it I'm
getting to the end of my presentation
but I wanted to mention that recently I
have found that digital evidences are
not presented in the appropriate way
have the power to admit an evidence
which may have been created in an
invalid way there are some parts
especially social and label part which
allow those evidences
however in criminal courts they are more
strict and I think we all the courts
should be as discreet I am that
efficiencies are nor well presented
however they are not rejected and that
has a consequence on the dispute and
Indian that part is going to be the one
that pays for it so in the last cases
I'm working mainly on whatsapp
conversations
logically our life is on social media
and many of our conversations are take
place in what's up
since whatsapp created the option of
deleting your messages was a turn was a
very important moment for experts you
need to check if the mobile phone is not
rooted you need to know if there is not
security copy with a date later the
the conversation it is easy it is not
easy to tamper with whatsapp
conversations but it's possible to do it
it is also possible to have another
device which is routed another device
which is not you tamper with
conversations in that rooted device and
you deployed a security copy in a non
rooted device that's why we need to do
those verifications today in trials we
still allow to present screenshots what
is from what because the one which
contests is the one who is going to pay
for the experts report but what happens
with what's up in a case in which we
have a conversation on an and screenshot
and then I go to my client and say
contest the evidence and delete the
messages in your devices at the moment
when you're contesting the evidence you
are saying that it doesn't warranty the
custody chain and then the other person
deletes their messages which will never
be recovered and lawyers then lost their
digital evidence this is the end of my
presentation and I wanted to make judges
and lawyers understand and maybe experts
needs to be more prepared
maybe we need experts but I think that
judges need to understand the
responsibility they have you know that
we only accept evidences that are
presented in a correct way
I hope that
dey's intervention was interesting for
you and i would like to thank you for
being here and i will continue with my
adventures to talk about them the
following year thank you very much and
open to any questions you may have you
said that recordings were lions it was a
copy from a computer but in an audio
recording and you want to change the
date that recording is played in a
loudspeaker and you recorded in your
team in your laptop and you recorded
with whatever quality it has how can you
know it is the original one or not you
cannot know it in these cases these
digital evidence may be in a system that
the expert is going to use in order to
extract the audio file in an appropriate
way for example if we're speaking about
our watts of conversation and there is a
two-part audio there is an audio maybe
you can ask the other person who
received the audio file to check if they
are the same but it is true they can be
tampered with the expert in that case
needs to check if the second evidence
the one that is recorded on the
loudspeaker mr check if that's the
original one because if we're speaking
about an audio file or about whatsapp
conversation
I don't want them to show me the
conversation extracted in a different
computer no I want to intervene in the
system that records otherwise I want to
present that evidence in court either I
extracted from the system that recorded
the audio because I know it's the
original wall or I won't present any
evidence so for example we have recorded
here right now
so if I play this sound and I recorded
with my computer you cannot know if you
have spoken today or any other way and
when you record that in CD or they meter
data still in the computer yes for
example when you record in mp3 the the
meta data from the original wall are
still saved you can do it in PDF Word
and notify whatever if it's online it is
the data are stored right but if you
change your computer's date can you know
if the date has been modified well if
you have down an identical copy so
control-c control-v of any electronic
file that's an identical copy to the
original one okay no in that case I
wasn't referring to an identical copy
but to record from the original why and
then you disconnect from the internet
you know they know to update the date
and then you emulate the moment yes
that's the conclusion I extracted from
the conversation of the of the
conversation it was a manipulation it
was a tempering so they tried to modify
the date and as you saw it was 1995
but if you
do not have an evidence to match it with
can it be admitted I'm sorry guys but
you're running out of time
you can keep on discussing outside
please
[Music]
[Applause]