[Music]
well I said already mention my name is
Jose selvi I'm from here in Valencia
I've been working in cybersecurity for
many many years and working with
multinational companies for the last few
years I'm an NCC grouper which is a
British company originally and I'm going
to talk a little bit about how I started
in the world of learning and this has
basically I work in penetration testing
it's looking for faults breaking things
and so on so around ten years ago I
started to with machine learning because
I was doing my doctorate to my PhD at
the time and what this was one of the
subjects that came up and one of the
areas that I liked the best so I'm going
to talk a little bit give you a little
bit of an introduction to the matter of
machine learning in case you don't know
much about it it'll be quite simple
there not too much detail and then we'll
look into a couple of examples of things
that have been resolved over the last
few years using machine learning at the
beginning we've talked about one begin
from around ten years ago and I'll talk
about things I did the errors I made and
the lessons that I learned sometimes in
talks that type-c people go to the
actual final solution and not about the
process and not talking about oh I tried
this and it didn't work I tried this and
it didn't work
and I think that actual process is very
important and that's part of the
objective of this talk this morning
so things that I've learned over the
years a few tricks a few pieces of
advice so that at some point if you come
across the same kind of issue in the
future then you have some indications of
where to go I'm going to give you a
couple of cases so sorry so mentioned
introduce a couple of cases and when we
get into the details I'll let you know a
bit more about that
so also some lessons learnt over time
and then we'll have the questions at the
end so this question of machine learning
how many of you are familiar with the
machine learning a few people a few
people here yeah basically machine
learning is a series of techniques that
we use in order to try and make a
machine learn that is you have a model
with which you work and you model a
series of entries and then the system
goes into questions over classification
and it is able to automatically classify
different inputs based on what you've
told the machine previously there are a
few people working in this field and if
in machine learning are a few people and
in cybersecurity there are a few people
who are interested in this field and
actual fact I was
I like to something that somebody said
to me a few years ago somebody said that
if you've got the skills for
cybersecurity and their skills for
machine learning you're kind of like a
unicorn so data science and machine
learning has had a big impetus because
we can process much more data now the
machines we had previously did work but
there were issues that we had because we
didn't have the power the ability at the
time and our computers do have that
ability this has grown immensely in
Silicon Valley they are being used for
the areas that they need and now it's
extending everywhere so in terms of
cybersecurity it hasn't been used for so
many many years in fact I think in terms
of cybersecurity companies I would say
it's in the antivirus field that
companies are using this the best
so there are continually more and more
variants of different viruses and
different types of malware and so it's
impossible for companies to have a group
of people analyzing that all the time
because this scale of the malware that
is being generated and everything that
needs to be a list is is impossible with
a team of people so the kinds of
companies in cybersecurity that have
invested most and best the ones that
have been done most in investing in this
field are the areas of the fields that
where this has many benefits is in the
area of the SOC s
because there are a number of a world
there were a number of alerts
and some rules that would give you a
number of bullets and manually people
would eliminate different alerts
different alarms and so this is an
attack this is not so let's say that was
a thousand person connecting a day
nowadays it's millions of people so at
that's gay it's impossible to do that
task manually to see if there was really
an attack or not so this is one of the
most direct uses that we can find in the
field of cyber security but it can also
be used in many many more I've brought
along an example today because most lace
is being you so defensive purses for
detecting malware but it's also being
used in other areas of more offensive
matters this is one example that came up
in death corn it's a conference that's
done in Las Vegas and there's a
competition and there are groups of
people who attempt to work amongst
themselves and they have to defend a
number of first servers and they have to
take their own vulnerabilities and stop
other groups attacking them and
exploiting them and they have to do the
same with the other groups so the more
service that you win the more points you
win so there was a challenge that was
set up within this area and this was a
few years ago now and in that was a
similar competition as this was done by
machines in this particular case so the
machines were looking for the failures
and exploiting them and her giving
they're setting up their patches and so
on so there were people had designed the
different systems and they were the one
that arranging the the competition it
was the
gene that was actually involved in the
competition not people so over time I
first seen that machine learning has
become a buzzword everybody is talking
about machine learning so it's
everywhere now so if product doesn't
have next-generation and it doesn't have
machine learning then it's worth nothing
we will also see a little bit later on
that machine is has a great deal of
power but it's not useful for everything
these are some actual sentences that
I've come across talking to people and
we're talking about how let's put rules
for machine learning detection in and
the response to this would be you don't
have to stick any rules in machine
learning the machine has to tell you
what the rules are if you give the
Machine the rules that's not learning
it's doing what you've told it to do the
products they say oh this has got
machine learning but in fact the machine
learning that it's got doesn't work at
all and it's just given a different
weight but actually the result is the
powering that that they've put in they
say that says machine learning but it's
not actually being put into use or in
some cases just for using the point of
using machine learning they're just use
just a few characters and actually the
power of machine learning is taking a
lot of characteristics and that's the
power and the potential of machine
learning and that's something that we
can't process if there are just a few
parameters then we can set up the rule
for ourselves we don't know the machine
to do that for us
during this time when I've seen these
things I have been a little bit
suspicious of that people say oh this is
this has a machine-learning but in fact
it's not actually being used that well
so I'm just going to give you a little
bit of an explanation of this and I'm
going to give you an example to see to
show you how machine learning works in
the industry and then we'll continue so
I just chose a person at random so you
do know who this person is mmm perhaps
you do yes I should imagine how does our
brain work I show you these photos and
you've seen images of this person many
many times so your brain is already
familiar with him and it's got an idea
of who this person is who this person is
what this person is like the world of
retina and the world of intelligence is
about perception and we perceive the
world in images and we create an idea in
our brain of who this person is and once
we have the idea when we get new images
of that person we apply that idea that
we have and to see if it fits or not so
is this the same person that showed you
before no it isn't you know it isn't
because it doesn't fit the model that
you've got in your brain is this the
same person well kind of looks similar
but you know it's the same person
because your brain doesn't always just
retain the images it's also about it's
not just about memorizing things that
you see
it's about using that information I'm
not quite sure how to explain it to you
but it's about taking new data and using
that it in saying that this is similar
so machine learning in fact is all about
using this model that we have in the
middle here this function and it says
does this belong to this or not and here
we have the same model in a little bit
more of a formal manner we have
different types of models here and when
are they used these are the models that
we have in to construct the idea of a
piece of data so based on the data that
we're giving the process for machine
learning is to extract characteristics
and process the data we'll see some
cases now in cases from which I've made
mistakes so the data has to be prepared
for the model that we're going to use
and then we use the model in most models
what we do is we obtain a candidate
model it's calculated how good or bad
that is and modifications are made and
tell the model adapts well to the data
that we have this is a little example of
the ways in which this can be done so
we're trying to get a model that would
adjust to the the data that you have on
the right and if the model is going to
be aligned it's got a couple of
parameters we sent them in at random and
we calculate the error using that model
which is rather big at first and then we
go adjusting the parameters so that with
every adjustment the model that we
interpret is better than the last one
until it's good enough
after several tries we haven't improved
much then we stopped so we have a line
in this particular case which are just
to the data that we have we don't need
all the data we don't need all the
photos of the person in our mind in
order to know who that person is in
machine learning there are two different
types on the right
it's a regression so it's a model that
basically adjusts to some data it's a
prediction of data and the other one is
what we find in cybersecurity and it's a
classification it's all about having
data of two different kinds and I want
to find a way of the system saying what
this is of one type and this is of
another type this is my way and this is
not this is an attack and this is not so
let's go on to the first example this is
from 10 years ago but I'm going to tell
you all about the different steps if you
know a little bit about with machine
learning then you'll see it and you'll
see that's not going to work and in fact
it didn't yes but you'll see how it
improved in the end this was a friend
basically that give me data from the
company was working in that had an
intrusion it had seven months of
classified alerts and there were 120
thousand false attacks that went real
attacks and seven hundred real attacks
this is quite standard in these
detection systems at the end of the day
the rules attempt to detect something
that is not real
back then to not detect a real attack so
this is more or less the data a piece of
data that I had is this a text from the
alert system from the intrusion alert
system and it would attacked certain
types of attacks so I removed some of
the data that probably would not apply
and I ended up with the textual
description the IP address and port the
time and that was it and I wanted to use
that to try and detect when a an attack
was repeated on many occasions and it
was a false attack if there would be
certain patters if it was coming from a
certain IP if it was coming at a certain
time of a inter tool find patterns in
order to match which were the false
positives and to determine which were
the real attacks so this was more or
less so what I had I put in the date and
the IP I put it in in pieces and the
classification which was the Arab one if
whether it was an attack or not so I
used a decision tree the name says was
it what it does but here we have some of
the characteristics of a decision tree
we have all of these here so which of
these characteristics in the particular
case would help me to divide the tree up
into different branches if I could
divide the tree up into different two
branches then that would help me to take
a decision and it helped me to set
priorities it was built in this way
characteristic was taken and you take a
decision based on that characteristic
and a baster and the rest will you build
up the tree in this manner
something that I also did was to add in
their false negatives you calculate the
error so depending on when your problem
is it might be so bad to in this
particular case detect an attack that
was not a real attack than to not detect
an attack that is a real attack so I
wanted to remove the false negatives but
I didn't want to get rid of any of real
attacks so when you calculate the cost
of how good or bad a model is if the
real attacks that you've got rid of
because you thought the way for sites
that's very very bad and that determines
the cost how are you going to it's
common to just take all the data train
the model and then test it with the same
data but that is really useless because
in the end if you test the model with
data that you have trained necessarily
to work well with data it has never seen
so these are the ways we use one is to
divide the data one to train and and one
here on the right which basically what
is us is exactly the same sort of
operation but it's only it changes a
little bit that it uses to test in the
end it trains with olden data and then
it tests with altered it is like having
a new window that you move so this is
why it's most widely used in academia
for example why is it important because
there is
big issue in machine learning which is
overfitting which basically happens when
your model does not learn but only
memorize so you train the model and it's
so used to that data to that date
everything that doesn't work with them
you can see the Google learning would be
at this curve but if it has it will have
weird things was that memorizing so what
happens when it memorizes that when they
give you something they have never seen
before we do it wrong because you
haven't understood how it works you ever
only memorize basically the way I'm
doing is from the data set I have I
divided my work data set and my work
dataset I'm further divided between
training data set and validation data so
I trained the models with training I
choose from with the validation data set
the model that has worked the best and I
use the test data set you will see that
your model is very good here but it's
very bad at you there so when that
happens is because you do not have
overfitting your model is it's
memorizing nor do your understanding
what might you look like trimming
techniques to make it smaller and if
this is the way when I tried it when I
test it it didn't work properly and why
because first of all it made weird
decisions best thing about decision
trees it's very easy to see the
decisions it's me
whether it's making nonsense model was
making a decision she classified false
positive taken into the last four little
bits of the IP that doesn't make sense
because to IP that's share the last
little bit is only by chance for the nor
related to each other now there were
also weird decisions when the inputs
were very different due to the training
if with specific data you've only
obtained and you might get bit of data
divided by the actual retrieve it might
be very far away but the way in which
the tree has divided space it falls into
the same classification were talking
about a hundred thousand false IDs
versus seven hundred alerts and those
very unbalanced so with unbalanced data
types then we find all data sets and we
find issues but that is very common in
cybersecurity having data sets because
we have many false positives not many
attacks and although we have loads of
malware there's also no binary switch
aren't good and are being generated why
did was right I'm going to think about
all the fields in which these issues
have been sold and so I thought about
nuclear how much data do you think we
have from nuclear plants who says many
losses
it'll few
whew right because nuclear plants do not
explode very often thankfully they do in
order to know when nuclear plant is
going to have a failure well what they
do is because they do not have data when
it fails but they do have data when it
works probably what they do is they use
one class model as their name says they
only have one class of model so the ones
that we do not have things are about we
know and so we only modernize those data
that we know and in this case is
everything that works so everything if
it's not that then I'm going to say it's
fact if it's going to be the other type
and that's why I did so I got rid of
real attacks not not really got rid of
them but I just put them on the test
data set to see how they were classified
but I didn't use a member for the
training try one was a support vector
machine which is basically tries to find
a high which is a pan in n dimensions
and separates the two different types of
data kikianus that you aren't trying to
classify right now I don't have to so
what I did was to use a variation that
uses a hypersphere so the hypersphere
what it does is I have a formula and I'm
going to minimize radio so I'm going
hypersphere all my data with a minimum
radius because obviously I could use a
bigger one but what I want to do is to
adjust it and everything that's out of
that hyper sphere for me everything
that's inside is the false positives the
things that I know that are false
positives and everything that's outside
it will be real attacks
and wasn't fake I'm going to mention
because you will see it yes sometimes in
the hive you will see sometimes it you
cannot separate your data whether with a
plan with with a line with a hyper plan
what do i do then well we do in sequence
form the space you will see later wanna
show you they said that I'm going to
write the our view scan or a
transformation actually write several
models in transformations and the one
the work the best but in this case
transformations you can see problem you
see all the data you cannot divide them
with a plan you can transform the space
dividing with a plan according to the
data you have you will have to transform
the space in one way or another
now the other just to show you one which
is more traditional
because now nowadays than or even but
some 10 years ago there were quite
trendy so why did is that I took this
and I compared it with mixture of
gorgeous you know how Goshen works I
have data and I can have it in many
dimensions and what I'm going to do is
I'm going to start adding those warships
and I'm going to find a model for that
data if it's a very simple model then I
will only needs one but if it's more
complex
I might need 100 all but in the end by
doing mixture mixtures of course you
could actually model the data that you
have and finally what I did once I
already knew I would use those two
models because I was going to use only
the false positives then I wanted to
start working a bit more with data
because important I realize
is that preparing the data is where you
find the best results if you invest in
doing a proper data engineering it is
more important than finding so basically
what I did with IPS was - it doesn't
make sense to only use the last bit so
what I did was use the vessel first and
second first second and third base so
that it understood that it was sub
Network and then I did another thing and
I'm going to these threes IPs these
three IPS which ones do you think of
more similar if you were the model and
you had to classify I piece which one
would you say is more similar to each
other and now if I show you this now
which ones are more similar if during an
attack which two you would think are
more related the second one and the
third one and why because it comes from
the same information we have not fed
into did not feed this information model
then the model will not be able to make
decisions based so when we give data or
information will we feed data into a
model we have to extract some of that
data as much information as we can and
then if the model decides or determines
is not important then there are other
techniques that we can use in order to
get rid of the features that we did not
give this very first place to the model
then the model will never know if it's
exists it doesn't now but another
question how about these IPS which to
you think are more similar I'm waiting
for you to say show me the flags right
well there you go now see you would
associate
similar origin for example the ones from
Asia why because geographically they're
close
well there is something that we need to
because this is not we have in some way
the model understands for casino because
we only use a category categorical
variables Spain Germany country the
model will not have a way of knowing
that Spain and Portugal and the United
States and China and the United States
China we know because our brain gets
more danger we take the metadata from
the information but the model won't know
so we have to feed it to be able to do
this then we have to find my
representation for the data the model
knows what to do so I did in this case
for example was because I didn't really
trust here localization in terms of
cities but I did trust it in terms of
countries what I did was to get the
cities in a certain country it's called
in it and there are many things things
that are close to each other but for
example in this data representation this
is not going to be applicable but in any
case I decided not to try this yes
rather than making it more complex and
they actually worked pretty well so now
this is the example with days which is
very similar and at the end of the day
the model but you can say what day of
the week it is or if it's a bank holiday
you can have a pattern but if you're not
telling your model today or tomorrow is
a bank holiday then it's not going to be
able to find that pattern
mother nobody's tambien you will also
see that in the cases that we're going
to see because there's only one class we
had to find rejection which is basically
taking into account all the tastes that
I have how many can be outside of the
sphere or of the persons how many can I
have outside because if I can or
hannover even one outside then these
Spears might be too big or the goalies
may be too big and then they might be
taking data line so I applied different
values for this as well to see which one
works better and we've had in the end
was something like were you seeing on
the screen now you can see the number of
courses here and then you can see the
rejection threshold you can see which
one do you think is best which one would
you choose any one the third one that
fit all this one 98.9 why okay it's it's
more yeah sweet but no because it's true
that it is more I have a little bit
because I haven't explained false
negative always bear in mind when you
study but you have to keep the problem
in mind all the time because if I define
a model that says is this an attack and
it always says having one hundred one
hundred and twenty thousand positives
and seven hundred real attack saying
always but it's not I will always get a
99% accuracy so I am very accurate I
have to take into account the index of a
false negative
amount of times but I have noted a real
attack so in this case to this problem
guys date said it's important accuracy
it's absolutely safe because in the end
when you wanted to really make sure you
do not miss any real attack if you
filter the 70% of positives that is
already a good result you should need to
reach 90 something percent but what's
really important is to not lose any of
the real attack so what we want is
taking all this into account getting the
minimum false negatives of the highest
accuracy so the best ones would actually
be this one and this one in the end
taking into account the mixture of
gaussians and the one class and you will
see that master sees in here because I
use different kind of a different data
set and it will always work better with
data said it's been trained with them of
course their owner I have been allowed
to learn in the data set but my company
will not allow to be precise which would
give me data and then we polish them
blue in the end because it didn't happen
I decided to give up on it and do
something else because you can use this
internally if you have a company you can
use something similar for companies to
lend you the data set of the attacks
thing again you can publish them which
you need by the way because otherwise
they will not be published
then it is really difficult so it's
something that you can use intently but
not publish so for me it was anyway so
out we're going now onto the second
issue way I said well first of all I'm
going to check where I have public data
set and then I'll run the experiment
because I don't want to be disappointed
again anything about malware analysis a
little bit but just to simplify you have
two ways static and dynamic static is
equivalent to getting it but you can not
start the car you can do whatever you
want but you cannot start the car means
you start it and you go third Drive
these could be the two types of
depending on which analysis you do on
the way all the way you're approaching
it you will use different kinds look at
the binary without executing it or you
can remember an executed and because
most of them are that we have nowadays
connects from somewhere or to somewhere
in order to do something and it's
usually using domain so they use the
technique known as deep what they did
was to use a domain name and when those
domains were detected and they went onto
a blacklist into the malware could not
connect any Morrison what malware have
done is not use domain names but
basically generate domains where the
seed and a terminus
and if you block this malware then it's
going to connect to different domain
which I know and so that makes it more
difficult because now now now where
analysis when they face malware uses
this technique they have to get into the
algorithm the use of certain techniques
they have to locate it so that they can
block it and block all of those attempts
so I wanted to try this issue to see if
I could detect all these names because
yeah weird names easily see this is not
a normal domain name ethos so I took
data from elixir they have it has a good
data and then I used a information from
jihad dude hub and then I had a number
of examples and codes that had been
taken from these algorithms and I
generated many many different names and
families as much as the many as I needed
was some work that had been done using
this and I'll explain this a little bit
later on and it's by somebody who so
name is Duluth and extracting from that
day name there would be a number of
different characters number of digits
and the domain name links and all
different kinds of information from the
domain name itself and then a number of
bits of data regarding the traffic the
DNS traffic and this information that
I'm showing here was sort of used to me
but not the other information because
had the domain names but I wasn't
capturing
all that information and also there were
families that weren't working anymore so
I couldn't obtain that Dana data so I
said what about using this data that is
useful and adding some extra things
would I be able to achieve such a good
classification as this person because if
a family of malware has is no longer
being used because it can't obtain that
data anymore so in the end the amount of
data that you have for training the
pattern width is reduced so one of the
things I end up with was engrams so if
we have a wind with two elements and you
move them along so you have this named
FA and then C II then Bo and then you
would move them along across the windows
some would be only letters other would
be pairs so if you look here then you
will see there was variations and mean
ratio and they were using them grams
just as they were so the number of
characteristics that you end up with is
absolutely huge and this makes it
impossible to use or makes it very very
difficult to use using normal hardware
so that's why I used two distinct and I
tried something and instead of using the
full alphabet I used it in a masked way
so there were just some letters and
symbols so generate a name based on the
one above and use the engrams using this
transformation
so this retains part of them for me
consonant consonant vowel and so on and
this information could be useful in the
end and the number of characteristics
that are required and much less than
what we saw before I used a random
forest for this the same as Duluth had
used but the characteristics that were
used would not the best of all of them
but they were cut in two sets and that's
why it's called random because they're
not all the same and then we have a
voting system so if I have hundred trees
and ninety-eight say these are the same
then I'll go with the ninety-eight and
this is more or less what I had in terms
of results and you saying one two and
three sized ngrams so I was doing this
in in parts in this case one two three
and four somewhere of two somewhere of
three from before some of just one and I
was getting good results and to do that
I was using a brute and so just get
random data and put them in the random
forest just like the others and one of
the characteristics of random forests is
that you can determine the importance of
a characteristic so giving the
importance of the day to the red points
that you can see here are the random
ones so you can see which bits of the
data that you've put into the model are
the good ones
which ones which have been useful and
which have not so you can see these here
down the bottom are not very useful
there are almost as say useful as the
random ones that I've put in but under
the hand there are some other
characteristics that are more important
and so I just said determined to use the
ones that had come out
best with the top 25 20 and 15 so I had
15 characteristics with 15 that you see
here and I had quite good level of
detection with that so out of the 15
there were 9 of the characteristics that
I had put in as additional 1 so what I
had added in was useful so you have a
little example of this here an example
of the characteristics for the examples
of using a random name and obviously as
you can see the results are quite
different I'd like to show you something
now I'm not going to to show you the
training session because it take about
an hour in this particular case and we
don't have it now we're here so I have
saved the model once it had been trained
and used and I'm going to use this to
show you a classification
so have a little think because I've got
a list of names that we can use so this
is what comes up after its put in being
put into use and I've got lists here
with names that I've invented anybody
here would like to add something to see
what the model comes up with what's that
okay so that's photo goat cheese yes
welcome
just give me a second
I couldn't find the model at the time
okay now we have it this is what it
comes up with once it's being used this
is how it classifies the information so
this is the classification that comes up
with its way but generated with the DGA
this with DGA so probably if it's not DJ
then it wouldn't attacked it
let's try chat loons dot AO t is that
right oh no it comes back as clean
because I've used D XI a algorithm so
that's what it detects so this doesn't
have a strange form to see to know if a
normal names got Malware then you'd need
to do other things to it so this model
has been trained to detect that manner
of constructing using an algorithm so
it's not going to come up with that one
[Music]
in my pub and in docker hub you've got
this information it's here in a docker
he'd got a docker pool and you can
download that you've got the data we
have got internet connection the data is
available to him so you can access that
no problem so let's just go to the
lessons learnt in the time that we've
got left here today what did I learn I
learned about keeping focused on the
problem in
and you have to focus on the issue and
perhaps the result is they only get 70
percent result perhaps the 70 percent
result is good for the issue that you
have perhaps is better than what you've
got now you have to concentrate on the
issue that you're trying to resolve and
secondly spend time doing feature
extraction if we only get extract two or
three little bits and pieces and we
intoxicate it with what we think it
should be coming up with but if we put
the blinkers on it will only end up
giving us what we want it to give us so
we're not making the most of the model
we're not making most of their
techniques for their model to tell us
and to give us some patterns that we are
unable to to deal with because they've
got different characteristics
I love machine learning it's very
powerful tool but I don't think it's the
solution to everything in this
particular case if you only had to use
these four characteristics then that
will work much better there's just a few
characteristics then you can end up with
the pattern so instead of getting into
machine unioning here which would not
make any sense we have to know when to
use it or when to use it there are
always different solutions and machine
learning is not always the best solution
you need to prepare your data carefully
for the model that you're going to use
you get the country the coordinates for
example all of this data helps the model
you have to leave it prepared so the
model can use the donator correctly
inappropriately try and keep things
simple in the first example that I gave
you it was more complex than the some of
the Gaussian so though the some of the
gaussians worked very well
some people only have a neuronal network
and they get the solution straight well
but this can be very complex and they
have it other types of issues so maybe
other simpler solutions that will give
you the results that you're looking for
don't get frustrated how many dogs can
you see in that picture horse baby so
what I mean is don't get frustrated we
put in the information before the names
in for the name of my company comes up
with as a malware result so there are
different different layers and your
model doesn't have to solve everything
don't get angry even though you don't
like the results of the machine learning
sometimes people get angry with the
result that they get and that's not
necessary so that's everything for today
if nessuno buddies got a question for me
thank you all very much
[Applause]
you