morning thank you for coming my name is
mater Sala and I'm the CEO of a company
called cyber talents we are hosting the
career zone in his exhibition area so if
you have any questions regarding the
career in cyber security please also
visit us after the talk so till we
switch to the talk today we'll be
talking about our experience in doing
capture-the-flag competitions across the
MENA region so we have run around more
than 50 competition in the last few
years to give you a brief about cyber
talents the cyber talents is mainly a
platform to rank the people in
cybersecurity across the MENA region and
even across the globe by running
capture-the-flag competitions and then
we help them to get recruited either
part-time or full-time in different
companies thank you
so just a quick brief about me I have
around 13 years of experience in cyber
security I have founded cyber talents a
few years ago and I'm also we're having
a conference in Egypt called the Cairo
security camp still happening next
December this is the ninth year for the
conference and His Word is the
conference this is where we started to
run all this CTF I've been running CTF
in the conference since 2011 and we find
it a very effective way to discover
talents in this this domain
well first opening a context about what
you are doing so why we're doing CTF why
we're having this problem the idea is
that all people talking about the skills
shortage about in cybersecurity but just
last months it has been released by Isis
squares the latest statistics about the
actual today what we have so today we
have three million security professional
in shortage across the globe
the other system will take about next
year we will having a shortage the year
after we are having more shortage but
now it has been announced by Isis Square
in the latest report in last October
that we are having around
million cybersecurity professionals in
LAC so we have unfilled positions 3c
million unfilled positions in different
countries these are how it is
distributed so in asia-pacific only we
have more than 2 million job position
maybe because we are having in the other
and different countries that have a
large population but form for Europe and
Middle East and Africa we have new leave
more than hundred average 150,000
unfilled positions and this is where the
area that cyber talents are trying to
help by using discovering the CTF so as
I mentioned we found that the CTF is
kind of a solution which is very
effective to discover talents the people
that balance in this region the second
thing is to motivate more people to
participate in this domain because what
we are having is in the future is that
with this gap is continuing to happening
and when there is a kind of competition
that motivate people to attend and join
this also bring more people interested
and in the beginner phase to join the
competitions and what's most important
thing also is to promote and recognize
the existing talents and what's very
interesting here is that people in cyber
security all those as did need already
having good salary and good packages but
they also need even is sometimes more
than a salary to have a kind of
recognition between their peers so we
see that the capture-the-flag
competitions model is bringing this
recognition aspects to the game so
throughout my presentations are coming
few minutes I will try to cut 5 minutes
because I run a conference as I told you
so I know when we are behind schedule we
want to keep schedule so I will say 5
minutes for giving us a schedule so all
the insights we all have only 5 insights
from the competition's that we run in
the last few years it's nearly we had
today we have around 9000 talents on
cyber part of the platform
distributed between the different
countries mainly in Arab region seven
other countries so is a competition that
we run we run in Egypt UAE Morocco Sudan
Jordan saltanat oh man there are other
countries that they can but to be sure
that this not include Saudi Arabia so we
didn't do any competition yet in Saudi
Arabia we hope you could do it in 2019
but that all the statistics and the
insight doesn't include Saudi Arabia
which is also have a lot of population a
lot of talents that can give more
insight about this so this is how how
the CTF that we run looks so what we've
been doing is that we run in national
CTF in every country so we have for
example youth national CTF Egypt
national CTF Jordan and then the winner
of every country travel to play a
regional competition between the themes
of who win in every country and then the
winner of the original travel to Japan
to play with an international
competition by Trend Micro so we also
try to bring some fun games during the
competition like the lock-picking
challenges these are pictures from
different competitions that we run this
one was from Roku's other from Sudan and
Egypt the the one of the bath as if the
last slide was in United Arab Emirates
also so the first insight that we would
like to mention here is the gender
inside the number of males that
participate in our competition is nearly
88% from the total number of come
talents that we have and the females is
only 12% although there have a pop it
trend now that the number of women in
cyber security is not large enough in
across the globe but our numbers here in
Middle East's compares to the numbers in
US and Europe still less than the number
there so for example now in US and
Europe the number between 20-25 percent
the number of females that are
participating in such activities but in
in what we have here we have only and
something interesting here is that when
we do sometimes we do orientation
sessions in universities so we find a
lot of females at
the sessions even more than males but
when it comes when we do the real
competition a physical one event the
females don't show up which make us
think about why is this happening
maybe it's kind of a cultural thing that
women would would like to compete with
males afraid that they have been
compared with the level of people with
male but this is this is actual what is
happening now so for example if we have
in 100 people participating in the
competition you might have only 10 12 of
0 females that's why I wanted let us
think about doing a specific competition
for women on in in cybersecurity and
this is what we will launch it in in the
conference that we'll have in 15th of
December should be first one in Mena and
the winner of this competition is open
for anyone or any female to participate
and the winner of this competition will
travel to Oksana master damn its flight
and ticket and accommodation and
everything to attend in hackus the
boxers there next May 2019
and also we are planning with women in
cyber security Middle East group here to
make also another competition here in
Dubai in February 2009 team we're still
in talking with them but we are planning
to do something like this next year also
solo and also when I when I think about
this also if you come near legs eyes the
competition is like like a sport so when
you sing like Olympics Games or
something so swimming will be good for
swimming only that yes so so we're the
thing about the Olympics capes or
subsidizes your fans that some women are
competing with women and male are
competing with a male so
for me competitions or CTF is like a
sports game so we will give it a try to
see how women will show up and appear so
I also tell people or ladies if you'd
like to participate please participate
in this one for the each this is also
the second insight so we have been
noticed that the people participating in
CTF is nearly 90 percent of these people
between 18 and 34 distributed between
even nearly 50% of them are students or
at least fresh graduates who are
participating in such competition and
then from 25 or certify which people are
let's say a junior senior position but
after 35 people start to be let's say
more lazy to participate in such
competitions or they are not seeking for
the recognition that the competition is
pending so you have already a job you
are maybe moving to a management
position so we don't thinking for the
recognition so we have been things at
the age in the students and first class
this is a second insight that we have
been seeing in the last few year
competition so talented but mapped by
countries and this is also as I
mentioned this is not including Saudi
Arabia because Dina Saudi didn't do
Saudi Arabia but if you have a look also
about the heat map of the talent since
our country since I miss me in the
region so it's also related by the
populations the number of people so for
example in Egypt the number of people
participate in CTF 36% of the total
9,000 people who are talking about 1/3
6% from Egypt this is because Egypt has
a population of 100 million person in
UAE or other Gulf region the number of
population is less however we can be
able so instead of Egypt we can compare
the other numbers together so for
example in Yui we have 6.5 percent from
UAE from the outside with 9,000 talents
that we have 4 percent a Roman or 4.5%
in Morocco and this shows that the
government or the entities that were
looking for cyber security start
in this country's a Sicily Nui is doing
some great jobs at providing people to
participate and join in such
competitions about the skills we also
notice that the number one skills number
one is killed is that all people
participate or have a large number of
people in his web security so all people
know about was top 10 and the web
vulnerabilities maybe because it has the
largest number of jobs that people can
reach after that as penetration testing
or something but then the number two is
digital forensics and number three is
malware analysis so if you distribute
the population or the number talents
that we have on the platform with the
skills you'll find that and this was
very interesting for me that digital
forensics comes second
after the web security and when we go
deep in this we'll find out that some
universities here and some other
countries also they teach digital
forensics in their class in
cybersecurity min masters or something
like this to teach digital forensics and
less people he take our deck lessons in
malware reverse engineering or something
is it also because it's kind of which is
not true but kind of for some people
it's easier to get into digital
forensics because tab gives a lot of
tools and some like this other than
Malvo reverse engineering that's not
actually true but it needs to know more
assembly norm or more coding stuff which
or more background to get into the cyber
security or to get into the model
reverse engineering otherwise and
digital forensics people can go directly
to the field and of course as a beginner
library of course so we have also some
general challenges that we have been
facing which is a language barrier so
all the challenge that we have and all
the ins actor phase of the competition
is in English but we have seen that some
people because we've been monitoring
also what people are doing so it means
that some people are translating
the platform and translating the
challenges into Arabic and some also
maybe in Morocco ziovo translate into
English to French so although this
problem might not having here in UE a
lot when as people speak English
frequently but in other countries like
Egypt Jordan and maybe and in other
countries also so they translate that
challenges and the description to a
different language which would is the
tool that they use for example when you
write a code or something you write it
in English it's the language in many
languages HP or C whatever you don't
have it in Arabic or something but still
is it still more comfort to see the
challenges and see the things in their
own language
the second challenge that also we have
is the ethical behavior so yes
CTF is a way to discover talents and
it's very effective however it is not
the only way or the the a unique way
only to to learn people with jobs
because some people that we have the
platforms you don't have the ethical
behavior or they can't miss some
communication skills that you can't
abort them in a corporate environment
and we have a lot of stories around this
ethical behavior but in a nutshell about
the fifth insight about it it's at the
not all the talents that appear in our
world rank that you'll be able to solve
the challenges and working well you
can't be learning in jobs in a corporate
environment and that's why maybe
something like bug bounty programs and
this stuff is is working good because
you just do the jobs and I don't need to
see you or don't need to meet you I just
do the jobs and get paid for it but yeah
for corporate environment it's not yet
the best thing so what's the next thing
so we are who now are preparing as I
mentioned we are doing as a woman inside
my secured CTF in Egypt in 15th of
December and we are also planning one in
Dubai here in February but also we plan
to do CTF for schools so we're looking
for long-term plan so that the people to
get introduced to the cyber security
program earlier before they go to
universities so that they can know that
we need you we need more people to join
in this field and we start to do CTF for
schools I know there is already one
happening here in Yui which is cyber
quest but doing there is a regional
thing or the global thing so that we
need compete here you'll be able to
qualify to the next round and originally
and then the next one internationally
this is what we are trying to do and
with the city our schools also we have
not this very important thing is that
although there are some correct skills
characteristics with people working in
cyber security like being persistent
like being kind of problem-solving so
this kind of characteristics for the
person and the knowledge you can gain it
then after this so we started to run
some boot camps with people who are
that's literally know nothing about
cybersecurity to engage them to start
doing the city efforts or to to learn so
again the objective is not the place the
city F the objective is to enter the
cyber security field from an interesting
way instead of taking a course and
getting into a class or something it's
having more gamification model of doing
learning so we have been thing we've
done some boot camps so a single when we
do a boot camp we distributed by days so
for example one day we have day for web
security another day for digital
forensics third day maybe for malware
analysis we have been saying that people
getting out of the boot camps are more
active and more effective to participate
in the competition although they have
not
about cybersecurity before entering this
bootcamp so we have done some boot camps
before and nearly 80 or 85 percent of
those people who attend this a boot camp
will be able to participate in the
competition's even even a chloral
outside of our platforms you can started
to go to City halftime and participate
in different competition and so we are
also organizing a boot camp as a
preparation for a woman in cyber
security CTF in Dubai that will
happening in cabrito reported we're
preparing one to happening in Jan so
that all ladies would like to
participate in the woman a cyber
security CTF can attend this kind of
boot camp and get introduced to what
they need to get into the field so I
guess that's for me I'm if someone have
the questions I can I can get her any
questions yeah please what wait a minute
for the microphone please so hello my
name is Hanafi I'm part of the crew so
we have been running city over the past
almost 10 years and I have questions for
like how do you measure the skills of
the talents I mean like how do you know
if he is really good oh yes something
like that
I see what for the students how do you
know he if it is understand what he does
and what he do like before he get a job
something like that so yes so others is
a normal competition we have something
called the public challenge so the
public challenge is that we push every
week new challenge and we have this kind
of world ranked that ranks the people so
every challenge when we build the
challenge it is not the the way the CTF
and Def Con is happening so we build the
challenge as a test to measure the
skills in a certain subject it has to be
different levels no it's not difficult
visually here in this region people are
new to CTF so if we go to DEFCON style
you will not solve anything so let's
take a step by step with them so for
example this challenge it's covering
only skill injection this turns not only
cross start scripting so if you'll be
able to solve this one then you have the
skills needed
in SQL addition to recover and then what
to be good with the jobs when how the
companies I would like to recruit
someone we filter the people who solve
this example if I need someone in
absolute security I filter all the
people who solved challenges in the web
domain security for example who knows
that I was top ten at this sample then
it's not only that but then they go to
the normal interview process them but
it's kind of sort ways to source people
quickly because we have also noticed
that that a lot of talents as that
exists here in this region and they are
not even graduated from computer science
or not good data from any engineering in
Egypt is a winner of our competition
Egypt national CDF
it was working he is a student in the
pharmaceutical University so very far
from this and it will not be even show
up to the series of jobs unless he
participated in something so we have
more questions probably it's more of a
comment I would I would say my I'm
heading the cyber quest by the way thank
you for mentioning it so we've got our
students participating as well in hack
in the box and cyber course we've been
running for the high school for the high
school and we are going to the sixth
graders for the last five years so by
the way this year we've got for the
first and women winning in the
competition so that was a big
achievement for cyber quest woman
actually or girls actually winning so
great with what you're doing thank you
so much there are great insights and I
can see there is a little big some
collaborations you're looking forward
actually thank you so let's see some
more questions in the room we still have
time because we're waiting for the next
speaker to come in thank you thank you
for all the insights to start with and
it's really great to hear that you know
the the ladies are doing very well now
with the CTF my question is about the
women CTF for ladies CTF because now
it's a trend everybody's talking about
women in cyber and so on so not to be
too blunt but are you doing this just
because it's a trend or is there
something specific behind this is it
going to be helping them in a different
way than a regular CTF is
what's the point really of doing this
for ladies only okay so as I mentioned
that there's a reason why we do this I
mentioned is a slide that we will be
able to see that when we go to
orientation session a lot of ladies
appear but when we go to the
competition's you don't come so we
thought that the one of the reason not
all all females but because some people
got end but maybe if some of them it is
not comfort to compete with males for
this and that sounds of what the reason
is is what we are doing is that we are
building different domain different
access for doing City app do that later
those women can also participate in the
mainstream one competition so they can
participate in that you National City
evidence we run or Isabel is a global
one to increase the number woman in the
main competitions that we are doing and
that's why also we are doing the school
one because also we in one of the
competition's we have we have some high
school players but this is because an
account of an exception so we want to
make build on this also as to make also
another competition for schools so that
they can if we have some good of them
appear they can also participate in the
mainstream competition so this is a kind
of way of marketing or bringing more
audience to the mainstream competition
and make it more become not a trendy n'
so any more questions thank you very
much thank you thank you as well was
great talk