[Music]
thank you
this was a round of applause I guess
right yeah let's continue
happiness fresh air allergies foreign
stretching his presentation as much as
possible but we will see the guy
the 40 minutes are yours
yeah great to see so many people I
approach the presentation from YouTube
about the guts of python and not only
pythons
since we are have been talking about the
compiler
we need to introduce you
believe that front is something visual
backhand is
not like that they have front and parser
from the card into some kind of tree and
back end is what's actually being
executed on the actual CPU or GPU or
special pu middle there's also Midland
that is in charge of um I mean there are
intermediary things in Midland and they
are also in the back end but in Midland
they're not related to the actual
process sir but they are important in
the back end that's the difference
then we'll be talking in some more
detail particularly about python
[Music]
um
on this slide
compiling conveyor on sea pipes it's
pretty much it you can take a look and
you can go and have a cup of coffee no
uh
front and if python is actually the
so-called tokenizer also parser into a
syntactic tree
intermediary notion in Python is uh um
backhand is the virtual machine that
executes that one
compared to other compiler in Python if
they can actually drag it out of python
if you want to all of the modules and
built-in functions which actually do all
of this it's called conveyor compiler
and this is Christianity
there are some abbreviations that you
don't know here CFG control graph almost
like byte code but there are some jumps
uncalculated there
and now we'll look into some more
details
a very simple thing roughly we have
three tokens it's better to have five
tokens as they say
tokenizer does not know anything about
what it is how it works that's kind of a
sequence of symbols for chunks
transmitted to the grammar
and the tokenized module in Python it's
not very useful you can import it from a
file or you can put it apart
frankly I have not encountered like real
life tasks that could be solved with the
tokenizer mostly
it depends on
foreign
[Music]
left one and right one and um
there are some numbers to it nothing
extremely complicated
[Music]
but there are more exciting things there
than um
you can use it as a script look at the
help
or you can unparse something and the
most exciting thing is
how can you actually look at what you've
been unparsing
is
the so-called visitor pattern from
pattern design that can allow you to
kind of procedurally go through the
syntactic tree at every knot we can um
[Music]
or we can just go down the generator
with the for Loop and go through every
nod
um
there's also the lightweight version of
eval raise your hand if you know what
eval is
quite a few great there is a more
lightweight version of it it's more safe
very secure if you want to write a
secure code
just you know fail python interpret
interpreter into the score dump if you
want to foreign
uh Beware
and um
there's also a cool thing
that you can actually transfer it into
the source code
you can put it together not from the
source code but
based on your very own algorithm quick
and create the tree yeah
here you have the python code the source
code congrats
foreign
it was introduced with python 3.9 before
that they had a parser based on ll1
grammar probably don't know what this is
about but
the major reason why it was slow and not
so great because in addition to abstract
synthetic tree they also had
intermediary
that was kind of pushing the memory
pretty well sometimes too well
accordingly Guido came together once
you're based PG grammar without
intermediate tree it's more memory
efficient than just faster Expedition
and one of the reasons why yeah
two to three another kind of um nail and
a coffin of 2.7 is that the converter
2.3 to two to three which dependent was
dependent on the old parser and in 310
it was completely removed I heard that
there are some Forks to three library
that can
convert 2.7 code with a pack parser but
that's extravagant
um
if we look at the images here's how it
looks as a plot
so at the output of the grammar we have
some function generated automatically
the C function
which creates different types of ASD not
for every node there is a function
generated so this generator was the old
parser and the new parser it's still
there but the grammar has become a more
gradual in the end there are more less
crutches
this is included right into the rules
we will not be looking too much at the
formal grammar we will just not have
enough time
another cool thing in Python is
been generated we can generate it not
only on C but all but in pure python as
well for example if you don't know
anything about grammar you want to add
some keywords new keyword try it
you did it
[Music]
whether it's correct and generated in C
and make a pull request
there are some drawbacks
which are inherent to python parser it
has cross dependencies to current
virtual machine so we cannot just slice
of the VM that's executing the byte code
which would have been cool
to make the distribution of code more
compact for example but I believe that
in the future sometimes someday they
will slice it somehow maybe I will even
help
and another another point about
applications
I personally applied
anti-plagiarism script
you know that students often when they
send you to an assignment hey
that sometimes even not remain anything
sometimes they remain stuff and even
swap methods you know
foreign
it's a very useful thing to look into
and see how it's working and in addition
to that
[Music]
I didn't mean anything
and according to the compiler Theory
there are three shapes of ir and byte
code is one of those
that's when we have the sequence of
bites
but in reality it's much better to look
at the lines
the printout of interior representation
which as a matter of fact is very
readable and it's not really far from
the source code it's not yet assembler
[Music]
and we see here that the coded function
itself is the last four numbers
uh the rest is kind of the uh
declaration if you want to look at the
function itself we can be easier we can
never need to look at the disassembler
and just shove their function as an
object you don't need to compile when we
declare the functions
there is a byte code in lines there are
two parameters in the memory and we
disassemble it
code
there are certain optimizations that we
observe python 311 for example there's
this thing called specialization of the
byte code meaning that certain
operations in the bytecode are becoming
specialized for a particular data type
for example
disassemblers can highlight that and if
we tell him that adaptive is true
we can actually heat that function up
with the integers and we see that
addition is geared up for integers
[Music]
and there is kind of a counter uh
we gave ends ten times but the country
says 53. I don't know why
maybe there's some bit values in there
um
so the abstract instruction goes into
this specialized more adapted to data
and also we can make a step back
just I mean we have optimized now
we have lines
or floats um
we need to make a step back and then
make a step forward but in a different
direction so that's uh that's an
acceleration definitely
10 to 60 when we were doing that and in
Python 312 that's been expanded there
will be a couple of instructions
and more things
specialized more
so it's returned to not what we used to
have but something similar and
um we need to continue continue pressing
on and in the end says well you guys
okay that will be
um uh exciting kind of a Unicode lines
Edition
a bonus for attention
there should be one double instruction
by the way that's why F strings are so
fast
it's getting nasty stack machine a stack
virtual machine
they're uh not only stack virtual
machine it's in the sea uh
evaluation Loop in Python other
compilers didn't have that that's
actually cycle uh according to the
instructions and um
instruction works
I decided to show the C code it's not so
scary you can see here something
reasonable yeah so there's this
optimization if if we
and are going to return to the abstract
version of the instructions so there are
there is a statistical counter that
expands
um
there is addition
wise we're doing the decrement counter
so we
decrement the counter of links so where
do we increment it then
I mean we're decrementing it how do we
incrementing it
it's a matter of fact
it's happening in the previous
instruction called load fast which is
quite logical isn't it I just didn't
that's right away and also we see that
there is a certain step here
which is a matter of fact
that's a different entity but the stack
on which virtual machine works that's a
different kind of stuff
and you don't have to know how many
questions
if you don't want to write another VM
yes
developers and from London there is
and generally we could hope that to be
faster than the stats so far though no
and it will not get into 312.
maybe not even 3 13. but there is a
development like that
um
we've seen this function already there's
internal API which replaces this
function into a virtual machine
[Music]
I could wrap up here but no
there's a good book
s
it's quite detailed right
a more compact person is a developer
guys
where we see a lot of
detail on the python interpreter in a
more concise way
I think we should even begin with the
dev guide and then get deeper into the
book
absor
foreign
language ecosystem
but that's a particularity it's not
something negative right
something that's not that great it's
compatibility with C extensions
everything that has wheels numpy pandas
all of those things are not quite
comfortable with bye bye let's just put
it that way and if you have C extensions
with the c types raise your hand if you
know this module and why you'd be using
it and
[Music]
will be gradually trans
there are some more promising
developments
which has been developed by the
engineers from Instagram
uh Facebook and Facebook that's a fork a
python purely with implementation but
not of the VM but jit compilers I mean
as a pie pie it's also on uh jet
compiler it doesn't use any.net it has
its very own implementation and it
doesn't use a ldm
representations high level ir and low
levels
high level IR similar to byte code
um
there is some different preference
counting there and music
but they have not been declaring that it
will be fully comfortable to see python
no probably
the Facebook Engineers have been quite
present
we will go into detail on jit compiler
which can minimize certain functions
probably you heard about numbers
and if you do have a certain function
here's a random example
it calculates whatever
you drop a decorator in this one
parameters
not for any functions
don't judge every single function please
number is using it actually
llvmo a well-known compiled ecosystem
and lightweight python wrapper
and it supports quite a few things
including some parallel things and GPU
based execution
an issue here is that c extensions again
may be quite unpredictable especially if
you're using uh I mean it can be used
with numpy but with pandas numpy doesn't
understand it and therefore
you will not get any acceleration
even there will be overheads and things
will be even slower so if you have a lot
of numpy
I will not be talking a lot about
implementation there's a good
presentation at the last icon
describe in much detail in the
presentation there is a link and you can
find it easily
uh
now let's take a look inside of the gut
well
compiler compilation steps not for
number only but also for other
programming languages like there's Julia
language
anyone heard about Julia programming
foreign representations
[Music]
because that's kind of a dynamic
compilers
show types
ecosystem has been geared up to static
languages so you need to dynamically you
need to make Dynamic types into static
types
intermediate representations
environments
uh
type output can be something relatively
complex there are some algorithms so
let's use them however there are cases
when um
these algorithms
no just don't stop
we cannot even call them algorithms
because
algorithm wise it's just not solvable in
any case
some of you have long faces I see it
might seem surprising
article and many thanks
there is an example when my pie just
never stops
you need to try hard for that you have
to engineer that it's not an easy thing
to achieve but still
so questions you cannot make a compiler
can you
well you can
I'll tell you more in a C plus plus
language
I also have types
and also the system there is
templates also is unsolvable algorithm
wise and in certain cases the file is
compiled for a long while and you can
come up with a few examples when
compiling will just never stop unless
there is a timeout of course
they simplified
[Music]
which is also simple logic but the
system is even more simple that's why
I'll watch it is just so fast and small
but not everybody knows how to use it
though it is
let's return to
to the numbers
we wrote some function which is not even
optimal intentionally how this thing can
optimize it constants are not filled
and we see the result
a simple example right
now
it's quite self-evident
it's a joke
it's a closer look though you'll see
some binary operations some kind of
product sums but you need to really
really dig into this one
this code gives some intimidary scary
image of the situation so um let's now
simplify this example even more
from time to time you know where to look
for by the way and this is close to
assembler by the way
we promised you an assembler here it is
but not not completely right now let's
talk about
the ecosystem
now we're getting into the god of it
ecosystem to create intermediary
representation
multi-level IRS
machine learning because machine
learning tools
multi-level because there's kind of a
low level and high level representation
a dialect um
we observe certain functions and
operations
for example linear algebra uh dialects
it supports
the product of Matrix
can transpose matrices so you can do
some high level operations there
you can transpose the metrics
kind of a zero down uh two operations
into one and after that
after this kind of um
dwindling down we can lower this
representation to a more low level a
thin dialect for example is
representation for four cycles and and
other operations that only four cycles
for which you can um make optimizations
that are using some kind of maps
so that's uh optimal math optimizations
we will not delve too deep into that we
just know that we can reuse them as a
ready-made and after that
we can make low-level representations
and execute that on a backup
there are also GPU dialects for NVIDIA
for AMD
which are also high levels
and the most important feature-wise it's
multi-level we can take different levels
different dialects and put them together
the meaning that they can be mixed down
in one intermediary representation I
think this is one of the coolest
features of
VM IR because this is heterogeneous
computation naturally
types and attributes by the way can be
dynamic We Remember music that if python
is a dynamic language
we could have done a dialect for python
we had a year ago maybe a year and a
half ago
and in dialogue
there are ways to optimize current
representation or lower it down to the
next level
[Music]
space dialogues tensor linear linear
algebra is something that they use a lot
and optimizers for neural neural network
models are also using compiler
infrastructure and you just don't see
that
um
gradually number is moving to this
ecosystem and there are repos where that
is being done and even a dialect that
they have now but it's still static type
at the moment Dynamic types are not
there yet maybe they will have it but I
don't know we'll see
and as a matter of fact even clunk is
very well known C plus plus compiler is
also moving to mlir
they're making intermediate
representations on that in order to make
code more maintainable so it will be
easier to go into the guts of class but
that's not something that's talking
about I promise that there will be no
blood only God
ml IR has python biddings so you can use
mlir from Pure python
unfortunately we don't have that in
pipes you cannot install it via pip but
there are Americans there is this
American dude
if Julia is named in order of the wives
of one of the developers uh Nelly is
named in the owner of the mother and
this thing can uh almost just take
almost pure python code a bit you know
muddled
you need to do quite a few Imports for
that that's the deal
so that you take uh the pure python code
and transfer that into the intermediary
representation but the mix of existing
dialects
that you don't have to reassemble llvm
that's quite a while and uh
I mean it's a bit more comprehensible I
hope so we have a for Loop
foreign
optimization command here and we can
tell it dude squeeze
lower our dialects convert into the
lowest level dialect llvm and it
responds nope
um
let's see what's wrong
okay the percentage within the cycle
is always there once if we look at the X
variables the second time in the sign
for a second time it's becoming X2 X3
Etc so as a matter of fact it's a
different kind of object already
and we see that
this variable percent four is within a
loop but nobody took it outside
[Applause]
it will look further and look into the
commentation to the dialogue then
um
here are a few lines
this thing will even go down
and we see something more low level
we need to write down here what type
conversions podcasts
easier said than done then we can
broadcast it to the lowest level and
execute on The llvm Interpreter llvi I
is for interpreters and if we take a
look at the scheme
then this dialogue at the lowest level
dialogue dialogue is going down to
llvmir and we execute it
not
I mean um
it almost Works
we're almost approaching the end yeah
so python accelerates preserves
introspection
we can still see how the byte code is
being optimized it's pretty cool you can
actually see what's happening there well
it's Midlands
Midland tools are also getting better
yes they have certain bugs but gradually
it's getting better
in a couple of years you'll be able to
use it
there's a number of them I cannot help
but mention them
there is a growl VM with the GPA
licensing though there's also Arc
compiler which also Dynamic type it
supports Dynamic type languages
both uh growl and Arc compiler they are
supported by one company llbm
except contribution from so many
companies people universities
that's why I prefer this one
that's great thanks to the fact that
the privilege you can add Dynamic types
and operations
and from Python and for Python and not
only for Python and also which is
mlr to create um you have very own
coding languages
and you don't want to replicate other
features in the other languages
just because it will be so much easier
to make your very own
[Applause]
um
maybe you will ask a few questions
uh the delivery guys are running with
the mics
there's a reason why we use this
delivery Club
so let's run it
thank you for the presentation
here's the question
we mentioned tensorflow
tensorflow now allows to compile neural
networks for microcontrollers right out
of python codes
going into an executable code for
microcontroller how does that happening
is it within some kind of um
and there's another machine within that
it actually puts together the code for
microcontroller yeah that's a good
question
that's curious about microcontrollers as
a matter of
facts
back end for like these very compact
devices there's a micro python for that
that's not related to what I was talking
about so if we speak about micro
controller is I believe that probably
know
there are other types of developers so
how's it happening I know for sure that
from python I can start some method from
tensorflow from some class and put
together a code that I can actually
put into the microcontroller that should
be somewhere within the python let's
clarify that are you talking about
microcontrollers
tensorflow website there is
a bit of a different thing yeah
a microcontroller with a DSP cords
there's a special kind of backhand
it's not within llvm but in the
tensorflow repo and maybe it can take
its own backhand and move it to DSP
processors which is a small question
about lazy computations
something right away but make certain
methods and then in a while kind of get
another method etc etc with how's with
this lazy computations on python
I cannot tell you about spark I don't
know spark that well I don't know what's
happening inside
Ducks okay thank you
football image
um
a very interesting presentation the core
questions
when you begin talking about heating
functions
because I've heard in runtime is not
even participating much but when I get
dirt a certain functional class I I saw
those types does that make an impact on
bytecode optimization no not really no
I'm sure next question when you have
four questions
no problem by the way
of course what the hardcore questions
which as they say is very fast and
really python-like all right
I heard about it
I said that it's probably gonna die
in my opinion
everybody's speaking about Mojo
they're using molars somehow but it's
not yet open source how they're doing
this I don't know
maybe there are issues on their measures
maybe they have been adjusting their
measurements for a certain example
there are C python benchmarks which can
measure different kind of things and you
can get the average
when they say that python 311 is 25
faster than fighting three times on
average faster for all of the sea python
batteries
so that you don't have to pay for the
third question yeah
foreign
and that's it
two questions in one actually foreign
[Music]
which you believe more
if somebody can make that happen for
processors that's great
appreciates
depending on their effort the effort
they invest into it acceleration will be
happening due to different things for
example gradually the micro instructions
are changing and they will be more
Optimus somehow VM will be optimized as
well
man
this dude who had many questions
but I love the questions too
just wave your hand okay
[Applause]
[Music]
um
thank you so much for the presentation
thank you for the for the work for
making this happen and for the answers
the resistance
sure 10 minutes great because usually in
10 minutes we'll be talking about uh
Statics analysis
foreign
[Music]