hello
let's start with the with the talk
today
i will cover some of my research
on apache apache http
web server
and
i will show you
also some of the vulnerabilities that i
have found
during this this process
but first of all who am i
well i am antoni morales
i work as a security researcher at
github
that is my
that is my twitter handle
where i usually post most of my research
and
inside github
i'm part of a small team called
github security lab
our main goal
in github security lab is to improve the
security of the open source software
this is just an example of our work
and i encourage you to visit our website
this is the link
to know more about
our theme and the research that we do
and in my case i mainly focus on c and c
plus plus projects
i'm also a fashion enthusiast
and more specifically
an afl and afl plus plus
fan
and these are some examples
of software in which i have been working
on
during the the last year
but today i'm going to focus
only
in the
apache http server security
okay
so the agenda for today has
these five points
in the first one i will show you a brief
introduction about the apache
architecture
in the second one i will show you a
summary of my fasting workflow
then i will go over some of the custom
mutators that
i have built
and why i have built these custom
mutators
after that i'm going to explain some of
the houston interceptors that i have
created
and
in the last point i will show you some
of the vulnerabilities and backs that i
have discovered
well let's start with the apache
architecture overview
apache is one of the most well-known
http web servers
so
i think that it doesn't need any
introduction
so we can skip this slide
okay and apache apache architecture
is compound composed of three main parts
the first part
is the the bachelor
that includes
some basic functionalities of apache
we can find
the modules
the modules implement
most of the functionalities of the web
server
and then we have we have the apr the apr
library the apache portable runtime
library
and between these modules we have five
different categories
the first one is the mpm modules
this type of modules are responsible for
basic request handling and dispatching
then we have the base modules
these are modules that are compiled
and loaded by default
we also have the extension modules
that are not normally loaded into the
web server
except for a few cases
and out of the apache distribution we
can find also the experimental modules
those are sorry those are available into
the apache distribution but are not
officially supported
by the apaches thing by the apache
developers
and the last group is the external
modules that
are those modules that are not included
in the apache kit
a very important
type of modules are the mpm modules the
multi-processing modules
this provides an interface between
the apache server and the operating
system syscalls
between the tasks that the npm handle
we can find for example
creating the network connections
listening for requests and accepting
requests for the clients
and
npm also can handle the creation of
proof processes and threats
and it's important to note that we can
only have
one npm
running
or loaded at the time
well between these three main modules we
can
or
best set we can differentiate
three main modules on unix systems the
first one will be the
prefork configuration that implements
just a
prefork web server
without threads of any type
that is how
the old versions of apache used to work
in the past
the second mpn configuration
is the worker npm
this npm implement implements a hybrid
multi-thread and multi-processes
multi-process server
in this npn each process
creates a fixed number number of threads
threads
and the last one
that is the newest one is the event npm
in that case it's an asynchronous
implementation
and the main difference with the worker
npn is that the event and npm is able to
re reuse a single thread for new
connection
so
it doesn't need to open a new
thread or for every new connection
and then we have the third main
component of the apache architecture the
apache portable runtime
apr is a supporting library for for
apache
it's provide a set of apis
that make possible to use
the same functions
across different platforms across
different operating systems
and some of the capabilities of apr
includes
are the memory pools and memory
allocations that i will explain after
also handle
the file input and file output
provides also
share memory functionalities
and for example other things as
multi-threading
or
time routines
and this is the apache operation diagram
it has three different phases
the first one is the
apache startup
this first stage includes the
parsing of the configuration file
the loading of libraries and the
initialization of the system resources
the second one
is the operation phase
in this stage the first thing that
apache does is to call to the set uid
function
in order to change the to a regular user
from root to a regular user
it also includes
the
request processing itself
and the third one is the cleanup phase
in this last stage apache release all
the resources including memory file
handles or sockets
now i will show you an
http request
and how
this http request is processed by apache
for example we have
our http request here
and at first this http request
will go through
these metadata modules
then the output of the metadata modules
will be processed processed by the input
filters filters sorry
after this the request is processed by
the handler modules
and by the output output filters
the last stage is the execution of the
login modules
and amongst the metadata modules for
example we can find
modules for url preparing or modules for
http access and authentication
as a filter examples we can find for
example modules for
for encryption or for compressing
well
now i'm going to explain
some of the most
relevant aspect of my fasting workflow
i have divided my fasting workflow in
four different parts
choosing a fasting engine
socket fasten
important code changes
and fasten modules
well
choosing a fasten engine
when it comes to the fasten engine i
don't have any doubt
afl is my my choice by default
i felt plus plus
is a fork of afl
but it includes a lot of new features in
comparison with the original afl
among these future
features i can mention for example
custom mutators
or power schedules
or
multiple in instrumentation modes
another problem that we face when we
want to fast an interactive server
is that afl doesn't support
native sockets fasten
so
we need to find
or we need to modify the source code in
order to be able to fast the server
for that my approach was to add a small
code snippet
into the mpm code that i saw to you
before
this snippet code self-connect to the
server itself
open a new thread
and redirect
all the input data through it
let's look at these two code snippets
you can see the self connect function
just here
that establish a connection to the
server itself you can see here the
localhost
and what i do then is just to
read the file data
here
and send
this data through the socket
this code snippets
will be then introduced at the npm
circles source code
and in my case i use two different
fasten
configurations most of the time i use
the prefork npm
mostly 80 of my of my time
with only one process at a time
with the aim of getting a good stability
but
i also fasted
the event npm
in order to catch
concurrency backs so to catch
concurrency issues
let's see now some changes that i made
to the source code
in order to improve the fashion process
for example the first group of changes
are aimed
at reducing the entropy
for example in that case replacing calls
to random
by constant values
here
you can see that
that i comment out
the generate random bytes call
and instead
i use a constant seed
the main idea
is to reduce the entropy of the
execution
second group of changes
are aimed to
reduce delays
for example removing some sleep or
select calls
the idea here is to improve the fasting
speed and you can see here
as i comment out the select call
the third group of changes are those
made in crypto routines
for example to disable checksums
in this picture you can see as i comment
out
both
crc comparisons
here and
here
and that's really important because
otherwise the faster will get stuck
in this crc so this is always a critical
uh
moment when we are preparing the the
fast the fasting
okay and now i will show you my approach
for fasting the different apache modules
what i did was to use at first an
incremental approach
where i started with a small set of
modules enabled you can see here the
httpd conf
and then i try to progressively
include new modules in the configuration
file and test the stability
following that i repeat the process
until all the modules are enabled
and the fasting process is stable
okay
let's give now a brief introduction
about custom mutators
so
what's the problem
that we want to solve
well by default afl and lift faster
implement
basic mutators like for example
bit flipping byte flipping
known integers
so
these mutators provide good results when
applied to binary formats
but
are not so good when
applied to complex formats
like for example the http protocol
so my solution was to include additional
custom mutators
specifically created for fasting the
http protocol
you can find all the code related with
these custom mutators
in my github
repository this is the link
tony morales
and for example in this
first example we can see a simple
customizator the line swiping
you can see here two different http
requests
the guest get request and the post
request
and below you can see an example of
mutation
where the content type
and the accept language
you can see
as
these headers
have been swapped
so
now the post request has two different
abstract languages headers
while they get requests don't have any
accept language either
in this second example we can see a word
swapping
that just swaps two words or more
specifically to part of the url
in the picture below you can see us the
http request get hello and post
hub swap
date url now the post
goes to hello and the get go to cgi
well but i have implements also some
other mutators obviously for example i
implemented
a charset brute force mutator
these mutators were inspired by hascat
passport cracker 2
and for example i implemented things
like two bytes brute force three bytes
brute force strings brute force digits
brute force
and in addition to use custom mutators i
used
custom grammars
for this task i used the grammar mutator
tool that it's include into the afl plus
and to use grammar mutator we need to
define we only need to define a json
file that includes a collection of key
and
value pairs
this is a
part of my grammar specification here
you can see
you can see it best
with an example
for example you can see
us every request
is composed
of a start line
then we have an
enough line
then the headers
the body
and the end of the request
and at the same time every single start
line
is composed of a method
for example get head post
the uri
and the http version so this is a part
of a
custom grammar
well and now it's time for custom
interceptors
but first of all
why do we need to implement houston
interceptors well
things are going to be a little bit
harder there but don't worry
so as i previously mentioned apache use
custom memory pools
to improve dynamo dynamic memory
management
for this task apache use the functions
that apr the apache portable runtime
provides
for example
if we want to allocate memory inside the
memory pool we need to use the
apr apr p alloc
instead
of the
standard malloc
because we want to allocate memory
inside the memory pool
so consider the following code snippet
where the program
calls
to apr
pialog
in this case the second argument that
okay so we want to allocate for example
126 bytes inside the
first argument inside the apr pool
this is the site argument and this is
the apr pool where we want to
allocate the memory
so
this is how apache memory pool works the
apache memory pool consists of a link at
the list of memory nodes
each node
has
a fixed
side memory available you can see here
the memory of each node
and as you can see also in this picture
the third node
has some free space available
then when more space is needed
the program will add a new node
just
at the end of the list so if we don't
have memory obviously we need to add a
new node to the link in the list
and this is the code of the allocator
alloc
function
and the thing is that
this function as you can see in this
comment
round up the minimum size to
8192 bytes
and of course
this will be a problem for other
sanitizer
so for example
i can show you an scenario where
we make a call
to apr pialog with a size of
126 bytes here you can see the output of
the debug
so um
this is the
output of the debug
in the
allocator alloc function
so
we have made a call to apr pialog with a
size argument of 126 bytes but other
sanitizer has poison and memory area of
8192 bytes
so the
result is a total area of
eight thousand and sixty-six bytes
arched as writable
by other sanitizer
but the thing is that this is not
real allocated memory
instead is free space
in the node of the
list
so for example
imagine
that we call to main copy
with a size of
this will lead
to an override of the rest of the nose
nodes memory
because
our buffer was
has is of
128 bytes
but however
other sanitizer
will not throw any alert message because
sorry uh
other sanitizer poisson poison it a
memory area of 8192
so will not throw any alert
and
the thing is that errors like this can
result in vulnerabilities such
as the one i published one year ago in
pro ftp
this is the
cbe of the use after three that i
published one year ago and this
use of the three has a public exploit
released
okay so how we can
solve this so to solve this we can
define
uh
our q stone other sanitizer interceptors
to define
our
other sanitizer interceptors we need two
things
the first thing the first thing
is to define
an
interceptor function
like that like this
where the fu
is the name of the function that we want
to intercept
and the second thing
is to call to the asan intercept
function
the first call
of the function 4 or prior to the first
call of function 4.
and this is just an example this is my
implementation of my
interceptor for apr pialog
there are three relevant parts
the first one is when i call to
real apr pialog
to get the original address
of apr pialog
then i save the address
of
the sanitized malloc
and in the end what i do is to save
both addresses
to free them later
obviously if we define houston
interceptors for
pialog or
whatever malloc
derivative function we will need to
define also q stone interceptors for the
free functions
so in that case what i do in the first
step is to free all the addresses
previously allocated with the other
sanitary sanitizer version of malloc
and then
we can proceed to free the memory
allocated
with the lipsy version of mallow with
the standard version of mallow the lip
say lipsy
cool
so now it's time for the most expensive
part
now i will show you some of the
bonalitis and bugs
that i have found
i'm going to start with a nude reference
in the session identity decode function
as you can see here
this back can be triggered set in a
cookie with a null key and value
so look at this example that clarified
the
the thing
in the first position of the cookie we
have the session
key
and the choco value
this is the
first position
in the second position we have the admin
user key
and
the number two as a value
but in the third position we have an
empty key and
empty value pair
what's the problem here well if you look
just below
you can see
two calls to
apr string token
these functions try to extract extract
the first and the second value that are
the key
and the value of the cookie
so that said let's see what happens
in the
string token function
when the first argument is null
just look here that we have the
pair a string but the second can be null
if the
key was previously
nulled too so
you can see in this line
how the while loop
try to the reference
the first argument the string argument
so in order to
uh so so in in that case it will it will
lead to a nude reference obviously
and
in order to exploit this bug mod session
needs to be enabled
and
this one reliability can lead
to denial of service
at the child level
that is affecting to the other threats
in the same process or affecting to the
other clients that are connected to the
server
okay now it's time for another
vulnerability in that case it's an ex
stack base off by one in the check notes
function
in order to exploit this back
the mob of digest module
should be enabled
and the application has to be using the
digest
authentication here you can see the
and for triggering this back we need to
assign
a specific
set of values
or a specific value
to the noun's field you can see here the
nouns feel
as you can see the the nose field
is a base 64 value
in the nose in the nose
so then the check non function
does a call to the
base base 64 decode binary
in order to decode this
64 value
base 64 value
the thing is that the first argument
is
a local array of size 8 this is the
first argument
but here below you can see us the
calculation of
n bytes the code
variable is grown
giving 9 as a result
so in this case
nine bytes will be written into an
uh
an eight bytes buffer
writing one byte out of the boundaries
of the array in the stack
okay let's see the third vulnerability
here we have an usable three in the
cleanup tables function
this function calls to
rmm destroy
as you can see
in this line
the thing is that this memory
has been previously
freed by the apr allocator destroy
function
so where we are trying to access to an
address that is no no longer valid
it will lead to an use after free or in
this case
uh sometimes to a new safety free and
some other times to a double free
it's important to mention that this
vulnerability can only be triggered
in the one process mode
okay another one in this case we have an
out of bounds right
in the hip the off by one pre the
previously explained off by one was in
the stack and this is in the hip
affecting to the escape
quotes function
this function escapes any quotes
in the given
string
the origin of this back is a calculation
mismatch
between the length of the input string
and the size of the allocated outer
string buffer here you can see the
allocation for the outstream buffer so
in this first code snippet i saw the
code
used
the code that is used to calculate the
length of the input string
and
in this second picture you can see
that the code for calculating
the size of the output string is
different
as a result
if we provide a malicious input to the
escape quote function
it's possible to write out
of write out of the out chart array
that
is it's a pointer to
outstring the output string array
unfortunately this back was previously
reported by google os os fast just a few
days before i found it so it was a back
collision
and now i'm going to explain
something totally different
in this case this back is a race
condition
leading to use after free
and affecting to the apache core
so
during during my fasting research i
found multiple bugs that i was unable to
reproduce again
after go deeper in that i discovered
a kind of race condition between
the
allocation function like for example
that
a lock and the destroy functions of apr
this leads to
a corruption of some nodes of the memory
pool
and
sometimes
the program will try to release
a node that is already present or a
block that is already present in the
free pool
at this moment i'm
well it's important to know that it only
happens when the npm is the even
mpm that is
the
standard de facto nowadays
and at this moment i'm still trying to
figure out how to exploit this
vulnerability in a deterministic way
that is the problem with this type of
race condition bugs
of course there are some
stack traces examples i have a lot of
them in this case we have an use after
free as you can see here is
use software free
look at this stack trace
we can we have the apr allocator destroy
the starting with the npm
in the the event npm but look at this
and for example
to here
a totally different stack trace but
related to the same problem the stack
trace is
totally different as you can see and
it's the same problem you can see here
the even the same
read size of a
and the thing is that
that thing or this problem is not a new
problem
this is a problem that has been reported
a few times
not exactly the same problem but this
type of problems has been reported
in the last years
for example i would like to mention to
hanovoc that reported this back at first
time of this type of bugs
three years ago
if you are interested you can check it
in the following link
their original reports and for now the
position of apache security team is to
not consider
these security issues
as a problem unless
we can show a practical
exploit so i'm working on it and
something similar happened
the last year with pro ftpd
we found a new sustainer free in the
memory pool of pro ftpd that at the same
time is based on the memory pools of
apache and at this moment
there is a
public exploit that has been released to
exploit this polarity but anyway
and during my fasting session obviously
i found a lot of other mineral bugs
so i would like to show you one of them
that is an integral overflow in the
session identity they call function
in that in that case it's not a
it's not a dangerous bug but i think
that it's interesting to show an example
of how trivial or how easy
is to trigger this bug
for example you only need
to send a lock
webdav request here is the request
with a loan
time out value
but don't get mess i mean this is not an
overflow i mean
we provide a really long
time out value but
it is an integral flow
i'm sure that most of you
are able to identify what is the problem
marco i'm sure that you are able
[Laughter]
okay perfect
that's perfect
here we have the addition of two integer
values you can see here that will be a
store
in another integer value
so if these values are big enough we can
overflow the returned value because
obviously we cannot store in an integer
the addition of two maximum interiors
that is a typical integral flow
seeing since this is this back is
triggered with a lock request
mod dab
should be enabled in order to
to to be able to trigger the bar
okay
and now i would like to say
one last thought
apache http security has been
extensively studied by researchers
but at the same time there is still room
for discovering new vulnerabilities for
example using fusing
and in the coming weeks i will release
new details about apache http security
including new bugs so stay tuned
so
that's the end thank you
to all of you for attending and now it's
time for for questing thank you
[Applause]
thank you antonio is there any question
i know i already asked yesterday uh but
i think this might be something
interesting for everyone how much time
do you invested in this specific
research
in that case or in general
in this specific case well i'm not going
to
i don't know i'm not able to
to estimate certainly because i mean i
put a lot of e4
but
it depends it depends it can take i'm
not going to give you a number i don't
want to
maybe later i can give you an answer
privately you know
but it takes
a lot of time yeah
no i don't know yet no
i mean
at the first
slide or well
you can see that in the last year i have
been working on
too many different projects so you need
to
to be able to find vulnerabilities in a
lot of projects in the same gear if you
want to to work
as a security research today yes
any one
any other question another question
yeah
come on
and
while doing the specific research
on the exploitability side are there any
bugs which are actually like easy to
exploit in a real world scenario or most
of them uh like needs also like i don't
know memory leak or whatever to be
exploited
okay there are like
what i usually
look or what i usually try to find with
fasting are memory corruption backs so
there are like two big
uh
type of bugs there there are logic backs
and memory correlation marks so
logic backs
for example if you are able to find a
logic back probably you only need one
back
to be able to exploit the server but
nowaday if you find a memory correction
back
it's very common to need at least two or
three different but backs because
probably you will need a memory leak
probably you need another
great
primitive like for example i don't know
a stack buffer flow or is used after
free hip overflow and then you will
probably need
another brutality to escalate privilege
so yes probably it depends on the type
of vulnerability in this case one two or
three bonaldi's
okay thank you very much
[Applause]
you