[Music]
do that
someone is recounting you network plots
okay what if it's a non-touch recon what
if we're finding out all three email
addresses from third parties that's
great for the internet which is legal
very legal link in Nicholas Creek
inside a basement not very effective so
we do it we get every time one of you is
going to post a link to our blog post
we're going to get an email that says
someone within their organizations blow
us up for our engagement even otherway
because we go by so many try to install
CMS on it and then get it categorized so
that when we go to fish you your content
filtering cousin
[Music]
you're right all right so when it works
is we go through an actual pen test here
the items that are how they deliver and
the process what we found the process
and what we know you could be anywhere
in this see something shiny to jump to
an explanation
I have lots of tools areas for recon the
idea here is that after we did a recon
for a fictitious company we found the
farming with some crazy young worth
there you're right what we found so far
and some users and services okay so what
is this up right we're just gonna here
and these things on your perimeter then
we're gonna try to exploit it so much
it's always yeah oh we gonna do it okay
so we have user accounts you guys no
more jealous yes the spring told you to
something you wrote a long time ago when
he was tired of something that any of
you used male sniper
okay you got it wrong
and then the strange toolkits to atomize
an old sniper Brad sis erupts we're
gonna show those Bulldog here in just a
second one of them interacts with
credential validation and actually
touches your DC for 771 and then the
other one does credential something
different than its event ID four seven
seven six so they interact a little bit
differently with your networks but do
the same using that information along
really good in past experience you have
a world which is not difficult
right it's on I saw something trifling
all right so the point years that we're
able to spray is taking this long so if
you notice my cell addresses so that
mouse title right we see the threads
running across here and this interacts
with an exchange box that tells the
exchange box can you go check each one
of these individual accounts against the
domain controller and tell them their
valid these tools take about
approximately the same amount of time to
do the same so I Killian logs between
look for is a bunch of fail
authentication tennis happening from one
place and in this case the application
is enticing to coming from exchange so
which changed to your DC
minimal times
[Music]
so anyway with both of these tools we
password spread we gain access to
credentials they operate a little
differently when all of these should
trip things on your network you should
catch us doing this this is a fantastic
place where blue cheesy to say we caught
you down red blue to perspective we
should be able to see a pastor sprayer
and with that passing fingers you have
bones available off your gun was
successful as soon as you see a bunch of
this is not on by default and you would
not believe
oh good okay perfect okay that's really
good
and then everybody familiar with not
against this one and actually using it
effectively
so we want to see
we what's inside was interesting emails
[Music]
so one weekend now and we've got access
to a vessel like this one down mandibles
and tell what you find on extras and
there's no direct way to get where
you're going
[Music]
[Applause]
what we do is internal access with
additional that's what your networks
looting or scanning probably moving
toward purple team
[Music]
okay okay yes use our powers
[Laughter]
yeah with extent we've seen almost do
with it with that password that the
interns changed and then emailed the
Playtex to other interns
[Music]
so here we go right we have the user who
requests the system name on the network
that is not resolved by your DNS
infrastructure windows behavior isn't
that right sure yeah that's me
we relay the poison response to our part
ok doesn't work multicast the save
request
yeah that's me right here and we said
that poison responds to our target s of
these systems let me recap that so I
opened up holders windows when I take
the interns here which is not a real
stare windows say yeah that server
doesn't exist I don't really know what
to do anybody on the letter - no - give
me to send you files on Windows so you
send me your apps on Windows and I'll
first you and then I'll give you
something that I don't have okay and
then the attackee server gave nothing
returned because it really didn't care
all the one was your house and next part
of that is this gonna take the hash it's
going to use it that's gonna get support
whereas you but all it has is my hatched
I did give it them password
speaking of hash does anyone recognize
that one I have one hash highlight does
anybody recognize this this is a blank
LM hash there is no Landman force the
password policy greater than 14
characters not 14 characters because
Windows with chalk let it happen
windows will shock that thank you if
your password policy is 14 characters
it's not good enough windows will take a
14 character password chop it in half
and store two chunks of hash which we
can crack my holding space time in our
GPU it's worse than that okay they bring
the white land man is so so bad okay
14 character password yeah that's a good
that's a great okay now we're gonna cut
it out we're gonna send into two
different seven character passwords but
before we do that we're first going to
make everything capitalized so we have
like what maybe 15 to its characters and
then we won't have to crack seven of
those at a time that takes the entire 14
characters basically and that takes
about two minutes so if you store
anything in man
on your domains and then everyone
changed their password
because the alignment attribute enacted
rhetoric and only store 14 characters
[Music]
la-di-da
that's the DNC line - that's right so we
always have a request for a user target
in the system with us would be signing
disabled so the idea is here we let you
get local admin because I'm a typo
because an intern takes an interest here
instead of interns centered
[Music]
countless wasting on your network oh
that's awesome okay so everything we
just did there your every sponder
respond are someone that's gonna say
window says hey is mouth certain they
have it and respondents we say hey
that's me and it's we're descent and
chillin real answers take that pass and
then use it to a thank you on that same
system to the track together just one
condition
note that targets is a variable so
definitely try it on that one system
we'll try it all the targets
[Applause]
okay it's not five minutes of 24 minutes
we're 24 minutes into a pendant okay
prepare every Constance actually took us
like 20 minutes before so we're 44
minutes into the pen test we have a
local admin and one of your internal
desktops the time there's not that
accurate the question is can your blue
team find all those connections and
block us within another time
what's the average response time yeah
it's more than two hours I hear too well
but usually we're in two hours really
awesome looting a really awesome sim
that's finding everything and automating
for you and then taking every resource
and walking on the floor
automatically without disrupting
business
this hurt my trouble before yes
yeah he's annoying lives in Denver area
we call them London services there
probably we've done account that has
local admin on leveraging the domains
alright so right now we're gonna be
retro and yellow right so we've got 259
ounce now we know where the owh server
isn't over the VPN server this you have
a valid credentials and additional
credentials in this room we know what
the internal network access landscape we
know the identified services the river
to a mind which is SMB which we've used
with responder investment be signing zip
which has allowed us to take those
batches to replay them over and over we
have the internal callosum which we
found this I have an email we have a
political as somebody which is given a
sign disabled and we found even happens
we just used here which gave us
additional lashes and I think we think
we missed in the screen
[Music]
this one this is going to tell us that
something touched L says what touched L
sets in here why pick you cell says
what's it L says Chris made me catch my
billfold plaintext creds on the memory
with those it's really hard to trigger
on that it was even harder for us to
sort out which ones so it's hard but
this one is amazing
okay time to learn how to walk properly
we install to spawn there there's
another problem with us and actually
identifying what we've done because he's
tell some hackers to go build a network
that's contrived and does a bunch of
automated things the way that hackers
are going to automate all the things
that make it look like user accounts are
to essentially installed malware
everywhere
so he's then trying to go back and find
where you're running malware
intentionally inside of all the other
intentional malware that's going to be
really difficult so if you're actually
looking at blue tier perspective on
Active Directory domain it just looks
like Matt what everywhere and all that
malware is to automate user behavior so
all the other project this entire Latin
we built Asafa is tapped in multiple
network connections
so the governor teams that do blue team
do they tried to do hunt team analysis
fishing who loves fishing anyone to SBI
security okay
[Music]
coefficient is the rebuilt and
sub-regional but if they're trying to
mimic with me here someone know before
so if using no before it's similar to
that except it gives you a metric so
tell you how many interviews is why her
company you search the news
[Music]
okay so we're going to fish someone you
really really want them to click on the
link you really don't care about the
consequences you can send an email from
each arm that says hey there has been a
complaint of nature and you need to
review this document if you start
talking about finances so organic
something you say hey guys bakery we're
in a position to acquire southern farm
district now check out these plants
which think and then you actually
include like the price of the farm and
maybe the value of the bakery system the
process people you know they shouldn't
probably be privy to that information
with you're going to click on it because
they're interesting another one we
didn't like the fishing in terms of
email Google Calendar injections yeah
that's scary ever you can send your CEO
orbit rarely keep pop-up this is a happy
at this meeting in 20 minutes
and the agenda is rakers put them
and Google Calendar in Texas is an
active feature so ball strike is awesome
okay see to infrastructure so it's a
kind of mess interpreter
Oh No so continue
a lot of documentation because
generating cues about 40 pages of
technical training which is not fun to
do after the faculty yeah that's bad
[Music]
explain for the first ones ever that
might be middle management
[Music]
you should say what the motor 41 what
6.1 why it matters how to make it better
in terms
get a better index position a
practitioner level methodology which
means you take that report you need go
step by step you can reproduce
everything that the pen tester did the
exact same way and come to the exact
same results the reason that's important
is after your team faces vulnerabilities
you want to be able to retest that
methodology without going to another pen
tester for you
[Music]
[Applause]
so yeah kind of lessons about fishing
yes so we get it domain you purchased a
domain we want that's a way to be look
legitimate
so if you have the Borden ended with
Cisco when you go to the web browser and
you open up with the targets that domain
typically good having good product that
filters then it's I should wear to check
in this database to see whether or not
that domain name this accurate
legitimate miscategorized and it's gonna
say oh yeah that's categorize to the
business sector so it's probably Jimin
for that user to get to it
in order for that fish to work we have
to go in
[Music]
everybody knew what it is marketers oh
what happens okay so SPF 30 can the idea
is that if I send you an email SPF is
what you tell receive email server
whether or not my email that I sent was
authorized to be sent with the front
domain that I'm setting it has these
together can tell recipient mail servers
they were not authorized to send an
email with dk when I sent my email I
then have to include a key and that key
is the public key that I'm sending has
to match the key that's in DNS so that
is one way to authenticate email it's
being sent with d-minor utilize these
two things together and you can build a
report back so the bleep blue teamers
perspective you can use a team on here's
what a bit like about this you can use
team up to determine all the emails that
are sent using your from domain that are
not sent by someone you authorized to be
sending email from right so China is
sending sorry if any one else that is
not use sends email on your behalf you
will get a report back from recipient
mail server saying hey when you receive
this mail we actually walked it
know that that's what democracy
recording okay so it's pretty important
there's also really great 12 dozen
Houston mark on its own here it gets
really ugly email reports back that are
useless they're like what's a great data
and stuff that doesn't make any sense
that anyone what you want to do is so
partner agencies
the marketing agency should be working
with the IT department the way they
don't but let's see what they don't
anyways if they did you come to get
better penetration where it's on emails
alright I think we were any other
questions yes how's the food the
increased move to reduce your ability
through this we ran the HTML was inside
of the fish if we sent that 12 is 365 we
will get an immediate beacon back to our
c2 sir that does not come from our
client no it came from yes it comes from
office 365 they're inspecting that
traffic they will recognize it as a c2
so you have to be clever you have to
make emails that look legitimate and
doubly directly to your Bimmer
[Music]
that is very very quiet very targeted so
if you'll notice before we did it pass
the spray no you don't do that we will
do everything we tend to find what we
know anyone a lot password to one valid
user account and that's one of the use
the same username so if not to raise any
suspicions it's much slimmer Intel had a
really cool
[Music]