alright everyone welcome to Bellevue
nana at 61 it was actually just yeah it
was actually 20 years ago yesterday that
the first nanog meeting was held in ann
arbor wasn't able to get a roster from
that list but i'm guessing their work
180 50 people there so thank you all
very much for coming out appreciate that
we also had a special conference call
this morning with the weather channel
they've assured us if you're in atlanta
twenty percent less chance of I
crippling ice storms this week they also
said don't hold them to that so we are
at / 158 hundred and fifty people here
so this actually makes it the most
attended nanog ever thank you very much
for being part of that it's a very large
crowd I can tell by some of the folks
standing in the back there there are
still some seats up here if you want to
work your way up we got a couple seats
left not that close I also want to thank
our sponsors here NTT as both the
conference and network sponsor you'll
hear hear it a little bit from them
pretty soon thank you very much MTT I
want to thank our premium sponsors in
particular our diamond sponsors Google
Microsoft verisign and NTT again thank
you
before we get too far into this I do
want to thank the program committee our
names are up on the board they've put a
lot of work into getting this program
together for you will be holding new pc
elections this fall at the next meeting
so feel free to find some of these folks
talk to them about what they're doing
and see if it might be something you're
interested in we're always looking to
add new people into the pc in the fall a
lot of things on tap for this meeting
we've got tutorials happening tomorrow
morning a great a great tutorial from
tlf on net comp we've got mpls from
richard steenburgen from gtt we've got
great keynote content this morning from
David Meyer as well as Lynn Bozak really
looking forward to both those talks
before we get too far into anything else
here what I want to ask is that who here
raise your hand if you've been to more
than ten nanog all right here is the
bonus question was anyone here at nanog
one oh yeah to all right
Steve Feldman and Bill Norton thanks
thanks for sticking with us through
sixty one of these I'm going to soon
you've been to each one so give you
credit for that lightning talk
submissions are open we'll be doing
lightning talks tomorrow afternoon you
can find those linked via the website
the submission page for that please get
something in it's about a 10 minute talk
a newcomer lunch this afternoon we will
be doing a newcomer lunch immediately
following the morning session so I'll
ask one more show of hands who are the
newcomers in the room all right that's
great I think we shall we've got over
200 newcomers here so I hope to see a
lot of you at the lunch in a couple
hours we'll we'll talk a little bit more
about the program and how you can make
the method the the most out of the nanog
while you're here socials we a lot of
socials coming up tonight we're at the
billiards parlor courtesy of NTT
tomorrow with the rock bottom brewery
courtesy of Microsoft and wednesday
night at lucky strike power play
courtesy of Facebook so free good
openings there events there thank you
let's see a little comment about rooms
of meeting areas there are some track
rooms adjacent here nearby there's an
air and help desk out in the lobby so
those folks are standing by to help you
if you need anything and my last note is
something on the microphones we even
have it
alright so I'll read it we have
guidelines posted all the microphones
here if you feel like you want to ask a
question please identify yourself and
your affiliation first I'll ask you that
you ask one question at a time and then
let someone know they'll speak there
several microphones there could be other
folks cued up and the last note is
please be respectful and professional we
all know we're passionate about our job
so let's keep it professional that I
will hand off too Betty Burke Betty hi
everyone everyone wake not too early we
started a little later to make sure that
you could all get here for these opening
remarks I'm very very excited to be here
as Greg indicated nanog is celebrating a
pretty large milestone and it's my great
pleasure to be able to work with a group
of volunteers that you see on this list
that make nanog work today it's a very
large organization and a group of
dedicated people which is part of the
community that makes 850 people possible
at an an odd meeting so thank you for
all the support that you give us so you
forget this working yes while you're
here at this day at you say it Bellevue
there's some lists I'm not going to go
through every one of them but there is
lots of folks who are looking at these
lists and willing to give you any help
that you need and finding your way
around or what's happening at what time
or something's not working for you so
please do let us know the badges you'll
hear about these a couple different
times and different venues have colored
ribbons on them which is just an
indication of who are the volunteers
where we come from just a little bit of
information for you and again as Greg
indicated a huge thank you to our host
ntt communications when I scheduled
hotel or did hotel contracts and site
visits and made an announcement that we
were going to do
nog 61 in bellevue at one meeting in a
hallway there were a group of folks that
raised their hand and said me me me we
want to make this this the biggest
meeting ever and mt tu surpassed all of
our expectations you've been great they
put together a lot of engineering
support to help us build a fantastic
network here and they've got great
partners and have actually reached out
and helped me with spreading the word
about the meeting so I really can't say
thank you enough and and Michael it's up
to you let's see if I get this right
here yep so we're now to Michael we're
back it's getting the side deck I do
want to before Michael steps to the mic
just say one other thank you Greg
mentioned but it's really important that
all of you say thank you to our sponsors
who are here today they've been
wonderful in helping to provide
financial support for the evening
socials for all of you to enjoy after
the meeting and to provide Xbox gifts as
part of the survey giveaway reminder
when you need to complete your survey to
qualify for the presentation survey you
can do that via guide book online with
your mobile mobile device or complete
the survey online on the website as well
either one will work and we will award
gifts by the program committee during
the program so a few reminders and again
thank you to all of our sponsors for
helping us get this meeting launched and
let me introduce Michael wheeler from
ntt communications
good morning and nanog hey Dori and
how's it going surprised to see you this
early in the morning usually don't show
up until lunchtime I just had a good
awesome breakfast at the Juanita cafe in
kirkland still can't figure out how
Smith didn't make that gig work out with
oli go now Dave please try and be civil
this is an important community and you
should be a bit nicer and how you talk
about the other members of nanog it
would be great if you could go find Mike
after the session and just well give him
a gig nanog hug uh oh the hell is
tempting hugging now he tried to hug me
in New Orleans last year and I almost
passed out Jared please please don't be
such an antagonist I know you're a sweet
guy at heart so please try and be a bit
more courteous we all just need to try
and behave like professionals exactly
Jared just be nice we know you have
wicked amounts of eggs because you're a
ginger so just dial it down a notch
aural have to whip you whip your good
hey does anyone here want to befriend
the whole time i was at comcast no one
wanted to be friends on facebook now
that I've move on to Apple maybe some of
you are up for friending me anyone Jared
I got a couple of mouths to feed at home
so if you could just grow a pair and
stick around her at one summer that
would be a great thing what am I going
to do with you guys I would greatly
appreciate it if everyone could be a
little bit more courteous with each
other and perhaps more professional with
our vocabulary choices if everyone can
just excuse me for a few minutes I need
to go take care of something uh huh I'll
be right back hey if anyone is heading
to downtown Seattle this week let me
know I've got to check out Miller's
guild it's a great new restaurant open
this year by Chef Jason will
yeah going downtown will be great I've
got to go check out the experience music
project I know they won't have any
ultra-cool Devo exhibits but I did read
that the grunge section is fantastic
jared is there any way you can turn up
the bandwidth the notch or two I've been
trying to validate some of my favorite
content sources from the Pacific Rim but
things seem a bit bogged down I'm sure
you were used to ultra high levels of
capacity in your former life but now
that you are in a bit less ostentatious
circumstances at one summer I thought
everyone including you would be served
very adequately on 100 gig e connections
here in Seattle maybe the Asian oriented
content you're looking for is stored
farther away in Amsterdam well I guess
it will be adequate
ok now you use close to the baby holy
crap Dorian what's the story with the
suit and the music oh I just wanted to
have a proper entrance to today's
session and I prefer not to go anywhere
without my official theme music Dorian I
don't care what your theme music isn't
and I'm not gonna be twerking around in
a pair of tighty whities with a foam
finger that's just not going to
happen well Betty uh I think that
Proclamation is a relief for everyone
now that we have that settled live from
Seattle it on 61
so I'm glad to hear there's laughter and
not stop being thrown at me so it means
that haven't upset anyone too bad so
anyway welcome to seattle welcome to New
like 60 120 years kind of an amazing
thing I mean you know the size of the
group speaks to it but the reality is
this group of people impacts the world
on a minute-by-minute basis now and I
think you guys all are a huge part of
that so I certainly think it's a
fantastic and get together and glad to
see that it's here in Seattle where a
lot of us from NTT are based so just
iming a couple housekeeping items for
tonight but that's really all the
excitement that I'm going to bring to
the podium here so there's 100 Giggy
experience center out in the back I
think people you've heard it kind of
mentioned in the animation but there's a
TV up there you can stream some live
stuff from netflix courtesy of dave or
you can also plug your laptop in and
stream your own personal content there
as well and kind of play a little bit
with that that connection we worked with
cisco and sign on that and they were
real helpful and putting that together
and putting all the equipment in place
to facilitate that connections so if you
want to take a look at some of the the
schematics vector you can as well
tonight the social is at the parlor
which is just across the street in the
neighboring kind of tower I think it's
on the third floor it will start at
eight o'clock after Bering gear wraps up
and our co-sponsor for that is
ragingwire kind of one of our sister
companies and NTT so we want to thank
them for their involvement with that
it's open bar there'll be food there's
going to be a pool tournament if you
want to sign up for the pool tournament
you need to do it today during the day
at the hunter Giggy experience center so
teams of two and there's room for 48
teams and so it's 100 people in total so
run that as long as it goes through the
evening and there'll be some some prizes
and stuff at the end and then the last
thing is during the social tonight we're
going to be doing selling raffle tickets
and the raffle tickets are to win the TV
which is a brand-new 55 inch samsung
ultra HDTV and we're going to be
donating the proceeds to Seattle
Children's Hospital on behalf of nanog
so will gets a chance to buy some
tickets there at the at the social
that's the time to do it so that's
really all I have so thanks very much
it's great to ever win Seattle and hope
you have a great week
alright thanks a lot Michael I bet he
mentioned it I want to underscore it we
do have surveys up you can answer them
on the web page via the guide book app
we will badger you about these almost
ceaselessly they're very valuable to us
we've made a lot of changes to the
program over the years directly based
off that feedback and Microsoft is
sponsoring some giveaways so there will
be some new toys to be handed out every
day based on survey respondents
you