I will go with your decision all right
wow that's a full room we did not expect
this I have to tell you these guys did
not expect so many people to show up and
on a personal note before I start off
blabbering about failing and b-sides and
communities I just want to say again
thank you to the organizers here I've
known them for about a year now
give or take and I can tell you that it
they worked extremely hard to set this
up for you and there's been a lot of
emotions around it and efforts and it's
every time there that I see a new b-side
starting off in in a city I'm amazed
it's each and every time each one is a
story of its own each one is you know
different personas and technologies and
communities and each time that it
happens it's like a home oh my god it's
it's mind-blowing yeah so I wanted to
talk today about failing and for the
rest of the day you're probably gonna
hear a lot of really cool stories about
your community about you know people
like us that are taking you know a big
step standing on this stage not like me
I'm just you know talking about stuff
but they're actually doing research and
putting out interesting stuff and
telling you about it and educating you
but they didn't get here just by chance
they got here by by doing a lot of this
and and I think that that's one of the
most untold stories that don't really
get the the front stage in in our
community or even in general and as
someone who's made a career out of
failing or failing successfully I think
it's it's really important to to kind of
understand that and that's really a key
to having something like this happen
yeah my you know initial conversations
with with these guys was like yeah we
can do it besides we probably can bring
like 20 50 people sound like that I was
like no no no
step it up it's gonna be a lot more um
let's start my name is Ian I'm the the
chief security officer for force impress
and in my my night job or any other jobs
I'm also the president of the board of
besides Vegas we've been doing this for
10 years now 11 yeah well we we suck at
counting so we're celebrating 10 this
year it's an utter fail and and there's
my animation suck ok yeah I'm gonna kill
you for this
we have you know we're growing up on a
lot of success stories a kind of the
heroes of our time the the Jeff Bezos
and the Bill Gates and Steve Jobs and
they're like the Titans of tech there
are the people who we look up to that
have made it that have started literally
with nothing not like the American
version of nothing
the really nothing and set up
multi-billion dollar companies products
that we're all using everywhere and
things that are changing our lives but I
want to talk about how they got there
and what made them what they are and
it's not really those successes the
successes we celebrate all the time it's
the failures and as you can see in my
own personal failure of not managing my
slides anyone remember the Microsoft
Zune ok ok I was expecting like a
younger crowd that's awesome Microsoft
Zune was Microsoft's attempt to compete
with the iPod I think it even came out
before the iPod and from not if I'm not
mistaken um it's a really interesting
concept or kind of understanding that
this thing preceded the iPod coming out
first doesn't necessarily mean that this
is going to be the successful on and
Microsoft miserably failed with the Zune
and is still not in the music industry
you know I mean they've lost that battle
a long time ago now it's mostly
controlled by Apple and Spotify and and
the smaller players Microsoft is not
even playing not on the hardware side
not on the the media side and that's a
again multi-billion dollar industry they
had it they had it they had ie they even
had like a few versions of it and it was
competing at your head with with an iPod
the market was there complete failure
when we look at Apple Apple even even
didn't start as a successful company
only after a couple of really horrible
iterations of really shitty computers if
you remember this is this is the Apple -
no Lisa yeah that's the Lisa this is the
Apple one horrible computers they didn't
work there ultra expensive they're
really really bad iterations of a
computer but they needed that failure
they needed to put something out there
they went on a limb and they said there
is nothing right now that fits what we
want let's build it they got some
feedback really harsh feedback trust me
it feedback that you know when I'm
thinking back about the the first days
of Apple that kind of feedback would
have crushed most people and they would
just just like you know what it you
don't want it they'll need it I'm gonna
go off make you know big big IBM
machines but they didn't they kept on
going and I said alright so so the one
wasn't good the Lisa is kind of it's
almost there and then they came up with
the Apple 2 which blew the market to
pieces anyone remember this phenomenal
machine the Apple Newton all right this
was before iPhones this was before iPads
this was before the Palm Pilots this
thing had like handwriting recognition
it was the most sophisticated thing it
preceded its time by by a decade at
least if I'm not mistaken they went
they designed a device with a
touchscreen with graphics the size of
you know a mobile device like a proper
mobile device the market didn't even
know what to do with it
it was just like what do you want we're
still in the Apple and an IBM like the
PC era and these guys were innovating
way beyond their time and guess what
disastrous failure disastrous and now
every one of us almost every one of us
holds one of those in their pocket
whether it's an iPhone or an Android
they've literally paved that way through
those horrible business failures a
project like this kills companies kills
them and this is not about some
financial resilience whiz-bang like
running the numbers this can kill a
company because the amount of resources
and the man-hours and the money that you
put into a project like that to get it
into a commercial version is insane
you're betting a company on something
like that and it fails what do you do
now Windows ME if we're moving on to
gates so we're done picking on on Steve
Jobs Windows ME again
colossal failure not that the windows 98
before that was a phenomenal operating
system but you know what you keep
iterating I talked about the Zune so
we're gonna leave it alone
phases I used to work for for Amazon you
have no idea no idea how many failed
projects major projects Amazon allows
itself to go through in order to be that
that hyper successful company Amazon
fire phone one of the few projects that
actually make it out
you know going through those additional
gates that a lot of other project just
stopped and kind of recognized the
failure there so by itself it is a
double failure because it failed to stop
getting to production when it where it
should have
and then in wedding to production we
need to full failure mode an Amazon
managed to I don't know within six month
if I'm not mistaken they've killed it
they were able to make the decision that
again manufacturing line software
hardware everything that went into this
stopped and they just killed a project
colossal failure guess what
still one of the most successful
companies in the world I think I've seen
a graph of the number of people that
work for Amazon they're topping 600,000
people like 600,000 employees when I got
there in 2015 they were at around two
hundred two hundred and thirty thousand
employees in a year they hired more than
a hundred thousand employees insane
numbers you can't get there without
failing on the way there is no way to do
that if you keep succeeding it's just
not gonna work and we'll we'll skip
pets.com because that's a that's really
old-school let's talk about some of our
own heroes like hacker heroes anyone
recognizes the guy on the left
Mitnick of course anyone recognizes the
guy on the right
not bunny
no let's borderline racist but no I'm
just kidding here nothing Thank You
Shima Maura rings a bell starts to ring
a bell
alright out of these two who's the more
successful hacker not famous successful
you don't want to play
it's it's the first the first hour I'll
give it to you so most people go like oh
my god kevin Mitnick
why is he famous because he went to jail
because he got caught how does that
qualify someone for being our you know
hacker community hero because he got
caught by the FBI
come on the real story about kevin
Mitnick and and I invite you to Google
this and read about it it's a
fascinating story is that kevin got
caught because he picked on a guy he
kept on he picked on Shimura kevin was
having problems a because he was he kept
getting traced back to his landline or
to the land lines that he was hacking
and using and he decided to go into
mobile and he didn't know about
mobile not that he knew a lot about
technology but he was looking for
someone who knew mobile phones and had
the right software and the right axis
and he found this guy
Fiona Morra was working as a consultant
Kevin stole the software stole software
from him
sorry using it and humor just went into
humor who wasn't really a hacker hacker
but guess what he was deep inside it's
not about what you do it's it's about a
mindset and humara went on full-on
hacker mode and decided to go after
Kevin because now we're talking pride
and you stole my software now you're
using it illegally to do bad stuff went
after him all of the forces in the US
all the FBI the police MIT Berkeley all
the other universities PAC bells AT&T s
of the world couldn't catch Mitnick one
person did Shima Morra he hacked back
that's the first hack back that that we
know of well there's probably before
that but that's the the most famous one
and Shima Mora learned along the way
failed a lot of times and managed to get
back in catch Kevin he was the one that
enabled the FBI the end of the day he
was consulting
eventually and tracked back Kevin into
his his location in North Carolina if
I'm not mistaken that's how he got him
and these are some more relevant
pictures of those two so this is G or
Morra back at his office in in
California if I'm not mistaken when he
was working on the the mitten the case
back at the time and this is Kevin in a
more natural environment we talked about
Steve Jobs before the real success of
Apple and the real ability to iterate on
failure and iterate on products wasn't
really jobs it was was Steve Wozniak
he's a real hacker inside of Apple he's
the real kind of innovator and techie
these are the heroes that we should be
talking about when we're talking about
successfully failing failures of
grandeur let's talk about how to
successfully fail how to do this
correctly first first and foremost you
have to step on a limp it's about
innovation it's about stepping out of
the comfort zone and saying I am willing
to take a risk and part of it is getting
into that mindset of planning to fail if
you start something off with no plans of
failure with no ability to understand
this is I am taking myself out of a
conference though this is not just
following instructions one by one you
will never succeed I love this image
everyone's like think about it when
you're starting a project and you're not
creating failure plans
this is the real fail when you're doing
anything that is not that has not been
done before at least not by you make
sure to take into account kind of a
couple of exit points all right what
happens if this this little cart doesn't
have brakes so I jump out of it at this
point good idea before it picks up too
much speed what happens if you
I can't break a certain algorithm or or
get to a point where my memory
optimization or you know my Rob my Rob
tricks don't work in this environment
have a failure plan if you don't have
those you're just not gonna going to
succeed deconstructing and building on
lessons learned think about all the
times that you try to attack something
try to learn something new and you kept
running into things that eventually
turned out someone else already found
using other people's lessons and and
failures is the key look guys I'm lazy
alright there's no other way to sit -
you need to go about it but I'm using my
laziness and convincing myself that
there's got to be someone else that did
something like that before I'm only
leaving whatever mental and physical
energy that I have left do actual work
for things that I'm pretty certain
no-one did before for everything else
someone's got to have a solution so
focus your energy on doing things that
actually matter deconstruct other
people's work use their failures to plan
your your own failure is the real
experience if you talk to someone who's
only had successes there's nothing to
learn like what what did you learn by
doing something and it just worked is it
gonna work every time are you sure is it
repeatable can it work better if you do
something and you're just like alright
that's it done you've done nothing
it's like gee thanks nothing to learn
from here let's get a little personal
and because people are like oh you're
staying on stage you're keynoting no no
let's talk about some real visceral
failures and this is a cool story when I
when I was starting off during red
teaming and and this this fits perfectly
because yesterday we're sitting around
picking locks and everyone's like
this big monstrous masterlock yellow the
the yellow that no one managed to pick
and ever like all right doesn't work
doesn't work it doesn't work and I'm
talking picking up the lock talking to
some of my colleagues and I'm starting
to pick at it because it's it's like
it's fun and and I popped it I picked it
and suddenly everyone just stops and
goes like you just picked that lock I
was like yeah of course I didn't get
good at picking just out of the blue I
actually really sucked at it and one of
my first red team engagements were I had
a physical element sawn into the
engagement I'm Anna - first of all
convinced myself to sell something that
really didn't exist my skill sets were
not set up to do any kind of physical
like lock-picking testing in a real
environment that is not this one lock
that I practiced on and I found myself
at an office building after I somehow
brilliantly managed to lock myself in a
conference room I spent a couple of
hours there you know as under the guise
of a guest I'm inside I'm hooking up to
like the the a/v systems and hopping I'm
pivoting inside a network everything's
going fine I'm getting data I'm doing
like hopping on voice over IP networks
everything's great at some point someone
comes in apparently the the room wasn't
booked anymore someone comes in opens
the door a little bit peeks inside I'm
kind of cowering in the corner they
don't see me they close the door lock it
walk away it's 4:30
it's like a semi-public company so by
5:00 everyone's gone and I'm like
starting to realize oh this is it
I'm locked inside I spent the next 45
minutes 45 minutes sweating bullets
trying to lock - to pick this like six
pin cylinder like super tight lock
sweating bullets I'm like I'm gonna stay
here until tomorrow and this is gonna be
a
heresy I'm gonna be a polo sweat is this
is horrible why am I doing this I
started doubting my whole career path
life choices
I was on the phone after four or five
minutes with my contact at the company
starting to play out like how am I gonna
explain that I need someone to get back
to the office get up all the way to the
like the 14th floor and unlock me from
the conference room I was supposed to
break into so I can go back home and
start writing the report as I'm on the
phone it was literally within like my
last shreds of dignity I managed to
unlock this this monstrous which is now
I realize a piece of hit lock make some
some fake-ass excuses on the phone and
and drag myself and and my shattered
dignity back home understanding that
this thing is either never gonna work
again and I'm not dealing with red
teaming ever again or I'm gonna have to
get a little better at this and get some
more practice fast word if four or five
years this is a from one of the red team
classes that Chris and I gave in
Columbia yeah this was the first red
team class we gave and these are
Colombian school girls that go to a
American continent you a American school
really fancy neighborhoods really like
rich families there were our translators
they weren't even like doing anything
there our translators for the class and
we were teaching them how to pick locks
10 minutes later our security detail
which we invited inside because they
were going like what are you guys doing
they didn't speak a word of English
we're like hand waving them inside our
security detail is working on locks the
school girls are teaching them how to
pick themselves out of their own
handcuffs
we wouldn't have gotten here if I didn't
end up locked up in that office building
five or six years earlier contemplating
life choices and considering like
changing jobs maybe because this is
horrible and and I suck at it and I
failed if you have any idea what is it
to pick locks and I highly encourage you
to do so
45 minutes working on the lock I can't
believe I did it
back at the time I was like I didn't
have my choice but it was a colossal
failure and that's one of the best
experiences that I've had that kept me
driving forward and kind of expand my
horizons into you know more and more and
more into the physical security side of
things look for the signal in the quiet
so we I mentioned our hacker heroes
before and our kind of industry leaders
and as you'll note there's a lot of
noise that these guys are making there's
a reason why almost every hand was
raised here when I asked who's the guy
on the left that's camping meth Nick
again media hero he's everywhere
everyone knows his name he goes on TV he
gets paid thousands of dollars to to
speak at conferences he's running some
shady businesses doing some shady stuff
done by other people but a lot a lot of
noise
Shiva Morra no one's heard about him I
had to like almost go one by one until
the guy at literally the back of the
room was like Maura no one heard about
it because there's no noise but there's
a lot of signal and it's really key to
try to pick up the the signal in the
quietness look for the guys who are not
putting themselves out there who don't
have thousands and tens of thousands of
followers on Twitter were not on every
freakin stage on every freaking security
conference look for the guys that are
putting themselves out there maybe have
like a
repo maybe make it to a small conference
look for these guys this is HD more on
the right and spoon em on the left
hey for those of you who don't know
there they wrote Metasploit anyone knows
Metasploit yes of course Metasploit was
a shitty program I know I've been there
at blackhat 28:12 no mm and what I wrote
it down here 2004 oh my god I'm getting
old um I couldn't find pictures from
blackhat for some reason so this is
their Def Con talks the same year and
when they released mouse Floyd for his
first time he was written in Perl
now again I'm old enough to be able to
hold on and do something functional in
Perl I'm betting you if any of the young
kids here understand what we used to do
in Perl they would just go like that
that is horrible
that is the absolutely wrong way to do
anything related to computing so they
wrote this thing there this project in
Perl in 2004 horrible but if you're not
it kind of worked it worked like in a
hacker way it's you know for the four or
five things that it was supposed to do
it did it did it horribly but okay they
are brave enough to understand this is
shitty we need to fix it we failed
complete rewrite not like complete
rewrite you know what let's pretty up
the quote with the Perl code let's make
it more and more effective let's
documented complete rewrite as in let's
change languages let's change platforms
and took all the hackish stuff
translated into Ruby built a new
framework in 2007 and up to this day
without that initial failure we wouldn't
have proper Metasploit modules and
interactions and researchers and all the
fun things that came afterwards
initially well he didn't have an
interpreter it's like you got you you
know you create a payload send it out
BAM done
now we have all those frameworks because
of that initial failure because they
wanted more and they weren't happy with
with what they had but they had to fail
and there's no way that matters Floyd
would have gotten there and think about
all the other talks that were out there
in at blackhat I was just fortunate
enough to be in the room because I
couldn't get to the other talks because
they were packed that are full and the
only reason I know HD and spoon and no
Metasploit it was because I couldn't get
to the you know the popular talks at
blackhat I was like ah you know what
let's sit in this this thing these kids
can probably teach me something and they
did and I was like a fanboy and it just
worked but without that failure without
going on a limb without me by again by
my luck now I look for speakers that I
was like I was just talking about this
with Chris yesterday and I was telling
him look I think besides Barcelona's
gonna be awesome I know none of the
speakers super excited to hear what they
have to say because you know there's no
noise it's gonna be all signal and we're
sitting you know over dinner last night
and I was like getting giddy on everyone
that introduced himself is like I'm
talking about this I'm talking is like
like yes I have no idea what this is I
have done no work on that this is super
interesting I'm gonna learn something
new finally this week be able to pick up
those ideas and even you know what I
guarantee you one of the talks here is
gonna be about something that really
didn't work or that's not gonna work for
you but if you can pick up a couple of
ideas from that that is going to be the
best success that you'll have here
turning to the community don't try to
look for again this is about making out
the signal from the noise turn to the
community because the talent is here
this is again this is literally why
we're here because I know and Chris
knows and everyone knows I've been to
Barcelona many many
times before there were security
conferences and hacker conferences in
Barcelona I know I was there I was
speaking there and then they were gone
and this is exactly what I was telling
like the guys I know that the community
is here I mean no they couldn't have all
just left within the past five six ten
years turn to the community and this is
the literal proof that it can happen
that the communities here the talent
he's here the content is here the money
is here everything is here this is where
you can find the signal you don't have
to look for the noise that everyone else
is making if you look at the big
conferences the black hats the RSA s try
to look behind the scenes and understand
how they work black hat submissions and
talks are due almost a year before the
event
sorry RSA the black hat submissions
they're designed to create media buzz
people are releasing research
specifically to get into black hat it
doesn't make any sense why would you sit
on information on data on research where
you could have shared it you could have
iterated over it
you could have failed and made it better
and better and better and eventually
made it make it to the next black hat or
you know what gives a about black
hat go to besides I might be a little
biased but most conferences run once a
year do you really think that there's
innovation that gets published only once
a year
screw those big conferences have a B
sides have a Barcelona hackerspace you
know the the Barcelona cybersecurity
thing you meet every month I've been
there and it's amazing and you can get
content talk about it fail over it show
stuff that's incomplete show stuff that
you know what shouldn't we shouldn't
make it to like a black hat or a b-sides
show stuff still and work so you can
iterate and and successfully fail so you
can get to that final submission
tune out the noise this is the most
difficult part social media is is is oh
god I love social media and it's it's
it's great for some things I have to say
something something positive but it's a
dumpster fire for most other things it's
filled with emotions people are very
easily detached with humanity before
when they go to onto social media they
turn into into horrible horrible people
and they're spewing out dump it's a
dumpster fire tune it out learn how to
utilize social media to your needs I'm
using it purely to either troll my
friends and get horrible things out of
them or use it for marketing for myself
for my company for things that I want to
promote and that's it it's not about
family it's not about friends it's it's
nothing if I need to call my friends I'm
like DMing or you know other things I
don't care about checking into places
taking pictures of food you know
commenting on politics again unless it's
trolling my friends tune out they know
is try to find the quiet ones on social
media the ones who post you know oh I've
updated something on my github I have a
problem with this this doesn't work for
me can anyone help me anyone anyone
wants to pitch in on a project look for
those it's really hard because they're
surrounded by last but not least I think
I'm good on time right you're not
freaking out yet you're not sweating so
I'm I'm gonna keep going last but not
least and this is the most important
message I think that I have noob it out
we're all learning things I mean today
in the last couple of days I threw a
little conference you know and in our
company and now learn new things because
my staff and my colleagues and my peers
stepped up and put up content and and
made a big thing and I was like yes this
is interesting I'm still learning I mean
if I if I were to get to a point where I
would be like you know what I'm good I
think I am a professional now you know
those I know no sorry I think I'm an
expert I have a cyber security expert
call me out because that's the point
where my career is done literally there
is no way to become an expert in this
industry and I'm willing to fight like
physically fight anyone who says
otherwise
or at least get someone to fight for me
but understand and embrace this noob
Ness it is it is an amazing energy that
kept keeps me going again I'm excited
this is the 498 b-side event that is
thrown worldwide since this guy here
started it 11 years ago because he was
pissed at something and we participated
in it and we learned and we still learn
and I'm as excited to you know to stand
here on stage and and clear this area of
and let the real people who are
doing work talk about what they're doing
because I understand and as I said
earlier like last night I was giddy
understanding that I'm gonna learn new
things that I have no idea about but
unless you get to that unless you
embrace that State of Mind
I'm a noob I'm going if I try to touch
this I'm going to fail so badly but it's
gonna be so much fun and that's the only
way it's gonna get better
so with that I just want you to
recognize that first of all the bravery
of anyone standing here I mean I'm
almost done I'm like I'm ready to go and
it takes a lot and to come up with
content and not just like fancy words
and talk about oh you should be brave
and fail and motivational speaker is
amazing it's absolutely amazing so
embrace that recognize it and step on
that stage it is scary as hell it's not
for everyone but it is so rewarding
because it gives you so much feedback
and it connects you with other people
and it enables them to connect with you
and that's the only way that really
successful projects and really
successful code hacks people end up
together thank you
[Applause]
comments this is not like a questions
talk but I'm happy to answer anything
that someone might have nothing it's too
early oh yes the teen testing yeah what
is that god how much time do we have
Red Team testing in a nutshell is full
adversarial simulation a are you
familiar with pen testing good it's not
been testing think pen testing but in
the real world no scope no limitations
no rules and as a red teamer you have
one task which is to simulate a certain
adversary whether it's a script kitty or
a professional hacker or a competitor or
a nation-state you are tasked with
assuming that role in being able to
subject your target with everything that
that adversary has in play from a
technical perspective from a knowledge
perspective from a threat intelligence
an intelligence gathering perspective
from a physical security social
engineering accessibility everything no
rules
no scope everything's in play your
target is the company it's the business
assets and it's not an IP address it is
not the URL it's not a database it's not
a computer that's in a nutshell and
correct me if I'm wrong
Red Team testing do all the things yes
more questions
yeah go ahead no yeah so what will you
consider your biggest failure the has
helped you the most
it's funny so the the couple of slides
that I added this morning and I was
talking about on the way here that this
is awesome we're using Google slides so
I can I can make edits until the last
minute and they're automatically sync
and this is my latest but the slide that
I actually added there I had the two
slides to be honest a one that talks
about someone else's failure which again
you learn a lot from it's the last night
if you don't know the fourth nation that
landed on the moon was supposed to
successfully land on the moon it's a
couple it's I know one of the the guys
that started this Israel had it's a
lunar lander or not lander faller it get
to the moon crash into it because they
had some failure along the way again
failure the second slide and and and I
was all about like this is a colossal
failure it is amazing there were the six
or seven nation to put something around
the moon and the fourth want to put
something on it I'm not gonna say land
because it made contact with the lunar
ground the livestream said last night as
I was like but it's an amazing
endeavor and they failed so successfully
and now the media is filled with like
kids are inspired kids want to go and
learn science and math and we just took
I was like oh let's do the math on
something that no one has ever done
before at that scale in a gravity that
we cannot simulate here and my personal
favorite failures are not professional
per se and I and that was the other
slide I had like three so picture this
picture 3a like Facebook profiles were
the default ones and I want to talk
about a learning from the three worst
managers that I ever worked under
horrible atrocious and Chris knows some
of them because I was I was bitching and
whining and it's like it's horrible but
I'm at it because I think I can do
something here and in hindsight which is
always easy I learned the most about
running companies managing people
managing resources projects all of that
stuff from those people because they
were absolutely at it horrible
horrible horrible to a point like that
should be a prosecutable offense and
that has been my personal favorite again
and it's about sticking it out and and
making sure that you get that experience
I know it sounds super counterintuitive
I know that most people like millenials
are like if I don't like my job I'm
gonna quit I was like really
I'll pull the privileged of you know
stick it out there's a lot to learn from
shitty jobs and shitty environments and
managers truthfully was the best like
management lessons from there I didn't
learn anything from like running a
successful organization I learned some
but most of it was through that a
lock-picking again probably on a
personal note one of the worst ones and
I had a major project that again
completely failed that forced me to to
create a new attack vector back at a
time I think I talked about it back at
the cybersecurity Meetup and where we
just could not complete the job and I
had to find a way to external trade data
and I ended up like creating a
hodgepodge of hopping techniques and
actual traded over voice over IP again
that's the cool story and Ania comes out
but what preceded that was a horrible
failure and what I neglected to tell you
was the initial report that we had to
send them that basically offered a full
refund because we sucked but we stuck it
out and I was like that sucks I don't
care about the money but I can't go back
and say that I failed an engagement and
it was a disastrous failure I mean we
literally forgot the money it's done but
leaving it off without the ability to
say that I man I got something can't do
it a lot of questions awesome alright
thanks so much
[Applause]