let's start with a little game or maybe
more like a thought exercise let's say
that you've just been appointed as a
head of security of some product maybe
that's in the game for you maybe you
have in the past or maybe you are one
right now then I guess it will be easy
for you but anyway you are responsible
for security of the product so what
would you do because I don't think I
need to tell anyone here that securing
things is not super easy so what would
be your first steps what would be your
first activities and I leave you with
with this question for a little bit
because probably I need to introduce
myself
so I will be talking about Freud
modeling and how we did it in my company
and we kind of scale it up with cards
actually and I think you understand what
I mean later on my name is Matteo I'm
from Poland and I've been working 19 for
about 11 years started a software
developer and around 5 years ago I
started drifting into application
security and now I'm working as an
application security engineer at Okada
technology you might have heard of a
kind of technology because we do have an
office and engineering office here in
Barcelona I mostly deal with Java web
technologies because that's most of most
of our products are written like that
but sometimes a little bit of more
unusual things I guess and from my
experience you don't really know what
application security engineer
because it's it means something
different in every company so my job in
Aikido is to help our developers to
produce secure code and I'll come back
to this later on and actually I decided
to create this dog with motivation that
can be summed up with a I quote to
somehow famous quote that in theory
there's no difference between theory and
practice but it's practice there is and
the problem was that we started doing
threat models in Aikido and it turned
out that the reason a lot of like
practical approaches me I mean there
wasn't a lot of materials to go on to
start and we've been doing quite a lot
of trials and errors and I kind of
thought that it would be nice to have
more information on how to do this in
real life if you are working in real
company so yeah that's why I'm here
and like a little thing I also wanted to
mention so yeah embrace your new penis
I guess because I do not consider myself
to be some super expert on threat
modeling this is not how you should do
this this is how we did it and yeah I'm
very open to discussions probably not
right now because that will be hard but
afterwards I'll be very happy to discuss
if you think that our ideas are good or
not
yeah just I'll be super happy to learn
from your experience experiences as well
right so short agenda is first of all
I'll try to explain more or less why we
think threat modeling is important and
why if you do this then there will be
I'll describe our process and finally
some lessons we have learned so going
back to the question from the beginning
you are this head of security and the
problem in my opinion that's obviously
only one problem but the problem is that
there is so many fun stuff you can do so
maybe you are super fond about bug
bounties and you want to roll and start
the program but like in the middle of it
you think but kind of we kind of suck at
deaf Cyclops and maybe we need some
tools to be integrated into pipelines
but you haven't even finished and your
lies that actually we are not training
developers so they don't actually know
how to write security code and so on and
so on the problem is if you are working
like this then you are not very much
different than Kevin here running around
trying to fix everything at once and I
don't think that's super optimal way of
introducing security so I'm not saying
that any of those activities I mentioned
before our bat are great but I would
suggest that you probably should start
with doing a threat model and this is so
you know so you have some kind of a
methodical approach to introducing
security and I kind of have this like in
my head I'm trying to I have this
visualization don't be a running
headless chicken or from the last reef
because and this is like pretty
important information do not Google
image search for headless chickens I
wanted to have some kind of a nice
cartoon picture in here but the results
are very disturbing and scene so I used
Kevin back then and I recommend you to
do not this is kind of still kind of the
way I am thinking about this to apply
some kind of you know order into your
to your initiatives and if you do that
then you'll be able to answer three
questions which in my opinion are very
important first of them being why do you
actually want to be secure and if you
think this is strange I'm an application
security engineer and I'm asking this
question I mean they are paying me to
make everything secure so why would they
ask this question well I think this is a
very important question
because I would say that you don't want
to be a zealot Security's a lot if you
want to kind of have like nice
relationship with everyone around you in
the company don't do this you shouldn't
be like that
security is important because it's
important because it's a security that's
unfortunately arguments a lot of people
are making in our community I am afraid
and I'd argue that that's not an ideal
way and why is that
that's because while security is
important and I do know that I don't
think it is the most important thing so
if you have a product then the point of
this product is to work to have
functionalities so one of my like funny
stories from the university time was
when we had this Java programming
classes and a friend of mine started you
know typing class blah blah and public
static void main I then sat down like
thinking what to write down right right
next right and the teacher was coming
behind his back he looked at his screen
and he said well congratulations you
have zero bucks which is true but at the
same time that wasn't really an
interesting program it didn't do
anything so it's full abilities just
don't write anything right but that's
not the point you've probably heard the
joke about the only secure server is the
one that this is very deep on the seabed
well this is generally funny but again
this is not true even from the security
point of view because if you go back to
the basic what are the properties of
secure systems there's confidentiality
obviously there's integrity yes but
there's also availability and guess
which one of those server on the seabed
is not having what what property is it
not having and product are for users
they need to function if you focus too
much on the security and forget about
users and by the way about developers
who need to deliver this product then
actually you might hurt security in the
end because we all heard about like
workarounds like of anything like the
famous post-it notes with passwords on
the on the screens
just because you are requiring to change
passwords every every 10 days or so
anyway let's say that you know why you
want to be secure but the next question
is what security actually means what is
secure system which is kind of
philosophical I know but I will show you
two secure systems in next slides these
are real life system they are secured
obviously because the locks and nobody
says security more than locks right so
this is the first one there's the door
gate there's a lock and this is a secure
system apparently because you can do
this which is funny so I kind of Google
another example of this so again you
have lock on the door and it works right
so the point is there's not a simple
definition of security and if you forget
about this you can do stupid stuff which
will give you no security in the end but
will make you spend a lot of time
working
I guess I mean you need to think about
your context about data you're storing
about your business model for example a
lot of security people in my opinion
focus too much on confidentiality of
stuff and again I'd argue that for a lot
of companies are very with availability
is even more important I know that for
my company this is the most important
thing that we need to be available this
is ecommerce if you're not available if
people are not able to purchase think on
your website then you are losing a lot
of money all right
and by the way yeah so the examples with
the locks were kind of obvious right
very funny ins and so on but it's much
easier to missed similar things with
software because with locks everyone
kind of gets it even if you are not a
trained security expert with software is
it's much harder to spot some problems
well finally you do know why you want to
be secure you do know what things will
make you secure with all your product
secure well that's easy now right just
do the thing but have you talked to your
product owners recently because their
backlogs are pretty full I I think can
you have you talked to your developers
from your company because I'm yet to
find the team in no kado that will say
that yeah actually we have nothing to do
for next six months let's work on this
security thing and the point is that
there is a lot of work on development
teams and you can't do everything at
once and you can spend like six years or
even months working just on security
because again the security is not the
most important thing you
to be delivering a business value at the
same time and because because of all of
that you need to prioritize your work
you need to work on each on problems on
or actually solutions that will give you
the most bang for your box right with
low effort a lot of security at yeah
this all sounds pretty reasonable I
guess but unfortunately again even
though we knew that threat modeling is
important we had some problems with
running these initiatives initiative but
and I think the important context for
this is in the kado up Abzug engineers
and any other security engineers are not
responsible for security of a product in
okada
the whole responsibility of everything
product related is on teams so it's
going to be teams that will be working
on fret modeling in the end so yeah that
that was kind of a point we were
starting with and because of that our
approach had to be at least somehow fun
engaging I mean if people are bored then
they will try to find every excuse they
can to not do this again right so yeah
also simple because they can't like the
development teams can't spend next month
or just like researching threat model
options and learning maybe some tools
used for threat modeling and so on we
kind of wanted to have a simples rules
as possible use white boards and Google
sheets not anything more complicated for
this and yeah that's it
and finally
at least our developers want to have
some sense of accomplishment so if I
make them sit for a prolonged amount of
time and in the end they feel that you
wasted this time again they won't they
won't don't want they will not want to
repeat the process again and that's why
we've chosen to go with so called by us
cornucopia approach actually there are
two card games out there one is
elevation of privilege by Microsoft the
other one is called copier by hours I'm
using current copier in this
presentation but we actually in Okada
used both of them they are very similar
and it doesn't really matter which one
which one you choose they are both very
good so probably you you can try both of
them and these are like cards
you can play a game with those cards and
actually we are starting with even more
fun which is drawing this is our step 0
it's not like the most important part
but we do want to draw a system diagram
it's again not required but it helps you
to reason about the security of a system
in the future so then you get this card
cards you kind of played them and in
effect you are collecting threats you
are obtaining a list of threats which
are applicable to the system but that's
only half of the job because then you
need to assess those threats and that
means first of all quantify the risk
associated to the frets so what's the
impact was the likelihood how serious is
this problem this is very important from
the prioritization point of view because
you need to have this in order to
prioritize also assess if you are
vulnerable because Fred
can be also matteri already materialized
as vulnerabilities in your system but at
the same time maybe it didn't happen yet
the so the thread haven't yet
materialized but you want to be prepared
in case it does in the first case you
want to probably fix the vulnerability
in the latter case you will want to
introduce some difference in depth
controls to make sure that even if some
foreigner to be vulnerability will occur
in a later on or maybe even if you are
attacked then you will be able to defend
yourself and then and this is pretty
important as well you need to agree on
actions so first of all can we accept
the risk associated with this threat
because not everything needs to be fixed
and definitely not everything needs to
be fixed right now so maybe we can
accept the risk like for a year or
something and companies do this all the
time this is kind of underlying the
foundation of businesses to take some
risks and it depends how much risk are
you willing to take but yeah sometimes
it's it's and it's a good thing to do
but even threat is pretty serious
then how much work are you willing to do
in order to fix this because maybe
there's some quick fix maybe you will
need to spend a lot of man days
preparing a fix and maybe you don't have
time for this right now well it depends
on the project but you need to actually
commit to do something and finally this
is not a part of fret modeling but I
thought it's pretty important include
this here as well so threat modeling
will be pointless unless you act in the
end so if you've committed to some
actions then do
this and introduce those fixes put put
some mitigations and things like this
right and I'll try to show you how fat
modeling mol/s could look like so
we'll be picking a card I mean cards are
already picked I was cheating I know
then I'll try to come up with some
threads applicable to tool the
application will be reasoning about we
are not going to do risk calculation
because it's kind of out of scope and
possibly we will propose some
mitigations and and repeat we have like
four cards I think but first as I told
you you need to draw so I drew a little
diagram this is some system let's see
some ecommerce system because you have
customer and he wants to put down some
orders in your e-commerce website there
is a retailer who wants to fulfill some
orders and there's also an admin of abdi
cloud because everything is in the cloud
because it's 2019 I guess so yeah
nothing really too complicated and see
yeah let's let's say we're doing threat
modeling applying the first card so this
is authentication 4 4 is the rank of the
card authentication is the suit and
Sebastian can easily identify user names
or can enumerate them so obviously I
will be simplifying things a lot and I
won't be going very much in depth but
you are talking with your development
team so it's disposable and you are kind
of presenting the idea of user
enumeration of vulnerability when you
know there's a different response when
you use wrong username or password
drink login and they are saying they'll
actually know about this and know the
error response is the same so we are
alright how about the password reset
this desire action actual conversation I
had and they are saying that yeah we
thought about this too so there's the
same message if you do a password we
said no matter if the account is present
or not but I'm digging deeper alright so
what about registration and it's like oh
and yeah it turns out that you can do a
user enumeration during registration as
well so we would put down a threat fred
is account can be enumerated using
registration functionality and then we
need to come up with solutions with
mitigations so one possible mitigation
would be obviously to return the same
same message no matter if the user
exists or not so yeah that could work
but the same time we're talking to
business and because of reasons business
doesn't like it so we need to accept
this risk in the end so all right this
is not bad I mean user enumeration is
not a huge issue so I think it's worth
accepting it this isn't an AI ideal
solution for me as a security guy but I
can live with this so let's play another
card and it's session management Jack
and Jeff can resend an identical repeat
interaction for example HTTP request and
it's accepted not rejected so let's
focus on those HTTP requests so we are
talking about reply attacks right and I
informed developers that when we are
talking about HTTP then as long as
you're using HTTP reply attacks are not
possible but if we're using a plain HTTP
then there is a possibility of reply
attacks
and guess what the green lines on the
diagram are actually HTTPS and the red
ones are HTTP so obviously we already
see that there are some places in our
system that could be vulnerable to this
and well the solution is simple let's
just introduce HTTPS but and this is
pretty important what are the dotted
lines on the diagram these are so-called
trust bond boundaries so the transit
when you are inside trust boundary you
are trusting everything that's also
within the same class boundary right so
for example we have HTTP connection
between our fronts and micro services
and our back-end micro service well this
isn't ideal but since we are inside our
trust boundary we decide that we don't
want to introduce extra overhead of TLS
and we decide to accept this risk in
this case on the other hand there is the
HTTP connection between admin and
database and that's actually not ideal
because admin is connecting from outside
the cloud so probably from stuff from
someplace like on the Internet
so in this case the threat is much
bigger and probably will want to
introduce HTTPS in this place so let's
say the dev team development team
commits to fix this in a week because
it's pretty serious at the same time we
have back-end microservices talking via
HTTP and crossing fast boundaries with
database so again this is not ideal this
these are these components are not
within the same trust boundaries but
because it's in the cloud then the
agreement is that we will fix that but
not right now we will introduce defects
in like two months or so so next one
cryptography eight-teen can access
stored business data for example
passwords because it is not securely and
or securely hushed yeah we read out loud
this card and developers are happy to
infer me that they are using
state-of-the-art joffrey function which
is obviously better than chateau so yeah
I now need to explain to them that
unfortunately even though Jeffrey is
like one version has this version number
bigger this is not how you should store
passwords and I explained the concept of
slow hashing why this is important I
explained the concept of offline
cracking and we agree that this needs to
be changed we don't want to accept this
risk but the problem is this is a lot of
work and we know because we've got we
didn't use a three we used back with
back rate which is like a nice function
but we kind of felt that we want to bump
up the hardness factor and we wanted to
migrate all the data into the like I
knew like the same algorithm but new
hardness factor and so on so we know
this is a lot of work and because of
that we can do this like overnight and
we need to be very careful because it's
password if we screw something up in the
process then we'll block everyone from
accessing our web page which is far
worse than having those sorry into that
database so we decide we'll fix this
within a year during a slow process with
multiple checks iterations and so on and
the last one I actually love this card
because it's almost always a sure thing
to have someone Suzanne frets to be
listed so Pierre can still convent the
applications controls because code
frameworks libraries and components
contain malicious code or
vulnerabilities so yeah if you ask your
developers what version of off struts
are you using over spring
they usually don't really know I mean
they might know the major evolution but
not the minor in most cases so usually
this is a problem but what are the
solutions so they could like daily check
for new versions of everything in their
dependency free tree which is obviously
kind of stupid because it's a very very
tedious work or they could like at like
some kind of automated tool to the to
the pipeline which stands for vulnerable
vulnerable components and there are such
tools and yeah well we are using some in
Okada because they're very interesting
but not yet in all projects so the idea
is that after fret model link there is a
single task created that one of the
developers will check like the most
important components but within a month
or so we want to introduce this
automated tool as well but again this is
the last card I'm not not going very
much in depth in most cases there is
more than one thread applicable to a
card
so for example in this case you could
also talk about third-party JavaScript
used in your webpage right because it's
a malicious code in third-party
component and obviously the fix will be
very much different because you'll
probably want to use some something like
sub resource integrity or perhaps
content security policy both of this can
help you with this the point is the this
is another threat even though I
applicable to the same card and you also
need to take care of this so the games
goes on and on and this is kind of how
we do this and what did we learn in the
process of the
this this is probably kind of
interesting so the first thing is that
we really do like threat models and I'm
not gonna say there are perfect and
definitely the execution is not perfect
but it gives you a lot of a lot of
benefits and like the most obvious
benefits proven benefit is the reason
why you are doing threat models but we
have found out that there there are
another like bonus wins made possible by
threat models so first of all
documentation and system diagram if you
have no documentation it's already a
good start and consciously I would argue
that every good documentation should
have read model included iMovie as like
the world are not Yeti for this to have
this required yet but I think that
eventually that should be a case and
education so mmm you might you might be
running some programs on how to train
people so they know what the
vulnerabilities look like how to write
secure code and so on but you know the
training is like one two three days then
they forget everything or not everything
but at least some parts and this gives
you an opportunity to kind of reiterate
also on some problem so I regularly am
forced to explain some vulnerability
some problems on those cards and after
this obviously after threat modeling the
side effect is that the dev teams is
also a little bit smarter because they
kind of learn a new vulnerability or a
new kind of attack things like this and
it really helps if you are using example
from all threat models in your
new faith models because you can say
that yeah you actually do want to fix
that because like team a and B also had
this problem and it was nasty so you
probably should fix that or if this is a
plant feature you probably should not do
this this way and so on and so on it's
much better to give examples from inside
your company if the guys know that their
friends made this mistake it's much
easier for them to kind of accept that
this is this really a problem and
visibility so I as a knapsack struggle
all the time to get the visibility in
the company my role I wouldn't be
possible if I if people wouldn't knew
that I exist so I kind of need to go all
the time and remind people that I exist
I am absolutely engineer here hi and I'm
here to help if they don't know that I
am there they will not come to me with
the problems they may have so fret
models are a nice moment where you kind
of present yourself yeah also present
yourself of specialists so during the
process they kind of see that I know
what I'm doing and possibly they will
trust me a little bit more but also
because of the way how we do threat
models because of the approach with
which is not like you need to fix
everything now but because of like a
more realistic approach they also are
kind of inclined to share the dirty
secrets for example and to work with me
not against me right and by the way I
said about showing dirty secret
the visibility's ability works also in
another direction so if it wasn't for
fit models I wouldn't know about half
the problems we had in company because
you know there's this service
everyone except two guys forgot about it
it's been running forever
it's not listed anywhere if it wasn't
from Fred model and like the quick Oh
actually I remember that we have this
service nobody really cares about
anymore but it's still running like
these are very desire mmm how
conversations sometimes look like and
because of that I can do like oh wow so
that could be a problem can I can and
gathering like knowing all the assets in
the company is obviously very important
it's not a wafer modeling is not a way
to gather all the assets but it will
help you to get some visibility of over
what you have in a company back hunting
it's not the problem like the common
misconception is that during that model
you are kind of trying to identify
vulnerabilities you don't you are
looking for a threat for threats but in
the process you might imeem regularly I
get these red lights in my head turning
on because yeah that doesn't really look
great what you are describing to me and
then after that modeling I'll ask for an
access to the application I'll do a
little bit of a hog pen testing I guess
or of wannabe hunting and usually I'm
able to find something interesting
which I can show a show to the team that
yeah I was right the this isn't the best
way to approach this again not the point
but also happen mmm more than once
and current copia and elevation of
privilege give give you also a little
bit agility which is pretty important
which will be pretty important in a
minute
so you have those cards but we actually
stopped playing cards like we are not
playing like having a game we are just
using cards because they are very good
like the friends described there are
very interesting and are a great
starting point but at the same time it
turns out that like teaching people how
this game wars what are the rules and so
on was they were just wasting time so
the feedback I continuously got was that
it's not worth the effort and who are
still using the cards but not playing a
game also because these are cards then
the cards are very agile right there is
a lot of cards in agile and you can for
example choose to play a card every week
or every sprint or every stand up maybe
and over time you'll play through a
whole deck right so this is nice because
that will be when you will finish read
model yeah but as I said no everything
is perfect so there are three biggest
problem I see with Fred modeling in
general and especially I mean not
especially but in particular with
cornucopia and elevation of privilege so
first of them is time Fred modelling
takes a lot of time and actually that's
kind of the outcome of very cool thing
so every time I start Fred modeling
there is a lot of discussions being
started so there's this card and there
is this thread described so are we
vulnerable no I don't think we are but
you forgot about this service yeah but
we have some mitigations in place so
maybe this one and it goes on and on and
on and that's kind of the point so you
can't really like it because you would
be missing all the important bits but at
the same time playing even one card
takes a significant amount of time so
yeah I still think this time is valuable
so you kind of need to live with this as
I said this a giant approach could be
something that will help so we are never
playing like all the cards on the one
sitting because it would take hours and
I'm talking like not two hours but more
like 20 hours probably and obviously you
can't host
sessions which are that long
because and this is another problem
these sessions are pretty tiring like
you wouldn't believe that I I think but
trying to come up with new threads all
all like constantly is is tiring like
really you are feeling tired exhausted
actually after an hour or two so first
of all again don't overdo this we
usually host sessions which are like
maximum two hours long and we are trying
to cut them even shorter we prefer to
have more shorter questions than one
long one for example to have one day
dedicated to fret modeling I am NOT
saying this wouldn't work at all but but
yeah it's probably better than to like
kind of split this also like you know if
you are kind of a company that can get
cookies into the room or pizza or house
with modeling in the evening and even
maybe some beer then that also helps to
kind of refresh the group but don't
overdo this actually we overdid it a
little bit and like not with the beer
fortunately but the point is you need to
be focused and like pizza can distract
people a lot for example and this is
this is stupid this is really simple but
I had this problem so many times that I
need to kind of stretch this out make
sure there is a fresh air in the room
because if there's not then after 30
minutes people will get sleepy they want
what he will be engaging in the
conversation as much and yeah that's not
so great and finally as I started this
presentation I told you that the kind of
a problem was that even for me and I was
supposed to be in like space
security specialist even for me
getting all the information on how to do
fret modeling how this could work in a
company and so on was pretty it was
pretty complicated I'm not gonna lie and
if we are talking about developers who
are not skilled security experts then
it's even worse for them and I
unfortunately don't consider those
projects to be so simple that you can
just tell your developers well do a
threat modeling use cornucopia you'll be
good
unfortunately that's not how it works we
are hosting a lot of demo sessions and
during these demo sessions we are going
through the whole process but I am
present in the group and I'm helping
them I'm explaining how how this works
and so on and so on and we are doing a
lot of those like eventually the Pala
there needs to be some point where I'm
almost non-existent on during those
sessions I only get results or something
but right now we are not there yet and
yeah this summer aigis do I recommend
doing Fred model Inc yes definitely I
still think this is one of the most
important things you can do to make sure
your product is secure it doesn't give
you like immediate security but it can
help you to plan everything further on
and the processes we have are not
perfect yet even Cornucopia even have
the elevation of privilege aren't
perfect but it's still better to do
something then do nothing right so don't
try to be perfect and just start doing
fred models and you will see if we if it
works for you or not and
I guess that's it I'm happy to answer
simple questions if there are hard ones
I like that we don't have time for this
so don't worry yeah but I I think like
the point of this talk was to kind of
make you think about this and I really
don't expect that many questions but
maybe more conversations later on and
I'm very open to this I I don't even
have time for conversations right now so
yeah questions are welcome anyway I
[Music]
[Applause]
imagine before you started this as you
said the team's agendas were already
filled how did you persuade people to
take part in these sessions I don't
think there's a simple answer for that I
think it needs to be clear in an
organization that you care about
security so there needs to be like
something like do you remember like Bill
Gates trustworthy computing memo that
went around Microsoft so that was a good
example of management very much
supporting the idea that we want to
produce secured software and I think
that needs to be clear and then I
actually think that I was pretty helpful
like I was pretty effective with this
because I had good relationship with
with with my friends my colleagues and I
I didn't talk about this but we strongly
believe in security engineers being a
neighbors
not blockers in our company so everyone
knew that I'm not trying to kind of did
this way this won't be like another time
there is this security guy who is saying
no no no no no but it will be a
conversation and we will and we'll have
outcomes that will be interesting for
everyone this is probably uh the you can
do to make sure that it works and
finally I was from the beginning very
open about the process about the
reasoning so like the whole process
starts with like simple 15-20 minutes
presentation I'm giving to the team
explaining why we consider first
modeling to be very important and
describing how we will do this later on
and again I don't think there's a simple
answer to this question but I think
those three things are helping a lot
hello just one question for curiosity so
applications and systems continuously
evolve right so how do you interact on
what Callens the set modeling exercises
on your applications and systems when
they change like I'm monthly quarterly
annual basis yeah that's actually the
the biggest struggle we have and to be
honest I don't really have answers yet I
mean we do recognize this as being an
issue I don't think I mean Fred modeling
takes a lot of time so you can't
especially if you are doing like
continue to deliver or something like
this
the you can't really fret model each
iteration but you need to repeat the
process every now and then I don't think
it needs to be repeated very often but
it needs to be repeated like every half
a year or year and and this is this is
how we are trying to solve this but well
till now to be honest it doesn't work
that well we are playing with the idea
which I kind of hinted during the
presentation to do this in a continuous
way meaning instead of doing thread
model ink now and then next one in
in a year let's like play one card every
week or so and you are doing this like
constantly they're like I don't remember
it's like time 13 I think
cards in cornucopia so it will take
probably a half or so
to go through all of them but then you
start from the beginning and we are
constantly evaluating this isn't this
isn't perfect
I know but again this is a huge effort
and we can justify taking a week work
like taking a whole week of work for a
dev team every month or so so yeah first
of all thank you for making it
understandable also for people who don't
belong to the security in this industry
like me for example I come from software
testing which means unconcerned it also
about security of course but I'm not an
expert and I like the approach because
as far as I understand if even though
you can end up accepting specific risk
you perform risk analysis and risk
management before in any case and and I
like it because I've been noticing a
worrying trend recently some project
management managers tend to not to do
risk analysis at all risk management
they just assume risk I don't know if
it's because they are not skillet
things or just because they know it
takes some effort as you said so my
question is have you been noticing this
issue as well and if so how did you deal
with it well to be honest like the risk
analysis from the business point of view
is a much wider topic than that just IT
security and I obviously focus on the on
IT security and even though not like
whole IT security because I mostly take
care of application security so I
haven't noticed this trend in our
company at least but I'm not sure if I
would because I kind of see a small
picture
I think threat models are great to
deliver to your management later on so
they can use this in the risk analysis
but our my point of focus is kind of now
narrow you know like it doesn't so we
are not considering things like you know
like robberies or or fires or floats or
some things like this which actually
should be taken into account in in a
company probably I mean like at least a
company like academ so I think and by
the way I hope I mean I'm trying to fix
this but I tend to say developers and
this is actually pretty bad because I
always mean development teams with a
Latino kado consists of many people so
for example we are engaging POS inferred
models we are definitely engaging
software engineering tests and actually
we had even user experience guys joining
us and everyone who feels that his time
won't be wasted during this is welcome
to come and I'm usually trying
make ourselves open as possible this is
this shouldn't be focused on developers
only so I probably said developers along
along my talk more than once and what I
meant was like development team like
actually just the team responsible for a
product so one of the things that you
mentioned was the threat modeling gives
you visibility of the issues which kinda
makes me think like you do on for
example services that already running in
there so I mean my question would be
have you also don't threat modeling
alone services that just on inception
like on the mindset of someone before
doing so and if you see in kind of
measurements in stemple instead of if I
don't threat modeling when I was
designing my service
I also reduced potential risk instead of
just you know doing when something is
already there I kind of have in like the
visibility of the fest are already there
yeah that's a very good point and
actually during my presentation to the
teams I'm explaining that threat
modeling is actually even better if you
are doing this from the beginning
because it's possible that you will
avoid a lot of design flaws because you
know vulnerabilities you fix them you
forget about them that's cool but design
flaws oh that's that that's nasty and
the problem is that unfortunately no
hado most of the stuff we already have
there is not that much I mean there is a
lot of new projects but unfortunately
threat models we were running were
mostly about projects which are already
created but if you have a chance to do a
threat model before development starts
in the like early design phase that's
even better because you can from the
beginning indeed mitigate a lot of risks
and just make sure this won't happen so
yeah mmm
I guess the simple answer is this is a
great idea we would
like to have this this way but
unfortunately in real life we didn't had
a lot of chances to to fret model new
systems okay thank you
[Applause]