today you want to talk to you about a
piece of malware called for MOOC which
well we will try to showcase a good
example that what we believe is
cybercrime and the cybercrime industry
and how it works and what it does and
how it does what it does okay so first
we will introduce ourselves
then because I don't know exactly what
background each of you has we want to
introduce just a tiny bit how cybercrime
is right now at this point any time at
this point in time
then we'll be loath of you the malware
sample the distribution of the malware
sample the panel how it works the tweets
it has that kind of stuff and afterwards
we will just talk about the threat actor
behind this behind this malware the
developer who made the malware and his
history with with it okay so let's start
I'm big telecine I am lab stimulated
blue live my job mainly entails threat
analyst with a bit of reverse
engineering on the side I know I wish as
well that this was like the other way
around but it is what it is if you have
any doubts about hope you have any
questions that we can answer right now
you can just send an email okay hi I'm
more ha I'm working him to live for four
years the last two laps team member and
I work in I'm working doing threat
analysis and protector tracking and all
their things
okay so let's cut to the chase
interesting part that's that's better
right
hello yeah okay so cyber crime is a
living entity it adapts the
countermeasures and it evolves with time
what does this mean that means that when
we try to look at that in at an event
that happened related to cyber crime we
also need a context and that context is
usually like time and the technology
available world events that kind of
stuff okay which is what we will try to
do right now
[Music]
what Wow
okay so what you cannot see here
is is a picture representing the current
the state of cybercrime right now a
cybercrime can be seen as a sort of
industry in which you have like you have
your providers you have people creating
services you have channels to exchange
information you have channels to sell
information and you have clients from
organizations well organized groups you
have a script kiddies you have almost
everything in here people that code for
money people that just his only job is
focused purely on distribution of
malware others that the only thing they
do is just trying to gather information
as well and sell it related to
distribution campaigns and then you have
researchers meddling in the middle which
sometimes you find as well in this case
because we're dealing with a malware
related cybercrime operation I wanted to
introduce you to the concept of the kill
chain the kill chain is just like this
this these steps which describe what the
threat actor or what the threat actors
have to do from the moment they decide
they want to infect someone or some
group of people to the moment in which
they manage to steal their data the
first step which would be reconnaissance
is just an attempt to gather information
let's say you want for example to attack
a company a known company so what you
want to do is you want to find out how
do they configure the users how their
emails work
what kind of signatures they have do
they have a firewall do they have a wife
that kind of stuff you know something
anything that can stop you when you try
to attack them in this case for example
if you wanted to attack United Kingdom
people just in general you know like
targeting civilians you would need to
acquire lists of emails that you know
belong there because that way you can
make very focused campaigns the next
step with this weaponization would be to
look for that exploit that exploit kit
that vulnerability or just a word macro
that you can use in order to infect
those people
Laer which is a next step these four
steps can be almost what these three
steps can almost always go together so
in an email for example an email
campaign you would have an email with an
attachment
and that email has a Content that email
is sent to someone in particular so the
email might be the Lord like hey have
you sets have you seen these photos in
here that I'm sending you the the
weaponization might be the exploit
that's inside those photos and the
redirection of exploitation would be
when you managed to get the user to open
that that file once the user has opened
that file the infection phase begins
this is when the malware sets up his his
house and he gains persistence and he
decides that he is going to live in that
computer because it's of interest to him
so we are assuming that it's a it's able
to tell one real user from a VM from a
sandbox from a researcher sandbox you
know that kind of stuff after verifying
all of that information it will contact
its command and control server which is
the server that the threat actor that
actor the group will use in order to
like manipulate the sample and then it
will begin stealing data so for farm
work oh yeah sorry I forgot about this
in here I'm just showing some examples
of forums mostly frequent by script
kiddies and that kind of stuff that kind
of low-level profile in which they are
already like offering in here in these
last entries as Windows installation
uniqueness this is a guy offering a
service he has already about not
deployed with I'm just making this up
because I can't I can't remember the
exact number but 1000 watts and he says
look I have a 1000 computers I am
renting them to you you can infect those
computers if you want and you skip the
for the first four steps of the Quixote
and he's just offering that service in
here you can see people offering
tutorials how to create an exploit back
newbie for newbies and kind of stuff
here tutorial for you is how to set up
an easy to be botnet panel so they are
trying to transfer knowledge they are
trying to teach teacher cybercrime
cybercrime people who will want to
commit felonies as well and that's just
another example as well okay now about
forum work what is form work form work
is known for being one of the best
information still malware out there
it has support for more than 80
applications for how will it tell you
about that afterwards it's the
techniques it uses are known as form
grabbing and keylogging I am sure most
of you know what keylogging is but form
grabbing it's not such it's not so known
as keylogging from grabbing is basically
a technique which works through the
infecting a known process for example
the chrome process and then hooking the
calls it makes to make the requests to
your to the server his contacting that
way he can examine the buffer that you
can have in that request and is still
information from there it also it's also
credential stealer we call credential
stealers every malware that has the
capability of going to the Chrome
Firefox or Internet Explorer vault and
the vault is where they store the
credentials you know that message that
pops up hey do you want to stop your
credential so this very critical service
yes okay well when you get infected the
marvel will go to that database and
still of your stuff and then another
characteristic that I find this very
interesting besides being sold on
underground forums instead of markets or
from peer to peer which also happens is
that for book offers a subscription plan
you can basically pay like $30 a month
and you get your domain and you get your
host and you get your sample and you
only have to distribute it and
everything else is set up for you so in
order to understand how form work works
and how the people around it are using
it we need to analyze every piece of
knowledge that we get and from a
research point of view the pieces of
knowledge we get our command and control
servers we get samples we get emails
used by the for the distribution we get
everything we can communications keys
they use all of that it is what we call
indicators of compromise or indicator of
actor and this stuff can identify a
single actor among a group for example
or a targeted attack just based on that
information and each what we will try to
showcase today okay now we're going to
continue with the distribution and the
campaign's we have detected for this
presentation why
we were investigating for look we found
some campaigns that where a distribution
of for book through email campaigns this
emails have attached it an RTF document
the most affected countries where United
Kingdom United States Canada suit Korea
and France this was executed in the last
quarter of 2019 and these documents take
profit about two to exploits and a
Microsoft Office and Microsoft Windows
common controls activist code execute
your narrative I know that the name is
like very long but I'm sure you have do
you remember if I'm not mistaken do you
remember like a news piece that said hey
be careful because we found the
vulnerability that exploits the equation
the equation yeah for malaria for for
talks well that's that's the thing that
they're using yeah both of them are
affecting the Microsoft Office where the
two are buffer overflow guna now it is
to why were investigating this we found
that they are using common subjects all
of them are talking about the products
order that we found that there are a
different subjects the quotation and
inquiry that we found six different and
documents we can see some of the
subjects they were using and we found
four different campaigns using different
emails we can see here that they bought
some some domain and here they were
using free domain and using Gmail maybe
from my cones that were still in here we
can see it two of the two samples of the
emails use it and you can see that the
both of yous
targeting some corporations and they
want to to infect this kind of people
yep basically the content of the email
plus the subjects we've seen before they
make reference to corporate contexts
which is why we assume that they are
targeting companies and not particular
people yes Oh individuals then now
Victor will talk about yeah about the
thingy the reverse engineering thingy
yeah okay so first thing and that's
something that I find very interesting
form would be sold and backed that's not
usually happens usually when you buy
when you buy buy where you find malware
the malware usually comes with a builder
and the Builder is has some sort of fu D
which is fully undetectable Packer which
gives gives you a final payload that
allows you to just distribute it
immediately that way when you sell your
stuff to script kiddies they won't
up okay and send something that's just
the raw malware this works in our favor
and against us in this case I found I
found four book with visual basic script
Packers Knapp C++ Delphi Packers very
different stuff you know with very
different techniques and packing into a
new into a new process I'm packing in
the same layer and as I was saying this
has advantages and disadvantages mind
you these are switched around these are
advantages for them not for me okay so
one of the advantages is that it's hard
to unpack automatically
I like when I'm investigating a new
sample or what I'm trying to follow a
campaign one thing that I try to do is
to make a script that we low to medium
packing so that I can more easily
identify changes and that kind of stuff
well this is hard with for mob basically
because each Packer use its own
technique and recognizing them it's more
difficult on the other hand as a
disadvantage for them you can find
samples that are not packed
making the first step of reckoning stuff
of trying to understand the malware and
find samples for that malware a bit
easier another thing that I found that
was very interesting as well is that
firm work has a ton of anti features
anti features at all of those features
that what they work for is to hinder the
researcher the researcher Alice's of the
sample and these are just like untidy
buggers and the sandbox VM and she
analyses all of that stuff I wanted to
make a special mention and I will ask
anyone who speaks French in the room to
please forgive me for making your ears
bleed I wanted to thank give me Julian I
know that I didn't pronounce that very
well from storm shield who published
like a very very very very very detailed
blog post related to these phantom
measures okay so let's just have a quick
overview of these measures for anti
sandbox and on TBN techniques
it has like dynamic function calling it
has it load it loads its own copy of
ntdll
so that it erases any hooks you may have
in that it checks for running processes
that are known to be used by researchers
it checks the loaded dll's sandbox paths
user names and there are a few more that
haven't been listed I wanted to speak
about just to add a bit of my thing here
just a couple of screenshots about the
dynamic function calling as we will see
later on form work
tries to have like the least amount of
information available on the go for
further research so everything is
encrypted in buffers and in this case it
has a buffer with the list of hashes and
these slices could respond to the crc32
of a function name okay so when it wants
to make a dynamic buna wants to call a
function in this case
anti system core information what it
will do it will resolve the address
first and afterwards in here I'm not
sure if you can see it there's a call ax
which will make the dynamic call okay so
how does it do that first it gets the
crc32 for that call and then it goes to
the header of ntdll in this case looks
to the export functions makes the crc32
of all of the functions until it finds a
match as you can see here in EAX
you have the same value here then you
have well not move but that's like a
Python command line and you can in here
down here you can see that there is the
same number and
then up there and that's the crc32
forensic query system information after
doing that it will just perform the call
as you can see in the X you have the
beginning of the function okay it also I
also wanted to mention I don't know if
there's a lot of malware savvy
researchers here but when malware wants
to iterate around the different
processes that are running in the system
what you usually see is is them making
use of a function called create help
snapshot 32 to something like that which
is things as an object of the processes
that are running okay in this case what
it does is use the function that I
mentioned previously and security system
information with the flag you can see
down there system process information
which will return the same structure or
one very similar to that of the other
column but this is like weig sneakier
when you are checking out the behavior
of the sample instead of seeing a call
that just tells you hey I'm looking at
all the at all the processes did you see
something waiting for information and
unless you know that oh five is the flag
that you need to get that information
you lost I just thought it was cool as
for other things it does it takes for a
for an T debugging as well and in this
case it's X for kernel debugging which
is not it's something unusual as well
using the same function I mentioned
before and then instead of going to like
every malware to the P to the P AV and
checking if it's being the work with my
being debugged it just checks if there's
a process above port open which is very
sneaky as well
and harder to bypass okay now to the
last encryption remember that I
mentioned some buffers well I hope that
the yes ASM would be better but it is
not so well it's fine I mean the only
thing it needs to do in order to decode
the information it has like two
different functions to decode different
types of buffers ones are encrypted
the others are encoded the rights that
are the developers that are encoded are
just he just applies like a series of
transforms that I don't think they are a
standard they just something he cooked
himself and the other one is encrypted
with 34 like almost everything else in
the sample
in this case what it does and that's the
interesting part is you see that
function here getting cryptid buffer the
only thing it does is called the next
instruction yeah
call sign dollar sign plus five will
call the pop AIX when you do the pop AIX
after the call has pushed at the top of
the stack the return address you put the
return address which is the beginning of
the function at the pad in EAX okay so
now you have these others in EAX
when it returns it will move it will add
two to a X so now it's pointing here and
it will get into the code block the code
block the only thing that will do is
check if that begins with the parameter
of the function as you can see in here
yes 55:8 be like here 55 and ap if it
begins with the point of the function it
knows that that after that call there is
an encrypted buffer it will add three
yeah and that gets you these others here
which is the beginning of the encryption
buffer
I just thought that was something cool
he does it's not nothing in here is new
I mean all of all of this is done by
other samples I just think that firm
work is very interesting because it kind
of gathers a lot of small things in
small techniques what you can see in
here any reverse engineer will tell you
that this looks like like a checking
function every time that that form book
detects every time that lunch is one of
those antics so the anti debug the
kernel debugging DMI being in exhibited
in a sandbox every time it does that it
will fill in a structure that it keeps
internally and this structure has got
just a bunch of flags and that's what
it's looking at here okay every one of
these conditions is it maybe in the back
no anybody in a sandbox not in a VM no
next next next next next when you have
reverse engineer some samples the first
thing you will try to do is say okay I'm
just a skipping all of this I don't care
what you think you with what you think
I'm what you kept I don't care what you
think you are I'm telling you what you
are and you are not in a sandbox so
continue your execution thing is every
time it fails one of these checks it
modifies the crc32 list so the next time
it attempts to resolve a function it
will get a null pointer it will call to
a null pointer and the sample will crash
so you have to actually manage to bypass
each of them one by one or else you
don't get the sample to get assuming it
passes all of those checks it injects a
payload in Dukes brother is a Nikoli as
well using lesser known methods and then
it's an exact secretarial from a list of
processes and then if that everything
that it made everything work correctly
it will tidy up the house it will gain
persistence so it can survive three
boots and then it will delete the
original sample so there's no choice
that it says it has been there and then
we'll start scaling it which is the
whole purpose of the marker how does it
do that besides checking out the D volts
which is something that's very common
already for week we'll hook different
api's some of them which are very common
like HTTP and request a or W and then we
just put a hook in there and get the
buffer you're trying to send a request
when examining the buffer even the
buffer it has some key words like login
username password it will keep that date
and send it to the command and control
server and now he has your data
the interesting part about this damn it
okay in there I'm sorry I just was using
like a white screen and everything
looked fine but in here it just
compressed of it sorry what it does in
here I don't know if you can well I
think the highlighted parts are clearly
enough so basically this is just a lamp
with volatility of a process being
hooked by my form book and what it has
done it has hook a module that it's from
from it's very targeted because it's
from the Mozilla the Mozilla framework
in CSS the DLL and this has a function
called peer write which is used to write
two buffers or sockets so that's what he
has put this very like very surgical
very surgical hook instead of hooking a
more common happy it's targeting Firefox
specifically I just thought that was
relevant as well
and now morph I will continue with an
explanation related to the panel and the
communications in the last month
for book was a wall bit a lot and you
now can find the version 4.2 but the
most common versions what we can find in
a while where the 3.8 and the 3.29 but
here we can see the version 3.1 that
it's it was fully set in a forum when
you look at in you can find the
dashboard in this you can see some
statistics about the exfiltrated data
here and well here you can see some of
the users where was their last login and
you can see the panel has a lot of the
languages with super to translate this
this panel you have a lot of the delayed
views about the the forums the
keystrokes or the the passwords that for
MOOC was stealing and you can see that
future of for MOOC that is pretty cool
because it's like file browsing in in
the computers that were infected by
phone book in this case in this case
this functionality in this version
wasn't finished but in in the newest
version Suites it's working and that you
have have you with the control panel of
the users every customer have a panel
individual panel that it's identified
with this part of the path this is the
account name of the author panel every
customer have one but every panel can
have multiple users let's talk about the
encryption and the communication with
the C to the face step 2 to the
communication is to get a key the key is
unique reddit account nickname to do
this for book takes the domain and the
and the account name and do a heist that
has huge result this is not the finality
because for book do especially it's not
a special operations he change the
Indian s of the of the files to get the
little endian version of the heist and
then we have the key and we can include
the communication using our c4 then the
phases of the sample 2 step itself in
the panel to do this must send a special
packet that starts with a magic
identified by fvn team followed by a
crc32 the version of the panel the
operating system name and you said
encoded in base64 all this information
is encrypted in in FC 4 and is included
in random parameter that later will be
used you can see here in green some
information and parameter that are fake
parameters to try to disguise the other
parameters and the important things to
exfiltrate information the first of all
take the information and identifies
every packet with this s where they say
the solar that are affected and they
kind of or the type of the information
that he is filtrating with all this
information the sample encrypt it and
put it inside that parameter followed by
another time they use it in base64
and this parameter that it's important
because that identifies the type of the
information that it's filtrating all
this information is another time
encrypted in FC 4 and put it inside the
previous parameter that we
since then in oh this is the panel
okay you can't see here a function that
is collet and this device the type of
that exfiltrated here
you can see that the beard parameter
when is nine he is calling a function
that is collet not locked is that it's
used to exfiltrate the keystrokes the
recovery data the passwords and all this
kind of information every packet that
it's C to recollects to information like
the IP idea of the boat another kind of
information that it's important for the
world and now we will talk about the
definite actor and how they were
evolving and in the last year's the main
actor and the parameter of the four book
is in decoded that starts his activity
in hoc forums and it's an underground
forum and it starts taking part in
programming threats that are talking
about assembly C and C++ and some pen
testing and hacking threads initially he
was selling some shell codes but in
February of 2016
he has started to sell for the first
version the first version only was for
grabbing malware and only works in
Internet Explorer Firefox and Chrome
later in May of 2016 the version 2 were
released in this case he added the the
one of the most important features that
is the recovery of past versions of some
so we're like all loot chrome and
firefox
well he created a new a new thread
to sell the rest but when she started he
started to sell their version 3 he dated
this then we don't know how was the the
how the logo looked yeah it an educated
guess yeah within that is pretty similar
then one of the things that is pretty
cool in the in for book it's that in
July of the 2016 he has started to sell
for book as a service he have three kind
of plans that you pay every week every
month or every three months and he hosts
your panel and will deliver you a binary
you can buy a binary hosting your own
Brown panel to well this is the same
when you have the pro plan when there
are updates you can send by a private
message your account ID then he delivery
you the binary updated with a new
version in April of 2017 the version 3
was released and there are a lot of
dates that were important like the
complete encryption of the communication
they have the Kinect and more brochures
and book fixes that were dated one of
the important things here is this now
one computer can be affected by two or
more for books then two people that buy
the different different for book with
his own account can infect them the same
computer well the prices will rotate it
and then now were higher than the
previous version but you continues
having the same kind of packages well in
October of 2017 and decoder stopped
selling for book because they were use
it to a makeup
and they say that is not the way that he
wants that full moon well you said yes
suppose the form book is an educational
tool and you have yes it you know
principal your eat your wife and this
okay after the CSS stop some some uses
way less covet by Impostors of a decoder
they were contacted via Skype and well
this is move it yes sorry at some point
we I think we misplaced this this is
just like the software supported but for
homework yeah they're in the top of the
matches you can see this words that have
super to the password recovery and there
are a lot of so where that supports a
keystroke its filtration the phone
grabbing and sniffs at the people at the
end what was a top was just broken roses
an email client yeah okay and this is
repeated okay and after this for books
to be appeared in some markets where
it's led to like this one that it's hot
tools it's a software or malware malware
market and there are other people that
says that half the crack adverse enough
for book and sell it you know their
forums I get the feeling that the
tendency of bad guys of using like dark
themes is playing against us here not in
this screenshot you're supposed to see
the text saying I'm so cool
and this is a guy well this is I write
that up three mmm the accounts of
subscription of for book I he wants to
sell two of them and they he has the
approval of the ng color that is the
main straight actor team already in this
okay so no back to me
really underneath to have these tubs and
be able to exchange you know to have
Borja take over because I sometimes
forget to breathe and at the end was I
like oh I have to scoop speaking and it
was really hard but you know well just
the conclusion okay overall poor book it
used to be coded by someone who has a
bit of experience it's not a malware
made by some script kiddie and that's
important because by how he works by
having a subscription model it allows
lesser you know like less lesser cyber
criminals to say so to use his more
advanced malware which gives them tools
that they haven't supposed to have and
enables them to do more damage with the
same technical knowledge as you have
seen during the I hope during the
assembly detail and well as you have not
seen thanks the orc has screenshot the
code is relatively clean the flow of
execution it's kind of alright as well
it has extensive support for many
applications that means that the guy has
actually went and just studied how they
worked and what functions did they use
and how to hook them in Windows 7 and
Windows XP in Windows 10 so you know
changes in versions that kind of stuff
ETS was being using like even though the
techniques key uses they are known they
are not something new he hasn't invented
something no but the thing is that most
of them are very sneaky and you don't
usually see them in common malware so on
the other hand it does make use of very
weak encryption mechanisms I remember
having when I was working in pen testing
and remember having a client telling me
that lc4 is not encryption its encoding
so you know well using lc4 for the
communication and encrypting the buffers
it's not like very heavily encrypted but
I do believe this is the result the
result of a trade off if you want to be
sneaky you cannot use like heavyweight
type API is like the encryption API s--
so that might be the reason the other
hand the choice for the communication
key that is like a mistake for me using
the
of the domain and not being backed by
default that I do think as well it's a
mistake or something that he could
improve so even though it has its flaws
we do believe we will know that the
model is being maintained still but even
though sales have stopped if the market
this thing is still being maintained
that must mean that the guy has a
generating enough revenue with a client
it nuts right now okay so that makes him
like a bit more dangerous because he
cannot like focus on those clients and
develop for them and we don't get the
updates because when he was posting on
the forum hey I have now implemented
like a new system and you're hooking in
giant okay so you just go to the part of
the hooking and you see the changes that
makes it more difficult for us to follow
him and to track him and he keeps - he
gets to keep doing his job which is like
try to steal from people I hope you have
liked seeing what we intended we first
the showcase just one research we have
gone global distribution how them our
works we have seen the panel the
communication encryption techniques it
uses with all of this information for
example the encryption key we can track
the different campaigns we can track the
different actors you can try to
correlate them for example as you seen
before the emails using the email and
then the sample that that's document you
can execute it in a sandbox get the RTF
extract the payload from the payload
extract the key or the C of the other
one and control server and you can
follow a specific group C who is
targeting why are they targeting them
what's the level of experience and
that's what we basically try to show you
how we do it I believe you will find
most of the IOC s we used for this in
relief community you can have even more
OC s for form book if you want to do a
bit of poking around
we have quando control servers hashes I
believe they're even some emails I just
think I encourage you to come and get
them if you want them and also if you
want to share you're more than welcome
so questions
[Applause]
I'm not seeing questions but I wanted to
thank all of you because I think I've
heard someone love of one of her jokes
and that really motivates me to keep
improving and making my presentations
better so see that guy Thanks okay I
great job guys thanks for the
presentation I just wanted to know if do
you have any estimation of how much
money this this guy may have like Gordon
from the software from the licenses we
did try to make an estimation but it was
running a bit wild about four more
guesses would they think are very bad he
was about making about a half a million
as of now but that's like I think
Twitter's everything because we were
just trying to count the different
domains we found which see if he's
domain identify the client you can get
the amount of the domain or the amount
of time that path was active and from
that you can try to assume in heat they
are using because they're not dumb the
cheapest subscription you can try to
like guess but I mean probably some
didn't PayPal rhizoma from the leaked
version probably some are they don't
know some they might be from the
beginning maybe they haven't updated the
subscription plans so half a million
it's like a while yes but yeah that
would be an option we haven't done it
yet though okay
you
[Applause]