all right next up we have our lightning
talks and our first presenters are going
to be Ian Flint and Igor Gusinsky from
Yahoo telling us all about you Dee ping
take it away guys everyone so how many
people have some like this in their
network bunch of lags fully meshed
between your routers and somebody says I
have a performance issue from source to
destination what the hell do you do and
that's actually the simple case but make
that go all the way across the country
where you have multiple hops of this how
do you detect monitor troubleshoot the
usual method is well not pretty you're
basically start taking links out of
service or city pairs out of service
until you find whatever is causing the
problem and if it's point five percent
packet loss or something along those
lines it might take you a couple of days
well as you can imagine in a large-scale
production network that doesn't work so
all also we have heard for many years
that there's going to be solutions to
this there is going to be BFD that works
for luck that will detect this there's
going to be eaten at om there's going to
be some other magic thingy and I think
after waiting for close to a decade we
decided that we need to do something
about it so here's the end to talk about
what you do hello so what we built to
solve this problem is something we're
calling UT paying what UD being does
it's an evolution of the one-way active
management protocol so it sends a stream
of UDP packets from a client to a server
the packets are emitted in groups we
chop them into groups of packets and
each of the packets we timestamp it at
the client and then we pick it up at the
server and check the time stamp at the
server to determine latency and we put a
serial number on every packet which is a
monotonically increasing singing serial
number so that we can detect packet loss
by basically taking the difference
between the last packet in the group and
the first packet in the group and
subtracting the number of packets we
received so
if the first and last packets are 20
packets apart and we receive 19 we know
who lost a packet on the server side
we've got a server that receives the
packet times Samson as they come in
does lost detection and then emits
status statistics to either stats D or
standard out so the features so that's
all very nice but but what was really a
challenge was to make this useful in a
complex networking environment like what
Igor described so so we do a lot of
tricks to make this thing sort of ferret
out as many problems as we possibly can
so the first is we do true one-way
measurement this means we can measure
the quality of service in one direction
versus another so if we have a funny
route in one way that isn't the other
way we can actually isolate that problem
we spread the traffic across multiple
next-hop great ways we would do that as
we actually write the ethernet frame and
we manipulate next top mac so that we
can force the traffic to go to either
the primary or the secondary or router
out of the network that we're emitting
from we manipulate the source port so we
can exercise if we have multiple ecmp
pathways we can exercise all of those
and you can do since we're writing the
link level header we can use as many
source ports as we want to you don't
actually have to bind to a UDP socket or
to UDP port you just you just throw the
packets on the wire and they go so that
makes it very nice it makes it easy to
deconflict multiple instances of UDP
running on a single on a single client
machine randomize the payload size so
you can detect like MSS failures you can
say I want to push right up to my MSS
and see if it makes it across or if it
gets fragmented and lost or you know if
there's any particular issues with a
particular packet size I know we've had
a few of those problems in our network
the other thing that we were really
concerned about was was resonance and so
you know if you omit a packet once a
second or if you omit a packet once
every half second or once every 10 to
the second maybe there's an event
happens every second or every half
second or every tenth of a second that
just happens to miss every packet that
you send or just happens to hit every
packet that you send so there's a
randomization method called Plus on
sampling it's based on a you know an
exponential curve and what it does is it
allows you to do random intervals
between packets and yet still have your
your emission frequency averaged to a
fixed number that you want to go after
and finally we collect statistics that
allow you to take the output of stats T
and turn it into jitter measurement by
doing some squares you can do a rough
approximation of standard deviation
across the set of packets we also emit a
sum and countin and maximum latency
what's nice about these statistics as
well is that they're additive so you can
do standard deviation across a single
group or you can do standard deviation
across ten groups or across ten minutes
or across an hour whatever you want to
do it all adds up in the math works out
so as far as deploying this in Yahoo
what we did was we started out by
rolling it strictly for for
point-to-point links so you guys
remember how I talked about what happens
when you have how do you identify where
the problem is well one way you do it
across a global backbone is you simply
say I'm going to test every city pair
and if I have a problem from one line to
another well the city pair that is
having the problem that we dip in will
again hopefully identify that city pair
at that point you still will have to do
the standard you know binary division
take out enough links and see where the
problem is but at least it zooms in and
where the problem is which is usually
the hardest part of the whole thing yeah
and I mean you know the other thing is
when we move to you deepen we move to
you tipping from a simple ICMP probe the
problem that I see in people open is it
only exercises one path you know where
you may have sixteen thirty to however
many paths between two to between a city
pair and so it does guaranteed that
you're spreading your traffic out across
your entire network footprint rather
than only exercise
a small portion of it so we started out
by doing this in a point-to-point
deployment we basically put it in every
pop in our back on our backbone and we
measured single hop latency single hop
packet loss across all those and emitted
alerts to our monitoring console the
next step was to deploy a full mesh
across our backbone and so every single
pop every single site we put one of
these agents in and we we set it up to
do a full mesh to every other pop in
sight and we're able to draw a nice grid
which on a good day it's all green and
look at the performance of our backplane
our backbone as a as a whole the next
thing we're planning to do is our data
centers at Yahoo are split into
availability zones and so we want to
deploy this into every availability zone
and build a full mesh between
availability zones which will give us a
couple of things it will give us more
redundancy in terms of our coverage of
our backbone if you only deploy to a
single box in each pop in your backbone
you you know that box becomes a single
point of failure but if you deploy to
multiple lazy's within a within a site
you have that redundancy and you can you
know actually tell the difference
between a single box failure and a
backbone failure and one of the reasons
that we do that is if you think about it
let's say you have packet loss from DC
to Bay Area so phase 2 is what will say
hey you have a problem from DC tube area
on top of what you have every
point-to-point links that says hey I
have a little problem between actually
Chicago and Denver so now that kind of
zooms you in and where you need to begin
troubleshooting by having multiple
overlapping layers of monitoring you
effectively can say I have a problem
from here to here and this is actually
the problem and even with the simple
example of New York to Chicago well on
that example you had four different
paths
effectively all Lag you could see if the
packet lost 25% there okay it's one of
the live numbers is the packet lost 50%
probably one of the routers is it one
percent okay one of the links is being
played
it really allows you but having multiple
overlapping layers to troubleshoot and
cement which you have to work on and the
spar is all it allows you to figure that
out at least with you depending what
10,000 packets per second over the whole
backbone yeah about that
with about 10,000 PPS you can detect it
hopefully way before your applications
here yeah extremely lightweight it's a
fully written in C I think the the
memory size of it's like less than 50 K
so you can run it and it barely has a
footprint on the host that you're
running it on so the best news I don't
know if you've caught the lower right
hand corner of the last few slides but
it's open sourced and so you're free to
download it for kit use it as you see
fit
contribute back we'd love to get any
improvements that you might have to it
github comm / Yahoo / UT ping that
closes the talk any questions yes you
have 27 seconds off actually we're going
to hold questions until the end of the
lightning talks if we have time for that
if not you're more than welcome to come
up and you know talk to Ian and Igor
afterwards but thank you very much guys
you