hello my name is Patrick Moore going to
be talking about a very long title here
but it boils down to network automation
some of the hospice arounds that the
vendors will feed you and then some of
the reality of what we can really do
today I'll talk a little bit about the
past ways we did it the current ways we
can do it in some of the future stuff so
one of these are some themes that I'll
kind of talk through through the entire
presentation automation is not something
you ever stop working towards us a
journey that you're on for the full
lifecycle of your company we're going
talk about traditional and future
automation and then some of the - and
reality like I said so the journey boils
down to you have your physical network
elements that you're used to dealing
with today
there's a lot of scripting a lot of
manual work that you do with that in
some cases that's what you're going to
always do
there's use cases that have been
infrequently enough it just doesn't make
sense for you to spend a lot of effort
trying to automate that you notice on
the slide we have modest improvement
limited benefits on that track that
where you do manual Plus scripting
that's totally okay for those things you
don't have to automate certain things
another thing complicating this journey
is virtualization and all of the various
things that are getting introduced to
that and networking today NFB has been a
big buzzword for the last couple of
years so you have different but
different acronyms that get thrown
around with vnfs and virtual routers
firewalls load balancers etc Sdn is
another big buzzword that's hot right
now that also plays into this the issue
with the journey is all of these
virtualization tracks are adding in an
entire set of tools that they're
introducing themselves and you have this
operational gap that that's being
created where there's existing
operational processes and tools that
you're using and brand new things being
introduced
use and our operational guys are being
expected to manage both of those things
and do so with not anymore people and in
some cases less people than they have
today so we think it's important that
you converge that operational gap and
we'll talk about an approach later on in
the presentation of how how we think you
should do that operational convergence
the central theme around what we think
makes automation possible moving forward
is programmability we don't want to talk
about Sdn because Sdn can mean 500
different things depending on who you
talk to which vendor you talk to which
approach they chose to take to it so we
want to use the we think that
programmability is the right way to talk
about it our definition programmability
is that you provide software like
interfaces to your network this can be
through api's it can be devices that
support net comp it can also be with
systems that you overlay on top of that
that provides you those api's or net
cost interfaces to work with those
devices that there may be legacy that
don't provide that themselves a big part
of it is modeling modeling and
intelligent templates of Yang is is a
popular modeling language most people
wouldn't consider gamal a model it
depends on how you use it as to whether
you that's another word that may be
different different people define it
different ways
Tosca is mostly a cloud-based service
oriented modeling language that some of
you may or may not be familiar with I
would imagine most people have probably
heard of Yang and probably mo as well a
few terms we won't I'm not going to sit
and read the slides you guys will have
access to these but I mention net comp
yang yeah MO and if the network function
virtualization if you don't know a whole
lot about that I'm not going to dive too
much into it because you could talk for
hours about it about the various
approaches and tasks I've mentioned
traditionally the way we've automated
our networks has been very script based
uh you have a specific task you want to
do you write a script to do that pass
that gives you something you can repeat
if you need to tweak the script do very
repeatable things but it's very
repeatable for a very specific task so
it's not as scalable as some of the
things that we're trying to put in place
now and in the future it can be
labor-intensive to maintain those
especially if you want to have a
centralized repository where everybody
is using the same set of scripts you
sometimes you may have a change to the
network that causes all of your scripts
to need to be updated or new scripts
created it does avoid your need to go to
your IT department and need a real coder
real developer to to help do that
because there's probably not a single
engineer in this room that's not capable
of doing some scripting I would I would
be surprised if there is so but it best
cases this is a very human driven
automation the future knows we skip
today we'll get to today in a minute the
future is moving towards that
model-based approach it's it's going to
be very scalable your your models are
going to be very flexible and able to
account for various scenarios that
you're going to be going through you
should have a smaller number of models
those models are going to be more
complicated than the script that's
that's a reality you may have to involve
an IT department or some developers or
build that expertise in your engineering
group that's that's that collision of IT
development and engineering skill sets
is something that gets talked about
quite a bit both sides are going to
think they should on this that's what we
run into that means you have IP
development groups thinking they should
start owning the network and
I'm sure you all react very nicely to
that just like I do you have engineering
guys that want to reach further into
some of the things with IT groups on now
as well some of the OSS tools and things
like that you want to take ownership of
those because if we're going to own this
piece we need that as well they don't
like that just as much as we don't like
them messing with our stuff so there's
some organizational challenges that are
going to have to be to be conquered for
this to work out well but uh and we'll
step through ok let's talk a little bit
about some of the hot your vendors today
vendors like to talk about that cause
that coffee is great you can automate
everything you have your game models on
top of that those translate internet
comp automation becomes easy because you
have Netcom there are some problems with
that
some more - NFV oh we're going to have n
Fe we're going to have these management
and network orchestration systems
sitting on top of n Fe the mono stack
everything is going to be automated its
virtual so it can be automated right but
a lot of people make that assumption
they're wrong naturally but but that is
an assumption many many people made so
we get into some of the the reality here
most network devices are not that
compliant today of different vendors
take different approaches some are
taking a REST API approach instead of
using that comp so you and three vendors
may take three different approaches with
your api's some people aren't trying to
do neck off or api's they want their own
proprietary solutions to how you manage
their systems and they will they'll
preach an automation message that and if
you buy every piece of equipment and
every management system from that one
vendor then their story is accurate but
that's not really that snot realistic o
our gang is not created equal
some yang models are more complicated
than other gang models some vendors
approach their use of yang differently
and they require different things yang
is a standard modeling language but some
vendors put a little spin on certain
things have an example this this is a
excerpt of the yang model for managing
access control is if you're a newer
person in networking you know CLI really
well but you have no bent towards the
the development world at all this may
seem like a whole lot of trouble to go
through just to do to manage of an
access control is on top of that this
gets interpreted by something into net
cause this is net comp that was
generated just to make a simple change
to one of the access control lists this
particular one was generated from the
Cisco's NSO product it's something that
we work with a lot so it was convenient
to generate our example from it there's
some operational complexity that's added
when you start talking about the
model-based approach there's new skill
sets like I mentioned over and over
there's more IT development type skill
sets to get introduced that you have to
worry about the there's lots of tools
some are good some are bad for the
commercial tools the NSO product from
Cisco seems to be a pretty good option
at the moment it's not cheap of quite
the opposite actually it's very
expensive and in that vein you don't
necessarily need a Ferrari if you're
just going to be running down to the
grocery they got something for dinner so
if your company is small enough or your
use cases are small enough what you need
to automate you would be crazy to buy a
Ferrari to run down to the local grocery
for four to pick up dinner so you have
to think about that as you walk through
here and you have to remind your vendors
of that oh the net cop game I mentioned
not supported widely enough to be as
useful as you'd like it to be yet and
the intersection of those developer and
engineering skill sets so there's lots
of options out there I mentioned there I
list some commercial options by no means
would this be every possible one there's
also some open source options that you
can get out there I would suggest
getting familiar with this so that when
you do talk to your vendors these are
some things to play with good good
documentation exists for most of this o
if you don't know a whole lot about it
it's a good thing to get it to get
educated on so that when you do talk to
your vendors they're not going to be
able to pull the wool over your eyes
convince you of things that of some
nirvana that they can deliver that that
they probably can't and I'm fine o means
things all vendors are liars that's
that's not what I'm trying to say there
but uh but if you educate yourself you
protect yourself from from some of that
I mentioned nfe is a big buzzword for
the last couple of years and if he does
not equal programmable it does not equal
automated it just means that you've
taken those networked devices that are a
physical box sitting somewhere and you
put them in a cloud somewhere it's that
doesn't that buys you nothing except for
not as many hardware boxes so the ad on
your network maybe people think the
virtualization means that physical
things are going to go away I would like
those people to explain where you're
going to plug your fiber into in the
future where you're going to plug you
need collects if you're if you're a
cable company where your wireless
signals are going to come from if you
don't have radios and antennas so
virtualization is not the end-all be-all
that that some people try to sell it to
be but it is still in its infancy as
well it's very immature
oh it's if virtualization itself is
nearing maturity but but the nfe
concepts are
are not really there yet a lot of
vendors have virtual as AI virtualized
by taking the code straight off of a box
and modifying it just enough that it'll
run on a VM that's you technically are
virtualized but you have not in my
opinion created a virtual network
function at that point you've just
duplicated your physical box into a
virtual environment and we can talk
later if anybody wants to grab me about
why I think those are so different if
you disagree Oh lots of management and
tooling is required that's not very
mature yet and once again continued
theme IT ops network engineering skill
sets there's this continuous collision
of those so we we think there's an
automation framework that it's very
generic the way I've drawn it out not
certain vendor products don't fit better
into it than any other one certain
open-source projects don't fit better
any better into it than any other but we
do think that programmability is the key
the technology that enables that
programmability isn't as important but
by no means is it unimportant so
high-level approach you have your
physical network physical network
devices your virtual network devices and
there's a reason I have programmability
and a box to itself and that's and it
overlaps the physical and virtual
because there are some physical devices
that have api's Cisco's next to series
is an example of that and there are
others there are some virtual devices
that provide those api's so you can
directly program ibly interface with
those network elements but for other
items the word I've chosen to use is
interpreter you need something that's
going to translate what that legacy
device that's been sitting out there for
five or six years in your network and
doesn't know the first thing about
programmability you got to have
something that can speak its language
and translate between that layer and
your
for management layers Oh I repeated that
enough I probably shouldn't say it any
more but virtual does not equal
programmable so on the orchestration
layer you have you got to have something
for those interpreters to talk to you in
the virtual world it's the mono stack
management and network orchestration of
from the net see the scen Fe standards
and then there's of various network
orchestrators there's NSO Francisco
there's blue planet has there blue
planet Orchestrator and others and those
allow an exposure of AP is to a
northbound system our northbound set of
tools I prefer to a network automation
control the that's where you can build
operational automation applications that
do specific things you may have an
application that provision services an
application that does golden
configuration including compliance
reporting and correction of that if you
allow it to automatically do that that's
not always a good idea it's usually not
a good idea to let it automatically do
that I'm talking more about the specific
needs
the interpreter like I said it
translates the models and templates and
other language involved to commands that
those network layer devices can
understand good examples of that there's
napalm that I know it's been presented
at the net nog conferences a couple of
times over the last couple of years it's
really starting to mature now
it has different modules to work with a
lot of the Cisco devices a lot of the
Juniper devices long list of vendors
that are they're active they're very
active community they're constantly
adding to that if you haven't checked
out napalm I highly suggest you check it
out like said open-source something you
can play with without having to spend a
lot of money ansible also open source
has its network modules to work with
those various including a module to work
with made
also salt is another tool similar to
ansible the latest versions of salt come
with napalm pre-installed so that's a
good way to start learning napalm as
well chef puppet and in the proprietary
thing Cisco's NSO has its network
element drivers that's the equivalent of
the interpreter as I'm calling it the
next level of the orchestration is where
you provide that modeling and that
template een capability so that you can
communicate down to those lower level
levels ansible can do this so if you
your playbooks
things like that can provide this
functionality you'll see ansible can be
used at various stages it's a pre
powerful tool OPA knows one of the open
source mando tools and nfe world those
are constantly changing they're getting
merged into various other projects so
there's there's a list of those that
shifts around a little bit
opendaylight has some capabilities with
Yang and talking down to the network as
well I open source Sdn controller and
then mentioned some of the proprietary
the NSO glue planet and other tools so
the automation platform this is probably
the one I've really not talked about
much at all yet so far so you need
something that can take a workflow and
overlay it across the top of all of
these things I'm talking about so that
you can integrate across different
domains so maybe you have service
provisioning for instance if you have a
customer that wants a VPN turned up
you're gonna there's one set of tools
involved there maybe they also want a
virtual server turned up in your VMware
environment because they want to host
exchange on there as well you're going
to have to have some system to PI those
various domains together if you're ever
going to get to full automation oh the
the group of people here that probably
wasn't the best example when you throw
in the exchange server
it's a our domain as a part of that
greater domain there's some various
tools activity red-hats JBoss those are
both open source or you can pay for
support of proprietary they're pronghorn
service now remedy any system that can
do some scripting a high level scripting
and orchestration and workflow those are
kind of the things that go together
with that and it's really the glue I've
heard people when projects I've worked
on where we've done this they refer to
this as the glue that keeps everything
together
so here at same diagram but I mentioned
some of the open source options that are
out there of once again this is by no
means all-inclusive there's probably a
lot more options in the the automation
workflow at the top I filled up some of
the other boxes but there's only so much
space here once again I will salt
ansible napalm good place to start
I also have a link at the end of my
slide deck to the network to code slack
channel very very very very very
valuable place to go look and talk to
people and ask questions if you've not
checked that out or a member of that
that's a very good place to go so
conclusions listen to what the vendors
say but listen with a grain of salt
there they're trying to sell you their
full stack they're trying to try to give
you sell your full environment
management tools pieces of equipment
everything from them they absolutely can
automate the heck out of your network if
you have everything from them that's
that is absolutely the truth that
doesn't mean if reality is you can't buy
everything from that vendor that doesn't
mean you shouldn't still talk to that
vendor because at worst case you're
going to get inspiration from some of
the things they tell you and you should
ask the questions of why can't I do that
if I add in a second vendor because some
of these open-source tools that you can
add in may
that that capability for you consider
open-source tools some of the bigger
companies are getting into that now it's
a big deal with ATT right now open
source is set goals for automation make
sure you set down and plan this out if
you don't have a target you can't hit it
don't just randomly do this make sure
you do some planning and some future
future thinking about what you want to
do so evaluate your needs versus the
vendor and open-source capabilities out
there there are partners around that
they can help you figure that out it
could be the vendors themselves that
would be fully willing to help further
enhance their products but but make sure
you're getting what you need and I think
that's any questions or come in or
anything else I feel like I flew through
that a little bit but and I do have some
some links to various things that may be
good references you might want to take a
look and like I mention the network to
code slack channel is a goldmine if
you're interested in looking at the open
source open source tools are available
and some experts they've done some very
very very cool things with it in some
cases cool things that are impaired in
parity with some of the commercial
offerings vendors probably don't want to
hear that said but is true so no
questions
you