good morning
here from Yahoo's Network automation
team and we're going to give a technical
deep dive of our real-time network
telemetry platform which we've codenamed
not these the key challenge we had to
meet when developing Panoptix was
scaling our platforms pulling and
persistence layers
simply put we needed to provide
real-time telemetry from Yahoo's tens of
thousands of network devices to Yahoo's
thousands of employees we hope that if
we made this data easy to consume our
fellow engineers who live and breathe
this infrastructure everyday would
create amazing tools with it and as
you'll see later in this talk we were
not disappointed but before we get into
the new platform let's take a step back
and examine some of the issues we had
with our legacy network monitoring tools
one of the biggest issues we had was
over polling over polling is when you
have two different monitoring systems
who query advice for the exact same data
naturally this taxes that devices
control plan for no reason the second
problem we had was with data
accessibility we couldn't easily
correlate data that existed in multiple
different systems and lastly all of our
legacy tools were dependent on SNMP we
wanted our new platform to benefit from
modern control plane features like
performant rest and net comp ap is and
whatever else might come along in the
future these problems informed many of
the design goals we had for penalties
our first design goal was to minimize
the effort required to pull different
types of devices or a different set of
metrics the flexibility allows us to
avoid vendor lock-in and quickly provide
new services to our internal customers
secondly horizontal scalability was
enough given our scale and of course
horizontal scalability is just
increasing scale by adding more hardware
and our last major design goal was to
make this data easy to consume through
clean and understandable restful api s
and later on in the talk Brunel's going
to walk through some example AP is that
were built on top of the not these
collected data not these consists of
three major subsystem we have a
discovery layer which enumerates this
devices to collect telemetry from we
have a collection layer that issues
queries to collect Plumtree
and then finally we have a persistence
layer that sends telemetry from our data
bus Kafka to various data stores we
implemented scalable discovery and
pulling through a plugin architecture
where plugins are simply Python modules
on the other hand the persistent flairs
main unit of work is a group of Python
consumer processes which consume data
from Kafka and load it into a
configurable data store with this
high-level overview in mind let's look
at how not these fits into Yahoo's
production network for the purpose of
this talk we'll consider consider our
global network as a series of data
centers pops and pods connected by a
backbone network within each data center
in some pops and pods we have our three
main cannot be sub systems our discovery
pulling and persistence layers we chose
to put a persistence layer in each data
center because we wanted telemetry to
still be accessible in the event of a
network partition in fact you would not
want to be without telemetry during a
catastrophic event like a network
partition later on in this talk Bruin
will discuss the scenario in much more
detail but let's step through each layer
in detail now starting with polling at
the polling layer we have our polling
plugins a celery task queue which queues
polling plugin tasks for execution and a
series of polar host which
cutes the task as I mentioned earlier a
polling plug-in is a Python module that
targets a certain type of device within
the modules code we specify how to pull
telemetry from that device Python has
emerged as the lingua franca of the
Network automation world so we have
ample open-source libraries to use in
our polling plugins everything from SNMP
engines to vendor specific clients so
plugins scheduling begins at the
discovery layer the discovery layer
calls an internal service to enumerate
which devices to poll for service
resiliency we cache the first of devices
for seven days again this allows to not
these two function in the event the
central service is unavailable or down
once we have our list of devices we try
to find a matching polling plug-in by
matching that devices metadata with each
polling plugins target information then
to actually execute the polling plugin
we place its tasks on the celery task
queue and wait for a polar host to fetch
and execute that task here we see a
polling host fetching tasks from celery
executing those tasks by issuing their
commands and then placing the results
onto Kappa for the persistence layer
consumer process groups to handle now
that we've talked about how we pull
let's take a look at what we pull soap
not these pulls dimensions counters and
gauges a dimension as a category
expressed as a string in this example
the dimension is the local address of
the BGP adjacency and the value is the
string one dot one dot one dot one a
counter is a non-negative integer that
increases monotonically an example
counter is the number of packets sent by
an interface you can also think of the
counter like the domitor in your car
on the other hand at gage is a point in
time measurement that increases or
decreases which is like the rate of
packets set on an interface or going
with the car analogy it's like the
speedometer in your car the goal of our
polling layer is to produce a metrics
group which consists of these dimensions
counters and gauges then we place the
metrics group onto the cap bus for the
persistence layer to handle but before
we before we get to the persistence
let's take a quick look at how we
implement our SNMP based polling
plug-ins again our polling plug-ins do
not have to be written in SMP this is
just a subset of all the polling plugins
we have in our repository we made
extensible SNMP polling by writing an
evaluator library that takes a Python
dictionary as input and produces a group
of metrics as an output in this example
we specified a target o ID whose value
is the local address of a BGP adjacency
along with the OID we have metadata that
specifies what transformations to apply
to this data before putting it into the
novice we also say the name that we want
to give to this metric and its type
either a dimension metric or gauge okay
so now that we've made it through
discovery in polling I'm going to hand
it off to Varun who's going to talk
about the persistence layer API vests
and applications that we built on top of
the Nazis
so um after we've done with bollock had
an episode we actually thought it's
going to be and you know wait for this
it will be a breakthrough in the
industry if you actually started storing
this data so with that tragically lost
we changing idea
we use we decided to use Gasca to just
get the data so that downstream
consumers could do untold unholy and
probably unsafe things with the data
that we've produced now one of the
things we do with the data is that we
convert interface counters in real-time
to rates because obviously that's a very
common use case in network arbitration
now this is interesting since the
traditional way of calculating rate has
been to actually take a data point
storage get the next data point fetch it
back calculate the value difference
right the time difference and then you
know come up with a final rate what
we've done instead is that we've made
this conversion as part of the pipeline
so that is available to all downstream
consumers now this is similar to the
derived data type in collecti or weight
in data log for those of you who are
into that sort of thing because we had
to solve various scaling problems to do
this rate conversion at our data volume
now this is a graphical view of what
we're doing what we mean when we say
they have multiple consumers we take the
data that have is produced and we
currently store it in two places
we store it in a central Aries time
series database that is available as a
service within Yahoo and we also store
an in Colo cash in my sequel and then to
the rest of these slides I'll talk about
why we actually have it in Colo cash you
would also see that we have a dotted box
and line for a future compute and the
example future consumer we've shown here
is storage which is actually another
time series database but you know after
hearing some of the talks here maybe we
could work with the Sonata team or the
Panda team two feet downstream telemetry
- or integrates with them as well oh now
next up for an example of the API that
we have built on top of the data that we
collect
now this API is built from the in Colo
my sequel cache the reasons were we
obviously want the data to be available
in case of a network partition at math
as mentioned and we also wanted to be
performant the thing with time series
data bases are is that they tend to be
optimized for serving a large amount of
data they tend to be optimized for being
able to run a lot of interesting
aggregates against them but they're not
necessarily optimized for speed and
returning one data point as fast as
possible
and that's the problem we wanted to
solve with the building a custom API now
I know this blurring might remind you of
products of the Japanese adult
entertainment industry but it's the best
API ever here is what we actually do
with that API we build custom
visualizations we with custom
applications on top of this this UI is
actually used by a network network
operators who publish things to answer
various questions and actually even for
capacity planning there is the view of
what happens to the data that we send to
us to a centralized telemetry store you
know the standard use case of sending
this data is graphing which you see up
on the screen and then being able to
generate alerts as well now one of the
things that matter to Esteban was what
was very important for us was to make
sure that we can survive network
partitions now when I say a network
partition and referring to one of our
network sites not being available to the
backbone I'm not referring to a network
partition within our network site not
never partition within a data center
because obviously when our network
partition happens we would obviously
want to use network telemetry data to be
able to troubleshoot why the network
partition happened
so the way we solve this problem is by
data Federation what happens is that
each data center actually knows about
the metadata in each other or in all
other data centers so you can have a two
step process the in first step you can
hit any data center and say hey I want
to get telemetry about this device or
you know various other filtering keys
you know not just the device and then a
few others like you know devices which
on this IP version or devices which
belong to the site etc etc it's a find
API and what that site would return you
is a response saying that hey I don't
have the data but I know this site has
the data the response is a JSON object
and then what the client does is uses
the response to follow and connect to
the site which actually contains the
data now in the normal course of
operations what happens is this is all
transparent to our users the
applications that we have and the
wrapper libraries they have do this
two-step call and as well as the users
are concerned they ask a question and
again they get the results back however
in the case of a network partition what
happens is that network operators can
reach any of these data centers through
and out of the out-of-band management
network and do local queries and you
will see as like I said that was the
motivation of federating the data and
not centralizing it now the data which
currently store in each data center is
the last point in time greater in my
sequel and we are considering and
looking at using druid as an in collude
longer term metrics tour so operators
could not religious ask what happens
last but what happened over the period
of some time with that let's talk about
the current status so Panoptix is being
deployed to all our production data
centers and we pull process store index
cache a millions of data points per
minute yahoo service owners actually use
the data that we generating for their
day-to-day operations as well as
capacity
a recent win for the data that we've
produced through this platform is that
our load balancer operation team was
able to use this data tried to ask how
many whips have been configured but not
actually are not actually being utilized
and the answer was surprisingly a lot so
we were actually able to cut down about
25% of our load balancer resource
utilization by analyzing the data that
this platform had produced a few lessons
learned so we knew going with Python
would be the path of least resistance at
smattered said because it's becoming the
choice of development language in the
network DevOps world and python has
delivered it was easy and actually fun -
Gordon - but it's also kind of slow and
the slowness of Python actually becomes
glaringly obvious at our scale
luckily interacting with unlikely
libraries through Python see and we did
kind of hand optimize scenarios for
example we don't use the pure Python
implementation of SNMP we actually use a
Python module which wraps the C library
is given by netizen mp4 speed another
thing that we learned is that creating a
lookalike network which would even
remotely mirror the complexity and scale
of a production network was going to be
very expensive and time consuming so
please don't ask me how we solved this
problem and finally I bet that juice
that the the best use for data B
produces not simply to feed it into an
analysis and/or a reporting system but
to make it available to engineers has
come true one example of this is we are
hammered by requests by teams throughout
Yahoo to use our API so that they can
make it part of their Vict pipelines and
they can actually look at the real Times
state of the network while they're doing
automated deployments and they can take
this
turns on their deployments based on how
the network is here is doing at that
time
future this is where I get to be
hand-wavy and convince my bosses to find
this forever so we know that getting
high-quality high-resolution enriched
data is the first step to being able to
generate insights because you know once
we are close to solving the problem of
collecting metrics at that scale and at
that resolution the obvious next step is
to try and feed this data through
machine learning and on anomaly
detection and possibly even use it for
auto remediation also as Matt pointed
out at the start of the presentation
SNMP booth served our industry quite
well issuing its age
we have already incorporated vendor
specific API based polling plugins but
one of the next things we want to do is
also to support ingesting streaming
telemetry from various devices into
properties in terms of coverage within
Yahoo we would be standing properties to
pour all the rack switches this will be
an order of magnitude increase in the
number of devices we pull though only
about a 3x increase in the number of
metrics we generate and the reason for
that is that the current set of devices
we pull actually covers a large surface
area of the young of Yahoo's network and
then finally a European optics would not
have existed without open source and
therefore we have a mandate from our
leadership to actually open source
properties so hopefully in one of the
future Nanak's Matt and I would be in
front of you announcing open sourcing of
phone optics and finally it was a big
project and a big shout-out to Ian Sean
stormy so Tom Malcolm Jess and the
rector for making this happen
and with that we will take questions
how he started people into silence david
Hankins twitter as a fellow monitoring
developer I'm more interested in sort of
the performance characteristics to the
system
what most cycle you reached and sort of
maybe a number of devices per quart or
devices per make of RAM however you
measure that in terms of how you would
scale it out I assume you just go
horizontally sure yeah we do scan
horizontally I'd make a few comments
about this one of the things we knew by
- by going with Python is that we were
trading off a lot of performance for
easier development so that's you know
something we knew upfront our criteria
to measure scaling is not necessarily
devices because we tend to have devices
produced tons and tons and tons of time
series so for us a better measurement
criteria tends to be the number of time
series that we can process
simultaneously um in terms of the
performance characteristics maybe I'll
talk to you about that offline I have to
check if I can even give you the numbers
it I will tell you that this our key
focus more than then scaling performance
was killing horizontally that make sense
and I'm sure you get why I said that
that makes total sense
we made exactly the same decision about
using Python in the head end of for
precisely the same reasons and also I
have merge request number 10 going to
netis an NP to push our version of the C
bindings up upstream sounds like we're
solving those problems in parallel
awesome yeah we use easy SNMP but you
know we look at what you have a fork of
easy SNP actually yeah we tried easier
Snoopy and peyote and I think six others
and they all fell down somewhere for us
yeah actually state of my turn SNMP was
quite appalling I was it was sad to see
it I agree with you I'm glad you guys
are solving that problem too many to
account yes so one
issue I think that one of us is you get
legacy tools that expect us an MP role
in directing the rounders and you get
the neat thing that takes it from some
data store like how do you you know
merge it so you can deal with the green
fields in the brown field and get it
kind of common view of things so there's
a two part solution to that the first
thing that we're doing is a we're
obviously a multi dependent network so
for any class of device that we pull we
come up with a pooling data model so if
we are for example pulling BGP telemetry
regardless of the platform we do it we
try and do a survey of whatever we use
and say okay this is the minimum common
subset of information I will be able to
get from all my existing devices and
this is what I want and you know try and
declare a model saying that no matter
what device I'm polling I must produce
this information today as of today
that's done by contract but the plan is
to actually sort of try and standardize
it I mean I think of it as trying to
declare you know hopefully maybe an
industry standard for what the data
model of pole telemetry should like look
like a abstracting away vendor specifics
so that's one part the other part is
integrate so you know on the pudding
side no matter what mechanism we use we
normalized to that data model the other
part is we knew that there will be
downstream legacy systems we need to
feed and that's what cost coterminous
and as a choice one of the examples I
will give you is we depend a lot on mrtg
like I'm sure you know a lot of us too
and we have a lot of cooling built
around mrtg so we don't want to break
any of that while we migrating to the
new system so one of the plans we have
in motion is actually to do the polling
through the system but right out mrtg
files so you know cut out the polling
this is why you know putting its
persistence is decoupled so not only
will I free to you know mines equal our
central telemetry store possibly an
incall telemetry store but also rather
dramatically files so that I can
continue to maintain compatibility with
my legs
does that on confession
yeah sometimes you know easier said than
done
okay thank you guys