hi
i'm stephen herwig in this presentation
i will be talking about my work in
building keyless content delivery
networks
this is joint work with my advisor dave
levin and our collaborator christina
garman
suppose we log into our bank's website
to pay some bills
although we envision our browser
connecting directly to the bank's web
server
the truth is that the bank and many
other websites
use a third party service called a
content delivery network
or cdn to host their website at their
course cdn's are
massive global network of physical ed
servers that act as caches for the
customer server
although the traditional value add of a
cdn is improving a site's speed
cdns also provides security by
mitigating ddos attacks and running web
application firewalls that block
targeted attacks in order for the edge
server to serve content over https
they must have access to the website's
private key
in practice the customer shares their
private key with the cdn
and this key is placed on each of the
cdn's edge servers
in fact the study from 2016 found that
43 percent of the alexa top 10 000
share their keys key sharing of course
brings many concerns
as the cdn is now a man in the middle
and trusts for the web as a whole
becomes consolidated to just a handful
of providers
i should also note that cdns generally
don't even want to have their customers
private keys
as this raises liability issues to
address
aspects of this problem cloudflare
developed the keyless ssl protocol
which allows cdn customers to maintain
sole ownership of their private keys
keyless ssl takes advantage of the fact
that tls
only uses the website's private key in a
single step
of the tls handshake and so with keyless
ssl
the cdn's edge server proxies the
handshake to a customer controlled key
server and the rest of the web request
is handled by the edge server
however even with keyless ssl the cdn
operator still learns
all the session keys moreover in
practice customers
ask the cdn operator to run the key
server on their behalf
thus the actual benefit is not for the
customer to retain custody of the key
but rather to mitigate against
heartbleed style vulnerabilities
cdns are just one specific example of
the broader problem
of organizations outsourcing their
applications or infrastructure
to a third party despite exposing
private data about themselves in the
process
beyond cdns my broader question is
whether we can maintain
privacy using legacy applications on
third-party resources
in this setup we assume that the content
owner and the third party
agree to run on the third party server
some software that the content owner
trusts
we assume a threat model where the third
party can arbitrarily interfere with the
software
and our goal is to reduce the third
party's adversarial power
to that of a network level tls attacker
as a central goal and distinguishing
feature of this work
i seek solutions that are compatible
with off-the-shelf software
in particular i don't want to have to
rewrite software from scratch to achieve
these security properties
now we have the building blocks to start
solving this problem
the challenge is to compose these
building blocks into a coherent
meaningful system let's focus on
building up this system
and then come back to building a cdn
specifically phoenix with this system in
mind
later in the talk as our core building
block for secure remote computation
we use intel sgx sgx is an extension to
the x86
instruction set that allows a process to
define a private region of memory called
an
enclave sjx guarantees via hardware
security checks that software outside of
the enclave
and even a physical attacker cannot
observe or alter the enclave state
in practice various side channel attacks
have undermined this guarantee
and in this particular iteration of our
work we treat mitigation
as an orthogonal concern
the first challenge is to design and
implement an execution environment
that handles the restrictions of enclave
mode to run such legacy binaries
the most obvious restriction being that
enclave code cannot make system calls
there have been a few projects that seek
to take legacy binaries and run them in
an enclave
the general idea is to move lib c and
part of the operating system kernel
now refactored as a library into the
enclave
libsy is patched to invoke the libos for
system calls
and the liberal as proxies to the
untrusted host for any system call that
it cannot service internally
the specific libos implementation i
built off of
is graphene sgx with this liberalized
design
graphene provides a foothold to add and
emulate additional features
for instance graphene's main added
feature is allowing an enclave
process to fork a child process which
itself runs within an enclave
however to run software such as a
multi-process web server on the cdn's
edge
we also need graphene to securely
emulate additional resources
that the various application processes
share
with conclaves my contribution is
extending the enclave security
guarantees beyond private memory
to these other shared system resources
the hard
for instance the hard disk and shared
memory and incorporating the respective
driver components
within either graphene or the plug-in
framework
of some core user library my insight is
to think of the application and its
execution environment
as a distributed system of processes
each running within an enclave
this leads to a microkernel-inspired
architecture
where kernel services such as the file
system shared memory or an application
key store
are implemented as dedicated servers
running within an enclave
and where an application's underlying
instance of graphene
proxy is a system call to the
appropriate server
as the design contains multiple enclaves
there is the need to bootstrap
trust in the resultant distributed
system and ultimately provision it with
private data
this part of the work is still a work in
progress but it follows from prior work
and the connections between the enclaves
are mutually authenticated
and attested tls connections
as an initial kernel server we implement
a key server
as a type of sgx rendition of a hardware
security module
with a companion open ssl engine we also
developed several implementations of
shared memory
all implemented as file systems within
graphene that expose a memory file
abstraction
in one version the application opens and
maps a file on such a file system
and then uses the f control system call
to lock the file the graph the graphene
libos services the call
by making an rpc to the memory server
the memory server manages the shared
memory segment as an
encrypted host file as well as managing
the lock owner and keying material
on acquiring the lock and keying
material from the server
the libos reads the encrypted memory
segment
into the enclave decrypts it and
and updates its memory pages finally
for an encrypted and integrity protected
file system
we convert a user space implementation
of a standard linux file system
into a server we then run that resulted
file system server on top of graphene
we emulate the hard disk by formatting a
large untrusted host file
as the backing store on a file system
related system call the libos again
proxies the call to the file server
the file server implements a block layer
that decrypts the virtual blocks on read
while also maintaining a merkle tree
over the entire backing store
i use the term conclave to refer to such
a collection of cooperating enclaves
to the application use of these kernel
servers is either transparent
transparent modulo and application
configuration option
or requires a small patch as with the
memory server
coming back to the cdn use case i use
the term
phoenix to refer to nginx configured as
a reverse caching proxy running within
an enclave
as a sort of conclave analog to an edge
server software stack
in our paper we discuss other details
such as how customers
could securely delegate provisioning to
the con
of the conclave to the operator we also
discussed deployments where conclaves
can contain multiple parties
now as a macro benchmark for evaluating
phoenix's performance
i use a web server stressing tool to
measure the web service throughput
varying the size of the file and number
of nginx worker processes
as a baseline i first evaluate nginx
running outside of a conclave
where i determine the legend as linux as
you can see
the throughput varies between 800 and
3000 requests per second
depending on the configuration and
workload i next compare
two configurations of phoenix phoenix
crypt and veracrypt
the kernel servers for crypt only offer
confidentiality of their respective
resources
whereas those of veracrypt also
guarantee integrity
with these workloads phoenix crypt's
overhead is roughly two to three times
that of linux
whereas veracrypt is between 3 and 14
times
needless to say this isn't great but
nevertheless it's a very promising start
for what
amounts to an unoptimized system we next
evaluate conclave approaches to
multi-tenancy which is hosting multiple
customers on the same edge server
in this evaluation we scale the number
of tenants from one up to six
conduct the stress test and then compute
the mean time to request a one kilobyte
file across all tenants
at these tenants numbers the non
enclaved linux baseline exhibits a
latency
that grows sublinearly with a number of
tenants
in our first conclave approach called
share nothing
each customer runs their own conclave
including their own dedicated unclaimed
instance of engine x
we see that request time increases
roughly quadratically with the number of
tenants
if we instead use an approach where
tenants share
and nonclaimed nginx but use their own
kernel servers
then request time increases only
linearly
now it's interesting to also plot the
number of sjs paging events
during these tests because we see that
somewhere between 32 and
48 enclaves there's a dramatic increase
in pressure on the limited epc memory
the take home message that supporting
massive multi-tenancy
indicates a deployment where customers
share enclaves
we include many other results in our
paper please
please check it out in conclusion users
continue to outsource their applications
and infrastructure to third parties
and in doing so for for privacy in this
paper
we present the design and implementation
of conclaves
an extension to the graphene sgx libos
that runs legacy applications safely on
third parties
by among other things extending
graphene's protection to the file system
and shared memory
i've enjoyed sharing this work with you
and i encourage you to explore conclaves
for use cases that you may encounter in
your own research
you