hello everyone thank you for
virtually attending my talk today i'm
samin currently doing my phd at nc state
and today we are going to be looking at
our work where we looked into pcids's
compliance of android applications
so one day i was about to grab lunch
from burger king and my friend told me
that there is this burger king app which
has many offers
which you won't get if you order at the
local restaurant so i downloaded the app
i was able to order my food
and when i was able to pay i noticed
that there is this option to pay using
google pay
which is convenient and secure because
they use tokenization so that these
consumer apps
won't be getting your credit card number
directly
but there was also this method to pay
providing your credit card number
which poses the additional risk of
exposing them
in our prior study we found that more
than 4 000 out of 50
000 apps from google play collects
credit card numbers from users
and since they're collecting credit card
numbers this makes them responsible for
protecting this information and the
regulation that dictates how that should
happen is called
pcidss we say this stands for payment
card industries data security standard
which is a guideline for how credit card
numbers should be
handled by any system acquiring them it
is regulated by
pci security standard council these
rules are mandatory meaning failure to
comply to them comes with some monetary
penalty
even though pci dss requirements are
broad there are a lot of these
requirements
that don't matter for a mobile
application for example
setting up a firewall is not applicable
in a mobile context
we marked 6p services requirements that
do apply to your mobile contacts by
accessing the document
these requirements ensure the secure
storage and
sharing of card holder data and
authentication data
in a mobile application the information
in a credit card that represents the
card holder
is called cardholder data for example
the credit card number
and the information that is used to
authenticate the card holder
is called sensitive authentication data
for example the three digit card
verification code on the back side of a
credit card
the goal of this work was to build a
static analysis tool called card plans
to determine if android applications are
handling credit card data
properly by complying to pcis
but achieving this was not so trivial
and came with several technical
challenges
first we had to determine which of these
requirements are
applicable to a mobile application and
how do you build the program analysis
tool to detect
these requirements which are stated at a
high level
again in android there is no well
defined api for taking credit card
numbers
as their api for taking imei or phone
number
and finally we needed to do some manual
validation on the results because
we were relying on a static analysis
approach
usually credit card numbers are provided
to the application through its user
interface
the programmatic approach is to grab a
reference of the ui widget
by calling the find view by id method
and then call the get text method
we use our prior tool ui ref which uses
natural language processing on
any label or hint associated to the ui
widget
to determine what kind of data it is
collecting
and we extract the resource identifier
of that widget which
is collecting credit card number and
provide that to the next phase of our
analysis
in this phase we use an existing static
analysis tool called amendroid
to generate a data dependency graph from
the apk
we then parameterize the data dependency
graph with the right context
so we can tame track the flow of the
credit card number throughout the
application
we design our graph traversal algorithms
to check if the credit card information
goes to any data persistence sync like
writing to a file or network sync
for some pcss requirement this was
sufficient
for example where we needed to verify if
the application is storing cbc
which is a violation of psidss this
approach was sufficient
but for some requirements we need to
ensure that credit card information is
going through
some intermediate methods to meet the
psydss requirement
for example in the epsilon requirement
which says
encrypt card uh card holder data or
credit card number before storing
we look for common cryptographic methods
in the intermediate path so the data is
obfuscated before
it reaches the sink
in this table we enlist the six pci
checks we performed along with the
associated pci dss requirement at a high
level
for example the first test was to check
if the cardholder data is stored in the
app
for this we marked the find view by id
methods
which are parameterized with credit card
number taking input widgets
as the source and some data persistent
methods as things
here we do not check for any
intermediate methods that's why the
required column is empty
but for test d6 we check if some
if the same data is going to any
external application unobfuscated
therefore we check for obfuscation
methods which are required
and and thus they are listed in columnar
we
implement our tool in such a way that
these source sync and required sets
uh can be further extended uh there was
an additional lightweight heuristic to
check if the
app is using bad socket factory or trust
manager classes or
bypassing hostname verification and that
was
just by looking at the application code
not uh to any data flow analysis and
therefore we did not
include that in this table
for building our data set we first
scraped
top 500 apps from every category in
google play
and reason for choosing most popular
applications was
popular apps are going to be impactful
however as we have seen from our prior
study that most of the applications
would not be collecting credit card
information thus that would increase our
analysis time significantly
therefore we filtered this set by
looking into the resource files
of the apks if they have any credit card
related string
uh this narrowed down our scope to a set
of 1868 apps
saving a lot of computation time uh at
the price of including false negatives
we ran our input widget resolution
framework qrf
and data dependency graph generator
android on these applications
and finally got 358 data events graphs
the remaining ones could not be analyzed
by these tools or did not collect credit
card information
so our test was on 358 popular apps from
google play
we ran our tool on this set and r2
reported 20 of them had
at least one flow that could potentially
be violating these idss
we found another 20 apps that had bad
socket factory or cross manager classes
we reverse engineered the source code
using a commercial tool called gft
compiler
and looked into the code to validate our
findings
we confirmed 6 apps where pcids is
non-compliant
out of the 20 apps raising red flag for
having a potential non-compliant flow
the other 20 apps having bad socket
factory classes
were false positives because they were
either dead code or
built for debug versions or they were
using bad socket factory to send
irrelevant data like like analytics
but not create your data all the
non-compliant apps
and the tests they failed are listed on
table below
here are some of our highlighted
findings we found most of the
applications are doing it right
which indicates popular applications
mandate good coding practice with
industry regulations
we found all the apps were performing
hostname verification and certificate
validation correctly
they were not using http url to send
credit card data
and they were not insecurely sharing
them with other applications
however we did find six applications
where violating pcidss
with collectively more than 1.5 million
downloads also we see a common trade of
common trend of writing sensitive data
like credit card numbers
in device logs without realizing its
implications
we notified the six developers to the
email address enlisted in google play
just one of the developers responded to
our email admining the flaws in their
app
and assured to fix them they also
appreciated our work
um a 16.6 percent response rate is not
ideal but
it is not unexpected either considering
responding to such email could
raise liability concerns
here are some of the deeper dive we did
on some of the non-compliant apps
first we have this credit card reader
app which insecurely
prints credit card numbers in device
logs device logs are basically used for
debugging purposes and they can be
easily retrieved
if someone has physical access to the
device and the interesting factor is
this is a merchant app meaning a
merchant uses this app
in his device to accept payment from
customers and it has more than 500k
downloads
so if any merchant is using this app to
serve say 100 customers per day
this app is secretly logging all of
their credit card numbers
which the merchant can get access of
thus this app would be exposing 50
million credit number daily
then we have this pretzel selling app
which writes both
credit card number and cvc in device log
it was clearly mentioned in pci dss
requirement 3.2
not to store cbc in device logs
also what this app is doing here is it
is storing some value in the shared
preference
but it is using the plain text credit
card number as the key of whatever they
are storing
which gets stored in an xml file in the
shared press directory of the
application
firstly this is making the app pcr jss
non-compliant
but this can also be dangerous if any
app with escalated privilege
can access that information
and lastly we see this application is
trying to generate a key using a secret
random object
initializing this secure um object with
a constant or predictable value we can
see it significantly
and that is what we see here they are
seeding the secure random object
with the most predictable thing for the
application the credit card number
there were several limitation of our
tool which we already discussed
there were some limitations due to the
underlying tools we used
for example the popular metroid app
marta what uidf identified as a credit
card number
was found to be a risk card number some
of the things we did not look into was
weak cipher suits or to detect
hard-coded cryptographic keys in the
application
which would be left for future work the
other limitations are well discussed in
the paper
so to summarize we built card clients to
perform pcidss compliance checks on
android applications
and according to our study the landscape
of popular android application in terms
of pci dss
is fairly positive still we were
successful to detect
real pci dss violation on several apps
good news is we have open sourced our
code which you can find at whisper and
system gate repo
so please check it out and give us your
feedback
so i want to wrap up by thanking my team
members from ncsu and ibm
and at this point i'm happy to take any
question