i'm abe clements and i'll be
i ain't eric gustafson will be
presenting hallucinated former
re-hosting through abstraction layer
emulation
both eric and i worked on this work
equally
if you think about the internet of
things we have millions of devices that
we use throughout our lives that are
interconnected and vulnerable
vulnerabilities in these systems
can compromise cause compromise
compromise private information
uh destroy equipment and disrupt our
daily lives
if you look inside of these internet of
things devices you'll find a bunch of
microcontrollers
running firmware a subset of this
firmware is bare metal firmware
where everything is compiled into a
single monolithic binary that runs
directly on the hardware
and accesses all the hardware through
direct memory reads and writes so it has
raw hardware access
if you compare that to like a linux
system where you have a bunch of
different sections within your binary
and kernel abstractions that are used
for hardware interaction
we know very little so if we want to
assess bare metal firmware
the options we have currently have are
to look at hardware
so we can tear apart the hardware to get
debug access do dynamic analysis using
that debugger
however for security reasons this should
be disabled and if it is present it's
very limited maybe a handful of
breakpoints
the dependency on hardware also limits
parallelism we can only run as many
instances as
physical devices that we have other
limitations to this approach are
the cost can be hundreds to tens of
thousands of dollars per device
and they're brittle it can easily break
so what about re-hosting so re-hosting
is the process of taking firmware
from an embedded system and running it
on an emulator on your desktop
well this can this this can provide
scaling
however rehosting firmware is a
challenging problem and hallucinator's
goal is to enable scalable firmware
rehosting
without requiring specialized hardware
prohibits are the biggest problem to
enabling
scalable rehosting of firmware we
currently have qmu
which is a cpu emulator that enables us
to
execute the instruction sets of cpus and
hence a handful of prohibits
however if you look at a modern
microcontroller like the one on the left
it has 20 to 30 different peripherals
that it can access and interact with
and the firmware by being bare metal
directly accesses all these peripherals
and will not operate without them that's
just a single device
if we look at mouse or common
electronics distributor it lists for
over 44
000 different microcontrollers that they
have available for sale today
across 35 different data sheets which
kind of represents the number of product
families so there's still a great
amount of diversity between its devices
and across 26 different manufacturers
so when we look at trying to scalably
re-host firmware
the primarily challenge is that without
peripherals
bare metal form will run in fact in our
evaluation we found that
most of our firmware would only execute
eight basic blocks if we didn't provide
support for peripherals and then there
are tens of thousands
of peripherals and combinations thereof
that any given that firmware
needs to use to operate so how can we
scalably re-host firmware
if we look at the way developers develop
their software we get
a clue so developers and manufacturers
of microcontrollers
put out software define uh software
development kits and hardware
abstraction libraries within them
to ease and simplify ease implementation
this includes like device drivers that
abstract away the level details of buses
and hard
different peripherals and these
hardwares are
these hardware abstraction libraries are
everywhere
so nxp stm atmel all provided
sdks and hardware abstraction libraries
and those are also embedded inside
common operating systems like riot and
reno and friartos
hallucinator leverages these hardware
abstraction layers
and enables replacing them during
re-hosting with high-level
implementations
and this enables us to transform the
problem of re-hosting firmware from
supporting thousands of different
devices or peripherals
to dozens of house if we look a little
more closely at the
firmware we again have this binary
monolithic
bare metal firmware but to the developer
it looks more like this where they have
their application code
middleware middleware libraries uh
hardware hardware abstraction libraries
and then the hardware
rehosting what we do is we replace those
hardware abstraction libraries with
higher level implementations replace the
hardware with qmu
system emulator and this enables us to
decouple
the upper layers of the firmware from
the hardware we can also replace the
middleware with higher level
replacements and run just the
application code
and this is what hallucinator does
through our implementation we take the
firmware
run it through a tool that we created
called lib match which takes the
hardware abstraction library source code
and produces a list of the function
addresses within that firmware
or the functions within that abstraction
library
we then implement a series of handlers
which provide interact
provide low level replacements for
interacting with those functions
to prohibit models which model the
behavior of the different types of
devices
which are then all connected through an
i o server which centralizes the control
of all the external peripherals and this
enables us to execute
firmware on a generic cpu emulator
without having to implement the tens of
thousands of different peripherals
i'll quickly go through a handler and
then refer you to
the paper for more details on our
peripheral models and io server
this is an example of a handler it's
written in python and you can see that
we're replacing the i2c
rebuffer function so when that function
gets called within the firmware it will
execute this python code which first
reads out the location of the buffer
and its length and then we just check to
make sure that it's
valid and then we retrieve from the
model the data to be written back into
the firmware which is then written back
in
on the last line of the example i'll now
hand it off to eric to describe libmatch
in our evaluation
so in order to actually locate the
hardware abstraction layers and
libraries in the binary
we developed a tool called libmatch
which uses binary analysis
to find function names first
we obtain the sdk files from the vendor
and we use these with the content
matching described by previous work
to obtain some direct matches for the
content
however along with this we get some
number of collisions
where the function's content was
indistinguishable from one another yet
they perform different functionality
in order to solve this uh lib match
utilizes
context provided by the sdks themselves
in order to look at the callers
and then the callees of these collided
functions
to disambiguate them and turn them into
correct matches
by the same token we can examine cases
where we can infer what the names of
other functions should be
even when we can't match their content
such as if they've been customized by
the
application vendor through all of these
techniques we can
obtain a much larger set of correctly
matched functions using libmatch
of course once we have a completed
system we can take it out fuzzing
we built a fuzzing oriented variant of
hallucinator called
alphas based on the afl unicorn
framework
along with doing this we had to solve a
lot of interesting problems
that come with fuzzing firmware such as
when does the program terminate
what to do about non-determinism from
timers and interrupts
and of course crash detection and you
can read all about this
in the paper to evaluate hallucinator we
obtained
16 for more samples from three vendors
whose functionality involved a variety
of different hardware
among these were these bolded ones here
which use network related functionality
and are therefore interesting for an
attacker
first let's examine the performance of
libmatch as you can see from this table
here
the context features used by livmatch
not only allow us to obtain
a higher rate of the correct matches and
a lower rate of collisions
but they also allow for up to 10 percent
more
names than we would otherwise have using
this context
related features
in order to evaluate the ease of use of
hallucinator we examined
the effort required to implement the
handlers needed to re-host those 16
firmware samples
and we we did this by dividing them into
three categories
trivial meaning it the handler does
nothing or returns a constant
translating which is also very simple
where the
handler collects the arguments passed to
that function by the firmware
operates on one of our predefined models
and then returns some results and
finally internal logic
where in order to implement the handler
you needed some piece of knowledge that
was not contained in the sdk's
documentation
in doing this we noticed that over 85
percent of the handlers we needed to
implement
required little effort meaning they were
in the first two
easiest categories the remaining
handlers that were required internal
logic
were those where the hardware
abstraction layer wasn't a very good
abstraction layer such as
hardware specific details were involved
or it used an internal feature of the
sdk
such as its own memory allocator that
was required for correct functionality
so of course once we have a completed
system we can take it out fuzzing
so we took those network related
firmware samples
and we fuzzed them with real parallel
afl and because we have
fully decoupled the hardware from the
firmware we can scale this as much as we
want meaning we
you were able to utilize hundreds of
millions of parallel executions
and we did find some crashes we crashed
the stm
st plc plc kit and we crashed atmel's
http server and
mesh network related firmware samples
interestingly we fuzzed the http server
firmware
twice once where we re-hosted based on
the lowest level
hardware abstraction layer and found one
set of bugs
or a single bug and in the
other where we we re-hosted using
everything but the application code
and we found a different bug this shows
that
this multi-level approach allows you to
focus on the
the areas of the firmware that you want
to find bugs in
uh the two the two bugs we found in the
contiki real-time operating system were
in fact
uh previously unknown and therefore we
obtained cve numbers for them
we disclosed these to the vendor and
they have since been fixed
last year we had the opportunity to take
hallucinator to a
hacking competition at last year's
see-saw embedded systems challenge
where we were tasked with solving
challenges on this hardware board here
in order to obtain points uh of course
naturally we re-hosted the firmware
running on this board
which gave us uh unusually powerful
debugging capabilities
allowing us to solve all of the firmware
related challenges
and take home first place
and finally this concludes our talk
hallucinator
eliminates the implementation of tens of
thousands of peripherals
by instead focusing on the dozens of
hals
you can find the source code for
hallucinator half fuzz and live match
at the github links here and of course
these artifacts past artifact evaluation
thank you very much for your time
you