hello everyone
i'm xin jung from penn state university
i'm here happy to present our paper
interpretable deep learning under fire
at youthnix securities program 2020.
this is joint work with new favoring
question sholingji shapur
we present an attack against
interpretable developing systems in this
paper
let's first talk about the deep neural
networks interpretability
while the ants achieve superhuman
performance on
video recognition language understanding
and game playing they are often
criticized as black boxes
it is hard for human to understand how
a deep neural network arrives at a
particular decision
this opacity may limit the application
of the earth
in safety critical domains due to their
unpredictability
therefore intensive research efforts
have been spent to develop techniques to
explain the other's behavior in our
paper
we consider four families of
interpreters for the image
classification task
all these algorithms generate an
attribute map
to highlight significant regions in the
input image
that contributes to the classifier's
prediction
they are back propagation guided
representation guided
perturbation guided and model based
interpreters
here we have an example on the left side
we have an image classified as a flute
with a high confidence on the right side
we have the attribute map shows where
the darker region
contributes to the model's prediction
an interpretable deep learning system
consists of a deep neural network
the classifier and an interpreter
such design involves humans in the
decision-making process
for instance the explanation of a
specific decision
could help analysts debug their deep
learning models
on the attacker side it requires the
result
for both the classroom and the
interpreter
to break down the entire interpretable
deep learning system
in this paper we take a step towards
understanding
the security vulnerabilities of
interpretable deep learning systems
our approach is to develop attacks
that simultaneously for the classroom
and
the interpreter the diagram here shows
the workflow of our attack
give a benign input of the fish the
adversary adds
a penny preservation to get adversarial
input
then this input will cause the
classifier to misclassify it as a cat
and the input also misleads the
interpreter
to generate a target attribute map
represents the overall formulation of
our adb square attack
the attacker crafts an adversarial input
that triggered the target prediction
city and
the target interpretation empty we
formulate the attack as
a constituent optimization problem we
want to find an
x that minimizes the magnitude of
perturbation delta
such that f x is ct and g x
f is empty it is hard to solve this
problem directly
because it involves non-linear deep
neural networks
and complicated interpretation
algorithms
we cast it as a regular red optimization
problem as below
here our prediction is the targeted pdd
loss
and our interpretation is the squared
out distance
between the generated map and the target
map
can directly apply the formulation in
the previous slides to
representation guided and motivates the
interpreters
we proposed two techniques for back
propagation based
interpretation the gradient sentence
interpreter outputs the absolute value
of
gradient of prediction confidence of
class c
for the input attacking gradient
sentence involves
second order terms of the neural network
while for the riddle function the value
is zero
hence we propose a gradient enhancement
for relu
during the backward stage besides
to avoid an empty attribute map due to
the grid saturation we apply the label
smoothing to the classifier's target
motivation guided interpretation we take
mask
as the target interpreter mask uses
optimization to find a small region
which greatly reduces the classification
confidence of
the target class when the region is
removed
in this setting we are faced with a
bi-level optimization problem
we use a approximation approach that we
alternatively update our estimation
of optimal attribute map m star
and input x we also utilize
an imbalanced update and periodical
reset
to stabilize our attack evaluate our adb
square attack on the
image negative side our target
classifiers are resonant 50
and this net 169 we compare the adb
square attack to the ptd
attack we set the target attribute map
to the p9 attribute map
the top table shows the attack success
rate
in terms of misclassification and
prediction competency
it shows our attack is as effective as
the plain pgd attack the two charts
below measure
the similarity between generated maps
and
target attribute maps the left chart
shows the l1 distance
and the red chart shows intersection
over union
we could observe that our adb square
attack
could mislead interpreters to the target
map
well the pgd attack fails to do it
to sample inputs prediction and
interpretations here
the first law are benign inputs the
second row are attribute maps for the
binary inputs
the third and the last row show the item
maps generated by pgd and our adb square
attack
as we can see we visually validate that
adv square attack is spider-eyed fooling
the interpreters
discuss why our adv square attack is
possible
we hypothesize that there is a gap
between the classifiers prediction
and the interpreter's interpretation
we conduct a random class interpretation
experiments to validate it
we show the experiment in the bottom
figure in the first row
we first select target images from
random classes
then in the second row we get the maps
of those target images
for the third row we perform adb square
attacks
against the b9 inputs with another set
of random classes
and set target action maps from the
second row
the last row shows the interpretations
of adb square adversarial examples
note that the target and adv square
inputs are fairly distinct but with
highly similar interpretations
the chart on the right side also
indicates this
as we can see our attack is possible
even there are no dependencies
in the target class and the target
attribute map
move one more step and we hypothesize
that
limitations of existing interpretation
models
cause the prediction interpreting gap
different interpreters might focus on
distinct aspects of dna behavior
for example gradient and intermediate
representations
we perform an attack transferability
test here
in each row we have adversarial input
generated by adv square attack
for one specific interpreter then
we inspect the attribute map of this
input on the other three interpolators
in each column ideally for a fixed input
the model should have a fixed behavior
to predict
however we observe that different
interpreters
focus on different regions here
for the last we discuss potential or adb
square attack
due to the low transferabilities of the
attacks shown in the last slide
we could use an example interpreter
in this way multiple complementary
interpreters could fully cover dns
behavior
we also propose an adversarial training
approach
for a model-based interpreter we want to
minimize
the prediction interpretation gap using
adversarial examples
we feed a pair of b9 input and adb
square input to the
interpreter and train the interpreter to
generate
distinct attribute maps for the two
inputs
as we can observe from the third and the
fifth columns of
the figure here the adversarially
trained
interpreters are more sensitive to the
adversarial perturbations
the table on the left side also
indicates this
this paper we propose the adv square
attack
against interpretable learning systems
we conclude our key findings here first
the interpretability of existing
interpretable deep learning systems
merely provides limited security
assurance
second the prediction interpretation gap
is one possible cause for the adversary
to exploit
both the classroom and the interpreter
simultaneously
third adversarial training aiming to
minimize
the prediction in the prediction gap
potentially
improves the robustness of interpreters
i would like to thank you to my audience
and my co-authors here
for any further questions about our
paper you can just
send email to me by the following email
address
any questions from the audience
you