hi
my name is gregory nevin this is your
work with manu drivers sergey korbinov
and hotek
i'll talk to you about pixel pixel is a
forward secure multi-signature scheme
with applications to consensus protocols
so the main application you guessed it
right
blockchain in case you've been living on
a rock for the past 10 years and don't
know what blockchain is
it's essentially a sequence of blocks
usually containing transactions
that gets agreed upon by a network of
nodes
these nodes engage in a consensus
protocol to agree on that sequence of
blocks
there's different variants of consensus
protocols some of the most famous ones
involving
proof of work where nodes have to solve
hash puzzles in order to
cast votes on blocks some of the more
environmentally friendly solutions use
proof of stake where notes vote on block
proposals
by um by depositing stake by depositing
tokens and for this vote and blocking
them al goran cordano ether and casper
are some examples in this class or
permission blockchains
where the membership of the network is
is closed and decided upon by the
current members of the network and they
also usually vote on block proposals by
an access structure
imposed by the structure of the
permission network ripple and
hyperledger fabric
are some examples in this class
now when i say that nodes in these
systems
vote on a block proposal they usually do
so by
signing and so these could be thousands
of nodes that in each round
are adding their own signature to this
to this blockchain
plenty of those signatures have to be
kept as part of the blockchain so it can
be externally verifiable
so that's a whole lot of signatures
flying around
and this is where multi-signatures come
in multi-signatures are a primitive that
allow you to instead of having this list
of multiple signatures by multiple
signers on the same message in this case
the block
replacing it with a single signature a
single multi-signature
that is short about the same size as a
single signature
and efficiently verifiable in about the
same time as a single signature
so this is a huge gain that you can get
and therefore multisensors are quite
popular
for the use in blockchain there's a long
list of literature
on multi-signatures not going to go over
that here but i guess we are adding our
paper to that list
but for the forward secure aspect i have
to talk to you about another problem of
blockchains
um posterior corruption sometimes also
known as long-range attacks or costal
simulation
the problem essentially comes down to
the assumption of a chain integrity why
do we think do we believe that there can
be no forks in the chain
usually we assume that if less than a
fraction of nodes or a fraction of the
stake is corrupt and we can prove that
no two versions of the blockchain can
exist
now suppose that we're working with the
threshold of one third of the nodes we
have a network of ten nodes here two
nodes
should be fine no forks can agree it can
occur but in case it would be four nodes
out of ten that are corrupt
forks can actually start occurring and
this is what we want to avoid
now um of course when you corrupt the
node signing keys you essentially
corrupted the notice this is really
discussion about the signing keys
of the node now
the problem is that the network is not
static usually
and so even if the current status of the
network
should be able to support to cope with
two corrupted nodes
those two corrupted nodes may have been
around in the network for a lot longer
and their signature keys as well and so
when when you corrupt those nodes and
get their signature keys you can
actually go back in time
in the blockchain and create a fork at
the point where those two nodes were
actually a forking majority
on the network and create a fork from
there so now you have two versions of
history that are impossible to
distinguish for an external verifier
this is exactly what we wanted to avoid
not also that this problem only gets
bigger over time
as the network evolves there are only
more and more sets of keys that become
an achilles heel
to the to the blockchain so the real
assumption is that
if there's any corrupted nodes that none
of them
formed a forking majority so to speak at
any point in the past this actually
is a problem because also it may occur
long after the nodes left and so
their stake have no more interest in the
network at all they may even have sold
their keys to the highest bidder
and it's even on top of that aggravated
by consensus protocols that use
committee signing for efficiency where a
smaller committee
signs in name of the bigger group with
adaptive attacks you could actually
focus
after the committees become known um to
focus only on those nodes who are part
of the committee get their keys
and create a fork at that point so this
is
a big problem for um for blockchains
what is the solution obviously rotating
in keys if you do that in a
straightforward way the public keys will
change all the time of notes
which is a bit impractical so forward
secure signatures are the way to go
here the public key stays constant but
the secret key
gets updated all the time and you sign
and verify with respect to a
certain time frame and the security
property forward secure signatures is
that if your key gets corrupted now the
time frames of the past will be fine you
cannot forge signatures
for the past and that's why
pixel the scheme that we present is a
forward secure
multi-signature scheme it is based on
bi-linear maps
there's the public key which is as
typical generator raised to secret
exponent
the secret keys follow the structure of
a hierarchical identity based encryption
scheme
the technique was first done by
televised
kanelli halevi cuts 2003 and our scheme
can actually be seen
as being underlain by the key structure
of the bone
boyan go scheme of 2005.
going to go into the details of the key
structure here
but the scheme also has some public
parameters
random group elements from g1 which can
be determined by
a hash function and
there there's something you could see as
a hash function a hash function that
takes the time frame and a message
and converts it into a combination of
products
of those h values uh depending on on the
message
and the binary representation of the
time frame
now anyway the way that its signature in
time t
looks like is this public parameter h
raised to the master key x times this
hash of the time frame a message raised
to a random exponent r
and a second component has this
exponent r in g2 to the r in there
you can verify such a single
verification by
evaluating these three pairings of
course the crucial part is can we
compress those
and yeah we can yeah we can compress
those suppose you have a whole bunch of
those signatures
aggregating them into a single compact
signature is as simple as just
taking the product of component-wise of
the signatures and you can check the
algebra works out that you can verify
this
with respect to the aggregated public
key which is the product of all the
individual
public keys now we prove that
this scheme is secure in a random oracle
model assuming secure erasures obviously
because you have to update keys
and the hardness of a linear
diffie-hellman assumption
performance is pretty good um on a bls
12 301 curve
with 1500 signers and about 4 billion
time periods signatures and keys remain
small public key 48 bytes the signature
144 bytes independent of the number of
signers in it
and are fast signing is fast just three
milliseconds
computing the aggregate for 1500 times
as fast just seven milliseconds
verifying that aggregate is also very
fast less than seven milliseconds
so all these operations are really just
think of them as a single signature
um there's also a trade-off you can do
between the key and the signature sizes
uh versus the computation by switching
the groups around one of the groups is
slightly slower and slightly bigger than
the other one but you can actually
switch elements around and the skin will
still work
no trusted setup is needed for the pixel
scheme which is a big advantage because
trust is hard to come by in blockchain
scenarios
and we also provide row key protection
by proofs of possession there's also
other mechanisms
that are possible anyway to show that
this scheme actually works we
integrated in it into the algorand
blockchain
algorand uses ed25519 signatures
by design and needs forward security
for their committee signing approach to
work out
and they use the valari miner
generic approach with the three-based
structure of forward secure signatures
those things take a lot of space and a
lot of time to verify
we replaced that with our pixel scheme
and obtained about
33 savings as well as in size
and in block verification time the
detailed numbers are below you see on
the left the block verification time
and you see here for 1500 transactions
per block
with the valarie miner ed2549
approach these this block verification
time here is all spent on verifying
those signatures
and you see that that whole block
essentially
vanishes because it gets replaced by a
single signature
verification so that's what for the
verification time
uh blockchain size also gets improved
quite a lot
in the blue here you have the the
original approach with valarie miner
ed25519 forward secure signatures
on the right here in brown you get with
pixel
so we get even forty percent savings and
signature sizes
um it all depends on how many nodes are
signing and how many
um how many transactions are part of the
block
but so yeah it it works and gets the
savings that we wanted to get from it
i'll keep it at that for now i'm very
much looking forward to your questions
thank you
you