hi my name is claus leno and i'll be
presenting the paper stolen memories
about white box membership inference
and this work was done with matt
frederickson so let me just start real
quickly by defining what we mean by
membership inference
the basic idea is that an adversary is
going to try to predict whether a given
point was part of a target model's
training set
now while the adversary will obviously
not have access to any of the target
model's training data they will have the
following
access to some auxiliary data that's
different from the target model's
training data but distributed similarly
they'll be given an even prior over
members and non-members
and they'll have access to the training
algorithm used to produce the target
model
so the reason we care about membership
inferences first membership itself may
be sensitive for example i may not
want somebody to know i contributed to a
particular data set or study
but it also serves as a practical
measure of information leakage in
general which
may be able to be leveraged by a
different adversary performing a
different attack
and finally it's directly related to
differential privacy which makes
membership inference interesting to
study from the point of view of defenses
so membership inference has actually
been studied a lot in prior work
and most approaches fit under the black
box threat model where the adversary
only has oracle access to the target
model's outputs
but there's also been a little bit of
work on white box attacks where the
adversary has access to the target
model's learn parameters
the problem we have with this work is
that it requires a sort of non-standard
threat model where an adversary also
gets
to see a portion of the target model's
actual training data
so the question is it seems like there's
more information available that the
adversary could use to do better with
white box access
even without access to the training data
basically can we actually leverage this
to make a better attack
and of course i'm sure you guess i
wouldn't be in front of you presenting
today if the answer wasn't yes we can
so in our work we show how to explicitly
identify memorization in deep networks
and how to weaponize it for membership
inference
moreover we find that our white box
attacks can be more readily calibrated
to increase the attacker's confidence
and positive inferences
and we also test our attack against some
popular defenses to try to get a better
understanding of their practicality and
i'll be
pointing out some interesting results
there about differential privacy
so now we've sort of laid the groundwork
for membership inference i'm going to
take you through some of the key
insights from the paper
so first we provide a more fundamental
understanding of how overfitting
actually manifests itself in a deep
network
and then i'll show how to use this to
make a new type of membership inference
attack
and finally i'll highlight some of our
key results and some interesting
findings on defenses
so the key intuition we use for
developing our attack is that a model
provides evidence of membership
through the sometimes strange way it
uses features so to just give a
kind of cartoonish example let's say we
have two pictures of two celebrities a
and b
that we're trying to recognize and
you'll notice for both celebrities they
have sunglasses and 25
of their images but let's say we sample
a training set and the way it works out
is that celebrity a has sunglasses and
of their pictures while celebrity b is
more typical with sunglasses and 25
of their pictures so now if we're going
to train a model on this
the sunglasses are actually predictive
for celebrity a since they show up more
often for celebrity a than b
so we might expect the model could
encode this as a feature that uses that
it uses to predict celebrity a
so now when we pass an instance of
celebrity a with sunglasses
the sunglasses feature would get
activated and then used to produce
the output a and so the claim is that
because the model used the sunglasses to
predict celebrity a
we can maybe think that sunglasses are
more common than average for celebrity a
sort of leaking that they're an unusual
number of images of celebrity a with
sunglasses in the training set
so if you saw a picture of celebrity a
with some glasses we might think it's
more likely to be in the training set
but so here's a slightly more realistic
setting with an actual model on actual
data
uh so these are some training points
from the labeled faces in the wild data
set
and we can see in the top right corner
there's a picture of tony blair with a
distinctive pink black
background now if we take explanations
on some typical
test instances of tony blair where we
highlight the pixels that are most
relevant in making the classification
we see that the model seems to focus on
his face like we'd expect although
there's no pink background here
but on the training instance with the
pink background we actually see the
explanations highlighting the background
so this is basically leaking the fact
that there must be a training instance
of tony blair with a pink background
so if we know that's rare we might think
this picture is more likely to be in the
training set
so the basic idea is that features that
are distributed differently in the
training data from how they're
distributing the general population are
going to provide evidence for membership
and this is going to be apparent by how
the model uses features
so next we're going to formalize this
intuition and
show how to use it to construct an
attack and we'll start with a simple
case with linear models and then explain
the key insights we use to make it work
for deep networks
so let's say we have two distributions a
to star and ada hat and they might look
something like this
so now if we consider a point x prime x
prime is more likely to have been drawn
from a to hat than from a to star if the
probability according to a to star of
getting x
prime is less than the probability of
getting x prime according to eta hat
so we can see here for example that
there's a discrepancy so x
prime would be more likely to come from
a to hat in this case
and so we can actually make a classifier
that predicts whether x prime was drawn
from a to star
a to hat by making a decision brown
boundary wherever the orange curve is
above the blue curve
so for this example it would would look
like this
uh and so to turn this into an attack we
can think of a
star as the general population or
basically the non-members
and ada hat as the training set and of
course
an attack won't be able to know the
means and variances of a to star
eta hat or even if they're gaussian but
the key idea is that the weights from
the target model can be captured can
capture some of the relevant information
so we can use this general idea to make
an attack that's based on the weights of
the model
and we'll look at that next
so the goal is we're going to sort of
make a connection between the weights of
the model and the training distribution
and we'll do that using some simplifying
assumptions that let us actually analyze
things
so we'll assume we have gaussian naive
bayes data
we'll also assume that we can model the
training set as a gaussian distribution
using its empirical mean and covariance
and finally for now we'll consider
linear target models
and the key ideas are that first using
these assumptions we can analytically
derive the optimal attack from the means
and covariances of the true and training
distributions
but we can also analytically derive the
optimal weights of a linear classifier
from the mean and covariance of the
training distribution
basically this is where sgd would
converge and so what we can do is
combine these and substitute in the
weights for the distribution parameters
to come up with an attack that's
only in terms of the observable
parameters of the model and basically
we can use this attack whether or not
these assumptions are met but under
these assumptions an attack would be
provably optimal
so to summarize how our attack works
first we train a proxy model on the
auxiliary data
then we compare the weights of the proxy
model to those of the target model to
create an attack model
and basically the attack model is going
to place a lot of weight on the features
that are used differently in the target
model than in the proxy model basically
the features where the weights of the
target model in the proxy model are
really different
and those are going to be the features
that are used to determine membership
so now we're going to show how to extend
this to deep network since that's what
we really care about
and we'll do this by thinking of
applying the attack we just covered to
an individual layer of a deep network
and what we do is we take what we call a
slice of the network which partitions it
into two parts
h and g where you can think of h is
computing some features to work with and
g is classifying using those features
and the key important ideas are that
first
the target model and the proxy model
have to share the same internal
representation so they're
basically working on the same computed
features and we think this is what's
caused prior white box attacks to
require access to some training data
because they're based on transferring an
attack from a model trained on the
auxiliary data
but there's no guarantee that the
internal neurons in one model would
represent the same features in another
model
which is why they need some of the
target models real training data to make
that connection
uh then we also use a local linear
approximation at each point we're
attacking to approximate the top of the
network
g as a linear model so we can apply the
attack described earlier and there are
some different ways of getting this
approximation which we discussed in the
paper
but for now you could think of one way
as just a tangent line to the network
so if you have a function like this the
local linear approximation at point
x would look like this and notice that
the linear approximation is different at
every point so we're not just replacing
the whole network with a linear model
and just note that we can make an attack
on the on each layer of the network and
combine them to get an attack on the
whole network at once and the details
for this are in the paper
and finally i'd like to cover some of
the key results from this work
we'll briefly look at the performance of
our attack and also touch on some
results we had regarding differential
privacy as a defense against our attack
in terms of the performance of our
attack our results could be summarized
as follows
so first we perform better than black
box attacks both in terms of accuracy
and in terms of precision which is
basically the confidence we have on
positive inferences
and then we also have the ability to
calibrate the attack for high precision
and basically we argue that it's not so
great to just like for example
label pretty much everything as members
but on the other hand if you had even a
few points where you could be really
sure that you identified them as members
that would be a serious privacy concern
and we found that previous attacks
aren't really well calibrated like this
and finally we can get good precision
even on models that generalize really
well
like for example mnist has only one
percent generalization error so not much
overfitting in the sort of normal sense
but we can get 75
precision on our positive inferences and
prior attacks really can't do much of
anything on eminence since it doesn't
really overfit much in terms of accuracy
and so i don't have time to go into
details on differential privacy
but basically if you train a model with
epsilon differential privacy then you
get a guarantee that no adversary can
achieve an accuracy greater than e to
the epsilon over two
and uh note that if epsilon is bigger
than log two which is about point six
nine you actually don't really have any
meaningful guarantee since accuracy is
always less than 100
uh so when we tried differential privacy
as a defense against our attack
we found that as expected a small
epsilon reduces the attack accuracy
but it's really costly in terms of the
actual model's accuracy
when epsilon is really small the models
were pretty much doing as well as random
guessing
so what a lot of people would want to do
is use a bigger epsilon to get a more
useful model
and basically you could imagine maybe
you still get some privacy benefits from
this in practice
even though the theoretical guarantee is
not really there but basically
what we found was a large epsilon
sometimes works
but actually often the attack starts to
do pretty much how it done without the
defense when you make epsilon big
so for example on labeled faces in the
wild when epsilon was raised to 16
which is actually something that would
be used in practice the privacy loss was
pretty similar to with no defense
and actually the other thing is on most
of the models where 16 did give a good
defense like on cfar
the accuracy of the model with epsilon
16 was still bad so
a lot of times it seems like you might
start to lose benefits once you make
epsilon big enough to get good accuracy
so this really suggests there should be
more uh work on training
differentially private models to
overcome this trade-off
and in conclusion i'll just go ahead and
leave these key takeaways here
and of course this is just a 12-minute
talk so check out the paper for
details on the analysis more
sophisticated variants of the attack
additional experimental results and
evaluation of other defensions
like regularization anyway thanks so
much for watching and i look forward to
your questions
thanks