hi
my name is chelsea conlow and i'm here
to present joint work with nick
mathewson and ian goldberg
and today i'll be presenting our work
walking onions
scaling anonymity networks while
protecting users
so our work uses towards a case study
and if you're not familiar with tor
tour is a privacy enhancing tool that
allows users
millions of users around the world to
use the internet privately and to
circumvent censorship
and how are users able to do that well
in order to access information say from
this server
a user will create a path to the network
in order to route their traffic
and in order to do so all users download
what we call the consensus
and this consensus is essentially the
state of the network
and it has entries for every single
relay in the network
along with some network parameters and
this consensus is authenticated
by tor's directory authorities which
users trust by default
and so to create this path through the
network the user first
selects one relay from the consensus and
they do this by
sampling this relay at random but where
all relays are weighted by the amount of
bandwidth that they contribute to the
network
and then the user creates a circuit by
performing a key exchange with that
relay
and then the user selects the next relay
in the hop and ask the first relay to
forward their request in response
to this relay and then finally they
randomly
sample a third relay in order to
complete
their path and create what is this
circuit
which allows them to forward traffic to
the destination server on the other side
so in this model um tor favors security
over scalability
and what do we mean by that well there's
two attacks that we have in mind
that are relevant to our work and the
first is that of epistemic attacks
and that means that users with different
views in the network can be
distinguished by their relay selection
so if some were if some users were more
likely to select
certain relays over others adversaries
looking at the network would be able to
distinguish these users
but torah protects against that because
all clients maintain the same
up to date consensus so all clients are
equally likely to
select uh these relays
and the second attack that we have in
mind when we say this
is route capture attacks and that is
when an adversary can influence users
relay selection
but torque protects against that because
clients maintain this consensus which is
authenticated
by the directory authorities and this
consensus contains
relays signing keys and so clients are
able to verify the responses
from these relays using these keys and
all of this chains up
to this route of trust
so what contributions do we make with
walking onions first
in current tour because all relays or
all clients maintain this consensus
as new relays join the network that
means that this consensus grows
and therefore client bandwidth
requirements also grow
but in walking onions we reduce client
bandwidth overhead to
constant size even as new relays join
the network
secondly even though we do
reduce client overhead we still maintain
towards existing security model
so we present two variants one has no
change in towards model
the other has a slight weakening and
forward secrecy but only for the
selection of relays in the path
not actually for content that is sent
um we demonstrate that there's immediate
performance improvements at networks the
size of tour today
and some of the design choices of
walking onions apply to network designs
beyond tor
so we'll do a deep dive now looking at
walking onions
and we'll answer three questions one is
how to represent really information to
enable what we call oblivious
selection of relays and then we'll look
at how to use this oblivious relay
selection
and verification to build paths through
the network for clients
and then finally we'll look at how can
we perform even more efficient circuit
construction
so first let's look at how to represent
relay information
so as we said the current consensus and
torted a consists of a set of
really entries representing all relays
in the network
and a constant size amount of network
parameters and this consensus is
authenticated by
directory authorities in walking onions
we take these same
relay entries but we add two additional
values
one is an authentication tag computed by
tor's directory authorities
and the second is an index range and
this index range represents
this particular relay over distribution
for all relays in the network
and this distribution can be weighted by
certain factors
so for example in the case of tor you
might want to again weight relays
relative to the amount of bandwidth that
they contribute to the network
but we can imagine other properties um
being weighted for this index range as
well
and so um all relay entries become snips
and all snips along with another
authentication tag
comprise an endive and importantly only
relays
in walking onions download this endive
clients do not
in fact clients only need to download
this network parameters document
and therefore their growth even as new
relays join the network
remains constant
so now let's look at how can we build
paths using what we call oblivious relay
selection
meaning that the client doesn't know the
state of the network because they don't
know the consensus but they still need
to select relays for their path
so in our first variant which we call
telescoping walking onions
clients begin by bootstrapping to a
relay and we described further in the
paper how this bootstrapping process
happens but it uses some out-of-band
mechanism so the client knows about this
first relay
and is able to perform the first step in
circuit construction
very similarly to infor today however
when selecting the second relay in their
path
the user just samples some index
completely at random
uh within the distribution that we
described earlier
and to determine the next relay in the
hop once the first relay gets that index
it finds a snip that contains uh the
client's choice within its index range
and it extends the path to that relay
and then
in returning the relay's response to the
client the first relay also can
returns the snip corresponding to
the client's choice and what that means
is that the client can verify that the
random
index that they sampled is within the
index range for that relay
and they know that this information is
authentic because it contains a
authentication tag computed by the
directory authorities
so the client is essentially able to
perform post hoc
uh validation of their choice
for the relay in the path and the third
hop in the path is computed
exactly the same
so importantly the client doesn't need
to know the full consensus but it can
still
determine the relays for its path
without
influence by any intermediaries
so now let's look and see how even more
efficient circuit construction
can be performed so we're not going to
go into too much detail for this variant
which we call single pass
but the intuition behind this variant is
that actually the client doesn't even
need to compute this random index
themselves
they just need to know that the relays
sampled for their path
are chosen at random over this
distribution
and we're not influenced by any kind of
intermediary
and in order to perform that we actually
use vrfs
so vrfs determine the second and third
hop
in single pass walking onions and then
the client
verifies the proof produced by the vrf
to ensure
that their choice is actually at random
over the distribution that they expect
and that the snip is valid again
similarly to
within telescoping
so with that um we know that walking
onions
protects against epidemic and route
capture attacks
because the clients can verify the
content within the snips
and they know that they're equally as
likely to
select certain relays as every other
client
but how do we know that walking onions
actually improves
the performance of anonymity networks
like tor
well happily our simulations show that
it does so
looking at the graph to the right this
vertical
black line shows a network the size of
tour today
of about 65 000 relays and so
for relays we show that walking onions
saves four to six times the bandwidth
over vanilla onion routing
and when we say vanilla onion rotting we
mean the onion riding protocol that is
used in tour today
and even more exciting is that as the
network size grows
this savings to relays just further
increases
so we see an improvement of 20 to 40
times less bandwidth
for an overhead for relays at a network
10 times
the size of tor and for clients this
picture
is even better so again looking at the
graph to the right where that vertical
black line is
that is the size of a network the size
of tour today
and we see that clients and walking
onions save 10 to 15 times the bandwidth
of the vanilla onion routing
for a network the size of tor and
um even more
exciting is that in a network 10 times
the size of tor
clients save 90 to 150 times the
bandwidth over vanilla
so again the improvements for walking
onions just compound
as the network size grows
so what are the takeaways for this talk
first of all we know that the design of
tor today imposes overheads to clients
as the network skills
and this is because until today all
clients maintain this consensus
and as new relays join the network the
size of the consensus grows
and therefore as the network scales
the bandwidth overhead declines becomes
worse
however walking onions removes this per
relay bandwidth and storage
and the reason why it does that is
because clients no longer need to
maintain
the consensus locally they just need to
this constant size network parameters
document
and they're able to verify the integrity
of their path
in a post-hoc manner
but walking onions does offer the same
security protections
against epistemic and route capture
attacks and we saw that
in that clients can verify the integrity
of the snips
that are returned and they can also be
sure that
their selection of relays is not biased
or different from any other client in
the network
and something that we're really proud of
is that tor's already begun the
specification work to integrate walking
engines into the tour protocol
and you can find even more information
about this in our paper and artifact
at this url here thank you very much
you