hello everyone my name is satwik prasad
and i am a phd student at north carolina
state university
i'll be presenting our work on robocalls
titled who's calling
characterizing robocalls through audio
and metadata analysis
this is joint work with elijah burma
sims atisha kiran mylapan
and my advisor brad rives
robocalls are automated or
semi-automated phone calls that play a
recorded message once you answer them
i still remember the first robocall i
received within days of purchasing a new
phone number in the united states
the caller was trying to sell a car
insurance scheme when in fact i didn't
even own a car
even though most of these robocalls can
seem annoying
some robocalls can cause significant
harm to our society
robocallers are trying to sell fake
covet test kits
and health insurance schemes to
vulnerable population
in this long term study we provide
insights about the robocalling landscape
we answer four main questions the
frequent news reports and consumer
reports give us the impression that
robocalls are on the rise
we look at the data to understand if the
robocalling problem is getting worse
consumer reports constantly recommend
users to avoid
calls from unknown numbers to reduce the
number of robocalls you would receive
we conduct an experiment to understand
if answering robocalls results in more
robocalls
next we uncover robocalling operations
that were responsible for a large number
of these robocalls
and finally we study some of the tactics
used by robocallers to deceive their
victims
but to answer these important questions
we needed data
so we deployed a large-scale telephony
honeypot
the principle behind data collection in
our experiment was to own a large set of
phone numbers
and to wait for calls to be made to any
of these phone numbers
as consumers to our service provider we
obtained
more than 9000 phone numbers which had a
history of abuse
for example some of these phone numbers
were previously used by fraudsters
we used asterisk to deploy our telephony
honeypot
and configured our asterisk server to
reject all the calls made to these
numbers
we also collected zip logs and cdr
records for these calls
our honeypot constantly evolved
throughout our experiments and we added
more numbers
we account for these changes in all our
results and you can find those details
in our paper
next we randomly selected 3000 phone
numbers and configured our honeypot to
answer calls made to these numbers
we also recorded the call audio
further we added more than 57 000 phone
numbers which did not have a history of
abuse
we configured our honeypot to reject
calls made to these four numbers
finally we identified about 3000 phone
numbers which received a large number of
phone calls
and configured them to answer the phone
calls and record the call audio
to summarize over 11 months we used more
than 66 000 phone numbers
to collect about 150 000 call recordings
and a total of 1.5 million phone calls
a detailed discussion of ethical and
legal considerations of our work
can be found in our paper now let us
take a look at the data
that we collected over the 11 months
this graph shows the normalized call
volume observed in our honeypot
during the first few weeks we observed a
relatively constant call volume
but in the month of april we saw a
sudden increase in the number of calls
on deeper inspection we observed that
some phone numbers received a
disproportionately high number of phone
calls within a short span of time
we characterize these phenomena as
storms
further we added about 57 000 phone
numbers and continue to observe a
relatively constant call volume
when we observed the weekly call volume
throughout our experiment
we found that the number of unsolicited
phone calls received in our honeypot
neither decreased nor increased rather
it remained stationary
over 11 months we were able to uncover
about 650 storm events
across more than 200 phone numbers
we observed that over 90 percent of
these unsolicited phone calls were made
during weekdays
and more than 80 during working hours we
saw that the call volume would increase
drastically during weekdays
and drop during weekends the takeaway
here
is robocalling is a huge problem in the
united states and there is no sign of
decline
next we looked at one of the most common
recommendations made to users by
consumer forums and news reports
users are recommended not to answer
calls from unknown numbers to reduce the
number of robocalls you would receive
we selected 3000 random phone numbers
and rejected all the calls made to these
numbers for six weeks
next we answered all calls made to these
3000 numbers for 6 more weeks
finally we computed the average call
volume over these two study periods
we wanted to answer the question does
answering an unsolicited phone call have
a significant effect on the number of
unsolicited phone calls you would
receive
surprisingly we found no evidence that
answering an unsolicited phone call
would result in an increase in the
number of phone calls you would receive
what this means is even though we
recommend users to be cautious when
answering calls from unknown numbers
answering a robocall does not
necessarily mean you will receive more
robocalls in the future
next we wanted to process the call
recordings we had collected
our key insight here is that robocalling
operations tend to reuse the call
recording to generate these unsolicited
phone calls
based on this key insight we grouped
calls with similar audio
into broader robocalling campaigns to do
this we developed a five-stage audio
clustering pipeline
the first stage of the audio clustering
pipeline computes the amount of audio
present in a call recording
the second stage identifies those audio
recordings that have significant amount
of audio
the third stage generates fingerprints
for these audio recordings
the fourth stage builds a graph where
audio recordings that are similar are
connected using a graph edge
and finally the fifth stage identifies
connected components in this graph
to uncover operational robocalling
campaigns
we processed all the call recordings
collected in our honeypot
using this pipeline we were able to
uncover more than two and a half
thousand unique robocalling campaigns
by manual inspection of the top
campaigns we found that the tenth
largest campaign seen in our honeypot
was a large-scale social security fraud
campaign
the largest campaign seen in our
honeypot had over 6000 phone calls
interestingly only a few calls were made
from most of these campaigns
to our honeypot using audio similarity
to identify campaigns
allowed us to study campaign-specific
behavior which was previously impossible
to measure
now let us take a look at some of the
strategies used by these campaigns to
deceive victims
anecdotally we know that caller id
spoofing is a common strategy used by
robocallers
we found that robocalling campaigns
regularly spoof caller id
or change their calling numbers this is
a trivial strategy using which
robocallers can evade allow list or
linealist based
robocall mitigation techniques to
quantify this behavior
we define and compute source
distribution which is the ratio of
number of unique caller ids in a
campaign
to the campaign size we found that the
average source distribution
was about 84 but surprisingly the top
campaign
had a source distribution of about 100
which translates to a unique caller id
for every call among the 6000 calls we
found
in our honeypot we observed that some
campaigns
use more sophisticated spoofing
techniques like neighbour spoofing
where the caller id matches the first
six digits of your call number
this deceives the victim into believing
the call was originated
from their neighborhood we observed that
77 campaigns
used neighbour spoofing techniques where
14 of them used neighbour spoofing for
all the calls they generated through
anecdotal evidence we know that some
robocalling campaigns
randomly generate calls while others
used a specific list of phone numbers
we observed that robocalling campaigns
are highly targeted
and a top few campaigns seen in our
honeypot targeted specific phone numbers
to quantify this behavior we computed
spread which is the ratio of unique
destination numbers to the campaign size
we observed an average spread of 78 but
interestingly
the largest campaign had a spread of
just under 20
which translates to about five calls
made to the same phone number
while manually inspecting the top
robocalling campaigns
uncovered in our honeypot we encountered
two classes of fraudulent robocalling
campaigns
the first class of campaigns were the
social security fraud campaigns
we were able to uncover two distinct
where the caller was impersonating
federal agencies in the united states
we observed that these campaigns used
toll-free numbers to spoof caller id
the second campaign we encountered was a
fraudulent campaign
operating in mandarin or chinese
this campaign was impersonating the
chinese consulate
and was clearly targeting the
mandarin-speaking population
we observed that adversarial campaigns
impersonated government agencies
to deceive their victims apart from the
findings presented in this talk
we discussed many other interesting
findings in our paper
to conclude the key takeaway from this
talk is that robocalling is a huge
problem in the united states
and we desperately need solutions to
tackle them
even though we suggest users to be
cautious when answering calls from
unknown numbers
answering a robocall does not
necessarily increase the number of
robocalls you would receive
next we found that illegal robocalls are
highly targeted
and regularly spoof their caller id
finally we uncovered fraudulent
robocalling campaigns
that target specific vulnerable
populations of our society
thank you
you