the okay so I'm
let's go to the next talk and work %uh
Marcus love you know and
our society ever talk about firm for
puppetry and I bought save more because
assault they have 211 slight so
just hurry up police your a
thanks everyone don't worry muscular
pictures of cats so I gotta go through
them
I'm pretty quickly a service for a bus
from thanks to you heard from her own
yesterday a me he also worked with us on
this but as an eye i'm gonna be
present in the stuff so out talkers on
sock puppetry
up both as on her own have shaped since
we took those photos
but mostly we work at things and we try
to work on
what we consider to be interesting
problems so
I am there's a guy called at someone and
we need to start is for the butt of a
broader look
tom was a guy who invented the term
network into neutrality at that point
net
neutrality over 10 years ago is a lawyer
in america he writes about
the intersection of technology and the
law
and in 2010 he wrote this book called
the master switch
a and the moss to switch was a
historical look
at how many types of technologies after
they've been invented
at some point this best of open and they
are
in support of freedom and exchange
information
and over time those technologies become
close and
basic examples there are TV radio
a and the old one is a the telephone and
somewhat this progression the question
as well
what's up what's going to happen over
the internet right so we've this is also
a new technology and
and has this thing absorb migrated into
the internet space and we've seen some
examples of this so in 2011 with
the the whole Arab Spring movement 'em
in
Egypt and in Libya by for those
countries cut taxes completed
the Internet when they're citizen
started talking about things that didn't
like
I'm even lost in turkey there was the
blockage
all YouTube when a video was published
that was unfavorable
towards the government and so the stuff
is
happening but in truth ultimately how
much is cut access
right to just have such a blunt saud
that to
block people from from saying the things
that they think I want to say
is immediately visible and people know
what it is that you're doing
and so there's alternative ways to do
this a
also in 2011 Tennessee it took a
slightly different approach they left
access
in place but this thought third fiddling
with the access
so what they were doing was collecting
credentials and Gmail Facebook
Yahoo and so on and so they wouldn't a
harvest credentials and from that use
that
to target specific people but they
didn't simply just cut internet access
which was a which apps have made a lot
more news but it's not just in the Arab
Spring
it's not just in far-flung countries
also in 2011
I'm in London the London riots a the
technology
use their with smartphones a man that
was used to track
a and arrest rioters so
the technology that was open can also be
used
for persecution a and so
we have decided that that's all all
technology the Internet is different
like what we know about the internet
what we think we know about the internet
is that is designed to router on
problems a
will leave the nuclear thing aside but
we think that
the Internet can router on issues and so
when it comes to censorship
we're just going to router on censorship
a
and so even when government put methods
in place to try and control what saying
what people are saying they will retire
on that and one other
ways that if you talk to people they'll
suggest up to get through to her on
is through user-generated content UGC
up and so the idea there is that when
a governments try and control and news
flow people can read tweet
I'm someone's views on the ground people
can follow
on social media and they don't accept
the official view
vacancy there are and so wanna be up
for me one other fine example the bus
was the the Russian soldier who
posted stuff on social media sites in
the ukraine
which had left his job location:
and the ukraine's you had an official
story coming out of a
Russian media and there was a guy
posting
pics on Twitter put him in the ukraine
so it is kinda veneers paradigm not
completely but the side thereof
but democratize content is something
which were slow
tried to deal with personal plan to
understand
and so if we look at it in terms of
censorship
the question then becomes well how's it
going to be handled how to people who
want to control
what others are saying reading sharing
and discussing
how will they behave in I'm this world
of UGC and site to look at that
let's take a step back because when it
comes to control the techniques a
well-worn
and is nothing really that new under the
Sun control is nothing new
it's not a new idea at all and so if we
start
if we frame this in terms of the sixties
in the US
where there were there was a absorber
movements against the Vietnam War and
other aspects but
I'm the the up or the student union
you a student movement in the US I'm one
of the ways that they were controlled
was direct force but when that became
a like it's pretty blatant when people
are getting clubbed on the head
on in the newspapers I'm you can then
start to
change the way that those crowds are
perceived
by having I'm other people there
both opposing them or acting with them
apparently
but at the same time I'm dragging their
course through the mud
so the side thereof rent across as one
which is well one and that a common
technique for
control so if we return to that question
about how
censorship will be handled in the age
I've
for user-generated content we can look
to
one OVR industry or movement evens
a well-known folks up
errant shots when he was still with us
he wrote on the internet on boy
that it's not how it's not only how
certain people
have a license to speak not everyone has
a license to speak
it's a question of who gets hurt to
everyone can speak with UGC
but if you can control yes
what has been said then you can control
effect
of user-generated content so it means
what we're worried about
to put it plainly is censorship 2.0
so in this world that UGC how censorship
been handled and we think this is a
profoundly important
topic which is why we spend some time on
that
and we spend some some time on this with
the assistance
of open Technology Fund one of the
reasons why
we think this is so bad is because with
tim was ideas
of DeMoss the switch it really does have
the potential to
to influence much control and this
particular kinda pack
Israeli attack against the human mind so
rent a crowd but in the age of the
Internet and in the age
of a UGC what those look like
and with not too much thought to arrive
at the notion of sock puppets and sock
puppets are
I'm for if you're not aware of the
definition this is one definition of a
sock puppet
but in essence it's just online
identities under the control
of alternative for of that party's and
they're used to push
certain people went and they can simply
be individual identities
or alternate identities or entire
coordinated
a mass movements armies of SOP
so we wanted to ask ourselves when we
started with this work
if we were some kinda evil corporation
or government
a how would we go about right so for
trying to understand how it might be
happening
we need to understand how we would do it
and so we had three questions that we
want to ask ourselves
so what can be done what will be done
and a what is being done not lost when
there's
particularly important as awesome as we
see it but in essence
the core of this work is we're going to
look at a bunch of different
methods a publishing UGC and what you're
trying to say is how can we
get more people to pay attention to what
we're saying
or alternatively how can we decrease the
importance
up something that we don't like how can
we make sure that other
far less likely to see a so that they
ought to approaches
and we we try but the bus increase the
attention on something
if you like decrease the attention on
something
but we don't like and very quickly and
perhaps this is one of the reasons why
you don't eat too much work in this area
I'm a problem you get is how do you
measure
efficacy how do you know if you're
actually making a difference
and terms of a increase in attention
would decrease in attention because
there is so much content of that
it's really hard to say well we did
these things to clearly
'em and book peoples were talking about
what we
we wanted to promote or we try to
decrease the tension on this thing and
fewer people
were talking about it we must you know
does that mean we succeeded
maybe maybe it's a Sunday night and
people on paying attention
or maybe they happen to be a public
holiday or an election somewhere else
so both also carnations are quite ticket
to help
so we we thought would focus on
at least and tried to measure we have an
effect we've with autofocus on
fall sorry five main areas Sep I'm some
a-list polls reddit news site
and common systems a follow along like
there's some fun stuff in here
and if you're online in The Lost you
might have bumped into summer party that
just went to wear so other will take us
from male may mailing list so I'm sure
your
some you may be asking ourselves well by
mailing list
and there's only two reasons first but
my situation by the wanted for coming
off the presses that
still interesting people using mailing
list I'm an activist Main St cost many
calling for a sec meanest
and the of course up a bit to standards
mailing list
where people the big question stanchion
musing
and the second season in many just
personal curiosity
at Main St I really simple just emails
going to Main St to pass on to everyone
else
is there any space to play around and
see what we can do and make more less
people
make people see things or Nazi think we
don't want them to do
so but eventually want New Year is
10 the motor main st and had not to
mention make more people see it all
make less people said and interject
refined me to find a way to measure how
people a
to measure how many people actually 90
so
we're taking a bus in major we just in
bed then click then click Send Email
I'm use that assumption a rough idea hun
people are are you know emails
is a question that comes but we have
done so in sending emails up
what she put in these emails up
typically
in the lazy guys get up well we just it
is still content from Eva out
have been fun the emails Cup in the
father but burst Cup in from wherever
and put them in but be making sure not
to make them too exciting time to be
knows
a roughly equal appeal so now first
experiment way want to do
is take a look and see can get more
people to renew most of it did you
is we'd send an email
and do nothing of this get a sense of
how many clicks the normal you know get
when we do nothing and then the second
time around
with send an email but this time we have
a whole lot about don't suck public
email accounts
I waiting on the side and when the mail
comes in
we followed up by sending holiday next
enough to make a long affect discussion
thread
and I email to it's really simple and
then
in in the main is archive you'll see
something like this nasa
initial email phone up by of a
conversation that that we've created
and there's no to this was actually
interesting so weepy dispensable time on
onto Main St VisionTek
and full disclosure and Boo is peaceful
baseline
controller email that typical some
number keeps you can get
and then the Green Bus are the kicks a
most get when we put up a pic discussion
said
so in general when you do this the pic
discussion to tend to draw more
attention to
to the things you sent to second spent
lunch eyes
okay with question that we can get more
people saying oh but can get less people
he subido want to see
maybe someone sent a really good idea
about a really good cond number
generator
and we just Khan had that going on in
our at the standard so
murdered if Nick spend again with
percent testing over to baseline
to get a baseline feel I make it happen
and then this time we send me not to be
followed up with a flood of new email
just got a whole new fits: me she can be
John out that tension
that this e-mail affect initially muguet
so look something like that and the
effect the Spanish
ain't name first to Jenny what happen is
just an email
and the funding the mother was followed
up a whole lot of
I expect fed but then get less attention
and the gym because people are
some waiting to all the other he knows
that he said but one really cool thing
happened
jeering doing online in this experiment
Tomoka promised you a picture
cats ever bring that up. now but what
are the wanna be suffering email
accounts we had was named uptake at
and essentially just send an email to
full disclosure which was
copy and pasted from a pastebin paste
and whatever happens few days later
and the same the same account the side
in a bun bo hue database as a security
researcher
so which is is for dinner I'm a little
bit funny that a cap it comes Q
researching
three days but it has been used but note
that when people are busy
echoing what evidence that just say and
it just for women trying to build up a
more
real-world believable personas one of
quantum anus is that so we had these two
things we can do we can join attention
to an email
and we can distract attention email and
is more effective thing we can do is
just to combine those two together
so into an improved way to distract
attention from some think so
missing you know that we don't like and
then I mean it usual spot is defined up
a dollar Baxter
he must decide on attention but this
time he said just say no emailed
we also add take discussions and couple
those emails you know it too
improve them on destruction that we get
and the nice thing is also that
you can pay your juicy destruction
tentative time but in the end it to play
more so whatever you wish to bring up
and and to that i've ever work best at
it as a distraction
so that s main st Jenny be seen on how
we can sort of
full attention of plywood emails and
wish I was on chemo so we want to see
annexing with a quick look at is online
polls
so it might take a look online pose that
this lease back teenage in his sights
such as Latin Palace
al Jazeera and of course many random
blog is across the internet
and the usual thing about paula is that
people see the results have been
so possible would try to manipulate and
nationally this is a very very very
ancient tradition people have been
manipulating poll since
a very long time ago under finest
examples were looking at was a
and 1998 example for when the People
magazine ad
the a most beautiful person paw and
United NC
when he was in his prime is Titanic bank
got point 1000 boats
but being detained Hank the angry jump
hank angry chunk of
got 250,000 and
and I just set up an example just 2009
when have moved the bond of 4chan was a
voted to be the world's most influential
person and of course
icon mention this but I'd say they also
sparked marble cake also the game
I'm on their and it is up so should you
expect this to be a South problem me
know maybe they just a trade-off between
a difficult in sign up
person's money but this patient get and
but doesn't quite seem to
so we thought we do is just take a
quickly get one or two and
do two things picking up champ are and
make that option being
by and obviously large landslide margin
ordered more sucking
and may have been my small margin so one
coming in you set up %ah services Paul
daddy
when we talk about it because it's owned
by every single money and poss
everybody and possibly the cat as well
and two be connected up
we should mention be happy to post we
just bought a green bar
now this is an exception exception
interview apollo
which %uh went much boats are simply
just a single Asian request
from a single IP so millionaires any
nothing to this you can sit at home and
do this from your
DSL connection I'm so we just take apart
like this
and kiss you not cursed at all how do
you respond again but better
by percent we can push it up to a to win
by a source Mona
touring to be the leading option by a
small margin and i'm looking as Bishop
Tobin
completely outright so in general Paz
have a PC is credible and
button so so that's because I mean we
can def need them
them admit played some results next time
take a look at
is made it so
on I know from sorry discussions a.m. at
110 as I know a summit is there may be
some it is in the crowd
and she may know how it works but the
first and last pitched a QuickBooks
more for about one minute to just
essentially aside for
posting links and content and having
uses
banking by voting them coming on them
and the most popular post
I'll opium or permanently so bedded
divided golan of sub communities called
summits
and major any focus on a particular
topic on me you know something
and the range from the totally cine like
pictures a bird but on
to the most serious up
world news now people come to figure out
what's going on the world today
soap we take a look at a summit and the
default ordering the QC
is something called the hot scoring a
song in a focus on
so that two factors involved in this in
this particular scoring the one is a
the number votes and I can get to that
settle up first minister Odom both
and be age but across a new articles are
not showing up on public
am we want to do year is
have a summer thing bubbling time do
with making this some kind of polished
going to take up things everyone to
promote but we aren't at the wanton
moat and will do this by uploading and
tankers many people thus it is possible
and that topic so we just want to hide
berry among people not seen an alarm to
that with numbered
but before we can get panned minute have
a need some accounts
so you can sit down easy and using some
open web proxies and
may be solving the captured man yourself
and a day's work
K two hundred or so cards so week eight
if you look on sand
initially an outburst testing up housing
broken they didn't seem to be having the
effect that we wanted been moving within
so the interesting is that but it is
Kenya where
was he trying to stop people gain and
when the thing they do is
they tried to hide the effects are the
your initial votes from you so the have
things like but buzzing they don't show
the actual votes called
by the show's collapsed near that's
there
near the true scope so in yeshiva you
know whether your boat is actually had
an effect take inside and he discarded
and Prevention quickly learning how to
make your much better but it turns out
that wasn't so much a public bus
we just got up at the accountant said
okay well misuse them
and then she doesn't have a large effect
i'm looking for. so
aswan accounts a spa submitted its PDA
not carpenter
unpaid just by person you want and up
putting it so
annette sec I machine him which is AM
pacific summit
am beginning an article up because
there's not that many subscribers are
not that many people boating
numbers I have a smaller but but I lots
a bit like
world news up isn't enough appointed at
some small effect but it really is
enough to make the band pages because
the lot more people involved I mean
world news typically has about six
million subscribers
saw 50 bucks up pretty much a drop in
the ocean but on the other side
I objecting went right down the St so
December insane things that can happen
anytime but besides just knowing the
school
at the first to end things up quite
useful like you're trying to
complete remove an item from the you so
the one option is some sub in a second
pick in lot in a bit more cautious way
and that if not a committee checks if
you down both
that article shunted completely off the
page and into moderation queue
when the summit Monday to and has to
prove it manually before
before it's visible again and it's
beautiful views when I get an article
just one again article quickly in and a
nice option is that
the user submited preference where says
don't show me any articles with a score
below a certain point
and if your votes not that article below
that's cool
that user will not never seen article
and that you you download
and they will never know that they never
saw the article so it's up
quite useful for the sort of thing my
head
shirt 130 downloading them they doing
less cynical trickle-down leading
I experiment by me my head do slightly
more not state board under any
but especially a more subtle version
down during the meeting was
we take an article and look at number up
but it had
and just on the as many with as many up
but at
and so when was nice but this his FB
could takes a bit
up but out targets post everyday like to
met
and continue trickle-down but the others
and
we have some progress in promoting what
we want people to see
time came back to the mess down don't
think so there's a reason why we have to
talk about that trickle-down dating was
because
initially ask the obvious question well
why don't we just take all the bus
vacated and just had them
foundered all the new post that come on
the summit something
that it seems that people should have
already done and she should have
Kelly be expecting so we began with the
up began with the world news and we just
kept but going
and almost immediately people start
Matusz that
to on you Perseus any attracted a whole
lotta
down dirt but then a things
this payment on Novamov delivered more
wilder
man we could have anticipated and on the
side in the post appeared saying hold on
month sub ita under attack everyone stay
calm yeah I can use a comma point
let's keep posting let's keep things
going and
the money is money rate this published a
post
me they said okay guys not happening we
can attack and
and that post eventually got about two
thousand comments
animistic uploaded all the way to the
top a turban page
entire visit site upset cause a little
bit of a stir
the same thing about this post at they
posted buzz that
it's all own words but when it's quite
clear funny
is that the monday tuesday konsi much
about what's going on tell me how much
visibility
among midday Mb even if they did and I
have any power to do anything
so in order anything actually done
inside many disturbing some the actual
site haven't
I'm a while that is all happening behind
the scenes up
the users under on the on that post for
but Mackey speculating
who is this so what is going on now who
could possibly be doing these disasters
things
and some other funny accusations were
that this must have been cute in but
some on one second that only
oneof the or the person being dumb but
except for per rushing past
wishes
I miss not having witnessed on burning
everything an accusation I just
it was innocent people recession was a
mocking intended to be taken seriously
and but one burka should point out that
depth there was a number other down they
can be case that apparently happened
earlier a a few months enya and
including one that happen on our
technology
and we had nothing to do with that
because people kept pointing things they
have no these must be the same people
at we had no idea who the other guys are
we were just a play monday via
estimate an issue to end the same thing
the same damn thing on a small it's a
bit netzer
and it miss Pasha was quite different
Service Inc moderate Isacc in the
essences
internet is by skills and the Kenyan I'd
anything yet okay the country what's
going on
they don't know enough to do to do to do
anything and they don't have outstanding
so no candidate admit talk about and the
summit and
that has been missing because the admin
to comment on this site so we can see
am how they previously game picking this
up and what are the cutest thing was
that
but again posted that they said okay
with anything about 20 bucks and would
disable those
up this is a stage we found by staying
because the
yielded don't at least 50 but that it
and where the others said they not find
them
and the one on the funny thing is that
they said you know
me everything to me that both but we can
tell them because that would you know
help the person running these but so
they just making a bit more clever
but then they go and tell us in the
comments anyway so be
I'm sort of knew that some women
becoming effective the reason why
surprised us back to him
in my surprise that that they respond if
you have them as a ship in any venue any
easy to spot today
and this is many crude so we had hola
but
were voting in the same time that some
the sign up time
comment you know the Manhattans coming
back to named the guy who dis is well
billion fun known
open my box is that you can see in the
Internet use agent have a similar
and credit thingy the account for some
one dimensional then intact but the
distance I
intact without the use it tho that they
should stand up quite a bit
but two months later and
been a change decided so they use to
show the Dundas and they no longer do it
anymore
that's an interesting because a
you can still down both articles but
this time
and uses both seen a donde today only
solve the problem love a dumb burning
it just means that you don't see them
play on sunny make a big fuss when they
see it happening
so it could be signed happening but
their net they had no indication
to check back at that point again late
in the talk about
having data available about what's
happening helps you able to detect
where whether something is going on that
you should do well but
the comeback to the more mission baby
did this but there's one
loss to Ashley with them she just
talking about is there no comment at
this
sup precise like made it and hacking use
is something notion of Commerce which
which is affecting the points that
measure how
and how much it contributes to the site
and now the pub and your contribution
and it's often spoken about in this
mythic way where people say that
you know that despite any come as a
result the incredible hard work
and you know much thoughtful much
thoughtful posting
so we took a quick look at at how could
go personas another cycle hack in use
just to see him you know does may take a
lot of hard work
and we had a hacking his account that
we've been running for about three years
and and posted thank the many many
thoughtful submissions
our stuff we put a really interesting
and that the washington any really
appreciate
but came they didn't because we only got
99 come up with I don't that right
first three years of waste and hard work
instead
or should have done was playing on a bit
more solo index was be
to get 10 line I can skip and what they
did was it just kept on a popular index
from popular blog and because new post
in eighty percent act and use
and the effect was astounded a VIN X 10
months
we go from 99 car points to 8,000 common
point
so clearly and
attend I'm I can skip as much but it
taste in good quality content men than
we do
at but in SF BST the end a bit
we've seen quite a bit about how we can
shut this number option for shutting up
things that we don't want people to see
and promoting thing think at the world
should know about the texting want a
quick look at
is new sites certain sites
make and obvious target right people
come there have been used and what they
see is
for me based on how they make their
opinions what's going on in the world
and we have too much influence on
newspapers in a trial site
but that by up to %uh possum newspaper
web sites that we can't control
cyclic look at many new site they often
have a panel such as this
shows D mostly country most popular
articles on them
and its in newspaper terms it's fun page
and above the fold such prominent
and people at Mackey said question of
what others can mean curtains panel
up and I mean can get stuff on it I
noted ok Angus top of it shut them out
and not have people see them so it was
cut off by taking a quick look at
prominent African newspaper and
they're fun panel looks something like
this: so to most read this kind week
mister moshood articles and
kind week and it said banking is just
pages
but pay his AZ we can control that began
on W get competed in a loop from one box
and eventually will end up doing is
suspending
punch the UN s I on think any do so just
shut off
any other articles that we should do
make it onto the site
in fact say stuff like that for several
days up to its
until the other articles organically
good enough
text him to get back on
an acceptable it was though Wall Street
Journal today have a
last night he def in metric and days
miss is a sort of Commerce said metric a
few
different ranking so they use make sure
our 30 percent from pageviews
up 20 percent Facebook shares been
absent for the shares continue my shares
and Kim said the number of comments that
ice busca so paid used to it now do that
like
did and the PDSA up traditions
perhaps you can do that we had a couple
of a a couple to cast lying on
and passive come to mind that we can get
fifty percent control over
that ranking the one interesting thing
though is that
but to the tradition content to date yet
tells you about
that the company keeps are issue link
a bum time turning to be shared is quite
easy to bump up
TV take a single could use a any
continuously treat the same link
that number keeps going up so you can
keep doing that as much as you want and
you keep inflating the number
mostly general just call that number and
bono
anything happen say out doing that
appeared about seven hours we could bump
an article from
compete in the bottom all the way to the
top even though
and we can actually be diet coke at the
payload I got
up we could pump pump it up anyway and
thanks so take a look at what the New
York Times
so their penalties
most emailed but unlike
others am before we can play on this one
we need
me two cuts on the New York Times in I'm
kinda new time shot
you don't have to share articles so we
took a look at the account creation
process
and there wasn't any captures doing can
you know vacations obviously
very much made a few accounts
automatically and see what we can do
and in the end we end up getting on
30,000 account
and in order to do the mushing and
we could bumping article bombing but in
to bellicose it up
and the same thing about this is that
the
the in thing about this is that they
might dispense
quite a bit on their thereafter menus
getting apparatus
but bus other kicked in the first bus
this was very cheap
I mean we did that entire shipping blind
a fifty-cent
said
its quite a lot of fun and death of an
easy and cheap to midday
what comment heart 'cause show up by
panicky on that most popular
and on a lot on website so the next
thing we'll take a look at
A's comment systems and Markel take us
away from their
Co
so I can read it becomes quite clear as
we get to the so get into this that
manipulating content is is easy
and one other places that people love to
post content on
is the the comments of all sorts of
sites discusses the comment system
its unlike you you've never come across
it I guess if you cross about JavaScript
you probably never seen a otherwise
everyone would have seen it
there any brief a description for
discussing the reason people use it
is because you can take three lines of
JavaScript embed that on your page
and I've got an entire comment which it
that looks good is updated constantly it
does live feeds and saw
so it makes it really easy for content
owners insights to concentrate on what
they're good at which it may be
producing
up blog or board news of some kind and
then the left discuss handle
a the con the comment and their big bike
there
by big I mean sorta billion page views a
month kinda
big 'em I think it's three million
at the time what two million users were
signing up a month for them
so discuss the big play they're not the
only one other there are few others
a but you can see why its attractive to
people
so as I say it's used by blogs a
tumblers soccer mom blogs
up but it's also used by a bunch of
legitimate news organizations
we did this work lost up at the time CNN
Italian
and Al Jazeera with both discuss users
um
Bloomberg next leg next web in a bunch
of others
rely on discuss to handle
their comments and so this is really
interesting from
UTC perspective because when you in bed
comments on the site
what it means is that you control some
other content but you don't control the
entire message
um lot of the stuff on your page is
being produced by someone else obviously
that's different from a Twitter feed
where someone's Twitter page its
entirety their own
this is and that there is a new story
that has some kind of
a built-in of them to steal trust but
part of it a
is the not this and someone to
graphically illustrate this for you
that's a
a screen capture of an entire story of a
CNN dot com
and one long a screencap gonna flipped
on its side
the redline is where on the left inside
that's where CNN and their editors
control the content the right hand side
is where the internet
can put content onto a CNN page i'd and
you can see just visually that split is
quite different
obviously you content for the up the
page gets more
attention but the reality is that most
the content doesn't come from CNN
at all comes from the Internet and so
when we were looking at discuss
again like these are these aren't you
the problems too Turkey's done to
I'm the question as well we won't
discuss users how easy is it to create
discuss users
and what I'm gonna show you with the the
next couple slides
is that the stuff is trivial ike it is
when I said struggle
I mean it's trivial we got one line bash
scripts that can give you 500 a conse-
in twenty-odd seconds I'm so
these are the script the point here is
not to say we can write horrible bass
the point here is that
when I said so online Bhaskar like is
genuinely a one-line Bastrop
I and so we've not got a whole bunch of
discuss users
that we can use to interact with the
site right so
this is side that this video yesterday
are %uh the video was with CNN this is
what the Telegraph
what you've got there's a comment on a
story of global warming that's gotta 176
up votes
um and perhaps this is something that we
don't want
to get prominence we want to bury this
comment and there's another comment that
we won't and its place
so one-line bash script we run it for
thirteen seconds
a we're not gonna up boat another
comment that perhaps you want to push in
its place
on this one runs a little bit longer but
we apply I'm
in this case two hundred votes either
way and then
as you can imagine we refresh the page
the comment that your residence was
right at the bottom
kept so we push that all the way to the
bottom and now
I'm the comment that perhaps who want to
promote gets
inserted at that prominent position so
it is trivial to alter
or influence what people are saying on
a site like discuss up they they've got
issues
a when it comes to us a complete control
with baskets which seems crazy
like where other protection mechanism
the SES
what discussed does is they they need to
provide trusted place
where it is the place for people don't
feel like they're getting completely
manipulated when
when they have conversations so like
it's completely
ham part of what has made this cuz grows
the fact that their
that so few restrictions so you'd like
you can all
I P or user registration is and I P
limited a
you don't have to verify emails they are
some restrictions
if you act as a guest but as soon as
you've got a cookie then you can have
are 500 of thousands of users acting
from
on the same place and even if you've got
it. restrictions
we know that those can be bypassed with
a proxy list
which we did to discuss really has
a serious problems with us and we gonna
look at it life I as an alternative
commenting system I'm they provide
similar services to discuss
and as you can imagine fungible to the
same attacks
at the same kind of things a possible
in in life I so I like it really is
I'm had at the radius
just open right so this is live-fire and
us just pushing stuff to the top of life
I that's for promoting content
you can but stuff down to a move it
in an order in but there's also a
comment in systems are also often have
this notion of flagging content other a
spare time whereas
unsavory content whatever I'm and then
usually that will remove it completely
from
view until it enters a moderation queue
or something and that can happen
discussion life I handle that slightly
differently on the Scots have something
get put into moderation and then gets
allowed
you caught move it back into the market
moderation but live fire has
like basic bikes something can get
kicked a moderation queue
allowed and you can just flag again to
get back into to the moderation queue
I'm so they don't have any history to a
and then in terms of actual other bikes
live-fire
I'm cross of Christ forgery observed
they've got that bug
you you get a life I use it to hit your
website
you can still his life I tote
can and then post up on his behalf but
what makes
those thoughts about quite interesting
for what we're talking about when it
comes to
censorship and and sock puppets is with
a bike like that
you can attract attention for life I
users have them come to your site
get access to the profiles and now you
can have a sock puppet
army which has a history which you
haven't had to book
I haven't had to worry about building up
so those thoughts a bug seem
a and they seem easily fixable
but the their impact when they're not
fixed a it is fairly serious
in terms of what we talk about
withholding sock puppet on his and
I'm not sure how long that was present
in live fire but it took us looking at
sock puppets to
point out that they were CSR affable it
seems a bit strange
so that %uh scrapping the token that's
just posting stuff
on a user but we haven't seen so
common systems by cob kinda rush the
discussed up a little bit
because I'm gonna deal with that some on
%ah but up
both discussed and live fire up pretty
rotten when it comes to trust in what
you can see
and it's pretty clear that the content
that you do see on the site
'em in I well you'd have to be
suspicious
so we dealt a common systems and declare
success there
so in terms of those the three questions
that we often initially
a what can be done what will be done and
what is being done
the question then moves to all what is
being done can we find some puppets in
the wild of people
doing this and like always we go to
history and the sucking up a bunch of
examples of us the 4chan Paul
that we mentioned earlier there's a a
fairly long history of people
manipulation read it
also use inside puppets in the early
days a bread it
the reddit founders were posting content
under
fake identities to make it seem like
that the site had more
support than it did I'm so growth
hacking of some kind if you look back
a there's a fight called common dreams
which is perhaps a little bit less known
up and basically they had
a it was pretty machiavellian so they
had a guy posting
anti-semitic comments turned out that do
dude was a pro-israel guy who is
essentially trying to
make people think that the website was
anti-semitic and in response people
pulled funding from common dreams
up and so that's like a straight talk a
protector a bunch of a const pushing to
view
but in that instance and this is why
attribution becomes really hot
a Minnesota you can swap to a
what what people might be doing it and
in this case he wasn't gonna push a
Proview
he was trying to push a view that said
people don't actually want to be
associated with it
so those are the two things that we're
quite aware of what's up puppetry it's
easy to promote stuff but
there's also the up approaches for
removing attention
again and and this isn't a pic on the
israeli but
the since the we spoke about stuff
getting flack
I'm and this one is just too good to
miss this is from the idea
I'm twitter feed and they're basically
saying like if you don't like stuff like
this about
not up like don't like spam spam
if you don't like a comment then flagged
as spam
because that just removes it from view
so both techniques are
are fairly common and or at least a are
understood in the snow and docs
there was mention of Chaitra group are
tough for the UK
I'm so sort of GCHQ crop
a and according to the docs be there
actively
manipulating online polls for the stuff
is happening so when we thought we were
gonna go look for
the one place given what we've seen is
that
discuss which we played with quite a bit
to that point
releasing to be ripe for picking I'm so
we went there to see if we could find
armies and the initial evidence the
initial
I our initial search in seemed promising
right
so at the time CNN's Most Commented
story
this was the highest ranked comment on
their most commented story
and what you can see it's nonsensical
doesn't make any sense
right the to what this suggests to us is
that people are completely gaming the
system
and CNN was a an interesting example to
their six hundred guests poets
I'm and 46,000 comments
on a story
so our approach when it came to trying
to hunt
Dom be sock puppet on his Ortiz to
detect if they were there
was well let's take a controversial
topic a
yep that's pretty controversial that'll
do within thoughts
we need to find a news organization
that's gonna cover this topic
a and those guys cover art in the
a lot of detail and then
what word is good al Jazeera's up well
we can use the discuss API that but a
really nice API
weekend poll I am a list of all the
popular stories
from the discuss a kite but that were
written on out there up
a and then for each story um
we poll user info for the users who
commented on most stories
and then we want to try and see what
stories to users comment on
we put that into big groff because big
data
and what we get is a scatter plot that
actually be content with like before
we get magic stuff just but there are
others and it never
appear out of that so we tried a few
things
to or three different ways to cut and
slice that particular data
up and then took a step back
and said actually comment on stories are
one way to
add your voice to something but the
other way to affect
actually the thing that we're looking at
is trying to impact whether or not
people are seeing things
not ever if we remember everyone has a
voice the question is who
case to be heard commenting is just the
voice
everyone has that who gets to be heard
is actually voting
it's not commenting and so we decided to
start looking at voting patterns not on
comment impact and so we then
essentially poll
a voting patterns and the metric that we
used
a in this particular instance was the
a Juve the voter commented on
that the age of a photograph voted on a
given comment so we would take
all the top stories for every story we
put it on
all that pic comments that were place
for that story
and then for every comment we pulled on
all the users who voted for those
comments
as a No what you've got other the sub
people who vote
on particular comment on a given story
and we decided to look at the
registration times
of the voters a
and in the final Potter this metric a
few following me so far
a is that we looked at the variation
between the voter age
all voters on comments on a given story
essentially what we're trying to do here
is to say aha similar are
the users who vote on a given story on
the comment on a given story
and one way one proxy for that as well
ha some other creation ages
answer the variance that but you can do
other things you can try and compare
update BIOS and names and all that kind
of stuff but voter age
is a reasonable one up for this and so
we get best each of the points
represents
a story um and the variance about age
on a story so this is a across Aljazeera
and you can see the variances a its it's
all over the place
I'm and we thought would then focus
while actually what we're trying to do
is to safety
if profiles a similar gonna have low
variance so let's zoom and then
on the bottom part of this and will pick
some others pointed round and you can
see there's
a number of stories but very low
variance it could be noise
but it's interesting they also had to a
minimum number of comments
in them so it wasn't like to users on
this
comment of voting on a story and so we
poll
the voters for those comments and there
were a few things that stood up
um just that first glance I'm with that
there was some patents so
41 mostly the accounts were registered
with an minutes of each other
but they were happens within the
usernames the profile name switch to
different and also in the email
addresses
we pull that data and what we can see
their
is a this is the last of the people who
vote
on
comments within a given story and
to suppress gone south of sauce ago
we're not seeing
I am at bay they start to look fairly
regular
but like it's not exactly commenting
back in my heart of hearts
I am expecting hawkeye 69 to appear
somewhere in that this because it's the
Internet
but that just before up
the with four names that's not enough to
convince so we decided to keep but
email addresses are a an interesting
aspect for discussed they're not a
requirement but
I'm you have to supply when it sign up
but they don't have to be verified
so if we could get the email addresses
for those profiles that we looked at
then there was a possibility that they
might be patten's there
but discuss doesn't give you the email
address the user that's a
private information a so we went looking
I we found an unmarked attack that lets
you get the email address to discuss use
up
son of a given random discuss use a you
control them
and their private mailbox wanted to a
and looked a little
little bit further and found the inverse
a given someone email address
up your friends or your family or
whoever you could map that back to their
I've discussed use and I'm a both of
those are reported affects oh that's no
longer possible
but we use them for our work and that
led us a lot
email addresses for the sock puppets a
and they had this very regular happened
as well first name surname
at Shemale the cop okay saw suspicion is
starting to grow
but the fires at the number puppets have
been fun seem smaller than we expected
like it was 17 and we thought well if
you will if we were running a sock
puppet army
we wouldn't just do it with seventy up
so we thought we'd try and in numerous
and like there's a buncha text there but
the point here is that
discuss gives you a every users are
finding his idea it's just a counter
so we can take the use ID's a pic the
users that we know about the sock
puppets let me know about
we just increase asserts pace a little
bit on either side others and we gonna
enumerate a bunch of users
for all the user that we download all
the information for which includes email
addresses
we then
I am we then apply the the patent that
we already know about
and see which of them match that happen
so
top be pulled in for five thousand users
a
we apply those falters a and what we've
got
was actually quite nicely faltered a
list abusers and they do start to look
very regular up
like what's the packing up some
softening on a text that so
if you look at that list its ordered
right
so the list looks like it's ordered a
and it looks like it's ordered by email
address
but it's not it's all about time
registration time
and it's quite striking that its order
by registration time but
the names are alphabetical the email
address of a pedicure
ordered so like that really does suggest
to us
that not even suggest us like that
sought to become pretty clear
that someone's got names but text and is
putting stuff other names top text
but just to convince a little bit more I
bus Crawford or the scatter plot is
shown you
a the delay between registration times
up the spot so stop gets registered
how long is it before the next one
analyst has registered and again you can
see you
it's very tightly constrained I'm and
effectively it's a Toronto asleep five
seconds as
and someone script so credit crackpots a
C-five create the next one
a and so that's the majority of them
that the one that the top right also
quite interesting for us
up its above a sidebar but effectively
we had must at that point wanna be
registration events in the Middle
so we sort of thought they were 10
seconds between those registration event
but actually there was one at five
seconds in the middle that a halt at
that point had been picked up
so we've got a bunch of attributes that
we a
that we can falter these accounts on and
discuss lets us what we can go a little
bit further
because discuss then says well given
user names you can find out whether
actor but and this is where the the
puppet army stuff starts become
quite active so for every user in that
sock puppet on me we polled on all the
comments they made
and we then crossed into this time the
graph makes a little bit more sense
a in total that post about
seven-and-a-half thousand comments
our about 7,000 comments rather of which
five and a half thousand were posted
to CNN it's a really active on CNN the
next one was
there were active on Al Jazeera with
about 1000 comment
and then the next one the next biggest
ones to under comment so you can see
this
a sock puppet army is read your the
active
in only two major places 'em and clearly
are
are quite active the other thing that we
find quite interesting as this row on
the bottom
all profiles that up part that they've
been
them at all the photos but they've never
been used a and so
we can we can only guess at that point
either they're being held in reserve
or they lost access to them because they
were just a cookie in the cookie got
lost or
got locked out whatever the case is up
but its a
is sort of the the coordinated action
along the ones that were actually in use
is
for us quite interested okay
so as I said we can we can pull off the
comments made by the users
and discuss had another bug at the time
which said that
if you mock to a profile is private you
could stop hold on the comments for
the private profiles actually private
profiles meant nothing a
now they had a few issues as you can see
but what he did was he pulled out all
the user comments
and again that starts because come quite
interesting so just six different users
or post in the same
comment so this notion of duplicates
exists
within at least the the puppet army that
we saw but it's less than you expect
Saba seven thousand above the seven
thousand on comments that they posted
the duplicates were in the order of
1000 1500 there were lots have any
comments there was a lot of
effort that went behind as Papa army
it wasn't a and the comments 2i
appeared to be reasonably written they
weren't they didn't look like they were
the result
of I'm a text generator so team like
someone is putting a lot of effort into
this crop is also
a it's just kinda messy but it shows the
links between users
and common sense trying to give you an
idea of
duplicate comment but there were a lot
of okay
so we've got that fall to we can see
that these guys
active on a the same places
a and like at this point we're pretty
pretty convinced so this is for the
results of the house
that particular pot army of sock puppet
army up to 190 60 them
they were active at the time when we at
the work to active had been active for
months
7,000 comments I'm of which
on an offer to pick up sup coming back
top picture of that CNN page and this is
this is actually one other
the stories that we look set you
remember we flipped on the side
that's where the dividing line is and
all of that
has bought activity sock puppet activity
so this is
the default this is the default a
comment like this is not a strange order
anything
up and Ike one analogy for this is what
if you control that much comment
and someone randomly schools dob they're
likely to land
into one of your comments right that's
the knots lead for
a sock puppetry is it just pile them and
their
and someone will see something that you
want them to see elect what are the
other stats for that
is all the top-level comments only four
percent were not
sock puppet comment on that story for
CNN
CNN's comments are pretty on and not by
us by
someone else up for the question then
becomes a what are they saying what are
they trying to push
I didn't skip that intentionally
a it bears a few things that come out
and quite interesting the one is that
the pews are consistent so we didn't
find instances of the puppets
disagreeing with each other what that
suggests to us is that
there any I'll try to promote a message
rather than just cause havoc
I'm the views of a multi-faceted so it's
not a
on a single viewpoint just try to be
pushed so for example
up while they are pro palestine an anti
I sis
there also anti-obama right and Sabina
been anti I sister not necessary
congruent with always been anti-obama
a or vice versa so Bell multifaceted
views that this group is trying
to push and so then
inevitable question is who is this and
this earth where we
absolutely pull away and said no idea I
get anything in this field is pure
speculation
attribution is hot just when it comes to
network is activity
when it comes to what people are
actually writing um
thats that's a problem that we
introduction to Hospice of
at this point so there's a few ways out
of this we could shut down the puppet
army
rights are lots of their email addresses
went even register to you could register
man address behind the puppets I'm and
then
can access to but that seems like a lot
of work a
the one thought that comes out is that
discussions thought
limiting their API and limiting the
information that they publish in their
API
but we think is a bad idea you'll notice
that we found the thing on the site
all on the on the service that provides
us with the most information
rather does not provide you with
information
Asian and so you cannot locate talk
puppet armies usually on reddit
a and there's a bunch of examples for
that discussed gives you access to the
data
and that lets us who don't work that all
and who are doing this
um in our own time we confine the puppet
arms
so for us but that thing is important
but
the new 52 taken a different approach
they're just facing our comments
for CNN los a phase-out comments
Jazeera's face top comments
on there's a bunch of sites Reuters is
moving away from its
a Rico it and and a few others so they
are not seen the value in having user
comments because of
the influx of that so
let's just quickly summarize and have
come a full circle farm
making out and suck a ban on and finding
others
finding finding others that make to take
the same shortcuts and worse than we do
I'm so without exception I'm and
assessments have just proven
absolutely should be able to manipulate
and within they work but not
because it's important day to be aware
that so that we can begin to build tools
to help deal with it
but just on that last point before we
begin building caught up do with it
its it's worth noting met marker pointed
out as well
that having that data available at hand
and helps Katie
and trying to figure out to if anything
suspicious gonna
thank you the
tho
thanks very much higher I was think I
take one question
just us to offer the opportunity I
on time
to I'm back to 100 K am just just a
question how did you do your test birdie
two prominent
did you inform a paper was the black box
staff there always was it
did you choose your returns are allowed
it to do that yes this is so the test
was informed by
um how would we do it like if we're
trying to influence the stuff what other
the sites that we would do up we
so like in this field and it's a bit of
a cop but in this feel like if you if
you tell people that
you gonna do the test then like your
your pre informing them
up so when we didn't store at this in
the mail in the sand and the other ones
with installs
a who likely when keeping track of
particular users
and their cliques um for discuss week we
inform them and they were a they were
okay with that um and fact we're
interested in the work
up but know in terms of how we we do
that we didn't
stop by approaching customers all
companies and requested
like yeah just did it okay so
Marco %uh thank you very much very true