so very homework come to look Arcata
Tony and modal
genteel we r we're already making some
kind of jokes
also last name add credit card if the
nickname because
I think the meaning of the last name is
like a being kind
yeah tomorrow can't the gathered for
tomorrow kind I am
they will a give a talk politics
a by the ability and the Flex SDK
compiler
I am that boss as far as I just wrote
already a known in the past and
race up again now so
you're on stage to stop I
thanks I like a marijuana looks like a
private setting size for her
I mean just ask question and drop as if
you're a fan of
have montel Noah be more I
were very happy to be here I we were
looking for a conference
but when we you know were close though
the
you know releasing the details and then
I we wean so NAS history for troopers
however happy day we manage
there was a lot of disclosure involved
in nine days research though
was complicated to put all the pieces
together ever
really what we're happy to be here and
have a thing was
when was properly in and made I
so my name is Luca I need the security
team assessment team
idling Dean I at base in Mountain View
Calif
and that today here communities mauro
argentina has an obligation to consult a
I wouldn't mind that security I anytime
consulting com paying for his own band s
and security I am
despite the names you know the first
letter are the names Luca
and so the Al and I am we're not the
region Mario I am
what else I am I
of course I usual disclaimer I
I you know our company data and/or
stills hurts
%uh miss our on find a view
and yeah I'm goes I
so Creek agenda for today so weak I
corporate be no introduction on same
origin policy if you own web security
is probably always to you but otherwise
it's you know it's make sure that we are
on the same page
and then a be no details around a
vulnerability analysis
um I their patch that the
a dub it really is and you know the
reversing around there and then
probably the most interesting Pira I
would perform an internal I scan
for partisan ability um as you will see
I am E it was complicated and we we
discover festival are meaty then
later on it was patch reported by an
army was someone else
and so are we gonna see I'm all all this
course is
so I started I think it's it's natural
that every time
someone present a security conference
diesel West in a starting point
and four oz was something like that I
you know 10 Haas
and I want disclose who is cool %uh send
a message that they are saying well I be
sitting on a bar from mom
I'll I do something about that right and
the outer my reply well I've know about
you know prior life I have no life so
what white onto you know when we start
using a bug and and and play around
and how we start playing and then you
know
one for some you know was fasting and
not a thing was working
because he was using you know some test
case there were any patch buy adobe
the other one was not and sell where
basically chopping all the time saying
get drunk you are
get them or yes it works aside may I was
is was by computing
I you know mind-blowing I'm in there is
something that I i cum on you
had to go cho et today and and and and
kinda my suggestion is
on whenever you're working on something
and you get an idea
just 90 da like taking a lot you know
not bad are at
text file on your high systemic Google
Docs whatever
II file you know very spying
I'm to basically no da but when I have
an idea
and then obviously we all be easy but I
have time to investigate this anyway so
you can get back in we actually a
you know started to sing to a few mom
probably years ago and then
can we left everything and then a.m.
started again
recently so um that that's that's our
kid
answer quick introduction I am
so Adobe Flex air which is now a hatch
back so i dominated the
can't I could best tune to the Apache
foundation in 2011
it's an Open Source SDK for building as
we file
cell you're probably familiar with he
knows we file you can be is going to be
less we file in two ways
can use pure ActionScript that's their
traditional way
at some point and I'll be realized that
at they needed to be and
account better frame or anything a
framework where you could basically
specify
up magician through I XML
obeys files and an actual skinny for the
actual code
and so when you combine a sphinx and you
build using their Flex compiler
I you miss can obtain air file that can
be played by the same Adobe Flash Player
um so not out not all as the BS filed a
you would find on the internet
are flexibly cation iron by Moss
keynesian when they are
actual applications are not not just BDO
or you know and missions
most likely its gonna be a flex file I
yeah so I any interest in things which
is basically where where we started
looking and the other at this bank is
the
at some point at all be decided there it
would be interesting to have a
dynamic localization right so if you
have an application for defriend
languages a you know it would be
convenient to have a mechanized to have
as you can see on the ride a placeholder
for spicy crashed train for example in
this case for a label
and then have on day on day left side
I you know different property files the
biggest specify
and and named a new pair I'm so that you
can have basically different an
organization resources depending on the
language
I'm and so
to be a localization into flexibly
cation they are basically two ways
one is compile everything in as one only
defile
see we have a huge file all resources
every means they're
or on for obvious reason you to make
sure that you you know you can have as
smaller
files I you can extend application
without recompiling
everything from scratch they decided to
enable also
a dynamic localization so at there is a
specific component
that is that basically when you compile
s we file
they as the kid a compiler have wrapped
around your file a brief
I am some components and what it does is
it a source module
she's basically the yelled into décor
cormack in his to load a a prime-time
the composition resources I'm
the way you use at a data source mod
your ass for flash far so I can up on me
I wish a
flash a YouTube is gonna if you want to
pass arguments to flash file
use flashvars a so you basically have if
I'm eating too
for example an object I and then you
pass a value
and so if you pass a value chorus a
small you what else
you would be basically able to pass I am
as
and dynamic localization so in this case
we're passing
a you know English we file the factors
and the localization
and there's a small dose are is an
uncommon to break the lease of your
house
or resources and you probably know
already where we are going here
I
quick quick slide on ass same origin
policy for the lobby
its slightly different than a
traditional salvaging polishing browsers
so a is example Robins AF
I i'm I have air as we filed on a
specific domain let's say he don't calm
a busy a dot com as we file can access
everything on a knock-on
on there is a the possibility to cross a
region interaction
and the way you do that is basically on
the second remaining to specify crosna
an XML file
Misskelley allowing on other file file
to you
accident or Sunday domain so oppression
will slow a
can access our stop on be dot com on the
phony
a you know you specify a they do Asian
demand in across the main file
om and one is pretty in pink is that
s on I you know i i flash file can
can send it should be any questions
allowed to send it should be request to
a sports guy website
on you physically get you know and
before the fall a the phone deal right
now you can send it should be depressed
the browser will have to give ya stay
cookies you would get back response a
cell
you're basically you know in control of
all
you know and try and tiring of
confession retrieve
I'm and if you're sharing web security
you probably remember a diff levels in a
flash
where basically videos to abuse and
Jason a mare p.m. point
to you some to be skinny reflect as we
file
in the in this case was an autonomic as
we file that would deal
I basic any a DNA checking so would
would send the requested a web site
and then retrieved and private data I am
USC a we will be basically using the
same
affect my cousin and his way in a sense
that up
you know we'll be sending request and
then
rushing responses that offers any
content data
on up into getting user on I guess
I did it's it's a it's very well-known
rob is the day if you will
if you upload their flash file a in on
your domain
on and it's not separated out whole from
your primary domain
and you know those are user supplies we
file
people can trigger cross escaped Inc %uh
you know that's not a surprise
and so people up Don you know use the
front counter measure
a sandbox the mains you know that's what
for example Google Docs
away user supply content goes to
completely from demands on
are forcing the you know download
through company's position and now
they're
other techniques I you'll need to take
care about
polyglot and parking lots I means filed
that I like a combination with a 5-4
from you know would be far
by be there I us you know where you had
to give I animated gif and that whatever
and and a jar file
on cell there has been a lot of research
on Sol polyglot filed for a sweet um
is just like a yeah genetic overview so
up
I we know that their web page can ask
blacks
ops 2 node resource more jobs there's a
small joke it can be a URL
so I mean it's you know it's easy into
managing that did you know what if
I try to load as we find from a
completely from the rain
cell that's what we did a back back to
I don't even remember you know how many
month ago I and the
or years ago probably and a.m. works
and so are you no big surprise was like
wow business seems like a very bad
things that happen
and then um yeah we need a we didn't
investigate for about that time
and at some point on when we started
studying in israel army t
we discover that out of the past eight
so I
we basically a find out today at all
bitterness the page
at patching to November 30 from
wage medically describe a very smart
thanks in this case was marked as across
it like universal across a skin thing
basically
I and we're going to details um
I know I i'm well when discovering our
media at that stage we didn't really
understand what was going on
I am and sell someone you know disclose
these things before before 12 so
I am props to whoever discover many and
LB
security team I am but I i find you know
we're very cute because
imagine you're doing a secure their
search I for sure you don't have time
gotta stop
I you understand there's something wrong
but you don't know exactly what's going
on
and then up some biases secure the visor
so the first thing to know is
you know getting today details and
trying to understand what's going on
I so we start against INR
the revitalize their sarge and so on
you know the example is you take as a
source mod URL
you specify and ask them how much we
file
and that DNA is your you ask the meeting
you know you lead the meeting low then
urged him out page
loath to source more George as a flash
car ion
and then as well as she disobeys gain
red mmm
leads to air is gonna same region policy
bypass I
so there are different expeditions an
area that we analyzed I am
a.m. day most interesting one
considering the current browser
implementation and Flash Player
again is that is there a bug and that's
the case so
and you know my work over disaster aid
is very interesting
aspect and tell it with the latest
browser and latest Flash plugin
the most interesting moment he well I at
Aki's
the same region request forgery where
you basically can stash to be quest and
read entirely to content
up and I think that we investigate it
was about you I
addressing so what if you with a SoC
modern you control
stinks right what if I'll you can create
fishing props
or somehow trade you know misleading
warning by basically just changing tax
spacing and other things right as so
that there's also something that we we
we played a round bead and then
I December December December ability in
order freshen of Flash Player
was basically a universal across
escaping I
because he was possible to pass the time
to from there
from the URL arm so 01 Sep back so if
you
if you load F clash file data from the
URL of the browser
the browser would basically
automatically create an HTML page
to buy their plate right where it's
basically loading an object
as we file and so on if everything is
campaign as a as you know has quite a
string by me there
basically gonna get I averaging five
belonging to that specific domain which
again that's the reason why leads to
across a scripting
on
in current version of of plaques
you cannot I Lord I saw small jewel from
the crash think
and so that's that's what breaks the
universe ask us a skating
and trust formed these things into
morass same origin
I you know request forgery counts thanks
I
we actually dunno if it's such a cute in
mouse Pandora Box I
again when we start investigating we we
analyze that on
on recent version that was the deal we
found on their
out a center for our heart Dhabi a some
people complaining about you know the
bill stop and was not working
and they officially apply was the
child's we file
I they are loath a long time sometimes
fail and it's a known bug
and it's not gonna be fixed I am at
and sell dissolution has been skinny at
specify other source mod US House within
an object so
in inside HTML um which again eight
minutes into the impact on the community
we have found a situation where
application are using custom bra purse
and so you still gotta universe across
skating but thats something then and the
opportunity really need to
a spend time on its own on
so I have hauled his attack on you know
same engine across 4G works
on the day is yet you let you know
you know that the victim I browse the
web site and then you basically
force the user to load your arbitrator
source
and then these are source I which
inherits their
security domain of up there the target
on fan then it should be crushed we have
cookies and everything
guess the data and potentially send back
did it out when the attacker
I'm would have been more details when we
have
is at how you're browsing the web
watching
cap you know BDO or you know unique arts
whatever you like
and then you go to iron ghetto and
affordable side login
and you're getting your stop at some
point you go to attack our site
um man browsing the web it's been going
going through
third party sites though 'em no big deal
here
I Bay a fireside well send you back an
HTML page
which basically contains an object tag
that includes
the region of flash file that is on
hosted on: deplorable side
and their sophomore year which is Austin
on the attacker site so
I step 3: include available as we fight
is because the flash filing
get sparse then played by the browser I
data and start loading and then
because it's using this as macho it was
fats their
I and we try to fetch data source model
from day
doctor side but first things is
obviously checkin across the main
can the 10 most side flash file retrieve
resources from the talk aside side
I am a and so we r we are managing have
him here right
minutes it's asking for across the main
on get back your site so
I am we have basically specifying
you know at why card every domain is
allowed across the main tool not a
problem here
on add a flash fire gets downloaded a
Los
an accident but at this point I mean
it's a arbitrage oscar-winning
catskills getting inside a browser us so
we can fetch private data from the one
about side and on them
being for today at Tucker I
be more detail about the called I that
provoke on today we made
and that's a simple consider we disclose
to all website
on so on the pub to see the landing page
so this is a page and you would with
these it as a victim ride and cell are
the bottom just an object tag
where you'll see it again prime either a
flash flood per meter
would evaluate a source module that is
all set on ebook com
which is you know our conditions going
for fund attacker
and then %uh if you notice that is there
another URL I'm either call from me it's
a mess that thing so I may be
complicated but it basically nothing up
on meter
which is an argument of our lunches we
file
against enemy and why why we need that
on
I on the top of failed the test the HTML
you also have a tax area I we fare class
city
axe I as he was in a second is simply
at way for us to display the content on
the page again as approval content
you could replace that part way if and
other jobs can that sense
and information to a third party website
or whatever you want to do
I the bottom yet across the XML
I was the I access for I
on all sites and so do the genetic
payloads thought we build their
a flash file packs filed there was
basically
a.m. doing the actual logic opted get
talk you know what what you wanna do is
a
and as an attacker so on up there the
first heard the first thing that we
ion highlight it's been going to get
into your apartment or from
from that it's possible to flash viable
and ADAS
we wanna have an automatic way of saying
fetch the specific URL
farmed a victim domain from there you
know target domain
on so that we could reuse dispense water
what I'm and
and on the bottom which is probably most
urging part is I
after a you know be up this ashen skin
fetches the URL
again we cookin everything gets back the
response we want that said the content
that we retrieved from the target side
to back today attacks a.m. area that we
have so
well we're doing simply replacing well
adding a better two day element
Wi Fi Deacs angered on am
again at that point you could
potentially send to other third-party
you know you probably do something
different if you really want to explain
his fangs
um term so we go we got done a damn I'll
maybe before before we start with the
demo on is the following the clear a
high level like if there's any question
now I think it's
it's better to be sort out everything so
that after we can proceed with the day
most in an hour thanks
so far so good I okay
sonya so before proceeding we wanna show
you a brief them all
in which actually we are trying to all
its a exploit
a CB 2010 461 testing amount
so actually up as a skill to have
are ISA web application host on
Ely on example dot com which makes
carrey allows users to lobbying
ans
yeah so miscommunication
allows users to lissy you are self
lights a
the commute flies in the car so
surprised
I obviously to concede a first name and
last name their mobile number
and they cancel change updating on
password
so actually as a concedes his hi
flexible occasion
a and it is I it iz
developed in a way that as a conceit is
possible to change deal
language so it makes so I by noting
up to Rs as model I at runtime so the
point here is that
is there any chance for a back at all
the same steel some prodding from
nation by exploiting the fund at the
supplication this for executions
wanna battle scene he 2011 2461 and
so let us assume that's I hasta meeting
to be easy to
before compass before concept webpage
hostile haven't gone
than as you can see medically I have a
doc on
is able to ask yourself how information
about you so it's just the first name
this
the second inning its mobile number and
the Antichrist a bespoke any
which is used for I changing his
password
so just to be clear I actually had
seized the
I HTML peach shows are
all the park works so the first thinks
that example up
the I mean to call makes I I'll a
MST a money LSAT winnable
35 which is flight reservation that
beats
ASCII two loads I and excel at a sudden
address is not in which is hostile
haven't gone and there's a lot to me
said
hey I guess request to beyond what beach
the page which contains some private
information on menus and
this and s obviously all-star acceptable
call
and a as you can see him Firebug
so actually are the S's Mobile
is loaded on I dot com does inquest told
the car bombing attacks on my heart
having those com
sings the quest is coming from example
dot com and they are
bureau missions as a model makes a
request to hold PHP
I in which it says and its actually it's
able to
a start some pro information about the
user's and a
uses which are looking so just to prove
that this
prefer constant really entertaining work
I can look out i can refresh the page
and
haven't gone and actually demolishes
automobile is upon Senate meeting
is not not be 0
so yeah 0 so at this point I ask why
interesting to
are to investigate to understand how
hard on the posh such issue in 2011 and
actually
up I W needs to take note in which are
hearing is a tool he reported
I'll developers can understand why don't
they Sui fires have my number not
and it also released at all wish
basically last one but if I whether you
asked we find some global
and it is also able to lissy up
to up pouch doubles we find a Swiss
fights we now need to recompile me up
but the crucial point is that it is
necessary to bash the
applications to protect users need a and
actually this is quite unusual
when dealing with flashbacks seen
Sweeney are we use to see that
Adobe usually freaks fixes up
security backs by Putian nerdiness I'll
in the Adobe Flash Player itself but in
this case
the the patch does not affect the Adobe
Flash Player
but instead of extreme abuse and this is
very interesting since abuse
this means that it is possible to
exploit are
levels we files a in forty password
brazzers
and with another special Adobe Flash
Player teens
durability is bashing
flex from recordings and martini I don't
push me a
I'll yeah as assays I actually have to
be provided a reliable tool training too
quickly identifying
the whether you're Sui 5 someone will
not
and we I investigated such to
not to wonder somehow the
were parched process works up
so actually a week we r up
we were interesting I'll as a saint
although be passed as she should and
we try to pass I step occasions I mean
when I move Flex applications which one
bashed by using the official Adobe
patched or
which I'll be honest units on techno and
by testing such
a Flex application sweeney understood
that we figured out that addresses
models
drought he married Miss embeddings Sui
for you anymore
in the case of past a Flex application
and this means that
it is not possible to exploit such issue
i in the case of
flexible a iced flexible occasions
%uh live up of heart all these may look
very clear this point we needed to
reverse the patch
I know the 21 to make sure that we
really understand what's
what was going on scenes doing the first
that the first
tests we were seeing some and see
inconsistencies
among the foreign nationals on the same
Flex application I mean
are we were seeing that forty salsa a
flexible cation
was looking up Atlas we've model schools
to me
where some other swell not at actually
this was
the expecting BM your as the first one
worse and web hubbell 2cd 2011 24 61
where the second one well not so
I in order to lissy were we were
another 20 understand the CD %ah
a
which was the part in the Flex framework
which room up
a which leads home BBT we needed to
adopt a specific methodology which which
is showing a slight
so we took to two different versions
let's say two versions of the same place
a petition sampled the first one will
know more
to this issue the second one passed many
Adobe Buchtel that we've compiled the
as we files and we def them and once we
got
the freeway people to understand what
the networks are skeptical and
and much I mean are dishonest to hun Sen
up
once we identify the passion we are also
able to identified a bootable called
ice the patch was applied to actual skip
to the global action script called
yep so in the end we prove that's how I
put scenes together with security some
boxing at us was indeed correct
and I me less youth yeah
so that up as you can see a high missus
the same the part all the Flex framework
you wish to reliability
was hopping so wearability
a took place I in the load meddled
on the class movie looking for a by ear
see
the compiling Abu nobles we five we were
able to
you such source and basically
the shoe square CZ scenes up a
actually the up departments we file is
loading
the a child's we fire by setting a is
security don't secure domain to its
current to me and
the schools that the child's we finance
inheriting be
security domain how the parents me for
this quite easy
are as you can see in the case by in the
case of have passed
refile I mean as we find which was
passed by using Adobe official bar stool
are actually up we can see that Adobe
patched
this issue by introducing a kind of are
always high school always course
completion
I wish mescaline does not allow to went
unbeaten
you branch and and this means that the
security to me i've
child 34 is no septal skewed to mingle
Q&A me know
department
fun and I mean to sis
the bus service this August but
I it goal is dust on the sandwich is the
point of the
Flex framework I wish D a
ActionScript code you know what actual
scapegoat was
a worse no
so okay from
policy from a say it is important to
note at this point that
arm I'll let's say developers
and us site administrators can protect
against such issue
and basically doughtery help shins the
first song is so sorry to recompile
nobles we find another subpar
Apache flex flex has the key by
including static libraries
and as we know that the letters version
of her but your Flex SDK
a it's not horrible such issue another
possibilities to posh T Mobile's we file
by using your BB official
Buchtel and this seems to be
quite reliable at least during our
experience
do you know what's best and well
the last the last option as: the by
is sexually to believe the when I was we
fires
if they are not used anymore are
well glass suggestions that you should
know he likes you across the Middle take
some of our
but its its a quite common security
I good practice
ohs so just to look up what we have we
have since
till now so we had to have a coup bug
but it turned out to be using your money
back so
CDT 2011 sick 24 61 was bashing the Flex
as the K but a is Cassie be exploiting
a 20 bash liberals in with the latest
version of Adobe Flash plugin
a not technically does somebody is
preclusion where
ever published and successful
exploitation also sheesh you move leads
who
matisse to managing I'll ceremony June
it was foggy
but also our costuming across site
content jacking
so that the stealing hands
action for me a so
a so I despite the better question is is
there any chance to catch memorial will
flicker
cations after four years I mean yup
after four years since though we passed
such issue in 2011 so
a in order to reply to this question we
need to win a sale to meet will bring a
beaded
session process so first we needed to
identify a balloon
a when I was we filed by using a
protected from the mighty fashion in
order to do that
we needed to be the tall a was name yes
about 10 G
a we needed to house misconduct internet
appalled at that point
we used a and modified National Park
Angie
which was which was using selenium know
that I'll to meet a real well but also
to downloads we find a sweet JoJo stand
up to gonna talk to me
to follow them into process them and up
to 2500 they were
affordable not to so she should I was
really needs to
repeats us such operation multiple times
with multiple computers
for Haney see I
for any targets
the me 272 October so we have here
speed up to that point was like okay we
do we need to speed up
so for the about the
let's say the first and second points
are we
obviously need to lissy understands how
to find a way to wanna say discriminate
among vulnerable to the files
and Nobles we files and are installed at
we wanted to
focused on dat part which is wonderful
tool
which makes a has Wi Fi wanna more at
the score
this is as as a portent before it is
lamentable
and modeling for class so what we need
we basically I analyze the ABC which is
the access key by schools
for I 10 below normal levels we fires
is allowed us to SAE are
to detect some part asking the
ABC duties to disassemble Heckscher
scripps called
a we each proceed to find the persons
hardy when ability
so once we got are be abc party pop
trance hitting the ABC
very bottom be there to which simple
tool it's a
country me assemble cold and tool
a to file some to find the spot on the
ABC so to
you would percent part Angie which is
the two
accustomed to we wrote to
which basically a law school I identify
whether I'll
whether a thank you once we finalize
winnable home not
to TV he 2011 but 2461 it is written in
Java
it is composed by just by a single jar
and
it can be used as a commonly used to be
but also as a bar Pro Plus but it's kind
of like
it obviously uses as we stomp
the other two created disassemble action
scripps
disciple so to count re: the the elite
from the because it belonged up so what
one thing is that
if you're I wouldn't be surprised if you
go download the plugin
in AU
use a curl and your you know bashful
scripting and download file and then use
the common line or
that only prober I actually wouldn't be
surprised by the end of the conference
you will actually find
a formal file I mean you will see we
need a wide interns can but then there
are so many website
out there so I am so
a display name we want to assure you
I'll established that more about us
about distal ans I'll
a sickly this possible to use it as a
commonly utility
so in this case back going to my local
webserver
homes yet its
basically can take as input as we file
ok I'll take a simple to
to a directory containing multiples we
files
and this case its was able to understand
the players wishing to order to use the
Flex application used
in the first demo is wonderful tool such
issue actually
so the Disick distal has a built on the
same whether the
Flex application was compiled with an
old version of the STK
and therefore is winnable or whether
itís
it was passed by using the Adobe
official patch to all-weather into use
it was combined a/c up original version
of the Adobe Flex SDK whole
party a party for assisting as the key
obviously the USS
amadio in this case disease their
addresses on this call her
at me han underscore US his team agent
present value and obviously it is not a
Flex application
ahh your so
you can also use it as or bar pool
busing SCANA planning so in this case
I'm setting
bahco as a local proxy so
this is coop actually indeed extender
up apollo 10g as being lobbied
I soon disabled intercepts
down come looking days to
web application we use them the first
demo I'll
yeah so I can switch to to the bar pro
and as you can see Park immediately
identified each issue and a I'll just
work
best Glee 0 the bar pro
buses Connor use the
looks for up a bus who looks for Bruno
for a Sui fires in the balls in your
browsing history
and if if visible time prime
from find someone this its a
bus assist them to the same the custom
in gym
which use actually part engine and
if they were on what do your petitions
considerable damn
about Mb and a little discomfort
just for the sake of completeness has
gone see
in the house five fields 5 I'll does
a candle lock about switch Rd we follow
us
which one analyzed by
by the
to the expansion and what else
0 yeah but looking on startup articles
0 before you can also see you want or
what was going on
yumm the same scanning process bomb
who wanted to proceed tweet which with
the presentation
so are
so between October and December 2004
Wisconsin a few interesting to me is for
detecting levels we fight
so it's kinda top 50 Alexa up
Adobe dot com and many sites running a
bug bounty program
and well %uh at the end of the day we
broke the gym tonight we therefore he is
old
when ability that was maybe never
are deeply investigated deeply so never
funny understand
and never surfaced so as you can see we
identified
a noble flexible occasions on
many hyperfine website as a casino
slight
but also many others which are not
reported
in this and a slight so cool
our so just to prove
just to make you %uh
understands so
a we just want two percent a a brief
demo and about
wish we we brought a proof-of-concept
against I'll be dot kom I'll
and which we were trying to steer single
sign-on tokens
I'll in order to let a steal some
private information about us
use a switch are looking audible.com it
does have been using seat was botched by
Adobe a few few days ago
weeks probably weeks yeah so
in this case I'm like being with my
personal account on
Obama got on bicycle seemed us mara are
yeah
to this is my account
so at this point I I'm assuming that the
victim
yes us to to use it to my nieces web
page that these
nearly past the post on I mean but calm
then its me since the crucial concept
web page
and as you can see your
so as you can see the by exploiting have
10 balls we file host on Adobe dot com
we were able to
assistance up rowing formations and
that's a very information about them
victim which use love being no we don't
go and
such as its email use a
first name his a last name and these
moment number so the POC is quite
interesting
scenes are as you can see
its in this case basically
%uh money she is a resident model
which is host on heavy disco mixer for a
sleek westall
oh that to me use up
this domain and this domain
actually selves some
a single sign-on web services and
policy %uh by making a request to add
this to mean is possible to steal
are single sign-on to me this happen and
single sign-on
at a single Saratoga and them be money
she says a lot to me to
sequin request second request to another
single sign-on to me
bypassing the just want your talkin this
this request and as you can see
the response to this up to the second
question
took the second up request
actually contains the information we
she's reporting to text area
where you can see a which is called
mixing victims neither so askew
a diesel at this quite interesting to
note that
the work process to work for concept
works scenes yeah so
be domains which are I
which are hosting the single sign-on web
services
are reporting such cause to me don't
text him out so
they are defining a past with respect to
your bubble column
to me and these mean that this means
that
a 35 which are hostile not only dot com
can access also be
which is fast on the settlement and the
system is online 21
befor concept works sings these we find
him
money just as a model he's noting the
booming
the excuse and most of the yellow dot
com but can still makes
make a request to so that two singles
and albums
obviously I'll
the same use for
seconds from single single single single
me
so yeah
okay
okay so assay before we reported the
Swan ability to many high-profile
security mus
up we provide a specific proof
specific proof of concept we also
provided the first national park Han Ji
and we hope to provide is I PDF we
a all its all the details haha research
anymore he tumbled party was him for
on a potential disclosure indeed once we
reached
a consensus we identified an appropiate
is crucially it is actually me and
up I was me up there are many there are
still many more
web sites but I'll hosting winnable flex
applications so I was suggesting is just
to try to use I want to
apart ng2 identify these
is global Flex applications to get in
touch with being bored secure teams
to report them and two more well just be
pedicle
and to be easier if you got a pen tester
II guess it's gonna be you know
three bucks for a for a few more weeks
and probably mom
the planning on you know the reaction on
matter website again we really tried to
do our best
I
we 95 probably forty
more more like society well tonight if
I'd and see
you know major CDM details he have
visibility over a lot of traffic
I unfortunately you need to patch every
single file
right the scenes I'll the patch is not
in there and the player
I'm it really requires everybody's going
web site on the war
to make sure that they are not all sting
the flash files are compiled in one
abortion so
I'm I if I i mean lol
we really think it's the only way is is
is
community-driven approach where you know
we all go around trying to look for
these things
a you know well awfully out or swinging
to Goodison check so
add that the overtime I know all
together will actually get to
a.m. to notify everyone I am if you are
all same one of i'll
you basically have a say more like a
same region pie to bypass for your
website
their wars again on whether browser San
it doesn't matter and Flash plugin is a
is updated
on if you get there by montieth ruinous
banks
police and as a pizza or proscar I
and one thing so I would also note is
that
a I guess from want to suggest new Wii
game to adobe is all set to know
well work on I'm especially patch hard
player again
as: gonna be very yam
gonna take a while before in all web
central violence was we file so
I would be beneficial I think to to get
a patch that an independent fresh player
basically just checking which version of
their the comp otherwise use and
'em Block Inc if know basically
implemented a large de mi implemented in
our tool
arm
okay 0 maybe
just another serb soldiers from about on
we we Saint
from how to protect slides I
a actually the protection metals
from lists a developer's perspective
perspective us
up from user's perspective maybe best
way to protect these
disabling Adobe Flash Player but yeah
unalterable just for sickle
comparables so yet that's that's all
get this also thanks for the
for the commode