okay so were come back true but a lot of
talking the
the Tekken research track and where come
back
Mariann motif are preventing I am
about analyzing bring this binary if
they are exploitable
and vulnerable at it's a kind of farm
I think I am maas thing so I think that
a lot of data that
a for of seventh so
belief think introduction
the stomach from work now yeah
yeah %uh other thank you okay call
I hello everyone and thanks for helping
our talk
however have to be held talking about
the most 32
when of binaries oppressive of a talker
just heard right now because we discuss
our
are problems in the development of that
project
are dealing with they to thats %uh
we argue toys Inc to evaluate when those
functions
in %uh fighters when this binaries to
see if there were a whole new level for
exportation or not
down %uh set up an interesting project
for a this occasional beta finance oslo
without oca
also have 3 Freddy vs walk into a bar
and left again just confined a table
alright
I thought of various thanks a lot on
third i'm talking about the most are the
ones bunnies and if you look at the
picture
the ball up there was not %uh is a there
for fun but I've
the born from the Wall Street in New
York City
my name is marianne
on my cause because name is what they on
her lazy buser in his presentation
is a grievous wins prestigious I work
for a company
earning Seifert was basically brand
usually working on
defending ahh attacks
from networks defending a PFX to their
switched sides on the of Penticton
British
so I'm out there security research its
course Inc
and that's all for now a
alright so going to talking about
when those box and exploit you might
have noticed
Evans box are bus in tel recently have
become love attention me a good Logan
website from
and %uh a very reer loft by
media and also was a very good for us
as researchers they get very good the
connotation because as people are very
interested
in the spot the research them off and
right blocks by them and read reports
and what happened
that a researcher from i think is from
United States Rhode a
optical block a bother when Chuck on
their ability
my to put up honorably before now this
point
I want to ask you I show up in here
last year at the choppers conference
C-one
okay fun happen here as I might have you
seen our presentation last year
alright cuz we will refer to the
presentation couple finds I especially
I concerns when Chuck horribly so
are the guy writing this blog thing Mike
my I agree
very much like Mike he sees probably
could but no matter how loud talker
bumper have it as your other blog which
we rather
began just because you're interested in
box so
going for his walk I F right a very
important
when you search for the love this %uh
this bike
you want but low but defined as Michael
kitten so
every time a shiner but when shop now
somewhere homes planned a kitten dies
reset okay looking at but we see to
a because they can reverse function in
an ESL
library are China hi Ana Calif um
was used to check out this one ability I
left without further
and find another picture showing this
asking job
where he mentions the function cryptic
or
object some your trip to could object I
remember function well
because are I do so it house
home to those for by like two or three
months so because connecticut option
something that way
recognized we've seen that before
cryptic object is a functional then we
talk about
last year so let me get back her
presentation from 2014 this one slide
or someplace like a stronger last year's
presentation and they fixed
the not on there so last year we talked
about
cryptic object as you can see there on
flight I am
a function been used in another function
named
dick alleged sequence you might also
want to
remember that function om this was
looking in the crypt
Doha library and last year
we are comparing r2 operating systems
when someone's later comparing libras
to find missing I we call them safe ATI
Stream
were searching for are missing sainty
check
functions this case a list ring CZ age
link which
Texas input string it lengthens
string yes lot too short Orissa prepared
for you
%uh find fun stuff once was not good if
a man called because you don't hear
writer talking about this nursing okay
test a cryptic object wish we could use
are
for is now covered because it allows us
to pass a string
which could be too long and wouldn't say
there was a check for security
point of having a hot so I hear some
more flights weak
research this is Logan could get all um
which is used
summer plans on computer I on your in
the system
weary such a strong cities link we
recess to complete an object
I'll talk about the sanctions lot saw
we saw there is a problem with all
comped decode object
a could last like according to the the
condition makes up for the lost past
being
for their are an object to the cold
which is not checked properly
but looking at the crib the OJ
or we found the case we didn't find a
way to
exploit this so we kinda life are
drop the can find option to use a
now Mike or whoever wrote the
when Chuck proconsul but Ingles him much
on a
arm from the same function which doesn't
check
the the coop checked properly in another
location
and he are however other %uh proconsul
on the way to actually exploit up avoid
the following way so on another way to
access a through
the as channel every they just said very
fine check
clients verify message tonto get to
decode
thing in reverse in there is among copy
operation which for that
missed check in because they could
object
which happens before going public %uh
has to be vulnerable to heap
of a commission for which
the exploit was actually able 2 X's
married to talking write access to
certain about Marie which
happen to be exploitable the swastika 30
nestle every
are Thomas R and
this is prolly the case why this was
such a famous
horribly the cup its proper mean some
market but
by now alright so there was a way to
call their body and
we thought we saw the used the laws we
have seen lost you know more like
I'll mike got or something really cool
we mister
we had like and part of such
vulnerabilities
only saw this and mister saw her
desperate as it
okay we have to do something about this
are
we had a lot of other candidates that
could eventually maybe low-risk
but we didn't find a way so re get
together again and
made a plan we have another idea so
there so I think the we we missed in
that case we have a personal flaw
within find a way to trigger it we have
to change something lol thank you
so we came up with this a plant
implemented new pool
which works a different basis or not the
kidney searching for missing say the PI
other trying to rate functions based on
attributes which could show us that this
other ticket function could be
vulnerable
and this
and Tyra idea that we've got yes
based um a hobby of muddy
yes mother in spare time is doing a
stock market does that tell you how we
came from stock market to
a vulnerability research okay so I
basically is she says I have a few of
these
one of them is dizzy with a market and
the second his day
it the stock market so but they figured
that that not so far from each other
and is that the thing that the between
this will feed Sunday said it how can I
use it dog is combined them and make
something good I don't
saw let's see so fast in the stock
market
you can arts Fred with your emotion
got big leading on turned upside down
payment you but to stop
is some point you have to sell it you
may not see anything too high a price
but senate before you lose everything
the same thing with a Zillow the market
let's say you find them on the ability
of under the old days
someone of value of X amount of money
you think it's not enough
you look for someone s again and again
but it will never be
agreed to this percent bikes you man
who's dating again
you have to understand also known as the
a in the stock market
you can use or saw in 20 the market
if you want not selling time event
though
we've watched as he led a and you know
that in the same idea
again should always have a plan
you find a vulnerability what you wanna
do it how fast you gonna do it
the same with the stock market you wanna
buy a stock
when you when I said the stock a 1.2 put
a stop loss
you have to have a plan befall you
actually dead
and this is actually very important
actually one of them someone actually
ted
can actually fall in love with the stock
which mean that he by the stove because
I love the company
anyone ever said the stock it was well
done
because he just I think the company the
same thing with Zealand a letter to
develop a refund is Eli base
is amazing the old days here about it so
much want to exploit everything was
great
but it to get a baby he actually care
about the court so much
that he cannot do nothing with it just
keep it in said
CF to remember this is not a Catholic
wedding
you find as you know that you're the
expert get a get out of it
said it
up are suing to stop
he does not go to bed by something you
know about us on a daily basis
you basically research what you know if
you're
expecting Windows you expect you is such
a Windows Linux
I O S annoyed invested time and what you
actually
what about the mucho they know about and
this is another one
basically stock markets if you are
always maintain can we think if you can
buy it or should buy
you can have a bite are so it does he
love his if you always think with a fine
with that not fine
you never even thought to find so you
see the same ideas upright
and this is exactly again
if you owe buy a stock
the idea said the stock if I miss the
old days
the idea to set as your day ended
everyone here that tied the stock market
know that there is a huge money
possession
which means that the big guys thank the
many per add the stock
to actually dissect what would be the
value of it
and how they do it because there's so
much money became basically
money for added value and the same thing
we did you know the market
the big guys should money government and
that is title but kantor
under the old days may have been a lot
of money and get information on it
and you can see it
find is still a day is as almost exactly
like actually having a stock
you have to evaluate you but the stock
neighborhood you know what will be the
venue you know and I don't want
another two months what is the market
the same thing with a few days
what is there viability which product
but it up loud appointees so this is
exactly what you should ask yourself
when painting and when actually doing
where's this at Irvine abilities
edit decade the stock
you can sell it same facilities ewbal
you find it
UK said it oh actually sometimes you can
actually
dead it with another developer and get
another 30 days
example a work that back into stocks you
buy the stock
begin with another guy you get another
one again
so how to value as the old days
someone basically in the stock market
it's called and I P O
before company go public they have this
game but I P aw
their of elite to is addressing these
apps make a bias
and then it's got to the market in
how do you value is your day is almost
the same basically you find as the old
days
now with the ban on the market how much
demand and all
willing to pay for it and how much you
willing to pay for it so the market he
said
divide you not the developer the more
popular nowadays
the more chance it would be hard to find
are dismayed thanks
the senate how high dividing will be
before it got to the market
inside
dating Sanu on a company and basically
it started
in into stocks so if you have inside
information
that didn't wanna bother does that a
company but somehow the company
when i buy another one on the ER is
pretty good
you actually have not aged other people
that have and this is easy for you to do
that I didn't
and actually get money out of it into
the lead the market
it's a you basically have access to the
source code
a specific company you walk in his
company in the justice of God
you can actually see the sauce audited
find them on in a minute is
actually have advanced when other people
who doesn't have access
butter sauce and you can actually
getting faster out
and get money out of it faster than
others by and said the same stock stock
more than once
explosive shells but does it mean New
Zealand sharemarket
you decided I wanna send a
Villa de one-time oh you wanna study
of your crimes if you did that that
exclusive ensure
hot sex though there's much more
higher-priced then ship
is also like a stock basically
the change and let's say now I but the
stock
had to sell it if I sell its owners
bought it
said got a good guy
and if they can wait to block said to
someone else
days before hand to hand the end our
song is on the market
develop on the senate percentage know
that the one company
by the company does 32 ideals crimes
in higher price and those Klein can keep
it a bit if you think the leather-clad
of course the higher price de día
weather-delayed
saw whenever stock there's few hours
Stock Exchange how they'll nuns on the
New York in Germany
and this is where you basically their
stocks you by Adele
you said they'll well do you do this
when you have a deal a day basically
have to option
the white markets and the black market
the white market
is something that many known to everyone
the DI
I defense people actually everyone to
buy their gonna bite
and basically make a special ed on are
there is the black market
which is much more money there and much
more
upon a twenty to get into it how do you
know this
so if you go to the white market you
don't need a boy or girl
everyone to lead most of the people have
died
use Boca which aimed at the book down
said the stock for them all by just up
for them
misled the middleman between the client
and the stocks dissenting
with disabilities you'll find a zero-day
if you go to the white market
no need a mock-up sever but if
you but the black market you need
immediate endemic to meet him in
which actually take your Zealand a
body weight and find a client willing to
pay the price
and cut Commission i'd of it them
exactly a private stock
apply also to build a the the Baucus
we find a plant and back to steric into
higher-priced
possible
so what he said to go when you buy a
stock
in office to find the company Microsoft
you can see up in facebook
I love that have basically steamboats
MSFT
AP and that's actually how you buy the
stock by the steamboat
you find the company so what is there to
block Sony
golfing on Windows functions
I love them have names these
that course a month and you can stay
this actually an audit on the ability
API it was found in the past
somebody'd icid: a look when the name
and then decide to go like the stock
market but Microsoft MSFT
ties had wish I will call this function
so I took no other
because he's like many populous a cue or
so decide to take care what from the
name 3
dick because internal quite a bit
so attack UK wat from this function
and that day that to see how many
function which is key what
I would if I didn't see them and then I
would be said that based on the key what
what the research something when you get
there
company c'mon the first get the same
boat who you know you need to research
the company and if it's OK you buy
same thing here I witnessed are the key
was
or the functional use keywords see which
one
indistinct something just by the for him
and basically research more the function
to see if it actually what
ok spoke about %ah not
heard no look very 12
by the stock market now call Aslam stand
more or less I got this idea
were Harvey gonna I'm be going I tried
to
alright functions like letter grade
stocks so
we came up where the system to find
vulnerabilities by
brain functions I think it's appropriate
time to has named evaluating below a
billion because %um cheap data and Ikes
so arm very probable
the toll called Wall Street ahh much
either another
explain to you how it's works so I
mentioned we were working together
big data I'll we're not relying solely
on
different functions but tried to find
said indicators
Tim Crabbe a a binary which
does not necessarily big data like
Google
world called book for us it was pretty
big because
reuse those Kaleido base to her back the
tall
on your ending a bus collided more later
let me tell yes clyde is not %uh
suitable for anything that takes more
than
are five different samples of they don't
so the big data was over the phone
is shown together but stop with the
whole Big Data public
lead-up to the conclusion that like Big
Data is
not really the the thing when it here
but a
the appropriate ways of abusing the data
that we were
collecting let me tell you know what our
approach for the data
except for cycle a bill the text for a
cheap people
because for once we didn't have big they
are a half a second
of of of a 1.5 with them have a suitable
database for reading the data
now with enough the right data and I'll
within half
the right measure how they to are the
right a concert was in that they had to
do
they don't mining or are large-scale
they are
analytics on are they to so we
a came up with simpler ideas a very
simple approach
that %uh explain to you is based on
five different steps to first uva is
finding a problem
with the problem you want to separate
vulnerable functions from
mumble novel functions the second step
after defying the problem was defined
attributes which would show us
discoverable functions I within our huge
set
it is a huge set so far as clay database
and what speed it up
and Armenia to find these attributes
which will help us
a find hunters we get as many attributes
as we could very fine
alright reviews with gathered to be a
civilian them
and then are cut down on that use a
really interesting for us
and then fine grain RR
results was not just producing
attributes but
shaping the beta on track gathering are
there from other sources and
trying to a really final problem to
something that we could XD
I know they'd up then as data analytics
if
by major we a place of magic now
well I'm gonna explain of magic that way
use for our data analytics with a simple
example oh my
let me show you %uh French
a column Frank the ship in the middle
the black sheep
is named Frank and we're not trying to
%uh
separate Frank from the rest of the ship
based on
data analytics okay so we have sent a
treasured before trying find black sheep
his thanks Frank on and tried to
separate him from the
white sheep so we stuck together at
reveals which entered with could use a
separate like black and white
haha bunch of them because
compare the hailing of the sheep we
could compare sound over the fence sheep
we could compared colors me find out
someone work the heroic this for two
years because probably have all
the compelling we have like it very huge
a the us-based reduced
to the color those are the fine-grain we
find out when I have two callers
we don't need the end herself colors the
entire cost base to happen on it too
because I
like to watch it noriko up with the
magic which in this case will be a
simple query
if we consider they don't miss a price
of
with this message because separate Frank
from the other sheet okay
so much a bother much heavier than their
let's start with me approach
for beginning %uh
working on the toll his third such a Reg
abuse which I they're called binary
education Inc i hella funny saying that
flight because
wrong
home so you might %uh maybe
know that just read the labels working
on a tradition
a lot usually Melbourne list and spend
sometime in addition lot more time
fighting the trolls
were after much addition so I like at
using
um I decided to dedicate the flights to
produce
and now Wade for people after come up
with complains again anyway
the very interesting research better his
so we're session for the Prince basis
which will be once
the function local space and be the
think the thing
%uh space what we found
the attributes this on the flight I
these are
already the sorry the ER yourself it
reveals how to find useful
which ones will be a suspicious mess
exploitable and a function same checks
EC Vijay hits the headline kinda
function municipal functions
safety case missing noise all talk about
these shopping
interesting to notice is the hutch local
attributes actually contain information
that help us
I by the function without comparing it
to other functions
and yet to business began dating site
are
unused in comparison with other
functions
so would again like try to compare
different versions of functional between
a brain systems
to making use of these attributes
alright
so we can begin you might have noticed
last year
be published at all tool was written
very well in my opinion officially was
not
it was a python script are oh so the
fight this group this year
as again so the pipes goods I'll a
be use all our coding skills on this and
capital recently like last year
it's not the fastest to all s %uh
we could imagine so we start working all
the libraries
that we had left from last year what
role decompile
song first that we held the compound
libraries and
at some time so altogether we had all
the libraries and drivers which
gether following someone's aid and when
the 10 and the first up at the compile
them
to catalyse fast supportive at halftime
we had like dollar see coat so sick what
of these binaries to park them to the
database
became over simple there is the same to
get these files Rupert Sanders in our
escalate their with
and spend a lot of time on parsing party
I'll probably still the party tomorrow
marketing presence actually finished I
was just a working on the
automated the thing anyway we spend
a lot of time on the part in this year
again and the commission for a slut is
not useful
for see big data okay
anyway it was bloody yet her fight some
when Dustin
as leisure died on the way on you might
have noticed the king and Peter
version of Windows 10 as just another
busy time for the official Shin
I'm tired just anyway we got some
results
so we managed to grab all these missions
editors from
the binaries double no explain
what these attributes are useful for so
we find educated suspicion
special like the following keywords:
as more than just before and the
question is: so if you find any of these
keywords:
in the No function you can show you that
something interesting is happening the
function if you have like a low other
decode
for a copy all right probably some
interaction
or in some but some functions some
interaction with
memory of the computer they can read
this function as more interesting
than the others in your evaluation
process
said you find his something seems fishy
the second israel's exploitable on the
other side
arm there you're searching for split a
function within that function
25 the following keywords which
indicates that there's
some potentially exploitable functional
with Ian
that function so I was looking at
the the skiers from two sites once on
functioning no
and once on function call level research
for
society checks say checks in a sense of
are if you're a smaller no this is not
based on my
like of coding skills them searching for
such simple wrecked but
I want to keep it simple stupid the
point is
to trying up let me tell you we're still
fighting low false-positive
especially inside checks but if you
happen to search for
more complicated are more complex a
Rake's you hope
I have a lot of are call false positives
and with us
rates navajos make-ups we find all that
the false negatives for less of an issue
thank the false positives so we kept it
with us
simple regular expression for setting
for
said you guys again you shouldn't drop
what's
once proven useful and here is actually
follows
of safety classes are searching for with
save it does
this is probably not the best inge term
would be something like this said he
checking
API call something which
as ball the such face them to leverage
swish
when those provides for whens developers
which care about
they type conversions or string
operations to see if the values
which I use for polling a actions
often say the PI are actually protects
it have a man copy
you might wanna see before if the string
which you're copping slot too short
do use such gonna say they played before
that
these are interesting for us a
fantasize a their present and your side
after
not present so I was researching for
them to function local basis to see
their their
and then researching them are dipping
basis to see if there were present
in one of the phrases in to check and
are missing
in a and all their own your operating
system
to see if we could find a professional
patch I tried to
described or tried to sum up the
presentation of last year and industry
last under
own office or cell also if a function 11
when this thing has to save a PI
where the same function the same library
in another version has no say the PI
this indicates that something was at
their for me is a
david Kerr was at a and potentially in
the case that the older version for the
wonderful
pressuring Iran just the sites like this
works interesting a all the other way
around you can see if something was
missing and 170 in the state
om was aryan
joe says i cant to see if something's
missing when the 10 those later on
patched in Windows 8 but the patch loved
rolled out for winston
and same thing works for when the side
when the Sun
for sometimes the older version of
leverage touch not no one
interest me which is also very useful to
know
inheriting fashions alright last against
you know someone come
a newness is probably also not good
English OVA
my brother some things like make
mistakes in English and I
very much stick to them so wickedness
unisex a pretty simple
me billiad if a functional sa at that
or was removed some functions present an
operating system hmm
they can leverage its valued with zero
and it is missing somewhere
which means it has been added or it has
been removed for some reason
and thriller with one here especially
interested
in the functions that were removed
because if something was removed it was
probably integrated somewhere else
for a reason
and because it was too much code there
because it was a slow or maybe didn't
work right
alright so searching for the missing for
and
like on the same thing this is all based
on comparing different versions of
functions
and there we take a some coat was at the
or
removed were figured out it's very
interesting only
look at this when their small changes
now there's big part of colour
our talk about this later alright these
are the attributes
now toll itself love been talking about
all time now
requires either pro to work at the
actress the compiler
otherwise you won't get all the
beautiful sick old and across our pipe
magic
which you finally get up it we present
and now it doesn't require in the sky
brother I wouldn't recommend
a using that all very much because
questions all-time
but you can use left my brother to West
database
%uh was being held i cant
Rev Maina for generating beautiful
officials have a show you later
um we don't accept any liability for the
code works enough because we're not
quite sure
what else crash another slut brother
nanking actually doesn't crash
pumping systems and if you want a choice
available
on my get approval on the WTF
p L that's now I D %ah what the fuck
public
life this out especially for people last
year which I like
are rating
about Minot putting a license
on the Polish Republic so literally
put the least restrictive license on the
car because I really don't care for
people
do with the top alright
gathered there now about findings
wouldn't fight okay so it how many
people you know this picture
I wanted for okay
unspoiled something about playing so can
you at the other
haven't seen it can you see anything on
the picture which you wouldn't expect
their
much to say that the colors him i'm not
the best
interesting they can anyone see anything
in there
cockade yeah I'm voting for the coffee
bean
area let me lemme thinking this list
there's a man hidden in there
like based on the colors as you can see
very well here see now
as frank to
though there have there's a guy hidden
in there at like the Windows binaries
rides or all findings from some update
us or
arm altogether we parsed
all burr by a reason to their ways we
didn't default them but concentrated on
the drivers now
because some drivers we only have about
like
500 binaries a horse just a few exist in
operating systems
might make the difference the thing a
bit complicated
altogether we parsed eighteen million
of the compiled co-op at lines at the
bar called
which is I'm quite a lot of other
collided with the bit too much
we found the bug man a 10 missing say
obvious where
about like 468 a local than one single
function that might be a very
interesting thanks much if not I i love
the
about the very interesting content other
Microsoft guy
had their for other the authors
play are also I am when the seven
there's a functional
the specific function using these
foreign 68
I cost 2s print F which i think is not
%uh quite the godiva southern designed
to put them in one question
but as much light on the sauce have a
calling
alright arm for libraries
altogether we the compiled wanted and
two million lines of coke polygon
database I was quite intense
but were finished now 102 extract a
potential vulnerabilities
all the struggles we found based on the
variation with it
are listed here in flight I wanted them
now but if you're already
nervous and don't want to be compiled
pars everything you could have a quick
look on these levers
and see if you find the stuff the wake
up good luck
a process in this house says we had a
big day that we couldn't get around
officials
and that he might remember from last
year I like colorful of so
had a dozen version of I'm going to
China
%ah financially so here you see a
of HX compared to exploit of home in the
seventh here's a version of Windows 8
has to russian Prime Minister
interesting was that the visuals
we didn't really get to any useful
conclusions
we compare these pictures highly
scientific and %uh figure out
the there's some animali in when the Sun
so if you look closely at these pictures
me a gray circles
indicated the same place because the
film didn't read
ungodly work on Robert miner but
you can put the spotlight on is rich in
up there
well put the question mark there's a lot
more functions 17
which are growing on this direction
which means there's more exploitable
from saint checks in there
then in wins then brings 10 much for me
personally was
interesting finding alright but back to
serious
I here's are we here's another
visualisation we pull other I compared
be
City OK for missing the same text and we
will be especially interested
in the safe API some missing and
functions where there's no sign the
strikes law
but just much more simple described with
roth
so try to derive rules from the findings
that we have a looking at are they to
in a senior at Midway
so much a ultimate at all and came to
the following set forth
much luck who said well I don't want
read them of you know
but well we found out while looking at
the data what's up
its usually the little changes for the
Rangers thing
to watch in are cold so
for example if you're going to function
which F
one-sided check a freelance cold this is
much more interesting than the function
which all of a sudden has 20 lines
up call it's 81 it was calm or and 50
say it I said it
so are this with exploitable
if you have an exploitable and those
ones I check thats
interesting because usually takes to
play checks to see something's not too
big not too small
arm if you have
a safe API which is missing it is
interesting
if there's any other function cause
being added
in the policy you wouldn't want to look
at the function call con
of a specific never us was a question
and sauce for so is the little changes
to have to concentrate on
and the following examples will show you
some
up the no change anyway we have another
problem
as you might remember the I come from
the beginning
we had like a potential vulnerabilities
are we knew there something
something lousy something fishy I'll
with didn't quite know though how to how
to access this
a vulnerability and save up searching
widened evaluates
that finding important enough to keep
searching for a way
to X are vulnerable function so you're
trying to find a way
to evaluate the excess boy if the
function by painting
car chase this is a beautiful
almost graphical orkut of the toll road
Chester
official as a function call today so we
feel our talk
a function a function ideas you can see
a pair
other little by little way can indicate
the functional you want to look at
and hola paint the tree to final ODI
exported functions from library which
are actually used
too cold out to the a to
this interesting question this years
a tree which is actually not through a
useful because it's just random
but you can see like are
on these leave no was eventually you
will find functions Witcher
fashion exported like this one process
control which is something
interesting many on they can go research
this function
it has called the mother function on
Samoa every and see if you can excesses
this function somehow for now if only
implemented
a levrie local tree generations from
don't look at interlibrary
calls which are potentially interesting
Highlanders for
the database you have snow some eschew
like a I'm the house must lead yes let's
kill
to query this function calls which could
appear in a light breeze
so the final every which is used to
actually
excess your are function which is
interesting
to eventually get through the windows
software which
woods which could be used to exploit the
pop
alright picking cherries
now finally here findings on
how last we have an example here
and EMS EMS the OL way fun polling data
we saw there was a small change and
the lines the Compal cold as the only
see
we see there's an exploitable function
in their official explanation there
we see there was once a day P I'm
missing we see there's one thing to
check
at and his origins so there's definitely
something wrong there
and we can see that the function itself
healthy indicator me get and smell
there something arianna open the coach
and throughout this is
a very short call tree because this is
already
the exported function I think yep
so hi we go to see
a love our coast and fauna
there's men copy in there the city
exploitable but we saw in the beta
there's me size well you which is used
for
the memory allocation he says well you
is once checked appear
if it's not bigger than the certain
values stored
in our demand for and is not
to initialize a pair in this through me
long
a line but as you can see there
it is apparently never checked it was
actually not too small
we look at this for a long time we're
not quite sure if this is a potential
underflow maybe if you find time to
spare time
look at it and if you find something
right allies blah to bother let us know
if this was actually RFR right picking
our show is
there was %uh one more thing we found
that the sage Excel others I mention the
small changes so
there's like exactly one thing the chase
which was
of suspicious just because the function
well then copy and because it's located
in the user three
today all so interesting larry looking
at
the cost me we find the very long
coaching which indicates the
there's potentially a lot of different
way sexually excess this function
which is good in the case joint
exploited has 0 it up close look
at the Cohen fell fun in the headline
interest exactly this so here
was a check added not actually Atlanta
called only the check
refined so on guild version the value 9
which is later on youth %um be ok %um
handle
function is checked if it's bigger than
and then the new version I was more fun
checked arm
which could indicator there something
wrong but what we found on later
is the winds eighty also and another
function
which I
could thank a
which thirsty security check in this
case so because I look at this one but I
promise you you won't be able to
exploited made a alright
so this will take some pasta a history
member that guy
and the critical object at all he would
get back there so
we have a full going and try to evaluate
the cryptic about to begin
to see if election working and
found out that weekend
find the a other
a cost for this function: within yes
channel every
and follow-up in there we find exactly
the same function
that my can you remember Mike when the
knobs block
but because second reverse saying this
in their we analyze the Khalsa can rest
at the toll
the fun that we see changes and lines of
code apparent change in with HX
member small tax for it to say a check
that
sophie loves could be interesting and
print the Kochi Atlanta here for the
cops and robbers who gets
check claimed brief a message don't love
by 2:30 verify
and going back to Mikes block we see
that this is the second one
found he went to that the tests are
verify saw
there %uh he can actually excess the
deco second reverse function matched
to use a certificates with
almost that the the second show which
should have been Didcot thats by the
decade second diverse functional
to actually chega the he PLO
Mayer Bologna for this is his pro
concert again thanks love Mike
for percent in this beautiful on our
ability
lol I for the motivation
to get the project because doing this we
go back to our hunch
interest decal that would be a six-month
figured out this also looks
rather interesting how they'd always am
go back to
tried to find a way to explain it still
which is now
that the more that mothers gonna show
you to percent hallway
are worked okay so
one of the result from the door was this
function am
as you can see on this claim decor at a
bar sequence
for someone so festival on Oct is
received the name
and thought that interesting the Deacon
was there but the four name is the cause
at the boot sequence
also some very interesting the next
thing I was looking about to see
actually if it exploited men not exploit
them in
and let them time to show now is the way
the Fiat if something is expired event
and how
so I would I have to decide the entire
process much as possible
in a Vega DDS so it would be any dent
taken kind so when I saw this function
their first thing they were sentido can
I to get here call option
biased that about how of law this
condition
I need to bring us something so I was
looking on this function
perceived as anything interesting why
not differ airlines I saw
was ma'am copy which actually a very
basics
C function for every developer is no
evasive min
thing it's Kobe for May
sauce to destination best on a site
so if I can take a people have lost that
overflow whatever
I need to contort Desai's so I have to
check
if there is any sent to check undersized
that he's getting supply
two men copy so
them in public victory Obama does as you
can see by the bush
yes I is basically the sauce
sauce boozed up a lot in the eye
is the day is
this is the sauce and I don't want yes I
did destination
and basically this one EX is how long a
how many bytes to copy for this
definition
and we can see easily bad this site is
is best on the function above this one
which is s talent this one
and what does s talent Dec
it taking s think and getting how long
best thing is so basically they don't
value
gonna be EX and its gonna actually get
likely push in men copy but
there is no sent the check how long a
can this thing be so maybe this thing
can be very long
we can all the flaw the destination
buffer
so the next step is to figure out what
is this thing
all about and webcam for so though so
I'll
you have to post call it a live oak and
you see it actually come
form a function called caped
be caught object so the fasting
make sense to go is to figure out what
in this keep
object they got no so the only way to
figure out
is basically check and then so that's
what is a possible
than a function
committee what's going on right
okay so this is the Palm a bill of this
function
what is interesting is basically to see
when
this think is what is the what were the
same come
on this function so we go up go back we
see that
EDI EDI hardest thing
to st. arlen well yeah I come form
if you go up in this one PV stock
in for of this Palmetto to create
the good function so I have to figure
out what is this
comic 2010 save up to them is it
and NSA be the stock in for
so I have to it what's going on so
it's messy a point out though inkatha
stock talk to be decoded so this is the
return value
how they say it then value look like so
fast ahora
its best on the first Palmetto
option this one
all this one so by knocking
enhanced the first bomb idea is one
and one is actually this one
so this is the one that accused the
president function so I pushed the issue
that's how it's applied now
22 what is twenty door see
against Stony is
with
K
22 and end up in court that NDS so I'm
dying to expand its Tony on papa was
how exactly are we gonna get it so than
10 if i do.
is the best on the 22 and what is this
20 thought is based on a structural
and thank you find a factual here easily
steam taking see
this factual type basically a point out
though I did they find the stock to type
this is all the consent form this okay
so now you see the list this is really
something I'm best
that actually can supply and affection
stoplight the number twenty 20
as you can see new 22 so I have to look
what is 22 ND test
okay so that twenty 20 is at EB ot
called the peaky CS achievement
and basically which means that day
a $10 value will be to stopped this Cape
actually met so I click on this this is
the return value
as you can see here is any
what is this thing that has been a dead
end
in this stop shop this thing is
the first time the first Bella Bella
Vista which is
PCs ed on Tuesday as you can see
so the return value is being hard in
this
laptop anestachio have a bar Taylor
to a stunning which is object ID now
the seems like there's no he meets how
long these ID can be
so the idea is that we will eat n
this stock 20 but this function with a
very long day
and he'd go to st. out and and all that
right
now the other questions you ask yourself
how do I
actually bought of rain this function
how do I get this ordered a day
inside this so the first thing to know
is to figure out
book on this function without you have
to tell you this
have to come to this press in somehow
some
in some complement the windows have to
come here
who is this the first thing you know you
think the function
facing Penn
and died 26 in anti like Billy
of Windows toys but Moyes gonna call
dysfunction why because if you go here
you see this is actually exported
function from these DNA
so the first thing to do is to figure
out which application
Ohno the modern cordis exported function
and from Dell you can go up see
what is going on because DNN just there
but enough we need something Accord is
function to make it easier
as you can see it this actually the DNN
is came DNG and while I scanned the bail
systems
I don't find anymore don't well any
application
but actually called this function so why
is this function
is there have to figure out how do I
think you're right I don't think it
myself but I think the Caucasus less I
need someone to 38
which compliment in Windows clinger this
so what they did
I see okay it's not in the system32
non-college so what's going on
so I decided to stash on is dead again
who call it
so I figured out that when this
bien get tested I can see him
it call where it is because
good because Etymotic once effect this
fax this name
and got another function which is
clipped
I just tell oh I D function so I have no
idea why this function actually no
when a second any to forget not heart
dysfunction
going on so I think dysfunction
move in it
its
okay this is the condition on this
function it's actually very very simple
def accent yeah just a did because I P
meticulous function
and when someone want to pass
something it with Tiger this function as
a call about
and you can see him at that
and how they and how does he know to go
dysfunction
by another up object ID as you can see
him so basically
there's another ID that someone with a
stoplight and they say the
we find a function what is this I D if
you go it's one of these permitting
this one disease already you can see
it's some sort of a number 2.5 that that
that
if something someone give this number to
add a function in the system
eventually it would think about the
function so let's see
what is this number as you can see him
the card
at a boutique wines their number is
team me pics
this is the number one .3 but this is
like an object ID number
I D so the first thing I have to do now
taking this number
and thinking of going to Windows OS
systems actually
use this number again because I cannot
find anything that you didn't
the official name so I just think his
number
and you can see this search stopped
unified any DNN
so my next thing is this this number
this thing and I D which is mean that if
someone to play the same day
eventually intraday go got a function
because the dentist date
when the end was know that so the first
thing to go
but he's not a someone must use this
number
to be able to bring it why did slugging
they don't have any question apostasy
welcome to say
quite a soaking but it is
again caveat
PBHG let's wait a little longer and see
what moment a fine
d
and
okay saw better not at the end and
which actually he fell for the same day
busy and a
is iiNet com it now they're
obvious thing to know is to open this
day
and open it see figure not what is going
to get a
so the first thing you know effect this
ID up and I don't the NN
and do a search
USS to figure out
how well these DNA and you this I think
tracing pad now it's finish
netday resort so this is well
I know its communication DNA actually
he fail the function by talking on this
by this function we see here that's the
number
which mean that accorded equal object
which eventually
may figure I believe it did because I
don't see question that'll be a lead
that was a the stealth
now then especially his how do I
actually trigger
pale this God yeah
think if at first computers dying I
so basically we saw that this DNA
have this on have died a and I think the
cosby I need to figure out fast
well it's been called so it's been
called by
this function and which one is being
the quad you can actually see so on
by just by the name which product
actually use this function
be caused by the door
at six it this is the class and there's
a good body
cord dysfunction eventually someone they
got somebody some message
which message you go up Nikon message
saw basically there is the message but
being the call that that eventually can
lead
to the vehicle at about sequence the
question is which point out
actually US be SDNN the
easy way to find it is to sell the
system fine
music as you can see not think
best art but very basic if you actually
open
if you're outlook only knows man and you
look again
candidacy
you can see its BC at
outgrew actually you think is getting
nothing but actually use it
yeah
I would do it again them a drug
is person when I him
fix it now it is a mess and no I don't
a wreck of the
so they've so I know I know the product
actually using his DNA and then I know I
did I'm
be caught message it's basically best on
assigned
Inc a big message justification so that
day that
is basically if you don't care more
commands
killed
fastened to invest
famous security so basically bad day
this
if we won a Cup in a min which says
thank
NKP with specific to object ID
as we saw and Wednesday eventually
outlook return my picky Pasig andrew de
Gea
the heap overflow so I don't have to
talk is basically
cuffed this kind of an odd animated
we def BCCI actually vote in it and then
we have a real one but it's a question
I'm going to sever
in 127 is body possible you can see what
had happen now
and that was being bad example thank you
there's any question show
thing kinda ran out of time
this is a question I don't know either
now or later outside the
coffee bar 0 way I dress red
Bradford I our all Thai red curry
no first so
first of all I wanna say that the joke
you told
at the beginning was really good a
and then I wanted to ask so there was
like this you know when does this
not genuine message on
on on them on thus X
cream so did you actually look for an
exploit in the binary the checks if
Windows
generate because that could become a
useful call you
the did I mention that we looked at all
the binary stuff we put together a
hands-on
it funny college see need big data yeah
probably within plum
much allowed for more money list for I
can get you the results that you want
for dinner for
yeah I do okay a
a pic by it was very good thank you
thanks for acabo questions
okay so my remote it's thank you very
much