some excited to be here om this is a
cool topic for me
I so love without further ado
about me I am the CISO for Motorola
Mobility
have been the CISO from overrule ability
since its been in existence
I as we split off from Motorola if you
wish to follow me on twitter
I'm secretary I is enough that makes no
sense
but just go with it on that site ever I
have crazy family
I Miami for kids arm
do not wanna father follow in their
father's footsteps im
anything technical or anything out yet
we have conversations
I truth common conversations that we
hide because we end up with
is much your daughters and one is
complaining that
the other one broke into your Facebook
account and posted thanks and
I look at my daughter I save did you do
it she goes she had a crappy password
and at some point you're like a
while karma is comes back and hit you
every single time
the second instance is a help sponsor
event in Chicago contact for kids
it's a kid security conference on with
everything else my youngest daughter was
in there
and I had a couple parents come out and
makeup in here to change your Netflix
password
and Mike did my daughter like give out
the past 15
no no no no she talked about how to
create secure passwords and used your
Netflix password as an example
a am going
I going to live to the c50
I'm not sure I'm doing this a really
really long time I do have experience on
both sides
have the facts I did a veteran security
startups
I did security Verisign
and air defense all successfully
acquired all
done very successfully on that site ever
I've also been on the corporate side
I work for some of the largest companies
in the world
both GE and Siemens and now Motorola so
I can go from both sides is a slander
stand and it was very interesting in
today because I've
played both sides of the attack in the
deficits like to tell you it is so much
easier to play
on the attack inside and on the defense
inside you sleep a lot better at night
tell you that I'm and where the other
key items that he brought up was
extremely
point is for some bizarre reason and it
has nothing to do with this stuff only
way we can make
our networks more secure is by adding
complexity and total
we're just doing ourselves to failure at
this point in time and if we don't
really have a choice
kinda made our bed we have to sleep in
it this is a huge problem that we have
to
under and work with and work around and
some other cases
so about the gaming area I'm avid game
I
I've got four kids yes I play everything
across the Sun
and everything else so I started looking
at security in gaming
when I first heard looking at the stop
again said hey there's a lot a
correlation between us
and we're not just talking about lag
we're talking about a lot of different
things
so are the big ones that I want to bring
up is what I refer to a security cam P
for how many gamers do we actually have
been here
okay we've got a few okay you can raise
your hands is not a bad thing
I'm so for camping actually is
is the ability to people like I don't
wanna go run around I'm not that good so
I just hide somewhere
and when I see somebody I shoot them
from a long distance or anything else
typically kinda like a sniper it's an
area on everything else and most the
people after a while ago
really I can't you do something else
besides stand there
and they will hunt you down and kill you
usually and is usually by
twelve-year-old you can hear laughing
across the
the mic at the other end of the phone
I'm but
it's one of those things that goes into
it but we do this in the security
organization as well
we focus on something so closely we miss
everything else and are some key areas
that we constantly see this a
the IR process the incident response
process we will get focused on this we
were Friday
book it will cover pages and
documentation call list
here's our here's ours liaisons and
everything else the second that
thing is paged published we signed up
for head go to the CIO CSR's
as everybody see this go to the board so
they know we have one it saturday
weather's been to reorder some marketing
by that warning or an HR the liaison
that was an hr's now left so you don't
have anybody
and no one figure this out tell boobs
pick up the book okay call the person DD
DD
numbers been disconnected
this is the problem that you run into
you come so focus you miss the larger
areas
you don't figure out how to do this in a
regular air were really big about
data center good people hey SAP
had to the data center it's a
we want to focus on this money and
effort and Watson's
things and bells and whistles and lights
and blinky things and
things that don't blink you put all this
time and effort in there and then you
realize that yeah
we have it's a third party
and they had it issue with the sas70
report and
yeah anybody at one point I'm could walk
in a plugin breach
our whole network and you put a lot of
money and effort in that the supposed
and gets by you because you're trying to
look so closely at this
and that's where the value actually yes
or someone gets power
with malcolm happens the be the
administrator for when the TV is
you end up with the data breach
we focus on a parameter Michael
nothing can get through I'm sorry our
printers today are like switch shoes
they would take anybody not to be able
to get through our parameters in most
cases were
that I think are safest place probably
outside
most organizations Internet is a safer
place than a
apartment inside your network and this
is one of the things you
you can see and if you're so focused and
on the target
like this you don't see the Chancellor
decides around you and you will not have
time to read actor
and will never ever see it coming you're
taken completely by surprise
you do get
own by twelve-year-old and you can tell
because we like to use marketer
laser-focused
it's like no bad idea because you're
camping at that point in time if you're
that focused on something
you realize that you're camping you're
missing the bigger picture on that side
up
so Argo for those s
dealing with aggression and what kind of
aggression it is well your
attracting things to attack so to focus
a progression that's their
on and the game it's it can be
useful somebody places like to use it in
security it's
really me about your attack surface and
our tax surfaces are a mess huge
we go well beyond what we were
protecting last year
it's almost like an to backs call it but
different kind of
walk Richards law pay your tax surfaces
goes by to access every year
because it literally does that's that's
what
for don't have mobile phones now you
have mobile phones
next year will be applications it keeps
growing and growing right now the
problem you get into it is
wearing how that attack surface is
extremely important you want to control
your
you don't wanna say hey come beat me up
and it happens complete do this all the
time
if you don't believe it it's like hey
stick a server out
just right put in your DMZ at a DNS
record and
upstart to stop watch people done it
before
it doesn't take long before a sensible
I'm attacking
weicker's no it attracted attention
it was something that changed in the
ripple effect
decide to get there now I like to use
the term shark in
the waters for this
there's a couple things you don't piss
off people
the part what
you don't wanna piss off security
researchers you don't piss off somebody
that's reporting
website for ability to you you don't
wanna piss off
group for people one-term you should
never
ever ever uses a term called theoretical
time and time again people love to use
this term
people like that's a theoretical you
want to make it practical
its just a little bit of ca we get
caught up in this
so when the key areas
you have to know how the attackers look
at your network and i'm talking about.
outside no information what do you look
like
pleasure name servers pull-down what is
your DNS information
what is the registry say about you order
all these things
externally the attackers a car look at
without ever touching you
or touching you that you'd be able to
figure out they're going to take a look
at this information and say hey
but actually they're so you have to know
your network and you gotta make sure
there's not something in the air
we see it all the time all this records
there and this comes back from
doing contest and everything else it was
like hey this backup server
testified it's not bad just all this
other day and house it does both
internal and external DNS for resolution
people
go after these things and they continue
to go it's one of the things that are
there
they take a look at the outside in all
your weaknesses
everything that you haven't done exactly
100 percent they're gonna see if
before that and so they will go on to
that
and they were attacking you see it you
see it with the vulnerabilities whether
it's
freak weather it's hardly whether it's
shell Ciroc
gay will see it they were scan you they
will come after
but actually they're so sparred gaming
there's what we refer to as grinding in
farming which are
different between the two but brian is
kinda the
to hear the extremities gotta go one
place I gotta go to another I gotta do
this I gotta do this at the level up
it's what we do had a good check the
logs
gotta do this it's not some other stuff
that we really liked it too
it's kinda the main game
kinda stuff that we deal with but it's
something we do on a regular minasian on
a mission is real good
now you'll see me say on a missions good
automations Eve which one is it
tense it's the hacker answer for that
but the CSL
pants guess what what you're trying to
do
really depends on whether automation is
the best tool suited for this
its credited over over stuff and if
you're just looking for
a binary operation animations good
if going out if the outcome is kinda be
different on a mission can be back as
the night goes think about Lodge
people like who I'm
you can show all a lotta logic but it's
time consuming and you may not be right
so look at things like IP lookups
back kind of animation hey go look and
find all information I can find about it
to give me
some cancel every day that is a good you
serve on a mission account management
which account is expired
make sure they're not exist anymore
that's good automation I
log analysis moon not so
good unless you're just looking for
details such as but there in five 22%
arm Microsoft event ID's
running through which is kinda bypassed
the hash
that on that people work for
but one other things you typically when
do there's a lot of tools %um Nana
vendor basher anything else but
typically your automation is your
automation your group automation your
company's on a mission don't necessarily
want to buy it because it's kinda the
square peg in a round hole
sometimes it fits sometimes it's much
bigger
I do I really want to spend the money on
yes
because it does this one thing that I
need but it does 22 other different
things
if you don't need the other 22 it's not
a really good
set so I like to go with the idea that
building you know your network you know
you have a structure better than anyone
else
you know what is Brian D what is going
around
what you have to do every time if you do
it's much easier to build been doing and
this is one that the areas that you get
into
so my next favorite topic lack flag
kills
and a discussion you can always blame it
on lack to its kinda like to thank a
in a game it's like bone om
it was lax sorry I you've got me on that
one but
lag is a gamer term for delay it's like
ok the controller lagged the network lab
and
the x-box lacked the PlayStation lag my
PC lagged
we do it on a regular basis and blame
for everything it's kinda like
game version I love the firewall
what's rockets the fire was well but
it's usually associated with networks
slowdown things like that be also have
to remember
the people lack and you can tell the
people lack
think about if you someone that cannot
make
a decision you know that person well I
don't know
what's gonna happen if you put them in a
decision are IRS response: processes as
you make a decision in 15 minutes
their head will explode
but these are some you need to know this
because you do not want them in the
process of trying to make something this
there do we take the website down yes or
no
I right or wrong
gotta pick a side
so it is
par decision process and people allowed
them to compare
state literally cannot make a decision
on that
now one or the other things you succumb
to lack
gamers everybody there is a lag portion
that's out there
you get the lead and you will get
killed I ten-year-old by an eight year
old
it happens but the problem is that goes
around and the processes that
is
Blackhawks impaction if you to let
and vulnerability reports is one my
favorite
like a slight turn those things and the
people found a bug here you go
and it pisses me off you I sent one &
Manuel
for today's haha pay what's up be nice
if you told me that you got this
and so this is some other stuff you run
back into
that that just as going to infuriate
somebody in somebody's gonna go hey hey
guess what
boom here you go fix this so Dave and
now you're dealing with a whole separate
problem for karla serve
whose fault you pointing fingers hey
we're in passion and Timex enter
them at the point it's gone its out
that broke down at like some bad
marriage so guess what
its over whether ir processes
is key to
key to the time that's actually there
the have to be able to work with us
always know that a problem that you're
trying to solve in this process will
never
correct itself it's not like asap L
the state average but it really happened
we have no proof irv exfiltration
therefore it did not happen
yeah people are laughing at them
that's an all-school wave going like can
you make this disappear
no sold this is where the issues you get
into
so a lotta games are multi-player
the people as I call multiplayer it's
fun you're playing against people
but I don't like to play in the world
where people can attack me and I like to
be in the nice
rainbows and unicorns doesn't exist
unplugged the internet stay away
multiplayer is always
player versus player but you also have
to think of it as
security is a team sport it is a team
you have a team of people
use them or maybe not
if you don't have a camera people we
have a team a friends
if you don't have to your friends by
some
the call consultants
they will come they'll be your friend
but it's all when you wanna thinks
anytime you want to do something you
bring your group it's kinda like gang
warfare
bring mine my say we show up altogether
and there's a reason for that especially
when you're doing processes
incident response correct the problems
other things the more people you have
decisions are being made now a lot of
thought and allow a lot of processing
lifetimes
its its for lack of a better term got in
some cases knowledge in some cases
and sometimes you need the person to sit
back and go
I'm what about this server that
in turkey when we cut this connection
it's gonna lose and that means all our
VPN traffic
for the restive Asia is now gone
books docked at the circus you but
sometimes you need the person to have
some
insight that you may not have be able to
go home wait a second but it's also one
other things as you get into it
they help make decisions
to you have this and one other things
too ass people
is when you say can you go do this yeah
you got this
sure yeah I got it done Obama it doesn't
help but wonder ground rules
long security team is like I can ask you
fifteen times if you got this
don't get pissed at me because
I wanna make sure because it falls on
the floor
bad things happen doesn't happen or you
say hey I can do this in 30 minutes and
30 minutes is now gone
you like oh it's going to cool a bit
longer new new
me 30 minutes or less so
this is one of the things that's their
and always do you need help
sometimes more security people like no
need quiet
your cocaine here here's your headphones
back
go go go go memorize just looking at him
as he types feverishly on a keyboard
hit backspace best-dressed I sup
it's one of the things that's their in
this multiplayer so you have the players
to bring
to the thing so power leveling
wanna my favorites because why we're
doing it
power leveling is that this is a map a
while this is
hey guess what you run around like a
chicken with my head cut off going to
fifteen different places and takes three
days
persons this way which I use a little
help from my friends and said hes go
here do this do that do this do that
much shorter much faster
so power leveling is about knowing a
strategy to get
batter 20 security conference is all
about
that's why we're here is
the power level her own characters for
lack of a better
ourselves
you can learn from friends you can learn
from strangers
and I'm really did not want to put this
in there but after this morning I think
I guess on my own guy so therefore you
can learn from all guys too
this also works
when you takin going to your vertical
market people like wall
okay this is what you would classify
as you need to mark this on
client confidential but spoke
the privileged information therefore the
lawyers can't look at
I if you work for vertical markets
number ever tell the lawyers
have your organization I know it's bad
but just get in the way
in some cases but you don't have to make
it a working
you go for beers you go for drinks
you got for lunch
everybody pays their own bill but
worrying from
other people and security folks have to
met working in vertical market day
we will share information they will talk
to each other they will tell you
what their problems are issues
hey have you seen this and that because
guess what in the vertical markets
targeted attacks all this other stuff is
huge
because they're going after different
portion Anderson and using your
competitors
or frenemies war
whatever you wish to call them is a
great way to share information to keep
them hey this is what we saw did you see
this
Yes No now we can see this won't be on
the lookout for it
is that a competitive advantage or
disadvantage
I don't know but I like to use the term
I don't wanna be in the lifeboat by
myself
it sucks and that is a key area
and my favor that I do for that will
probably be repaid at some point in time
because they will get hit with the next
round
stuff
works in the community community share
information very close net
we have group from Chicago ever own
communities
that set up a meet on regular basis
everything from
city government to
to aviation to other sides are all in
tertiary information
with out any other entities involved in
the mix
I'm not a big fan a government sharing
not that
it doesn't work the problem has that
it's a one way street most the time hey
if you share with us
yeah we'll get back to you on that you
like really
and now you're certain to see at least
in the US side that they're kinda
cursed because we're all sharing with
everybody and we're kind of like a you
had your chance go away we're not gonna
talk to you
but we want to protect you are we saw
that before
national sure about that so governor
sharing
if you're involved in it works great if
you're not involved in it you're not
missing much
for that much Saida was checked Twitter
its perfectly fine om
sharing is great I like to do whatever
refer to as a trial by fire
yeah it's great for looking things
I like to conduct honey parts collect
well when that
sounds like you take the things out and
pay go get this clay target 10
all sorry now I'm hun parties were
looking for stuff on the network gather
much people around
we say hell the school fine thanks
one indicators do we have are we seeing
what's there let's go get it and we do
we find stuff from binaries hashes
network IP addresses here here here
and everybody works together because it
forms the synergy that works really good
people get used to hey we can go through
this it also help bring people in from
the
outside of that were and it helps them
as well because they hail hail now I
know who to go get
from the speaker pieces of information a
I love to invite
executives because they're like 1000
the stuff still by we got stuff going on
how is this gonna be
safe to get on the network no no no
don't get on the network I
this is some other areas that are there
I executives are great to bring
to thats like this it's an I opening
experience for most other
I rather be any kinda love
security affect on this really a
conference is dealt with knowledge
learning
and stuff along those
major it is hugely important and
impactful for these organizations
because I I personally love from people
there was like all your SAP system in to
go look at a SEP
you should go see it through all these
topics for me
and tell me how bad it's gonna be
this is some other stuff you want to get
back to the people that have
this information MPC's
non-player characters the part of the
story without on
it would be really born born gay because
you won't talk to anybody because
gotten must other character want to talk
to you and if I was that way I'd be like
I'm attacked its character
let me alone is following me around now
non-player characters
yes
you have to have them but you also think
government in the IT security space
is your cloud providers your help desk
this is your supply chain these are
people
that you depend upon to make a product
make your support actually function
so you have to sit down and think about
it
if you need to make a story you use them
now
don't look abuse them because they was
the stock not
talking to you but you need to use them
for what they're there for
use the supply chain to figure out hey
how things are moving
materials again allow the supply chain
folks are the ones that reach deep
inside your organization to go to data
on that site if they have malware it
reaches deep inside game system to go to
the day
and time and time again it's like a
this is on this trusted administrative
VPN access that 0
doesn't have any firewall doesn't have
anything just has IP address that
that's it and they can go to yes these
two IP addresses Richard the critical
servers up the company
on understand that always remember when
you're dealing with non-player
characters
who pays the bill sometimes they forget
and that they're like all that's not in
our contract yeah
so is Slaa so is this so is that that
we've overlooked in okay I guess we're
going to have to
terminate this again a lot of times they
don't wanna do things because at the end
of the day
maybe you didn't strike the best deal in
the world
they thought you he told them you're
going to buy more
didn't buy more therefore the Commons
not ups
set with you but hey we're trying to
count on this
million dollar deal and it's only a five
hundred thousand dollar deal and we're
kind of like
myth at this you sign the contract you
live with that
so dealing with new characters
NOP snoops in the games are the ones are
like our my gosh
you need to embrace it if you like what
I'm not going to embrace an 8-year-old
in the game environment security wise
embrace the people coming out of school
and their haha to drive me nuts
that's good the one thing they cap
passion
seen it time and time again you go here
here's a turbine a lot files can you go
through this people I can be back in two
weeks
next morning he is in your office
waiting for you here to report
me but wall stop that first you make me
look really bad
second I'm when abuse if you do that
again cuz it's like wow how did you
process this
you watch not in process anything I went
hand sorted through this
Rock Hall but there's a passion is the
key
they hey what toll on now anything in a
you get up you don't have to spoon feed
it to them
it's not all dogs learning new tricks
it's a puppy and you can teach it
anything you want to
and they're wanting to learn
I'm sorry for all the students in there
are just called your puppy please
forgive me
but it is true the youth in this
the noms a newbie they're just coming
into this don't have all the baggage
that we have
to to be quite honest that governments
regulatory and compliance issue they're
not by the time they're done with this
are probably never even heard of that
they're going back to hey look now where
workstations are you ball
they've got it right in a lot of cases
because they're in
the new area versus trying to be drawn
into the new area
teach know you mentor them
catch them to your employees
here set with him but a should now mover
here
they like it they know it
you have for lack of a better term you
have
backup train but at the same time at
least the knowledge doesn't happen if
someone gets hit by a train you're not
like hopes
nothing no one knows anything in it
worst you can use them for cannon fodder
pay go distract
the director why we do something that
we're not supposed to do
sup
they're not just the security market we
have interns we have other things
go find them see come out has again the
high-tech the court
they see things that you want to be able
to see and it's really cool tool
embrace that and get them to be
deputize you can't run an organization
by yourself
it's huge its problematic at best
to try to run something so big but
if you get deputies hey arkin standing
up another web site
through this third-party I think you
should know about it
okay I will go have a conversation with
the director Mark
before you would never even known it was
there until hey here comes as PR
announcement you like hot we bang my
head on my desk but
this becomes your process it's there
leveraging used a
on AI
I really think is misused its
often abused by vendors hey
we do as we term AI
we do machine learning you're like haha
your writing parsers
now having them machine right person is
that right parsers
that is not intelligence thats parsers
one other things that time and time
again and if you talk to anybody
they're really give actors person versus
machine and then there's no te hey you
can sort i cant
I can get his lap as elastic as I need
to get
I can do a lot of processing power at
the end that and maybe a fun stuff
her brother well but if you start
digging
the unknown unknown it's always gonna
win
because there's something they are not
only person that's going to actually
find it
is the person and it
you can call it a gut feeling you can
call it some knowledge locked away they
look at something in the go that's not
right
convene never sends
two packets after
why is there to not four to
you can even get draw success
so what's up with that
why is that way
to find don't big unknown I there
something wrong
I hang on to this the right move on but
I can alter something here and sure
enough
on the whole there's something there but
it is part of the process and his
partner the intelligence in part the
people process that we kinda
slight left behind and we're getting
back to this
need people to be able to do the things
that need to be able to do
glitches they exist
or software errors we see now in there
in games
pay this treasure reappears forty
million times
I you can get killed here I can hide
behind this rock
transparent I can shoot through whatever
it yes
we all know these an all too well
no on our network their own abilities
that need patching gotta fix them we
have more up front that we have
days in the week most part A
the problem is that if you start sitting
there thinking about it inside
if you think
we have issues on this he always had a
holler for
crashed this the servers bad at all
we're really in trouble
the same thing goes for the other side
of this is well now
are the issue with clout I like to refer
to it is kinda
slightly less glitchy
because now I if you take an overall
summary of it it doesn't go down for the
most part
most the cloud providers and services
that are well orchestrated
railed on they stay up now there are
outages
I will be the first to admit their
outages but if you take that as a
a look it was down shame on it it's in
the cloud that's the reason it's like
WoW is probably a bunch of other reason
but if you took that into your own
internal
network how many times would have been
down usually there's a pretty good size
factor that it's not
so in some cases where you don't want
glitches and you don't want stuff hate
the clout does make you think just
remember
touting control it's a non-player
character give them stuff
you hopefully they'll keep it but it's
one or the other thing that's their
now pardue games
is always the Easter acts and
the Easter eggs are just at it's one of
the things that's
hidden messages inside application which
at this point if this direction never
exist if you look at secure
a life cycle for code development it is
not
it somebody sure looked at this and said
hey we do not need to put all the name
to the developers in the pictures
doesn't exist bad well apparently I'm
its okay and it still exists today you
see it in there
head of full version of Microsoft Flight
Simulator
index up
that should tell you where those fifteen
million lines have chrome exist hey
there's a online game with the transfers
jumping over
cactus or something Mike really
okay but this is something the stuff you
into
is that there always is head and thanks
but
from a bad guys version of the strengths
may leave things behind
because they're really bad a cleaning up
themselves so they leave the tools
why cuz they may come back army still be
there
the leader talks there River shells
nom hash numbers net sniffing
things because they don't want to use
your tools because your tools locked to
the Windows Server
shows off her is typically don't and
some cases
in these typically do different things
so these are tools that you search for
on a regular area now you'll never find
all that use to Rex you can talk to the
US State Department about this
like a were shut down our mail system
were shut down the network
where turning everything off because we
can't get these people
out over network as I report to rip burn
it all down
you saw that for those that familiar
with the New York Times hacked the
last year so they literally pulled up
dumpsters
and through equipment and the dumpsters
took everything out because they were
told to rightfully rightfully so
and sometimes that's the best way
because you ever you have no idea what
in fact and what's not affected and
I don't care it's very difficult to 100
these people
and more times than their but
if you look at it and in the search for
things like IP address hashes
I processes DNS requests files
registry keys I don't have
those some pool functionalities inside
my
enterprise check countries tracks at all
so I can search for you're gonna never
be able to find these tracks
they're already there they will remain
hidden
or your replacement will actually go
find them because they will
due to bad things and the network no
guarantee guarantee that
and they probably already are some cases
so if you can't look for this
come when the basics that need to be
able to be done because they're they're
every single time now
tanking so what a tanking is is somebody
that gets lots of armor lotsa boson
everything else is hey I can take a hit
rule number one there are no such thing
as major tax
I don't care when he said his there are
no major banks they were close to her
can't do anything I don't care this is
problem with that we have these common
myths the major banks
is a call compliance sorry I'm not a big
compliance person
per se I don't want think a piece a
paper really going to protect me
and a lot of cases PCI hey look we have
PCI compliance for yesterday
ok now we put everything back the way it
was I
policy and procedure look we have this
book procedures that we told everybody
and sign a piece of paper that said yes
they're gonna follow
that's not protecting you in time you
know what people are going
I mean it's good
its requirement don't rely on also hey
I'm PCI compliant typeset
now did good
get your awesome armor get your stuff
and it's one of the things that's their
com you increase the specs that matter
you increase the ability to say hey I
can respond to stuff
I'm not worried about preventing it I
know what's going to happen I want to be
able to detect and respond to that
much quicker then they have which gives
me a
beneficial to other things you look at
our attack surface
our tax surfaces static
we don't change why cuz if we change it
are that would cause problems hey this
IP addresses really now over here
womb hard to do
but the problem is that detection and
response and time is
people to mobility I can change that I
can change firewalls
I can change things on the I can add
different things into environment I can
reroute traffic if needed
given that flexibility gives me this
specs that actually matter and I know
how to fight now one of the big things
on kinky as I look at it as I R
incident response something Bad's
happened
you're gonna have to take a hit you
don't sit back and got
I we're not going to comment on that
it's going to get worse
for my kids would you are you gonna get
mad at me if I tell you
no I'm not I'm you're grounded I'm
it's one of the things you have to be
able to take the hit you have to be able
to deflect
information is there period in come up
with something good
PR firms are really good at this is
called spear
else been anything into a good thing and
you have to get to spend
appropriately
now not all games are like there are
many different types
they're like organizations not
organizations are like what works in one
does not necessarily work in another one
always play the game that you can win
not when go for the top
also don't play cuz you don't really
have a choice don't play okay shut the
doors was moved router this business
not gonna do that go for hi figure out
how to
get the talk
you know I cases everyone's plane for a
lot of ties
not for any other reason cuz we don't
have the budget or the money
to say hey these threat actors that have
nation-state kind of support including
our own nation I
really can't compete that level
so what do I do i play for the time
and again not organizations home make
the games that why choose
realize some games you lose understand
wine
go back in play here this time to play
to tie
or maybe play to win
work it
inside and understand really
the who what where how the games are
being played internal rather you want
call is politics or whether you just
want to call it
ear to the ground in this one other
comments those brought back up is
are this is really not good because this
information
is not so we don't want to release this
and is back to the same thing it's a lot
a
understanding that a lot of trust
and it's good to have the trust and its
easy to develop
they see it they go you're on top a
I'm not to worry about trust me and I
are process is much easier when you run
something
and your CEO sense thanks when you send
a message hey we got something going on
news like thank you I was like no
questions no nothing they know that pay
under control as a huge one for that
site %uh verses now he's
contacted 15 over there other people
there are contacting you going hey what
are you doing about this year
I'm answering emails not working
so this is one of the things that's
their
final boss
all games haven't the big thing at the
and it comes out and tries to kill you
when you spend 35 minutes trying to kill
it
and died five or six times and
everything else problem with security
there is no final boss is never over
it is always something going on you feel
like you're in a grocery store and it's
like cleanup on aisle sex cleanup in
Aisle seven
couch I'd like to say I'm the chief
janitor officer because I'm cleaning up
messes most the time but
it is not over and oh yeah by the way I
love clean up messes
month what you do my security people
really have a passion for what they're
actually
till final thoughts thank you
very much I really appreciate coming out
and speaking and if you need to get
ahold to me secretaries fine
om are rushing at Motorola to answer the
question there
is no extra life when you're at a caso
level
so you better grab all the power-ups all
the boss
all the pushin all the spells roles
anything that will help you
against the hordes the is of course
completely outnumbered
outclassed outmatched but it's gone
5 oh yeah
self resurrecting is allowed thank you
very much
I
thank you here today
out I'm scared you now I'm going to take
aggressive recon I
expected that I expected that
track
you think
lights
part
that
okay log question I in compliance a
question cool
confidential information up I'm
you are you have a couple a different
locks
farm question there is a data retention
policy that all companies have to say we
can keep blocks for so much
if you ever tell a lawyer you keep blogs
over that period of time
they will head will explode or twist
around side ways and
the environment for whatever I so you
have to be careful love that side of it
on the issue with locks is
you have a lot of times when you're
discovering something
like all someone releases a report or
anything else and I
look at the dates and this is this is
research done six and a half months ago
eight months ago in your like my large
go back ninety days this is really
helpful
not really so this is par the issue logs
are good to have around for ever now
logs that are online
searchable it used should not be around
forever
they should match what your data
retention policy yes so if you backup
logs are put on an
archiver some of the other stuff you can
use the talk to your rediscovery
personal data retention person say hey
this is there
because they did data retention people
we don't want on have logs for
everything to go back for however
but a good way is the least a year's
worth the locks because most the stuff
you see
is dated back to the point where you not
be able to find things
and that's kinda critical I
very critical and a lot of cases because
hey I got this IP address or this DNS
name to go back all we can to
really is kind of a downer because
you're like
I kid and you can't find think so that's
one of the key areas for that
yes
yeah
is like a deorbit a good until yet and
this is this is why you have a lot of
the places that have such a hard time
clearing out
the threat actors because they'll come
and the plant themselves
they'll mediately once they're
supplanted Dell change
their code in migrate to something house
hopefully that you won't actually see it
so you'll see that ones that are talk
but you miss one or two
point x1 they got him once before they
get in again it's not like they
don't can't get in and out at kind of
really well for most this case is so
but having the logs is hugely important
com
on that's like as you go back and in
Vail about a what's there
what's that actually outsider that and
things of
another question for lots external logs
com
going out are much more important and
what's coming and
pertaining logs for like your e-commerce
system environment crack tickling good
but typically contain a lot a PIII
information which is kinda data breach
material so you don't necessarily why
hey our web server logs which have all
this data in here retained for year
is that makes your data did abortions
very huge
so that is one of the things I'd rather
worry about extra-large rather tryna
gather things that are coming into to be
not much later
other questions yes
here
him
there is no major thank you what number
one it's back to the same thing
a you its its kinda why those think this
is OK
practically it works but at the same
time your
guessing for what
yes what current is available in its all
about what you see not necessarily in
the future and
and what's gonna that happen next in
this weather issues that comes at
you don't sit down and figure out that
hey
I don't need this I can go rapidly
recover
my stuff for anything else you look at
things such as
I we don't we don't me all these
sophisticated tools or lightweight will
this
blow things and and and completely
reflash if something goes
wrong am the new ways people are getting
an
USB I
I'll browsing hijacking
other sides ovett you're only as good as
watch you
actually developed for not what's coming
down the pipe so
at one other point sometimes it's going
to be like we've seen is that you have
the security
heard that says hey this is really
popular and think
and we fix it but we never really fix
site goes away for a year and a half an
ounce on appears back up again that's
the kind of stuff that will
defeat the major take some time and time
again that
how it we've had things we've seen
things that people might find Citrix
images and things like that like a look
all your vendors now over my where and
perfectly great South I'm
thats that's one of the areas that's
their I hope exact answer
enough or we talk more offline 12
any other questions
thank you very much