appreciate very much stepped up security
to talk here to some security aspect
experts
and to share our thoughts with you so
welcome to our talk
I'm let's clear up the de Paris what the
Snowdon leaks mean for your IT security
strategy
this work cell
okay I'm so the unique I miss it
employed
MIT security card i din for a long time
and I'm also a member of the bought
often
my NGO the fifth it's a form Informatica
on for free now because they have to be
fun photo or
computer responsibility me much computer
expelled for
responsibility in this society and I'm
kinda tough
I'm actually working for against but run
to you which is a
big insurance company of course and
afternoon do some legal a slim I also
work for fifth
I'm hand this is this
I'm officially not officially speaking
volumes but this is my private opinion
and I think over group communication
with appreciate this
okay thank you very much restarts
okay and knowing me my I okay
yeah who have you knows the slide this
is
officially from the Sloan known leaks
and this is
partners strategic partners that are
companies that cooperate with the NSA
and they say in both missions and both
missions mean
espionage and also means summer Walker
I'm okayed so I just have a question for
the audience
who have you has at least with one of
these the
guys relationships products in place
partnerships
ok Yahoo with at least three of them
no okay so ended this what we are
talking about today
you know okay that stuff okay yeah
first at all we want to talk give you a
lot of overview on the content of the
snow Knicks
the link with the security aspects send
me
do some threat assessments on but we
found and send me give you some ideas
for true can do
miss a lot I TC Q&Q strategy finally we
hope to tweak I you
some interesting a.m. discussion when
okay is a bike you discuss and ban on
pot officers known leaks
huge mister message wayans of so who
internet
some parts are really they're known like
wasn't temple are
and X ke score but there are a lot of
other awesome
which didn't got much that met
much attention night and track free and
fair skin of a tall
and mystically to and dish why our and
peace
not miss some number ass am
so Templar is this weed daily
for take on the traffic on the Internet
BakBone k birds
and made out to start even for 30 days
and excuse go offered us
and analyzes some estate of which temple
are
collects to find a needle in the
haystack
and tempo X keys coke and much more
its can also an yeah
correct date of from private persons up
computer us so they can much more than
already who does the data bitch course
sweet temple a and pesca is a given
location data
base this and five billion entries
of devised in person and its
that is connected and few days only like
thing contains
any financial transaction performed by
credit card payments
and most of the money to Huntsville
and not the Standish high up with SSM
Palo to forty-nine million
SMS Panday and asmara
program mystic with your sis 30-day
telefoni for take of addictive countries
like I am
ugh and Panama that is fun 2011
is letters well up okay
and there's no index also bought will
right that
several companies acted as Sep 2 2008
Davis suspects or and elect Petrageous
of the end is a saw ever saw in jail got
paid for his efforts
and follow now it's possible it bitch
complicated because they've lost forces
to cooperate
this fines before to head to pay
M I think I'm 2000 the
240 50 thousand
dollar per day if they don't am
properly and so they were forced to do
so a.m.
so both hand-written espero no name and
but CSC and trade for officious up
providers of the NSA
and yeah he has to soft like this the
eighties but she's Potter
just a few of them isn't a with
am are specially mentioned by name
in the league next year saw them well as
other on
last but not least you know a lot of
tech or scope to work directly
when telly the of of bylaw
for interception so and Germany we can
pay it
they did and tension close out to
Bella's
rise in the rising as the provide of
our Parliament so I don't think that the
severely
nice idea and also leveraged by a level
three is the
provide of our because internet note
he ran from Fort online though
when you look at the snow on documents
you see several different thoughts of
the day
Andreas of compromised in
IT technology so products turnout
services and supply chains
most easy saw unknown Boehner matisse
or in taste tension known and businesses
and
back to us that with i'd in
goes a bit and deniability so then known
as maybe that
and cuddle ok is a fifty-page MK don't
talk this
attacked words which can be or not by
intelligence services is easy as like
with
who offered auto were he I order a
cuddle ok
am some of the IT products among people
aged
youngster shipment if you're auto
something
miss an Amazone you might be
unhappy because you become future a.m.
but you haven't bought out a.m.
the lists intentionally
introduced be cooked resistance okay
mention Sr and bovine is a and is a
program do you think this is a breaking
of
encryption and pre-cooked to like
a.m. are sepia follow and md5
do not possess Boylan corporal I as a
tix
so the question is ya how many
IT products and services from the US
companies are compromised
and and some historical
exclusion exit clear me excursion in
fashion site
do you remember in 1990
9 seventy very over to Anna's a key
and most probably you with to weakening
so Microsoft and tonic with two
functions
and also in 1999
M builders it has become known that
lordosis
there too backdoor in his software and
questions with who ordered and anybody
heard about
top out sheep ok
yeah it's and iPhone toys in hospital
under Section
so overall nearly we have been nearly to
a tale of
of tossed in almost everything you with
and
yeah if you look at the and ketorolac
it is their hair Harshal am happier
sniffers a place in Chelsea sand couples
be done for dusky both of storage
devices
in specific a.m. be picking stations
was a bit with the customer hard disk on
Seagate
something best on the 22 a money played
it on the concall 11
militias and from there and also a
netbook at figment from Cisco
day HP hugh way am
Huneycutt netbooks a money paraded
products
of these companies are gonna be to end
is a exploits
that I mention indicate a rock there's
no evidence of active
a.m. corporations from these companies
baseness a as high as
been all the site and HP and Cisco
the wrong at first light so
in other dangerous aspect in the leaks
is the evidence
of an extensive and increasing as I just
don't
and increasing
and test because going military units
of the internet for often def a.m.
military activities
so quantum and so it is a collection of
the wood exploit swept the cations
that designed all shops pockets this as
a
and as a name for targeted attacks
against into the kids
Fox X's means performing social
engineering attacks
against adviser with of misuse
second early targets its
like admins or targeted systems
and and detain excess operation is and
as a hecka
unit dedicated to prepare into
conduct a.m. it takes and sis and unit
the oxen's and 1990 8 and the heifer
ya been 68
nine thousand baht so clever
that's complies system spankin
2011 and be think it is so hot standby
so i won army and
to him
on so the Mishnah intelligent
quiero tu framework although I S by and
for the event
President Obama but only 35 percent of
the budgets of the fight
against I was in saw
the next it was the biggest pot as
and economic a.m. espionage so
international financial institutions
like banks or insurance
identified this affect the highest
priority so
you know but that tension
with very am
but also employ and he does from
government opposition is this Angie oath
international organizations and M
United nations and the European Union
are
dust-up and so at ease a steam a
compromise
to read along and cooked it
communication
love into San Antonio covered the
in turn in for debut with of for Baines
to it for private per person easy and
stocking all for yeah stocking for
private interests
and a touch of the fees are has them
complaint
which he played a.m. quincy tradition is
call him it'd and affection activities
against
US citizen is there
saw
buys into in full well for
systematically
this information and propaganda is
intelligence services staley business
information about butts and bono 30s
influenced by intelligence services can
BS cannot fortified on misleading
define down or exhilarated
a.m. so we have
and new perspective on manhunt a porch
all
semantic we can report and
because of the lack of transparency
intelligence officers are difficult to
control
democratic control both misinformed up a
diet
and the when is a has also money paraded
financial transaction
and this two-cd too important in the
snow and you commence but both leaked
unintentionally buys a report of the
Obama Commission investigating
discovered overstep a poser
then to stop this practice and one thing
we have another talk later on
about some popping puppets and I think
this is also going in this direction
means so
the next partisan but does it mean for
the company's and former
sweats and
this opposition problems so
any company or three of can become a
target this valley Inc
impact all probability as a niece
this innovative products SBS many
picture of
security products and communication
technology even supply ass
and subcontractors of primary target can
come with
target a.m. so
by but spying and abeyance makes it
easier to identify people
especially knowledge and whites palm a
targeted
company as happens too big a calm
it was a admin who both
the thinking target so the social
engineer at the
at months of back home and then gotta
access to their networks
million yeah and me out to talk to gain
specific and useful information about
the sandwich it's
to perform advance social engineering
and
spear phishing attacks also black mayor
of loss to corroborate in Richards or
anti-age
organizations with potentially progestin
damage
to hand over a.m.
or cop allege and
me to head over corporate or government
secrets order for us all to influence
and decision makers to cooperate and
particularly interesting objects are
hosting provider of cloud service
providers hot that manufactures
suffered enough admins this privilege
excess whites
in
so we have a big challenge a.m. each
peach
a piece of the information must be
protected
but we have no MCQ communication
shiner left to do so
am so each
hominis piece of information is screened
and I S and several contains the risk of
a potential this
of and put into this and has to be
protected
internet all confidential business
communication is at Wisc because
economic and military
and would you get it is spewing ash even
climate content information of employees
is underway Kylie misuse of for talking
to takes
and social engineering Nick Muse in
meter data connection your location data
pinned a dog can review and question
information
says they are no conclusions on the
intensity
intensity and and nature of existing
public and business relationships
I'm so
every public Channahon biatch
telephone no bio said it was AP and so
on
is an observation cope with netbooks US
leased lines for Antonia and data
communication
from collaborating te course compromised
and user who were devices back to us and
not publish big news is an operating
systems and applications software
the two is better situation that no
trusted platform for and
kept chin exist anymore he also
delivers and manipulation of popular in
2010 on the
delivery wat and posh today partially
compromise them encryption technique %uh
week
computer systems even TPN hey if the
WISC
of baked was because most of them he was
an
close of their and strong exception if
body Houston just the minimum of a part
of communication
they are just so few highly
and youth X sections like
your no pgm or tr pollen and cook to
communication
with K
so we have to switch know you shit
statesman
attention nice and issuance human
important
you women's its decision from 100
mmm the complicated because
with Matthew muscle you
moment
K
so
I'm one thing we are talking about is
the threat of military usage
in and we think that this is really a
very big issue we have to look at I'm
even without facing really concrete
cyber warfare texts the already or
review have already faced some but the
its
just just the option to to use the
military things as
really have a serious threat for any of
this four dimensions of security
and I think confidentiality already
talked about with those is you not
the integrity of already talked about
with this manipulation things
am every ability is something about
someone that they
take tone systems maybe and
non-repudiation
this is really an interesting thing but
just think of the many relation of
Finance of
veteran the finance transactions or
just have in mind that you might wanna
blackmail someone you enter this pussy
and you drop some trout on it now and
you a poison the chain of custody in an
agreement the
process or so this is daily business of
secret services things to do so
okay am why
do we think that cyber weapons really a
big issue
cyber weapons or we can more column
exploits on my way whatever
I'm they need it undisclosed liabilities
course they need and because they're all
the names stuff is already known can be
fixed any pensions on
and a.m. was a useful in this building
on disclose when abilities ninety
products we already mentioned that also
so and all these things up of the
potential to bring the infrastructure
down or two
shut down the system %uh something the
switches off destroy it the
the there's another problem they can
discovered
and and exploited by everyone know not
everyone but any good Penders the press
something up that I'm and
so the come also in the hands of
non-governmental
criminals I'm we happen next problem
that private servers provide us
the
also takeovers terrain functions of the
state for
agencies like the NSA am
and maybe they wanna get some extra
money
those people or the employees are being
then they sell the things to
organized crime and if you remember
Stuxnet
that broke out by programming arrow in
the violence
so these things do not do keep in in in
a military usage
scenario but come true public and to our
normal things yes %uh maria's
military or tendon service knowledge
used for
maybe potential a text or you can use
projects already
does not remain exclusively in this
domains but it comes to public it
because
will be used by anyone um
we have other threats one is that US
companies
the are under pressure or the local
national all
and we had already seen national court
decisions against
for the to hand over there there person
their customer data
and we saw another decision this is
still ongoing in the second round I
think
against microsoft to hand over data and
one very important thing as a patriot
now I'm the Patriot Act the
has a a very specific players scored
National Security Letter and as a No
and this is really you what we call in
listening to anything to get order now
so uuuu forbid somebody to talk about
anything what happened there and they
come in they get today to offer
customers and so on and then
but what happened to mister nice guy
here this is the reason from love it
and he was lucky to have one of his
customers
with the name at what's known and then
they came now I'm
and he was you not even to contact his
lawyer for these things
and talk with them about happening on
okie should behave
when you look at your legal issues
as the contractor for other companies
you have to look at this Privacy
contracts now we have
the for for example if you wanna
for process some data and American
medicines the safe harbor agreements
I'm and they are still valid but
the a.m. for example if you have a
non-disclosure agreement with the US
companies
to you should look at this this is
really worth what it said
it s you in your paper actor you have a
chance when
and US government comes and say you have
turned over this data what about the Sun
now and I wanna go to deepen this micro
something
a wild boys Markus of going to court in
an
fighting respond because that's a
business model they have a data center
in Ireland
and the store European data personal
records of customers
and the problem is that the New York
Court wants them to hand it over for
for York's lawsuit in in in the US
and this which the be against a European
Union privacy law so they are in a
dilemma now now
and they hope that they can fix that but
that's not true
how it works I'm it is another thing I
can can can we trust on our own
authorities or is it more this another
but I'm as we think our
German government works in this things
remote server
positive for example they didn't react
on anything what
what the to go your with an ex that it
was passed
but a pin no not go past before okay
and sir yeah it's that them
but just when you look at the reactions
were they what he did when there came up
this
things to light snap there's no evidence
was noone there
the investigation committee in the
German parliament was hindered even
now and their now I don't do it is
that must be next like this
some we have seen cooperation of our
intelligence officers with the NSA
so upbeat and EU how it's going it's
part of the problem really
with long-term cooperation seen already
with all the Alice
the secret service since world war two
and a then there are the
agreements like swift agreement like
person to record a
flight agreement to hand over that and
the exchange today to
with these services: and we see the BND
cooperating with the end is a in several
levels
the there's a bidirectional data
exchange somebody
quoted stocks change for data that they
really exchange internationally between
how I have some you so you can you give
me some others
I'm they handed over the they have a
they sniffed on that the 86 note and
praying for and we have a joint venture
rumor for civilian space in but I bring
though they operate this together
just sit by seed Anna
we have the end as a dare complexes in
this is juicy them
dumbstruck and that was cool fun as the
German tax money really as a wee bit up
some some
rescue nassir stations here in Germany
just against the civil service
that's interest I'm and the B&D also
uses X the score
which was one of the two instruments
before and also of a possible short-run
supply list
I'm yeah German government wants to
become one of five riser amendment
am sub contractors and consultants of
the NSA
are also used but German government was
one popular example which is in a
discussion just CSC in a moment
so
and when we look at this mall and
undisclosed one ability problem
miss the Nystrom stopped going on %uh
so this is more or less a governmental
Trojan horse and its
talk tomorrow for lawful interception
open crib in traffic so
permanence for example
and the Constitutional Court Germany
called it
illegal in the way they used to stand
and made it a bill that
and the the problem really behind
all these things is that the wrists or
this is that the one abilities
that these two issues have to be
disclosed cannot fix them you cannot
the fix your home company-owned economy
their own citizens so you can publish
the problem but you have have to use it
and that's the same when you use them
for cyber weapons and military way like
the German armed forces is now trying
and I'm yeah
we had some discussions about the meal
which is a German
initiative a project to to spread hours
good encryption for citizens and that
was just US layer
based encryption as a transport Leah and
the
there is an option for entry encryption
and I think there's no discussion going
on to implement pgp on it
but it took really some years already
and not of critics
the because nearly use this and their
use already see the influence of the
the services of the security services
that that didn't really want the
citizens to communicate securely
they wanna intercept these things and
the latest example is the recent
election of the trip to warning page
we hope that already ended in in the
last century
and that it is coming up again like a
zombie
and yeah you know it's installing back
doors for
the recovery key escrow in encryption
things or governmental issues
so let's go to the PSI
the so this is this is a German BSP
I'm the in authority I'm
that is all or also you meant for
Falcons outings citizens and companies
that's why we're talking about here we
think that the vs
he fails to protect really the company
it is not
independent it has a conflict of
interests as it has to follow the orders
of ministry up in a fast but belongs to
minute also exists for the interests of
the intelligence services in the same
house
and the there was
not solely so I think this week that the
BND also yeah it was yesterday
that the BND also worked on this top
story on a
and helped to develop its untested so
this is the problem I meant Sony the
should protect people and they develop
our
now I'm and some members of the couple
Department of the India
wendover for the BSC
also so these are for for mommy and the
people's
in parts and the BS report one yr
abilities from proven
yeltsin's yesterday we know why she am
and so and this is another question how
far can we trust the cons I think the B
is your fucking trust certifications
they of our issue
to someone you not gonna miss all the
smoke grenades this information
propaganda things
the as we mentioned intelligence service
the daily business
but what about the consultants working
for them what about the vendors and the
partners of the people
can we trust their recommendations can
we trust what they tell us
their search in study results we rely on
this really
that might be cool financed by someone
suspicious I'm now what about
consignments of collaborating companies
now just just think of this thing on the
NIST standards which were compromised
and we can't
and when one very special
friend of us is the mandiant report
there's already
the drone is is a an example for
attribution how we can
find the the attack over Cybertech and
yeah it was already mentioned anything
some some
troopers ago as a as a template to blame
how to blame the Chinese
just if you wanna camouflage is a
Chinese Ateco you just look at this
and you know how to do it and two men
and a boat was fun at Presidio Rd
yeah so so
this is a lot of threats and then you
look at this I'm
I'm we have we have some things
how the intelligence services the X the
this is really nearly zero if they could
or
even political %uh journalistic juneau
them limitation what the
have our they they do not consider of
diplomatic problems that you are when
they act
the with Italy's even I think we release
may not
the advisories a.m.
they they do not interest and the
reputation of US companies they might
force to cooperate
%ah I'm they do not who is it aids the
to no good customer confidence or
violating even though their own
constitution
so no limitations at that place and what
isn't
the most daring me think is is this they
wanted all approach
so they want everything resist going on
the internet on some
companies on that works with whatever
and that means that they don't accept
secure throws and try to compromise
anything
and that means any information is a
potential sensitive one
it has to be protected because it can be
misused for social engineering attacks
for looking profiles about means they
can attack and so on and so on
I'm yeah I'm most existing IT products
and technologies
a compromise somehow or there are
weaknesses in their
mmm we have vendors and service
providers cooperating
also problem we have no assistance from
our government
consultants research studies rely on
yes but now so after all
we have to consider that they are also
it takes on
on the hiring fruits so it's not just
this most things they do it anyways any
permitted to of course
but this anything what they can do
they will do is this is I wanted all
approach now
and so you have to think of if you
interesting enough in this I'm going to
think something is interesting enough to
F
the Met right so we also have to
consider paranoid scenarios
arm upcoming things that
might be very theoretical in the moment
or very
very costed and support a causal
so
the let's go what what can we do about
all this
now from so when you look at all these
things is
same now it's hopeless we have no chance
to defend against these things
we have to give up the fight and we
think
yet we have a huge showmanship butts the
and there's no easy is up a lot of
course
but we should and according to restrict
phase
we have to do something I we have to the
mountains think and
what we think of is a long term or a
midterm ballistic and big investor
approach
so that's something else and you said
for the Microsoft thing you have to do
anymore
them and we we call it stop crying on
the rear rotor farine
those are reroute overall what we call
the
for my strategy is really based on close
of products the
based on ever use the Internet as a nice
non-military zone where no battle
field is I think this is this is the
wrong way
so and that means that you might see the
write-off for decades have invests in
the wrong products and the wrong
directions
cop thing but you should do this as soon
as possible and as soon as as much as an
affordable
and you should look at your vendors and
suppliers
as well as a depending pros says and
maybe you have to change some things
here
look at your outsourcing contracts
perhaps you should terminate the 10
yellow
this and avoid black box
close all software solutions or products
check them replace America possible
we have some new consequences we have to
to follow
so a media ski pack up the paragraph 11
assess you have a mandatory check of the
liability of your subcontractors
so just check to the list of the
subcontractors if they cooperate
and think if they are still reliable in
this mean
so what is what is massive aliens and
supporting massive aliens for
for and intelligence service it's nearly
the the opposite of
for privacy really wants from you now
and
for mister providers and therefore any
outsourcing contracts the
has to be reviewed and probably
terminated if it's with the wrong person
and new contracts also risky
since their customers become a more
aware of this
the thing after the scandal so we really
realize this
the discussions and there's some privacy
activists mites
stocks on lawsuits against you if you
don't react
on these things and better education is
anything
nothing very good Anna privacy laws also
with the safe harbor thing which is
still valid and the moment but the
European Union Parliament
already discussed to end all this trade
agreements to and thus the
fly to a peasant agreements lift and
also say power
was no discussion and maybe the bases
is away then I'm I already mentioned as
Microsoft thing
I'm another thing as liability in
general not just in privacy way
when you do not choose a reliable
partner there might be other
if things that come into a liability
term
you can lose your crown jewels of course
in that may cause some some lawsuits
also
as for stock operations for example
there might be a fine and financial loss
lawsuits from from
showers and investors and the for our
company and also
many others we have special management
lab I L liabilities forests
from mistakes and failures and risk and
emergency management so if you don't
react and if you know better
then you have a problem liability and if
you know your
you are you a victim up a potential
victim of espionage and you have to do
something
and the very specific thing is
the liability for disturbance if you run
and critical
infrastructure that will be a very
interesting liability problem
so too I think week skip this because we
haven't done much damage should be think
that is totally stupid to build up with
German or is european internet or
something that
sup yeah but I think it's very simple if
you if you look at it
review yet multinational companies bf
this supply chains international
we cooperated in every other continents
so the stupid to
as you know and we need to talk about
what we can do
Beach them we can check and rework our
outsourcing guidelines and contracts for
example and
I think it's a good idea to include some
no spy clauses in these contracts
and to the Mons this also for
subcontractors and that
becomes very tricky am purchasing
department guidelines
why do not have a positive rating of
somebody who says
I do not cooperate with intelligence
services
that might be a plus a natural selection
of provide us
yeah careful choice of security products
and services
I'm yeah look at two hidden back doors
and and and
collaboration just just imagine you you
run in
the 90 s and this is not looking at
specific things
especially because they ever forced to
do so
I think we had some discussions on fire
yesterday Aurea II discussion
yesterday in debt yes that's what I'm in
and wherever possible test the
effectiveness if the surrounds good
I'm also against the sophisticated
attacks
mean donde voy black box things and
close all solutions
another thing what you can do is going
to increase
I'm we we face that there's no strict
segregation
anymore between private life and
business life so you have a BYOD
bring your own device scenarios 00
one another example is Facebook accounts
if you're
run business Facebook account somebody
then you also use that for private
purposes because facebook allows only
one
so if you are in Facebook for
from person for your company and then
you are also your private person there
so there's there's just one account for
this or privates
calendars and and and business calendars
if
the people still have two separated once
and that's not all
the case the then they were synchronize
the state's
now so there are there's there's no
restrict a room
a strict line between these things
anymore
so what you need to do you have to
engage your employees
by their own personal and private
motivation on privacy and security
and raise their rounds on the risks of
private and secure behavior and the
public or in the private
to social networks or whatever and
and the also for their devices security
for the devices of your employees a
private devises
is the miss you give consultancy and
support for these things
it said anyway for a company why don't
give
some regulations for how to secure
private equity firms or something about
I'm
if you use the BYOD this should be in
good idea anyway you
I'm and and think of this folks s at the
spear phishing attacks against employees
so also just talking about how I'm
working for ions another
and I'm doing this and this and this is
nice can be a respring you
and it can be reached the day or two
open to whatever your
that happens then and the nothing teach
them to encrypt
as it's quite is simple you know the
crypto party
to movement so we started already to
make a purple party
corporate parties in our company just
service and part of that is normal I T
education program and the Texas of
course Jeffrey software
in or at least open source products
which is not the same
when I'm talking about free software I
mean richest or months to finish in free
is the meaning of freedom
not a free beer and there's no free
lunch
and that leads the to the thing you
should support
if you can free software projects with
Mani
now especially if you use them 44 pretty
good things
like encryption so a you should finance
called audits
and quality reviews on on these products
I'm
and if you develop close of the might be
a good idea to release it at that
gets that gets better now for the public
fee some back find us I like to build us
know your company developers to publish
them fermentation and free
licenses I replaced no source wherever
possible
and we had a lot of discussion about the
hot be back and yes it's the stupid
thing and it's really really really bit
but we think that it's it's morning
sample it that
open source really works because the
back find this movie founded
texted now so in that was possible
because they could look into a coat
how many problems do we haven't lost
souls products when you have these in
open source things
now I
go over this I'm encryption as the
cure-all silver bullets arm I'm
at once known said that strong cripple
still works that's nice
and that's why I N is a has this big
bull run program to
outbreak on these things butts I'm
there are some recovery in some products
you have to skip of
and nothing is you should use
strong cryptographic possible not just
in the
I wrist scenarios I'm any replication
you have should be
security Anna you should use perfect
forward secrecy always think I don't
have to mention it here but
and it should be d-fort for anything why
it makes this they wanted all approach
difficulty
they have to look more and they have to
spend more resources on breaking all the
stuff
and so they might over see also the
important things that they can
concentrate on on the other way so why
not
have Nena you make night in any company
with the
pre-configured s my more pgp installed
on it
and ready to use for every customer
every ad hoc
this contrarian cryptids from so you
know it's the that
them now and also demand and offer
encryption communication
options whatever to your partners to
your customers
so make the
I want it all approach more difficult
for the NSA one problem really be faces
that we do not have really trust its
encrypting and decrypting devices
anymore when we look at all these things
we just mentioned you some but this is
really a problem
you have to work on I think there's
another talk from from banish the
compound
the about the secure hardware maybe
we've
find something there Anna
using Rhys noon yeah
this this a normal things you should do
anyway segregation the Central Asian
as Asian redundancies I think that's
it's quite obvious that the
reduces the risks if somebody comes in
it's not that easy to
that the whole network is owned and so
on an you have better control its on on
your network boundaries
you have the robustness against a.m.
perhaps even a cyber warfare tech and
isolationists
thing widely mentioned this year because
it's the opposite of what
some management's to really in the
moment so for
security people it's clear but today we
have to tell the messages
necessary in still this is something
be caught it advanced paranoia
procedures
so if you accompany you with the
on this on this Obama list with a high
priority so we are not high priority
with just seconds high-priority
if you're a military unit what you
produce arms
then your more interesting but if you're
Finance Institute if your insurance or
something like that
then you're in the second highest
priority list already and
for the protection of your very very
crowned roads
you should look at these things expect
also the unexpected
so this is what I meant the mites
get some sophisticated attacks this is
theoretical no its not theoretical
they might use it it's important am
the shipping problem you are some
software they open the box
and they put in some sniffers in perhaps
you should mask
a radio delivery lines I don't know the
possible
to go to a third party in TA order that
for me but don't mention that it's from
be
trusted provider party baby without red
carpet man of my company
you %um interesting I'm
but remember they have traction and they
can re
the you locate any order over any credit
card of
in that there was a company kind of this
company okay so these routers going to
this company
just many played a bit and another
challenge
is conspirator if business meeting so if
you wanna plan a merger and acquisition
you wanna by another company or you get
bought by another company and there's
some some
organizational things the in place and
the well the booking for this conference
before this meeting the
hotel reservation this is interesting
how you do that
without using your company accounts for
this and maybe you should book a private
holiday you
trip to the same whatever exotic
location we also the other person's life
to
I'm and yeah
just managing Outlook calendars or are
these these commanders
over across the company's and and doing
this in a cryptid way
or at sending the invitations to improve
chances already a change a thing
and just to with uses to refer this to
avoid the metadata
in so this is really paranoid 13
that but I heard that there was a
company doing this
datacom yet to come yeah okay I'm
so again I mean look at this priorities
of course start with a quick wins stop
now to change your IT security is pretty
in the right direction
to what's free and open software only a
had crowded further funding for and
companies fund the development of secure
open source solutions and platforms and
there's another thing
nothing we can't fix that just on a
technical way but we need pressure on
politics
so you should ally as this
company isn't as private persons with
associations in the civil society
against this massive Agency Inc
and against cyber warfare and of
intelligence services in our internet
because we use at all and that's why we
had some earlier
to is funding from the fifth campaign
really wants a running
the cyber peace campaign and we're
trying to work on the politician
political pressure against all these
things yeah
so we come to a last letter opener yeah
so I said is it hopeless
those who fights can lose those who do
not fight have already lost
thank you for your attention