that
I
well West
air whatever care to hide
I I welcome every month to a lil
workshop
a just a few words before I start
we come from so what it's a a little
town on the north of serbia
and the with itself so development for
embedded systems
so this a subjective this
workshop is embedded Linux device
drivers
a I will keeper are all
give are short introduction I will keep
it short because
the we would like you to have the more
hands-on experience than the
long talk
so about the embedded systems what is
more
most characteristic about an embedded
system
it's a it's dedicated function so
by the finish in are embedded system is
a system which is a part of a larger
system
which one dedicated specialized function
it's the usually based on
microcontrollers
microcontrollers the are basically
Cebu's which the differ to standard
general-purpose jib use because
they usually have or they always have
onboard memory and peripheral
controllers
one more thing which is important from
the standpoint of the microcontrollers
is the optimization
that means that a microcontroller is
usually highly optimized for
I'll special task for for example
there are a
digital all the a process or the SP's
the
another the
think about the microcontroller
controllers today
they are there is a very at the OFC
applications basically a
from from the
applications in consumer electronics
doing just industrial
the applications then there is health
care applications military and so on
from the hardware standpoint
as I already mentioned the specific
thing is that the peripherals are
on chat you have all the needed but if
ariel's
on your microcontroller the many CPR
detectors
are produced so the
for example an IPS the
the some proprietary like or
and I S the architecture the
however today the most popular
Architektur is
arm by far the from the standpoint
of the world length they are usually
from aids to 32 bits
but today for example the ARM processors
sorrow
available in 64 bits as well the
another great thing about these platform
is that there is
a lot of cheap development boards so
anyone can
start working with them for example the
are the No which you already probably
know
another the important
the term is SLC system-on-a-chip this is
basically
a highly integrated microcontroller
which consists usually of
more than one microcontroller you have
one sort of a
general microcontroller and for example
hardware decoder
and the set the father chips which do
for example digital the processing and
so on
saw
the from the standpoint of Peru for
reals
the
the there is really almost anything that
you could the
imagine from Syria Communications Inc
interfaces
to synchronous serial communication then
there are the union is there a
Universal Serial Bus controllers network
interfaces
Field buses these are mostly
characteristic for industrial
applications then the timorese
and the discrete
input/output general-purpose
input/output ands
analog to digital or digital to analog
converters
so
this is the typical hardware which you
will find one
microcontroller not all but let's say a
combination of these
so a about them bad Linux
the its similar to the microcontroller
its purpose-built
so we optimize it for the application
which
we needed for the
it by definition it's the
consists of a colonel and the minimal
user space the minimal use a space
might be the made usually with the
buildroot
or it might be embedded into the kernel
itself it's the so called in at around
FS from the
a standpoint of the device drivers which
are our topic today
the you can see that's
the device driver actually provides
a connection between the physical device
and the use a space so
that's the role of the driver from the
standpoint of Linux Linux
the creates the very at the very a tix
classes of devices
they are at for devices
storage devices USB devices and so on
typical operations when the you want the
rights
a driver is memory mapping often
internal tunneling handling and
application of
various time routines for example
application of high-resolution timorese
and so on
and
sensor our topic is
or are subject is a workshop I would
like to
give the world to my colleague Andrea
who will now
proceeds with the actual workshop
but the in the meantime before we switch
the you can find all the sources for our
workshop on these
URL's my name is underprivileged a I
will
dodi practical demonstration all this
are there soul a
first all a this presentation and the
practical example is
is built upon is based upon buildroot
so in order to builders you actually
does
do the it glow depository you run
a few simple commands soul first all
make Raspberry Pi
the config so this is the default config
for for the Raspberry Pi
the builder to keep in close this it
will a
make a configuration file for this you
can run make
and config to adapt this if you want
and then run make so it will actually
build everything
at that point so it will download
absolutely everything that it needs so
starting from our
compiler for your host computer to the
Linux kernel sources and everything good
that you have selected for the target
platform
and of course depending on your hardware
this can take from
maybe 15 minutes to over on our key
and questions or
non-traditional key and
a presentation and a moment through
but apart a.m.
okay so I have the rent on and its
booting I have already built the entire
build rodin's
copied it to and as the card and it's on
the Raspberry Pi
so this is the system booting and
the wrong from looks like this and but
basically it's very minimal
system okay
and
case I have prepared a few examples and
should have opened most to them key
it so the
most basic example adjusts so this
is the little driver the for single
length driver needs
is and in its function and an exit
function
so you define these a
they have some predefined a template
you can name it as you want you use this
moderate micro to actually defined for
your module
what is the in its function and this
model doesn't really do
much its basically the most basic
GPIO a model that you can have
so when the model initializes here
it will right out hello and then it will
a iterate through this array that have
defined
saudis been numbers are
actually from the datasheet all the
hardware
and I have connected my abilities
directly to these GPIO Ste so
this not random you have to know your
hardware
want to actually do so you need of
course to
do some includes and
basically to rate over the think a
requests
the GPIO that you want to use configure
it does
a note the direction and give it a value
one so it will go to I want to urge
this is trip when she was seen this
case and the core the return function
has two the
in function has two Ritter for the exit
function
a similar things done but in this case
it will actually so it again computer
the output
direction on the GPIO and will give a
value of $0
so it will turn off so doesn't really do
much but this is something that you
start to build from
and I have older a in this case the dust
everything you that you see here is
available already under get absolute can
disclosing its and you can just its
run a simple make command it will
build you'll have a few files
the most important is this one that and
we'd dot
K 0 so that's colonel object or
a module a loadable module so
going back to our as brit by I can login
here
I have already rebuilt and Coppins
all the models here so because they woke
up sometime and
I can't insmod insert module
this first example
and it will say hello and if you look
around here you can actually see some to
Bo's light up
and here as in don't you and if I remove
the module
the model name is actually
raspberry GPIO but I have does rename
the files for
when loading I can distinguish which 1i
want which was I want to load
and when I remove its it will say bye an
adult or not the Tribune does
so simple so
you know there's no dark we do magic in
writing a driver
can actually start very simple so for
the
next example this one
actually starts also from the in this
function
months apart from outputs you can also
have
inputs so imports are purely buttons or
switches or
something similar and of course
just like you requests the you the Dove
GPIO pins for output and you said
I want this one to be an output in the
same man are you do
again our requests for an empty
for a GPIO an essay and I want this to
be an important
and one more thing so
this example does is it initializes
timer
called oblique timer
Richwoods obviously do some blinking and
for so this is defined here
as a global structure so
this you initialize East Timor you say
it has a function and then when
a time at the course this function will
be called and we actually start timer
the so disc daytime Sat
he's fun is function which converts
normal time to jeff is which are
internal to the kernel
timing mechanism so this will do one
second and 0 90 seconds
and of course so when the
timer triggers it will call
dysfunctional
and in here I had defines us that
credible Richwoods
change each time by negated
and for these outputs I
do some Maduro I
random I in all done even numb
number bins woods have different outputs
and I also
readout the input pins so I can
do get value of
I think the been and bring this to the
the bulk terminal
so a the show this so this would be
this while and now its
drinking and
its as I had said its showing the
input values so he has to input pins
define
and they are both at a high level the
this is because how the harder it
connects I have
connect to this d buttons to short the
input been to the ground when is pushed
so I'll
doctor that this
one of these got there
you know
novel
this
okay so this mattered unearth
reading out imports at predefined time
intervals is called
bowling but it's not really a great idea
because a for fast signals or if
somebody's board
you can actually put a release the
button before timer triggers
and this something you would not catch
because
at the boat I'm should read this the it
will be in the
high-value so you can miss some signals
and this is where interrupts come in and
interrupt is
a sort of a signal in the process or
when something changes and you can
for all these the DPI owes separate
unloaders
to stop it
okay so the next one is
interrupts so a similar
thing for the timer so I'm that the same
but I have also done
so for this people pins I have
requested the GPIO but I can also
request
interrupt a IR Q is interrupt requests
so i forward this the DPI number two and
threw up
and do some more flags so I once
to be notified when this signal is
rising
and when this signal is falling so when
it changes from 0 to 1
and one from 120 so in both of these
cases
are real gets this function called
reads my GPIO well actually with the
interrupt number and then I conclude
that so
other than that this example does
basically the same thing so it's
again when it's unloaded it'll turn on
turn off everything and
it still has that Steiner so this is d
example number tree
K so again its linking
its bowling but when I also touch the
bottom
it will show up immediately thats
the signal has been requested under so
this
okay so as you can see it still bowling
is still reeling
but even in the middle if something
changes it will notified right away
so basically thats trigger din
interrupt handler function is called
this one in
I get the interrupt number a bit I
converts to
GPIO number and then I readout that
value
and I bring that to the terminal so as
you have already seen on the example
so it's nothing really the complicated
but it's very useful that you don't
really have to asks
so sure doing communication too hard the
trip don't really have to bother that
chief reed
are you ready are you ready are you
ready are you ready
no it real notify you when it's ready
you know at that moment the trip will
attendance output level and actually do
something like pushing a button
and you get this interrupt and when you
get this interrupt you can actually
ask that cheap exactly hey what's up
what do you want to tell me
and then to say okay I have some data
ready for you I
or there something wrong or something
whatever
but you don't really have to constantly
ask
and is really bad practice to constantly
all
signals and ask they are ready are you
ready are you ready
okay so a going on
a okay so we have
time are which blinks but wouldn't it be
nice to actually
be able to turn that of or on on demand
so this is what's the next sample oz
so a the
initializing functions has grown quite a
lot
so for this for studying you need
to register or device class
so your device driver needs to belong
somewhere
and that some were at war would and up
in here
and
so
UN sis class you have the
different classes for a device drivers
and inside that those you
would then have various drivers and
components
so first we need to a make a class
where this driver would would be long
and of course I have Picts an
appropriate name
knock-on 2014 and
through complete so next thing
is to read author character device and
well
character devices are some legacy but
not really legacy but
the first type of driver that ever
remains so basically they emulates a
serial
inputs and outputs reads a file so you
have
a Berto file which has some reading
rides
handlers defined and you can write
something to that file
and this would be returned to your
hardware or a memory buffer some Thai
that
and again when you read something it
would go in the other direction
but a this will be handling the next
example
but for the starters you need to
actually have on
objects in crawlspace Richwoods a
have some other structures defined with
it so first you need to define one of
these
character devices k so your def I
you click create a class you register
character device
you create that device so you can
actually had something the
in the whatever and
that file woods be registered in created
automatically
and then with this you can actually
the well apart from that you would also
have I'm
a truck to load the module and show it
so insist class I have now on local
2014 and in here
I have a raspberry GPIO example
as I have defined this Ford desde if
device name and
the stink as a so somebody's our default
so you can have this Devin they've file
which actually gives you up major and
minor
number for the Linux kernel
drivers so every character died device
in so I have now
also created this file and so we also
have the same
major number and minor number in here so
a a system like you dive or something I
that's
handles this device tree can great sorry
remove these as needed but
in any case so you need also so
in here says class so our class our
driver
you also can gets this directory and
with it you can do whatever you want
so what I wanted to do is create this
blink control and
to do this I actually had to define a
read function for this file
and a right function for this file
so basically d read function
those tracks whether the time are is
active
brings that is an integer as in 0 or 1
and that's it the right function woods
read out what's was given in this
buffer written to from the user a
Conger that to an intruder and then
check
do you want to turn it on or off so if
you want to turn it on
and it was not active than actually 2d
start the timer if it was already active
than just
right out some informational message and
in the same manner as you want to turn
it off check whether it was
already of and than just don't do
anything
so I can actually writes
something to this and
timers not actor it was starting and I
can now turn it off
and to start blinking so its
quite simple so you actually have to
define a few functions like this
you define this attributes with a macro
called link say what's
Rd permissions on its so
I want this to be a reason right for
absolutely everybody
who has extras computer swords
readable by the user group others
writeable by the user group others
your lame two functions and then
this attribute is given put inside the
oven
array and that that's put inside the
group
so yards kinda love a little containers
layers but for this then you just say
a greats Asus affairs group
read this object that I have registered
here so this device file the
character device file that group and of
course
if there are some that are return back
and of course if you are unloading the
module damn you'll have to actually
removed that
as well so basically whatever you have
great ads
when the model is on loads destroy its
otherwise you can be left weeds
a whole lotta crap and
the I'm
the fifth example actually
uses that character device so a one very
nice example of character device
is seven segment display which you can
see
on the board and
it's actually going to print out some
numbers well
d number sequence and you actually see
the display it has
done that okay so this this time now
this now this file actually has function
so I can
do something write something to it
and of course this is some garbage that
will be
outputs and spit will do some
alien language signals but this is also
not really
difficult to connect so mmm
whom
okay so you have to define a final
approach instructor for this character
device
then you have defined rights
open release and both course reading
from
a samsung Display is not really a useful
thing to do
but I have putting a prototype just in
case you wanted
so a when you open its
when you actually want to write
something to that file first you
open its then you called the right
function then closing down so you have
to define altri not just the right
functions
okay so you you open the device there's
a
you text so for mutually exclusive
access
sold no two processors can lights at the
same time to thats
character deweiss so if the
new taxes on available then say this
device is busy
and just abort and otherwise the
you text will be logged in you have
access and you can actually call deride
functions
the right function doesn't function
doesn't really do much
its does does again
GPIO output for a
I have defined for these the Sun segment
display for
each segments 1gb I L and Justin
disarray
so its bits has
whatever a sold since characters are it
betrayal use
what I rights to this character to eyes
I have just
did a bitmask and shifting and basically
one bit
is written to one segment so if you do
some issue do know how it's arranged you
can actually writes
a number sequence or some signal that
you want
so you can so dysfunction gets cold
and it's actually configures the GPIO
those you can see the output
and this is well basically
how you don't communicate weeds very
busy car this how you actually
communicate with
even advanced hardware some cases you do
with masking you do GPIO input/output
but of course if you want some high
speeds you
used already predefined protocols like I
square see
SBI or something like that I you can
beat bank most to them so you can
actually do
fine-tuning vote you can match
bit masks and 2 o'clock out the clock
out that online
in and then signal output and all other
and achieve some results butts it will
be slow
so she want to communicate with proper
hardware trip dan
use a some better signal but for the
sake of this
introductory example this is basically
what I have wanted to show you
so now we go back to the presentation
and key question slides and
so any questions okay
should space
versus re me you right
or all and
this a datasheets
are something to rally very painful to
obtain
for some reason did slight top-secret
military
achievement or something i I don't
really know why
so if you want to write a your
own custom-made hardware and drivers for
thats
up becoming a factor that actually
cooperates and gives
data sheets with the trip otherwise you
will have had eight
I mean somethings even if you do get the
data sheet
it will not be completes it will lacks
information
or it will be and the wording can be
also quite confusing and you don't know
that
for some some things to do you have to
reduced to do some other things and
initialized things differently if you
want
to run in that other mode or something
like that so yeah
if you reverse engineering is doable
but takes too much time in Leeds maybe
not worth the effort
any other questions
I'll take that as a No sold
thank you for a time and your attention
%ah
then
the
that