that
well West
air whatever care to hide
you thank you to lose probably only
the course not that's not playing the
dirty news last year's but
anyway well talk about some
cause issues for sergei police and what
I'm
gonna tried to do today is basically is
a
I inform you about some issues
that we research air defenses share from
nation deal with on a daily basis in
regards with the
to freedom of speech online from several
different aspects like
technical aspect I legal aspect and
ethical aspect so I'll
assign with this story which is probably
a familiar to you at least for those of
you who are from serbia
its I'll take it each and I said
who I've subtitle little support would
teach because
its the title of the material that
course this entire entire
I'm story first hole during just almost
no loss in northern Serbia
memory this year data then the
first black president of the government
the present prime minister
I took part in the rest reaction and it
was seeing the place peckish
here in vojvodina I to national TV
ifas drug test the video a video
ish rescue action some structures
who are disagreeing with dish populous
state
day think it's populism policy ought to
a Prime Minister a thought dead dish
have duplication
to react somehow indeed a day major
parody video which was published in your
chip
it had some the circus update or someone
you might have
CA and soon after the published a video
images appear
on the Internet with the above
because its copyright claim submitted by
Amy K
visa dish so on digital distribution
company Beijing
Vienna Austria deduce so responsible so
to speak
for distribution of copyrighted material
I
the the company claimed a as:
the national television %uh serbia was
your client but a
to date until today actually no written
agreement between DA
at JS and the kuch dil
is is presented so we've got something
like this
I don't know if you can really probably
can
the bigger parks on the
the video I was published and no was
republished by several
I channels on YouTube and are
it disappeared from each and every every
one of them and a problem back then was
it
people didn't really make call piece on
your hard drive so the video so there
was
not really oh we school to put do feel
bad
bed online which has fortunately change
I which I'll but I'll talk about that
somewhat later during the presentation I
so Serbia and what ironweed really
dealing with is
basically this is the saddest vicious
of our the most recent statistics of
a virtual adjoining July this year we
had the
dishes are all up news portals and
journalist related
sadistic streak at six cyberattacks on
I news agencies to use Portales web
sites
six cases of physical pressure
on journalists like no no digital but
real
pressure a political pressure on
undernourished to court decisions that
can potentially harm to freedom of
speech is it easy
which is not deny really good change
nowadays hysteria
and I'm up because a police
a a events a
international community and a and the
professional public and experts actually
in Serbian international
submitted by the negative reactions
which were
unfortunately pretty much neglected do
legal framework
is searched everything it is
unbelievable the
nationally and internationally and
internationally and I'm just going to
show you some some parts
both issue regulations i I believe it
the declaration was side to quoted
couple days ago here as well so
according to the united to Nations
Universal Declaration of Human Rights
article 19 actually um says that
everybody has a right
also opinion and expression um
the freedom to to hold without
interference
%uh to hold opinion so without
interference so
nobody should you should use mines to
people to make your opinions
and I expressive throat and the media so
there are no limitations only to
traditional media
which means danger 90s also cover be
this article
all done universal the cooler
Declaration of Human Rights
and the Constitution of the Republic of
Serbia in article forty six esta to
freedom of thought and expression shall
be guaranteed
and it can be restricted but only in a
certain cases which do not include um
something that's called the
political opinions is a my me
a makes this case was clearly
politically incorrect so to speak for
for a certain person which had it
removed
I my he here are only some cereal
those serious so reasons why include
freedom of expression being restricted
whatever parent because he/she
day something and make it funny did he
spare and
percent article 5.3 K
so the information missus at
directed by the EU which is not
obligatory by the A's
a an example of a post-practice for
EU member states answered yes country
that aspires to the European Union
should be in accordance with these
director says an exception to copyright
infringement infringement
if day in france je for his be used for
the purpose of caricature party
were besieged then again we also have a
local or national law that regulates the
same thing any such totally not
accordance with Jay
European a European for reunion Fremont
and it says that
350 shimon to publish corporate project
at work is a large
when it concerns I'm not among other
things parody or carry pitcher
so I'll watch fish really did debase
for a for censoring DC
this video her according to the laws has
a ship should not be applied to
republicans is a serb it is not too low
actually it's fine to the Constitution
of the Republic
and I'm and then again I
censorship is forbidden to do is
conducted that's that's unfortunately
the
the reality apps a survey and who is the
sasser
any it's really hard to answer this
question but
I put some pictures here dead
moms and some kinda masses
lay government protecting you from your
reality
today really have to write to the bed
did
them the logical stay a
muster most the conventional media could
be satellite TV newspapers
et cetera is changing and because it is
not on an alternative to independent him
a sources to have a mechanism of
publishing hear their findings their
information
online without depending on budget so
or I don't know where the tourists et
cetera n
people kept taking it online with music
several different
different waz I've bullet tweeter first
because the Twitter community
is serious quite strong fortunately and
people are really tweet
about important changes not just for fun
but a
it's just cereal serious social
social and political political from
connotation and facebooking lower as
well not so much a straighter but
Madonna gender changer also in important
way to distribute
tweets so basically derringer also
significant Jess Jeter
part of the missing you know the slow
side
food here actually are some I
organizations or web portals that
I used by a independent journalists and
investigative journalists
to to reach out to the public jerry is
shining
and the CS don't national once
and doin aight only use ciation which is
an international
association of over 2,000 I
different agencies or a information
agencies do it
deal with investigative and only only
gene only singer vital for
for our democracy at the moment because
I in some way Jersey review only
so probably a trustworthy
media outlets not being sasser
even though they're under pressure
constantly but different
political and economically strong
structures
and we get dis this is something that
was
quite of chain and is seen serbia
jurate me two months of May and June
July does you who
who leave here probably remember for
sure certainly remember the
on many also I'm the news portals that
reported
I information regarding done Florence
and
the floods that have been made this year
and we have come to be heated
tho with and entire story where taking
Dom
no due to DDoS I attacks
some different bonanza attacks which I'm
going to
talk about a little bit later in the
presentation so basically we go out
I
the errors under on the web sites and
a people were panicking because they
were does is so
whole website website taking down
during period of 24 hour stores no
capacity
to mediate debt eiffel of attacks
and now we come to the challenges with
charger
miss something I'm now let us something
someone to oversupply me some the
mission of
know what I what I said are earlier
and and doom several different types a
challenges only five
to 10 maybe percent videos
as attacks can can be you really clarify
intervene in the Sasso
determining your source and
a month so boss a
included any tax so in most of the cases
not really possible to to determine
where is the
DDoS attack came from from the first
place you meet
you see the botnet route but she didn't
know who is dead brain on the
entire operation you can only make some
suggestions which are you not really
backed up with wat strong evidence which
is
I we changed it dan you cannot take
that case to court because it it Kong
dreamy
whole our deposit provider so
fortunately I know
are not usually very helpful because you
today
acknowledge germ I presence of such did
US tax dept and gives them a better
education that
their servers and not release a very
strong enough to
to support his this kind of attack said
basically what they say it know if there
was a problem with your website
you know your own database became too to
loom
I be in both the support OES published
sensitive material like
shocking information and a do providers
usually say it will you publish shocking
information so that's why people come to
USA
me ten million people cannot visit a
website in serbia
in the or so 24 hours to the survey has
about
many people are the something like that
security was or is something that was
or on the Securities not something to
seriously consider
you today unfortunately even though
after all these a
happenings from the beginning of this
year until now people started to really
thinking about
arm miss security in securing their
systems it's not
it's not still on now um I satisfactory
level
so that we can say that I systems in
serbia
PTC the system so far from from BGC and
I general habits of the people the end
users who were made
mostly journalists and lawyers and some
sort of people who are not really
um technical people I
don't care going to technical cats
such as the lack of
a backup is in the most common problem
because
when you going as them for a backup in
order to
get it there laissez alive again they're
just so
backup we don't do that so basically
country to help them
I generally better shave real patterns
switcher
resulting query general technical
literacy
any serbia poor people who are really
well educated but
the general public were into people who
deal with these
types of problems are not really really
the do
who day don't really want to educate
themselves news on it some kind of
special education are you too
learned several tools and tricks in
order to
to protect yourself yeah be issued from
the technical perspective ish
cost all 1s I mean you see
my ranch a botnet form
as much as sixty seventy 100 Dollaz and
successfully takedown a website date was
pretty much a dime a dozen said
a basically a it's easy for
new even the the structures didn't want
to censor something they don't really
need a lot of money
or resources to it they can just rent a
botnet 10
sorry get that from China Brazil
wherever d
next for me very important issue ish
demanded a 10
you'll see in the second case already
they had a
that the importance of of meta-data a
softening
more I'll is something bigger and end
the importance of the content itself
because
meta-data never live me that's not
entirely true because here
waste for UT may matchday Asia
line but and as I said before not many
people
I really use these tools interest you in
order to
hiding something some way or just
protect themselves
hum nothing to legally shoes feature
probably the the heart is because you
know the technical part
a bunch of technical people we see it
will sit down and soul
maker security strategy oranges security
system
as much as possible but when it comes to
the legal issues you have to deal with
to say it
and the same doesn't really deal wat
such
issues delores
regarding media and
it digital communication et cetera is
not really clear injured
buncha raise almost where I someone can
operate and
successfully fulfill their mission
without being punished by little we know
today being
considered a any in a court case
the courtroom processes loss for too
long
does to you again for from serbia a sir
Tony
no that you minimum I'll and dove
court process here would be about two
years for for something many more
and dish more complicated cases loss for
mean something silly dance an entire
decade or a couple of days
depleted the police doesn't have the
infrastructure to in the investigation
other crimes
I i think that this is not entirely true
mid because need to head the
infrastructure but
I problem is a lack of interests
in on their site to seoul I
some local some up to issues did it
happen on daily basis number also going
to clarify
on this later on in the second case say
there is a huge conflict of interest
isn't there was this one case rear
I'm material was taken down from a
website
and we me because this year mind and
that's me sticking meshing beginning is
how you know
wheelchair the fans offer free
services from technical problems for
both from both technical and
legal aside for people whose digital
rights have been affected in some way
so dispatcher was so sasser from the
internet practically and
I the text was related to you one
really prominent political fear in
serbia is silly
in a sort of power and a
we months to police and said yet we have
these evidence that someone from
I sure he actually took down the CDC
these texts from this website and we
wanted to investigate it and they said
okay we'll
and mom month or so later
day went to know I'm educational
training in Barcelona and
educational/training was funded by did
institution
ok which the person affected by the
materials
did we and it was taken down a
with the practically destitution be for
two training for the policemen to go to
Barcelona so
it's a fear a conflict of interest to
you I mean if someone gives you
something you're not really in the mood
to be
I me something victory is bad for him
its
actually theory conflict interest social
media are still not legally defined
which is really really bad UK
a it gives the power to reports to come
to some things to pursue consider them
arm I media like any regular media and
other times changes don't a.m. Saturday
if I publish something on on on a social
not toward
it might be considered I might be
considered a media or not depending
on what hurts me more which is I
they don't give the protection of love
David
media get burnt day also
don't give the a but debuted
disadvantages such as a editorial
responsibility
accuracy of both the materials that you
published cetera
so basically I'm ABC is really
the another grey zone as mentioned
before
your many domenici the it will take some
time we headin your
media lauded bastard couple of weeks or
a month ago
and it's still not so good enough in
order to solve these
issues on a more permanent permanent
level
data a las both did legally issues she's
probably
probably the most important and instead
bed data retention less protection laws
so
in in service still not defined fool
Hollow where when can
I use do retained 8a in order to
prosecute your
Jess I'm listen to
tool or use your communication whatever
it is a really um I mean legally during
are some limitations but
its tone is still not a clearly defined
coup in sao can can doing now
couple and yes they actually a change a
they're going to merge the I
be a and I love you have we share the
military and the CEO
I am
intelligence agencies and jail will be
and you'll also
na even nobody will know who and how can
and can't do
a can operate free week to redeem the
to which are retained by an almost in
mind internet providers small my love
the returners landline operator sister
dude
easily so ethical questions that I am II
rosso I'm going to discuss each
one of them shortly
um the first one is who watches
watchdogs
in in our society we can't legally have
watchdogs featured the police the secret
services the government in general
but squeeze 2012 watches damn we still
want to monitor their opportunity
in the weekday do work that way I'm
our detail or day work with the
censoring materials cetera so basically
we don't really a had watchers the
watchdog Scopus a
and it is a really ethically
I am is a easy during
there is no legal necessity for for
something like that
there is a strong ethical background to
to this question because
I home much can you trust your
your I government and special the secret
service's
is a huge deal I wish I
me personally I don't really
trust especially to the secret services
and I think it
people who have dealt with their
sensitive data says insanity for share
my opinion
I curiosity killed the cat but
satisfaction brought back
in many cases the government says that
days censor some people
or we told some I information in order
to
to protect the I'm the public
so that this first part the same
arrests killed the cat so that's why you
shouldn't be curious you shouldn't care
for
the information we hide from you because
it's for your own good at a race you'll
be killed
meant for sp but then it comes to the
second part dissatisfaction brought back
the satisfaction of knowing something
is natural the I comes natural to any
human being
everyone wants to know everything we're
curious by nature
i mean they're people who are not but
dear percentages
is is slightly are serious runner
smaller actually and
portion of us who want to know it all
and
a we we do have to write
to know how our who wants to real scene
in our country and what our governing
really does
self-regulation of or or so censorship
this is more om
related to the traditional media have
ito real
he added to our social in utah real
responsibility
you know so in many cases dad immediate
themselves
team down some material did they have
already published in a sense
and now that I've into something yes
politically
I not serve really I am
correct and Daisy publish it and you
in a couple days GB just a key takedown
and the precious
is it the is that act
herself Rachel a regulation because the
legally have to write to do that
but its small so some censorship which
is
really the worst I've censorship curious
I meet you can fight general censorship
with different tools
which I'm going to talk about it later
but self-censorship you count Yukon
because
I 80s and Gnasher chance that
doesn't really exists out there each
they can only see a self regulation we
published if we have direct tv did not
but what we don't know aren't
circumstances
under Rule which day no talk down to
said material
and I no we come to dish
this actually force you too much but
everything but not because everyone
is I'm I don't know if you
know the case so third the polish
a newspaper to publish I
picture of Angela Merkel breastfeeding
the the prime minister of Poland and I
think both
the Czech Republic nature but a and end
the Prime Minister
although it was a huge scandal couple of
years ago in Germany
and Prime Minister falling down said
it's okay it can be considered already
you can laugh at everything
buyer not with everybody so it means day
you should watch how you talk with which
is again
a shortened form of censorship you know
you should be able to share with your
opinions without frontiers is a
Universal Declaration SS so
I think this center she say you can
laugh at everything
with everybody an immediate Snyder
be HUGE HUGE issue even even nomination
I
many of us are all for anonymity but
I hear people who abuse it of course so
basically it's really part to me
now with the present tools that can be
used mostly for good
I but sometimes there are use for bad
things as well
I to the journey I'll
who does what out there in cyberspace so
basically that's why I'm
on me just one issue jessica Lee shoes I
mean
people should be able to be anonymous on
the internet but
um be able to do better teams are also
known as sole
and we should find a way to telecheck
not today
mister I collective responsibility
because
this but not for sexual get refunded
DDoS attacks
was just ok many many many different
computers people let's hang
so I'll who is the one to blame
its sa7 in couples like that it's really
hard to determine
the source of the day entire attack so
basically there is a collective
responsibility of all the people
there included Indias in this process is
and define one is does the government
has a right to
to protect to protect its people from
themselves
my answer would be no because I'll we're
smarting off in all not too a full time
to decide for our everything so why
would determine need to
protect us from ourselves so we should
be able to
access all information at hand decide on
what is clear about for us so
finally came to the second case I have a
prepared for today and it crashed
questions until now
yeah long ago the
to the you can
say up been on
movies you when I new
you you
Europe so who
yeah well russia's not really good
example for freedom of speech to age is
slightly
you know but basically thats that's one
really really big issue because
that's about social media used blogging
blogger service whichever
I you have millions of them and
basically if you had
more often is a 90 5 but i wasnt or
something like that
yeah and doesn't really matter some mark
which is not really unreachable
a bearing in mind a number of people
that are online special is writing
English everybody can
can from every point in the world can
reach you
so basically day debt is sort of abuse
arm for me to just I
day again day don't give you that
religious of being the media
buddy give you the rest possibilities so
you have an extra responsibility dare
you to not publish whatever you want
but you don't have the protection did
the law gives to the standard
journalists with and it is
I future both political and ethical and
legal
legal legal question I mean to what
extent can
I'm that abuse of a story
goal you and I i agree with you that
that's a really
really but policy so I hope we won't be
getting that anytime soon
in certain areas
nato than normal so to speak European
countries
not to rush not normally I like putting
I
mmm I just that second cases
CES cynicism Center for Investigative
Journalism
of serbia Center in Neenah I
deposition asthma dishes that case I i
talked about
a with a policeman going to Barcelona to
to be children to educate themselves
ever I
Center for Investigative Journalism
serbia published an article about the
special treatment
0 child of a prominent politician in
serbia so soon after I bought two or
three days after publishing not
really about the a day after day the
published article
the only to Article disappeared which
was not to DDoS attack it was under
entire portal only be de single webpage
was not available didn't exist anymore
on
in the same time s chill the Street
low it was injected actually in india
database so that
it could listen to to juror email server
and just collecting meta-data
all everything that goes in and out or
or older
a email service and those of you who
deal in technology know that that's
pretty much everything
so every single email it should get can
be
I not ready but is
it's meant to detail which a I hope you
are familiar with it
I'll I explain to me how to meditate of
an email consist of the
source I email address this nation email
address
source IP address in most cases and at
times sent
to subject and some water other
information and
by mapping and connecting days a
information you can see practically who
is communicating to call
and for the Center for Investigative
Journalism that means dead
de Jian really find out to manage their
sources switcher
on in some cases even people who work at
just before the state Lake insiders
so Acer really really big issue an issue
I'll which have your sources mad and you
new shows us will probably I just saw
sharing information with you because
Gaydos problems
so do journalism the
work in CA it I'm see it ceaser still
under
pressure or digitally and physically
sued duties is
DD the feel that there be
the trackball basically and you
like a movie where do they go from work
to home to supermarket everywhere
and moving to tell the whole life don't
publishes don't up Thursday
not too interested parties wish I know
more about because I was part of it
day investigation of this entire story
first the whole world
happen for us I mean we've got a call
from seeing say they told us
hey you know our our website was hacked
and the I'll we are missing an article
and we don't know what happened within
so please help us and %um first the
first thing we didn't actually issued
older hosting provider and ask what the
hell went wrong did you
return to the 20 backup version of the
website was a problem
though
low-cost provider was not really
cooperative they were like or you come
and see for yourself you don't mean all
something happen
and we we have no idea what's going on
our service which is really
impossible if you're serious a person
provide on
and it took really time to
to access the server and gain access to
the server
because related okay give us a login
information so that we can login to the
web server and
just you what's wrong initially not like
you need to come
physically here hooey we cannot really
do you do
type booking information you said okay
we will come when can we come
and a set in about two weeks so a
in a week if you leave if you have a
normal crime scene when
something is stolen or someone is killed
%uh if you live it
unprotected for a week can you imagine
what happened away
everybody has access to a probably
detector still has access to it he can
you raise all the evidence
and Auburn factor see a place in mind I
don't know what dog cat can pass by
changes
rowing your evidence saying when you
come up to reach you find
nothing which actually happened for us
and down we can choose
go through this entire process of
recovering
I'll recovering dead stage of the
server we in which was bad a week ago
it's not only you cannot
you can never get 100 percent blast in
the meantime
does hosting provider I install some
occasions
on the web server which our for
protecting ice had yeah it's good that
you remember after the attack Potter
me it doesn't really have a point O to
stall
something that protects your computer
after get access
a been done and no investigation has
been conducted
so we managed to get her some
information
and so we went with does in data to the
police
and a of knowledge didn't exist sooo
criminal case you're so
d shifted up and they send it to the
prosecution
office for cyber crimes which is the
state organiser VM and a lame
the don't have to capacity to obtain the
evidence the jury
the prosecution of his or cyber crimes
what text crimes to case all 50
don't have to pass it to talk to him the
steps above its big question
and dad team cyber forensics managed to
obtain a list of 15 IP addresses for air
potential sources suggest film injection
because on
as I said it's a huge stain they're
listening to song is the same to
your entire meal going in an arch don't
really control
do email for anybody can send you an
email and that can affect your
reputation and image channel
so once we got this Lease of 15
IP addresses who went back to GDoc
the prosecution office for cyber friends
a for the center France
and day asked for a shorter lease
and then we submit a list of six IP
addresses and they asked for a shirtless
again I mean what can be shorter than 6
IP addresses that hard to
I new DVD cease-fire they said it's
impossible to track
6 IP addresses and it said
really curious no number two bearing in
mind that
estate access to a bo roughly
300,000 times to
date at all farm different typos
subscribers trading mobile or landline
phones
tomorrow I mean day country the 36 users
which is
funny and after that curiously
to born 22 into summer recess and it
still has its own eight ish
started working actually week ago but we
haven't really managed to you
to see up to what point our
our case is gone but it's not really it
hasn't advanced
that's for sure so dissolutions side he
started talking about problems which I
don't rely
I always like to see it the bright side
so that's why I'm going
tell you what kind of solutions we
suggest any there's some
I trance year included I'm not
advertising for them but
it's what we use and we find them useful
you can use the same or
something similar whatever said
we had the issue probably you all know
what these things are basically
whistleblowing case a new trend me
not sure you've a it's become quite
popular and I'm
each became popular actually with
suitemates
and now we have local league speech is
sad really really extremely useful tool
for
for a result lower Sen
the journalists and people who are
activists in are interested
hot social topics and political issues
and I put your security job
I don't know if you know what it is but
it
Buffington boss title low lease
platform so I some I am news agencies in
the world
use with someone platforms to collect
the
information from the community and the
good thing about these tools a special
globally sees it
Dege the whistleblowers the people who
submitted a
the material total on me so your say
s DHS its access to internet web server
generally your your Mets DJ spy
protected
I'm yeah mechanism so
protections dear I divided among
I left her and right-sided I huge blast
which
I don't know if anybody has freed up but
he said something that is
symmetrical to DDoS if it did you
ascertain
distribute it in a way to attacked my
server
nao deflect the gives the possibility
tradition to
this unique event website on several
different occasions
there randomly chosen and you don't
really know where your website is but
its its online and I each mitigate
videos
acid attacks as they have to say
practically had
I if some part 2 if one location of your
website is attacked
you have the other one a lot so it's
really hard to
attack all of them at once it's
practically impossible
and deflect a strong infrastructure in
doing that indeed really have space for
for whom many more web sites and also
many people now
here some get
them gave some donate some up there
infrastructure link bandwidth and
memory and their servers for or deflect
which is really
which means that it's really
community-based and he
I'll is from the community community and
and for the community doing really great
if I see a few
if you want to secure your website I
guess I'm
against the USA strongly recommend that
and on the other side we had a
a different kind and tender mediation I
mean it's sort of whistleblowing but not
really
I death to all web portals find me
in serbia and the first one is in 10 min
said I'm tea and a sec
a move which means the region and
remembers everything and
the second one is the says all of coal
which
could be in doubt as a censorship firm
I cash so basically
BD should platforms well what we can do
is solely solo in some way which is not
true that were not home so it's
I much easier for general public but
again if so ha sitting awaited gives
a
lemme we saw or so to speak for the
people we who had the material
I don't virginity to to remain anonymous
and
right so basically he's going to make
any sense we use and recommend for
for so for protection and
me tatt these I issues we
week at debt would be everything from me
so if you have any questions thanks you
too
master and here is my email and on the
website so if you have anything else to
ask chase you can contact
me or us there yeah also DLC black
both of these domains workers also
basically questions
yet largely
I
you low the
yeah I feeling
the this
even goals
is a the look
the the
this is a
you re the
so the yeah
with bells well
at me tool to fix the city's knowns to
human
is I can be used for both bed and
good you know evenly December you take
form
putting nails in the wall you know good
you can he is the same tools so we
cannot see did
anonymity is such is good or bad but the
way someone uses
an immediate I mean you can't not really
exclude bed
bad people from the site to get this
impossible virtually
so don't balance I don't know where to
balance would be but
up issue regulated in some way it
depends incorrectly to be cute because
you keep giving the company to see the
power
to regulate and meaty do want regulated
day and me to just won't be existing
maybe we need another independent body
like
I don't know 9 the
mmm independent agency
may be dead range leases but again a
maybe data and entire point of
firm the entire solution would lie in
some distributed way of protecting
anonymity because
everything this centralized is so back
in general said
basically dangerousness his show knows
that doing the best three
the more centralization and is the
worsened freedom and
and general a
man execution of human rights in on the
internet is
is impossible if its centralized but
when you distribute even
people the when the power actually in
the responsibilities distributed to
several different areas day have more
transparent and
real home freedom
on the internet and I i think that
deceiving would happen over time with
anonymity because I the anonymity
something that is this necessary in the
chain generally in the world need
privacy of some sort so Monday
debt would be my ass really hope you are
satisfactory
%um the yeah of course
it's all it's all up to possibly I who
when we have the saucy people talk about
things did we can meet the government
change something but
what I think my personal opinion is that
every each and every government
each and every party likes to have
control worries people so it's it's a
mechanism
governing all government so we need to
change our habits 9
in order to protect those ourselves not
expect from someone who sees during the
parliament or
the government or any ministry to to
protect us because they want
never not cheering on Team the
Netherlands not to US not in England
noting the Russia
or so basically a you
world well dei you does the same thing
to its people said
his family you know basically yes
so any other gone
many girl dress the go
cool the I
proclaimed
I you
a jus be I'll
love is world your room and
breathe a little easier is where the
issue with you
cool deserve this
it well the our experience says that
our cloud hosting is slightly better day
conventional our seats so if you have
time I need the resources to
to have something close to it on the
clout and probably
outside of serbia maybe to Madeleine's
just a suggestion
if you have the money and the
possibility to do that I think this
a much better way to go then hosting it
right here and a it's not good
one provider is worse than not very
windy
face this issue so dade am having a
problem with security on their servers
because most of the servers 0 hosting
providers say is your be around server
somewhere else
mostly Germany Romania et cetera
bulgaria's of said
a day have these contracts wheat Shire
not really clear on who has a
responsibility of
doing what if the Germans here for you
day have so
Davis do is a bunch of issues that
come with it because they're not a real
providers say you're late
agents of the providers you know so
basically
the best way to VoIP system find a real
provide ample have to cook as
physical servers and who has full
responsibility over those servers both
physically
the digitally and in anyways so I think
I N
if you can afford a cloudy best so
miss it and %um
questions comments whatever now than the
mistaken he you
a lot of home Mayo relations lol
but I think you the whole getting ahold
p.m. what he does the same thing any
government does the same thing
said on paper everything looks pretty in
pink but
the practice is different this loses all
who see his
the visit was went to a harlem
leave is a
troops the sinuses
prolly the lows designers
older lynn Love line do the invisible
are all sorry who's this the lead in all
the the
well I mentioned a lack of education in
India be here in fetters I don't really
think about it day to see
free to be cheap to be OK and you know
like some basic things they don't really
think about security as much as the
Chilean several
brothels during the the years being love
the
those you fools you
losses well they're starting to do it
now and what they said about the mature
so forget to mention that
I in the beginning I when he talked
about the fake IDs video I told you that
people didn't have homes but
when the floods came everyone not turn
on the people who are interested in
activism in this kind of things
everybody on them made copies in their
hard drive so it was
much easier to start says ok and
internet so fun to because they publish
such materials
after the people had the module so
people can now
published something they have it on
their are says is the
the real that
does which lemme
Liz his called but yeah I'm now
well he had it but he was afraid to
publish because there were legal
suggests he could go afterwards so if we
don't really know who the author is
because he was anonymous
yeah London had something to do this
loaded with up
low dress low you
and the go on
you soon
I gene that is on the menu labeling
holding the
people is is lazy love you
will I'm or up to you
United States and you they made the
these old cause there are
the borough's time
the the see the manual
do you %uh
I you need to borrow do you use your
home
how many your you over
literally need to borrow people
on three holes I
I
they and yeah the long is cool
in lawyer who did using CA
I'm more you really and and is on the
whole movie
%um and a half problem deal your
assertion
me the well I'm movies
the Menasha little of both so you're
done
learned people be go to the polls on
the netbook old there a little earlier
the better
more the renowned
well the
who are they
he might be published yeah it does we
deflects good because you can't locally
somewhere but
to you also have coffee so several
different places so the last one cop
gets killed another
money becomes alive so basically and
love their new video in the I'll
this
by I'll yeah the
the I'll maybe bob love you
is the a hollow
luv changes in with you see the lol
know which you mom can be a good thing
to some extent noon but
its treaty and its tributaries I mean
this
all this scene she talked about her
still in developing so
basically you cannot offer a final
solution that
souls it all you %um can make
suggestions and that's it
so thank you for your attention and my
its
its then
yeah
on