that
well West
air whatever care to hide
yes arm
the day or so they say good morning I
don't know
who has been to the party yesterday me
okay party ok it's really stressed the
with the rest of the guys are sleeping I
guess so yeah
yeah some though do you throw more baby
so obscure energy systems I was amo
booklet ok a the PG okay as I said
my name is there anything other than
this than the greater girl
and we will be talking about the injury
today our soul
this is Bo come 2004 edition why because
we're all
arm last couple of months and previous
months and next months pure
we gonna be talking about Andrew Toronto
euro so on beam let's start so
are actually who we are just two guys
from the
take seriously ansel we shared one state
sometime long ago and then face
all went wrong somewhere so
well we have low fun breaking the stuff
love to play with a application all I
own the company so
we are specializing application security
and now it looks like
six hours to get here from Selina so all
over is actually is the No for those
that did not know because
Selina is not about consul I
looks like from this kind of mad that's
shown outside
I've checked yesterday I lost he has
over here
from the gonna are and so official
definition of speedy I just some
not quite clear styrene is balkan war
it's not
Bob from this map all we can claim that
he knows not welcome
but anyway we're glad to be here so
although
just for short a Nazi have some on
well-known Haitian people also from
Selina
are maybe somebody knows this guy
yes actually this is guy that almost
looks like
Edwards modem know if you take date from
the right angle
but actually he's the guy who is ski who
has been
and actually she still it is on though
FBI most wanted list are because he was
greater
of the Sahara that was actually behind
the Mariposa botnet
I am and its walls
arm his softer actually
no what's ustinov what made the close
like
it was effectively with like
Fenton 12 million computers are on the
wall
arm and officially they say that only
two
States only two countries in the world
are
can be infected maybe somebody would
guess which two countries
with David not clear as one yeah
that's right and the second one not all
russian mom
up the second was so tests after all
because it officially it also is that
white spot on the internet map
so all the
he was convicted who's loving you
he got almost four years so
present so I the moment he is so
writing his appeal are games that
verdict but also
from the United States for me haha what
do you think coming years he would get
fordice crimes 50
the blog like 25 to life here summer to
be that the six years
in the United States so he still no he
cannot go all title
please let me know outside to be your so
but its
that's why I'm pointing to solve because
it was all
let the underground story goes that so
actually arm
United States came to hearing on the
whole to get a job
at Hawaii know why you fly
snow then was there
and he turned down no you'd just rather
go to jail than go to you
work for the united states of we have
some famous people know
all this one got caught and I guess
there are some other
checkers also from Sri also concerned
okay
so we're going to be talking today up
with me and Daniel
bow soul we gonna see little bit so
motivation behind why we actually did
are you will have some short
11 ABK soul who has been playing with
Android application already
who has been analyzing taken by you
okay 12 okay you're going to see that
it's not that hard
also we gonna go a little bit about to
analyze this so
and talk a little bit so about static
and dynamic
and we gonna show little quite a few
demos
so whose cool who likes them it's
okay for the demo species are we have
one regret
than with any other don't act wireless
networks
if you have wireless networks when we
will be showing it
share %uh you don't see the dams because
it's
gonna who in they won't work because
even the
be playing real are like the life gets
and you have some a close up of okay
where we are today that I enjoyed sewing
also mobile application
are actually it's kind of complex words
that's pure living can also if you're
talking about the mall locations
why because the PCB me just see a
Android
our framework you know there is a lot of
love Irish
love building blocks and components that
are actually part of the
enjoyed framework in this release also
this
there are several are issues with the
mobile application
arm fortifying said it already had to do
the anything unless you're that are
the researchers can find in abilities
in about ninety percent of mobile
application that they have been
analyzing so that's kind of
no on worry about it
and also if you take 200 recent
both wrong yesterday or day before solar
researchers compiled a list of and
Rachel occasions that the law amendment
best
so they're not checking their SSL
Certificates ranged DPS connection
so you can play with so on the
connection is set yourself in the middle
of publication and the server
soul this kind of though miss kind of
the reasons
all brought us to this fence that they
are sexually a big need for more though
s and we also got love requests from our
clients the best mobile applications
also from Android entire as some home
on other operating systems and it's been
here
looking at this mobile applications so
it left the seems like the developments
know if each like nineties
so love us going Jackson on
server-side lot of problems with 0
client-side
arm and we have been analyzing also
love bottom but most is the medium
a mobile applications and BC love
lot of issues there ranging from very
simple
on to learn complicated stuff pfister
okay our own
11 a picky so actually what is ABK
how to get it how to combine it all
tested and at the end how to exploit
well we're gonna go this just
up quick through it so it's actually a
look back at five former
nothing else I'll and its I
I'd Indian didn't you this but you can
actually
who's running BlackBerry here the same
but has Blackburn
know that
but you can run a pic a signed right on
blackberry diversion
so I can you this but be keeping you set
so it should be
should be but I'm gonna try this so
are so I pick a sexually
as a setback should package for much
it's nothing more than a zip
so it's really an excuse me Java with
major libros you can have needed by
ballistic says there
the other parts of so there are some
lying
Android system and you have different
components like
activities services broke a six years in
use leather
so the somebody is
Jul Android developer here somebody
developing injured
from okay three so this is not nothing
new for you
right you have some resources at its
source code you can buy the
are you will get the dollars by
called put it in the glasses decided
I'll
and actually third you've tested their
push push it to the Google
to replace all new Ripper so that's a
that if we're to believe you're a decade
but what's are
you can also see what's the opposite
side so hard to reverse it
so how do you get the ATK for Spain case
you can copy from the fall
so just get ATB poll or
call more
and get the education the fall copy from
the backup
you can create a backup group on kind of
applications that you have on your
mobile phone
and you get to a BK way just go if you
know the application
full name which is go to the that you're
all
and use citro download it for you so
this is the first step you need a BK
or there's another way you can download
from one trusted source but I do my I'm
not sure if you want to run
from one trusted source who'll who wants
to run a pkg
from one trusted source taken from
Russian
forum ruled source
sorry who'll this
a good question anyway month yeah
qualm sometimes yes sometimes no but for
months resources sometime forms and
maybe sometimes you can find also with
thong who'll
so the next step is just to compile it
so if you bullets from the fall like
here like him
once every day to be binge isn't that
good I love
ghetto classes decks I'm just
to compile it J league with because it
does everything for you
are you can use if you want to look
defendants morning
you can though on there's only
there's a second way to to do it arm
then was gonna show
little bit living off to to his life
think how this is done
and so these are the tools that are
use I love to know
reverse injury ABK so thanks to george
you get from plastics to juror
although from classes flies
up to there's job well and the people
a good tool if you wanna go simplest way
you know because this
well sometimes you don't wanna go
through all the steps
although they're quite simple regions
goals online upload your a decade to do
so
with this site and it the composite for
you
also that he was gonna show you it's
just little bits
so how fast and how we use and actually
what you get from the combined
the serbs this
okay I will just show you who he is
the to get the source old baggage so
here we have fun treats package
and it's nothing but unzip file
so let's do another eap
and here we have the classes they expire
this is actually the
bytecode do you find the route to the
week
its is like job I've called but optimize
for a hundred
the I'm and untruthful so
I'm going are transform this darling by
gold to Java bytecode this take some
time
and snow over run Jiading we to show you
the
actual source calls and here you can see
sources obfuscates you have a lot
face the EC's but actually you can get
through it and if you manage to do
something replacement and stuff like
that
you will be able to read it sometimes
and understand the source
comment if u you suggested we
how many of you do know whole program in
jail
okay very so yeah I i manager fell
afterwards because we gonna meet some of
our some statement and
we're trying to figure out what works
whether those K
okay
from
okay so all we have an obligation for
what they actually you should be checked
if you're doing all securities as
members reinvesting
for all over mobile application so
definitely there is our transit security
so we want to see how we will traffic
goes back and forth with application
I from application to the server room
the back
are we gonna see how the sessions ok and
no whole session is found all
so if it so right way or wrong way to
certificates although they fit so
also we cannot go and man the middle we
cannot thank you man in the middle
thanks and there there are some other
protections like by love you
or maybe if there are some kind of data
is Lincoln SQ
she collided database some by okay she
I'm
very important also to change a loss
what they actually though
duplications bits into the Los look
quite
sometimes you can find their very
interesting because tho
specially logging like user names and
passwords just dumping here
little all I'm the next step is by your
own life is so low
to compile the same way as the show into
the duplication
if there's some kind of this cation RV
all such a
you need to check times cited: injection
is this possible to
do some kind of for just $15 jack
cheapens the recited somebody's
many Milan wants to own the world you
isolate lease obligation
and of course the results wat
interesting part or
Park libraries that or Tom already lying
there are
I
and the applications using them so you
wanna does the application
know the simplest way is the starting
later arm
wall with a proxy we will show that
you're using on the scene later but the
real device
any guesses while this
it's faster exactly see major is quite
it's quite slow
although they say yes if you enable alt
arm trying also
graphic art were arm acceleration it
should be okay
because after one conference some guy
approaches that should be better but
we still using the real device because
its little bit faster
so you just so lovely cation later
device menu spires four pillars that
work with everyone
Charles to using the arm my quest
run application and I just see the logs
domes crashes fires in every that's cool
so this is actually what you see if your
no doing a man in the middle or you're
running a proxy
to see that loan application it's an
eagle so
all can somebody gets both
this is
make address a while of devised by this
idea
and this is also sent to the more money
sent to the server in this case
why do you think they're using it my
yeah for identification device so you
know which kind
device are you so and those are some
other interesting stuff if you want I'll
if you sometimes wanna see what's
actually sent to the server
all kind of resolutions and your own
joint versions and
to your arm disarm serial numbers and
things like that so you do see
this is the request going so to the
server
and what one what we see
that's coming from the server is all
very often we see this
can somebody reduce was actually 730
base64
Mahmoud contrite but some
you don't get anything it so it's not a
but this it drifted off it skated to
change into binary something
now I'm loving mother of applications
are you doing this so if you're going
man in the middle
if you wanna try to meet this it's
almost impossible to do it
right or somebody can do it if somebody
can reduce sandy
the crib it yeah
who yes showed was good
new ruled see okay
today later in the day so are on 3 p.m.
when he gets up
yeah are are you did
over there reason okay great then we
gonna
get him this and you know it's Steve
Watts x2 coming up but
it's really liked to get to know it's
really worked hard to see
and here are some variables here are
just some
words here to some scores here as the
sometimes results it's actually bring
back
are they're also kinda other tools that
you could use
I like Dexter it gives you all do let's
say
classes the compilation a what kind of
permission services
in all the stock arm so you can
easily see what the big Asian dust where
you can use this one promo i think is
from Turkey he won by which
already broken bone which like that
he gets ever think you're just upload a
pic AP K
and you got the sources you covered on
strengths euros
even the net to check that is going on
home
in from the application he's that guy
that actually
are to the home 00
the will play but he was playing with it
so he sent a couple
or AP case where he will play and the
are replacement phone
so he found an ability I'll
otherwise i think is fine he may have
crashed into play if couples times
all are she's really nice guy so you
wanna
he's on Twitter following but
home you must no halt to are
read Turk Turkish language or use Google
translate okay if you're going for it
now for a static analyzers first that's
why I was asking you
first meet how to read and understand
John Wall called
well you don't have to know all the
classes you just wanna
know a little bit of programming can to
see how they actually done
are with static analyzers you cannot see
they're all replies
while because the application is not
running so you don't see what actually
send to the server and getting back
are and you have quite a few problems
the application is awfully skated some
hola renamed like.
we have been seen before how many of you
can have in your mind to know if you
have like
100 classes which one Jul 01
ATK vacation been named eighty how many
can you can map this kind of relations
you have 180 classes I guess it's really
hard
through to get it in all and makes
glasses bien si yen anbe SEC
so but it's very important for something
analyzes
to identify important things in court so
like what would be
important segments from the cold writing
yeah communicating to the server writing
to soak HTTP connections sending
encryption if there's some below the
activity like Greece if they're used
how the reviews all writing to Los
or someone I'll home
really little yeah that's cool ASP like
communication
said so. up because like seventy percent
in all seventy eighty percent is most
agree still
thats it's not interesting but sometimes
it is
and then you know it's going to be
showing why we is also some
sometimes important if you're playing
the games life because
know with call in 10 minutes thirty
gives you all do
secrets and Keith and solutions
but it's really nice tho all identify
that important segment so if the
applications as well dump answers like
no don't buy it seems that the movement
that started it inside the application
okay so when you're looking at the Asia
analyzing static implications are
looking at the source called
sometime soon in to be feeling like a
piano that
button on the pool are handball
I'm a local ask you if you can help me
to reduce services except from Guam
dog coat minutes from very important all
worry well-known slovenian game I'll
and we have been be taken by live and be
so this sucks
I inside the inside the sourcebook can
you ask and somebody gets what they
actually this does
who said that he knows how to read Joe
okay
what does it do
yes a okay saving something to the
server right
can somebody guestbook tenu means
you is using and what is T no
no you have ordered
in the in the server name it's like
torture or corals score
yet so this is a score so this is a
score
this is the username Center Server love
to you play the game
this is actually called the server so
how would you Emily this kind call find
expected just like this in your lover
and you're the top score of the day
shown it's it's it's really that simple
lights really
its welllll I think it's quite high
because things means like
20,000 Katie plays per day
so he's we have a little bit calculating
so he
he gets quite a lot of money at the end
of the month
no just pulling the banner some on this
kind of them
gay and if you're not feeling lucky you
know you'd
to get something like this know and some
done so
you don't get the whole day compilation
all from though
don't get the job corps because of the
gdgt who uses
I'll pretty old java Decompiler
to get you get this knowing sometimes
it's really hard
arm hard to read them hard to imagine
what actually
there because she's doing all
and its beside the static analyzer
there's a memorable I will
analyzes we already shown before someone
search angel
traffic with proxy so you a man in the
middle I'm changing what's going back
and forth to the server
if the server all the traffic is not so
let's see
obfuscated the cryptids or some kind of
15 then it's fine
if you just score sense on me to bring
Dexter but if
to its it's incomplete then you have
part-time there's also the boy Inc
but know the bug is kind of know step by
step you know you have to find a way
where to
I'll put the bread break points and no
step 1: boztepe and then i think is that
we are using to go home
it's kind of reflection all who knows
what reflections char
okay someone so what's actually
reflections 0
know it's a language actually its
language ability to inspect the damage
to class
call classes and methods and Vince and
that should do it said
other place at the wrong time so many
applications running
you can call it in actually it's like
John looking job
I was like ultimately
what she wants what kind of classes do
we have worked anyway it was we had
so what's actually difference between to
Buckingham reflection
the reflection we have a high level view
so we have all the classes that we have
to compile all the methods all even
there or
their own set to private all protected
to another all
attributes that to the methods and the
I think which you can you you can change
it all
and you can actually what's most most
interesting you that interact with the
application in real time
so if you're playing the game on this
poem you naturally
over into tool indirect yes I'll
in real time with the BK shit so we
gonna see how this is
per so there's this is also the other
features so you can access all the
variables
methods change in weather news all
we are also using a BB shell all because
it halts
love fades to do it because sometimes
you know we're also
we don't have too much time and
sometimes feel so lazy
and that's why we use be show well
you can write try to juggle and
compliance
I'll then energy so you don't have to
repackage a BK alright joke 03 package
when it's on and run it but actually you
can are fragile called
and random empty but its best way to
show it
after Mike to couples like so why did
you use be shut because it's
jar interpreter all it's free to use
it's quite small alright sweet snatch a
scripting language for jobs we have seen
other solution
all like being on other schools they're
using bite on because I'm
since they using by Tom you need to have
kind of conversion from bite into Java
and sending back and forth and using
Java also on the client side that's how
it's much easier and that's why you're
using this binge
okay when you analyze the gay she's the
love
interesting things in a lightly p.m.
certification pins and system lawls
internal IP's are hits the love
occasions that our store all
internal IP's there a case and sometimes
even user names and passwords
to do a protected content I love times
you have
like testing cases you know like 15
classis inside the UK because they
didn't clean up before they publish it
to the
will play soul just looking at the
source codes you
sometimes not be found really
interesting stuff there okay so we have
no
sec I'll eyes as we have an amicus
realizes are we should be looking at the
other alters that have been going ground
accomplices in preventing the stuff but
they're really
really really wanted some more you know
we would do you want that to happen kind
of run time
all runtime: tool that weakened
change on the application and
in real time so team directing real time
clothing methods
arnoldo don't do although very both and
were even create a GD platform
so we gonna show Johal you can
on create one cheating like
67 lines of coke something like this you
know I'm
application is actually gonna play Halo
itself no
so and he'll come in all the time so we
went
really dig deeper then you almost I'll
was feeling desperate because he tried
several methods and
on the world but then again who came up
with a big scene and daniel is going to
be
telling you more about it selection we
came up with a great deal
i think is rated up what we've seen is
this
pool for dynamical analysis and there
what it does
is days under investigation it to the
injects a service included and then
next to the service the duplication
besides the service in jackson also be
show
and the mean I'm already told what you
jealous
this enables enables us the
to you get all the variables at
runtime: change them a long some Java
coated wrong time
and to do dynamical analysis you can see
there a picture we've seen
on the left side is just a modified
duplication with the injected with the
service and the
I'll be show library at the connection
is established through a TV
tool with its to help move the TCP
protocol
and on the right side to conceal seeing
which causes the losing to face the best
cute and
the accompany the this call with my face
changer
the best if this actually hard time
seeing the
the slow their packaging stall them
and solo you can ask me anything about
the
the deters I won't go into that because
we want to show you something else
so actually watching what what's
possible we'll see needs
I don't know how to say flat Shoals
here you can see the user interface
we've seen on the left upper side you
can see
all the I objects that are you said
wrong time by the Education
on the the other than all
now you can see the activities they are
and its automatically during the
activity life cycle management a hundred
and after right clicking with the most
welcome
on sum up the video object will simply
return all the fears that this activity
or lunch
test and their eyesight you have all
a view that's cool to watch
waking at some very nervous and monitor
all day are changing during the
execution notification
and blow you it's the scripting part you
can write to the usual state's jobless
or school
and they will be executed long time on
the file
all the throwing a vacation so let's do
a demo
but the floor I give you the street
the you got it
okay let's do it
you can see the ball on the site this
project is
and no around boxing
be so this is the poor Partha the
provisional %um
should be home lungs here because
otherwise
so will not it will not work
sword
working no its or yeah that's the
problem really liked impulse you know we
have
fall three films already but we really
want to see
we want to show you all in real time
others work all
the something also retrial me for today
0 as the occasionally do
language so in serbia we have all these
which manages
is this a not so you can play it body so
although the problem is that there are
only a few users and playing in serbia
thank you to actually one for sooo okay
yeah while you use and
really only first way no no is showing
the other
use is subject to a user let's run the
game
but it's quite important we have they
didn't need me
pressuring me and from you all
we don't have you didn't know any all do
medium and
French words but be over with a the game
every time
okay you can see I just click on the
I activity the right the most modern and
the
X you were murdered only all the fields
the deceptive TX
so you can see the feel sorrow
and the gold was up a skated the
obviously you have a lot of A's B's and
so on
but effecting your own show my thoughts
and do again
the right click also the methods are
displayed and
some are off to skate at but some are
not
and this is interest think and
yeah lead with me the whole idea
yeah it was a lot skidded because rather
do is rest of world lol
those methods were above that did this
for us love them
another said it's really good to look
into the the source code
and to see if you get DUP of answers
well
can anybody guess what it does a
the name of the battles know if its use
but just to see that's merely rear
actually running inside the application
daniel is gonna be
well executing JavaScript
no see here so dole's calling up those
make expel Bo
and we gonna see that's actually right
years old you're running at the wrong
time the cation so
we can control it totally to know to
call the method still
all but the if you do your static
analysis
you figure out where the answers are
stored so let's bring them out
and watch this and paid to be located
and you can see here kansas law all I
have learned
Phillies I when I was safe and month
afterwards
everybody's photos no what with their
to remove they're getting
yeah okay but if we can do better so
let's
sony has imports all weekend you know we
can go the the key point in the game is
to learn how to play the game until he
got the words
okay paying I got 10 but
I will execute is don't dance was
murdered and let's see what
campus on the left upper parks the game
you can see that this was long
you soon we actually know in a bid to
get the answer so we could get up to
eighty
idea at all a where to start
all the negativity or you know
you you get to all things that are here
hollow you should go to trial though do
the worst together to get
almost six words than words and the
movies or just call in one min
from or we can fall we can make it even
better
since we know that all since we know
that
the answers are stored here weekend
right
1234 670 okay about timelines
call and I'll what does this
called dos we get sure the answers
although share duo
our answers so here is all possibilities
here are answers
so you run and actually delegation
of copies the answers to the results
table
and %um all the time so
I have from to get the the solution to
say that
and we need to wait another minutes
for the results birds in the meantime I
can show you
that the much you mixing this excluded
because
during the less refreshment if I I can
right click on the game to activity for
example
the
up the
variables that I have been changed
during two left last year's freshmen
have radical or so you spots the
edges changes serve
the before so let's wait
mother for two seconds it because it's
really hard to know if in half like
one thousand berry a bill it's really
hard to see
what's have been changed or what not but
the dismay
you see that this one has been changed
its fun this farm
all all also you can easily
session lutherans Mueller my about the
whole
make more visual all
call we are not all loved you need to
with connection to Source following
Nations hu J things changing
all Road
yeah I make yes it's a it's it's a good
suggestion
we can also be also applied to go into
the
the you know if you want to have like
score like 10,000 if you wanna go
ridgeway table base and also just
remembered the
310 one point is months result
all and you can see we have to Mark's
school
yes 0 votes mambo home to care for his
it's a winner at the moment so all
dude I think your question are we trying
also to going to do
deep to search all the classes all the
methods but their application dissected
going into battle for
yeah because its long both resources
because their not ok so its
heap space is a the problem but you can
get a lot of
for interests thanks tho religion or
just inject into the Google
play and but we can show you this little
bit late
okay so all that was last year the start
its and play with it
and then do a CCC conference came and in
all
although it's also connected with the
city's the same as both own this song
conferences and we got to be have
seem very good presentation from all
calling winner
and he was talking about so darling
dynamic dollar instrumentation but on
different way because now you're
changing KPK
so need to have a BK our ticket on
change it
upload it back to the device or emulator
and run it
are and total so we went like
he in can be somehow we use his so
are his research and so we don't have to
change a PK
so if you're going little bit deeper
all I'm into the enjoying system can be
changed show all every so we can thank
you
inject into one process into they got
process
on this are ok seem tall and Daniel
yes so we came up with a solution we
exchanged some
other males with calling I'll charm
where
thankful he sell and what we do is
using the hijacked his program framework
and hijacking this is Eagle process
and injecting a want to live here is
that we've seen use this
and we are actually hooking him do that
unsorted activity so we are checked in
call I bring to it
looking dismantled and after a
our staff is executed to me
a we proceed with the regional mattered
so I will show you another them all
and I'm hero show we hope to be easy it
is
to this earth will see no connect a
digital replay
sign this time you actually not changing
a
case and more so we're changing movement
all
layers bombs and Android and
cookie the all ABA calls and then
injecting the same
overseas services into the are running
place fear I have everything in place so
let's run the demo
them
and here his framework is actually a
really stunning
Florida obligation to start so let's run
Play Store
and you can see the library has been
injected
no let's rock scene
and you can hear see that we are on
will play and from here now you can do
pretty much everyday Inc the would have
seen with this approach you can see here
to the user's name that is
a register to the phone but don't worry
it's fake
yeah although finally really uses
were interesting user names and
passwords on Gmail I kissed the bottom
so it's actually no I was running inside
the Play Store and we haven't modified
so a BK the same as its came from though
with though the fall and updated though
with us so what we're doing the question
a.m. injection
you know my your and Imperials me know
from and session so all not from
different because you can see the rooted
phone that that's a difference between
the
do the two methods if you're using pros
and cons over the baby came with doing a
can be enjoyed
if we have a decade there's no need for
lead to fall
you can do this on on rooted phone AB
all AB needs to be enabled because we
are pushing
and to you also hold
or so when I for its
that's all there is an issue with
untrusted sources
you have to download modifying a blow to
the fall read a BK
I'll known only through the phone we do
in 2000 injected directly into Android
although there is no need for a pic a
modification soon just injecting the
runtime
up what you need to do to fall and
injected shared libraries and that's why
you need a little bit more skills
because it's BAE have been having some
be sure the beginning but because
compiling and no
hijacking the native calls when starting
the application
but the it so we so threatened
say or true around with the yellow
hey this is a instrument yes
this all you can use me have small
growth tall some
face like UK call it's all looks even
girl send it to the rhythm SMS messages
you can get a phone is doing something
that
with all this kind of call call
like 15 plainly like 20 lifeco
and you can some runtime: no don't have
to mission
lash yeah it's actually mission to those
who can play with access to the very
least so that's
FX's along to the on the line only thing
more
you can executed happy great religious
longer so that means that there are
changes ahead to know
there is 0 possible different kind of
usage
I had been proved it's not only from the
foreign joint
I this kind of use it be tested one
client
are requested us to test this year to
test oracle forms
have anybody who usess use Oracle Forms
well know they're still love that no i i
was also convinced that their desk
because Oracle
on all that they gonna be retiring at
but at that moment there's still some
companies developing an Oracle Forms
so all we had Oracle Forms
broder's for the best think the to it
took us like
one day to change it ok see
and actually be injected into the oracle
forms and you're lying inside the World
Turns
getting all the way it was the same as
enjoy and there are some also kinda
quiet
crazy ideas like all I know my son
always 12 have me you know that you had
his minecraft
no game when he is playing
someone cares maybe no injected into the
Minecraft the moon
his having fun with this kind of RNC
doesn't he
you can create the ultimate CD players
multiple you know so we got up now we
gonna see
are we still have one day all all at the
end
for the final them all but you can see
that
this is Saul Saul quite good possibility
so just before the devil
some fun hopes it's quite some small
script twelve dollars going to all
written in the group and it's not gonna
be finish more because we have other
things to do
are but it's only get up you you've got
the URL you can
to take it played its are sent the email
loro some suggestions
and two can help testers note right
sometimes cases the best duplication
IOM Packers cheaters and this is in the
open for suggestions from
comments and things like that soul are
since we have been in August all we have
been doing our presentation also also at
the desk along
well wall cheaper and decides in Las
Vegas
RV for presidential know if if you
presented last biggest need to present
some
online game no you cannot goal no all
I'll to Vegas to present so that is
gonna show you
then it's gonna show one more game how
to see and you will get
you will see how all game developers in
all
sometimes missus or sometimes my
they're missing some things because
they've really want to optimize
or making make their life much more
easier
me too from another time okay we will be
paid by check with a vector
ok even help me because I i suck it
lecture so well-rounded education
written
I in this game well complete so
okay his own CCV will be running this so
big J so in the road really don't see
that's the screen the time when I'm
and i won today no I wanna play wanna
play
ideas are
the connection lost on she
solutions
all in all this is club
well quite useful
because wants release it's real
favorite s phone that's why it's a
little bit
mmm not working we will but you gonna
see
arrayed yeah okay all I would say
also live so we're doing a lot of them
all all and we're playing for online so
let me let me sit somewhere here
buy into the game okay
its bid for another room but I will
execute this cold at sea
K you can see no the for next cart
the title guess so this is good for the
soul
low it's not actually the baby because
certainly thank you
know although the array of the cars
there are coming
no if he doesn't answer every time the
but you can also see the Nexus garton
on the graphical user interface so can
you see here to
souls 15 soul of what should i do all I
have 48
into to they get their stand you
kid
okay sow seeds its sixteen and three
hid okay 7
JK Malkin saw stand okay so
all as I see it sold these are the next
cards are coming for you wanna check the
for the band and other users always one
working
stopped working also be with him that
name
yeah people from was his response is
him maybe love this business but maybe
we can show issues
you maybe we can show potential to cope
but actually the Colts that's running
behind that
you will see all for support all here
I put some resources into hedge mad rich
I use
later so this is why we will see the
results because
before you have seen here to cause
that's ok because we will show cause
want to look at it we
the cards were getting here so you know
what mix guards its gonna be
after them up to date I am jus a
running in the loop in our
on you dread and I'm displaying
this this variable which is starting and
some
some game at PGE some things like that
and just printing it out and below that
I am
replacing the card to this that is
actually drawn to the
to the user interface so nothing special
here and here I'm sleeping
existing concert so actually they say
well that's really no magic that's
upbringing that's me enables you to win
although
all the game would at least you would
have a better chance for
for many no it's not that complicated
just let no have to on all
native Java programming and be a little
bit pation
to find we're actually just bury a body
said a hidden
in mind test because you know with all
obfuscation and changing the names and
the
arm the classes and methods
but that's it you know so sense our time
is up
are there any questions are asking you
read
very yeah somehow
should will concern myself
the game so these days dos something
but when you deal mile great Kasia
okay
because i saw this on me
oh who lay it will host
office no it's not always time to pass
from the developer sold
if the run it through in some well I'm
touring cars or something like this:
and the bullet but some seem which is
always the
guess were his soul to soul solar once
form starting also because this is a
must-have looking
yea the feds is also different of his
case you different kind matter what kind
of a big issue they're using but all
but most most of the yeah these days
application or some kind of all stay
hidden plays
I'll actually people say
I'll move on to say
more there is a day for
well called skater three
well we can talk a little so just stop
cause troubles
note may be SOL because you're running
very some other questions
love you so the less
Carlos blood levels I'm Yahoo example
I lisa is in close levels
lows %uh and lonely the usual
long later I love this I
I the
room doing ASEAN regional Jim
all yeah actually
steeton actually a I'm
love scenes showing hugh the changes
during the day last
fresh mint if you have fun and give it
and click on it with the rightmost
bottom
me he will show you the
the very was a have been changed in this
activity
so you need to spot this activity in
normal because we
you can do deep search or something like
that but where do that he could to keep
you know he banned don't use phone
precious ever seen its
actually it's going every known 23
seconds you know
what from that class is that you have to
open it in goals and the pressures over
it and it's positive they have been
changing
the change in the caller so you can
easily spot but do what you can
you can set it all right we see all of
them
week we you can have here if you won't
find a very able you can set it as a
watch
and humid here you will have to all the
variables just
Dec 28 was that are interested for you
just keep can bring this to this so the
state
into this list and it will show you all
the ravers the church angel
so that's it order any other question if
not
you can find though cause if he hadn't
seen on our Get Well
mind if you have questions feel over
here offer today tomorrow we're leaving
seoul
thank you very much costs
then
you