hi everyone hope you're having a good
day at the conference today I've already
used my beer coop and unfortunately
found the point levels are like really
half of the one we are used to so I hope
you will enjoy this and there's been
some fantastic lineup today and thanks
to organizers for this fantastic event
I believe you're enjoying it and my
topic little bit relates to the previous
one and given by Zola Turner about
Windows but really concentrate more
towards Active Directory because I
believe it's one of the most underrated
topics not given enough attention
because of the amount of issues we are
having especially Francis always the
glamour part but the difference is
lacking the attention so we've tried to
deal both the sides of the fence this is
a little bit about me so what company
defends abase of Manchester UK so mostly
work for UK and release clients usual
fantastic life red teaming fantastic
applications Wireless pretty much
everything runs with IP a little bit of
conferences and training experience and
yeah that's pretty much about providing
assurance to the clients so some look
about it some don't and some don't fix
or something okay so each to their own
this is pretty much the agenda we are
going to cover today so I know Active
Directory is the two familiar name
pretty much every man among you might
have come across it even though they
don't know maybe they work in a
different domain and they don't come
across rent controls or things like that
but as soon as you log into a computer
in your office they are most likely part
of Windows Network which is known as
Active Directory and there are many
reasons like in in a day to day life you
come across these but the security is
always in the in the background picture
and because of the
the the insider threat the latest buzz
words that you see in the media and all
are done to Active Directory in Windows
environment so we're going to go through
fundamentals although I know it's a
security cone but I really believe that
we need to cover the basics a little bit
to set up a picture and a bit of ground
first and then move towards the domain
domain controller workings
what's its functional role in the in the
Active Directory environment and then
cover the threats and detections so
hopefully we'll cover that in the time
we have yes let's go for right now so
this is where of negotiating with you
the expectation levels how are we gonna
go from this so this is nothing like a
presentation of any rocket science or
any big topics or any research this is
all just an information gathered around
from different sources put for useful
cause so if I can do any of you can do
it as well the word security I'll just
mention it so the word security in the
first 1/3 of the presentation is all
about you know typically how admins or
the people in the networking industry
I'm talking about 90s you use the word
security just to define the boundary it
had nothing to do with with the actual
cyber security that we talked about
today so that's more about logical
boundary so whenever I speak about this
word it doesn't mean the attack and
defense part there's more like more like
just a normal boundary really logical
way of saying it if I provide you
example it'd be like few years ago even
now some admins call VLAN as being used
for security although it's not
configured at the switch interfaces to
do the security work but they just call
it ok because it's logically dividing
the segments of the network even though
the flow of the information is same and
even if it's trunk they still call it
for security purposes so it's that sort
of concept ok so I will try to be fast
with the fundamentals so apologies in
advance if you think it's really fast at
the start
by certainly important to set up and
connect the dots in order to understand
the later phases which are really the
crux of this talk and why I am
presenting here so as Irene knows I mean
aqueduct Therese is more of trademarked
directory service of Microsoft and the
main reason this is so popular although
is also so popular in the security
community is because of the centralized
approach it uses to to automate the
network management of the data of the
users data for administrative control
and it's really designed for distributed
networking environments ad was new I
mean I will often call ad now for Active
Directory ad was new to the Windows 2000
because was just a start with Windows NT
kernel and then 2003 we see it was a
night not to turn 12 2016 is in
production almost now so it's mainly
helping you with providing the
redundancy or fault tolerance basically
maintaining a good network growth where
things can be automated and there's a
centralized control of the whole
environment so the structure is composed
of these components Forest it's like a
forest it's like a security boundary for
for a network for a Windows network and
it'll be a collection of every attribute
that's part of of a Windows network that
would contain domains that were
organization units sites all-in-one is
probably known as forest then is a
domain domain is really a collection of
computers put together in network
topology topology is more like aleko
fashion but in a technological way and
all these computers in a domain follow
some set protocol that means set
policies names and database of the
members is collected together and then
authentication is on the domain basis
only so I'm gonna clarify further you
know with the diagram on the next slide
how the different domains can be put
together in a forest and Hardison looked
like and now this the oh you is like an
organization unit so it's like different
departments in an organization
so this is more like like a container in
a domain so the the way we are going
down from the definitions is like in a
hierarchical structure so this is a
structure that's presented in any domain
and then there are sites which are like
the physical groupings independent of
the domain and they can be
geographically apart and then they're
connected by by the links which is like
normally we have these MPLS or network
links and they can be based on the
speeds which are high or low and then
are more often defined by the IP subnets
now this is this is a quick this is a
quick picture showing how a domain and a
forest is laid out so if you see this is
like a corporate domain this is also the
forest root domain and forest root
domain has got subdomains which can be
part of different departments here and
the arrows you see are bi-directional
that means that's the trust trust set up
between them so if it says by direction
that means the flow of any user related
data or any administrative data or
management of the domain related data
can be can go from this child to this
parent or from parent it can flow down
to child as well so there are different
sets collected here and then you can
also have a similar set up here the same
forest and all for all different domains
can be part of one for us which will be
appearing for us here now going towards
the different types of Active Directory
services what are their functions and
this is these are the different sources
that we have domain service is really
about storing the directory data or to
manage that for to maintain a
communication between different users or
objects or computers and then the
certificate services is all about
maintaining the certificate management
between between different identities or
to present these identities in a secure
fashion in order to make sure the
communication is it's secure and then
there's a Federation services this is
the modern concept I mean it's been few
years now but it's more about how
single online session can be used to use
to put a trust relationship so that you
don't have to login a user doesn't have
to log in every time to a different
application which is directly enabled so
over this lifespan of a one session you
can be part of all the different
applications and this is also what we
call is based on web-based single
sign-on technology and then there's a
lightweight directory services this is
like a portable version of directory
services where you don't really need the
Active Directory domain services but you
can still use it
independently for certain units or
stores for example and then the last is
rights management this is this is about
the protection of information and how
you actually protect protect the
information more about file rights and
who signed it and also takes care of the
management of digital signatures as part
of this so these are these are the major
major services that are part of the
Active Directory environment ok so this
is just so quickly about so I'm gonna go
through each of these in a little bit of
detail about how all of them are what
are they what the benefits and the roles
of them and then we're gonna slowly
start moving towards the security side
of things later on and the basics are
done so this is this is really a DDS is
like a domain associates which is like a
distributed database used for management
of information about network sources or
user data or the attributes set for each
of those users or the computers and it's
done in a hierarchical manner and the
benefits are it's a scalable because if
we see now the way windows are growing
or the Microsoft is growing the Windows
is also coming out of a network
previously used to be you need to be
physically in a one network and then use
same computer to log in and then you'll
be part of a network now with the advent
of the new technologies and all you
don't need to be part of the same
network you can be part of a different
country but that will be
previously after that it was like more
you need to still need to be part of the
same site which will be part of the main
global headquarters but now you don't
need to be in the office but there are
technologies that will do the
relationship trust relationship for on
your behalf on your computer behalf and
that will still can be part of the
domain which would be part of your
office Network and then there's a
delegation which is delegation
delegating the control of permissions of
different objects down to perform
different sort of functions based on
privileges and then there's a security
is one of the benefits as Microsoft's
ace for authentication and access
control purposes because a single
Network logon is enough rather than
providing the owners of maintaining
these user credentials on the user's so
this will help you but then on the
security side of things will later see
how a single network logon can also be
helpful for you to compromise the whole
domain when I say domain is like 1 1
unit of computer network other features
these are different type of steps or
sort of like a different components part
of the domain services which contains a
schema schema is just like a definition
of all the objects and attributes that
are used to store data in a in Active
Directory environment and then there's a
global catalog it's it's always on a
domain controller domain controller is
the computer which is a server main
server that takes care of the
administration of the whole Active
Directory and then the querying
mechanism for four different objects to
to index the data so that objects can be
found fast by the network when they're
queried upon by the network users or
applications and then there's a
replication or take data between the
different member servers or or primary
and secondary domain controllers and
then there's an operation masters role
this is more done for ensuring that
consistency is maintained and there's
less false and the fault tolerance is
there in a in a domain so with time now
we see Windows have developed obviously
so since Windows Server 2008 we have
these new features in as part of the
Windows domain
when you say our ODC this means I read
only domain controller that will act as
a domain controller but will not have
the same content as the main domain
controller this is mainly done to avoid
any risk of theft of credentials
basically because the cached passwords
are removed from this read only domain
controller and it can be installed at
some other location for the for the
efficient purposes efficiency purposes
for example let's let's think about a
big network where the headquarters have
got a full-fledged
IT team and they have got IT operations
team but then they are in a
manufacturing environment for example so
they also got a workshop or a factory
where there are like 200 users so in
order to make sure they have a login
process which is efficient they will put
a copy of read only domain controller at
that workshop because they know it's not
that secure so that means even if that's
compromised but that not compromised
that empty that means the passwords of
the active directory uses similarly
other advantages that their admin role
separation so you can you can actually
separate the roles of the of the users
and secure installation media so you can
you can now secure using anti des backup
sorry
okay yeah and then restartable ATDs you
can also restart the sorry just a second
I guess I'm not able to use my mouse
here on this okay yeah that's fine
sorry sorry will a DDS and as it's a
restart of fine grained posture policy
you can also different password policies
on and account lockout policies on
different users and the global security
groups in a domain that means new
password setting objects and the
president's rules have been added to
remove the restriction of a single
password policy for the whole domain so
that can be set for a different set of
admins and all so now the certification
services education services as the name
says it's really about enhancing the
security by binding identity of offer
device of off a person to the
corresponding private key so it should
be cost effective solution because it
could be hosted within the environment
on a server or on a domain controller
itself as well but in in line with good
practices they always say it should be
on different so and then the supported
application include all these
applications that we use in modern day
world IPSec VPN encrypting file systems
and as mom's which is like the secure
multi-purpose internet mail extensions
and then these are the different type of
city of yourself says that we have CA is
certificate authority that's responsible
for issuing and the management of those
certificates to all the users and the
computers within a network and then
there's a web enrollment this is this is
one of the methods by which you can
actually connect to a CA which is the
certificate authority to ask for a to
request a certificate or also request CR
Elle's which are the certificate
revocation list that contains the list
of all city which they have been
relegated and then the online responder
which is for application status purposes
and a network device enrollment service
which is for the network devices for
example routers or firewalls which are
not domain joined so they can use this
to request the secure services
this is a quick certification surfaces
architecture diagram which just shows
that how the flow happens I'm trying to
use this it doesn't breaks out okay yeah
so this client module is exactly the
function of this is to request the the
certificate request to submit it to the
situation services engine so this engine
is responsible for the processing and
then it's asked policy module whether a
requester qualifies for that criteria
why it's asking for certificate if does
valid request then it will send its own
decision and the certificate services
will then generate a private key and
distribute it to the request protector
certificate which is done by this crypto
API is below part of this if you see
these entity and then the certificate
database is responsible for managing all
the all the information about the keys
or or storing the CRL lists and and then
the active directory is used to sync all
the selected transactions and the audit
trail is also maintained by the city of
a database then the next in our list of
sources or Federation services this is
all about the web SSO which is the
single sign-on that we use to
authenticate a user to multiple
applications over the life of a single
online session so that you don't have to
login to the different services and the
user doesn't have to store multiple
passwords or multiple identities that
also adds a security risk to the to the
ordination to avoid that it offers that
in this different types of rules so
these are the all services for this
Federation services proxy claims where
and windows token these are independent
applications who were responsible for
providing the Federation services to in
a tea environment most of times we see
Federation's of Suzanne proxy I've also
put together a quick diagram to show you
how the session happens the first
request
apologies I guess this is the wrong
direction so read 1 as a 2 2 as a 1
because the request is initially
access is requested by the user to the
cloud service which is directly enable
cloud services asking for access so it's
like a simplified diagram to show how
this mechanism works and then this ad FS
server sits in a DMZ because it also
talks to the ad server internally and
outside the user is on the internet so
when this user asks for quest requesting
for access to the cloud service it
requests a token and then this user
request for a token from ad FS so this
Federation service conforms whether that
user needs any user is a valid token and
then conforms it with the ad because all
the identities and secrets are sold here
so once this is requested by the ad to
the IDF s over the issues of token so
similarly if there are multiple
applications for example here another
one another one they will be all
belonging based on the same lifespan of
the token issued from here sorry if
you're finding a bit faster we need to
cover the basics quick and the time is
running so after that moving to security
so this is the lightweight directory
access protocol it's like a directory
service providing the flexible support
for all the directory enabled
applications so you can you can provide
directory services for direct enable
services without actually incurring the
setup of a proper domain controller or
the ad environment so this can be
integrated with the already established
ad for example in a big enterprises
there are different directory stores and
there are different extranet sonication
stores for the vendors so they set up
lightweights and directory services
which contains the personalized
information about the applications or
the users or anything specific to that
business unit but they authenticate the
identities and everything are tentacle
to the active directory which is set up
and in the corporate environment so
that's that's pretty much the gist of it
this is the rights management services
this is more about protecting the and
the individuals allowing the individuals
and any of the administrators or the
staff an ID through information rights
management policies to specify access
permissions on the files so this could
be any of your documentation
additional workbooks and and these
permissions stay with the file so that
it doesn't matter if you move the file
to somewhere else because the
permissions are actually stored in the
file in an XML format in these word
files so the benefits are because these
are persistent use like I said it just
remains with the information no matter
where it's moved or you send it to
somebody else or forwarded by email also
prevents the unauthorized recipients
from performing authorized action for
example you're part of your company but
you're not having a high level
privileges as an admin or super admin
still if you forward it to somebody else
or outside that doesn't mean I mean it
will just figure out it will tell you
whether that authorized person has
permission to access that file if not it
won't lets you to do it but one of the
good things about this is also it offers
a modular support with the hardware
security modules as well if companies
are serious to implement this this can
be integrated with the hardware security
modules so this is a quick diagram so
this diagram is stolen from the
Microsoft TechNet you'll see I've
mentioned at the end the sources for
these images so what's happening quickly
is it's just showing you how a quick
access mechanism happens so if Terry is
requesting for applies his access
restrictions on a document and the RMS
client actually this is our Emma's
client and this launches a request to
Dharma server and then aramis so returns
the client licenses so they fade back to
Terry and then he can send that document
with the right permissions to to this
user who's Lola and then she can
actually send the rights protected
document she can actually receive that
document and try to open it if she has
got the right permissions and those will
be checked against the rms server for
the access so yeah that's pretty much
okay moving on to fast forward to 2016
as you see now Microsoft and especially
Microsoft has put so much stress on
mobile security and cloud one of the
things that is happening at a major
level is since
2016 so allow releases
boats they're trying to keep the up
readability and the security in a in a
balanced fashion and because cloud is so
important these days obviously for the
obvious reasons cost and efficiency and
speed and and whatnot they're trying to
so Microsoft has improved this windows
over 16 with some of the major
improvements which is a Pam so if you
have any interaction of the Linux
operating system you'll know what I mean
by Pam and then is or ad join which is
again a way of keeping the BYOD devices
bring your own devices to either
resistor or join the domains remotely
and then there's an MS passport which is
also hello business they call it this is
a certificate based mechanism for
authentication purposes I guess the the
reason they came up with these is
because Microsoft really found its pain
in the backside for credential tough
techniques and stuff that we are reading
about from the attack perspective mimic
ads or the password steal in pass the
hash pass the ticket over pass the hash
ticket sorry and these techniques so
they're trying to come up with these to
say that they admit these things can
never be stopped but then the real issue
lies with the identity and excessive
permissions applied to the users because
if somebody's made an admin in our
organization he just enjoys their rights
forever because there's no process to
actually revoke his rights soon after
and that's always the human nature
because if you know and he for example
somebody database developer he needs
access and that needs to run some
function at a high privilege he'll be
given DBA privileges probably for our
and then they forget it so this is the
problem that Microsoft has tried to deal
with using the Pam module here so I'll
take you to a quick diagram the way
privileged access management sorry it
stands for privileged access management
the how it deals with it there are other
improvements as well time
synchronization no I guess these are the
more pains on the administration side
how difficult it is to maintain some
time
when the servers are out of sync I've
done that at my first job so probably if
there's any admins on you would know how
painful it is sorry the one of the other
improvements was group membership
expiration so you can always provide the
time limit to the users who are
sometimes added temporarily to certain
groups so this is a quick diagram
showing the requests in the seven steps
so what we are going to go through here
is like HR admins is the group here
which is having hard privileges and s ID
is the system identifier for Windows
Active Directory that at the back end it
just denotes through this number at the
end I'll show you later what it means
and then the second is it shows that
because someone from the HR
administrator base privileges database
admin access in order to do it and then
I share the principle that no members is
actually created in the in the bastion
forest so this is like a like a shadow
forest created at the same time by small
like really isolated forest no one has
their privileges and microsoft claims
it's like ultimately secure thing so for
the time just think it's like a shadow
forest created here by the Pam and the
corporate HR admin group has got a
member Chen who's asking for access to
it so she needs to go through ma m which
is like identity manager for Windows and
through that portal she needs to request
the privileges in order to access with
the higher privilege so this MFA could
be a multi-factor authentication applied
to the portal where she goes in to
request it once there my impulses are
checked whether this request is valid
the access the way access granted is the
bastion Forest creates a similar account
with the similar s ID at your admins and
then allows Jen access temporarily
through the Kerberos authentication
ticket temporarily for that time and I
guess that's known as TTL which is the
same as the concept used as time to live
so that time to live tells you how long
is the access main
and for and if she is part of multiple
groups then the lowest value is taken by
the by the windows to ensure that the
limit is not not abused sorry so yeah
that's a special concept of Pam
so advantages are it just isolates and
scoping of privileges and because
there's a time exploration as well so
it's not like you can abuse it and
there's an additional locking of the
workflows through the portals and as
Microsoft said it's trying to mitigate
these threats so we're gonna deal with
these later
now the next advantage was as your ad so
it just allows you to register or join
the devices which means the devices can
be resisted but still remain outside the
network or devices can join but still
remain and they will remain they will
part they'll be part of the domain the
benefits are single sign-on and they
have got integrations with the mobile
device management solutions and also
they can access nexus resources and the
last advantages with this is Microsoft
passport which is like a certificate
based authentication approach where
Microsoft is using one of the biometric
or a flexible pin in order to login to
the to the device and then you can
actually sorry that the private key is
linked with that right pin or a
biometric feature when you authenticate
and then that decrypts the in the
function that's used to allow access to
this so because the keys are actually
Hardware tested so these keys are tied
to TPM 1.2 and these modules is the
reason Microsoft was trying to say that
this is very secure I've seen in a
couple of implementations where these
new surface and the surface notebooks
that we see so they've got retina
authentication and that's how they're
using Microsoft fellow for business to
be part of the domain although you can
be sitting here and accessing the
activity wireless network you can still
access your internal applications and
portals moving on quickly to to domain
controller to the different parts of
directory service agent sorry for the
of a jump pair we need to discuss this
because domain controller is the
heartbeat of any network so if this is
compromised you would know that these
are the keys to the kingdom
anybody can steal NTDs debt which is the
database containing all the password
hashes you can crack them or use other
techniques where you don't need to crack
them and pass on so directory service
agent is actually holding holding all
the all the all the cracks here which
means this is main ad component and it
runs as part of the else's process which
is a local security authority subsystem
and that takes care of the
authentication packages and the user
sauce is what so these are the
interfaces here if you see the different
two faces LDAP Rapala is for application
listen messages this is for messaging
and Sam is the security Accounts Manager
and then there's an TDs a dot DLL which
is the directory service agent air which
provides interfaces through which
directly clients can gain access to to
the interactive database because
database is here there's no direct
interaction so it's us acting as a
separation layer and then this is the
physical structure so where the ant ID
estate is so if you see the data file is
here and there's a link table security
descriptor table here and there's a log
sale so if these logs overflow that
there are new logs that are originally
created and that's pretty much I guess
the basics if you if you see this let's
move on to to the hacking now so what
we're gonna discuss here is now the main
steps of a cyber kill chain which are
actually related with Active Directory
hacks so the CKC as they say
lockheed-martin have developed this
framework they call it secrecy so we'll
be mostly dealing with these let me see
so we'll see the the exploitation phase
installation of any any malware on the
owned assets inside and then the command
and control servers which are for
persistence to stay there and for
lateral movement and then their actions
on the objectives so whoever is hacking
it he or she has got up up
either to destroy some files or move
some files out of the network or get out
steal the passwords or they might have
some anyway it could be to hack some
elections I don't know this is actually
the bulleted example for each step where
it's not absolute list of options it's
more like if a server intelligence
analyst has to make an assessment as to
what are the correct answers for threats
facing them or the missions they're
trying to support these in all the steps
that actually from from the decision to
act to actually provide executing those
provided opportunities so I've
highlighted these elements which are
really related to our talk right now
here so these are the ones which would
be linked to an internal network here's
the full link if you want to read the
full intelligence report by them so on
the nest site so most of time the attack
techniques are actually in an internal
network they start with with a ground up
so that means you need to build up the
ground first by collecting information
and then analyzing them there are
different techniques whether you need to
make noise on the network or you just
want to do it with say PowerShell tools
these days or even with gabbros SPN
scanning and stuff which I'm covering
later and then the second part is
escalating your privileges because
you've gained access to it with
low-level privileges you can never see
or do these things like extracting
passwords or performing functions to
change the state of the of the system or
deleting logs or things like these so
you need higher-level privileges and
then there's a stage where you access
secrets which means the the passwords
either in a clear text form or stealing
the hashes or dumping them so your info
collection is really a main part of this
I would say it's a home work of any
hacking exercise so for from the offense
part we are dealing with this in three
stages so recon is short for
recognizance
you're just as these terms originating
from the military where they do these
activities and then that's like
gathering information and
performing an analysis and then
escalation target exploitation and as
persistence means maintaining the access
how you can maintain the access for as
long as possible you need it now recon
these are really basic things I put down
but the the stress of women in this
presentation is to not to tell you any
references to other tools because we are
looking at that the latest rays
attackers are doing this is not using
any custom built tools but using the
built-in commands within the operating
system or the servers or as part of the
remote support tools which are installed
on them but these are the basic dos
commands or you can form user numeration
in simple English this would be like
retrieving a list of all the users that
are part of a network that means part of
your office or your corporation so this
is this tells you which ports are
actually used for querying this this is
only one way through a protocol known as
SMB there could be similar other ways to
perform on different protocols as an MP
or or anything else so there's a
technique this is known as recycling the
term I mentioned earlier security
identifier looks like this so even if
you have changed for example rename the
administrator to say guest but that
doesn't mean he's a guest user so this
is the identity that tells you at the
back end whether it's really a admin or
a serial user so 500 is always fixed for
a built in administrator so you will
know that this is there so that's like a
security by obscurity if we say moving
on to red so I claim yeah this is just a
one of the ways so you can do it from
one a tentacle perspective or with the
tentacle perspective as well time to get
it would be a user user privileges and
then this is how it looks like just a
quick screen shot the reason of putting
this here is because this will make the
sort of access will make noise on the
network if you got the right level of
monitoring and event analysis going on
so you should have this as a first alarm
that there's some activity going on the
network there moving on to escalation so
these are a little bit of different
techniques or you can gather information
about the operating system that you have
jumped on and the patch levels to
quickly find out if there's any any ways
to escalate
is locally and then all the information
more networking 5-volt state what's
running there and the societal process
similarly little more tricks there I
guess some of them if you see are
similar to the previous talk soliton I
mentioned group policy references as
well
this is a quick cheat sheet really that
you always look for veneer part of the
networking looking to escalate
privileges I'll take you straight to the
domain controllers what we can do about
these so most common ways for
compromising a domain controller really
contain the cat bros attacks these days
because they are stealth they're a quick
easy win within 5-10 minutes you could
have the highest level of privileges in
a in a network and then all these
techniques pass the hash pass the ticket
over pass the hash and then looking for
any insko service permissions like
dalton said i guess actually he's made
my job easy now i can refer the examples
back to the previous talk and that talk
was not supposed to happen i guess one
of the speakers backed out so they put
sultan to do that exercise so that's a
good one and then the stepping up other
member service so if you have
compromised one server you can actually
use some techniques like pass the hash
to jump on the other servers on the
network till you find the highest level
privilege they looking for and then
there could be nested administration
groups where the privileges are screwed
up so this is the talk from there
Kerberos attacks start so SPN scanning
is one of the ways to actually quickly
to stealth exercise to find out all the
service principal names it stands for
service principal names it's mainly for
service accounts so the soviets counts
are most likely configured with higher
privileged accounts so that's a quick
vin if you actually get round to those
accounts so any of these services that
doesn't mean this is the whole list it
could be any of these services sickles
over or RDP protocol or could be
exchanged client access service running
the SPN so you can request the SPN types
from from a domain controller with a
domain account that means you need a low
level privilege at least a user level
privilege on a Windows network to to
query this and then using those you can
actually request Kerberos TGS which
Atika granting service request ticket
useful to find out whether you can
actually get the ticket issued to you so
when I say this ticket that actually is
encrypted with some algorithm and inside
that is the his access for that so the
encryption used is actually most of the
times if it's using rc4 then it could be
ntlm based password that you can
brute-force to find out the password
offline and then silver and golden
tickets so silver is the one where you
get TGS to take a grounding service
ticket for service count t GT is the
ticket granting ticket from KDC from the
key distribution server of Kerberos that
takes care of it then the the famous I
must 14 o 68 where a fake ticket can be
can be issued to the Kerberos to get
access as a domain administrator as a
user admin sorry as a normal user in a
domain and then there's a Kerberos
technique which is which is quite famous
so Kerberos is really like the it's the
same process that I've explained above
it's like a really effective method for
extracting service account credentials
starting with us been scanning as I said
from ad as a regular user so you are not
sending any packets so you know making
noise by because users tend to choose
poor passwords and then the same goes
for service accounts so if the service
counts are of the same length has domain
passes they're not a big deal to be to
be correct so you you get the hash and
then you just throw the brute-forcing
offline against it until you find a
right right password for that in order
to crack it and use the use the service
yeah but it's also possible if you can
sniff the tickets sometime with the rc4
cipher that we're saying is the problem
with the Kerberos technique and the
weakness that it's tries to exploit so
if you are able to sniff that sorry the
sniff is not the English sniff word I'm
using a sniff is more like if you're
eavesdropping on a network and you go to
access to and you're capable to monitor
network traffic over a wire then you'll
be able to get that pass get that packet
information out so that's what sniffing
means in the security world so yeah I'm
us 14 Oh 68 so I'll go into details of
this to show quickly who was the problem
so basically you're able to request the
TGT without pack pack is a privileged
attribute cert but by by sending
actually just a normal request with a be
a pack request set to false and the
reason that the whole process here is
that we are trying to fold your back
because if with a normal user privileges
the pack can be forged because because
of the way domain controllers missing
this patch and the problem with the kgt
the Kerberos and then once you have
created tasty G's tedious RQ message
with the krbtgt which is the user for
Kerberos in a Windows environment you
can actually use this along with the
fake pack that you created to send this
to vulnerable DC and that will that will
issue you a new Kerberos ticket that you
can say when use it for its lifespan so
that means you'll have unrestricted
access for the lifespan of that ticket
the by default that ticket is issued for
a life span of 7 days after that it
expires so then probably the domain
controller is yours these are this is
the minimum information you need in
order to run this by cacti cake is just
the name of the exploit which is written
in this Python script that when you ran
when you run this you need at least so
for example I've shown Bob here Bob is
like normal domain user so you need his
username password security identifier
which you can find out he's livid hue my
command on the DOS
you need the name of the DC domain
controller
and then you need to make sure the time
is synced from the computer you're
trying to hack with the domain
controller because time synchronization
is important factor when it comes to
Kerberos volt this is just showing you
hoe with user Bob's credentials we are
trying to request to DC for a ticket and
this is the name of the ticket that we
have gone and that we've got
successfully you can move it to two
local temp directory where you want and
then you can present it with one of the
one of the SMB clients this I'm doing
from the for the linux linux distro so
you can have access to to the drive
whichever you want because now that
ticket is valid through the domain with
the super admin privileges this is this
is one example of attack for the
Kerberos fake ticket attack but one of
the other ways which is really stealth
and very popular these days in the
Scotty comment is using offensive
PowerShell I've named some of the
modules here which are popular used by
the pen testers around to bypass loads
of controls inside so for any security
intelligent products they miss because
it's very stealth there's no noise made
on the network and it's a new concept so
people and businesses are taking too
long to enable say PowerShell logging
and related mitigations talking about
passwords so once you have that access
you can always dump these passwords also
using the built-in built-in controls for
example you don't need to create for
example doing alsace injection to get
the hashes out or to dump all the user
hashes you can always use NTDs util dot
exe which is inbuilt and TBS binary in
the domain controllers and you can
create a snapshot of an to get state
database move that database and you can
always cracked under hashes from that so
there's no need for injections or other
techniques here as we see the threat
landscape is changing very fast so
today's attacks are actually outsmarting
the traditional attacks using the tools
or the techniques and the frameworks
which are now probably banned so the
another factor that's
actually helping these attackers get
more smarter results so the security
analytics work which is missed by the
threat side of the world so that the
defensive side actually is also stepping
up their game by using the security
analytics which means security analytics
is all about setting a baseline based on
the patterns collected on the user
objects in a domain so you will actually
be creating like some sort of mechanism
without deploying any agents and all
with all the information more the domain
objects and attributes to make sure you
can use that information in correlation
with the detection attacks to make sure
that you catch the attacker activities
early in the cycle not when the
compromise has happened but when the
recognizance or the earlier phases are
going on so that's what these threat
solutions are are these days I mean
there are a couple of them going on for
example you have heard of Microsoft
advanced threat analytics thus known as
doing some news around the zero data
centers Microsoft has also started
rolling out slowly to the corporate
world but also I guess one Israeli based
startup is their javelin networks they
have developed some product which is ad
protect that also works on a similar
manner
so yeah in defense these are the three
mechanism that we can actually use you
know it's like a sequential approach we
can apply to in a different manner
which will be identifying any any events
which are in action for example recon
activities using instant on event
monitoring then you can mitigate threats
to to the infrastructure with the use of
efficient volunteer management process
and then prevent is all about stepping
up your techniques and defenses to make
sure next time the same mistakes are not
repeated using the purple teaming or
honey pots or we have a keynote tomorrow
or with her own mayor so don't miss his
talk is really one of the famous
personalities we have his idea the
started his company was doing is very
good mechanism as well similar to
honeypot so well he hasn't paid me or I
have gotten no connections but just
saying because it came to my mind
talking about the difference and then
after that the calbro's attacks we
discussed now from the defense side what
all we can do so as I said because of
the issue with the Kerberos thing was
really about exploiting the rc4 cipher
based encryption type so we can always
look out for that when when the Kerberos
noise are is made if you're logging is
enabled efficiently so you can always
look for these events here these ones
where cat Ross tickets is requested this
will be and then with the ticket
was renewed so the first event is very
noisy so that the volume of logs is
quite high so you need to make sure that
you are keeping the balance and and
making sure that the configurations are
right in terms not to avoid any
shutdowns yeah so these are again admin
log on log off event and then the golden
for golden ticket you need to look at
the logs at the bc only or the domain
controller and for the silver tickets
it's from any member of the domain which
is any computer part of the domain will
be sending that generating that event so
if we are if we are doing the event
logging respectfully I guess that would
be really helpful here this is the list
on our Microsoft blog site of the after
cipher sorry for the encryption types
which is in the hacks if you see oh 17
this is the 17 and 18 so these are let's
see for ciphers that can be used to as a
keywords to block this although the
modern operating systems when as a
modern since windows indict the Kerberos
itself has been added with AES support
which is AES 128 and 256 bits but then
sometime before the big corporations
what's happening is inter 4s
communication is there and then that
enter forest support still doesn't use
automatically so that's configured with
rc4 so that needs to be done to improve
it to a yes to enable that support is
there for the trust so this is where the
or it can be set within the win the
group policy these two events this is
how it looks like in Axum format any
event log so if you see here this is
event ID and then this is the
information about the username
just targeted for the event logging and
then there's a domain name and the
related information the city is there
which is a security identifier so now
the monitoring recommendation because if
you keep on monitoring everything okay
let's start doing this that could be so
much of pain because the volume of the
traffic being collected is humongous so
that becomes the operational overhead as
well so you need to keep in mind which
all categories you should go for for
example you're looking for high
privileged accounts and ways that main
domain admin and built-in admins DBAs
and then account naming conventions for
example this is this is very common team
deployed by that means all these
machines in a network are named using a
naming notation so you can easily set
some regular expression to see that if
the name is not familiar to your company
that means some other laptop or machine
is connect to the network so you can
always raise that as to be logged so
that can be dealt with quickly
similarly outside working over people or
external vendors and then non-active
disabled or guest accounts there also
red alert and then restricted use
systems or devices for example sometimes
companies leave the screens outside
running and those kiosk modes are
actually Windows operating systems
behind the scenes so they can be broken
out off just like Citrix or any other
remote working desktops detection
process so protection for process for
offensive PowerShell these days is very
important because Porsche has come up
with really lot of security enhancements
since version 5 so you can actually
enable the logging per module and then
the script block logging here will log
pretty much everything for you that
means that the way they are executing it
will contain the full content of the
code the entire script and also if it's
addy office created code sometimes you
use - encoded for base64 or any other
things - to pass your payload without
getting recognized and that will also be
there so it really provides a good base
for incident response jobs this is
because it's automatically enabled these
are log events you need to set it to off
or configure
the way you want it this is mainly for
PowerShell the tools here when I refer I
guess most of times mimic ATS is is very
popular through PowerShell to to read
passwords in clear-text or pick up
hashes or changed passwords or the
hashes for certain users so these are
the keywords that can be used to
actually sort out or to search through
the logs and they can be further taken
for analysis and the event ID is this
one for 103 these are just the examples
this is not a full list of when you're
monitoring some ad events which all
events are actually of some importance
because obviously this side is the
security world where you want to log in
everything but this side is also the
administration and the business side of
compulsions where you need to set a
balance you can't have a big team
actually just looking at the logs whole
day it's it's a headache at the end of
the day so you need to only log optimum
amount of data that can also be dealt
with accordingly fast so this is a quick
list but I've also put a link here that
that contains audit sensitive privilege
use which will contain all the elements
for example if a token is created if
debug programs are there or any drivers
are loaded or any firmware and one mint
values are changed or somebody's
impersonating a client basically all the
sensitive parts which will issue issue
red flag and in the mitigate approach
it's all about how Kerberos thing can be
actually mitigated or Outsiders can be
reduced or minimized you can always set
the service account passwords to - quite
long practice and ensure that these are
not guessable and then there's a new
concept launched by Microsoft during we
understand this MSI which is
anti-malware scan interface this can be
integrated
wherever Windows BitDefender is so the
whole game is being changed by Microsoft
now if you see next two years I highly
believe that if you see Windows
BitDefender I don't know how many of you
rely on this but I rely on its heavily
for understand you don't need to spend
on an anti viruses so this is giving a
really good competition
to all these big anti voices and then
even in media there are news now that
there's been some online legal fights
going on between these vendors and
Microsoft and then Microsoft is stepping
up its game with advanced analytics
which will be there so I think this all
will be components will be part of the
operating system now the one when it'll
be given to the users so that you don't
need to rely on different vendors I
don't know if it's a business move but
security wise if they're doing it right
and efficiently I guess that would that
will add bonus to their sources on the
operating system so all these different
modules are enabled with the log in here
powershell javascript Wiebe script
security and NT and anti-malware these
script engines are actually integrated
so as soon as there's any alerts or
events they just pull that and feed it
to the anti-malware engine and that
looks into into the malware things in
the in the prevent method what we can do
to reduce these activities and how to
learn these lessons to not repeat again
these are the three main examples of
belief one be the implementing least
privilege administrative model where
privilege is the main problem because
everybody's given permissions quickly
but the time to take off or revoke those
permissions is quite long or they're
often forgotten so they can be misused
and similarly implementing a CRM server
host if you are asked your configuration
hard lines defined for servers and
domain controllers against an attack
they are really useful here these are
the details about the same lease British
Australian model how these can be can be
useful in terms of those over past pass
the hash attacks or overuse of
privileges because so is down to
privileges
sometimes these enterprise admin domain
admin and built-in accounts which a
built-in admins are not seen as really
powerful because people say okay if it's
domain admin that's more powerful than a
built-in and Men but the whole game is
about stepping up from the local admin
as well so local admin holds quite
powerful
function in a network this should be
disabled by group policy
and reducing the privileges again
disabling the local admin configuring
your group policies to restrict
administrative accounts securing the
built-in accounts in this and these are
couple of examples where you can
actually use two to the controls which
are inbuilt to limit these for example
the account is sensitive and cannot be
delegated flag so it will immediately
tell you if the attribute on a domain
based account the credentials cannot be
presented to other computers when you
are trying to actually throw the hashes
around to see if they leave because if
the account you're trying to use on the
domain admin it will restrict you and
not let you login
similarly if smartcard is there for
interactive logins that will be flagged
immediately yeah so I'm flying through
now I guess we were running out of time
so it's cure I my co-host this is more
about the principles about separating
the privileges within a trusted and
under non trusted areas I've made this
quick list or you should look at it from
the different perspectives means the
account configuration physical security
is also important and then the app
Locker policies for for restricting the
users RDP restrictions are also
important because of the remote access
and then the patching is one of the
important as we showed you through MS 14
or 68 and blocking internet access on
the servers because that says no use you
don't really need it and then any
anasazi software as well and then
virtualization is also very helpful at
times when very possible outside
consider implementing these virtual
machines as that mysterio host because
that can create per user an incentive
system that you can create more rather
than actually adding up to the cost and
then parameter firewalls on the
defense's these are references images
are stolen from
TechNet apart from the blue ones that
created events to monitor link is here
securing ad best practices and then this
this source is really helpful if you're
looking at reading in detail concepts
about a Brussels attacks I've read this
a lot and I follow this guy so huge
thanks to him that's pretty much for
today