I also vacuum everybody my name is Ron
Kumaresh and the topic of this
presentation will be the Lockheed
ransomware and this talk is about the
unti analyzes techniques used by the
ransomware but before we go into the
technical details of the difference
methods used by the ransomware I want to
tell a few words about me again I
graduated from the Budapest University
of Technology and economics few years
ago in software engineering department
and at the MSC in the university I
joined to the creases lab and its
student core and to the respondent has
captured the fact the city of steam and
now I work at the academy technologies
cafe as an IT security specialist and
first of all in this presentation I want
to speak about the low key ransomware
and I want to answer an answer this
question that what the lucky ones are
very easy and I want to tell a few words
about it's probably about it spreading
method its distribution technique and
short summary about its working method
and after that I want to focus and the
anti analysis techniques used within the
runs number and I want to focus on our
analysis results and add remaining part
of this presentation I want to talk I'll
talk about a Hungarian ransomware called
a key which is a short for the Hungarian
loci and I want to highlight the
similarities and mainly the most
different season and most significant
differences between the low key and the
hockey runs number because hockey looks
like as the low key runs number but
there are huge differences between the
two brands of our families and at the
end of this presentation I want to
conclude the results of our examination
so let's start with a short introduction
to the low key ransomware the low key
runs on Paris is a rentable marker that
is released in the February
in the February of 2016 and the road
number itself is delivered by a phishing
campaign using some kind of social
engineering technique and ransomware
itself using an email in an attempt to
Microsoft Office document that contains
malicious macros so if the user opens
the document and enables the macros
within the document the macros will then
save and lounge around somewhere
sorry downloader adulterer binary and
this will be the first phase of the
infection and this Dell other binary
will download the actual encryption
payload that if the runs over itself
from a command and control server a C&C
server that is controlled by the
attackers and after that the payload is
loaded into the memory of the user
system and encrypts all files that make
particular extensions on the victim
computer it is important to note that
there are numerous versions numerous
variants of the low key ransomware that
are using different file extensions for
the encrypted files and the name of
these versions will be the name of the
extension that the that runs over uses
when encrypting files so for example
Loki Odin Thor and so on and it
important that in this presentation I
want to talk about the tour variant of
the runs over that is originally
delivered by J as JavaScript or VBS
visual basic script attachment and the
ransomware itself is also active in 2017
and the most recent version of the
ransomware is the Aussie riff
so the the most of the name of the most
recent version of the razzleberry so
series it was released in the in the end
of the last year so so a few words about
the working method of the reservoir as I
mentioned the runs over itself
encrypts all files on the user's
computer with a specific estate
extension and other encryption
it is displayed on the user the next tab
here you can see an example for this
ransom note for this message and this
message instructs the victim user to
download a specific browser at all
browser and to visit a specific cyber
criminal operated web site where the
victim can found can find useful
information to decrypt his or her file
ok the reservoir itself is a 32-bit
Windows executable that contains the
malicious core pegged and encrypted and
of course office gated and within the
outer executable the reason an encrypted
DLL so the ultra executable ample
employees and encrypted the 11 stellar
and after unpacking the internal
encrypted DLL the executable dropper
creates a new process from itself spawns
a new process from itself and injects
and loads the extracted already
extracted dll into the newly created
process it to the address space of the
newly created process and finally passes
the control flow to the entry point of
the DLL so after deployment transparency
drop copy usually from the actual user
stamp folder and encrypts all files that
have the specified extensions as I
mentioned earlier the encryption is
performed using strong cryptography
algorithms such as the RSA a symmetric
key crypto algorithm or the AES as a
symmetric key crypto so and because the
attackers poses the private key pair of
the RSA key it is practically impossible
to decrypt the encrypted files manually
the sample communicates with the C&C
server with its remote C&C server with a
custom HTTP based protocol using HTTP
post requests and the full communication
over this channel is encrypted and it is
important to note that
the public RSA key that is needed by
general somewhere to encrypt the files
and the ransom note and some other
information are also fetched from this
remote C&C server by the internal of the
reservoir but in the focus of this
presentation using the the antenna is
techniques of the ransomware and here
you can see the unique hash fingerprint
of the samples that we have like the
mind during our analysis and in this
presentation I want to focus of the
results of the analyse of these samples
you can see the md5 sha-1 and share 256
fingerprints of be examined samples so
it's important to note that the outer
executable the outer 32-bit executable
of the ransomware itself uses multi
layer difference method and the first
layer of its different method is a new
soft installer package so the Rosenberg
binary and this outer executable binary
is packed into a new soft special a
specific news of installer package so
the installer package is used as a
packing method but has an affiliation
layer and the loaders to you an obvious
example for some an obvious examples for
some strings in the binary that
indicates that the runs over uses the
nodes of this data package can be seen
here for example the new soft in string
winning the binary the presence of the
string in the binary the presence of
these strings in the binary of course
the unpacking process of the binary is a
very simple exercise you can extract the
binary using for example some kind of
zip application that can extract nsis
packages and
to extraction we get the following list
of Pfizer you see a plug into your
directory and some other files the
important thing is that the most of
these files are not important or not
relevant for us they are just some
component files of the installer package
there are two important files for us is
the NSA s dot NSA file that contains
script code and another file that
contains encrypted content which has a
random name in this example and if we go
it in the plugins directory there are
further files the the only relevant file
for us here is the system DLL file which
is a which is a plugin of the of the
NSIC stellar package and this module
this plug-in enables for the developers
to invoke directly windows API calls
from the prayers mentioned anise is not
an SI script the purpose of the unifier
NSI a script is to is to describe the
necessary steps the necessary process to
install the binary itself and if we if
we look into the look into the look into
this file into the script file we can
see the unit function at the top of the
slide this function is automatically
called within the script file when the
anasazi installer package is executed
and the number is a very simple of whose
Kashin technique as the first layer of
device of its defense it only includes a
lot of junk code within the within the
script code and if we remove the
instructions or the lines that is
starting with the in top instruction the
code of the script can be more read can
be more readable and another important
thing is the system call
inside the script the call function is
implemented in the mentioned system but
DLL plugin and using this call function
within the script the script can invoke
the windows api calls directly the only
parameter of the call function is the
name of the windows api call and another
of vocation technique that is presented
within the script is that at the full
name of this of this module windows api
at the funny but this windows api
function or call is built up from
substring is an example you can see an
example for this yes if you see the SDR
CPI function in the third line of the
script and after be manually will tap
the from these sub strings the name of
the of the of the windows API call after
that the decoded - is instructions will
be the following so we get the following
code snippet at the in the first line
the ransomware tries to retrieve the
address of the cannister kernel32.dll
library because when the when the
process is running the chemistry - dll
is already loaded into the address space
of the of the runs over so the the only
purpose of this function invocation is
to retrieve the address of the 2d
actually loaded medulla and after that
right after death the script uses the
cat + address windows api function with
this which is again in the kernel32.dll
module and tries to do try to retrieve
the starting address of some karna 32
the dll functions for example create
file virtual agreed file and close
handle and the addresses of these
functions of the starting addresses of
these functions we
restored in r2 r3 r4 and r5 variables or
or registers if we use the terminology
of the NSF's in stellar okay and if we
look at the second half of the script
snippet and if we replace the register
names with their values we can get the
following script snippet and here we see
that the that the ransomware
tries to not not that tries to create
but tries to open the already mentioned
five with random name from the root
directory of the installer package and
then using the read file windows API
call it simply reads the content of this
encrypted binary into the newly
allocated memory area that is allocated
by the virtual I'll log in those API
Cola and then close closes the handle of
the file it is not important for us and
the important for us is the last line of
this code in the last line of the code
the runs over invokes a specific address
within the already loaded encrypted
binary because the starting address of
the this binary will be in the r0
register and you can see an and offset
value after the name of this register
and it passes a single parameter to this
to this code which will be the name of
this encrypted binary within the NSA
installer package okay so the from here
in the focus of this presentation will
be the encrypted binary payload and
within the end encrypted binary payload
our multi-level ixora encryption is
performed
as I mentioned in the previous slide the
NSI script passed this control flow to
the next security code snippet we didn't
be encrypted binary because not the
whole binaries encrypted but there is a
few lines of code that is clear and here
you can see the code that is not
encrypted within the within the
mentioned file and here you can see an
assembly trace an assembly instruction
trace and if you look at to the first
instruction the first assembly
extraction yeah you see a move
instruction this move extraction moves
the 0 XC 3 value into the DL register of
the CPU it's important that the 0 axis
real value is the hexa that in a
representation of the assembly read
instruction so here the purpose of the
assembly trace is to find within this
trace the first read instruction and
after it finds the read instruction it
it pops up from the binary the next to 4
byte values the first 4 byte value will
be the length the length parameter and
the next 4 byte value will be on XOR key
and this XOR key will be used to decrypt
the the remaining part of the binary the
remaining encrypted part of the binary
ok and after the decryption of the
remaining part of the binary the next
instruction the decrypted instructions
assembly instructions after after the
length and an Excel key parameter will
be this will be the second stage of the
decryption routine and it is important
at the second stage of the decryption is
the same totally the same instructions
that were in the in the first stage and
the bad news is that the runs over
employs further six layers of decryption
but the but the good news is that that
all the crucial layers contains the same
instructions so the binary performs a
total of eight layers of decryption and
the only difference between the stages
is the value of the decryption langston
and the value of the XOR key parameter
and after the last layer of decryption
the control flow continues at the
beginning of a C function after a jump
instruction but is not necessary as okay
so as I mentioned the final malicious
payload is an and that didn't encrypted
dll inside the executable
but this DL ADIZ is encrypted now and
this DLL is inside this encrypted binary
blob at the start of this angry
encrypted binary blob and right after
this encrypted binary blob will be the
LVDS and retrace Nitai that is so okay
and the next layer of the the next layer
of the novice difference method for the
roughest kavia there will be further
verification and encryption in the
executable binary and the malware
after this after the after this assembly
trace essentially performs the following
tasks with some kind of import address
table that is used to refer the
necessary external library functions
primary for from Canada 32 DLL and from
a DVI API 32 the DLL and the binary
tries to find the specified functions
within these modules within these loaded
modules
based on their export export table as
biggest and based on the functions
specific checksum value and the
reservoir tries to find the appropriate
function based on the checksum value the
ransomware it is important that the
ransomware uses a modified version of
the crc32 checksum calculation algorithm
and after it finds the necessary import
functions from the kernel 32 dot
dialogue and the db-api 32 dll modules
then first the already mentioned import
address table here you can see the
manually imported the manually imported
functions of the runs over itself from
the kernel32.dll and ADV api 32 the dll
modules ok and the last and the next
step of the of the the of the unpacking
method that is applied within the
ransomware is to is to extract the dll
and decrypt the DLL from the encrypted
binary so the on process of the
executable that is the NS is a stellar
package and its process was the
originally encrypted binary image of the
ransomware this will be the file that I
mentioned with random name and this file
and that malicious encrypted the allele
at offset 0 X 0 X 11 and from this
offset the the encrypted the Olalla
we replaced the encrypted binary robot
the DLL will be placed within the binary
and the DLL is extraordinary
so the DLL is decrypted using a simple
xor xor algorithm that we
see in the next slide and the length of
the decryption and xor key is stored
right before the encrypted binary blood
of the dll okay oh sorry
the XOR key is not stored right before
the encrypted binary by the Unicode
string of the fine name serve as the XOR
key of the decryption it's correct okay
and here you can see the X or decryption
routine it's a simple it's a simple
Excel decryption the the algorithm goes
through the embedded and encrypted
binary blob and and and and and the
actual for by it four bytes of the
binary blob is ex-ored with the 4x6 or
key and the resulting key is further and
the resulting values further exhort with
an offset parameter that will be the
value of the index parameter in our case
okay and as the last step of the
unpacking process the original process
spawns a new process from itself using
the NSIC installer package and expose
the process in suspended state and then
the embedded dll is manually loaded and
relocated it is important that the
binary contains relocation of
instructions using the standard windows
p relocation table format and then the
dll is injected into the address space
of the newly created process using a
shared memory between the original
process and visit and between the newly
created process using two entity Lidl
functions namely the anti create section
and anti method of section functions so
the mother
create an allocated memory within the
original process using the ante create
section and using the ante Matthew of
section the runs on verb Maps this
memory area to the into the address
space of the newly created process and
then simply copies the content of the
decrypted DNA into the address space of
the target process okay an interesting
feature within the ransomware that the
anti DLL functions as I mentioned a nut
code directly from the entity ID of the
other module the binary directly invoke
the appropriate system calls that are
related to the actual anti DLL functions
and to achieve this it runs on birth
determines the appropriate system call
numbers based on the code based on the
instructions of the mentioned anti DLL
functions and this is done most likely
to make it difficult difficult the
automatic in the automatic analysis of
the runs over and maybe to be hidden
from detection and the last data so in
this in this phase of the injection the
DLL is injected into the address space
of the target process but the control
flow is not passed yet the entry point
of the Diyala so the last step of the
injection is to hijack the control flow
and in order to do this the original
process modifies the value of the image
base address matter some kind of metal
into information within the suspended
process to the base address of the
injected Dayla
and then hijack the control flow of the
suspended process to the entry point of
the DLL
by exchanging the value in register AIX
of the CPU because this register right
after loading right after the loaded the
binary the register AIX contains the
address of the entry point of the
suitable but it is important that it can
be done directly in modern operating
systems so so a process can't directly
exchange the value in any of the
register is in another CPU in another
thread context in another process so the
runs over itself uses a simple trick
risk standard method the original CPU
context is saved by the runs over and
then it exchanged the value within the
AIX register to point to the entry point
of the dll and then restores the CPU
context within the within the target
process using standard windows api casa
and then reserves the newly created
process so it will execute after its
suspended state ok and as i promised at
the start of this presentation i want to
talk a short about the hungarian run
somewhere called hockey which is the
abbreviation of hungarian loki and at
the first glance this ransomware family
looks like loki looks like too low-key
but if we if we look at the runs over
closer we can see that there are huge
differences between the two runs of our
families so here you can see d the only
cash fingerprints of D of the eczema in
samples share one fingerprint okay here
are the similarities between the two
runs on four samples but ransom verse
aim is to encrypt valuable files and to
demand money for the decryption the
encryption process is quite similar in
both cases a s Keys randomly generated a
s key is used for file encryption in
both cases and this random randomly
generated
Heskey is done further encrypted by a
public RSA key and at the end of the
encryption process the victim machine
looks similar in both cases in this
picture you can see an example for the
case of the Acura number okay and the
differences between the two runs over
samples the main and most significant
bit differences that indicate that that
that hockey that the hacker on soccer
fan family can be created by the same
threat actors at loci okay so the most
the most significant difference between
the two runs over samples is the
programming language Loki is implemented
in C language by a hockey uses and based
on Microsoft visual basic.net so it uses
managed code and it is implemented in
visual basic script a kiss code uses
Hungarian words as namespace and not a
variable name is a' another difference
is the public encryption key loki
retrieves and retrieving method at the
time of the public encryption key loki
retrieves the public RSA key from a
remote C&C server that is controlled by
the attackers in the case of hockey the
public RSA key is hard-coded sarkodie in
XML format and an interesting thing in
the background somewhere is that all the
examined samples contained the same
hard-coded RSA public key a key displays
a dummy word document while encrypting
files and after that perform the system
restart in case of Loki these activities
at in the binary and not implemented in
the binary
another difference is the payment
requesting metalder loki instructs the
user to visit tor pages in case of a key
actually requires victims to send an
email to the given major address here
you can see a code snippet from the
decomp I'd source code of the hockey the
recommend the comments are placed by us
and here you can see the Hungarian words
in variable names in object names and in
the names of the functions so as the
conclusion of this presentation I want
to tell that in case of the documents on
where we see we saw that that this
random value is not using any new
technique any any new trick rather it's
using well-known for the standard
techniques but the quantity of the
techniques used in tourism when applied
in the ransomware indicates that the
author's invested sufficient and
significant effort to hide the internal
side the internal working and internal
malicious functionality of the runs over
itself maybe this is done in order to
make difficult static analysis of these
samples and the reverse engineering of
the samples and also to hurt them the
analysis in automated sandbox
environment and we saw from the example
of the hacker runs over that other
threat actors usually try to copy the
behavior of successful run long bars
maybe in order to increase their chances
of getting ransom payments from victims
so that's it thank you
[Applause]