[Music]
I'm Kevin from Lenovo so I'm going to
talk about the open source graphic
engine actually this is not something
like how to implement the Rhenish
specific schema but a kind of framework
to help us develop our radish service
quickly yeah we we had this idea about
since the beginning of last year because
you know the real fish is moving very
fast we are consider the TMT of
discussion and update on the radishes
schema and radish spec so sometimes we
have to change our design and also
repeat to some repeat work because of
there is a new education on the property
because because there is new enum enum
member or new annotation we have to some
change to to adapt this new change but
adapt this in a spec and schema update
so we do want a more efficient engine to
reduce the maintenance effort on the
schemas and the red fish spec upgrading
but focus more on the red fish schema
itself okay what what we want to want
from the red fish engine first it should
be a small engine with with small engine
with fuel memory footprint and it could
be the library so it we want it to run
on post p.m. C and the laptop means
and we do want to have a measure to team
the to tune the response time one of the
most important Singh for redfish engine
is we have to separate the redfish per
taco stories from the redfish data model
for example I'm focusing on the red
storage controller is unnecessary for me
to know the detail of the how to
calculate the attack how to assign the
privilege I need to focus more on the
data model of raid volume drive right so
you know the redfish spec has a long
list of requirements we don't want to
this one this becomes spreading or the
skimmers but we do want put all of the
protocol and service related modules
inside the redfish engine and also we
want to extract most common things in
the real fish schema outside of the data
model so based on which we can make make
the most automation work for example we
can also generate the crossfire which
containing the static definition from
the schema and we also want to do auto
generation for our redfish response or
the most common commonalities like the
headers the meditator the OData the
OData information the navigation
property the links and so on and also
you know the redfish cover a lot of area
which means we need to get the data from
all kinds of the data source so we doing
neither unified method to represent
their the diversity of data type and
data source this can also make sure we
have a common coding style when multiple
people much more people working on the
redfish schemas and finally about the
performance as you know we cannot
promise each schema has the same
response time but we do want a measure
to tune tune the response time most time
it means the caching okay
let's take a look at the snare
architecture first basically it has
three parts the first is there in green
color is the web server and application
server we are using the nginx
and the Judy comb and the flask of
framework which for which using which
use their tablets Jie interface the I
think this has a couple of benefits
first we can move some work balance work
to the nginx instead of and then invent
it in the redfish engine and also if we
have better choice on the web server or
application server we can replace them
without changing our engine code okay
the second part is the engine as I just
mentioned we put the most protocol and
the slowest modules inside the engine
including the request parsing the data
model parsing and redfish related
related service a service module like
session token authentication privilege
and we also exchange most commonalities
from the relevant schema we put the base
class in this engine for auto generation
of the response we put our auto
generated a classifier in this layer I
will talk about it later
the third part is the exact relative
schema implementation we also put the
data interface layer here to help
developers to to work on their own
schemers and we have their back-end data
provision inside this base layer and
also providing the caching we also have
the standalone tour to generate the
schema the class files from schemer ok
next I will introduce several design
point house never take the efficiency
into account first is about the class
hierarchy so at the bottom is the base
class and resource class map map to the
standard schema in this layer there are
many methods to use to help assemble the
response data without your menu work and
we we put the most common and
commonality things in in this base based
classes and in the middle the middle of
the middle block in the auto-generated
cast there are
from the schema files so this prey and
bring a great benefit from schema
upgrading for example if we are we are
planning to use the upgrading upgrade to
the schema 2018 country there are some
new notations on the property there are
a new privilege defined for the class or
operation or there are some new enum
enum members we just need to use the
utility to generate all these class
files from schema and replace them so
the base class will contain all the
privilege of validation the enum
validation in the request body and even
the annotation inside the schema schema
class file so you don't need to need to
change the implement implementation or
the best class you just need to replace
the auto generic the classifier above
the classifier exactly what you need to
focus on the schema class you just need
to fear in the dynamic data you are
interested in to implement in these
files this class files and they are when
to when when mapping to the
auto-generate in the class for example
the computer system you interact from
the underscore P computer system and the
chassis and the power and also on the
top is the order redfish protocol and
the service modules you can extend your
modules based on the update of the
redfish schema without change
the engine code or schema class class
fare okay next is about the resource
tree basically result research you can
view the redfish data module as a
resource tree the concept in in redfish
spec is the resource tree is actually a
set of URI there is only one we all know
URI that is their service service route
but actually we cannot make sure all the
rest the UI are consistent because it
may change our hardware configuration
for our designer yeah and sometimes the
cross reference reference in the between
the class resulting the reference ring
so let's considering how the network
adapter collection how does it know how
many members under it and how does the
network adapter knows the reference
being to PCI device on the system schema
apparently hard code is not a good idea
so in snapper we introduced their
accessor key you can make your own lower
two to define the accessor key each URL
is mapped to the accessor key here we
defined a successor key with the
instance ID and class name now
you can map between the URI and
obsessive heat
the question is how do we get the
topology
of the UI are a necessity if you are
using the data module passing you can
certainly get part of the topology but
is not enough you must implement the cat
member ID access a key for each resource
that means when the PCI device
collection cards their PCI that you'd
want to know the PCI device ID it were
called or PCI device cat member access a
key then this function will return the
instance ID and the accessor key so that
builds the relationship between the
schema instance ID and accessor key and
the URI so back to the previous question
how do we know the how does the network
adapter knows there is a link under the
system schema is just called function
members as a key for the PCI device
class then PCI device class will return
the accessor key and based on the
information inside the Sasaki is the
slot number on Baldwin and sorcery then
we use their mapping API to kill the URI
yes and please note if you are using the
hard code of your eye the TM TF markup
may change may move the PCI device from
system to the chassis over time we don't
know when he makes the change but if you
are using the accessor key you only knew
to to a small change for example if you
are under the chassis you can determine
they're determine you if you need to
return the right mapping by the
containing pass if the containing pass
is under chassis then you return this
psi device device table but if you are
under the system you don't need to
return any Macky okay next is about the
unified data data in the face layer
since the redfish schema cover many
areas there are many data sauce and the
tail type so internally we were used or
binary JSON Pisan to represent the
internal data structure and based on
which we can provide a common API to set
in the carrot ater this actually split
the data provision to two layers one
layer is just simply fill in the schema
data and the other is for data driver
which actually interact with the
hardware interface and we can group this
theater you know redfish request
normally they read read or write a bunch
of data so we can group the groups in
digital high profile we can put the
inventory data together we can pull the
red wiki data together we can put the
reddit or together by different profile
so as you can see several schema can
share the same data returned from this
API so furniture this kind of data
interface can centralize the data
caching management
this is an example of the interface API
we provide the two api's calendar and
senator the first example carried the
data from profile computer system
non-volatile data which means most of
this data are consistent we don't need
to retrieve them again and again and and
the we can also called a function
defining the XML with parameters and the
set data by key value format yeah
on the right side the XML define the
profile in the computer system group you
can see we support the variable and
table and there are flags for the right
potater and at the bottom is the usage
of P so you can see this kind of vision
usage is very straightforward and easy
to use
so next talk about the data caching in
previous data interface by Nature it has
the caching management capability so
basically we in stepper we can have to
cash layer the first is the json text
json text caching is mapped UI 2 to the
json response the most common scenario
is the log entries for example you have
five four thousand log entries this this
kind of data will take a long time to do
sterilization so if we catch this
in memory or database laggin readies you
can save a lot of civilization time that
this kind of caching has a problem that
is the Quran analogy is too big it
cannot share between between class okay
then we have the second layer air to air
to caching based on piece on because B
song is a binary you save lots of memory
and we can group this data by profile
here take an example we pull the storage
inventory together in you know you know
piece on object and we also put we PDF
raw data in another piece on object and
and also about the network adapter here
is an example when you when the clan
they used their car or postman to access
their network collection the back end
actually already have other network
adapter information from from board to
sort 1 2 3 so if we catch this data you
don't need to access them again when
next time user access the slot 1 network
adapter so the most important thing for
l2 cache is how we group this data how
we determine the granularity of this
business object
yeah I I did a comparison between the
snapper and BMC web actually I don't
find many example to do the comparison
so so please forgive me if I have missed
understanding in this table here is a
little unfair to compare BMC web with
Napa because BMC app is actually to
everything web server which support not
only redfish but also the web GUI the
console direction where snapper folks on
the redfish Engine a lightweight
lightweight engine it does not create
the web server it can even replace the
web server it connected to so I think
it's possible that we can integrate this
engine with BMC at BMC web and because
it is using their index and the flask
framework it can leverage many open
source features like ssee misaki from
the nginx and the nginx and flask
modules and we also create the data
interface layer to reduce the effort of
schema developer about the performance I
think the BMC web is using the booster
tau I so it should be we should have
high efficiency on performance snapper
use the C extension module and we rely
on the Python networking library G event
for concurrent access
because the junii comb is prefault
the pre for the worker mode mmm is
support they're much much more process
module so but but we also have the
capability to support multi thread and
we have two levels of data caching to
tune the performance about the protocol
and stories
I see the BMC web will rely on the web
server cron support I also see there are
some missing function defined in the
redfish spec like attacked or auditory
tank property and aquarium parameters
and the task and the head had operation
our snapper in our snapper implantation
we are fully compliant with relevance
back 1.5 and also if tmpfs redfish back
have new requirement on the protocol
service and we can easily add a new
modules without changing the current
schema code engine code or we should
only change the engine code next is
about the redfish data model i see the
pmc web schema class is derived from the
node which is covered with the chrome
app instance for each schema it is using
the static you are rotating which means
the class is binding it with the hull
code URI and all the schema
implementation should be in there
schema class an action class but for
snapper we are running the runtime
runtime band in between the URI and the
real fishy resource because we have the
data model passing the EDM passing so
there is no hardcore UI and we are also
trying to - most automation work - like
we generate the most common data in the
response for each schema about the red
fish upgrading yeah I do see I to see
the PMC web I have Auto generation for
the magic message registry but when they
I think when they they are going to
upgrade the schema they need to change
the code for the schema version UNAM
dispatcher for snapper we generate all
the registry including error message
registry event reduced privilege
registry from the skin of schema fair
and for the base registry we just run
time generated from the data we got from
UEFI yeah and we also as I mentioned in
in the class in
as I just mentioned the efficient
someone the class and hierarchy the
snapper used the utility to generate all
the schema header files from OData XML
schema yeah for if you want to operate
the schema bundle we just need a few
minutes to replace the head of our next
these are what we want to do first never
in future first we need to move move the
move from Python to 2003 since the
patient to will not be maintained in
2020 but the snapper actually has less
dependency on Python you should not
should not be a big work and also if we
want a smaller footprint for the redfish
engine mmm I think we can consider a
better web server
I don't entity you know the Python will
consume memory more memory than C or C++
code yeah and also for the outdated
schema passing because currently the
redfish schema bundle is very large so
when we parsing the XML file you need
more mount memory but we can disable
some functions like we don't need the
description long description notation
that will save a lot of memory I think
the the most saying I am interesting is
the PRD m4r de this is the new
specification from the MTF is just
published couples a couple months ago
but as you know this standard is very
important to support the aisle
management it actually provides the
renovation management capability on IO
device the PCI device so basically the
BMC act as a proxy between the redfish
client and i/o device so what what we
need to do is to translate the redfish
message and operation to clear their
message operations two things we need to
do the wine is the binary JSON encoding
decoding because the option card does
not accept JSON text
they only accept binary so we we want
the MTF to to have this kind of tour
organ sauce and also we need the schema
dictionary discovery and we also need
the PR DM library to support the new PID
M type for a de next we we want to add
the bus interface apart you know data
interface layer it can be used for a lot
of data source like telemetry cache
refreshing avenging currently we we have
simulator opened on the github Lenovo
repository is part of the snapper code
it
but it almost cover most the engine
particle you can run on your laptop or
if you want to run inside BMC yes you
can change the make fair or to do it and
I also want to have a quick introduction
under few slides this is the auto
generation class the left is the
resource classifier the right top right
is the registry top water bottom right
is the privilege fair so for the schema
fair you can see the it cleared most
static information from the schema
including the property and the property
attribution and action information om OM
property and also the the attribution
under the annotation all kinds of
annotation on the properties and on
further registry you can directly use
the function to add the message into the
rad official response
this is how snapper generator resource
tree on the left is the recursion to
build the topology is that from salutes
and transfers are the properties and
expand them and also called get member
function CAD member ID access a key of
the child node finally it generated the
URI and assess the key table mapping
table so take a look at the PCI device
of computer system how do we determine
how to reach that further value for this
property
it's just invoke the function for PCI
device and the PCI device class will
return the table of ID and access a key
so based on the table based on the ID
and accessor key you can search the URI
by the information inside the access key
then you call the data for PCI device
this is our UI runtime binding we don't
have called the URI but for each segment
in the UI we will plan it to class like
Reggie facially when we burn with the
binding is south load and the chassis is
so it's chessick collection and chassis
ID 1 means chassis class and key segment
1 and power 4 per class
this is all yummy extension the family
this is what the schema implementation
looks like is for the error interface
look from this handle gate function you
just need to fill in a few dynamic
dynamic properties probably dynamic data
for the rest data in the response you
don't need to care and right in the red
side is the patch operation okay I think
that's all
any questions
if I wanted to try out snapper is all
the code out on Lenovo / snapper yeah
that's correct
so do you have any actual performance
numbers comparing your implementation
GBMC was CPU usage that kind of thing
yeah I have since I implement the the
lonoa implement the snapper work on
stack including the engine and specific
schema we implement the 27 to 33 so part
of the data provider code are the no
private code so this parameter R or
based on the for code stack so if you
look at the fair size the engines has in
is about 400 400 kilobytes and the date
of data interface is a large is about 1
megabyte because we have the all
underlying code including the database
database access our camera access mcdv
idea make sense they are all in there so
this dating phase is is a large and we
also have the snapper provider which
implement the order dynamic data of
skimmers it's three methods when you are
using the snapper engine you need to
replace there you need to implement your
own provider and coding on your own data
interface layer maybe you can use your
user debug d-bus
you can use your own database in the
data interface functions and the
profiles so that the data interface
library in your system depends on your
data Java implementation and also the
test provider residens about the memory
footprint the junior come I just
mentioned the Python will consume large
memory so much income is 10 Macbeth in
the 10 map at 2 is Unicom is itself the
other 8 Macbeth is flask frost module
the web framework and currently with the
radish schema bonded to 28 industry the
passing result will occupy 8 Macbeth but
if we reduce the unnecessary a notation
can be smaller and the photos snapper
engine and for provider because we have
a for stack is a 16 Macbeth but if you
want to check the rear side of a pure
ratify a snapper engine you can use the
simulator and remember stupid affair in
current open source I haven't stupid
affair yet this is the we are a yeah
I walked in late sorry from repeating or
asking questions you already answered
this uh did you say this was a this used
to be a private code base and now you're
open sourcing it is that what happened
the engine code he'd already opened but
did it start off as a proprietary code
base and now you're donating it or
developing this code stack in the open
since the beginning the only pro
probably coda is our provider
implantation the whole engine is already
opened I understand I understand it's
open now did it start open yeah we just
open it a couple of weeks ago because
you know we need to go through the open
source really process of our company
yeah so we open it about a couple of
weeks ago right okay and how long how
long have you as a been in-house can you
say we have this idea since the
beginning of last year okay was there
like was there ever a point in you kind
of your decision-making process where
you're looking at BMC web and and you
decided no we're gonna really do this
not exactly since we are looking at EMC
app because we have is actually
happening in our x86 server we have some
problem when the real fish when the TMT
of Rhenish from forum upgrading the
design just Bank the schema we have some
pain point like the schema updates the
property tribution UNAM sometimes we
have to redesign our real fish or to
some repeated work so we want
such a more efficient engine to help
accelerate our schema development yeah
the comparison I just did this operation
recently before that I don't I don't in
last year I haven't look into the BMC
web one more question so like there are
a number of comparison points there it's
a good chart like why would would it is
it possible to get these things that are
missing from BMC web into BMC what
Brasilia kind of opinion that it's sort
of a real ask I think the snapper can be
compared at the library and his web
server can either replace both so if we
have a better choice of web server and
application server we can replace the
end ganks and Unicom yes I think it's
possible to integrate the snapper with
BMC web ok thank you
your questions okay thank you
[Applause]
[Music]