[Music]
okay our next speaker is Crestwood she
is a principal engineer at Lenovo and
has been working on EMC firmware for 16
years but just recently joined hope and
BMC community today everybody good to be
here I was here at the hackathon
actually not here but in I guess it was
Beaverton last year got to meet a lot of
you see a lot of friendly familiar faces
we were there for our first time when
Nova was to get on board with open BMC
and I should stand here when you hear me
better so in the time since then we've
done a few POCs in-house and just wanted
to share with you some of the work that
we've done on some of our our products
that normally go out with our Lenovo
branded BMC firmware but we're trying to
explore and in the realm of open BMC so
the most of this talk is all about open
BMC on on lenovo branded hardware
specifically the sr9 50 so I'll get in
get into some of that so the first step
is the the the the Perley based systems
as the sr9 50 is a perlier based system
and we we build our hardware with a
speed pilot for chip so how many of you
here have used the a speed pilot for or
I've heard of it yeah okay great
hmm a lot of customers have it so that's
good
anyway the pilot for chip goes on all of
our pearly platforms and the first step
in getting opened BMC working is to
enable the silicon so we worked with the
a speed hardware engineers who are here
today and and firmware engineers to to
get the you know open BMC support mostly
the primarily getting the drivers on the
the you know in the open BMC development
framework so what the what did that
involve the
the a speed BSP or SDK comes with a lot
of drivers that are primarily written
for testing the hardware validating the
hardware so a lot of the drivers needed
to be touched to to work in the open BMC
framework and so what I've got here is a
very crude block diagram I did get
permission to show a much more detailed
one but anyway I went with this one
because it conveys the information
basically everything that's in green
where all of the drivers that had to be
touched to some degree or another
including the the basic that the chip
enablement for the for the processor
mm-hmm this this represented many months
of work to get going and you can see you
could go out to the github app provided
the github link on a speeds account to
to pull that branch so you could
actually play with this yourself you had
a pilot for BSP or a Lenovo service the
only hardware changes we had to make
were the adding the 32 megabytes by ROM
we boot from a smaller spy ROM so that's
that hardware change plus the associated
straps so that was step one which was
not an insignificant step it took many
months to get going we did initially
enable it on one of our lower end
servers SR 650 which is a two socket but
this endeavor was to see who could get
going on the SR 950 so that was a joint
joint operation with HP SR 950 just to
give you a brief introduction about it
it's kind of our flagship server and
this isn't a sales pitch about our
server and just need to give you a
little bit of background about what we
chose it's it's a very dense system so
it's a xeon based family the Perley
generation of processors it's got a lot
of i/o it's got sixteen PCIe slots for
power supplies it's highly modularized
so we have CPU trays and you can see
there we support eight sockets 96 dims
it's pretty storage rich and a lot of
fans so what this means for open BMC is
lots of sensors and a lot of potential
you know d-bus activity so this is one
of the reasons we were interested in
targeting this to see how well open BMC
scales
out to a very dense platform also I
wanted to point out the okay I wanted to
get still hear me okay yeah I just want
to point out the main board has of
course the pilot for which we talked
about and an FPGA the system FPGA is
it's common to all our platforms and
it's it it's a very significant piece of
our hardware so I wanted to give it a
little bit of a sound bite because
enabling the FPGA was also part of
getting the the open BMC to boot and run
right this is where power control is
this is where a lot of inventory comes
from and some temperature sensors and
fan control so we've offloaded a lot of
things on to the FPGA so FPGA is I don't
know how common they are in most of the
building blocks with VMC's but obviously
they've been around for a very long time
we chose an FPGA for this system because
frankly there's a lot of hyoe on it and
it's for what it's capable of doing it's
low-cost right you can you can change
the fabric after you spend the board's
we have a hundred and twenty voltage
regulators on our VRD devices in the
eight socket config of this platform so
with the power okay and the power good
there's you know 240 plus i/o that's
that's putting a strain on a on a
typical BMC just for GPIO it's also got
as an FPGA it's more real-time right so
you're responding in nanoseconds without
you know program loops inside this is
useful for power sequencing right so
when when you have a power fault you
need to back off those reels fast enough
you've got to do it fast enough so that
you don't get biasing this is to protect
your hardware so the FPGA is quick
enough to do that
across all these rails also there's some
LCD control so on this server we have
little LCD front panel up front and the
screen needs to be painted
you don't want your BMC constantly
painting pixels on the screen right so
the fpga takes care of that there
there's a long list of other things you
might use an FPGA for that fall under
the category of real-time offloading
anything you can
an FPGA up to your BMC and you have a
fast-enough link low enough latency you
can you know it's kind of a cool little
playground to imagine what what software
function you want to push out to the
FPGA it doesn't have to be Hardware
function you could accelerate a lot of
things with that so I'll leave that to
your imagination the other thing you
might want to offload is like time zero
so if you want to boot the server a
little faster what sort of things can
you can you have what the BMC could
normally do but you want the BMC doing
other things so it's not necessarily
real time but you want to do it in
parallel while you're booting so this is
you know we may have to configure the VR
DS based on the processor SKU that's in
the system and we want to enable power
as quickly as possible so the customer
doesn't plug it in and have to wait four
and a half minutes or whatever for their
BMC to be ready before they could turn
it on the LCD initialization - right
before video you get you get nice little
LCD telling you that the server's
working properly inventory there's a lot
of dims out here on well not on this
board but on the CPU boards so one could
imagine you can wire that FPGA and all
its i/o into multiple i2c buses to
pre-harvest SPD content or you know
other other things right then the BMC
can come back and ask the FPGA what
changed so a lot of value in putting an
FPGA with the BMC yeah so the other
thing is that it's it's a field
updatable I think I touched on that it's
it's hardware that kind of changes after
you build your board so you can you can
offload function let's say you find some
piece of function that's broken and you
don't have time to resend silicon
whether it's the BMC or something else
right you you you can push stuff onto
the FPGA and reduce your dependence on
on other silicon okay so what did we get
done with the SR 950 and this is this is
the part that's made me nervous because
we didn't actually get everything we
wanted to do completed before today but
we are still working on it right so we
do have a made a Lenovo layer where we
have support for the sr9 50 and the SR
the SR 650 is there as well I just
didn't list it it's under a different
name but yeah right now it's an internal
get repo because it's not mature enough
to share the rest of the world but the
intention is to make it available at
some point the it does include support
for the system fpga we we were able to
obviously build the code that's not
really challenging although sometimes it
is we you know there was some discussion
about how you can deal with in the lab
when you're developing on a system that
has a spy ROM your spiral emulators
those are great we've used those in this
particular solution we've gone a
different route we have a Raspberry Pi
that basically has the flash ROM from I
think the chromium project that we pull
that in and we can use that from the
command line to to read the ROM contents
and then flash their own contents
without having to go up and touch this
thing so we can stick the Raspberry Pi
on the server and throw it in a rack and
walk away and SSH into the Raspberry Pi
and have our way with the spy ROM
without having to do anything physical
with the server so this allows us to
recover and and analyze in the case we
we corrupt our spy ROM which we did
quite a bit going from four megabyte ROM
to 32 megabyte we had some issues with
three by four byte translation let's see
so we've got you know ipmi up and
running so this is kind of a testament
to the stability of open BMC in general
right so you build it you put it on your
chip it comes up and you get IPMI right
there's not a lot more you have to do in
order to get the core ipmi function so
that was working and then some basic
sensors came up automatically a couple
of three voltage sensors and six fan
sensors there nothing nothing behind
them
right so our goal was to implement all
these sensors for all the devices right
but we we didn't get that done but not
to leave you hanging we do have some
these are things that we were intending
to do so we're gonna share that with you
now because I think this speaks to a
story that's often overlooked in
performance and so our perspective here
was that this is going to be a
performance sort of survey of the Cape
when we look at our when we go to our
customers a lot of our customers ask us
how fast the BMC Boots right what sits
on an AC cycle Holland's it take before
IPMI responds how long before the web
responds and redfish etc warm resets and
first boot scenarios after an AC flat
sorry after a farmer update these are
all different scenarios across which
these times matter to customers and so
we wanted to to profile open BMC in this
category and you can see we got some
numbers from the IPMI stack that was
running in the base image with the pilot
for support courses
where did I get the time to live
expected numbers right so that comes
from our history and what our customers
seem to be taller these are upper
thresholds of what of a lot of our
customers are tolerant of you go beyond
that defects have written code has to be
respond or you know it's it's not a good
day so those are pretty high numbers I'm
I think it would be interesting if we
had a set of criteria for within open
BMC to say these are our thresholds
right obviously can be configuration
dependent you put a high end server with
a lot of sensors can take a little
longer but what what should that be
should there be sort of a formula based
on how many dims what are the factors
involved
what should the upper limits be
similarly the things the same thing can
be said about service response times so
it's not just how long it took your ipmi
stack to come up but how responsive is
it to get a sensor a complete sensor
listing if that takes a minute and a
half that's not very good
if the round-trip time for an IPM I
command is beyond a certain amount of
time which at that time be that's not
good because you know a lot of our
customers when we analyze the IPMI
traffic there's quite a bit of ipmi
traffic there can be many thousands of
IPMI commands that are issued every
minute all right so these performance
numbers matter walking you know other
examples like walking the redfish tree
if you want to go and just pull the
whole schema pull all of the the urls
and redfish
that can take a while especially if
there's a lot of elements there like
logs and web login page this is
something that that we've we've profiled
on our side of things how long does it
take for the login page to show up how
long before you can actually type in
your username credentials and then how
long after you hit enter before the the
home page is loaded right so a lot of
those are a balance between just not
just BMC performance but network
performance which we can't really
control a lot of that there are some
variables we can control but the client
performance if you've written your
JavaScript poorly that can take a lot
longer right so and how you're
expressing your your web you know
widgets that can that can take a lot
longer these are things that it might be
important for the client side to profile
another thing that's very important is
flashing times and I should also say
flash sizes but mostly everything I'm
here I'm focused on here as a time wise
flash times so I you know three basic
metrics are the time to transfer the
image and the time to update the image
in an activation which is usually
deferred till later customers are okay
to go ahead and push the image down and
defer the activation until some other
time when there's a maintenance window
especially if it takes a long time to
transfer the image they want to be able
to do that while the server remains 100%
functional so these are the metrics that
were interested in gathering so we need
some sort of system to gather this you
could you could look external to the box
that's that's that should definitely be
done and it's probably the most obvious
thing to do is to write some sort of
automated test harness to go and every
time you release code to run through
these paces and find out where you sit
but what I'm going to suggest is that
part of keeping your performance hygiene
is is an internal system inside the BMC
it's not meant to replace an external
system but it can augment it it can give
you a better view of what happens when
you fail to meet your IPMI boot time
boot readiness time your IP my time to
live if you if you have a test case that
just tells you oh this release of code
it broke that 90 second budget
next okay so now you've got to go get
all this data from the BMC reproduce it
well you got to reproduce it or plug in
serial debug or do some sort of analysis
all right so the point of this proposal
here is that the BMC can sort of self
monitor and yeah so I'll just walk
through the example the idea is that we
use a hardware free running timer
initialized at in start-up early
assembly sorry early startup code in
assembly so we start one of the timers
we run it at about one tick a 10 ticks
per second so 100 milliseconds per tick
because for this kind of work you don't
you're looking at how long a service
takes to come up you don't necessarily
need a lot of granularity or fine
granularity we we don't have a real-time
clock at time zero we're an early
assembly code and maybe we want to
profile some of that early code so we're
gonna wait until we have the real-time
clock and then try to fix up all those
times after the fact so that it's nice
and human readable when you get one of
the the reports from this boot perf we
log all of these snapshot entries to
temp that's where we do it today I would
I would recommend logging it to a temp
file system there's some discussion I
know there's a telemetry workgroup and
you know this is something that we would
like to work with them to see you that
that this profiling data could be made
available through the telemetry system
as well so what is exactly boot perf
it's basically just an API using this
Hardware timer that's available
throughout all phases of the code early
assembly you boot see the kernel drivers
and user space you could link it to a C
program you could call it from a shell
script there's a boot perf binary as
well that you can run from a shell
script and I apologize it's a little
well it's bigger over here I guess but
yeah it's a little small just an example
of the entry of the API where it's going
to make use of a region and SRAM that's
available immediately and initialize it
and then load it with every time you
call it
Stickley it's going to snapshot the free
running timer it's to get in memory
alongside the code that uniquely
identifies the checkpoint that you've
added to your source all right so it's a
very simple call it's very low overhead
you're not passing a lot of data we do
pass two pieces of data we pass sort of
a type and a subtype and the the idea
behind that is we have components you
might have an IPM I stack you on a
profile you might have redfish stack so
in you know large firmware components
can have their own type identifier and
subtypes can be common codes like zero
for start-up maybe you can you could
pick a number like 255 for fully up and
running and then you can use any subtype
you want in between to profile whatever
of the startup code or throughout the
lifetime of that that that service
whatever metrics you want to publish you
could call this API with you know just
create a header file and define the
values yourself so here's an example of
the output after a boot of a system that
shows just a little debug here where it
shows the sink we use timer 5 in this
example timer 5 happened to have that
16-bit value and the real-time clock at
that time was equal to that and this
this was printed out after the real time
was synced so you see the date and time
on the right is all backwards notated
right reverse notated so you can look at
any any of the data and you know it's
it's a human readable time so it's
showing there that at 6 seconds the boot
started so in this particular case you
boot finished in 6 seconds that's where
we happen to profile it we said there's
no point in saying when you started you
know that that's zero but you can say
when the boot started and then we
validate our kernel and that's at eight
point three seconds and well that took
you know 1.1 seconds to complete anyway
you can fill this up any way you want
the the value here is as I said earlier
to be able to once you know something
has exceeded a number
you can go look at this data and get a
lot more granularity you wouldn't
necessarily test for each one of these
you might just test only for IP my
commands ready and if that blew up that
was really long then you look at this
and you can find out what other things
were long that led up to that right it
might not have been that last step that
took a long time okay so this is this is
a a way to get the data after the fact
there's another concept that you can
take from this and that's self reporting
where the BMC itself and developers can
at Build time specify what they think
these thresholds should be so if I p.m.
I ready should be up in 90 seconds or
maybe you want yours to be up in 15
seconds that's great you could you can
create a config file in this case I gave
you an example of JSON that says I want
this particular service to be available
in 300 seconds so the time to live it's
in the domain of that timer running at
one tick every North 10 ticks a second
so that had better appear by that amount
of time and if it didn't then I have an
action I could generate a log I could
mark it as a failure and what does that
mean basically you have the service
that's looking at these checkpoints and
looking against these times that are
specified in this JSON file and when
something breaks the budget it takes
these actions this allows the BMC to
self-report there would be an OEM ipmi
command that you can issue you could
expose this through a variety of
interfaces I just chose Oh am i PMI to
find out like imagine a test harness
that is doing flashing maybe they don't
really care so much about performance
but that's not the primary function for
their their tests but along the way they
want to know if the flashing if the if
they broke any budget for the time
constraints that were set this command
would just give them a simple indicator
that there was a failure
an additional payload data would would
tell them the breakdown of what failed
then they could pull this log and and
get more information so it's pretty
simple the other idea is that you can
have the B
see identify the scenario so the BMC
hardware is very capable of telling us
what the reset sources were whether it's
because power was lost or a user
initiate initiated a reset command if
our stacks robust enough we can tell
whether that was through redfish or IPMI
or there was a watchdog timer there all
sorts of scenarios that reset scan
occurred it could be because you were
just flashed and then you reset you know
it's noteworthy that the first boot
after a flash there's a lot more
maintenance to do on your way up so you
might have a different threshold for
that scenario so it's good to be able to
identify that in the firmware and then
compare it against that scenarios metric
for success okay well any questions on
the performance hygiene yeah actually
and one of our implementations of this
it's a very thin header file but but
yeah right you could implement it as a
library and you would have to have it in
every phase of boot right so our
implementation of this is it looks the
the pound include basically determines
whether it's being built for you boot or
that's being built for the kernel or
whether it's being built for user space
so it's the same source file yeah not
not publicly but yes we have that and
that's just getting to what we're
wanting to do yes that's the goal right
yeah that's true certainly by looking at
the experiment you you change the
outcome right but the idea here what we
found in the years and years that we've
released firmware is that it's easy to
not pay attention to these things and I
think it's worth paying a little bit of
price to to monitor them and yeah I I
think that the you're using a hardware
timer using a very simple API the code
path is very very small once
I should have mentioned once we move
into the kernel we have access to more
memory well in in early code the idea is
that you're not going to have that many
checkpoints so initially you're loading
you're logging them to SRAM but these
BMC's have limited SRAM so when you
transition to the kernel then region of
memory is allocated and it gets logged
there but it can be a region that's not
managed by the kernel right so it's not
necessarily memory alloc you can just be
a chunk of DRAM out there that is just
as fast well it's not just as fast as
SRAM but you get there's a couple more
i/o cycles but it's it's fast it's not
gonna you it'll be negligible the the
mod so that's the logging portion of it
the monitoring yeah that's gonna take
some time but again I think I think it's
probably worth it in order to have good
hygiene so you're you're aware of when
you break a budget I would expect the
overall flow to go something like you
you write a new piece of code and you
you check it into and you test with it
and you find that you've broken certain
things you go back and check make sure
that your code is well written there's
no bugs in it for example
but you realize now that there was some
inherent impact to power on time that
you just didn't you weren't aware of so
at least it brought you brought that to
your attention right so yeah so they so
this was just a one-off implementation
sort of in the general sense I think
that they could be strings they could be
defined by you know you could have your
own definition for them they're
associated with a string at some point
right so we can generate this log book
keep going the wrong way so we could
generate this log here for the
description the IPMI command you could
you could issue and it would return the
check points that exceeded their
threshold they wouldn't have the string
names for example I mean you could do it
in a way that it you can query the
strings that probably be more portable
right so you don't actually have to have
the source code
yeah you could have your own things and
this is this is something so if I were
to jump to the very end it's kind of a
call to action we we would like to
sponsor a workgroup on performance I
gene right so this is where we're
sharing with you some of our ideas
things that we've implemented one off
that I think the we could if we could
put into the open BMC and get some an
input from everybody on what it you know
how to make it a little bit more robust
that that's our goal right so obviously
changes welcome yes in our
implementation it didn't it does not but
you you could you could migrate to if
you know for example you're gonna shut
down you could move it over to long-term
storage you could have something that's
running in the background or you you
haven't a chance every time boot perf is
call to the API is called you could
implement something to copy it if it
gets to a certain size or under
different conditions sure sure
absolutely because of one failed
component which is kind of that's true
yeah and and and we've we've seen that
before
right so you could you could implement
some rate limiting yeah right you can
rotate the logs from temp to long-term
file storage compress along the way
right yeah that's a good that's a good
problem sir no we haven't
systemd analyze already has a profiling
tool built into system D that lets you
know when the kernel loads all the
application start times yeah when just
me execs it so it has a lot of the
functionality already perfect yeah so I
mean it the intent of this is to span
all boot stages right so it gets the
early assembly it gets the
you booed as well and it right so the
intent here was to be able to cover all
phases of the boot but and if you're not
using system D - of course but something
we found is that sometimes when you're
really analyzing performance problems
you know at a top level it can look like
wow this this program has launched at
time zero and then 55 seconds later it
came up and started responding to
requests what the hell happened those 55
seconds and boot cerf has come in handy
for us where you know we found that this
arrant condition caused us to go off
into a for loop over here that we sit
and spun for 35 seconds and that that
was what was causing us to to break our
performance budget so another benefit to
this is that you can get inside your
application and you can really profile
your application as ad as granular at
the level as you need you can use
compiler flags to increase the
granularity to decrease the granularity
for that that's another benefit here
that systemd analyze didn't provide to
us okay so go the next thing one of the
since your number of limitations has
been mentioned a few times here and we
did some poking around we've we ran into
the sensor number of limitation years
and years ago and this is sort of the
approach that we've taken so I wanted to
just share that with the community
obviously you have 8-bit value for
sensor number but there's the LUN number
and there's there's some really good
conversations that are out there on the
open BMC forums about this but I didn't
see where they landed on this particular
solution and instead what I see is
typical suggestions are OEM
implementations right where you have om
IP my commands and handlers to get the
sensor numbers so what we found is that
this works and this works with IBM i2
which is a pretty common utility that
customers use for managing their bmc's
whenever they're doing IPMI so because
they're limited to 255 well that's where
you have your limitation so in the sdrs
type 1 2 & 3 records there are the
there's a lung field and I've got a
pointer to it it's the second second
image on the right that lung field can
be used to associate that sensor with
different lines right now it means
pretty straightforward
we know that Lund 2 is reserved for
message messaging sorry the message
bridging the get and send event commands
this leaves you with since sensor 255 is
reserved you have about seven hundred
sixty eight sixty five sensors I did my
math right the there's a little snippet
of code over there on ipmi tool that
shows where it is basically pulling the
STR from the BMC and looking at that
lung record this is what it does today
and then it will go back to the BMC to
get the sensor reading and it will use
that lung to get that sensor reading so
you actually will implement the sensors
to get sensor data on a variety of lungs
as you've defined your sensors or spread
them out across the lung buckets but the
the ipmi tool will actually use that
lawn from the SGR record to do that
interrogation sensor reading it works
seamlessly so this gets us well beyond
the 255 sensor limit for our server I
think and Connor can help me out here
with the number I think we were around
392 sensors so now we have had some
customers that require us to stay within
one line maybe they have an older
version of of an IPM I like IPMI util
for example that does not play well with
lund numbers I'll just type EMI
utilities in play well with lots of
things but they're you know one
suggestion is if you're limited to IPMI
is to become get a little bit more
clever with
using the use of a data to an event data
three not necessarily suggesting you go
OEM with it
but them sensors for example we have 96
of them so you can group them right you
can you can have one sensor for a set of
them and then use the event data to or
you can use one sensor for all of them
and use the event data to carry the the
dim number of in data three and that's
standard ipmi specification so that
frees up a lot of things and if you want
more than that then maybe it's time to
move to redfish yeah so I wanted to
share that with the community what has
been your experience with using sensor
numbers above 255 anybody reach that
limit okay perfect perfect yeah there's
always that right yeah so this works
seamlessly I think there have been some
patches to ipmi tool a long time ago
that fix some bugs around this but yeah
it's been working for a long time okay
so another thing that we worked on in
getting you know open BMC going on the
pilot for was the enablement of QEMU for
the pilot for chip something we're
excited to do so we worked on that
in-house and Lenovo and this is that
same map with a few different colors on
it kind of giving you the status of
where we are we found this to be very
useful I I think maybe open BMC is used
primarily for getting the kernel up and
running people that don't necessarily
have a hardware available to them our
approach was to try to enable a little
bit more simulation of the system there
obvious down pitfalls to that you can
get really excited about some some some
simulation that's just not really gonna
work as well as you think but we wanted
to do more than just the kernel because
there's a lot of value there in running
your precompiled binaries just plopping
it right here and letting it rip and and
you can do some profiling here you can
do
a lot of good things with qmu so we
started with a pilot for model we got
the processor up and running and then we
started filling out some peripherals and
you can see the green is what we've done
the yellows sort of in progress in that
we've done a lot of it enough of it for
our internal stack to be able to boot
and what's planned is you know in blue
so we'd like to be able to fan it out
more and you see that some of the system
interfaces like kcs our plan so how do
we go about in the host OS obviously
we're not diving into running you feet
on on qme without at least maybe that's
not obvious but that's not where I would
think we'd go this is for simulating the
the BMC itself you can have all of the
the backend of these peripherals go out
to some socket server if you wish and
then you can simulate your system
however you want so some of the
limitations that we had on the things
that are in green for example are that
we the the pilot for uses the tulip
network controller we so instead of
spending the time standing that up which
is not supported in QEMU last the last I
looked you know we can use the e 1000
which is and that's just a matter of
using a different driver in the kernel
we did take the PWM attack and and route
it out to an API this is what I was
referring to earlier where you could go
to a socket server and then simulate
that with a dashboard if you want and
whether that's a graphical dashboard or
some automated test harness and I the
reason I put that as a limitation is
because I'm making the assumption that
the PWM signals and the tax attack
inputs are being used for like on a fan
which might not always be the case and
the ddr controller we didn't implement
all the registers there that's just
claiming i/o space enough to get us past
ddr in it so we're picking our battles
as to what we simulate which i think is
a sane way to move forward we're not
trying to read in
laid everything at the register level
you'll notice that one new block showed
up there that wasn't in the pilot for
block diagram and that's the system FPGA
which is obviously not part of the pilot
for so that is part of the this the qmu
project as well that we're doing when we
go into emulating the system so I'll
move that on so we have preliminary
support for this r9 50 in the SR 650 in
our QEMU code base and we have the FPGA
we communicate with FPGA over spy it's a
it's not a terribly complicated protocol
but it's it's fairly robust and and so
all of that we've we've actually got
modeled the FPGA itself and you can't
really see this because it's so small
but like I show the invocation for how
we kick off the QEMU on the sr 950 with
a pilot for using our xec code and then
on the bottom using open BMC and really
all we're doing there is changing the
system because we have to have a
different sized firearm and in the
building blocks of the BMC that we're
simulating but then also we we pass in
the fpga def pj image it's the raw
binary that we create for our fpga that
we send to the manufacturing to flash on
the chip
I'm not simulating the FPGA by looking
at the bin file right I'm looking inside
the bin file for a signature basically
and then and then the FPGA model and
qemu is behaving accordingly so ideally
if your model is thorough enough at a
behavioral level then you can change the
fpga image from version to version and
your model will follow your response
will follow yeah where are we with this
unopened EMC I said we got our our
internal firmware booting open BMC right
now is hanging in new boots so we're in
the middle of debugging that but you
know debugging in qmu is pretty
straightforward just a matter of time so
our plan is to get that out to in that
pilot for model in QEMU upstream
when we get the kinks worked out so we
have to we want to get open BMC booting
all the way up and I think we're close
on that because of all the other
peripherals that are actually running
and then we need a bit of a bit of
cleanup I think I talked a little bit
about some of the value of the qmu that
what I found while while working on that
port was right away we could see where
there were a lot of wasted i/o cycles in
our early startup code going out to
registers more times than needed and you
trace the code and find out why gosh
we're calling this routine way too many
times things you wouldn't notice if
you're just going for functional
correctness and you might not notice if
you're just measuring time right because
it's very fast to go through maybe spy
initialization every time you go to the
chip but you don't need to so it opens
up your eyes to things that are doing if
you start looking at things at the i/o
level at the register i/o interaction
level or the the bus interface level so
if you tap into the spy bus and you can
see the commands going back and forth on
queuing yeah that's pretty useful you do
snapshots with this so if you are
simulating your system and you have a
bug you could share that with other
people right and then they can help you
debug that problem they don't
necessarily need the hardware that's
assuming you can reproduce the problem
with the simulator but that's one of the
values of this another value and perhaps
the primary reason that we wanted to go
in here to get into qemu is resource
limitations so we've got 512 megabytes
of ddr4 solder down I'd love to run
valgrind on some of our applications in
the real real world obviously it's going
to slow down a lot but you need a lot
more memory to do that there are a lot
of memory profilers we've thrown at our
at our code right about if you want to
throw many of them had it you need a lot
more memory right so short of replacing
that BGA ddr4 chip with a bigger one if
you can get it running in qemu great and
it's not really that hard to
remember you have available to you in
qmu let's see so and then as I mentioned
earlier the lot of automation testing
can be done at a lower level but just
another caveat here to be careful what
your expectations are time domains and
simulations our problems your test
harness has to be aware of a lot of
those things so I think you just have
the the word of caution is to just be
mindful of what your gonna simulate and
what the value of it is and before you
spend too much time trying to write a
model for something with hopes you're
gonna get a lot of benefit out of it
just think about a lot of that stuff up
front that's pretty vague but we're not
trying to do everything with this mall
so what we'd like to do next is you know
having said all of this stuff and shared
with you what we've done so far you know
enabling the pilot for on a variety of
platforms right so in open BMC and QEMU
is we'd like to you know being new to
open BMC so I will try to sponsor well
not try to but sponsor or begin a
workgroup for the performance monitoring
sounds like there might be some
interesting comments so we can we can
work on here the as I mentioned earlier
being able to make use of the telemetry
for making this data available that's a
if it's just a file that you can pull
off externally and you don't necessarily
need the OEM IPMI command that's great
so we look forward to kind of partnering
with the telemetry guys on that the
multiline sensor support so enabling
that in open BMC would be a good thing
to have right so how many people are
doing that sort of lund solution today
in open BMC so we didn't see where where
you created the sensor that you could
actually specify the LUN its associated
with yeah yeah so we'd like to work on
trying to upstream something that the
community could benefit from
yeah perfect
Oh time oh-oh-oh-oh at the boundary of
this sensor limit yeah perfect okay yeah
okay thanks we talked I've done lots of
work on the a speed I'm a model upstream
and I do lots of kind of work for open
BMC in general and I used to come here a
lot it's it's great we write lots of
models for stuff that we don't have
silicon for we've bought the 2600 up in
comeyou before we had hardware and stuff
like that so yeah thanks for talking
about comeyou and how good it is just a
few comments you the ethernet driver i
model you're trying to do this PC ayah
so if you BMC doesn't have PCI you'll
have trouble okay come talk to me assets
I've got some ideas for you sure and
simply with you about hanging are using
upstream we're using the open BMC fork
we're using the the a speed off the a
speed repo that supports file for
because that's not upstream yet okay
cool Abbadon Singh which code base that
is yeah so that's I think off of what
Sud four one nine sorry I'm talking
about the KU mu brunch
well the Q mu branch oh yeah so I don't
remember the version number I should
have put that in the charts that's cool
I pulled it a while ago we updated who I
don't want to guess I can yeah
I see the FBI speak I'm a model that's
upstream is it's become pretty high
quality and the a the Kimmy maintainer
points to our model when he's telling
other people had a build a machine which
is good but it's also really annoying
when I'm trying to work out what to do
because there's no reference so yeah
that was one of the things we learned
with it was qemu is if you look there's
a variety of API is that I I suppose has
evolved over time and there's a lot of
machine implementations that use one or
the other of the the calls to
instantiate other components and so we
patterned it after the HP 2500
and which we found to be one of the more
mature
one's yeah spend a bit of time on that
it's very useful so the open BMC CI runs
against ku mu model for every clip that
goes in which is great when it passes
and it's really frustrating when someone
makes the kernel change that doesn't
support it but it's something we're
working through so thank you
great thank you well if the point is to
say that you can use an FPGA for
something like that right so your
implementation would be specific to you
all right
mostly what I'm trying to say in
introducing the FPGA at all is that it
was a bit of effort in order to get it
going with open BMC but that for
high-end systems like this
there's plenty of opportunity to offload
from the BMC onto something right so I
don't know I maybe one could predict
that FPGA czar may be more likely to
appear in the common building block
hardware that is a BMC that goes down
onto a server with that many iOS for the
RDS for example you need something right
faster than code in our particular case
that's what we do we go and we go talk
to the FPGA to get dem SPD and we pull
that it's very it's much faster yeah and
and where has the benefit of us not
being on the i2c bus playing playing
poorly with the CPU alright to see or at
some bus controller there's some
advantages okay thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]