[Music]
we're continuing Julius hi I want to
talk about verification in coreboot and
it's only letting talk so that's jump
straight in this is how verification in
coreboot works today and it's
essentially all based on having hardware
web protection on your spy flash so we
sort of separate the spy flash into two
regions there's a read-only region which
is permanently right protected and then
there's the rest where you can put
updatable firmware and in this read-only
region we have the core boot boot block
so there's there's where execution
begins we have a CB FS with a bunch of
other stages in it and a root key which
can be used to verify the read white
version and stuff like that
and so if if you run this essentially
execution will start in the we the only
part in the boot block and then jump to
the worst stage which is still in
read-only and then the worst stage is
the code that verifies the we'd white
section by checking the signature which
is in the weed white part and verifying
it with that root key which is in the
video only version and then using the
hash from that signature check to
validate this weed white CB FS which is
a whole CB FS with all the other stages
that you need to boot but our current
system doesn't interpret this as a CB FS
so it was essentially treats it like a
blob and the whole thing is read at once
and hashed and one go and then you
continue booting from there so you only
verify as a one shot verification at
this moment essentially and we
implicitly trust that everything in the
video only version is is trusted so
there's no verification going on for
those parts and this is some surface
pretty well for awhile but there are
some issues with it for example one of
the problems is that we essentially end
up reading all these we double the
read/write bits twice because we read
them once when we verify them at the
start but this is before D um is up so
at that point we can't really save them
we just hash them all and throw them
away again
and then when we actually run those
stages we got to read them again
so we are wasting time reading the same
bits times five twice essentially and we
also have a thing called a time of check
brothers time of useful and ability
which means that if you would open up
the Machine and for example disorder the
spy flash and replace it with an EMR 100
you could feed it back different bytes
depending on which stage of execution
you're and even if it's reading the same
piece on flash so for example while it's
very like while the worst stage is
running and verifying all of this you
could feed it back the correct parts and
verification would succeed but then
afterwards when you're actually loading
the warm stage you could feed it back
different bites and inject malicious
code so this isn't really a problem if
you just rely on spy right protection
because in that case if you open the
case and took up a dirty prague you
can't beat it anyway but if for example
you wanted to extend this to into the
boot guard or a similar SOC vendor
verification mechanism then that could
be a problem that you might want to
defend against and you also have the
other problem with those vendor
verification mechanisms that the the
root of trust over there's essentially
this whole block so you would need boot
card to verify the whole we'd only
section which may be very baker
sometimes we have recovery code in there
and you can't really verify all the
individual parts that you need to boot
because you need that boot block you
need the verse stage you need that key
and you need a bunch of metadata that
spread around the flash and not really
in one compact area that you can just
cover with boot guard so we would like
to get a better system for this and it
would be great if we could somehow put
the verification logic into cbofs so
that every fire is actually verified by
the time i use it and not all in one
shot and the system we would like to
implement for this somehow looks like
this so let's start with a quick
refresher of how CB FS looks it's a
really simple file system it's
essentially just you put all the files
one after the other and every file has a
small header which tells you the name
and how long it is and a couple of that
fields and if you look at the file and
cbos what you do is you always start at
the first file you compare the file name
see if that's what you're looking for if
it's not you look at the length to see
where the file ends and
the next arrow starts and then you look
at that header and you check the name
and if it's not what you're looking for
you go to the next one and so on and we
could put a hash in those headers to
hash individual files we actually we
already have sort of that code in
cordwood right now it's not really used
but the problem with that is that's not
enough to ensure verification because
even so essentially you you gotta make
sure that the header you find is
actually the one you were looking for
and since it does this linked list
lookup through all the files until it
finds the one you're looking for
you got to make sure that all those
headers you go through before that are
also secure you can just secure a single
file by itself and the way we propose to
solve this is to have a master hash for
the whole cbofs which is essentially a
hash of all the headers concatenated
together so the headers aren't actually
concatenated on the flesh the flesh
layout stays the same as it is right now
in the middle but for hashing purposes
you virtually pretend as if all the
headers were just concatenated and then
you calculate a hash over the whole
thing and with that system you can do a
secure file lookup essentially the same
way as before so you start with the
first file you check if that's the file
name you're looking for but at the same
time you also throw that header into
your shower function and then if it's
not the file you're looking for you're
going to the next header
you're comparing that file name but you
also throw that header into the shower
function and you keep walking the cbofs
chain until you find the file you're
looking for but then you can't stop yet
you got to save that header away for
later and then you still got to keep
going until you go through all the files
and keep throwing all those headers into
the shaft function so that in the end
you can compare this the hash that you
got there with this master hash but you
got to put in your hood of trust and at
that point you know that all the headers
you just scanned were valid and then you
can go back to the header that use safe
to side and use the file hash from in
there to very verify the data of the
file you're trying to load and in that
case you would have to verify it while
you're using it so if it's a stage for
example you copy it into memory then you
verify it and then you decompress it and
then you start running it and that way
you can get around this time of check
rails down view things so let's see how
that would look in practice
they're still mostly looks the way it
did before but now we have this master
hash and we would embed it into the boot
block program code and that means that
we can use boot guard or any other
verification mechanism even if it can
only cover a single contiguous area we
just need to cover the boot block with
that and from then on we can chain into
our own verification system and when the
boot block loads the verse stage it
would use that master hash to first
verify all the headers in the read-only
CB FS and then use the header of the
rest stage to verify the first stage
file and for the are W side it sort of
looks the same except that the master
hash is now the hash that is verified
that is signed by V boot so if we are
booting we still go from the boot plug
into the verse stage and then the verse
stage will do all the signature checks
like it did before with the root key and
you can also change the root key into
that we only see BFS to get your
verification chain there and but then
after that signature check we do not
load and hash the whole WCB if I said
once we just keep that hash in memory
and that will be our master hash for
every a WC b FS final look up later on
so then once the worst stage jumps into
the warm stage over here it would again
like check out all the headers and erwc
v FS and hashem and then use the warm
stage file hash from those headers to
validate them on stage and those master
hashes essentially you would have to
keep him in memory between stages so
that every stage has it available to
hash the next one and with this we can
both solve the time of check for the
time of use problems except for some
platform issues I get to in a minute and
we also solve that problem that we're
loading everything twice because now we
are really only loading it when we use
it and hash it at that time so this is
mostly the proposal we have it has a few
detail issues the most important one is
it works great for arm it has a couple
of problems on Intel occurs in x86
rather because those are executing early
stages in place and execute in place is
a problem and you want to protect
against time of check rails time of use
because the
Spyke controller memory maps your code
and when you're essentially executing an
instruction this PI controller I will
fetch it and use it at the same time you
don't really have a spot in between
where you can get in there and hash
something so this is not really a
problem you can solve I think you can
try to argue about the the behavior of
the caches because the spy controller
usually loads it into a cache and then
if you fetch it again it should fetch it
from the cache but that depends on the
cache behavior depends on the exact
cache lines and architecture and the
information to guarantee that you could
make this work isn't really freely
available I think so I think that is
sort of a problem into the has to solve
we sort of talked to some of the
engineers about this and they didn't
have a good solution yet either so this
is an open question on the Adams side of
Sunday Adam CPUs we actually already
don't execute in place anymore instead
we load stages into caches Ram areas and
then execute them explicitly from there
so in that case that solves the problem
and on those CPUs we should be able to
support this on the core line for some
reason they do not support that yet and
I'm not sure why I hope they start
supporting that in the future because
then this will work but for now you may
not be able to get full time of check
runs and some of use protection on those
systems if we look at performance issues
this should mostly come out either as
wash or sort of ahead of what we have
right now because you're saving all that
time from not loading everything twice
but you have a little bit of extra time
from doing those cbofs walks because now
you have to always walk through the
whole cbofs and you can stop at the file
that you're looking for so amortize that
would be a factor of two of extra bytes
you need to read from spy flash every
time you look something up you also need
to hash something but in general the
hashing times should so those by reading
times should dominate hashing times so
that's probably not a big problem and we
could further solve these issues by
caching the cbofs metadata once we read
it so on most platforms we probably have
enough cash as RAM or SOA I'm available
to cache those and then we can further
this
that up so yeah that's pretty much the
idea we have right now and it's
unfortunately only an idea right now
because we don't really have anyone
lined up to implement it yet but yeah so
essentially this this whole idea came up
from Inter trying to implement something
that would support boot guard and
coreboot but it didn't solve all of
these issues so we were trying to first
come up with a joint proposal that would
really solve all the issues and then now
we need to find someone to implement it
essentially but maybe we'll get to that
next year sometime that's all I have
anyone have any questions back one slide
so you could put the I mean at the
moment you're going and reading all of
the bits from the RO CPF all cbofs all
the headers if you put all that in the
boot block then it'll be in one place
and it would already be hashed and you
could just use that so you want to pull
all the CVS metadata into the sort of
sin that was maybe you later slide but
yeah so you could do something like that
and then you wouldn't have to chase down
all that data right so like one of the
main goals here is to stay compatible
with the old CB FS system so if we do
this you can just disable the hashing
and see BFS will look the same as it
does today and you can enable the
hashing and then it has an extra
attribute but otherwise it's the same
see BFS so all others see BFS readers
don't have to be updated you could of
course invent a whole new file system
which doesn't have these issues that CBF
SS but we think with the sort of
penetration that coreboot has like
sticking to the thing we already have
that's already supported everywhere it's
a big win so that's why we're doing this
so why do I need to hush all headers and
then verify to read them all why not do
like a blockchain thing so like each
next header depends on the previous one
so you would want each header to have a
hash of the next
some of the previous like each other
including hush which depends on previous
headers hashes on the previous headers
contends or like there is no field in
the header for harsh or something well I
mean you'd have to clarify the details
but I think that would just be less
efficient in the end because right now
even if we have to go through all the
headers on every walk by every edge you
have to go through half of them right if
you just look up a random file it might
be at the end it might be at the end
beginning so an average you go through
half of them anyway and if you had a
hash for the next header in every header
then first of all you would have to
calculate all those hashes where you
walk so you're spending extra time on
that and second of all hashes are not
that small
so the headers themselves right now are
probably like I think 40 bytes or
something and sha-256 is 32 by it so
we're already almost doubling the size
of the header with this and if we add
yet another hash so and that's for the
hashes for the files only so if we add
yet another hash to every header that's
just for the previous header then we are
blowing them up even more and then
you've got to read all those extra bytes
every time you walk so I think in the
end you would come out yeah you can
combine information when you hush you
can combine file contents and the
previous header so you would still have
just one hash and if you do this
blockchain thing even if files in the
end of the of this chain I destroyed at
least the files before then you can know
that they're good if you harsh all
headers together and something is
corrupted somewhere you everything is
lost yes I do I mean we don't currently
see any use cases where that corruption
would be a problem but that's true I
guess we could think about other ways to
do that more efficiently so it's
interesting for systems with boot guard
would people still be able to tinker
around with their biases if it's enabled
but that's of course the way everyone
hates boot code and me too the problem
is some people want to
Kovu this way and they're going to end
up implementing something so we want to
make sure they implement something that
works for everyone in the end it always
depends on what you do with boot-cut how
we can use it normally of course if you
so this is only a hashing chain there is
no signatures involved so if boot guard
protects the boot blogs and everything
and the cbofs cannot be modified anymore
so in that case if you don't open
developer your scoot but yeah that's
sort of an issue that the platform
developer has to solve right for example
they could release the keys to their
boot guard to the owner and then you
could private design something as well
that's sort of out of scope we're just
trying to make something that's secure
and then how you use it depends on who
uses it okay for one yeah this one I see
you have problem with the catch a string
right yeah I've only if you use the tff
sthiti for cash as well in need or use
copper version I don't think it makes a
difference for this but I think I know
the neurochip score would use because I
suffer as npnp previous hair we found if
we use FF CT and you give it a try
Michael Cole before we launch ffs DT to
get temporary memory in it but the 10
years I've previously I was using hope
wood with I don't need to you can just
avoid FF sthiti sure but you still have
caches right yes the fundamental issue
yeah the thing is the intel has the
arabs TT i wanted if we had can help we
we found Intel Fox here then we should
we get Intel Fox I can the open source
ffs DT because this is about tempo
memory in it not like for Cicilline then
we can leverage it both ways because for
Intel FFT is in needed last level cache
to be the problem in memory then for
corporate version is to in need that
cash Australian and just fresh I mean a
network as read-only last level cache
your copper has a lot of cash but it it
doesn't
previously okay yeah I mean yes overlap
those close to infinity overlap to cater
okay so I think this is to be honest I'm
not super familiar with the platform
details because I mostly work on armed
systems but as I understand this is sort
of a hardware issue so it doesn't really
use a finished beauty or I wonder if we
can have some voice on FX or to open
source FS TT yeah because that one is is
overlap so it's not that worthy we spent
much the boy from yeah on that sure but
I don't think it would have put this
problem because it's a hardware mystery
yeah it's how ways you so it seems to me
like you really need the boot guard to
verify your master hash or someone can
just replace the contents and update the
hash right like a second thing is does
this protect against buy-busts attacks
it seems like it does not you're
verifying the hash of files as they're
loaded so first of all so the idea is to
put the master hash in the boot block so
when boot boot guard covers the boot
block the master hash would be in there
and so the master has should also be
covered by we've got if you're fetching
things over the spy bus as you're
executing code then someone could just
use us by bus attack and replace the
data that you're getting right right so
this is sort of I think you're sort of
getting at this execute and case problem
so first of all if you don't execute in
place for example if you have an arm
system which always loads code into som
then this should be safe cuz so the
first part that you're executing the
boot block would be verified by the SOC
master form and then when the boot block
loads the next case stage it will verify
it after loading so even if you have a
spy bus attack and if you inject
malicious data at any point the
verification should catch that if you're
running on an inter system with execute
in place then you're running into
exactly this issue that there's not
really a way to secure execute and play
systems against this unless you try to
reason about oh we like caching with
boot garden loads did here because you
know time is running up so I'll just say
boot guard is not supposed to be
susceptible to spy bus attacks but we
can talk offline but it
is on caching behavior that's not well
documented so that's but we can talk
later all right thank you very much
[Applause]
[Music]