[Music]
so passing config data from the firmware
to the operating system for example
training data for memory as on Intel
platforms is currently only possible for
through proprietary components so
opening an app would make the
development on many many platforms way
easier so that's actually been done or
at least in the works and so next two
speakers are going to introduce you to
that concept so please give a warm round
of applause to Zarate and
good afternoon
I know it's lunchtime I will try to make
it quick so that we can get to lunch
quicker anyway so this is the same talk
we gave in both CP in San Jose so we
have a little bit more information so
that's why I brought I mean sorry they
actually came with me to present this
additional data what we have okay so
let's start of course so everybody knows
I mean we are here because we know the
advantages of open standards and open
source right like I mean he introduced
us so basically there are we have some
standard I mean many standards now but
there are some gaps we find particularly
in terms of like training data memory
training data how we get it so this is
mainly about that and how we can close
that gap and going forward let's see
okay so we have some I mean standard on
DMT F like sm bias red red fish and we
have a CPI tables and there are so many
different tables related to memory and
all the different things and we also
have jtech specifications on DMS PD data
so these are all standards we have
already
and there is a gap like I mentioned
particularly the DRAM demon training
data so we know that in the reference
code actually there's most of the
training and that training data is
usually passed to the next layer and
it's up to many times we have to just
look at the bias or the firmware logs to
figure out what is the training data we
get right so that's okay if you are
doing like once in a while like let's
say bring up and things but if we are
looking at a large-scale deployment and
monitoring different things then that's
not that's not scalable basically right
so basic proposal is a mean proportional
is basically to get a a CPI table and
make it more flexible so that right now
we are in the ddr4 and then let's say we
ddr5 and also like different training
data not only like memory right the bias
actually does a lot of things in the
earlier installation stage so we want to
get this out so that it can be
expandable to different data set so
that's the main point we are trying to
make here okay again so what what is the
usage case so one is the dim repair
workflow and another way I mean like I
said to get a holistic view of data
center operations probably I will we go
through the next explanation about what
we miss and what we have then I can
explain you more detail on what what
flow cases I want to talk about and that
sorry we talk about the next things
thank you ever so basically uh as he
mentioned right there's a lot of dim
specific training data that needs to be
exposed to the operating system entities
so they can make decisions based on the
margining whether atom is close to the
margin or whether it just no healthy and
things like that so there are a bunch of
information that needs to get passed but
apart from that is also a speedy
information that needs to get passed so
the voice entities can go and directly
read this PD data from the Dems but the
problem with that one is we have
something called closed-loop thermal
throttling so the memory controller
keeps polling for the using the SM bus
to go read the you know key salt or the
temperature sensor and I to the
throttling so that bus has taken over in
runtime so when BMC or worse entities
want to go and talk to it and he did
read the SP information it's not
possible right so a better way for it
for this data to get exposed is by
surfacing this by in by a standard
mechanism so it has of course as the SPD
is yet expanded right we all know how
they all look like but they keep
evolving for different technologies as
well so even you know if you look at you
know when the memory controller comes up
and it trains memory for different
configurations different memory vendors
daemon vendors so these things will
change right based on platform you can
do it for one platform and scale for
multiple platforms its platform specific
data so and then basically MRC goes
through the whole thing it will train it
will find healthy items it does post
package repair it can go and disable
some channels if it needs to or offline
some number if it needs to and then it
will
get a hand off block and it passes it on
to the next stage of form we're right
and basically this hob is then used to
build your ACPI tables you are some bias
tables and things like that and no we
have generic things like an OS fact
table a slightly table for numa
descriptions we have HVAC table
heterogeneous memory attributes table we
have n feet table things like that this
all describes the memory topology of the
system but they don't describe the
memory timing parameters right so what
we have is we do have a table called a
beaded table it's called a bias data
area HB a table right and that table is
basically today is in a proprietary form
so now you know the the firmware
basically builds a CPI table the
assemble our stables things like that
but the BMC has to go and read from the
DIMM modules or directly read from the
memory controller which as I said before
it's not possible with CLT T so although
voices or drivers can it's also go talk
to memory controller or SPD modules
directly so today what we have here is
the William specific structures in here
the best HCP table both these are
proprietary so what I mean by the
volumes specific structures are this the
ECPA table itself is going to carry some
rod data right because this data moves
with technology it evolves his
technology it changes from vendor to
vendor from silicon to silicon so
instead of changing SP expect every time
there is a change in the technology we
are providing a rod data in a CPI table
the solid we give right and the raw data
to make sense out of the raw data we
provide schemas which are public domain
so that will be a grid that matches the
the schema - there are data so you can
make sense out of it so that's the basic
idea here so when you see here the
volumes specific structures that's
pretty much the schema that describes
the ACPI
mirror structure and this is also I
think this diagram points there's some
bias truck just not the schemas so the
goal here is to not you know make it
proprietary make it open so we are
working on the AC PCR to create a bead
at table in a CPI and we're also working
to basically push through yeah opening
up the schemas so it's already approved
so we're going to publicly put the spec
out in public and have some schemas out
there to tie into the a CPI spec you
want to take off from here so this is
the one I
I mean talking about like what is the
usage class right so sorry talked about
I mean the training data what how it can
be useful in the bigger sense so like
for example let's say I know that some
of the what do you call it
I know certain systems are like not in
within the margin or it's going to fail
at least I can make a decision from the
view in a bigger view that not to
schedule a job or maybe try to have a
certain job scheduling a certain things
right so that's what we want to do in a
bigger view so one of the example is
like so we can build a system somewhere
and then we can ship it to a let's say a
data center or somewhere right and when
we power on so sometimes we want to make
sure that the data when we built a
system whatever the RMT data we get
which is direct margining tool data is
as similar or same as the one right if
not then there is something not either
it's not inserted properly but something
else is happening and I know it will be
if in the worst case the dim will beam
will not show up in the memory at all I
mean in the
Tector at all are disabled by the
training data so that's easier case but
if their margin is a little bit less I
want to catch it before even I run
anything on it so that's the main
approach I mean we want to see so that's
why and we need the training in addition
to the SPD and other information right
so this all like just general what we
have right now in the SMS structures and
why there is some gaps right so like
sorry they explained it so we have
explained I mean what me what do you
call it it's a so policy of the memory
and the types and everything but we
don't have exactly the error type and
other information not error exactly but
more like a margining data right so
again in smbus most of the time if the
DM is disabled you won't get any
structure filled in most of the time and
so that means that I don't know that
there is there supposed to be a team
which is disabled so that's one thing we
here we can find out and or else so
general information about SM bias and
sorry talked about s rat and asleep
tables sorry I'm just rushing through
because I prefer people ask questions
and we answer that's much more better
than reading the slides are I telling
you something okay and most of you I
mean you know it's all in the spec
that's what I mean and so let's give a
little bit more on the B dot structure
right so B dot structure I like the
structure so I find it's mostly disabled
in the bias and it still needs some work
which we are working through but the
main idea is so it provided a header in
a a CPI and give you a pointer to
somewhere in 64-bit memory where there
is a raw data and the draw data contains
schemas multiple schemas and the schema
again it has a standard header which
sigrid and from the grading you know
what's the data behind it right so that
I find is much more flexible so in that
sense like right now we have already the
beaded have multiple versions of data
and going forward I like to propose in
the open standard which may saw thee and
me
well I mean working through so we want
to publish some standard schemas first
okay and in an open forum and then get
that approved and going I mean then we
can add multiple schemas over it so
basically start with simple SPD data
simple timing data and then we can
expend mode because right now the data
is very complicated like it's literally
packed all the data into one big schema
which is more
I mean much harder to pass okay and so
that's the B dot so like so we have this
what we are proposing basically so sorry
this already working through to publish
the beta table in the open public forum
and already there is a easier in flux to
add the bead head table and then we are
working through getting the right
schemas define and publish it in the
future of open forums and this will
actually basically what I I mean my like
bigger goal is to have the support in
the kernels in various kernels built
into it so that we can have access this
data by sisyphus nodes or other
mechanism so that it's easier for higher
stack to use the data okay
it's so basic thing is like we just want
the community to help and then we work
together to have all these things
properly set up and what add anything
yeah so basically this is right now yeah
you know appropriately table right so
when open by opening it up it scales
across multiple vendors and multiple
technologies so not just memory but if
we you know I can come up with things
that voice entity might need to know
about the platform which is not today
present in any form by a CPA or has some
bios or whatever then we can add schemas
to it and make it more flexible so you
know if you guys can think of any such
messages you know maybe there are lot of
training that the bias does not just
memory right the interconnects between
CPUs that are strange and things like
that see if you guys you know feel like
that is something that we need to bring
in
then this makes a lot more makes more
flexible to add those things later on so
that's pretty much and when Shiva said
initially that he'll make it fast
because I go for go for lunch he really
meant it lunchtime you see 11th it yeah
we are open for questions
thank you that's having a round of
applause big round of applause
open standards are so important so we
have infinite time for questions
basically between your lunch and your
talk we're going to be holding that so
quitting right like the Guido structure
is like when you talked about those like
do you anticipate one for ddr3 or 4805
is it now you panned out those I mean
how are is it memory vendor-specific
can be good at it too so our I mean in
the open thing we want to be standard
specific I mean like ddr3 ddr4 but if
it's anything proprietary that can also
be accommodated okay so that's why the
scheme approach right so I want to have
something similar I mean like common
things so you know that if there is
something I mean in this structure you
have at least ddr4 timing data yeah and
then if anything else it's up to the
particular driver and the proprietary
things on the scheme yeah yeah then the
other thing is like MRC today like if
the system is not rebooted in 90 days or
something Vico reestablish the
parameters I mean there are certain
mechanisms in place in the MRC the way
it is implemented in server right so the
one thing that you talked about exposing
the data to the operating system but the
other one is out-of-band telemetry how
do you push this data toward herb and
damage how do you anticipate that to
take place big the one thing that you
alluded to was you will prevent you know
putting VMs or containers is done if the
if the life is wearing out of a team or
something right for you to take such a
decision it has to be done not inside
the node but it has to be somehow pushed
outside the node but if the limits node
itself is faulty how do you anticipate
those
the data to be basically telemetry what
is the telemetry story that is
surrounding the training that you kind
of established oh yeah
so it's true but the one I was more
interested in is like so there's two
different thing right one is runtime
related data so that you can get from
other mechanism like PI key or other
things but the training related data
that I know it's not every server is
rebooting multiple times but when it's
reboot whatever data we collect we like
export it so the right now it's
available in sisyphus there will be a
driver above it which exposed to the
higher layer and there will be outside
monitoring things which captures that so
it knows what's the difference between
the two different values and also it
knows that other service in the same
vicinity other things have a different
are empty so then it will can make a
decision that okay something wrong in
this particular system so probably I do
I need to look at that one so that's
what I mean yeah it was basically a
static way of collecting data it's not a
one-time telemetry per se it's
information that the bias produces
during boot yeah yeah I know it does
okay so what you're saying is just prior
to the voice out during the handoff you
still send the data across or the wire
or something yeah and and then only
after that you start I mean allocating
VM surveys and whatever X or step okay
that's basically you're beating out any
outliers that may be there yeah but do
you have a point about the BMC yes all
right so any out-of-band entities that
want to use this data yes yes maybe we
can enhance the driver to talk IPMI to a
red fish to the BMC I believe that there
is a story that needs to be filled is
right it's like multiple subscribers not
just OS is the only subscriber to this
data that you're publishing they gotta
be an outer band listener to the same
habitat you know that's something that I
feel is also need to be complimented so
the last line oh yeah okay I see that
okay I should have a simple question
easier now you have dim
formation right that the bus is no it
may not be hundred percent Jared right
yeah yep and so how you dealing with the
situation if you use Intel mashing and
amassing or arm server yes that's what
the skimmer comes in come play so so you
can have a common scheme on which
actually address that it's not a
technology specific it's more like I
mean it's a media for technology
specific not the platform specifically
simple question as well you need the
actual data or do you need the
intelligence out of the data so if bias
tells you the margin on this dam is not
good is that enough or would you rather
how the actual later and make the
decision yourselves this is only the
data so I want a higher layer to handle
the actual intelligence so I think the
question was if you can do a percentage
of margin instead of the actual data
will it make it more sense it depends
but in this case actually it doesn't
matter so as long as I can take some
value like what do you say comparison to
different thing right I know there is
the difference which I can clearly say
there is something is not right then
it's good we actually had a use case
where we did something but the bias
determines if the margin was good
warning or critical and then we'll pass
that information to the voice it will
trigger a memory retraining if required
accounting for thermal variations are
sure sure so I think you have a point
though that because if you're going to
have any information that the vendor
doesn't want to public right could be it
could be very like a no trade secret
kind of thing right so basically they
would they might want to not publish the
data right and insert can give you a
percentage so things like that just fine
action so the main aim is to find that I
can find that particular thing is bad so
it doesn't matter follow-up to that
question
seems like if you get enough of this
data standardized and exposed to the OS
then we can reduce the number of system
management interrupts and maybe obviate
the need for protected runtime mechanism
sort of talking about the intelligence
not necessary it could be in an
operating system driver that's later
does that's really different I think
yes that was a more static thing than a
ton time thing one question about these
mclees and you're trying to standardize
their interface to pass information
right so country they also has a SM
bounce table there and now it's a CDI
table to do the same thing so how do you
propose which information we should pass
for the SM bounce interface was the ACPI
interface what's going to be the trend
going forward for that actually there is
no is some bias related thing for
exactly this part oh yeah but but what
I'm saying that as a mouse it's kind of
interface where gamma you can pass
information from your firmware to a
store memory so that's also a path but
the higher if you've got a data how do
you determine which side you want to do
agree but the SMS one problem is the
structure has to be like 255 bytes okay
so that's a very big limit actually so
that's another why I like this one so
you can expand much more I mean more
data so basically I said yeah I could be
the new yeah in the face right okay and
also we can have pointers to some pass
structures right so basically you know
which get are basically maps to which
physical okay just like an fit like I
said we have at least an infinite amount
of time for questions okay now only few
to go to lunch please have a warm-up
round of applause
and you guys play work
[Applause]
[Music]