welcome to the presentation on the work
titled 2 to the n over 2 time algorithm
for square root n approx shortest vector
problem and hermit shortest vector
problem
this is trying to work with diverse
aggro world and noah stevens david do it
so first of all let's look at some
basics
what is a lattice
a lattice is a discrete sub group
so here i have a two dimensional letters
and it's specified by a set of linearly
independent basis vectors
the last the lattice is then generated
by all integer combinations of these
basis vectors
why do we study lattice
lattice has been used for cryptography
since the seminal work of eye tight in
and it has a bunch of
advantages
so there is this worst case to average
case reduction therefore the security of
latin space cryptography
relies on the worst case hardness of
some lattice problem
it is believed to be resistant to
quantum computers
and it can do more for example it can do
homo fully homomorphic inclusion
next let's look at the
lattice problems that is the focus of
this work
so we start with the shortest vector
problem svp
it looks for a shortest non-zero vector
of a given lattice
so for example in the two dimensional
letters here
the red vector v
is a shortest vector
and we use lambda 1 to denote its length
and for an approx version
gamma svp
it looks for a short lattice vector
that is of length within gamma times
lambda 1 and it's a nonzero vector
so for example if we take gamma to be
equals to 2
then any lattice vector within the green
ball here
is a valid solution
to the 2 scp problem
the shortest vector problem is a half
problem
so just to give a simple illustration
for example if
the only information that is given
is two basis vectors b1 and b2
and this set of bases is not a very nice
set of bases
it's not straightforward to see where
the
shortest vector v would lie
and more concretely there has been a lot
of studies on the harness
or the complexity of gamma svp across
different approximation factors
and
when approximation factor is around poly
n
is most relevant to cryptography
the next problem that we'll be looking
at is the hermit shortest vector problem
hsvp
so for each of the letters it has a
determinant
and
basically the determinant of a
lattice is just the
volume
or over here because we have a two
dimensional lattice is the area
of this parallelogram
and
from the diagram we can see that
if a lattice has small determinant
it will imply that it's fairly dense
and the gamma hsvp problem
therefore looks for a short lattice
vector
whose length is within
gamma times
the determinant of the lattice
normalized to the power of one over n
and because of the minkowski's theorem
we know that for any lattice
there exists a its shortest vector is a
within
a factor of square root n
times this normalized determinant
and moreover for random letters
this actually takes equality
up to some constant factor
so in
other words
the best approximation factor that we
can hope for for hsvp it's square root n
so why do we care about this
hermit svp forum
because of the existence of this slide
reduction algorithm or the bkz algorithm
where they reduce poly approx svp
to concern approximately svp of lower
ranks
and we make the observation that
in such reductions
they are using the constant approximate
vector
problem
as a oracle for a square and approx hsvp
oracle
so in other words if we can solve square
root n across hsvp
it suffices for us
to use it in this light reduction to
give to to get a good algorithm for poly
approx svp
so what do we
achieve eventually
we find a 2 to the n 2 time algorithm
for square root n approx svp
and also for square root approx hsvp
and because of the slide reduction
we are able to give faster algorithms
for poly
poly and approx svp
for almost all
polyene factor
i would like to emphasize that this work
actually has no direct impact on
cryptography
because there exists heuristic
algorithms for the shortest vector
problem
that runs in much faster time
so they achieve a running time of 3 over
2 to the n over to
running time
and in these heuristic algorithms
they bring in heuristic assumptions that
are not proven but experimentally
verified
so in some sense there is a huge gap
between probable algorithms and
heuristic algorithms and this will
actually
serve as a step towards closing the gap
between provable and heuristic
algorithms
for the shortest vector problem
next let's look at what our algorithm
actually do
so before that i would like to repeat
again what is our goal
we are looking for lattice vectors
they are short
and they are non-zero the zero vector is
uninteresting
and here is a overview a high level high
level idea of
what's happening
in our algorithm
so in the beginning
we are going to sample a bunch of
vectors lattice vectors from the input
lattice l
such that
this vectors has some nice disk nice
property and the expected square norm is
going to be some parameter t
next
for the next r iterations
we are going to keep pairing the vectors
and subtracting the pair that we have
so in one step we get about a list of
vectors that falls in l1
and after our steps
we're going to
end up with a list of vectors
who falls in lr and we'll make sure that
this lr
is going to be 2 to the k
times the input lattice l
so it's a
scale up version of
the input lattice
and we also then show that the expected
square norm of
these vectors that we receive at the end
we have x would be 2 to the r times t
now we if we do a little bit of scaling
so if we scale them
down
to
become the input lattice
its expected square knob would be 2 to
the r minus 2k times t and if we can
show that
the factor here
it's less than 1 then we are making
progress at least in terms of the length
now let's zoom in into
what happens in one step of the
algorithm
so we start with some nicely distributed
vectors
that falls into the
the force in the lattice l0
and for sub lattice l1
we are going to partition the vectors
into buckets
and for the audience who are familiar
with lattice cosets these brackets are
just cosets in l0 over l1
we partition the vectors into brackets
and within the same bracket we are going
to arbitrarily pair
and subtract vectors
and
in the end we are going to receive a
bunch of
nicely distributed vectors
that falls into the lattice l1
the reason why these vectors falls into
l1 is because when we take
a pair of vectors in the same bucket and
we subtract them
the offset is
cancelled out so the remaining component
has to be
falling in the lattice l1
now let's see what happens to the
expected square norm
so we are taking a pair of vectors and
we subtract them
now if we expand out this
norm squared
we have the expected square number of
the first vector and the second vector
and we have a inner product term in the
b
in the middle
and we claim that this inner product
term
is actually going to take the value of
0.
this is because
this
list of vectors that we get
are going to be distributed as
so x is going to be distributed the same
as minus x
we guarantee this property along the way
therefore the expected
value of the inner product
is going to be
the same as the expected value
of the inner product but we can allow to
take one of the vector to this negation
and it has to be
equals to zero
therefore
the expected square norm has to be
double the expected square number of the
vectors that we start with
so
in one step
the expected square norm
is doubled
in r steps the expected square norm is
going to grow by a factor of exactly 2
to the power of r
next
we recall that the vect the lattice
is also getting faster and faster
so we will have 2 to the n buckets
and over here the number of buckets is
actually the
number of cosets we have
and in our steps it's
not hard to see that
the
lattice that we end up with lr
is going to be 2 to the
m over n times r
times the initial lattice
and we set this value to v2 to decay so
in other words k is equal to m over n
times r
now recall we are going to
scale down the vectors
so after scaling down the expected
square known we have 2 to the r minus 2k
times t
and in order to make progress
we want this 2 to the
power of r minus 2 k term
to be a lot less than 1.
in other words we want the exponent to
be a lot less than 0.
now if we substitute back the value that
k is equal to m over n
times r
we want this term to be less than equals
to be a lot less than zero
and if we manipulate the term a little
bit we can show that we
need m to be above n over 2.
so over here where we have a small
remark on the running time
the running time would be 2 to the m at
least because we need this many vectors
to start with to make sure that
all the buckets had something in it
and we are not losing too many vectors
along the way
so the number of buckets is a minimum
requirement of the number of vectors
that we
have to have
so the running time has to be 2 to the m
ls
and we just show that m has to be above
n over 2
and therefore the best running time that
we managed to achieve at the end is 2 to
the n over 2
plus small of n
so with this
we show that the vectors are actually
getting shorter and shorter
i remain it remains to show that we are
not seeing too many zero vectors in the
end
and to do this we will need the help of
this nice distribution
essentially the discrete gaussian
distribution
so what is this discrete gaussian
it's basically for any discrete set a
any vector if we draw from the discrete
gaussian distribution
any vector would show up with the
probability that is proportional to the
gaussian mass
and you can take it as a analog of the
continuous gaussian distribution
and it's also associated with a
parameter s
this parameter s can be seen as the
standard deviation
of the continuous gaussian distribution
so in particular here is a nice
illustration on the
discrete gaussian distribution
on z square
so when s is large on the left
it will it looks fairly smooth just like
a continuous gaussian distribution
and when s is small
it looks more and more discretized
so we have a few remarks on this
discrete gaussian distribution
for each of the lattice it has an
associated parameter called the
smoothing parameter
and when the
value of s is above the summoning
parameter
the discrete gaussian behaves nicely
like a continuous gaussian distribution
and this allows us to manipulate
fairly fairly easily
and more importantly why are we
introducing this
it will allow us to upper bound the
probability of seeing the zero vector
and with its help we are going to show
that
we won't see too many zero vectors
at the end of our algorithm
now in the in our algorithm
the actual distribution that we are
using
is a variant of the discrete gaussian
it's called the mixture of discrete
gaussian
so in particular we have some
target subletters l prime
this target sub lattice alpha is not
necessarily known
it's only it only shows up for analysis
purpose
so basically if we look at
vectors
that are in the same process of l prime
these vectors are going to be
distributed like a continuous like a
discrete gaussian
but of course across different code sets
they may
not have any relationship
at all
we only cared what we only care is that
within the same coset
the vectors behaves
like
a discrete gaussian
with this
we can show that when our algorithm
stops
we are going to see vectors of expected
square
of expected length square root n times s
where the value of s is roughly the
smoothing parameter
of this target sub lattice l prime
so it remains to show that
there exists some target sub that is l
prime
that has a small smoothing parameter
and here we are going to use the reverse
minkowski theorem
which is a fairly heavy hammer
and as a direct corollary of this
reverse minkowski theorem we can show
that for any lattice l
there exists a sub lattice l prime
whose small whose smoothing parameter is
upper bounded by poly a log n
times mean of the lambda 1 the shortest
vector of the lattice
or the
normalized determinant of the letters
so one term would then correspond to the
svp problem that we're trying to solve
the other term will correspond to the
hsvp problem that we are trying to solve
now plugging in the values together
would therefore manage to show that the
output length of the vectors
is going to be upper bounded by
square root n
times the mean of lambda 1
and
the the normalized determinant of the
lattice
so
that concludes the algorithm
okay so some of the open problems from
our algorithm
so can we find a better analysis
to bring down the approximation factor
of the algorithm
or in other words can we actually have a
better guarantee on the approximation
factor on svp
in particular
before this work as far as we know
all the
algorithms that solves
square root n hsvp
they will also solve constant approx svp
at the same time
so and there is no reason why our
algorithm is not doing so just that our
analysis at the moment is unable to give
us any better guarantee
for svp
is unable to improve
the approximation factor
and therefore we are wondering if we can
find a different way to analyze the
algorithm
and if we can show that it actually
gives us a better approximation factor
for svp
secondly
um
i've mentioned just now that
there is this our running time is 2 to
the n over 2 plus small of n
and this is exactly because we need at
least 2 to the n over 2
number of code sets
for the algorithm to make progress
so it seems that 2 to the n over 2
running time is a
barrier here
so is there a way to break this barrier
and ultimately matching the running time
of heuristic algorithms
and that's all i have thank you for your
attention