hello everyone
my name is daniel casters and i would
like to thank the organizers of
eurocrypt 2021
for giving me the opportunity to present
our paper called c minion
symmetric encryption based on
tofoligates over large finite fields
this is joint work with kestel dobroni
lorenzo gossi
and omagining
now c minion is a cipher defined over
large finite field
its main motivation is to
minimize the number of multiplications
so let me just start by giving an
overview of why this optimization goal
is important
to this end consider the problem of
multi-party computation
in multi-party computation there are n
parties p1 up to pn
and each of these parties has an input x
i
and the goal is to jointly evaluate a
function
of these x i
called small f
and importantly
there should not be a trusted third
party that is involved but rather the
parties should communicate amongst each
other
and there are some other constraints
namely
that each party wants to keep their own
input x i secret
and each party learns nothing apart from
what can be in turn inferred from the
output y
there exists a number of protocols
realizing multi-party computation
and for a subset of these protocols the
following two properties are
namely
non-linear operations are expensive
and fine operations are cheap and by
expensive i mean expensive relative to
the f1 operation
examples of such protocols include yao's
garbled circuit protocol
with a pre-extra optimization
and
in this protocol the function f is
represented as a boolean circuit
comprised of a number of gates
and
these gates are garbled
now it doesn't really matter what
garbling means
but what is important is that the
garbling of an xor gate
is cheap because it involves some simple
additions
whereas the garbling of an end gate is
expensive
because it requires calls to symmetric
primitives
and there's a gmw protocol
and again in this protocol small f is
represented as a boolean circuit
and the inputs to small f are shared
amongst the part
evaluation of
an xor gate
involves some local computation so it's
cheap
whereas the evaluation of an end gate
requires communication between the
parties so it's expensive
suppose now that
p1 up to pn
want to compute a symmetric encryption
function
called e in this case
which depends on a key k and an input x
now there are many ways that this e can
be implemented for example
there could be two parties where one
party has the key and the other has the
input or maybe the keys are shared
but what is important is that we are now
looking at the case that small f equals
this e
in traditional symmetric ciphers
design decisions were made based on
your laptop as a computing environment
and
the gates in your laptop
are implemented in cmos where an xor
gate
is say 2 or 3 times larger than an end
which is
i would say comparable
whereas in the protocols of the previous
slide the difference between the
non-linear and the linear operations are
quite large
so this has led to a class of low
multiplicative complexity ciphers where
people have really tried to minimize the
number of nonlinear operations in
particular the multiplications
in the tables that you see here you see
a number of such ciphers in existence
i don't claim that this is an exhaustive
list but it's just to give you an idea
of what people have been doing
what these these ciphers
do not have in common so maybe but the
difference is is that
basically some of these ciphers are
defined over bits whereas others are
defined over prime fields others are
defined over binary fields
and some are defined over both
and
it turns out because this field is
relatively new that
designs are not as well understood as
these traditional designs so menu or
some of these cycles at least have been
broken by decks
so where does c minion come in well it
fits right here namely it's defined over
both prime fields and binary fields
and with c minion we wanted to give a
an entire suite of
building blocks that make up an
encryption functionality so that means a
mode
a permutation the round functions that
make up this permutation a key schedule
etc
and we were motivated by
based cryptography as i will show you
later
and it turns out that cminion is
actually quite competitive if the key
schedule which turns out to be quite
heavy can be computed during an offline
phase so for example if e
is computed by two parties so in a
two-party
computation setting where one party
computes the key and the other has the
input
in the following figure you see
a number of ciphers
including c minion
and the number of multiplications that
they have so on the x-axis you see
plotted the variable t
which corresponds to the number of
elements that that should be encrypted
so the number of plaintexts basically
and on the y-axis is the number of
multiplications
and as you can see c minion is in blue c
minion performs quite well and
our closest competitor in terms of
minimizing the number of multiplications
turns out to be hedes mimsc
so how did we achieve such a low
multiplication count
well in order to explain that i will go
over the building blocks that make up
see me
so first of all
the mode that we use in c minion is
based on farfallen so what you see in
this picture is the portfolio mode
and
portfolio is actually defined over just
bits
and there are a number of important
takeaways here
well first
you see that there are a number of
permutations involved pb
pc pd and pe
and many of them can be computed in in
parallel
so this has a positive impact on say the
[Music]
the and gate that of
a circuit implementing this
this mode
and there are also other performance
benefits
then a second important thing is that
not all these permutations need to
protect against the same attacks
so for example pc just needs to account
for some subset of attacks whereas
pe then accounts for another subset of
the tech
and these are properties that
will help to to minimize the
multiplication curve
so
this is the mode that we are using in c
minimum
like i said it's based on for quality
but we have made a number of
of changes
and the first change that you see here
in in the red circle is that we have
merged the permutations p
small c and p small b into one
permutation p capital c so importantly
we don't need this accumulator stage
that we saw in the previous slide
and we just need a single permutation pc
and the goal of this pc is to
protect or ensure some protection
against higher order differential
attacks
so
it's it is actually responsible for
making sure that the degree is is large
and
i should emphasize that pc is is called
only once and it doesn't really depend
on the number of inputs
then here in the
in the purple circle you see that we
have truncated the output of the
permutation pe
and the idea behind this is that an
attacker
cannot easily then invert the
permutation pe because this would
involve guessing
the part of the output that we have
truncated
and this helps for example against
protection against meat in the middle of
meeting the middle style effect
then
in the orange circle you see that
we have
moved
the key from the output so that is to
say
it's no longer added to the plain text
but it's moved to the inside of the mode
and this prevents bypassing the key
edition because an attacker is now no
longer easily able to consider just the
differences
which bypass the key edition
and
moreover we have also increased the
number of key indeterminates because as
we will see this
is something that
makes
solvers for systems of equations a lot
slower because they depend on the number
of equations
and in this figure you see the c minion
round function
and it is this round function that is
repeated to make up
both the permutation p e and the
permutation pc where the difference
between the two in the number of such
rounds
an important thing
to notice in this round function is that
we have used the multiplication it's our
source of non-linearity
in many of the the previous designs
the non-linearity came from the fact
that a single field element
was for example qubit so a power map was
applied to it
however a downside of this approach is
that it limits the diffusion and
using a multiplication involves
different field elements which is a
beneficial to the to the diffusion
and also the the multiplication has very
good
properties in the context of linear and
and differential grip analysis
next there there was the choice for a
linear layer
so even though i've said that
none of your operations are expensive
and linear operations are cheap that
does not mean that
linear operations are for free in fact
they can have quite a big of an impact
in certain protocol
so we have decided to go for a
relatively lightweight linear layer
and
one of the important things is that we
want to make sure that if we consider
just a single field element
and consider its univariate degree that
also this univariate degree doubles
during each call of the round function
and this is why we you see these
these joints in in this little circuit
because they ensure that that each field
element
occurs in many different branches which
make sure that indeed the univariate
degree is doubled every time
then there is
the addition of a number of round
constants they are there to to make sure
that
um
any symmetries that are present are
removed
and of particular interest is this round
constant four
it turns out that
if you look at
the linear properties of the round
function and if you do not include this
rc4
and consider
fields of characteristic two then it's
possible to find linear approximations
that have a linear potential of one
thereby basically
breaking this round function and more
importantly they can be chained so
you could just attack the entire
permutation in that way but that's why
we have included this rc4 round constant
so that's for the round function
so in this figure you see the key
schedule
notice that the the number of keys that
we need depends on the number of inputs
that we want to encrypt so it makes
sense to have
an initial secret and then just derive
the keys that we need on the flow on the
fly
so we start out with two master keys and
an ip and then
use these as input to a sponge
construction
and what is important to to realize here
is that the permutations in this sponge
construction are the pc permutations and
as i have already into that before these
pc
permutations will be quite heavy because
they are the ones that need to prevent
higher order differential analysis
so in fact the key schedule itself is
quite a heavy computation
so this is why i i said that
in order to be competitive we assume
that this key schedule is
computed during an offline stage
now in order to derive
the number of rounds that make up both
the permutation pc and pe
we have done some security analysis
so first we have looked at differential
and linear cryptanalysis
again the non-linear component in our
round function is the multiplication map
which just multiplies two field field
elements
with each other
and
this multiplication map has very good
differential and linear properties
namely its max dp is equal to 1 over q
where q is just the cardinality of of
the field so if the field is fb then
that would be p and if the field is
f2 to the power n then this q would be 2
to the power n and the maximum linear
potential is equal to 1 over q squared
so from this it follows that
as as soon as as you have one active
multiplication then
differential and linear crit analysis
are no longer a problem so what does it
mean for a multiplication to be active
well that basically means that the input
difference is non-zero or the input mask
is non-zero
so why is it that not a problem well
actually our security parameter s
is
dependent on the the the field
cardinality
so again as soon as one
multiplication becomes active
these attacks are no longer a problem
however
when what i said during the
the slide about the round function is
that we need this rc4 because indeed
without this rc4 it's it's it's possible
to to to bypass this multiplication to
make sure that it's never active
and
yeah
the point here that i'm trying to make
is that many people claim that for these
for this kind of cipher differential
linear cryptanalysis are not an issue
but
you also need to take the linear layer
into account
then let's look at higher order
differential attacks so in a higher
order differential attack the goal is to
find a
fine subspace of large enough dimension
or a multiplicative subgroup of large
enough cardinality such that summing
over this fine space or
this multiplicative subgroup gives
the zero value so basically it's a kind
of zero-sum distinguisher
and in order to prevent this kind of
attack you want to make sure that the
the
degree of your
function representation is quite large
large enough
so
the main permutation responsible for the
degree growth is this p of c
and
again this p of c consists of the
composition of the round function and
each round function has degree 2 over f
q
in other words
if we want to make sure that
our function has degree at least
2 over s we need to figure out how many
rounds we can linearize it turns out
that we can linearize the first two
rounds
so from this it immediately follows that
if we have
s plus two rounds then
pc will have degree two to the power s
and
these higher order differential attacks
are no longer a problem
and as people have done in the past in
other papers we also conjecture that
if c minion is secure against higher
order differential attacks then
automatically it is secure against
interpolation attacks as well
then we have considered
grignard basis attacks
the idea behind a grinder basis attack
is that you represent your cipher as a
system of equations
and then this system of equations
corresponds to an ideal
and the grouping basis is a particular
kind of generating set for this ideal
from which
it is easy to to read off the solutions
to your original system of equations
uh in general this this happens with
back substitution
so importantly the cost of computing a
gurner basis depends on the number of
indeterminants in your system of
equations the number of such equations
and their degrees
now we have considered a number of
strategies that we thought were the most
promising
the first one was relating the input to
the output
and
in this strategy the attacker
has both pc and pe involved and you can
kind of view them as
one big permutation where the number of
rounds involved is the sum of the number
of rounds of pc plus the number of
rounds in pe
and
the idea is that each nonce
is input at the start
but you don't know that the two key bits
so the the two key elements so the two
keys are actually the indeterminate
so if we then have two nonce inputs this
means that we have actually
two equations in two key indeterminants
and the goal is to to pick the number r
of such rounds
for this grammar basis computation to be
infeasible
so we want
so we have actually a system of
equations of degree 2 to the power r
and then we plug this into the greater
basis cost and it follows that
already by picking for pc the number
s plus 6 for the number of rounds
that's enough to depart this this kind
of attack
then the second strategy is
relating the intermediate state to the
output
so in this case
only the permutation p e is in full
and here we have an unknown intermediate
state
the state actually after applying pc to
the nums and the two key elements
and the goal of the attacker is to
recover this unknown intermediate state
because from that intermediate state it
becomes easy to uh to break the system
so
what we have done is conjecture that
a different kind of mode
is
let's say easier to
to break than the original mode so if we
can
not break the easy mode then it's also
not possible to break the mode that we
are actually using
so what we are considering here is a
mode in which the the key addition that
is in the middle has been moved to the
end again
because that allows us to consider
differences
and by considering differences we can
remove this key edition at the end
but what do we do we consider two nonces
and
each nonce leads to an unknown state of
three
unknown elements so that gives actually
three in determinants and because we are
considering two nonsense we have six
indeterminants and it turns out that we
then have a system of six equations
in six indeterminants of degree two to
the power r minus one two to the power r
two to the power r plus one and two to
the power r plus two
and by substituting these numbers into
the grotner basis
cost equation
we find that if we choose r such that
it's
at least s plus 37 over 12 then this
kind of attack becomes
infeasible
and that's then the number of rounds
that we choose for this pe
permutation so this gives the following
table where a particular interest is the
row in the middle
where we consider a data limit of two to
the power s over two elements
where
this corresponds to the birthday bond so
for pc we then have a number of rounds
equal to two thirds of s plus six
and for p e we have the maximum of six
and s plus thirty seven over twelve
and i just wanted to point out that if
you for choose for s the number 128
which is a kind of standard security
level then
the number of rounds for pc is much much
larger than pe but pe is not
it's not something that you can neglect
because pe is called many different
times depending on the number of output
words
so
in this table you see
what i showed at the beginning in a
graph but here with concrete numbers
and i would just like to show you the
the the first row that of c minion where
in both it shows you the number of
multiplications
which is equal to 14 times t over two
plus t plus 89
this 89 follows from the number of
permutations for the number of rounds of
the number of multiplications of the pc
permutation which is called only once
then for each running function in the
mode
one multiplication is performed so
that's why we have this t value here
and
each pe
call has four around 14 notifications
involved however you output also two
elements so that's why you have this
this 14 times 2 t over 2 here
so indeed we think we are quite
competitive
now we have done some preliminary
security analysis
however we believe that maybe more can
be done so we encourage you to try and
break ground produced versions of
cminion moreover we have a version of c
minion in the paper
in which the
the round sorry the ronin function is
instead of non-linear linear
to maybe even minimize the
multiplications further and we also
encourage you to have a look at that
and with that i would like to conclude
this talk and thank you for your
attention