hello everyone i'm takashi today i will
talk about classical versus quantum
realm oracles this is a joint work with
mark gentry
the random org model rom was introduced
by pillar and roger in 93
this model is the idealization of
cryptographic hash functions
in the rom
some random function h
is randomly chosen at the beginning of
security games and then adverti is
allowed to make
oracle access to the random function
and the rom
is very useful for analyzing practical
cryptographic schemes so this has been
used uh
for a rising variety of constructions
the quantum runway model qram is a
quantum version of the rom
introduced by bonnie ethel in 2011.
uh the difference from the original rom
is that in the qram otherwise allowed to
make quantum coverage to the random
worker that is
it can query a quantum server position
of input and then the oracle returns as
output in superposition
and the reason why we should
consider
such a quantum access to the oracle is
that
the random oracle
is
usually instantiated with
some
fixed
cryptographic hash functions in the real
world therefore
uh if adversary has a quantum computer
then it can
quantumly evaluate the hash function and
so this corresponds to quantum work
reactive in the quantum runaway model
and this is why we should study qram for
ensuring post quantum security
here i'd like to review what are known
about the qram
and pointed out by the first
work by bonnie ether
many proof techniques in the realm
doesn't work in the queue rom at least
in a straightforward manner
those techniques include pre-image
awareness and adaptive
programmability therefore in the past
decade new approved techniques in the
qram have been developed and this line
of research made a great success and now
almost all major protocols in the rom
are also proven secure in the qram and
those protocols include fujisaki okamoto
or aep fiat chemir and full domain hash
and so now there is no known scheme and
that is secure in rom but insecure in
qram
then it is natural to ask the foreign
question
does security in rome imply
security in kurum this is our main
question
in this work we give both positive and
negative answer to the question
and our first result is a negative
answer so we give the first separation
between rom and q rom
specifically or we can give contractions
of pke and signature schemes
that are secure in the rom but insecure
in the qram
and i remarked that a similar result was
also shown in concurrent work by zhang
and
on the other hand we also give
some positive results that specifically
we give
our some rom to kill rom lifting
theorems
under some conditions
and we also show some applications of
the lifting theorems
to the setting of signatures and query
complexity
from now i will explain more technical
details about our separation result
uh and forgiving our separation we
introduce a new primitive which we call
proof of quantum access to random oracle
poqro
which captures the essence of the
separation between rom and qram
and intuitively
this is the interactive protocol between
improver and verifier available proves
that it has a quantum access to random
oracle to classical wi-fi
more specifically
the fire first generate pair of public
key and secret key and send public key
to the approver and then prover given
public key and quantum access to random
function that generates the proof pie
and then
sends the proof part to the fire and the
provider requires a proof
to
output acceptance or rejection
and we require completeness and
soundness completeness means that if
both parties work honestly then
verify access with probability one and
soundness means that if prover only has
classical access to random function a
simplifier asset with negligible
probability
and if you're familiar with the notion
of proof of quantumness introduced by
brackets guitar then
you may
find similarity with poq however the
difference is that in poq
we only require soundness against
completely classical cheating river on
the other hand uh in our poqro we
require soundness against or even
quantum cheating river
with only classical
rocket access so this is the difference
from poq
we give two constructions a poqro in
this work and the first construction is
based on the lw assumption
interestingly this construction is
actually exactly the same as the recent
construction of poq by
brackets key ether that is we just
observed that the
poq actually also satisfies soundness as
poqro
and because the construction is exactly
the same
i will not explain the detail but their
protocol looks like the following
the verifier first generates glo-free
permutation f and sends after the period
and then the prover run some quantum
computation by using quantum access to h
and finally gets
some pair of classical strings m and d
that satisfy this equation
where x0 and x1
are the glow of
f and especially what is important in
that we have a time of h of x 0 x or h
of x 1 here
therefore
if
a cheating period only has classical
access to random oracle
then
this x or is uniformly random unless the
other box requires both x0 and x1
however
it can query both of them only with
negligible probability by their claw
freeness
therefore if prover cheating approver
only has classical access to random
oracle then this time looks
random and
therefore
it is difficult to generate m and d that
satisfies
this equation with high probability
therefore uh
this gives the separation between
rom and qram
and by using poqr uh we can easily get
uh rom-current separations for signature
and pk schemes and for example i will
explain uh the case of signatures
let pi sig be your euf theme is secure
signature scheme
and then consider modify scheme pi prime
c through the signing algorithm to
return the secret key if the message is
valid peer cure proof
and this modification doesn't affect
security in the rom because by the times
of poqro
other battery in the rom cannot find
valid poker proof on the other hand uh
this modification makes the protocol
completely insecure in the queue rom
because the other three in the qram can
find
a
valid procure proof by the completeness
of poqro therefore it can just queries
uh such a
valid poqr proof to get the secret key
to completely break the qe
therefore this gives
example of the separation of for ef sim
signatures
and similar separation
is possible for in the cc apke by
embedding poker verification into the
decryption oracle
and here we observe that the
those separations rely on the fact that
there's an oracle that uses secret
information like signing and decryption
records
and so this technique is not applicable
to euf nma signatures where there is no
signing key signing queries and
in cppke where there is no decryption
queries
and the reason why we need oracle with
secret information is that
the lwe based poqro
or needs a secret key for the
verification
therefore if we have publicly verified
our poqro or where specification can be
done publicly then or we can
uh extend
those separations to euf and nma and in
cpa pk case
and therefore next we study
uh constructions of publicly verifiable
poqro
for constructing publicly verifiable
poqro we rely on equivocal correlation
resistant hash e c r h introduced by
ammos ether
eclh is a function f that satisfies the
foreign two properties
the first is the collision resistance
that just means that one cannot find the
collision if f and the second is
equivocality
which means that all one can sample
image y
along with some quantum state s k and
that enables one to find
a pre-image x such that f of x equals y
and p of x equal b
for either of b equals zero and one or
where p is some predicate that is very
balanced uh here we the very balance
means that the sizes of images of zero
and one are not
too different
and here i remark
that uh we don't claim that
one can find uh for images of
the images with p of x equals zero and
one simultaneous three or rather uh sk
only in everyone to find either of them
however the point is that the b can be
determined adaptably
and i remember that this is a unique
quantum capability because if
this can be done classically then by
rewinding or we can break collision
resistance
and in the work of ammo ether they
constructed
ecrh
for
the case of predicate is said to be the
least significant bit of x
relative to some artificial classical
oracle and we observe that the their
proof naturally extends to arbitrary uh
predicate as long as pes are very
balanced
especially we consider to set
the predicate by using random oracle or
with one bit output
by using a ecrh for such a random oracle
predicate or we construct publicly
verifiable qro as follows and the first
we
construct foreground version of
the poqro
in the protocol the verifier first is
generate eclhf and sends f to the prover
and then river generates the pair of y
and sk and offend y and the fire
randomly picks a
challenge b
and send b to the prover and then the
river or finds x such that f of x equals
y and h of x equal b by using the
equivocarity of eclh and then sends x to
the
fire and then the verifier checks if
this
equation actually holds
and the completeness is clear from the
description and the soundness can be
seen as follows
by the collision resistance of f
if p only has graphical access to
h then it can know the value of h of x
for at most one pre-image of x
of y
except for negligible probability and
then
the probability that this particular
value of h of x
is equal to
b
is one half because b is randomly chosen
by the b fire
therefore the fire axis with probability
at most one-half plus negligible and
this time with error can be amplified
to negligible or by
uh
prior repetition
and here i
observed that the third round message b
is just public kind so by using the
standard technique of viet xiaomi
transformation or we can reduce the noun
the number round of the protocol
if we consider the power replication
version of the previous
protocol and then
we derive the challenges b1 to bn by
using
another random oracle g and then we can
compress
the protocol to two round protocol and
by the standard technique
we can reduce the soundness of this
two-round version to soundness a foreign
version
and now we obtain a two-round publicly
verifiable
poqro
from ecrh
next i explain how to use publicly
verifiable poqro to give separations of
rom and qram uh for
in the cpu secure pke and euf enemy
signatures uh for ncp secure pke uh the
idea is similar to
the case of in the cc secure pke but the
difference is that
now the verification can be done
publicly so we can embed the
verification algorithm of poqro into the
encryption algorithm
of the pke rather than decryption
algorithm therefore uh this naturally
gives separation for individual security
and similarly by embedding poq or
verification into the verification
algorithm of signature or we can get
separation for euf nme signatures
and here i remark that because
the contraction of ecrh
rely on
some artificial graphical organ so those
separations also rely on the same
classical oracle
therefore we don't have
actual instantiation of such schemes but
we can interpret these results as a
negative evidence for rom to qram
lifting theorem for those security
notions
next i would like to move on to our
lifting theorem part so we give lifting
theorem for
what we call search type game
which is described as follows the search
type game is the interactive broadcast
between quantum adversary and classical
challenger
where the classical challenge finally
outputs acceptance or rejection
and our listening theorem is stated as
the forums
let's cave in the number of challenges
queries and then for any quantum
polynomial time a making q quantum
queries
there exists quantum polynomial time b
making k classical queries such that
the probability that
a
lets challenge accept
is upper bounded by 2 cubed plus 1 to
the power of 2k times probability
that b
lets the challenge accept
and especially
when
k is constant and q is polynomial
then
we have the following uh
if the probability that b let
challenge accept is negligible then
uh the probability
that a lets charge accept is also
negligible
and one can see that this corresponds to
the security in the rom because b only
makes graphical queries and this
corresponds to security in the queue rom
because a makes quantum queries so in
the setting where challenger makes only
constant number of queries
this theorem can be seen as a
listing theorem from rom security to the
qram security
and i would like to explain some queries
of our written theorem
and first uh we can see that there is no
poql o or where the number of refined
queries is constant
uh remark that uh uh for both of our
contractions uh the verifier makes super
constant number of queries because we
amplify the sounds error by using super
constant number of uh power repetition
and second for any nisk in rom food
setup and verification algorithm make
constant number of queries that is also
sound in the queue rom and the typical
example is fiat me nuke
and we can show a similar lifting
theorem for euf anime signatures
unfortunately we cannot extend this to
euf cma signatures or in such a general
form
on the other hand we give
extend
lifting film to ufc signatures with some
additional conditions that are satisfied
by fiat chamier and fd chicken shoes
and their intuition behind that is that
uh
we we already know that there is a
euf nma to euf cma lifting theorem for
those signature schemes so we first
apply our rom to qram lifting theorem
for euf enemy
security and then after that we apply
this listing theorem to upgrade the
security to uf theme security
and we also obtain an extremely simple
tool to get query lower bounds in the
queue rom
and for example we can reprove the
optimality of global algorithm only in
two lines
so this is very simple and useful
and the caveat is that this tool often
gives non-tight bounds
but
we believe that this tool is useful when
we are not interested in tight bound and
we are only interested in giving
a
negligible upper bound which is often in
the case of in the cryptography
and finally i would like to explain uh
our proof idea for the lifting theorem
so the lifting theorem is described
like this
for explaining the proof idea
let's first consider the classical
version of the lifting theorem
or where
we only consider
other three a that makes classical
queries
and i remark that this is still
meaningful because
a can make unbounded number of queries
or whereas we can make only k queries
which is the same number as the
challenges
queries and for proving this classical
version the idea is the following
for each i equal 1 to k
b randomly guesses or when a queries
challenges i query for the first time
including the choice that a never query
that
then b embeds real random oracle values
to their k
guest queries by querying those queries
to the real
random oracle or while simulating other
queries by using fake random oracle or
that is
simulated by b itself
then as long as the gate is correct
b
correctly simulates
the view of
the a
and the probability that the guess is
correct is 1 over q plus 1 to the power
of k
therefore here is a reduction
between the probability that a wins and
b wins with the reduction loss of the
factor of q plus 1 to the power of k
and
our idea is to generate this to the
quantum case
and when
a is quantum a makes quantum queries an
obvious problem is that because a query
is a quantum so it is
it is unclear how to embed
classical random work values to those
quantum queries
and solution is to just measure those k
guest queries
and
even though such a measurement
may be
uh
noticed with non-negligible probability
by a
however
uh
by using the the the measure and the
reproductive glamour introduced by don
etta
we can show that this works with slight
reverse reduction loss of 2k plus 1 to
the power 2k
and this is
the proof of the proof sketch of our
living theorem
this is the summaries right or we give
the first separations between rom and
qram
and on the other hand we also give
rom to qram lifting theorems
for
type games or with constant query
challenges
and we also give some applications of
the listing theorem to signatures and
query complexity
this is the end of my talk thank you for
listening