hello
welcome to my presentation of our paper
on the compactness of hashing modes and
efficiency beyond mercury this is a
joint work with elena and riva from tuv
vienna and arnold roy from klagenfurt
the general outline of the rest of my
talk is as follows
i am going to start with one slight
description of our result
to describe things in detail i shall
first state our motivation and recall
some background results then we jump
into our results on the two modes that
we present abr and avr plus
finally i am going to briefly discuss
some related extensions of our work
here is the one slide representation of
our work
we introduce two hashing modes abr and
abr plus
both the modes are based on 2 and 2 n
bit compression functions
the parameter of avr mode matches stems
bound from crypto 2008
when compared to popular markletory
abr mode compresses around 50 more
messages by making same number of calls
to the underlying compression function
in comparison abr plus achieves
indifferentiability security notion
the only compromise it makes
is it compresses one message block less
than at the abr mode
our work has both theoretical and
practical motivations
indeed achieving stamps bound for
general parameters have been an open
problem since 2008.
from practical perspective the problem
relates to minimizing multiplicative
complexity
as more function calls implies increased
multiplicative complexity the natural
question is how to compress more
messages by making same number of
function calls and thus minimizing the
multiplicative complexity
of course an efficient hash function has
other applications as well like in
archiving proof systems etc
let's start from the background
a hash function takes strings of
arbitrary length as input and produces
strings of fixed length as output
a cryptographic hash function needs to
satisfy some security notions
two primary requirements are the
collision resistance and the pre-image
resistance
we say an adversary finds a collision in
the hash function
if it can produce two distinct messages
m and m prime such that hm equal to hm
prime
that is the messages are mapped to the
same point
we require that it takes approximately 2
to the power n over too many hash
evaluations before the adversary can
find a collision
similarly for premature instance
the adversary is asked to invert the
hash function h on any given point
we expect that an adversary needs to
make approximately 2 to the power in
many hash computations before finding
the pre-image
there are notions like second pre-major
instance or target collision resistance
analyzed in the literature
however they are implied by collision
resistance
in the last 15 years indifferentiability
from a random oracle have appeared as
major security criteria
it says that the adversary should not be
able to distinguish
distinguish the hash function h from a
random function from 0 1 star to 0 1 n
i would like to point out that in
differentiability from random oracle is
indeed a very strong security notion and
in particular it subsumes collision
resistance and premature distance
the hash functions are designed in two
steps
first one chooses a suitable function f
which is a mu bit to n bit function with
mu greater than equal to n
the hash function is implemented via a
domain extension algorithm or a mode of
operation algorithm which on input m
iteratively queries the function f as a
subroutine with suitable inputs and
computes the hash value based on the
responses
in the figure the blocks gis are the one
which decides the output of decides the
input to query
the function f
the security argument for the hash
function is established via reduction
from f
it is shown that an attack against h can
be converted into an attack against f
often information theoretic arguments
are used
where f is modeled as an ideal object
like a random function or a random
permutation
two classical and yet the
state-of-the-art examples
are markle language and markletory
market omgart is a cascade construction
where the message is pre-processed by
applying a padding
for marquetry the data tree data
structure is used
to evaluate the hash
the messages are injected at the leaf
level
the functions are evaluated level wise
and the output of the root node is given
as the hash value
modern hash designs employing material
good or marquetry often uses padding to
ensure the functions are independent
blick or md6 are good examples of such
pen
in this work we ask how can we construct
the most efficient domain extension
algorithm
in concrete terms we wish to construct a
collision resistant k into n bit hash
function yet making minimum number of
calls to the underlying to end to n bit
function f
of course we are not the first to ask
this question
in euro crypt 2005 black koshan and
shrimpton proved that to construct a 2
into n-bit collision-resistant function
from n-bit permutations
more than one call to the permutation is
necessary
rogave and steinberg generalized this
result to show that any k into ln bit
function from
permutations need to make 2 k minus l
many queries to the n bit permutations
in 2008 stem refined the above bound and
conjectured that any collision resistant
t plus s to s bit function from n plus c
to n bit function requires s plus 2 t
divided by 2 n plus 2 c minus s cos
in concrete terms stance bound implies
to construct 2n to nbit function from n
to n bit functions three calls are
necessary
similarly to construct k n to n bit
function from 2 n to n bit functions 2 k
minus 1 by 3 many calls are necessary
the only upper bound
achieving n by two bits of collision
security is the shrinkdown stem
construction from 2008.
the construction is described in the
picture
the construction uses three n to n bit
functions and compresses two n bit
message to construct n bit digest
however the problem is open for general
parameters in particular we did not know
whether to construct k into n bit
function from two n to n bit functions
two k minus one by three many calls are
sufficient to achieve collision
resistance
and to put matters in perspective we
recall that the marquetry makes k minus
one many calls
we show that yes indeed such
constructions exist
we present an augmented binary tree abr
hashing mode which compresses k n bit
message to in big digest by making 2k
minus one by three calls to the
underlying two end to end bit functions
and achieve n by two bit of collision
resistance
compared to markletrain this gives
almost fifty percent improvement as
fifty percent more messages can be
compressed
we also present a simple modification of
abr tree that we call abr plus mode that
can achieve indifferentiability from
random oracle by making the same 2k
minus one by three calls to the
underlying functions
the only difference is that in case of
abr plus we compress one block less
the avr tree is shown in the picture
starting with a tree
at each non-leaf function call an
additional message block is served
with both the input
like shrimp and stem
one previous chaining value is feed
forward and solved with the output
i am going to present an overview of the
collision resistance argument
the main difficulty is in handling the
fact that the adversary may query the
functions adaptively
for example the adversary may make some
queries to the root say and later make
queries at the lower level and try to
match with the previous query input
the core idea
is to define a bad event if such match
happens too many times
we derive an upper bound on the expected
number of such match and apply mark of
inequality
in more detail the crucial parameter of
our analysis is the notion of the load
of the of a node in the transcript
it is the number of computable messages
in the transcript with queries to all
the nodes in the subtree of that node
the idea is
conditioned on some bad events the
collision probability can be derived in
terms of load square by 2 to the n
the main technical task is to find the
correct bad events
such that the derivation works
and the load is suitably bounded
we identify two bad events
the first one happens
when a query to a function increases the
load of that function by k to the power
l for some suitably chosen k
then here l is the height of the tree
the second one happens
when a query to a lower level function
say f j minus t b prime
increases the load of a function
f j b
by k to the power l
here
the function j minus t b prime is in the
sub tree of j b
what we could prove is that the
collision probability
of each of the small blocks
conditioned on
the bad events not happening
can be bounded by k to the power 2 m
times q square
by 2 to the n
we can also bound the bad events
individually
for the first one
one can employ a previously known
technique however for the second one we
need our mark of trade
the avr plus mode is shown in the
picture
compared to avl mode
the additional message block is not
solved at the leaf level
the general idea is that a collision
resistant pre-image aware function when
composed with independent random
function gives indifferentiability from
random oracle
so in case of avr plus we take two abr
trees
and then
envelop them with an independent random
function
to compute
the abr plus hash value
now this idea of indifferentiability
is analogous to the well-known principle
that collision resistance followed by
prf gives us a prf
the same idea works here
the collision resistance of
the abr modes
ensure that the query to the root
are all fresh
and as the root function in itself is a
random function
the arguments go through
now
i am going to talk about certain
corollaries of our result that may not
be very apparent
to start with
consider the direct extension of shrimp
and stem construction in the two end to
envied setting
here the function compresses five
message blocks
with three calls to the function f
this construction in particular has a
simpler collision resistance argument
here it is sufficient to consider level
wise adversary the reason is that the
messages are injected that are injected
at the leaf node
does not affect the transcript as the
probabilities are calculated over the
randomness of the function f as well as
the each of these function f i's are
random functions
thus there are broadly two cases to
consider collision at the leaf node and
collision at the final output
conditioned on no collision at the leaf
nodes the probability for the collision
of the leaf node can be individually
bounded by q square by 2 to the n
whereas for the
third condition we give a new counting
argument
where we prove for the collision
probability conditioned on no
collision at the leaf can be bounded by
n square q square by 2 to the n
once the collision probability is
settled
then like the previous case we get an
intermediate indifferentiability result
we take to 5 into n beta construction
and add an independent random function
as envelope
like previous case we can argue that the
pre-image aware collision resistance
followed by random function gives in
differentiability
these constructions
give an intermediate
relatively easier to prove collision
resistant hash function
where the additional messages are
injected at alternate levels
for the proof of this
we need to recursively apply our
indifferentiability result with the
composition theorem
to conclude
we presented new design principles for
tree hash with almost 50 percent more
efficiency than market tree
this is the first general parameter
construction towards achieving stamp
spot
interestingly we get an almost optimal
efficiency with indifferentiability from
random oracles as well
a natural open problem is to achieve
stamps bound for double length hash
functions
this concludes my presentation thank you