hello my name is italia now would like
to tell you about my paper cryptanalytic
applications of the polynomial method
for solving
multivariate equation systems over gf2
in this work we consider the problem of
solving polynomial equation systems
the input to the problem is a polynomial
system denoted by e
that consists of m polynomials over a
finite field f
where each polynomial has uh n variables
and is given by a its algebraic normal
form or a and f as a sum of monomials
now the algebraic degree of each
polynomial is bounded by a small
constant d
the goal is to find the solution to e
meaning an assignment to all the
and variables
that basically zeros
all the monomials all the polynomials
now for d equals one
the system is a linear and can be solved
in a polynomial time
using gaussian elimination
however the problem is npr'd already for
quadratic equations even
for
the specific field of f2
now in terms of prior works
uh start the standard technique to solve
polynomial systems is to find a
convenient representation of the ideal
generated by the polynomials usually in
the form of a grommer bases
and it should it should be said that the
complexity analysis of such algorithms
is typically heuristic
on the other hand at soda 2017 luxtand
of
ital presented the first worst case
algorithms with exponential speedups
over
brute force for solving polynomial
systems
now these algorithms were based on the
so-called the polynomial method in a
circuit complexity
which is basically a technique for uh
proving uh circuit lower bounds
that has uh recently
been applied in algorithm design
now this work we
will be
mainly interested in solving polynomial
systems over
the field f2 so the problem is basically
the same but now we're specializing
the field to be f2
and as i already mentioned the problem
is np hard even for quadratic systems
in fact assuming the exponential time
hypothesis
there is no sub-exponential
algorithm for the problem
however it is still a fundamental
problem in computer science
and it's widely studied in cryptography
especially in the domain
of multivariate cryptosystems
this slide will summarize the most
relevant prior work
in the 2010 ebuyaguet al
presented
an optimized exhaustive search algorithm
for
the problem with very detailed
complexity analysis and the algorithm
was shown
to run
very fast in practice
in the year 2013
bardet allen presented
an algorithm which is based on a hybrid
between exhaustive search and linear
algebra the complexity of the algorithm
was at the order of 2 to the
0.79 n
and then later at 2017
zhu and pizza presented another variant
of
the hybrid algorithm
it had no
detailed complexity analysis but it was
shown to run quite fast in in practice
and what about the polynomial method
algorithms so the paper that i already
mentioned from 2017 by luxtana vital
it had the
complexity for quadratic systems for
solving quadratic systems of
the order of uh two to the
0.87 n and they also
have an extended analysis for a larger
degree now this uh
algorithm was uh improved in 2019 by
brooklyn the cascan williams to run in
the time which is at the order of
two to the
point zero
zero point eight
uh
zero four n and again
they had an extension for a larger
degree and in 2021 this algorithm was uh
was uh further improved
now in this work we'll be mainly
interested in a concrete complexity
of
solving f2 equations
and now what i mean by concrete is
[Music]
non-asymptotic meaning the complexity
analysis should have no hidden terms now
this type of uh analysis is relevant for
uh choosing parameters for uh concrete
cryptosystems
in terms of uh prior work
so i already mentioned that uh these two
algorithms were shown to run
fast in practice
and the algorithm by berdataal
was analyzed by the authors and
they estimated that it beats a a brute
force
for uh
instances uh with n
uh at least 200 now these are quite
large ends instances but still they are
uh relevant for cryptography
now in terms of the
polynomial method algorithms uh
unfortunately the complexity analysis of
previous algorithms was entirely
asymptotic but if you
look uh
deeper into these algorithms uh you will
it's not very difficult to see that
these uh
that this asymptotic
notation hide quite large
hidden constants so it's not really
expected that as they are these
algorithms
will be relevant for cryptography
the main result of this paper is a
concretely efficient polynomial
method based algorithm for solving
equations over f2
and the complexity of the algorithm for
random equation systems measured in
terms of bit operations is n squared
times 2 to the 0.815
n for quadratic systems and there's also
an extension for
a larger degree
unfortunately there is a
obstacle for obtaining a fast practical
implementation of the algorithm which is
a high memory complexity which is
roughly 2 to the
0.63 n for
quadratic equations
now this algorithm seems to beat
previous works in terms of concrete time
complexity for
many interesting
parameter ranges
but as i already mentioned it's
downside the downside is that it
currently has no
fast practical implementation
here's a complexity for uh some specific
instances you can see that for quadratic
systems the algorithm
beats exhaustive search in terms of time
complexity
starting from fairly small values of n
say n equals 80 or smaller
and perhaps a bit surprisingly it also
beats exhaustive search in terms of time
complexity also for a
larger degree say degree equals 4
starting from
n equals
100 or so
the main application of our
algorithm is encrypt analysis of the
picnic
signature scheme
which is an alternate third-round
candidate and the post-quantum
standardization project
uh currently being run by a nest
and what we show is that some instances
of picnic 3 did not
achieve their claim the security level
you can see this from this table so the
larger instances
with the claim security level of 196 and
255 bits
um so our attack is uh
in terms of time complexity as a
is below the claimed security level of
course the attacks also can consume a
very large
amount of memory but the
security claims were only formulated in
terms of the time complexity
next i will give some background
then
i will
give an overview of the algorithm and
finally i will conclude
let me uh
first define some notation so
i'm going to use capital letters
for symbolic variables
and the lowercase letters for
assignments to these variables
as an example uh here's an equation
system e
with the n equals
n equal
five variables uh m equals uh three
equations
and
algebraic degree of d equals 2.
okay so let me now give
some background about the polynomial
method
given an equation system e consisting of
m
polynomials
let's define the polynomial f
which is the
just a product of m
terms where the i therm is uh
equal to p i of x plus 1.
now let's assume an assignment x is a
solution to e meaning it zeros out all
of these polynomials
and therefore all the terms
of f
are going to uh equal
one and therefore f of x is equal to one
and it's also not very difficult to see
that the other direction holds as well
and this is why uh essentially we i'm
going to call f the identifying
polynomial of e
so it will be kind of useful to analyze
this polynomial f
unfortunately
in general the degree
algebraic degree of the polynomial f can
be as high as d times m because it
contains
m terms each one
is of uh degree d
and this this degree is
basically can be basically too high to
manipulate uh efficiently
and therefore uh what we will do is we
will define
what is known as a probabilistic
polynomial
and we're going to denote the
this polynomial by uh f-tailed so
f-tailed
contains
l terms for some parameter l which is
smaller than m
where the i term
is equal to r i of x plus one
where each r i of x is basically a
random linear combination
of the m polynomials of e
now it's uh similarly to uh to the
previous uh definition uh f tilde is the
identifying polynomial of uh this
equation system he tells which
basically consists of the our
of the polynomials are i
now this f tilde has two uh interesting
properties the first property is that it
approximates f
in the following cell so let's assume
that f of x equals 1 meaning that x is a
solution to the equation system e
and therefore it zeroes out all these
all the polynomials p i of x
and as a result it also zeroes out all
the other or all of their linear
combinations
uh which means that it is a solution to
a
e tilde as well and therefore f tilde of
x equals 1.
now if if f of x equals 0 this basically
means that at least one of these
polynomials its value on x is 1.
and because these ris are linear random
linear combinations of the polynomials
of e it's not very difficult uh to to
prove
that uh with probability at least one
minus two to the minus l
then this
equation system e tilt will
[Music]
at least one of its polynomials will
equal 1 as well and therefore this means
that f tilde of x equals 0 with
probability 1 minus 2 to the minus l
okay so that's the first property that f
tell the
satisfies the second property is that
its degree is relatively low compared to
the degree of f
and this is because it contains l terms
each one of them is of uh degree
d and therefore its degree is at most d
times l and we're going to
to choose this l
such that the degree of f tilde uh will
be uh relatively low so it will be
um
more
it will be more efficient to
manipulate this polynomial
so how do we
exploit this f-tailed
in an efficient algorithm
so the way it's done is as follows we're
going to
define another parameter and one small
which is smaller than n and we're going
to partition the variables according to
uh this parameter so we have the kind of
the most significant
most significant variables
y 1 up to y n minus
n
1 and the z variables z 1 up to z and 1.
now the basic algorithm the basic build
building block that we're going to use
is is the following uh we're going to uh
i'm going to describe it next but uh
the the main idea is to compute
uh expressions of the form u of y
where
u of y is basically a sum over all z's
of f tells applied to y and z
okay so this is basically a function of
y and the algorithm the basic building
block is going to uh compute
um
these expressions for all y for all
possible y's
and it's going to uh to do this
relatively efficiently meaning it's
going to do this faster than exhaustive
search or faster than brute force
which has complexity of 2 to the n
because uh you can
kind of
very easily do this in complexity
roughly 2 to the n just by iterating
over each y independently there are 2 to
the n minus n 1
such wise and for each one of them you
just evaluate
f tild
apply to y and z for all possible z and
then you sum the values mod two so that
this basically iterates over the entire
space and it has complexity
of two to the n but we're going to do it
to do this more efficiently than that
now uh after defining the basic uh
building block the main algorithms that
use the pointer that are based on the
polynomial method
they use this building block in order to
compute the solutions to the equation
system e
now uh i'm going to uh describe to you
how this is done later but the main
intuition here is that if you consider
this expression u
u of y
it basically counts the number of
solutions mod 2 to the equation system e
tilde
when uh this this y uh these variables
are just fixed y and this is because um
f tellt is the identifying polynomial of
e tilde
and when you sum over all z matu you're
basically counting the number of
solution mod 2 uh to this uh restricted
equation system
and uh
you're essentially
counting the parity of solutions to this
restricted equation system
so this kind of gives you intuition why
uh this
this expression relates to the solution
of the
polynomial system
now here's how we're going to implement
this uh basic building block
we're going to consider
this
this u as a polynomial in the symbolic
variables y
now because
u is a sum of uh partial evaluations of
f tailed which is uh of low degree
uh then the degree of uh u is uh because
it's at most the degree of f tilde then
the degree of u is also relatively low
and we're going to exploit that in in
the algorithm
so here's a sketch of the algorithm
the first step is
basically going to interpolate the
algebraic normal form of u as the
function of the symbolic variables y
and the second step we're going to
evaluate
the polynomial
u on all possible assignments meaning
all possible
y's and for both of these steps we're
actually going to use a fast polynomial
interpolation and evaluation
algorithm
so let's uh do a sketch of the
complexity analysis
so the first step
its complexity uh formula involves two
terms the first term uh this
term here
essentially accounts for the number of
monomials in the symbolic representation
of u and why do we have this uh this
number of monomials well basically the
number of variables the number of y's is
n minus n1
this is the number of y variables and uh
um the term here is basically the degree
of u and the
number of monomials and u is essentially
n minus and one uh choose the degree of
uh
a few approximately
and
the second term here is n is 2
to the power of n1 and this accounts for
the fact that in order to evaluate
u at any point at any y we have to sum
over 2 to the
n 1 values of z
so in order basically in order to
interpolate
the algebraic numeral form of u we have
to evaluate uh this
we have to evaluate this expression
for this many values of of y
and this uh explains uh this first
uh
the the complexity of the first step
as for the second step we're evaluating
u on all possible y's and there are two
to the n
minus and one such wise and this
explains the complexity of the second
step
now if you select the parameters
carefully uh you can balance these two
steps
so that each one of them its complexity
is smaller
than
uh 2 to the n
which means that the overall complexity
of the algorithm is a
is a
is faster than 2 to the n as a as i
promised
now polynomial method algorithms use uh
such parity computations use the s basic
building block in order to output
solutions to the equation system e
now one of our main contributions in the
paper is essentially a simpler and more
efficient way
of computing solutions to the polynomial
systems from such a parity
computations and this is what i'm going
to describe next
now i'm going to give an overview of the
algorithm
remember that we have our equation
system e
and
we've defined the polynomial f
called it the identifying polynomial of
e
we've also defined the
probabilistic polynomial f tild which is
the identifying polynomial of the
equation system e tilt
previous algorithm solved e by defining
and manipulating many independent
probabilistic polynomials that
approximate f
and this resulted in a large concrete
overhead
a simple observation that we're going to
use is that each solution of e also
solves e tilde because
if x zeroes out
all the polynomials of e then it
obviously zeroes out all their linear
combinations r one up to r l
and the algorithm is going to use this
uh basically by iterating over all
solutions of e tilde and checking if
each one solves e
and
this in this way it is a sufficient uh
to find all solutions of e
it remains to describe how to iterate
over the solutions of e tilde
we're going to use a variable partition
so for n
1 smaller than n we're going to
partition the variables x into two sets
the ys which are the most significant
bits and the z's which are the least
significant bits
i'm going to set the parameters such
that for each value of the ys there is
an expected number of a single
value for the z
such that yz is a solution
to e-tilt
and if you do the calculation then based
on some randomness assumptions uh we
need to set l to be roughly equal to n1
but i'm not going to use this in the
remainder of the presentation
so assuming we've set the parameters uh
so that this property holds now the
algorithm is a basic uh divide and
conquer
algorithm
and it works as follows so for each
value of the y's the most significant
bits we're going to fill in
the say single value of z such that y z
is a solution to e tilde i'm going to do
this by some parity computations
now we have a solution to etel then we
can test it on e and if it satisfies e
then we can output the solution
so it remains so describe how to fill in
this value of z for each y
recall that u
evaluated on y
counts the parity of solutions to
the equation system e tilde restricted
to the specific value of y
now in fact it turns out that f y prime
z prime is the only solution to e tilde
restricted
to y prime
then you can use n1
tweaked parity computations of a very
similar type to to you in order to fill
in the n1
bits of z prime
i'm not going to describe exactly how
this is done
and you can look it up in the paper
okay so that was a this is kind of a
sketch of the
divide and conquer algorithm and let's
try to sketch the complexity analysis
so the complexity of iterating over all
y's is a 2 to the n minus n1
so if you want to just
optimize test complexity then the step
then you will set n1 to be roughly n to
be
very close to n
however this is not a very good idea
because remember that the parity
computation uh cost
n one
n minus n one choose uh the degree of u
times 2 to the n1 and if you choose n1
to be close to n then this
term will explode and in fact it
if you uh
if we remember the degree of u
also depends indirectly on n1 because it
depends uh on the degree of f tilt
which is roughly d times l and l
again if you recall is close to n1 so if
we
uh if we set n1 too high then also the
degree of fuel is going to be relatively
high so the conclusion from this is that
uh
we cannot set n1 to be very high and we
need to choose it carefully in order to
balance the complexity of iterating over
these u's and the priority calculations
finally let me conclude the talk
so i sketched a concretely efficient
polynomial
method algorithm for solving f2
equations
and in the paper we have additional
contributions
for example we reduce the memory
complexity of a naive implementation of
the algorithm by an exponential factor
unfortunately it still remains
relatively high
furthermore we optimize the algorithm
for breaking concrete cryptosystems such
as picnic
so there are several open problems that
remain
for example can the algorithm be further
optimized
and in particular can it be optimized
for solving over
defined systems in which the number of
equations is much
larger than the number of variables
finally it would be very interesting to
have a fast implementation of a variant
of the algorithm maybe a variant which
uses time-space trade-offs
so that's all thank you very much for
your attention