[Music]
ladies and gentlemen welcome back to the
auction
please everyone give a warm welcome to
our two bidders from web3 foundation
switzerland jeff
and from ibm research also switzerland
lucca
and now let's discover today's auction
item please admire this rare piece of
beauty this unique totally non-fungible
piece of art a picture of a dog
expressing profound statements on life
love and death
well actually just a url the points to a
place on the internet were someone's
story in the jpeg
marvelous
luca jeff are you excited to be on this
fantastic masterpiece
yes
let me recall the rules this is a seal
bid auction and thanks to crypto you
will not have to trust anyone but
yourself
each one of you is going to
cryptographically commit to his bid
later when i tell you you are going to
open the commitments and we will learn
who wins the item
all right
to start gently this is a second price
auction the highest bidder wins the item
but he only plays the price of the
second highest bid
do you understand
marvelous
jeff luca are you ready
please show your commitments
ladies and gentlemen a round of applause
and now let's open the commitments luca
will you please reveal your
[Music]
one million iucr coins
wow
that's some bid great job luca and now
you jeff will you please reveal your bid
jeff
may we see your bit
no
ladies and gentlemen what a shocker
we are the winner congratulations luca
the pictures is yours please do not
forget to pay the million isrs before
you leave
what do you mean you don't have them
the auction is invalid i don't think so
luca we also you bid 1 million iscr's
congratulations
jeff
who's jeff
second prize
i don't see any other prize you're so
funny luca thanks for participating but
now we must go on with the show please
do not forget to pay the million when
you go bye bye
[Music]
and that my friends is what happens when
you try and run auctions without a
trusted party
now this seems to be a difficult problem
jeff
how do you run a
auction
if you cannot force the parties to open
their commitments
this seems like a problem that may be
solved by npc maybe
yeah nbc sounds hard maybe instead of
some kind of timed commitment and
perhaps instantiated with the timelock
puzzle
uh-huh time commitment but this i guess
you mean something like a commitment
which after some time it opens itself
yeah yeah um except that the you
the commitment isn't just going to open
itself somebody will have to do the
opening oh and so this is where you use
the timelock puzzles can you see a
little bit more how you want to
construct this yeah so the the timelock
puzzle it's a you someone constructs a
puzzle that they're a cryptographic
puzzle that they
have they believe they have a good idea
how long it takes somebody to solve and
also where
as a process of the construction they
understand what the result will be and
then they can encrypt to that
oh i see so that would give you a way to
encrypt your bit using the solution to
the puzzle and then
the other participants will need to
solve the puzzle in order to decrypt
your bit that sounds very smart but
is this going to scale too many
participants
no not really because they'll it's the
same amount it means all this work for
each participant
well that's that's a bit crazy if we
need to run options with thousands of
participants
um
so what other solutions do we have there
um ideally if we want this thing to be
scalable we have just one new puzzle for
everybody
ah that's interesting
i recently heard about homomorphic time
lock puzzles or you have this idea where
you have many puzzles and you can
without solving them combine them
homomorphically to a new puzzle
uh which encodes the solution to the
homomorphic circuit so for example here
we could have everyone
encrypt the bit uh inside the puzzle and
then we run the maximum circuit on the
puzzles homomorphically what we get in
the end is a puzzle which contains the
solution to who's the winner of the
option so maybe this could be a solution
so um yeah maybe
computing the maximum in the in a
circuit sounds quite expensive well what
you maybe there's some other way that we
can have how you know create a puzzle
and and have the
and then extract the key from it later
so you're suggesting something like we
want to encrypt to a public key
now and extract the secret key
later
yeah
so this is something that sounds a
little bit like identity-based
encryption right because in
identity-based encryption what you do is
that you can encrypt to an identity
and even if the secret key is not there
yet uh eventually the master
the the truck the master authority will
produce the secret key associated to the
identity yeah let's go over what
identity-based encryption looks like so
in identity-based encryption you have
these four algorithms
you have keygen which
generates the master public and secret
keypair
and then you have encryption which runs
kinda like normal encryption but where
you will encrypt
using the master public key pair and the
identity you want to encrypt to
and now
to
in order to decrypt you first need to
extract the secret key from the identity
so this is the operation that is called
extraction and that can only be
performed if you know the master secrets
and then once you have the the extracted
secret key you can take a cipher text
the public master key and the extracted
secret key and you can get back the
message so if this so if we can do it if
this extract operation
is slow and doesn't require any secrets
huh that's interesting so yeah we would
just need a slow extraction and then
maybe everything can be public
cute we could call this delay encryption
all right well let's dig into bona
franklin ibe because that's one of the
simplest ones
yup that's a good starting point indeed
so let me recall bonnie franklin needs
sending a pairing based scheme
and so you have these two bearing groups
generated by say g1 and g2
your
master key is your is a usual elite
curve key pair so you have a secret
scaler call it m and a public key which
is m times g2
and now when you want to encrypt what
you are going to do is you are going to
play it like a key encapsulation method
so
the pairing will produce some
secret which are then going to use to do
a symmetric encryption
and so what you want to put in the
pairing is on the one side the master
public key so m times g2
and on the other side you want to put
something that's related to the identity
so what you will do is that you will
encode the identity to analytic curve
point
and then apply a secret
random scalar which is going to be an
ephemeral sequence and so call this u
for example
and then this gives you the symmetric
key to use
and then you also produce a ciphertext
which is going to be the ephemeral u
times g2 and this is you are going to
send to the decrypter
and now for decryption you just swap the
rules of the secret u and the secret 10
inside the pairing equation
so on one side of the pairing you will
put the ciphertext u times g2
and the on the other side you need to
put m times the identity
so this is something that can only be
done by
the one who knows the master secret and
so the extraction will consist in
computing just a scalar multiplication
master secret times the identity so this
extraction operation is very very fast
which isn't what we want but there's a
there's an isogeny based verifiable
delay function
that
where the verification equation looks
like bls except
that the the
the actual
you know delayed compu the slow delay
computation
is evaluating a long sequence of uh of
isogenes and this replaces the scalar
multiplication
huh that's uh
that's a very cute idea indeed so you're
using the fact that scalar
multiplication are very fast but
isogenous you can make very long chains
of isogenys which can be as low as you
want and which
essentially behave a little bit like
scalar multiplications particularly are
compatible with elliptic curve pairings
so let's see if we put in the ebony and
franklin the esogen here instead of the
extraction will
our secret instead of being a skater
will be a nisogeny a long chain of
esogenics which is going to be slow
so to derive the master
public key you will you will apply this
long sequence of exogenous and then
extraction will be again applying the
long sequence of hexogenesis to the
identity
encryption will still be fast because
you don't need to apply the esogenic you
just use something that was completely
the key generation and now all you need
to do to make this work is that you just
don't make anything secret like the
esony can be public because
you need to just
run the evaluation there is one thing
that is somewhat secret the the identity
of the auction
has to be uh has to be secret our house
has to come into existence be discovered
when the auction starts so
there there's the the timing of this
randomness is important
hey these guys apparently just
discovered a new primitive uh and they
seem poised to put us auctioneers out of
work
but so what exactly is this delay
encryption primitive
the analogy with ib runs even deeper
than it may seem at first sight
in ibe you have this extraction function
which extracts the secret key from an
identity
and here in delay encryption what you do
is just that ask this extraction
functionality to be sequentially slow
then all the rest runs exactly like in
ib and um you will just have no secrets
everyone is capable of running the
extraction you don't need any master
authority to do this
but now if we look deeper into this
analogy something interesting appears
ibe is known to of course imply public
key encryption but also in an
interesting way it does imply signatures
the way you sign with ib is that you
encode the message to an identity
and then you extract the secret key from
this identity and this secret key will
be the signature and then to verify you
just encrypt and decrypt to this
identity
now you can try and play the same trick
with delay encryption
um and so first of all of course
from delay encryption you will get some
variance of time lock puzzles the same
way that you get publicly encryption
from ib but more interestingly
you can obtain proof of work from uh
from delay encryption the extraction
will be the work
and the way you verify that work has
been done is exactly the same you will
run encryption and decryption to the
output of the proof of work and now if
you add one more requirement if you ask
the output of extraction to be uniquely
determined by the input
then in this case what you will get is
exactly verifiable delay functions
and so if you um apply this
transformation to bony and franklin ibe
what you will get are bls signatures
and in analogous way if you apply this
transformation to the delay encryption
that these guys just discovered what you
will get is
the defeo masson petite en sanso
verifiable delay function
so this seems all very nice from a
theoretical point of view
the pieces seem to fit well together but
in practice
there is this sequentiality assumption
on chains long chains of small degree
isogenys and
how do we know that this operation
really is sequential
jeff what's your take on this
ah so um
it's uh
so so
evaluating one of these degree two
isogenys in this in this sequence is um
is
uh it means evaluating two degree two
polynomials this is you know these
things can be optimized in relatively
well understood ways
um there's uh
there's also optimizing the finite field
um this is also reasonably well
understood uh so so any
massive shifts it's it's believable that
this could would would come from some
kind of uh
you know fairly major breakthrough and
um you know of course we actually have
to see what people can do in specialized
hardware
yeah and so since you spoke of
specialized hardware um the first thing
that comes to my mind is fpgas of course
how fast do you think it would be in
fpga to run one exogenous evaluation
so the most similar thing that's
happened so far is the if there is the
ethereum's
effort to do
rsa
squarings in an
rsa group of unknown order which is
different from what we're talking about
those they get on fpgas they get down to
25 nanoseconds
um
ours of course will with all lots of
field optimizations and whatever else
you know it will be cons
each multiplication will be much faster
than that but maybe 50 nanoseconds we
will have to see but my understanding is
the field sizes are like the ring sizes
are more or less comparable between rsc
and this yeah this is the the the field
here is is is somewhat smaller but uh is
1500 bits but yeah
that's very interesting and so
how
um
many like if you are thinking about the
10 10 nanoseconds something like that
how many
isogenics you would need to run through
in order to get a delay of i don't know
one hour for example
so with uh with these kind of
guesstimated numbers so far it looks
like we're we're talking 70 billion
but remember there's a um
each each of these degree 2 esogenies
it has a has a field has a curve
parameter that shows up and each of
these curves is different
and um and this this curve parameter uh
so we're talking something like 12
terabytes to store all of these curve
parameters so there's a there's another
feature of this of this vdf and of the
delay encryption instantiated this way
which is that you need to be pulling
these uh
these curve parameters from memory
and that memory bandwidth
it could either it it could either be
good or bad but if it matches with your
computation speed once both have been
well optimized this is probably good for
the for the vdf because it means an
adversary has to break two things
instead of just one
wow
12 terabytes of storage that's that's
insane so you mean that
maybe not the verifier but the evaluator
needs to store all these data
and every 20 nanoseconds he needs to
take out of the memory one field element
and bring it to the cpu to do the
computation
uh this is an insane amount of bandwidth
this is like gigabytes per gigabytes per
second
um
and
i mean these are not the speeds that you
can reach with just common hardware so
this is a very interesting technological
challenge
um but so
we may try and build the best hardware
for this but how do we know that nsc
doesn't go a hundred times faster
so um any of any sort of delay primitive
whether it's time lock puzzles or vdf or
whatever
should have um a safety margin security
margin
and and this is often ignored
in a lot of papers which is a real
mistake but um the you know if if
if you if you know the evaluator runs at
one speed you you should assume the if
you know the honest evaluator runs at
one speed or sorry the honest prover
runs at one speed then you expect the
um the dishonest prover can possibly run
considerably faster ten times faster
maybe a hundred times faster and this
just needs to be so you have two speeds
you have this this big t speed of the
honest evaluator and this little t speed
of the
of the of the malicious evaluator and
there and and
their ratio is just a thing you need to
bake into the design of the protocol
and
and how confident you are in that ratio
really comes out of how you build the
hardware
okay so if we get back to the auction
example this means that
if you
think that little t is the best the
anyone on earth can do like nsa can do
uh you will need to receive the bids
before this little tea time yeah but
then you will need to wait a much longer
time big t
to know who was the uh yeah little t has
to be a little yeah so um you have
whatever your little t over your your
your ratio of little t and big t is and
then you have to choose little t
large enough for the various network
back and forth messages that your
protocol needs well this is an
interesting technological challenge
but
here there is another technological
challenge these
isogeny based delay functions beat them
delay encryption or verifiable delay
functions
they all seem to need a sort of trusted
setup don't they
uh yes so you
um
we have this one curve uh
super singular curve with j and variant
which we know about and we you know we
we we don't want this to be one of the
endpoints of our vd vdf because
then someone could find uh
could find could compute other isogenes
between different curves that would that
would provide shortcuts um instead what
we need to do is to be is before setting
up the vdf we need to
uh do a random walk in the isogeny graph
and find a
and find a curve
um
uh
and find some other random curve and
then forget the walk so that this curve
has no known connection to the super
singular curve of j in variant 1728.
okay i see so um the problem is really
with this special j environment 1720 a
curve and maybe with other special gene
variants but if i take a random curve um
then it's fine i can run these protocols
and they are assumed to be safe and so
really the only difficulty is that the
random walk between this special
starting point and
the random super singularity curve must
be kept secret and so this is where the
trust lies
so
maybe we can
reduce the amount of trust needed by
doing this in mpc maybe like for example
when you think of of this
like you have n participants and so the
first participant starts from 17 28 and
then walks to some new curve
then the second participant starts from
this new arrival point and does his own
random walk and gets to some renewality
curve and then so on so on so in the end
if at least one of the participants has
been honest and thrown away the
information on the random walk no one
should know the path to the beginning
right yes so the the only caveat here is
you don't want any of these participants
to sort of reset the path back to the
super singular group of jam dragon 1728
so they all need to provide a zero
knowledge proof that they actually
started with the previous guy's curve
uh-huh yeah that's right that's right
that's interesting um and so uh yeah
what what what happens what options do
we have for zero knowledge proofs let me
think
so we have sidh kind of proof of
knowledge
but that first of all i don't think they
apply to this case because sidh curves
are not really set up the same way they
know that the same base field they are
very special
so they're probably not going to be
useful
then we have
seaside
style of proofs like sea sign seafish
style of proofs but also those they are
just limited to curves over the prime
field which is not going to be the case
here so these things are trying to be
post quantum and we don't need post
quantum here
you're right you're right about this so
maybe we can exploit the pairing
equation which are already exploiting
for the delay function and the
verifiable delay uh
for the daily encryption excuse me and
the verifiable delay function so maybe
we can exploit the pairing equation to
prove
knowledge of a secret work
um that seems to be
the way to go actually that's uh that
can be much more efficient than than
every other proofs we have of course it
won't be post quantum but none of this
is quantum
okay that's
that seems to be
a
kind of complete solution to the problem
so
we may really have a new interesting
primitive to explore what do you think
yeah
okay that's um that's a nice and
complete solution it seems so we really
have a new protocol to explore and it
seems that as an auctioneer i'm out of
work so i may become a cryptographer now
well thanks everyone for being with us
today and see you at the next delay
conference
[Music]
you