hi everyone my name is nicole aboard and
this talk will be about a joint work
with pearcarbman called fast
verification of masking schemes in
characteristic 2.
so first a little bit of context
so we want to make crypto
implementations on observable devices
and more specifically we want to do
secure finite field notification uh in
presence of leakage
so such operations are often used in
non-linear components in similar crypto
for example in s-boxes
and in such components the input and
output are usually secret
and so we want to protect the
implementation against an attacker that
can observe the device and leak
information during the computation
that are
so called side channel attacks
to do so one possible contour measure is
to use masking which is to split a b and
c into shares using a secret string
scheme
for example we can use an additive one
here we have the original value x
that will be split into
d plus one shares the x i
such that the first d shares are taken
uniformly at random
and the last one x d is
computed
such that the sum of all the shares is
equal to x
then
we want to compute the operation so the
multiplication over the shared operands
to obtain a shared result
and we want to do so while ensuring that
no information can be gained on either a
b or c during the computation
um so here is the first attempt at doing
so for the multiplication so we define
ck as the sum of l all the ak bj
for all j
here is the corresponding circuit for uh
for g for yeah for d equal one
um the problem here is that any single
ck is actually revealing information
about b for example if c1 here is
non-zero then we are sure that b itself
is non-zero
so intuitively this strategy is not
secure and now we will see
how to modalize this
to formalize this into the probing
security model
so
first some quick definitions so what we
call a gadget for a given function f
is in fact a circuit that is working not
on the input of f directly but on the
sharing of the inputs
and this circuit is also outputting the
share
a shared version of the result
the circuit itself is described as
arithmetic gates and also some special
gates
providing additional uniform random
values
during the computation
here this equality is just stating that
the circuit is actually computing the
right function f on the under shared
variants
then on on such a gadget we can have
some probes that are just mappings
that
maps a given wire to the value it takes
you during the execution of the gadget
and so in 2003 ishai scion wagner
introduced the concept of d privacy
d private is a property of a gadget
so a gadget is said to be deprived when
every set of less than d probes on this
gadget
is independent is the distribution of
these probes are independent from the
unmask values on which the gadget it is
evaluated
so
in the same paper in 2003 they designed
d private masking schemes for ned
which has quadratic complexity in the
order of the masking
this complexity
is both in term of the number of sums
the number of products
used but also in the number of
additional random masks used during the
computation to make sure that the
the gadget is secure
here is an example of
such a gadget multiplication gadget at
order d equal one
so
first we have the the sharing of a and
the sharing of b we make the tensor
project between the
these two to obtain all the aibj
and here we see that r0 is an additional
random value that
is used to ensure that the circuit is
deprived
as output we have
c0 c1 which is a valid sharing of the
product of a and b
here is another multiplication gadget
but this time
secure at order d equal three so it's uh
three private
from uh but at al in 2017
and as before we are doing this first
the tensor project and then we use
additional random mask here
there are four random masks
r0 to r3
to secure the gadget
we see that the the complexity of such
circuit is
increasing quadratically in the number
of
of the
in term of d the order of the masking
the main problem about d privacy is that
it is not composable which means that if
we have two d private circuits then
their their composition is not
necessarily the private
so we can't
chain the gadgets
so in 2016 but i introduced
new composable models that are called
non-interference and strong
non-interference
and that that are based on the
simulatability property so
simulatability
is a property of a given set of probes
here p
and so this set of probes is said to be
t simulatable
if for a fixed input sharing
of the x
the distribution induced on this set of
probes by the additional random masks
can be simulated perfectly with the
knowledge of
of less than t
share
less than t-shares for each input
okay
so from this simulatability property
we have the this non-interference and
this strong interference
so we say that a gadget is a dni if and
only if
any set of atmos d probes is
dissimilable
for the strong interference it's a
little bit different
um
because we are uh
regrouping the the probes into two sets
one that are on the input
on the internal wires of the circuit
and
some probes that are on the output wires
only of the circuit
so
we say we say that a gadget is dsni if
and only if
any set of d probes where we have d1
probes on the internal
wires and d2 probes on the
output wires
and this set of probes must be
d1 simulatable
what is
useful with these security models is
that first
it's imply
they implies they imply
deep privacy
and also most importantly under some
independence hypothesis
the composition of a dsl dni
gadget with a ds91 is itself dsni
so
thanks to this property this composition
we can
compose different
small gadgets in order to create a
bigger
secure circuit
but now we need to
check the security of uh
in the security of a given gadget in
this model for example if we go back to
this
circuit this gadget
we
i said to you that it is d private in
fact it is also dni but to prove that
this gadget is dni
in absence of a generic proof
we need to check that for every
set of less than d probes
this probably similar to the problem is
that the number of sets of probes
is
is growing exponentially in the number
of
of a wire
so
to check a given gadget given masking
schemes uh when we don't have a generic
proof
we want
first an easy to check condition for the
simulatability of a given set of probes
uh
and
most
and also if we want to have gadget over
f2 we want this easy to check condition
to be valid
over f2
and then once we have a condition that
is easy easily
checked
we want to efficiently enumerate over
all the subset of probes
and
to
for this to be efficient also we'd want
the set of probes uh to be as small as
possible to reduce the exponential
to mitigate the exponential growth of
the of the number of
sets of probes also here i will talk
about dni but we also want to check the
dsi property
and
also we
we
can
think of
extending the verification in a more
hardware oriented model called the
rubber spring model but we will not show
here this here but it is
written in our article
so um yeah so for the easy to check
condition first
so in 2017 uh ballet that all produced
this condition uh which applies to
billionaire probes
so billionaire probes are just
probes that can be
expressed as the sum of some aibj
some ai
some bj
some additional random masks called r i
plus eventually a constant
in general in in in the masking schemes
we are going to look at all the probes
are built in there are so everything is
good
so a set of probes is said to satisfy
this condition
if and only if it exists a linear
combination of those probes that can be
expressed
only as
some aibj some ai some bj plus some
constants
and so no additional random masks r
are
appears in this expression
additionally
we want that the the all the rows of
this block matrix are non-zero
or all the columns of this block matrix
are nonzero
why we want that
we want that be because um
this
this means that if there is no
uh zero row in this block matrix it
means that
the the the linear combination
functionally depends on every shares
on all the d plus one shares of
a
here
if we don't have any
zero column it means that
the linear combination functionally
depends on the on d plus one shares of
b
so from this condition we can
state a theorem
which means which state that
if a set of probes satisfies the
condition then it is not d simulatable
so if it is not d simulatable then it is
an attack against the dna property
and the converse is true with the
constraint
because if the the set of prop is not d
simulatable and the size of the finite
field is strictly greater than d plus
one then we are sure that it satisfies
the condition
as a corollary uh if the the the finite
field is sufficiently
the size of the the finite field is uh
sufficiently big
then
if no set of less than d probes on c
satisfies the condition then we are sure
that it is dna
so
from this corollary we can
have a direct algorithm
to
to to check the dna property of a given
gadget
the problem here is that if we want to
to check a gadgets that work
on f2
then
this constraint is not met and then
we can't use this theorem and corollary
so we are going to
state a slightly different condition
that is uh it is
the same as the previous one inst but
instead of having
um
but instead of saying that
all the the rows must be non-zero here
at least l plus one
rows must be non-zero
or l plus one
columns
where l is the number of probe on our
set
so we take a set of uh
of l probes
and if we we can
[Music]
we if we can find a linear combination
such that
this linear combination does not depend
on on
any additional
random value r
and
it depends on
it actually depends on more share
than the number of probes in the set
then it's set to satisfies condition 12.
as before we can define a theorem and a
corollary
that state that if we have a set of
probes of l probes that satisfy the
condition
then it is not as simulatable
and if
the set of probes is not dissimilable
then there exists a smaller
set included in the first one that
satisfies the condition
and as a
corollary
if no set of less than d probes on c
satisfies the condition then it is a dna
so thanks to this corollary we can
design an algorithm that will go over
every set of less than d probes
check if it's satisfied condition 12
and at the end if no one satisf no no
set of probes satisfies the condition
then we have proven the property the dna
property of the gadget
that's what we are going to do and to do
so efficiently we will rewrite the
condition
in terms of weight of indicator matrices
the the matrices that indicate the the
functional dependence on the aibj the ai
the bj the additional random
ri
etc
and so we will use
a vectorized instruction
during the implementation to compute the
the matrices and the weights uh very
efficiently
and also we will use a combination gray
codes
to efficiently enumerate over all the
subsets of probes so to go from one
subset of props to the other with the
with the
list
computation
possible
at peak performance on a
single thread and a
thread at 2.6 gigahertz we are able to
check around 200 million
subsets
by second
and because we use combination gray
codes
we can easily parallelize the the
computation
by enumerating different um different
enumerating the space of all the subsets
of less than d probes
in a parallel parallelized way
so as a result
of our contributions uh we have
a new condition for the dni and also the
dsni security
of the small fields we are we are not
constrained by the size of the field
we also have a new algorithm to check
the dni and the sini property that is
valid over f2 it is correct over f2
and
this algorithm is implemented as a
publicly available tool
to to check the the security of gadgets
um
and this tool uh improved the
verification performance by
three orders of magnitude
so for example
for eight is nine verification
uh
with the state-of-the-art tool it took
13 days on four threads
and with our tool it took less than
10 minutes on a single thread
with our tool we were able to
verify the the ni and sni property of
concrete masking schemes
up to order d equal 11
where it was previously verified only to
order 7 and lower
we were also able to disprove a
conjecture by about at all on the
security of generic transformation
of any gadgets into sni gadgets
in fact this conjecture is
well the the
the generic transformation is correct
until a
given order
above which it is no longer correct
and then
we also used our tool to design new
masking schemes and to verify them
straight away and
thanks to that we are able to
to have masking teams at order g equals
which take 17 less additional random
masks
so if you want to read more about it you
can read our article
which full version is available on
eprint
this version has
additional examples and figures
and the implementation of our tool is
publicly available on my github
so you can check this out too
thanks for listening