so hello everyone
uh
the title of this work is improved
linear approximations to our ciphers in
attacks against cha-cha
uh
joint work uh
of myself
murillo coaching and uh sosanato
we are both researchers
at the research and development center
for communication security
in brazil
so let's start talking about uh the
string cipher cha-cha
um
the cipher was proposed by bernstein
2008 as an improvement of the string
cypher salsa which was one of the
winners of the stay stream competition
chacha consists of a series of arcs
operations additional rotation and xor
on 30 32 bit words and it is highly
efficient both in softer and in harder
and as everyone knows
churches heavily use it it's one of the
cypher suits in the tls for example use
it on on chrome android um and protocols
such as ssh noise
and vpn applications such as wire guard
and actually also the pure energy
and linux kernel
newer linux kernel
so
of course as
charge is very important and then it's
it's also important to to understand
very well its security
and these are the the the main uh
results of cryptanalysis of the
reductions
of south of chacha and
as you can see here
uh this work improves
the the tracks for six rounds and uh
seven rounds of course in the case of
the attack for seven rounds
we have a trade-off on time and memory
but
it's also the first work in which we can
and we developed some linear
approximations which
can get up to the the seven heart
cha-cha as i said is on our side for
and uh it's based on
a function which is called the
quarter hunt function which receives
four integers and
update these integers as this operations
on the left side here and these
operations can be represented as the
circuit
on the right side
also charge is organized as a
matrix is this the state of the the
cipher
on a four by four matrix matrix
and uh
each element of this matrix is an
integer of a 32 32 bit
uh long
integer and the quaran function is then
applied first on the columns
on other rounds and in even rounds on
the diagonals
respecting the colors that i
plotted here in this
slide the initial state of structure and
it's very simple you initialize with
some constants uh
the two
bit key
and uh announce and a counter
okay after talking about cha cha it's
time to talk a little bit about uh
definition linear crypto analysis of
course uh differential cryptanalysis and
linux
are the most important
tools
for cryptanalysis
since the 90s with the work of shamir
behind matsui
and
and so on so
uh it's possible to combine
both of these techniques and then
you divide your cipher into parts which
you will call e1 and e choose two sub
ciphers covering m and l rounds of the
main cipher so you
apply an input different ratio
on the subcipher e1
then you have a transition probability
to another differentiation after
uh those m rounds and then you apply
apply a linear mask
m to gamma out which occurs with
probability
q
sometimes
you cannot actually divide the cipher in
three parts as was done in the work of
barely in crypto 2020 when attacking
cha-cha
and yeah this
is the
to
the basic review
okay so now
we are going to to
to talk a little bit about the line
approximations to our ciphers and more
specifically to the string cipher
cha-cha
so in previous work um
in 2016 should the hurry and matrix
develop a theory for selecting specific
combinations of bits to give a higher
coherence for cha-cha and they did that
by expro exploring the mathematical
structure of the algorithm
and of course as expected the difficult
part is to deal with the addition
operation which is the non-linear
operation for arcs algorithms
first let us define right now that the
function theta of an x and y
is the carry function of the sum x plus
y
so we defined that
theta subscript i
as the f bit of theta x and y
so by definition remember that theta 0
is equal to zero
and then
in
that work in 2016
should here in matrix show that we can
write the quarter hund functions
equations of cha-cha
as these expressions and more
importantly that these equations can be
inverted
so you can represent any bit of the
state of cha-cha
uh in a round m minus one
as a combinations a combination of bits
in
one round
after
so
here you you can notice that we have a
linear part
xor a non-linear part which is
represented as a combination of bits
of carry bits and the function theta
and these are the linear expressions
that we get for cha-cha
and
the important thing here is that using
properties of theta is possible to
obtain linear approximations
for the quadrant function
and in previous works after use the
following result in which we you can
approximate that um theta in position i
has the bit y in position i minus one if
correlation i have
for example
uh take the bit
i
of the word b
and when applying applied in the
quadrant function as we saw in the
previous slide we have this expression
and then we have here a linear
approximation
to the speed with a correlation a half
so
in previous works of crit analysis of
ciphers
outers concentrated and find these
linear approximations
by using these equations for one hand
and repeating repeating
these equations uh for each hound
that you desire to expand
however
uh we showed in this work that we can
actually create a strategy to improve
linear approximations when considering
more rounds by combining the following
linear approximations for theta
the first one is the the one that you
you we saw previously
and the second one is new and
you can see that we have two adjacent
beats
of the of the carry
and
they cancel out to zero with coherential
so for example again consider the bti of
the word be as as we did
some moments ago
then we're trying to find suppose that
we try to find an approximation
to to this linear combination of two
adjacent bits of the word b
so in previous works we we would use the
the the the expansion that we are
showing above here
two times one for this bit and one for
uh the second bit
and then we would get this linear
expression
below
with correlation
a quarter
instead we could use the approximation
that cancel out the non-linear terms
in this case
is easy to see that
the expansion would be
this one so
of course you can cancel out these these
two terms and this leads to to this
linear expression that is not only
[Music]
does not only have fewer terms it's a
good thing when you are trying to expand
further but also has a higher
correlation of a half
so why this is useful against i are
cipher
ciphers because it is possible to reduce
the complexity in several cases
for example a very simple example right
here consider the sum z
equals 2x plus y
if we want a linear approximation to the
beat the seventh bit of z then we can
use the first approximation of the
required function to to obtain
by definition
this expression so this is this is by
definition for the sum of course then
with the first
linear approximation to the curry beach
you get
this expression in which you can see
that
you have two adjacent bits here um
as a given so every time that you use
the first expression you get the second
one from first three three so
in the second round it would be
uh way better to expand
expanding the the the equation using uh
that expression instead of individually
expanding with the the the the linear
approximation for one round
uh
and this works because since the xor
operation will not change the indexes
and the rotation we probably keep these
these two bits adjacent then yeah we can
use the second approximation to to
cancel out the nonlinear terms
and applying this idea
we derived and proved more than 15 new
linear operations for one round of
cha-cha
for example for multiple active input
bits
in route and -1 and multiple active
output bits in rod m the following
linear approximations hold for charger
with probe with correlation one over two
to the power of k
so here we see three three examples in
the chat we have combinations of bits in
a round
so
even combinations of three bits with a
very high
correlation which is which is very good
so using
these results that we proved
in our work we we tried to improve our
own previous work in 2020
and deriving the following in which we
derived the following linear
approximation
so in that work in 2020
uh we showed that this expansion for six
rounds leads to a correlation of 2 to
the power of minus 13.
however we can do better with the
proposed technique
and in fact we present here the first
explicitly arrived approximation range
in three complete rounds of cha-cha and
with correlation two to the power of
minus eight
so this is the extraction it's a very
beautiful expression as you can see
and this was proven in our paper the
proof is there for anyone who is
interesting to to understand
and also
we verify these results computationally
so
um
now the challenge of course uh we had
approximation up to six rounds and in
the the challenge is to try to find a
distinction for seven rounds because in
2016 should we mitre
remarked that x and expansion
for this battery due to seven rounds
would be very unlikely to be useful
indeed applying this this their
technique as they presented in their
work
aggregated correlation for seven rounds
would be two to the power of minus 109
thus using this linear expression of
course
in a different
differential linear attack would be
deter
a distinguishing complexity
very high
no less than g to the power of
436 which is
of course useless
however using our linear approximations
you can get a much better result
and in fact we proved in our prepare in
our paper that the following linear
approximation holds with correlation 1
over
2 to the power of
and again it's a very
beautiful expression um
it's hard to prove
but
we did it and also
verified the results computationally
by
segregating independent parts completing
the correlation
and using the pilot apparently pandemia
to to get the final result
and so yeah using a differential
correlation of our previous work
in 2020
we can
create new distinguishers for six rounds
with complexity two to the power of 51
which is way below
anything um we currently had uh
against chacha
and for seven rounds for the first time
uh distinguishing using the the framing
or work of uh should hoodie mitra
which
she
which was impossible to to get
a distribution for seven rounds now we
have one with complex two to the power
of 224
so
um
we showed in our paper that we can
actually get linear approximations up to
seven rounds
with smaller correlations uh provided
that we can
get a differentiate for three and a half
grounds
so we expect that this
it should be possible to to improve a
little bit for the attacks for anyone
that is interested so these these were
the the main results of our paper
and
but we
additionally found some new
differentials
um
as in previous works these differentials
were found experimentally
and to do that we divided the cipher in
three parts as presented in in the early
uh
in crypto 2020
and in that work the author showed that
the following differential
characteristic occurs if probably two to
the power of minus five on average
for the quadrant function of cha-cha
and this procedure is computationally
intensive as some of the correlations
are very small
and to achieve this amount of
computation we use eight nvd gpus
and we actually made
this code publicly available on github
anyone interested can can get the link
in our paper
and
as far as we know
this is the first code uh public
available of
crypt analyzes of charge
and
yeah this is this is the results of the
differentials that we could find for
three and a half
rounds
we should do note uh that uh since the
first version
of this
paper was published several independent
researchers reviewed our results and
code and we would like to thank juan
vasquez who didn't fight and a small
mistake in the code that we made
publicly available it was just a plus
one
and online but
we missed it but actually that
that affected the results of this table
and uh actually they at all
in 2021 independently noticed that the
results reports were not accurate and
computed an alternative version of this
table
so conclusions and future work
this work represented a new technique to
find linear approximations
for our ciphers and applying this
technique we presented new linear
approximations to this tree in cypher
chacha which gave us new and proven
distinguishers
and we expect that the proposed
technique can be used to improve attacks
against similar arcs based designs as
the string ciphered salsa and half
function black
additionally we believe that
maybe possible to improve
further the attacks against charge
um
because
uh as we
we showed
the the
linear correlations for the the the
differential
and position
bit zero of the word five
was higher than the one that you
actually used to to create attack
and the weight
of the linear correlation and the
complexity attack is higher to the on
the linear part thing is in the
differential part
so
maybe someone can find a compromise
there and
it may be possible to improve
a little bit more that talks to charge
using these techniques
so
yes
with that we finish our presentation
here are some references of course in
the paper
we you can get the full list of
references
and we would like to thank everyone that
got to this point of the presentation
thank you very much