hi everyone i'm chris columbia it's a
pleasure to be here today
at eurocrip 21 and present our work
entitled message recovery laser fault
injection attack on the classic macular
descriptor system
this is a joint work with pialowy
kerrell vlad dragoy alexandre manuel and
lillian bosu
so as it's well known most public key
cryptosystems bases their security on
the hardness of number theoretic
problems such as the discrete logarithm
problem or the prime factorization
problem
but actually in 1997 peter shore
showed that quantum algorithms can solve
these problems in polynomial time
therefore they are threatening the
security
of
those public key crypto systems and
actually with the
quantum computer being more and more
realistic by the bay in 2016
nist started the process for
cryptography standards that are quantum
resistance that is
an attacker does not gain any advantage
by
having a quantum computer available
so we are now at the third round of this
process and in the key and encapsulation
mechanism category
four finalists were announced on july 22
in 2020 and one of them is classic
nicholas which is a cryptosystem based
on error correcting codes
so classic machilis as its name does not
suggest is based on the needlewriter
cryptosystem
so for key generation in this
cryptosystem we have three parameters n
k and t
so we first
get the
parity check matrix
h
of a
n k linear code that can
correct up to t errors
then we sample an invertible matrix s
over f 2 of size n minus k
and then we generate the public key h
pub which is s times h times
p which is a random permutation matrix
and so the public key is
hpub and t
t which is the
error correction capacity
of the code
and the secret key sk is
s
h and p the permutation matrix
so now whenever we want to encrypt the
message m
with the public key to get s which is
the syndrome or the cipher text the
first step is to encode m into a
constant weight
vector e so the weight of the error
vector e is
t
and then
we multiply
h by e to obtain the syndrome s and
that's the step we will focus on today
the security of this
uh cryptosystem is based on the syndrome
decoding problem so the syndrome
decoding problem the binary
syndrome decoding problem can be defined
as the following we have a matrix
h over f 2
with n minus k rows and n columns
we have a vector s over f 2 of size n
minus k and we have t which is a natural
positive number
and so the output of the syndrome
decoding problem is a vector x of length
n over f 2 such that the weight of x is
below t
and such that
h times x is equal to s
and recovering
the vector x is known to be
np-hard since the work of their account
in
but actually if we look
a bit further
into this
syndrome decoding problem we
find that it's quite similar to the
another problem which is the integer
linear programming problem
in this problem
we have n and m which are both positive
numbers b is a vector of natural numbers
of size n c is a vector of natural
numbers of size m
and a is a matrix
of
size m n
and so the ilp problem is defined as the
following optimization problem we want
to minimize
b transpose times x
such that
a times x is equal to c
and this time x is a vector of size n of
natural numbers and it's positive
and actually we can draw some
connections between those two problems
because we
have a
matrix multiplied by a vector
on both sides
the matrix is h
at the top and a at the bottom and the
vector is s
for the syndrome decoding problem and c
for the integer linear programming
problem
and actually the con
the
the constraint
for the hamming weight in the syndrome
decoding problem so that the weight of x
should be below t
can be actually related to
the minimization of b transpose times x
as we will see
so what we do now is we define
n
syndrome decoding problem as opposed to
the binary syndrome decoding problem so
we have now a matrix h
of n minus k rows and n columns over
natural numbers
we have
those
the entries of this matrix which are in
fact binary either 0 or 1.
and we have a vector s which is not
binary it's a vector of size n minus k
of natural numbers and we still have t
which is a positive
number and we want to recover the vector
x
which is binary such that
the weight of x is
below t and such that h times s x is
equal to s
and so we have now the following theorem
let us suppose that there exists a
unique vector x star
over 0 1 to the n
with the weight of x star is equal to t
which is solution to the nfdp then x
star is the optimum solution of an ilp
problem
what this shows is that the n syndrome
decoding problem can actually
be solved by a linear programming solver
and so can also be solved efficiently by
a linear programming solver
how so
we simply follow the following procedure
which has for inputs
the matrix h the vector s and t
and so what we want to do is recover x
which is solution to the nsdp
so we set b to be the vector of all ones
that's for the hamming weight constraint
and then we want to
solve the ilp problem using the linear
programming solver
then once we have
x star we will round it to 0 1
because
because of the convergence of the linear
programming solver the coordinates might
not might not be perfectly zero or one
and then if
h times x star is equal to s and the
weight of x is below t then we found the
solution and we return x star
otherwise we say
we written an error saying that we could
not find the solution
so h the matrix and t the having weight
are parameters of the cryptosystem
so the next input that we would like is
to get s but this time we need s to be
a vector of natural numbers of size n
minus k
so that we can be in the
nsdp framework so we need a way to
obtain
this vector uh over natural numbers
instead of over f2 and for this we will
rely on
a laser for conjunction
so laser fault injection is a technique
which was proposed in 2002 by skull
bogatov and anderson
and the principle of this technique is
to shine an infrared laser on the back
side of an integrated circuit so as you
can see here on the left the
integrated circuit must be
um prepared for laser fault injection we
need to have access to the back side of
the die that's not so common
and so then we simply shine
the infrared laser on the
on the back side of the circuit
and because the laser is infrared that
goes through
the substrate and that really it will
reach the active areas of the
transistors and inject faults
inside the integrated circuits
so laser fault injection has been
quite an area of study there's been a
lot of work on this area but recently
laser fault injection was performed in
flash memory
and when we perform fault induction in
flash memory we get the following fault
model we are able to perform monobit
faults
we can only perform bit set four so zero
are turned to ones but not the opposite
and
another aspect of this fault model is
that it's a transient
fault that is
only
performed on data which is fetched from
the flash memory but the data which is
actually stored
remains unchanged so if we fetch the
data again without injecting fault then
it's correct
and what that allows us this fault model
is to
corrupt the instructions whenever they
are fetched
from the flash memory
before they are executed by the
microcontroller so
as an example we can turn the aorts
instruction which is represented here
we can turn it into an add
adcs instruction which is add with carry
by performing a bit set on the
8th bit here so when we perform a bit
set we effectively turn
the addition in f2 into an addition in n
and that's exactly what we want to do to
get the syndrome
in and instead of having the syndrome in
f2
so the
function that we will target is the
matrix vector multiplication that is
used for syndrome computation
s is equal to h times e
so this function is the following we
first initialize the syndrome to zero
and then we go over the rows and columns
of the matrix
and the vector and we perform the
bitwise and between the
matrix entry and the error vector entry
and we accumulate the result
by successive xors
in the syndrome and what we will do here
is we will turn the xor into a plus
so that the operation is performed over
natural numbers and not in f2
so after performing n minus k times n
false during one encryption what we get
is the faulty syndrome s star
over uh natural numbers
so we will now be able to feed this in
this faulty syndrome
to the ilp solver and recover the
error vector e
so now some
experimental results what we use for a
solver is the standard scipy
lp solver that is uh available and so
not a fancy server nothing too optimized
uh and for the parameters of the
cryptosystem we used the one of the
classic michaelis submission to the nist
standardization process so
here we
give the values of n k and t that
correspond to
equivalent bit level securities of 128
196 and 256.
the
public matrix h has n minus k rows and n
columns and it's the parity check matrix
of a random linear code so we insist
here that we use a random linear code we
do not pick any uh
special codes so that we don't exploit
any structure inside the
the parity check matrix and the vector e
is of size n and of having weight t and
that's the one that we want to recover
with with the solver
the first interesting aspect of this
attack is that we only need a fraction
of the faulty syndrome entries to solve
the problem so this the number of faulty
syndrome entries that we need
actually depend on the weight of the
error vector t
the higher the weight the more syndrome
entries we need
but actually when n grows so when we
want to reach a higher
level of security then the required
number of syndrome entries actually
drops
so here if t is of the order
square root of n then
you see that for n equals uh
10 to the three we need 35 approximately
40 syndrome entries but as as n grows we
need less
uh
a smaller fraction of 40 in german trees
and so for the
classic macular crypto system we need
just less
than than 40 percent
faulty syndrome entries to recover the
secret vector
e so that's interesting from a fault
injection point of view because we don't
need
perfect
false
and get the full faulty syndrome we only
need 40 of it to recover the
the vector e
what is also interesting about this
attack is its uh computational
complexity it's
uh quite fast as you will see so on a
desktop computer we don't run it on a
server it's a
standard desktop computer with six cores
running at 2.8 gigahertz and 32
gigabytes
of ram
so here the
purple stars are for the
classic michaelis parameters and
what we see is that the classic necklace
cryptosystem with 128-bit security can
be attacked in less than one second
and
with 256 bit security it can be attacked
in less than three seconds so that makes
the attack very
efficient from a computational point of
view
and another interesting uh observation
here is that if we consider the full
faulty syndrome then we have
an attack complexity which is cubic
with respect to n
so it's
shown here as you can see the
the slope is
cubic but if we only consider the
optimal
number of syndrome entries to recover e
then the complexity is
quadratic so this isn't just an
empirical
observation but just to show that the
the attack is
in fact very efficient
so to conclude in this work what we
proposed is a message
recovery attack
so given the public matrix h pub and the
syndrome s
what we want is to recover the private
error vector e such that s is equal to h
times e
so this message recovery attack is done
in four steps
first of all we perform laser fault
injection during the encryption process
so that we can modify the xor operation
into an addition so instead of
performing
addition over f2 we perform it over
natural numbers
that allows us to get a faulty syndrome
s star over natural numbers
and then
we feed this faulty syndrome along the
public matrix
h pub to the integer linear programming
server
and that gives us the private error
vector
e
in polynomial time
what we would like to
do to continue this
this work is to
try to export this idea to
key recovery attacks instead of message
recovery attacks
we would like to also study deeper the
attack complexity of the full and
optimal cases so that is
try to find out why when considering the
full syndrome we have a cubic complexity
and when we consider only the optimal
number of entries we get a quadratic
complexity
we would like then to
try to extend our attack to other
codebase cryptosystems for which we can
get an implementation on the
microcontroller
then we also would like to
inspect other
fault injection techniques to correct
the instructions because the laser fault
injection attack is quite costly it
also requires quite a strong attacker
model because the attacker needs to have
access to the back side
of the die so it's quite restrictive we
would like to improve on this and
try
cheaper photo injection techniques to
achieve the same goal
and finally we would like also to
look into other types of corruption of
instructions such as turning
xor operations into shifts or other
instructions and trying to define new
challenging theoretical problems
from this
i'd like now to thank you for watching
this video and if you have any question
please feel free to ask them to
the two
my two co-authors who are present
at eurocrypt21 in zagreb
pialui and vlad
thank you for your attention