hello everyone i'm gg li
the title of our paper is new lattice
two-stage sampling technique and its
application of functional encryption
this is a joint work with 100
the outline of this presentation
consists of three parts
background or contribution at all
timings
first let us focus on the background
considering the scenario of a circuit
mass transmission
taking pke for example we always assume
that the receiver is first need to
generate a pair of pks k and then send
the pk to the sender bob in this case
bob can run an encryption algorithm and
send the server type city to alice
finally alice can get message m
from city
through using herself key
we notice that the mine coming of pke is
that it requires a lot of work to do
public key management
in order to
overcome this limitation we can adopt
ibe schemes in this case we need to
assume
authority who view issue mpk total
parties and then baba can
directly encrypt messages
using alice's id
finally alice can decrypt
through using her secret key from the
authority
in order to further increase the fine
grain access control for the decryptor
we can use abe schemes in this case
message
m is encrypted with the receiver's
attribute x and the receiver secret key
is corresponding to a function class
function f
alice view decrypt successfully if fx
equals one or above mentioned
increased games are or nothing still
in order to further increase the final
access control for the encrypted message
itself
we can use function encryption
in this case when decrypting through skf
the receiver can just obtain the partial
information as a fm
so we think of function encryption as
the most advanced inclusions still and
it is significant to construct much
better function encryption schemes
next we recall the syntax of functional
encryption
according to the above generalization of
increment schemes from pke to fe the
regular syntax of fee can be described
as follows first the center of algorithm
output appear of mpk msp second arcade
algorithm take npk msk and a function f
as input at the output
a secret key as kf here f is a function
from mass space to arbitrary b string
third the encryption algorithm directly
encrypts mask m under pk
npk
finally with skf we can get a fm
through decrypting the server test
in fact fve also has a more fine-grained
sentence compared with this
regular one
these fine green centers have the
following difference
first the function f has two different
parts at p and g where p acts as a
predict
whose output is 0 or 1 and the g
is a function of message
second the method m also has two
different parts x and u where x is
viewed as the index and u
the real message load
third for decryption
the decryptor get a key u if
p x equals one and the button otherwise
from above all we can summarize the
difference between regular syntax and a
fine grain syntax in in this way clearly
the uh thus two notions of syntax are
essentially equivalent
this is the money because their function
class can be expressed by each other
in this paper we would like to focus on
the fine-grain syntax
notice that
function does not only capture ib
pe av
naturally but also divided in
secret key and index into
one zero key and private public index
respectively
and this will provide many more
perspectives to promote the current
status
of us
on rve
next we recall the security definitions
of fe schemes
generally
in a secured game for fe after obtaining
mpk from the challenger the adversary
can conduct key extraction and the
challenge queries in an adaptive way
finally
the adversary outpost is some
information offered on the chinese
advertised city in this process we need
to consider the following things first
from the view of the adversary the index
acts of the honest study generated
several times maybe public or private
second
the challenge attribute ice star and
magic star are children by the adversary
in
selective semi-adaptive
or adaptive way
third key is charging queries can be
separated into two parts
pre-challenging query or post john query
fourth
the summary size depends on the concrete
function class of f under the times of
key extraction
queries made by the adversary
for faith
the security
for this interactive game can be defined
in
indistinguishably based or simulation
based way
of course from the challenging message
we need to consider single or multiple
chinese methods
in this paper we might consider two
settings of every year in private index
or probably index
next we first recall on providing data
starting
according to the above statement about
the providing dive setting
the function class of fe is generally
denoted as
p times g
notice that after a careful
consideration it is significant for us
to just focus on
p times i
uh where i is the identity function
furthermore
for security we can consider two types
simulation based or andy based
in case of a profit index we prefer to
simulation-based security and
as it
it gives much more security guarantee
here we give the simulation based some
adaptive
security notice that in the real game
the same adaptive is just with respect
to the challenging text and store
which is children just after
receiving the master public key
then is the ideal game
it is necessary to consider four
simulators such that the real game and
the in ideal game are indistinguishable
then for the case of public index
we also consider
both sim based or id based security
first we are just interested in
anti-based one this is because know that
the indexed x is available for the
adversary
it is more significant to passive
efficiency rather than too strong
security
for the function class we just focus on
the subclass of p times i p where i p
denote
inner product in particular we focus on
ib
times ip and av times ip
more formally the ind based security of
public index of i fe can describe in the
following way
here we use a different color to
indicate the choice of the challenge id
changing challenge index in the
different states in particular they
indicate indicate
the
selective or some adaptive or
unadapted security respectively
next we introduce the current state of
art of art on simulation-based
fee
as we know the prior works have given
many results on
simulation-based ive in particular bsw
and agvw have proposed two lower bound
on the construction of stem fee
for post-challenging queries on the
chart and several sites respectively
so we can conclude that for single
challenging massive case there is no
probably a police team fee here we use
the first poly we indicate the number of
one key query and the second party as
the number of zero zero
zero key query
and then gvw gave a simulation based iv
which has a
strong security guarantee
by the pole efficiency in particular gbw
support q times one key under zero key
queries in both pre and post challenging
steps and
its changing that can be adaptably
children
but
its standard size depends on the
circuit size of f and the cluster is a
multiplicative
uh big o q two four
here we use q to denote the number of
one key
queries
then
gqpv they proposed fe with much better
efficiency but with the cost of
the achieved
security
then ar
agrowa and av
[Music]
also proposed a different same same
based rve
but all those constructions are still
not satisfied
in both security and efficiency so we
want to ask is it possible to further
promote
the security and the efficiency making
simulation-based fee to approach
the existing
lower bound
this is the detailed case of a current
state arc of simulation based ive
so this derives the first mind question
of this paper
is it possible to construct much better
simulation-based fee
next let us see something
on the current state of art on andy
fe for p times ip
in particular
hcgu proposed fe for
ip times ip
from combining ibe and fe for ip but we
know that even even
each building block is a adaptive
security the resulting of the
scheme just satisfy selective security
so we may consider
uh
how to construct
how how to construct ndfve
for av times ip and achieve the adaptive
security
this is the detailed case of the current
current state of art on simulation on
the
rve
and
our second question is is it possible to
construct much better and the best ide
for p times iv
however the mind goes in all paper can
be presented as the following two items
next we start to introduce our
contribution in this paper
the first is a mine technic contribution
on new lattice 2-stage sampling which is
believed to be our independent interest
and may be used in other lattice-based
cryptography
in order to explain our
new sampling process more naturally let
us first recall the existing lattice
lattice sampling techniques
the first is gpv sampling
tpv says we can sample the tuple
matrix a vector you write y into such as
statistically closely
this means that even a random matrix a
we can we cannot we cannot only first
sample
a vector u and then sample
vector y from this criticals and
distribution over largest
but also first sample
vector y from discrete gaussian
distribution
over integers and then
multiply it to matrix a from the right
hand side
the second is abb sampling
abu says that given a short matrix r
the gpv sampling algorithm still works
we can note that in the previous
construction of ebe or pe and even fe
construction from lattices this matrix
are always depends on
which secret key queries the diversity
contact
and the in that case
we require the adversary to first claim
the chinese attribute such that we can
embed the hard problem in the simulated
public key but this will inherently
result in the selective security
so if we want to achieve adaptive
or some adaptable security we need to
consider how to delay the usage of
materials are
in this paper we give
we give a new method to delay the matrix
are in particular
in
stage 1 we first choose
a matrix a and
vector x from the corresponding
distribution and then compute vector u
then in stage 2
given certain
small
matrix r we can sample vector z and
output
vector v in this way
finally the sum algorithm output the
tuple
in
a a times r vector u y
we notice that this tuple satisfy this
equation
is denoted as the sampler tool in our
paper and
it is essentially used in the security
proof
and in the real fe constructions we will
use this variant sampler one
clearly after starting on corroded
parameter thus two operations should be
indistinguishable
then we see or control uh we see our
contribution in fe with private index
positively all results can be divided
into three case three cases single qrv
reusable cable circuit and
multi
overall
all construction has a significant step
forward in the security and the
efficiency relative to the existing
result due to time limit i will not see
too much too many detailed details about
that
from above all we need obtain
significant progress in simulation-based
fe
and our result is quite
approached
the existing lower bound in the security
and efficiency
then for the fev public index
up until now there is just one paper
is acgu that have proposed and the fe
for ib times ip with the selective
security
and
all construction can support ap
times ipv the semi-adapter security
hence all contributions are still
significant just as
a list by this table
next we focus on all techniques
in fact our technique is in is inspired
by that of agua
and we both rely on the notion of pgpe
which means particular hiding
um predict encryption
so that as the first recall algorithm
tiny and then local differences from
them
in particular
these strawberries are
one zero
zero poly selective php and then
upgraded into
one poly very selective php
one poly some adaptive php two poly
summer wpb and
pure poly summer wfe we noted that we
noticed that agua has
limitations in security and sanitized
size
in particular although their
construction is also semi-adaptive
they require the adversary to commit or
one key queries just after no the master
public key
and this means that their construction
will not allow the adversary to conduct
the post challenge
one key queries and there certain size
is growth with
big o q 2 2 in an at that additive way
in order to further improve this scheme
we adopted the technique map as starting
from
zero poly selective php
and then
upgraded it to
a one poly selective ptpe one poly
some adaptive pgp qr poly summer wtpp
and the kilo polyzama wpp
except the
last last step from some adaptive
pdp to some adobe fe we employ several
new techniques for the three steps from
zero poly
selective ptp to pure poly
some adaptive ppe
in particular from zero poly selective
ppe to one poly selective ptpe we
adopted a new
lattice
two-stage sampling algorithm to replace
the corresponding sample algorithm in
approval
from one poly a selected selected pcp to
one poly summary ptpe we adopt a
lightweight encoding by pke to replace
the master of the matter of nesting two
of these schemes
from one poly summative as some adapter
php to qr production ppe we construct
post the chinese simulator
to answer
uh post challenge 1p queries and use a
more efficient car free
stat to reduce the time size growing
speed with q
up until now after putting all above
things together we get the desired
simulation based rve
for the case of andy based
the tiny is quite similar please say
your paper
thanks for your attentions