hi everyone my name is dakshita kurana
and this is the eurocrypt talk about the
paper non-interactive distributional
indistinguishability and non-malleable
commitments
let me begin by telling you about
non-interactive distributional
indistinguishability which is a special
type of proof system
a proof is a way for one party that we
will call the prover to convince another
party called the verifier about the
truth of a statement
traditionally the way we think about
proofs is that the approver writes out
an entire sequence of steps that he then
sends to the verifier who then checks
these steps one by one and accepts the
prover's claim if all these steps check
out
some of the really consequential early
results in cryptography and complexity
followed the realization that proofs
could be
interactive
a verifier could send randomized queries
that the prover would have to repeatedly
answer and only once the approver
successfully answered all of these
queries would the verifier accept the
broker's claim
as usual it was important for these
proofs to be sound which means that if
the provers claim was false then with
overwhelming probability the verifier
would catch the prover in a lie and
reject the move
now one of the most beautiful
consequences of allowing interaction was
that it enabled zero knowledge this
concept was introduced in a seminal work
of gorwasser mikali and rakov and allow
for the construction of interactive
proofs that revealed no secrets to the
verifier
the only information the verifier
learned from such a proof was whether or
not the prover's claim was true and no
associated secrets that the kruger held
were potentially
would potentially be leaked to the
verifier
now zero knowledge proofs have become
the basis for most privacy preserving
proof systems that we use today
and while interaction enables zero
knowledge
interaction is also prohibitively
expensive in situations like ledgers and
blockchains but there are many
participants verifying the proofs of
many others
and thus one of the really important
goals of modern cryptography is to build
privacy preserving proof systems that do
not require interaction
now one could begin by asking whether
zika arguments are achievable without
interaction
and while this is possible via heuristic
constructions that can be proven secure
in idealized models
or if we assume that players have access
to a trusted common reference string
they actually turn out to be impossible
to realize in the plane model when
players don't have access to a trusted
third party
so an important question is can we
achieve privacy preserving proof systems
that are not zero knowledge would
satisfy somewhat weaker privacy
properties and that still suffice for
applications
in the plane model and without access to
trusted setup
there have been some positive results in
this direction
and starting with the work of barack
onwardhan um who themselves built on a
work of work in our
uh as well as subsequent works of growth
ostrowski sahai and bhitansky and panit
obtained notions of non-interactive
witness and distinguishability
where essentially the guarantee is that
the verifier cannot tell which of two
witnesses was being used by the prover
there have also been constructions of
witness hiding arguments most recently
by coic and alan zandri
but these rely on non-standard
assumptions and
not all of them are explicit
constructions
as such there are major gaps in our
understanding of
what it is that we can achieve
non-interactively
what sorts of privacy guarantees are
achievable
from standard assumptions
let's try to better understand what this
gap is with the help of an example
suppose i want to finalize a transaction
say on the blockchain but i would like
to keep the contents of the transaction
hidden
let's say i only have 10 units of
currency in my account so the
transaction should only go through if i
have transferred less than 10 units to
someone else clearly i cannot transfer
more than i have
now
if i want to keep transactions encrypted
i'd also like to be able to guarantee
that i'm not cheating
so i can compute an encrypted
transaction
um
and then without revealing exactly how
much money i am transferring
prove that the amount i transferred is
less than the total currency that i have
in my account
and it's a simplification of this let's
consider approver and a verifier the
prover encrypts a message m and would
like to prove that the encrypted message
is less than 10 but without revealing
what this message is
this is called a commit and proof
argument and for the reason i already
discussed we would like to be able to do
this non-interactively
i mentioned the word commit because this
encryption i was talking about is not
really the right primitive here indeed
the functionality that we need
a commitment allows a committer who has
some secret input m to put this message
m inside a box lock the box and pass it
on to a receiver
later the commitment can the committer
can send a key using which the receiver
can open this box and recover the
message
note that once the box is sent the
committer cannot change the contents of
the box can only later send a key to
open it
now what actually happens is that in a
commitment
the committer and receiver
run a commit phase at the end of which
they obtain a transcript
this transcript commits uh the committer
to a message without revealing to the
receiver what this message is
in the decommit phase the committer
cannot
later change her mind about the message
he committed to the most she can do is
decommit
in a non-interactive commit and prove
argument
approver with input a secret message m
and a public predicate phi
generates a commitment to the message m
and additionally proves that the message
m satisfies the predicate phi
the soundness guarantee is that if the
verifier accepts the prover's proof
then the commitment c is indeed a
commitment to some message m that
satisfies the predicate phi
the privacy guarantee is that the
commitment and proof together do not
reveal the message m
what this means is that for every
predicate
and every pair of messages m1 and m2
that satisfy this predicate the output
of the prover given the first message is
indistinguishable from the output of the
approver given the second message
while this seems like a really
fundamental and necessary privacy
guarantee unfortunately existing
non-interactive proof systems like
navies and witness hiding arguments
do not offer this guarantee
in particular navies do not suffice
because they do not offer any privacy
guarantees and settings where there is a
unique witness which is the case here
and on the other hand witness hiding
offers a much weaker hiding guarantee
than the indistinguishability based
hiding that we desire here
moreover witness hiding is not known at
the moment from well studied assumptions
and so in this work we take the first
step towards rectifying the situation
which brings me to our results
we introduce needy which is a new type
of privacy preserving non-interactive
proof system
we construct needy based on
indistinguishability obfuscation and
variance of one-way functions
and finally we show that needy can be
used to obtain commit and proof as well
as non-malleable commitments that are in
some sense non-interactive
so what do i mean by some sense
well the interaction pattern of the
resulting commit and proof argument is
as follows
the prover on input a message m and
public predicate phi generates a sampler
and sends it to the verifier
the verifier given the sampler runs a
local randomized algorithm on the
sampler and obtains a commitment string
c
we have the usual completeness property
in that
the the commitment string c that the
verifier obtains is indeed a commitment
to the message that the prover intended
to commit to with some randomness r
the soundness property is that either
the verifier aborts
or when it does not abort
the verifier obtains a commitment string
c that is indeed a commitment to some
message m
that satisfies the predicate phi
of course this this guarantee is
randomized and holds with overwhelming
probability over the randomness of the
verifier
the privacy guarantee is that for all
pairs of messages m1 and m2 that satisfy
the given predicate
the sampler for m1 is computationally
indistinguishable from the sampler for
message m2
in other words there is an uh there is a
cpa style hiding of the message m
now let me tell you a little bit about
the techniques that go into constructing
a non-interactive commit and proof
argument
indeed a needy will be nothing but an
abstraction of these techniques into a
clean primitive
recall that the prover in a
non-interactive commit and proof will
send the verifier a sampler that encodes
the provers secret message m and outputs
non-interactive commitments to the
message
when the verifier interacts with the
sampler
the sampler will actually take the form
of a circuit the circuit will have
hardwired a key k for an appropriate
pseudorandom function and will also have
hardwired the provers secret message m
on input nx this circuit will compute a
prf and output a commitment to the
message in order to hide the message the
circuit will be obfuscated via an
indistinguishability obfuscation scheme
as such this will satisfy completeness
and soundness
uh sorry
completeness and privacy
but there is no soundness yet because a
malicious prover could send an arbitrary
circuit that outputs commitments to
arbitrary messages that do not
necessarily satisfy the predicate
therefore in order to achieve soundness
the circuit will actually also attach
proofs
to the provers commitments
the specific proof that we will rely on
is a two message proof of which the
first message will be supplied as input
to the obfuscated program c
and the second message will be computed
by the program itself
the specific construction that we rely
on is one due to pass
where in the first message the verifier
generates the output of a one-way
function and this is an appropriately
chosen one-way function
on a random input and sends it to the
prover and then the prover outputs a
commitment to zero and in addition
proves by a navy that either the
statement that they were originally
setting out to prove was true which in
this case is that the message m
satisfies phi
or
that
they inverted the one-way function
and
managed to commit uh to the inverse of
the one-way function
on the value y that the verifier sent in
the first place
so coming back and zooming out coming
back to our setting of commit and proof
this obfuscated circuit that the prover
sends
will obtain as input a pair x and y and
then in addition to computing a
commitment to the message we'll output
the second message of this
to message proof system with respect to
the input string one
so the next question is why does this
proof system hide the provers secret
message m and why does this provide any
privacy at all
to understand why let's consider a
hybrid experiment where the prover sends
a slightly different circuit that
instead of committing to the message m
has an arbitrary index i hardwired in it
and if the input y is less than the
index i outputs a commitment to m1
otherwise outputs a commitment to m2
and these circuits um
two circuits that have indices i and i
plus one respectively will only differ
on a single input which is y equals i
plus one
and so it turns out that by relying on a
punctuable prf and indistinguishability
obfuscation and some standard techniques
developed in context of using
indistinguishability obfuscation one can
prove that these two circuits that have
i and i plus 1 hardwired in them
respectively are indistinguishable from
each other
and if one
carries out sufficiently many hybrid
experiments in particular
equaling the number of possible inputs
to these circuits then one can show that
um
that a circuit that always outputs
commitments to m1 is indeed
indistinguishable from a circuit that
always offers commitments to m2
this helps establish privacy as long as
the obfuscation commitment and prf are
at least two to the n secure and where n
is the size of input to the program
so in other words we need that
if the size of inputs to this obfuscated
circuit is n bits then the primit the
prf the proof system the commitment and
the obfuscation scheme themselves are
all due to the enzyme this presents some
challenges when proving sadness
um
one would like to say that because of
soundness of the navy if the message m
of the prover does not satisfy the
predicate phi then their proof that the
circuit provides will implicitly contain
an inverse of the one-way function f
and one may hope to try to use
complexity leveraging to extract this
inverse from the proof pi and derive a
contradiction however recall that
we needed the proof pi to be 2 to the n
secure where n was the size of outputs
of the one-way function
and this in particular
prohibits the use of complexity
leveraging just because it's going to
take much longer to extract the inverse
of the one-way function from the proof
and requires us to come up with a new
technique our main idea is to rely on a
different axis of hardness and in
particular we develop a new technique
where we rely on a non-uniform hardness
and also at the same time achieve
non-uniform security
so this is all from standard assumptions
io
and
non-uniform security of one-way
functions
and like i had mentioned previously a
needy is simply a generalization of
these techniques uh to encapsulate
what you can do more generally
uh approver that has input a language l
and a distribution d that samples
instances and witnesses that satisfy the
relation corresponding to the language
can generate a sampler
and send it to the verifier
in such a way that the verifier can
interact with the sample and obtain
samples from the language that means
obtain instances in the language
and be convinced that
that indeed
if the
that
if the verifier did not output bottom
then they indeed did output an instance
in the language
l
and moreover the privacy guarantee
states that for all pairs of
distributions um
that sample instances that are
indistinguishable
we have that the sampler for the first
distribution is indistinguishable from a
sampler for the second
we are also able to use the same ideas
to build a non-malleable or cca
commitment where the extra where the
interaction pattern is the same as
before in that the committer on input m
sends a sampler to the receiver and then
the receiver runs a randomized algorithm
on this sampler
on input the sampler to obtain a
commitment string c
in a nutshell the non-malleability
property guarantees that
a man in the middle that obtains a
commitment
from an honest committer is not going to
be able to generate a sampler that will
produce valid commitments
to
a related message
in particular the guarantee is that the
commitment c prime generated by the man
in the middle
is going to be a commitment to some x
that is independent of the input m of
the honest committer
the reason that needs help in this
setting is that existing non-interactive
cca commitments or non-malleable
commitments have an important tag
amplification component that requires a
commit and proof mechanism
where the committer commits to the same
message many times and must prove that
all commitments are to the same message
and this is exactly where a needy turns
out to be helpful and allows the
committer to do uh to run this process
of tag amplification non-interactively
in summary in this work we build an idi
which is a new non-interactive privacy
preserving proof system that is
applicable in settings where statements
being proven have unique witnesses
and very roughly it guarantees that when
two statements are indistinguishable
then so are the statement plus proof
combinations
this privacy guarantee is morally quite
similar to what strong witness and
distinguishability which is a notion
that's different from regular witness
and distinguishability gives us however
the completeness properties of an idi
are different in that the prover cannot
really control the exact
sample or in our examples the exact
commitment string that the verify would
end up with and the prover can own all
that the approver can do is send a
sampler that outputs a randomized
commitment
and we show in this work that these
techniques have applications to commit
and proof arguments as well as to cca
commitments and we believe that this
notion of a needy may find other
applications in settings where one needs
to prove something
non-interactively while still giving
strong privacy guarantees
that concludes my talk
thank you for listening