hi i'm arshi i'm going to talk about
order c secured multiparty computation
for highly repetitive circuits this is
joint work with gabriel beck abhishek
jain and gabriel capchuk
to begin with
mpc is an interactive protocol that
allows a group of mutually distrusting
parties to compute on their private
inputs
the security guaranteed by any mpc
protocol is that an adversary corrupting
a subset of the parties should not be
able to learn anything beyond the
function that the parties are computing
since its inception extensive research
has been dedicated
towards trying to bring mpc closer to
practice
and as the efficiency of mpc increases
the hope is that it can be used to
compute large complex functionalities
such as training machine learning
algorithms or simulating large ram
programs on massive distributed data
sets
let us now look at what we know about
the complexity of existing protocols
as it turns out most concretely
efficient and implemented protocols have
a total complexity of order nc
where n is the number of parties and c
is the size of the circuit
clearly the work done by each party in
such protocols is proportional to the
size of the entire circuit
and if the circuit is large then no
matter how efficient our protocol is we
are expecting the parties to do a lot of
work
as a result the only parties who are in
some sense capable of participating are
ones that have massive computing
resources
one obvious way to avoid this limitation
is to design protocols with a better
efficiency than order nc
in fact we already have protocols with a
better asymptotic complexity of odorless
but these protocols are not concretely
efficient
in fact the o tilde notation hides poly
logarithmic factors in the size of the
circuit and polynomial factors in the
security parameter
we also know of order c mpc protocols
but only for a special restricted class
of circuits called cmd circuits
i will explain what these circuits are
a little later in my slides
but the problem with these order c
protocols is also that there are no
known implementations of these protocols
so the main question that we consider in
this work is whether we can design order
cmpc for a larger class of circuits
but before talking about how or whether
this question can be solved let's first
discuss some advantages of an order cnbc
protocol
first of all since there is no linear
dependence on the number of players
in the total complexity of this protocol
it can be run with many many parties
moreover when the number of
participating players is large the
honest majority assumption becomes
significantly easier to justify
also the work required from each party
in such a protocol
is proportional to
the order of the circuit
divided by the number of parties
which in some sense means that more the
number of players the better it is
in such cases parties with low computing
resources can also potentially
participate
finally such protocols can also be used
with large-scale volunteer networks that
have recently emerged such as bitcoin
and tor
these networks are already used to
performing incredibly large distributed
computations and it would be interesting
to use them for npc computations as well
this would enable a crowd-sourced
application like mpc as a service that
still respects privacy
such services can be used by clients to
delegate large computations
moving on to our contributions we design
order c mpc protocols for a larger class
of circuits that we refer to as highly
repetitive circuits
we design both semi honest and
maliciously secure protocols that are
secure against static corruptions of a
little less than half fraction of the
parties
our protocols are information
theoretically secure and our maliciously
secure protocol achieves security with
the bot
finally as far as i know we provide the
first implementation of mpc that uses
patched secret sharing
now let me explain what simdi and highly
repetitive circuits are and what's the
difference between the two so simi
stands for single instruction multiple
data
these circuits comprise of multiple
copies of the same sub-circuit
for instance in this example
the circuit contains four copies of the
same sub-circuit
highly repetitive circuits are a
sub-class i am sorry a super class of
semdi circus
but before i talk about highly
repetitive circuits let me define a
class of circuits that we refer to as a
b repetitive
we say that a circuit is a b repetitive
if it has arbitrary number of blocks of
width at least a that repeat at least b
times here we refer to blocks as a group
of gates that are on the same
multiplicative depth in the circuit
for example in this figure this orange
block repeats multiple times and so does
the green one and so does the gray one
this is an example of a 3 comma 3
repetitive circuit
we define highly repetitive circuits as
a b repetitive where both a and b are in
omega of n
where n again is the number of bodies
now this might appear like just another
definition of a subclass of polynomially
sized circuits but but as it turns out
this is actually a very interesting
class of circuits and many known
applications belong in this class
for instance for loops and while loops
in programming languages are highly
repetitive
computations
machine learning algorithms are also
highly repetitive
similarly block ciphers such as aes and
hash functions such as sha-256 are also
iterative in nature and are highly
repetitive
let me now elaborate on how we design
order c protocols for highly repetitive
circuits
the rest of this presentation will be
organized as follows
i will start by recalling some standard
techniques used to design efficient npc
protocols
and then proceed to discuss our main
ideas
starting with a very high level overview
of the approach used in most existing
order nc protocols
these protocols work with a circuit
representation of the function that the
parties wish to compute
and the circuit is evaluated in a gate
by gate fashion these protocols start
with the threshold secret sharing of the
inputs and maintain an invariant that
the parties will hold a sharing of all
the values induced on the intermediate
wires in the circuit throughout the
computation
for edition gates the parties simply add
their shares
since this is a non-interactive
computation it does not incur any
communication
for multiplication gates we assume that
the parties have access to a double
sharing of a random value r
one with respect to threshold t and the
other one with respect to threshold 2t
the parties start by locally multiplying
their shares of the input values and
then mask it with a 2t out of n
secret sharing of the random value r
then exchange these shares and
reconstruct the mast value
finally the parties subtract a t out of
n sharing of the same value r
from this reconstructed mass value to
obtain a sharing of the outgoing wire of
the of this multiplication gate
assuming that the parties already have
access to this double sharing of r it is
easy to see that the communication
complexity incurred by evaluating a
multiplication gate is order n
but how do the parties obtain this
double sharing of r in the first place
so these shares are obtained using a
badged randomness generation process
where each party starts by sampling a
random value
the parties then compute
two kinds of sharings of these random
values one is a t out of n sharing and
the other is a two d out of end sharing
since each party sends these shares to
every other party the communication
complexity of this particular step is
order n square
upon receiving these shares from all of
the parties each party locally
multiplies its received shares with a
hyper invertible matrix or a van der
waal matrix
these are publicly known matrices
that are decided in advance
since the dimension of this matrix is n
cross n minus t
the parties end up with double sharings
of n minus t values
from the properties of these matrices it
is guaranteed that if the parties follow
the protocol honestly then the resulting
double sharings are of random values
that are unknown to any individual party
or the adversary
as a result we get n minus t double
sharings with order n square
communication
which means that the amortized cost of
generating a single double sharing is
order n
therefore the total cost of evaluating a
multiplication gate is also order n
now we move on to recall a tool that is
used in the design of existing order c
and otilla c protocols called packed
secret sharing
we know that using a regular secret
shelling scheme we can transform a
secret into n shares
such that no subset of t shares is
sufficient to reconstruct the secret
packed secret sharing is an optimized
variant of regular secret sharing that
allows transforming a vector of order n
values into n shares
however this efficient representation
comes with a slight loss in the
corruption threshold
the maximum corruption threshold that a
packed secret sharing scheme can
tolerate depends on parameter epsilon
which in turn depends on the size of the
vector that is being shared
similar to regular secret sharing patch
secret sharing also has some nice
homomorphic properties
in particular given shares of two
vectors u n v if the parties locally add
their shares they end up with a fact
sharing a t out of n patch sharing of
the following vector
similarly for multiplication if the
parties locally multiply their shares
end up with a 2t out of impact sharing
of this vector
similar to regular secret stress the
threshold or the degree increases when
we multiply the shares
all existing order c and o tilde c
protocols rely on these homomorphic
properties of packed secret sharing and
the batch randomness generation process
that is used in order nc protocols
in particular let's consider the
following cindy circuit that has order n
copies of a sub circuit of size c
which each takes a different set of
inputs
to compute the cmd circuit it suffices
for the parties to start with a packed
secret sharing of the following vectors
where each vector contains at least one
input to each of the order n copies of
the sub circuit
using this
packed secret sharings
the parties evaluate a single instance
of the sub circuit exactly as in an
order nc protocol
except that now the parties work on
packed shares instead of regular shares
as before the communication complexity
incurred is order nc
however since we are working with packed
shares this protocol allows us to
compute order n copies of a sub circuit
of size c
as a result the amortized cost of
evaluating a single instance of the sub
circuit is order c
while the previous ideas only work for
cmd circuits
dam guard at all and kenkin at all show
that any given circuit can be
transformed into a circuit that is
compatible with batch secret sharing
by embedding routing networks
however this circuit transformation
significantly increases the size of the
circuit to o tilde c
as a result the complexity of the
resulting protocol that uses these
circuits
uh is also o delta c
to summarize all existing order c and o
tilde c protocols use a combination of
packed secret sharing and the batch
randomness generation idea
however as discussed earlier these ideas
limit the scope of order c protocols to
just simply circuits
or
communication instead of just order c
which is clearly not ideal
we now discuss our main ideas behind
uh
moving beyond cmd circuits without
requiring any expensive circuit
transformations
i will start by highlighting some main
challenges in extending extra existing
ideas
uh and then proceed to discuss uh how we
leverage the structure of highly
repetitive circuits to overcome these
challenges
and finally i will also briefly mention
how we achieve malicious security
from the previous discussion it is clear
that in order to
get you know
from the previous discussion it is clear
that patch secret sharing is crucial for
getting savings in the order c setting
let's assume that the parties start with
back secret sharings of the following
input vectors
and now they want to evaluate this
particular circuit
which is clearly not assembly circuit
in order to evaluate the first layer of
the gates first layer of the gates
itself
the parties need to be able to perform
different operations on the individual
elements of a packed secret shared
vector
however as discussed earlier computation
with packed secret sharing only allows
us to perform the same operation on all
the elements of the vector
moreover in order to compute the next
layer we need to be able to realign
vector elements across different patch
secret sharing vectors
this again is traditionally not
supported by packed secret sharing
overall to summarize in order to go
beyond cmd circuits without making use
of expensive circuit transformation
techniques
we need to build support for different
operations to be applied to different
vector elements
and that are packed secretion and for
the realignment of vectors across packed
secret shared vectors
i will now elaborate on how we overcome
these challenges and enable such
computations
starting with how to enable different
operations on different elements of the
vector
let's assume that the parties have
access to patched secret sharings of
some
appropriately correlated masking vectors
given packed secret sharings of vectors
u and v
the parties can start by both adding and
multiplying their shares locally and
masking it with the masking vectors
these resulting shares are then sent to
the parties
this party can now reconstruct the two
vectors
and create a new vector with
appropriately chosen masked values from
the two reconstructed vectors
this party can now also compute a packed
secret sharing of this new vector and
distribute the shares amongst the
parties
finally the parties can compute a
sharing of the unmasked vector by
subtracting the shares of the
appropriate masking vector
clearly this computation relies on the
parties having access to these
appropriate correlate appropriately
correlated masking vectors
one masking vector is used
for masking the addition operation the
other one is used for masking the
multiplication operation and the last
one is used for unmasking the final
vector
this unmasking vector contains elements
from the previous two masking vectors
we can use similar ideas for realignment
of vector elements across batch secret
shared vectors
the correlated masking vectors for this
computation can also be chosen in a
similar way
these two techniques are now sufficient
to compute shares of these vectors in
our original example
since both differing operation and
realignment use similar ideas we can
further optimize this computation by
combining the two techniques to compute
the c and d vectors directly in a single
step
for this computation we will need the
following correlated masking vectors
we need these initial masking vectors to
mask the addition and multiplication
operations
and then we need these correlated
vectors for unmasking the final vectors
notice that the vectors used for
unmasking
uh the final vectors include elements
from all of the initial masking vectors
while it's clear that given these
masking vectors the previous computation
can be done the question that we haven't
addressed so far is how do we generate
these correlated vectors
note that the correlation between these
masking vectors depends on the topology
of the individual layers of the circuit
that is how one layer connects to the
other and what gates are included in
this layer
for generating these masking vectors
with a particular correlation we can use
the same batched randomness generation
idea as before where the parties start
by sampling random vectors and compute a
secret sharing of these vectors as well
as appropriately correlated
vectors
the parties then multiply their shares
uh of these correlated vectors with
either a hyper invertible or a random
one matrix
and as a result
uh the parties obtain n minus t sets of
correlated random vectors
however the important thing to note here
is that all of these resulting n minus t
sets have the same correlation
and these sets are generated using order
n square communication
but since we get order n resulting sets
of vectors where each vector is of
length order n and each of these sets
allow us to evaluate order n gates the
amortized communication for generating
these masking vectors per gate is order
one
but the amortized cost is order one only
if you are able to use all of the order
n resulting correlated sets generated by
the previous procedure
this is where we leverage the structure
of highly repetitive circuits
in particular as mentioned earlier a
highly repetitive circuit consists of
blocks of gates with multiple
occurrences throughout the protocol
since these repeated blocks have the
same configuration they will require
masking vectors with the same
correlation
if each such block is repeated order n
times then we can use all the correlated
masking vectors
uh generated by the batch procedure
moreover in order to get savings from
packed secret sharing we need the length
of each block to be at least order n
as discussed before both of these
properties are satisfied by highly
repetitive circuits
as a result we get in order c mpc
protocol for such circuits
to summarize
the parties start by generating packed
shares of correlated masking vectors for
each unique block configuration in the
highly repetitive circuit using the
badged generate randomness generation
process
these correlated masking vectors are
then used to evaluate blocks of gates in
a layer-by-layer manner using different
i'm sorry differing operations pss and
the realignment process or packed secret
shared vectors
let me now briefly mention how we
achieve malicious security
genkil and all in 2015 showed that most
packed secret sharing based semi-honest
protocols are secure against malicious
adversaries up to linear attacks
which basically means that the attack
strategy of an adversary
a malicious adversary in such protocols
is limited to injecting errors that are
arbitrary linear functions of the packed
secret sharing vectors
this observation has been used in
existing works to design simple
maliciously secure
compilers that transform such seminars
protocols into maliciously secure ones
by running multiple instances of the
semanus protocol and performing some
validation or comparison checks at the
end
similar to the compiler used in 3.0 we
show that we can also achieve malicious
security by running two copies of our
semi-honest protocol
to conclude we designed the first order
cmpc protocols for a class of circuits
that bigger than just cmd circuits we
present constructions of both semanist
and maliciously secure protocols in the
honest majority setting
our protocols are information
theoretically secure
we also provide implementations of our
protocols and to the best of our
knowledge these are the first
implementations of npc
that make use of packed secret sharing
finally we also introduce a new
non-interactive share conversion
technique that allows parties to go from
regular shares of individual values to
packed shares of a vector of those
values
unfortunately due to time constraints i
won't be able to go over this idea but i
invite you to take a look at our paper
on eprint for more details
thank you