is on the nested subset differential
attack a practical direct attack against
luov
which forges a signature in 210 minutes
um this is work by jintae ding
joshua
bishaka
and joshua will give the talk
please joshua
share your screen and mute yourself
okay
sorry i was not um
can you hear me and see my screen
uh yes we can hear you loud and clear
cool
all right so i'll just begin the top
then so in our paper can you can you go
into full screen mode
[Music]
i believe it's up at the top under view
does that do it or am i still not
because i don't know what i look like on
your end
yes that's correct
does everything good
yes okay excellent
all right so
uh in our paper we introduced the nested
subset differential attack which we call
nsda against the signature scheme lifted
unbalanced oil and vinegar by bruins at
all
nsda is an improvement to the previous
attack subfield differential attack sda
both of which make use of the lifting
modification for which l u l u of v is
named
so l u of e is a multivariate polynomial
scheme this means that the public key p
is an m tuple of multivariate
polynomials over a finite field
and we'll say that we'll have m
polynomials and n variables
the private key is a way to compute p
inverse by which we don't necessarily
mean it's invertible but we have a way
of finding pre images but we use that
notation
when you're signing the hash of a
document it's just finding one of these
pre images so if y is the half of a
document the signature x is just going
to be a pre-image of y therefore
verification process just seeing that y
is indeed the output of x
now luv is based on the oil and vinegar
signature scheme which was introduced by
padrin in 1997
and in that scheme
p was the composition of two maps f and
t
f is quadratic it's easy to compute f
inverse
t is a linear invariable map it's used
to hide the structure of f
we then see that if those two maps have
these properties we can find print
images as x is the pre-image of y can be
found by first computing f inverse of y
is w
and the then t inverse w is equal to x
notice that p is also quadratic as its f
composed of t and x is quadratic
i won't go into any details of how euler
vinegar works
in here these are time
now luv takes an oil and vinegar private
key over a small field f2 which is the
finite field of size two and lifts it to
an extension field f2 vr from which it
signs its signatures this allows more
efficient storage of the public and
private keys
and that means the public key p of x has
coefficients only in f2 so alpha beta
gamma or an f2 but it will be a map from
f to c r to the n to f to the r t m
now in our attacks sda and in sda we
rely on the quotient ring representation
of finite fields which means that i take
a base field f2 and an extension field f
to the r i can represent f to the r by
the following quotient ring
where d divides r and g of t is an
irreducible polynomial of degree s is
equal to r divided by d
elements in f2 they are can be
represented by degree r divided by d
minus one polynomials and this
polynomial ring here
now it's more efficient to solve a
quadratic system over that intermediary
field and over the extension so the goal
of both sda and in sda is to tend the
problem of solving over f to the r for
solving over f to the d
in the original sdi attack we looked at
transforming the publicly by adding a
random differentiable x prime and
solving over f q to the d that should be
a two instead of a q
so we defined our new map
p tilde of x bar is equal to p of x bar
plus x prime
and this separated out linear terms for
all powers of t but kept the quadratic
terms contained at t to the power of
zero is equal to one this made the
system easier to solve
what we did is we
decomposed the message y into the
following sum
we each of these are going to be vectors
in the vector space over the
intermediary field and we solve for the
higher powers of t using the linear
terms first
and that's because p tilde of x bar
takes the following shape or we have
these quadratic terms
next to t to the power of zero and a
bunch of linear terms for all the other
powers of t
so we solve for the higher powers of t
using linear terms first and then at the
end solve for the quadratic terms and
this is easier provided it's possible to
do which means do we have
sufficiently many variables
in response the authors of luv proposed
new parameters which in particular made
the degree of the extension field prime
which protects against sda there are too
many linear equations to solve
here's the table of the six new
parameter sets
our attack nsda is against the three
cases when r is equal to seven and it
breaks these completely
so r is prime we are attacking these
parameters here
we'll note that our attacking sda does
not defeat the other three parameter
sets but only the ones when it's r is
equal to seven
so throughout here we're going to have r
is equal to seven
we will construct the sign integer for
the message y piece per piece using
differentials
however instead of choosing the
difference randomly like an sda then
such solve for them one after the other
for r is equal to seven this can be done
in four steps
for our attack to be efficient we want
to always solve no more than m quadratic
equations over f2
at least as many variables as equations
and we have to solve f2 because there's
no other intermediate field t to the v
because d can only be one because r is
prime
throughout x bar will be an
indeterminate point and f2 to the n
and we'll just introduce some notation
here quickly and that
we'll always truncate the um uh powers
of t that we're dealing with which means
if i have just an element of the finite
field i raise this bar s over top of it
i only go to the powers of s
and it's similarly defined for
polynomials and systems of polynomials
so step one of our attack is to look at
that zero truncation of p
and that is just going to be by
definition the original quadratic
polynomials except we're now only
considering them over f2
and we just find the solution to this
system over f2
second
we take that solution of f2 and we add
an unknown differential x bar t
and when you do the arithmetic
you'll get the original y's that you
solved beforehand plus some linear terms
multiplied to t to the power of one
and these are easy to solve so we're
going to let a1 be a solution to that
linear system
the third step is basically exactly the
same except now we're adding a new
differential x bar t squared
and this will give us linear terms for
the t to the power of two we again let
a2 be a solution to that system
and then finally we just uh
look at the system completely using this
uh
differential here
and we'll have three terms for t to the
power of 3 to the power 4 to the power 5
which are linear
and
terms which are quadratic at t to the
power 6
which is
r minus one which is the highest power
of t
for f to the seven
to be considered
we find the solution source s for the
linear system first and then we attempt
to solve the quadratic system over the
actual solution set
and if that is possible we will then
have a signature for our message y
the complexity for the level and prime
was set is actually low enough that we
wait to reform a practical attack
against it we run an experimental attack
against a public key with leveling
parameters and we were able to forge a
signature in 210 minutes
for full details please refer to our
paper
uh thanks and we'd like to
say our appreciation for both the taf
fund nist and the nsf
thank you very much
are there any questions
for for joshua
here in the room
um
are there any questions on uh online i
i'm not checking them
um
okay um
if there's no other questions i can i
can ask one question so um
so you're um
attacking um this lifting mechanism
right
um and um
it's
it's present in all parameters uh of
this luov so so how come that um so does
your attack not not at all give any
improvement for the um parameters that
you say
you don't defeat or is the improvement
that's not significant enough uh it let
me i should probably share my spin again
just to show you it does not
because as we're adding more and more
differentials we get more and more
linear terms for more powers of t
so like for r is equal to 47 we would
just have too many linear equations to
solve to then solve over the final
quadratic equations
so
we have to does that answer the question
or should i
share my screen again
no i think that answers the question
thanks there is also a question in zoom
chat
okay can you can you read it out
sure this this is from alexei uh
uduvenko sorry if i mispronounced that
and it is could intermediate size
constants help or is it futile
i'm not sure what he means by the
question
perhaps
alexei could unmute themselves
um
or not
okay
in that case um i think it's time to to
to thank joshua one more time
and we are moving on to the next speaker
ah one second and
sorry
how do i do this
this is which one is yours
this one
um
cannot go back to zoom
okay
um it's just the last thing i do need to
just share this thing
okay
and now
[Music]
i believe if you go to slideshow
yeah that's there we go
okay
now it should be good so the next talk
is by uh wired buildings and it's about
improved crypto analysis of uh uov and
rainbow
so yeah hello everybody so yeah i'll be
talking about oil and vinegar and
rainbow so what's that those are two
multivariate signature schemes
um the first one on the vinegar is the
oldest one it's invented in 1997 by
pateran
and in the following years there were
some cryptanalysis results then uh
quickly those
attacks dried up and have not really
been any uh real improvements since then
and the good thing about oil and vinegar
is that it has very small signatures and
it's very fast but the main drawback is
that the the public keys can be quite
large for example 60 kilobytes for a new
security level one
and on the right hand side we have
rainbow which is uh basically multiple
layers of oil and vinegar on top of each
other it was invented in 2005 by ding
and schmidt
and it's a bit more complicated but also
has a little bit
smaller signatures
and importantly it's one of the
finalists of the next post quantum
competition
and in my work
uh the main contribution i would say is
that i simplified the exposition of oil
vinegar and rainbow and because of this
this better
understanding of the scheme i was able
to find some new
more efficient key recovery attacks
so yeah these oil vinegar and rainbow
are are based on multivariate trap doors
so
particularly that means your public key
will be a multivariate quadratic map
that looks random so we believe that
it's hard to to sample pre-images for
this function
but um
map is actually not not random there is
some secret information and if you know
this information then you can
efficiently sample pre-images and a
signature is then just like an input s
such that p of s is the hash of your
message where you use some some hash
function that outputs elements in your
in the codomain of your your function
so yeah the only thing you need to know
to understand or the vinegar and rainbow
is how these trapdoors work
and yeah if you look at a typical
rainbow paper for example then you will
have an explanation
like this and if your brain works like
mine then you'll have a hard time
understanding this
and even if you convince yourself that
this is a trapdoor then you still don't
have the feeling that you really
understand what's going on
so that's what we're going to try to
solve in the next few minutes
but before i explain rainbow i'll
explain oil and vinegar because it's a
bit
more simple
so the trapdoor is really simple so just
a linear subspace of your input space
of dimension m where m is the dimension
of your output space
uh such that p vanishes on on o so that
means for every vector o in this space o
uh we have that p of o is equal to zero
and it turns out that if you know such a
space then sampling a pretty much is
actually very easy
so how do you do this you start by just
picking a random input which of course
will not be a pre image
but then you can solve for some
correction term in the soil space
such that um yeah so that p of v plus o
is your target
and you can do this because um you can
write this p of v plus o
um as like this so this is always the
case for a quadratic function if you
have p of a sum then you can write it as
p of the first term plus p of the second
term plus
something that's linear in v and o and
this is something we call the
differential of
p
and so in our case we can solve this
efficiently because like p of v is just
something fixed because we fixed the
choice of v
p of o is zero because p vanishes on o
and then we're left with something
that's linear in o so this whole
equation is just a system of m linear
equations in m variables so you can just
use gaussian elimination to define a
solution
and in an unlikely event that there is
no solution you just go back to step one
and try again with it with a different
vector v right now you just output
people so so that's in a nutshell how
oil and vinegar works
um rainbow is a little bit more
complicated so instead of one space o
you now have this chain of spaces from
one up to okay where k is some integer
and you also have a chain of spaces in
your output space going from w one up to
w k minus one
and uh we wanted our our trap drama p
behaves in a nice way on these two
chains so in particular it sends o1 to
w1 or 2 to w2
and so on and finally it sent okay to
the zero vector so so it vanishes on
okay so so you see that this is just a
generalization of oil and vinegar if you
put k equals one then you've got just a
vinegar uh structure
but on top of this property we also
demand something else
uh which involves this differential that
i i
defined earlier we want that for every
vector x if you plug it into this
differential
then you get some linear map that maps o
i into w i minus one so so if you have
these two properties then it turns out
you can sample pre-images
and uh yeah the stretch is basically
multiple steps of this oil and vinegar
id so you start with a random vector in
here
and then you solve for a correction term
in a 1 such that your correct pre-image
up to something up to some vector in w1
and then you're going to solve for
correction terminal 2 such that you
correct up to a vector in w2 and so you
go back and forth until finally you
solve for a correction term in an okay
such that you have a correct
uh
pre-image right so and each of these
steps is just solving a system of linear
equations so you can do this
very efficiently
so that's that's how a rainbow works and
this is i believe a much nicer
explanation than the the standard
explanation and this allowed me to find
some some more efficient attacks i found
two
key recovery attacks the first one
i called the intersection attack and
applies to both uov and rainbow and the
second one is more efficient but it only
applies to to rainbow
and yeah i don't have time to explain
how the attacks work here but it's
fairly straightforward so if you're
interested
please watch the video or read the paper
so for now just focus on the complexity
of the attacks for the parameters that
were submitted to the niche competition
so
yeah in this table the first two columns
are the the two new attacks and you see
that they're always better than the
previously best known attacks and in
particular this mean record minimike
attack is is the most efficient so for
the new security level one parameters we
improve on the best known attacks by 20
bits of security and for um yeah the
the third one it's 40 bits and for the
for security level 5 it's 55 bits
so so yeah it's a significant reduction
in the security
uh so yeah that's that's it so in
conclusion uh in this paper i give this
new simplified uh explanation of how oil
and vinegar and rainbow work and using
this uh this new insight i was able to
find new attacks that uh significant
significantly reduced uh the security of
rainbow
so yeah that's it thank you very much
[Applause]
thank you
are there any questions for a ward
you need to switch on the microphone
thanks for the talk um i believe the uh
authors of rainbow have acknowledged the
attacks but said that uh they don't need
to change parameters is this correct uh
what's your take on this
yeah so um
they claim indeed that it's not
necessary to to change their parameters
um but they had to change to a new model
to estimate their um the complexity so
previously they only looked at the at
the
gate complexity so how many gates you
need for the attack
and now they switch to a model where um
you also take into account the cost of
accessing
memory and yeah if you take this into
account and of course the the
the costs of the attacks are larger
uh so so in that sense you can make um
an argument that is still secure but
that doesn't change the fact that you
lose 20 bits of security or 40 bits or
55 bits so
uh yeah whether it's still secure or not
that's kind of up
to how you interpret the nist's rules
that's not for me to say but the
important thing is that however you
measured the security the security has
gone down by
at least 20 bits
thank you very much
um is there one more quick question
okay if not then
let's thank guard again
okay um
the next speaker is uh online i believe
yep
let me
try to share my screen
yes that would be great
yes the next talk is
um
oh um
there we go okay great um the next talk
is by uh itai di nur
on crypto analytic applications of the
polynomial method for solving
multivariate equations systems over gf2
okay thank you very much for the
introduction
so uh in this workout we'll consider the
problem of uh solving uh polynomial
systems over f2 where the input is uh
consists of m
polynomials in n variables
where each polynomial has a bounded
degree of d
which is typically small like d equals
two and the goal is to uh find the
solution to the equation system which is
basically a
common zero for all of the polynomials
now the problem is known to be np hard
even for quadratic system and it is uh
very difficult in practice
as well it's a central problem in
computer science and
specifically in cryptography
now standard techniques for uh solving
uh polynomial systems uh are based on
grobner bases and they are typically uh
heuristic
however in 2017
vital
presented the first uh worst case
algorithm with exponential speed up over
brute force
now this algorithm is based on a
so-called polynomial method and circuit
complexity which was originally
originally
introduced for a proving circuit lower
bounds
now here is a high level overview of a
few uh related works
uh that include optimized exhaustive
search
and
grommer basis related algorithms
now
the
polynomial method algorithms have been
since their introduction they have been
improved and now they actually
give the best known asymptotic
complexity
for solving polynomial systems
however
in this work uh
we'll be mainly interested in the
concrete
uh or non-asymptotic uh complexity for
solving f2 equations
and this is relevant essentially for
choosing uh parameters of concrete
cryptosystems
this is the
main motivation
unfortunately uh
close analysis of the polynomial method
algorithm reveals that the constants
behind these asymptotic formulas are
quite large and algorithms have no
concrete uh
cryptographic relevance
so in this work uh what i do basically
is i present a
polynomial method algorithm which is
concretely efficient for solving f2
equations
um unfortunately there is a caveat
because it requires a significant amount
of memory
and
this is an obstacle for obtaining a fast
implementation of the algorithm and
practice
however in terms of time complexity it
seems to be the best known algorithms
best known algorithm for a wide range of
parameters
and this slide gives uh
uh numbers for some concrete instances
as uh as you can see
and perhaps a bit surprisingly the
algorithm beats uh
uh brute force uh at least in terms of
time complexity for a relatively large
degree say of d equals 4
for problem sizes that are
actually relevant to cryptography
so the main application of the algorithm
is in a cryptanalysis of uh
of picnic which is an alternate third
round candidate in nist post quantum
standardization project
and it essentially uh shows that some
instances of picnic three do not achieve
their claimed security level and you can
see this from the uh
from the
stable
so
essentially these two
larger instances do not achieve their
claim
complexity level at least in terms of
time complexity
okay so let me give a very brief
overview of the techniques i don't have
much time but i'll give you just a
flavor so um
given a polynomial system e i'm going to
uh define
uh a polynomial f that uh
um
that single point on the f that
evaluates to one only on solutions to e
unfortunately if you define it
correctly the polynomial
the degree of the polynomial is too high
to be manipulated efficiently
therefore
what polynomial method algorithms do is
define a probabilistic polynomial f
tilde that on one hand approximates this
original polynomial f and on the other
hand it has lower degree so it can be
manipulated efficiently by algorithms
so previous work essentially exploited
the low degree of f tell to compute the
parity of the number of solutions
uh to the equation systems and from this
you can actually solve e
the equation system uh however this uh
required uh working with many
probabilistic polynomials and was
inefficient uh at least in terms of a
concrete complexity
so one of the contributions of this work
is a more direct and efficient way of
solving the equation systems
the equation system from
parity computations
so let me
briefly conclude so in this work i
divide the concretely efficient
polynomial method algorithm for solving
f2 equations
the paper there are additional
contributions such as reducing the
memory complexity of a standard
implementation of the algorithm by an
exponential factor although it remains
still remains high another
contribution is optimizing the algorithm
for a concrete cryptosystems
now there are several open problems one
of them is to optimize the algorithm for
over over defunct systems in which you
have many more equations than the
variables
and of course another open problem is to
obtain a fast implementation
of the algorithm in practice
so uh thank you very much for your
attention
thanks to ty
[Applause]
okay i can already see some people are
lining up for questions
hi thank you for the talk uh i was
wondering does the new algorithm include
any um
sub steps doing an exhaustive search
that could imply a quantum algorithm by
just globalizing
some smaller component
yes i think you can speed it up with the
my feeling i i haven't done this uh
computation uh
uh formally but i think some steps can
be optimized and i think there is a hope
here to get
also
um
faster algorithm uh
using the
on a quantum computer but like i said i
haven't checked the details so
not exactly
sure about that thank you
uh okay
so thanks for the talk uh i had a rather
technical question like directly
concerning the paper
so if i remember correctly you were
defining like n1
parity counting functions
that from the first one you were getting
the values of y so the n minus m1 bits
of the
the solution and then you were
evaluating the rest on the value that
you got for y in order to get the rest
of the bits true
so
uh what i was wondering was that can't
you do like some linear
mixing of the variables in the beginning
and instead of like doing n1
parity countings just do the first one
like multiple times
and try to like solve the it's like do
some gaussian elimination or something
to get all the bits because minus m1 i
remember was like way bigger than m1
i think i think uh you cannot uh maybe
you can do some
uh minor tweaks here to improve the
complexity but i don't quite see how you
can uh
um kind of improve this uh
uh in a substantial way i mean uh you
can do some linear algebra tricks and
maybe uh
uh
maybe obtain slightly better concrete
complexity in some cases but i don't i
don't really see what you mean by uh
substantially reducing the n minus n1 uh
term here maybe
you can send me a
concrete proposal by email and i look it
up but uh yeah
i don't quite see how to do it
and another question so
i was wondering that's if i remember the
attack only worked for like the full s
box layer instances of low mc right
so i was wondering if it's essentially
you you can try to apply it for a
partial s box but the partial s
equivalent of more rounds so the
algebraic degree is larger and therefore
the attacks will be much
less efficient
yes true i was wondering if there is a
trick to like have like introduce more
equations but with lower degrees somehow
that would somehow
make it you can introduce more variables
that i can see how you can do but then
of course the complexity will uh
increase uh proportionally and therefore
i don't see how the algorithm
would be uh
valuable in this case i mean
if you again if you have a suggestion
i'll be happy to hear it but uh okay
thank you
okay um i think um
we should probably move on to the next
speaker so let's let's thank itai one
more time
um
so the next talk is about um
round optimal blind signatures in the
plane model from classical and quantum
standard assumptions
and this this work by shuichi katsumata
[Music]
yes loud and clear
okay i'm going thank you for the
introduction i'm going to talk about the
blind signature this is a joint work
with huge katzmata shot yamada from ice
and takashima from entity
uh this is our result we proposed round
optimal blind signature protocol
uh
that has uh
three desirable properties
first
our protocol does not rely on any
trusted setup
assumption
and second
our protocol
is based on standard class current
quantum assumption
so
[Music]
our talk uh was assigned to post-quantum
cryptography but uh actually our
protocol is not post quantum city
because we use uh standard cluster
assumptions
and uh our protocol does not rely on
complexity leveraging okay
so first
let me review
the
notion of blind signature this is the
digital analog of
children envelope
with carbon copy c
there is a signer and user a user has a
message
and the sender
the user send a message
put the message into the sealed envelope
and send it to the signer the signer
signed the message uh
without opening the cd see the
because uh the the envelope with carbon
copies uh
if
the signer signed on the envelope then
this seat has the sign
signature so next the user opened see
the envelope and get a signed uh message
but this is a
brand signature
there are many applications of brian's
signature
but in particular
brian's signature is a
crucial building block of
privacy-preserving cryptosystems such as
e-cash e-boarding anonymous credentials
direct direct anonymous statistician and
more
this is the seat of the art of round
optimal blind signature
most of them
rely on some trusted setup assumption
such as common reference string model
or london locomotive
fisher bower etta and
he their follow-up works uh proposed the
round optimal blind signatures uh
without uh trusted state assumption uh
by using
interactive assumptions so
those protocols are based on strong
assumptions
uh in fact around optimal brand
signatures without trusted setup assam
trusted setup from standard assumption
is impossible under some conditions
gaga at all
overcome this impossible result by using
complexity leveraging their protocol use
compressive complexity leveraging twice
gag and groups are also presented around
the optimal grind signature
protocol with uh
by using complexity levelizing uh this
protocol used only once but
notable feature of this protocol is
uh is the protocol heavily rely on the
algebraic structure of parents
so the our
brain signature is the first around
optimal blind signature without trusted
set up assassin from standard
from standard assumptions and we our
protocol doesn't rely on complexity
leveraging
uh our portal is based on brian's
signature protocol by gagato
uh
the protocol is as follows designer
generator stand uh generator or kpi of
standard signature
and
the signer and the user run the secure
functional evaluation portal and the
user gets a signature for the message n
and the signer gets
nothing so we can uh
the user can obtain the signature for
him
without revealing a
messaging
however
the signer might deviate from the
protocol so uh
we need to use zero knowledge protocol
to
force the sign for the protocol
so
by using zero knight we can uh
prove the security of this branch energy
protocol blindness falls from the right
soundless of zeronites protocol and the
receiver security of secure functional
variation
the unfoldability follows from zero
knowledge and the sender security of
secure functional evaluation
uh however uh their protocol uh need to
to use complexity leveraging to prove
these two properties
our basic idea is as follows
using uh using complexity leveraging we
need a super polynomial super
preliminary city equipped system
cryptographic cryptography
we replaced uh super polynomial secure
cryptography with quantumly secure one
by using a quantum path quantum power
for super polynomial
reduction
this idea was inspired by the work
client planner
however
there is one issue
the protocol by gargato used compressive
leveraging technique twice
the
quantum technique
only works only for complexity levels
only once
so we cannot simply
use the technique by client planner
in fact the protocol by gargant gupta
use compressed composition only once so
we can might use uh
the quantum technique uh for their
protocol
however their uh
land optimal blind signature protocol is
not compatible with quantum simulation
due to heavy use of algebraic structure
of
gross hyper system
to solve the problem we introduced the
notion of blind signature conforming
zero knowledge this is neurologic
protocol uh
only to to move during a protocol
and prove by chemoregister
possibly inform the public keys because
we use this neurologic argument for the
breathing block of blind signature uh
the prover is the user of the branded
signature so
the proof account register public key
and in
this drive
the simulator simulator is quantum
phenomenal time simulator so the
simulator can break plastically secure
crypto cryptosystem in reductions
so this
can be used instead of
complexity leveraging
to solve the
complexity leveraging twice program we
use
many techniques one of the key tools is
public key encryption with invalid key
statistics certifiability
we can prove that a public key is
informed for regular public key crystal
system by using the proof system by ahan
of land layer
we
carefully combined this public
encryption with lossy encryption and
that so we can overcome the
the complexity leveraging problem
please see the
video or paper of the detail
this is a summary we achieved the round
optimal bind signature protocol by using
standard class current quantum
assumptions
this protocol does not rely on any
trusted setup and we don't use
complexity leveraging technique
we
introduced the many interesting
techniques for this protocol
exactly thank you
thank you for the talk
um
i'm not sure
whether we have we have maybe time for
one quick question
maybe i will just take delivered two to
ask one um so basically um you need um
you're honest but your pro some parts of
your protocol to be quantum secure and
then um
you use um
quantum simulation to break
some some classical secure parts so
basically if you wanted quantum secure
quantum security for the whole protocol
your technique would would not be
applicable right
yeah our uh techniques does not work for
post-quantum secure cryptosystem uh i
mean i mean our brand of signature
protocol is not the possible secure
because right and basically
the technique is fundamentally uh not
suited for that right because yeah but
you would need the
breakable quantum breakable things okay
thanks
okay i think we should move on to the to
the next speaker thanks
rio
thank you
sorry
um no this was not what i wanted
and so so can you
open your presentation which one is it
okay
there we go
okay so
the next talk will be uh by amit agarwal
and it will be on post quantum secure uh
multi-party computation and constant
rounds uh you'll actually need to switch
around the display settings so in the
upper um
left i believe because we're seeing the
presenter mode uh remotely
this is this
yeah uh swap presenter view
okay perfect thank you okay
this does not work because now the
audience in the room sees the presenter
on one second oh great okay
[Music]
as you all may have gathered we are
still working out kinks
um
let me try and
share it with this
how does it look now
online
uh it's still loading so i think
give it a second
i'm hoping it's just a lag
i don't see full screen
i don't okay
it may also be under uh display settings
that same menu uh there was another
option that i believe said duplicate
slideshow that may also be what you need
to click i'm not sure oh i see okay
thanks
sure
so
thanks for your patience everyone from
the disembodied voice in the cloud
there we go sorry for the delay
perfect
hi everyone today i'll be talking about
my work on post quantum mpc in constant
rounds and this is joint work with james
bartosek vipal goel dakshita karana and
julia manohara and i would like to thank
james for letting me use his lights
so
let me first start with the setting of
mpc where we have a bunch of parties
each with their private inputs and they
want to compute some public uh circuit
on their private inputs and the
adversary might corrupt some subset of
these parties and the goal is that the
advocacy shouldn't learn anything about
the inputs of honest parties about apart
from what it can learn from the output
of the functionality
and the setting that we are interested
in is quantum polynomial time
adversaries with malicious behavior
dishonest majority and static
corruptions we note that in the
two-party setting there has been some
prior work to solve this problem in the
plane model but in the multi-party
settings this has been largely
unexplored
and the main challenge lies in uh
working against quantum polynomial time
adversaries because of the snow cloning
theorem it states that given an
arbitrary quantum state you cannot make
two copies of it and this creates
challenges in simulate simulation
techniques
so our high level approach is the
following so we note that there are
already existing constant round
classical mpc protocols secure against
classical adversaries with a trusted
setup and furthermore if you instantiate
the underlying primitives used in these
protocols with your post quantum analogs
then what you get is a post quantum
secure mpc but with a trusted setup
and this trusted setup is a common
random string
and what happens is that the simulator
in the security proof programs the crs
and hence once the programming is done
the simulation is entirely straight line
so we know that it suffices to build a
constant round fully submittable
simulatable coin flipping protocol which
helps us instantiate the common random
string
so let me describe the
setting of fully simulatable coin
tossing so we have a functionality which
is just returns a random string r to all
parties and a natural protocol template
for realizing this functionality is the
following so each party commits a sample
some random
string ri and sends a commitment to it
to all other parties
then each party broadcasts the opening
values to these commitments and proves
in zero knowledge that this opening
value is consistent with their
commitment
and if all the proofs verify each party
outputs the xor of all the open values
now in the constant round setting
uh we need this first round to be a
multi-party constant on extractable
commitment and the zero knowledge proofs
should also be multi-party constant on
zero knowledge groups
and the main challenge lies in uh
constructing this multi-party constant
on extractable commitment in the quantum
setting against quantum mechanisms and
once we have that we can uh get
multi-party constraint on zero knowledge
proofs from there on the extractable
commitments
so if we were just interested in
two-party setting there have been some
prior works which show how you can get a
non-rewinding no cloning extraction
technique and this is known in the
literature as a homomorphic trapdoor
paradigm so here we have a
committer and a receiver and we want to
create an extractable commitment where
extractor doesn't rewind that visit so
let me
give you a sketch of how the protocol
looks like so the committer samples are
effective
trap door and a lock value so this
protocol by the way makes use of fhe and
compute and compare offer station so uh
just keep that in mind so this is the
first step and then as a second step the
committee computes an encryption of the
trapdoor fh encryption of the trapdoor
and then it prepares this very special
computer and compare program which has
the fhe decryption circuit hard coded
within it and a target log value and the
output is the secret key and the message
so if inside this pro so if you feed an
encrypted trap door to encrypted lock to
this computer and compare program
then what you get in as the output is
the message and secret key otherwise you
get bought
so uh committee obfuscates this program
and sends over the triplet consisting of
public key encrypted trapdoor and offers
kitted program to the receiver then in
the second round receiver has to take a
guess at what the trap door is
and if the guess is correct the
commander returns the lock otherwise it
returns bought
so naturally a real world receiver
cannot guess what the trapdoor is in the
second round and therefore the lock will
be hidden from its view and
hence the
compute and compare program will hide
the message
now an extractor which has non-black box
access
so by the way this simulation technique
makes use of non-black box techniques so
it ha we assume that the extractor has
access to the code of the addresses
so x an extractor which has x non-black
box access to the committer
can uh get the same triplet
like a real world receiver it cannot
guess at what the trapdoor is but what
it can do is run the sports step of the
committee under the hood of
so it can just supply the encrypted trap
door
under the hood of fhe and evaluate this
fourth round and get out the third round
message which is indeed the encrypted
log because under the hold of fhe the
guess was indeed correct
and once it has that it can feed it into
the compute and compare program
to get out the secret key and the
message and now it has successfully
extracted the message
now we can try extending this technique
to the multi-party setting where we have
multiple committees which we are
interested in
but it runs into some issues so the
extractor gets
two triplets of public key encrypted
trapdoor and the compute and compare
program
but
it's unclear how to evaluate this
guessing step in one go
so the issue is basically that
the extractor has only one shot to
evaluate that was it and in one shot it
has to do this fhe validation but the
trapdoors that the extractor has are
encrypted under
independently generated public keys pk1
pk2
so it's unclear how to do this
homomorphic evaluation in one shot
so we note that there is this notion of
multi-key fh in the literature which is
a natural generalization of single
client effigy now here we have multiple
clients each with their public secret
keypads and their inputs they can
encrypt these inputs
using their public key send it to the
server server can then do a homomorphic
evaluation of the cipher text under the
joined public key of all the clients
and then send out cipher text to all
these parties ciphered these clients
using the secret key can locally decrypt
this cipher text and compute what is
known as a partial decryption
now the crucial property is that the
these partial decryptions add up to the
output of the actual function
so in our paper we
since our adversary is quantum we need a
multi-key fhe scheme which works for
quantum circuits and we construct that
by combining single key fhe schemes for
quantum circuits and multi-key fhe
schemes for classical circuits which are
already present in the literature we you
combine these two to create multi kfh
scheme for evaluating quantum circuits
so once we have this tool we
directly plug this uh
tool in our fhe validation step now we
can just replace this fhe validation
with a multi-key fhe validation
supporting evaluation of quantum
circuits
and feed in the two encrypted trapdoors
so now what we have is encrypted locks
so now we we are
in a better position than before but the
problem is not completely solved because
the encrypted locks are under joint
public keys and to make use of the
compute and compare program we have to
peel off the layers of public key i
won't be able to go into the details of
how we do that feeling but uh we make
use of the
spooky property that i mentioned earlier
that
partial decryptions add up to the output
of the function to peel off the public
key layers and then feed them into the
obfuscated program to finally get out
the secret keys both secret keys and
both messages m1m2
so i'll just um not go over the slide in
the interest of time
yeah so this helps us finally construct
this constant on multi-party extractable
commitment secure against quantum
adversaries
and
using existing techniques we can
directly use extractable commitments to
uh construct constant round zero
knowledge proofs
so we note that uh uh just having
extractable commitments doesn't solve
the entire issue because uh
an adversary might be able to mall an
extractable commitment so what we end up
also needing is uh non-malleable
commitments uh which are constant rounds
so in this paper we combine the erasure
channel based approach of constructing
constant on uh commitments
with tag amplification technique to
construct post quantum constraints on
non-malleable commitments
and we plug this into our final coin
tossing protocol
to ensure non-malibity so our final
results look something like the
following so we uh
show that there exists a constant on
classical mpc protocol so there is no
quantum communication happening inside
the protocol which is secure against
quantum polynomial time adversaries in
the plane model assuming an lwe based
circular security assumption and this
assumption is used in order to create
the quantum multi-key fhe scheme that i
talked about earlier and
we use that in turn to create constant
on parallel extractable commitment and
then constant on parallel zero knowledge
which are both secure against quantum
mechanics the second assumption that we
rely on is a mildly super polynomial
hardness of lw
uh
and we use that to create post quantum
constant or non-mileable commitments
thanks alice
thank you
i think we have time for one question
um
is there any questions online
otherwise maybe i can um i can ask one
question so um
sorry if it's not not about your work
but some something you you use as a
component um so how exactly enters the
um the sub exponential hardness of lwe
in your
in the protocol so how how do you make
use of it
um
so we assume super polynomial hardness
uh superpower you know
modulus noise are you referring to this
uh
last assumption
yeah there might be super polymer so we
need this to uh create constant on
normal level commitments so basically
we create multiple hardness levels to
instantiate this irregular channel based
approach
so
uh
in this work by kurana and sahai
so basically what happens is you create
an eraser channel between each uh pair
of players and this aeration channel is
created using a secure function
evaluation and by
having different levels of security of
each secure function evaluation you have
different eraser channel security levels
and that helps you create
a non-malleable
uh non-malleability between each
communication channel
okay
and yeah so that is needed in order to
create these
multiple hardness levels
thanks
um
okay um i think we should should write a
wrap up
let's thank all the speakers of the
session one more time