uh in person and to online talks
um so the first one
is um sorry let me check the title
so the first talk is efficient
bootstrapping for approximate
demographic encryption with non-sparse
keys
and the the paper is by jean-free bosua
christian
juan trumposo pasteuriza and jean kiribo
and jean-philippe will give the talk
[Music]
sure
thank you very much for the introduction
i would like to add that this is a soft
mesh with the next talk that will be
given by john woolley from seoul
university
so approximate from free encryption is a
kind of scheme that allows a third party
to evaluate a function on a ciphertext
without the knowledge of a secret key
and we call a search scheme approximate
when the decryption separates the
correctness it relax to an approximate
result
and this kind of scheme has been
recently
very useful for applications that do not
require exact results or can tolerate
errors such as machine learning training
of inference
the cks scheme is one shot scheme and it
is currently the most efficient schema
for a floating point or kept at 14 point
arithmetic
it is a scheme that is based on the ring
learning for our problem and it encrypts
the vectors of complex number
it is a level scheme meaning that for a
given set of parameters one can only
evaluate a
circuit of a finite depth before either
decryption is required for bootstrapping
is needed
so the bootstrapping for the case
scheme is a complex procedure which is
still an area of research
and it has a multi-dimensional
trade-offs between its computational
cost
the residual homomorphic capacity which
is the number of operations that one can
do after robust trapping before the next
one is needed
the precision
and
its variability and its security
and in this work we improve all these
dimensions by proposing novel algorithm
for score building blocks
so
cipher text live in a brain family
[Music]
ciphertext leave in a preliminary
question string
and have a degree at most d minus one
for the power of two and have integer
coefficients uh taken a modulo ql a
large opposite number of
of primes
and so to embed a message in a in this
finger we a floating point message we
multiply it by a large scaling factor to
enable fixed point representation and
when two such messages are multiplied
together the scale will increase
exponentially so to manage the magnitude
of the scale
this game proposes a rescaling operation
which is to divide the ciphertex
coefficient by one of the primes the
modulus
and which divide also the scale by an
equal amount
the only thing is that when a rescaling
operation is called it returns a
ciphertext that has oneness prime
uh which was one used for risking and
after l rescaling we end up with a
cipher text at level zero with only one
prime and we must either decrypt it or
apply the bootstrapping procedure to
bring it back to a higher level
so the bootstrapping procedure starts by
bringing back the ciphertext at higher
level and this changes my message to a
new message that is the only original
message plus some
multiple of the modulus q0 added to a
message so the goal of the bootstrapping
procedure is to apply a homomorphic
modular reduction by q0 to retrieve the
original message
it starts and it ends with homomorphic
especially discard fourier transforms
which are evaluated with homophilic
matrix vector products
and in this work we propose improved
rotation keys for hoisted rotations
dual hoisting speed up for the matrix
vector product but also measure sparse
and
unpacking and re-packing for sparse
plain text and merge constant
multiplications
the middle step of the bootstrapping is
a reduction homophilic reduction by q0
and this is done by evaluating a
polynomial and this step has two main
challenges the first one is to find a
good approximation of the modular
reduction
that is both precise and friendly for
automotive evaluation and the second one
is to have an algorithm that can
evaluate this but evaluate this
polynomial without adding too much error
while being still efficient
so the first challenge i will not found
generally we'll talk about more about
visual channels in the next talk and
this in this work we propose a solution
for the second challenge with a novel
polynomial algorithm
that allows to preserve the input scale
of cipher text and to manage the
intermediate scale
such that it has
us errorless addition through the entire
evaluation while at the same time being
depth optimal and retain a low
complexity
additionally
we propose new updated 128-bit per
secure parameter so the bootstrapping
instance we also propose a first
practical bootstrapping instance that
does not use a sparse secret
also on empirical failure probability
analysis a step-by-step algorithm for
parameter selection and fine-tuning and
an open source implementation
so we evaluate our work against the
previous state of the art using a
throughput metric and a failure
probability the throughput is a
the number of plaintext bits that are
bootstrapped personal
and in the graph we can see that our
work has about up to 14 times better
throughput than the previous state of
the arts
and that the instant that use the dense
secrets still has a throughput that is
about four times larger than the
previous state of the art
so in conclusion our improvement allows
a throughput for bootstrapping for the
full rns variant of the ckk scheme that
is an order of magnitude larger than
previous state of the art
and our work is implemented is the
library latigo
which is an open source library written
in go and it currently has the only open
source implementations for the
bootstrapping of the fully arranged city
class
if you are more interested in our
results and contribution you can watch
your full presentation and
better thank you very much
thank you so
i don't see any questions soon
so do we have questions here in the room
anyone
the first one is always the most
difficult so just try
no
okay
so thank you
um
oh you have one
sorry
so the second talk is also on
bootstrapping um it will be online from
correct
um
[Music]
so there are
four peop four authors on the paper
or five i don't i don't remember
um so the title of the paper is high
precision bootstrapping of rns ckks
homomorphic encryption using optimal
minimax polynomial approximation
and inverse sine function
so the equator of the paper are
jung
and
[Music]
and the speaker is uh
so i guess you're in korea so thank you
for sticking with us so late
yeah can you hear me
yep can you hear me
yeah
and thanks for introducing our team
and
my name is juno lee
and this talk is about the paper high
priest jump to stripping of rna ck kkk's
homophobic encryption using optimal
benefits of polynomial approximation and
inverse sine function and this is the
joint work is insanely
the previous team explained the tkk
scheme and it's produced stepping very
well
our main focus of the research is the
bluetooth stepping precision
previous works regarding the rnscks
prototyping only reports 15 to 20 bit
precision of the protester pin
though this precision is now
sufficiently high in many practical
situations
so more precise rnck splitter stripping
is needed in various applications
but previous works did not focus on the
capacity of the bluetooth-saving
precision thus our key question is
how
how high precision can be supported by
rnck scheme and are there any further
techniques to improve the potential
precision
the degradation of the progesterone
precision is generated in homomorphic
modular reduction process
the function to be evaluated
in this process is the blue graph the
previous works regard the target
function as a part of a sine function
and evaluate the approximate polynomial
for sine function
so there are two approximation steps in
the homo oping modular reduction process
in this work
we propose two new techniques to improve
each approximation step
polynomial approximation step is
improved by improved multi-interval
remains algorithm and sine approximation
step is improved by composite function
approximation by inverse sine
the first solution is the improved
multi-interval limits algorithm
the multi-interval remains algorithm is
an algorithm for finding the optimal
minimix approximate polynomial for
piecewise function
but unlike the
ordinary cases our target function is
rather extreme case
the length of intervals are very tiny
there are tens or even hundreds of
approximation intervals the polynomial
degree is somewhat high and we need very
high precision approximation
so we need so we find two optimization
points to make the algorithm more
practical even for these extreme cases
two mode search methods and maximums
absolute some condition
in this method we implement a robust
efficient and high precision variant of
the multi-interval image algorithm to
approximate any piecewise function best
the second consolation is the composite
function approximation by inverse sine
this shows the sine function
approximating the modular reduction
function
which cannot exactly evaluate the
modular reduction function
it proposed to compose this sine
function with the inverse sine function
if we compose the inverse sine function
the composed function is like this graph
this composite function exactly
evaluates the modular junction function
in the approximation domain and thus the
approximation error between the modular
reduction function and the sine function
is completely removed
the tables show the comparison between
the maximum precision without inverse
sine and the maximum precision with
inverse sine
the maximum precision of the bluetooth
stepping is 32.6 to
45 40.5 which is improved by 5.4 to 10.2
bits compared to the previous purchase
checking
so we could significantly enlarge the
capacity of the bootstrapping precision
of rns's kkk scheme which makes the rnck
scheme work appropriate to various
situations requiring high precision
so we verified that the new techniques
significantly improved the precision of
the bootstrapping thanks for listening
to our talk
thank you
questions
okay so then
let's thank the speaker again
thank you
so
[Music]
yes the net next talk will be on live
so the the two uh author of the paper
are uh
sorry i forgot your name
oh bailey and daniele michencho
and
title is
on the security of morphic encryption on
approximate numbers
just click on
share this one
okay
for procedures
thank you for the introduction and this
is a joint work with my advisor danielle
michelle
um so
okay so
this talk is also on homomorph
encryption which is a crypto primitive
that allows us to compute down encrypted
data
and so also thanks to the previous two
talks we know that the secret ks scheme
is now a very popular choices in many of
the previously preserving machine
learning applications
so cks is a bit different from the
typical homomorphic encryption scheme
because
typical schemes
are exact they satisfy the correctness
requirement
but the secret guess is an approximate
home amount of encryption screen which
means that the decryption result is only
approximately equal to the underlying
plaintext computation result
so we started the passive security model
of approximate home of encryptions in
this work
um in the passive security model
attacker who can
we consider an attacker who can
influence legit users on their choices
of text messages and also their choices
for homomorphic competitions
the attacker can also abase drop the
communication lines to learn separate
taxes and also very importantly the
attacker can also observe the final
computation result in plain text
so typically to formulate such passive
attacker we end up with the classic in
the cpa security which is the classical
security notion for exact home of
encryptions and also it is satisfied by
the cks scheme under the standardized
assumptions
the
indicated security definition is only
concerns about the encryption and
evaluation apis of the scheme it does
not concern about the does not formulate
the decryption
api because the adversary already knows
the decryption result how exactly scenes
but this is not sufficient for
approximate encryption schemes
so we introduced the new security notion
the index apd security or in the cpu
with special decryption oracle security
as a conservative extension of
individual security for approximate home
of encryptions
we define it as a standard
indistinguishability game
and in this game the adversary has
access to three stateful oracles
so we have the
encryption evaluation oracle which
provide the same functionality as you
would see in the in this api security
definitions
and but we also have a special
decryption oracle which
is it's kind of special it only returns
the decryptive result of
honestly generated cipher text
so here i want to emphasize that this
this indicated this security is very
different from active security such as
cc or cc2 because adversary cannot hold
this decryption oracle on an arbitrarily
generated separate text
so for exact schemes this decryption
oracle does not provide any useful
information and we can show that this
new in the cpd security is equivalent to
industry security for exact schemes
but for approximate schemes this
decryption query may leak informations
on messages or sometimes even the secret
keys
so this brings us to the attack uh the
key recovery attack on this eks scheme
which well the cks scheme is typically
instantiated on the ring rwa encryption
where the raw decryption function
computes the inner product between the
secret key and the separate text
so in ckks the decoding function doesn't
do any error correction it applies the
canonical inviting on the scaled version
of this plain text message
and the full decryption function is just
the composition of the decryption raw
depreciation function with decoding
function it is a linear function in the
secret key so the attacker can may just
compute the inverse of this decryption
function to learn the secret key
and this is exactly the underlying idea
of our key recovery attack where the uh
in this attack the attacker can observe
some separate hexes and also can observe
the decrypted numbers of those separate
hexes with those information the
adversary can just the attacker can just
try to re-encode this decrypting numbers
and then compute the inverse of the
decryption function
so in practice there are a few
amount of connections has to be
satisfied for this tech to be successful
but generally speaking this implies that
the secret gas is not a passively secure
scheme
so we implemented this attack against
most of the many of the open source fhe
libraries and we conducted non-trivial
attacks against them in order to make
our attack harder
and we were able to successfully
successfully recover the secret key in
almost all of those requirements
and we disclosed this attack to those
library teams in october last year
and following the disclosure there have
been more sophisticated attack in this
tower and also at the
following following that there has been
some heuristic measures implemented in
those libraries
so in conclusion
we introduced the new security notion in
the cpd security to formulate passive
attackers against approximate home of
encryptions
that is equivalent to industry for exact
schemes but it is strictly stronger
for approximate schemes and in fact you
can show that there is there
exists a strict hierarchy of the variant
of this in the cpd security
based on the number of decryption
quarries
we also showed that the ckks is subject
to a passive very efficient single
efficient key recovery attack
and there has been heuristic accounting
measures implemented in many of the open
source libraries and we also have
full-bodied secure counter measures but
i think it is still open question to
find an efficient solution
to this in the cpd security
so with that i'd like to finish my talk
and please check out the details of the
definitions of that hacksaw in eprint
and thank you for your attention
okay so are a question for bayou
no
hello
yeah so um i'm a little bit confused
about your definition of passive
security because uh
although you're not provided directly a
decryption oracle you sort of see
decryptions for ciphertext
that you somehow call indirectly created
as far as i understand is that correct
uh uh can you repeat that so my
understanding is that you send or in or
or influence a message yes and then
there is some homomorphic evaluation
possibly and then there is a decryption
step where you get to see the decryption
of the message
uh yeah so you can see the decryption of
the
of the separate hex that's generated by
the encryption of the evaluation oracle
those are
like honestly generated separate taxes
yes
yeah it still it feels a little bit more
than what in cpa say from i come from
more from the public key encryption
literature and it seems a little bit
more than what just cpa gives you uh
yeah so well if you consider like
passive security notions in the network
settings so
the attacker can observe the like
communication lines and also
attacker can just observe the the final
computation result from the
if you consider that like a black box so
the defining computational result in
this context is the decrypted
decrypted result so decryption
decryption numbers so that's um i think
that should be like considered for
passive attackers
yeah i see okay thank you thank you
more questions
no so i have one for you okay um did you
look at other security notion um
for example uh looking at uh
one awareness
as a security goal instead of
indistinguishability
uh yeah so we look as like
um for example just purely k uh key
research uh acute recovery uh security
but we think so
like the indus indistinguishability
security should be the minimum security
you you are targeting further for those
games so yeah yeah that i understand but
uh your goal is pretty easy so it's cpr
cpa plus
so you may
have another goal i mean
more difficult one in that case
uh you mean like just to consider the
key recovery yeah yeah so i think yeah
you can formulate a weaker version of
the security just say um
just to formulate the the
adversary's
success being based on like not able to
recover the security key so
yeah it is
we actually consider that as a weaker
security notion
yeah
thank you thank you
any question questions or sorry
no so thank you
[Applause]
okay
so i'd like the title of the next talk
um
so the the title is the rise of paella
i'm glad because pascal is just in front
of me
so homomorphic secret sharing and
publicly silence ot
so the the paper is by claudia orlandy
peter school and sofia yakubov and peter
will be given the talk
i should be sharing
uh let's present to you
okay
that should be good thanks for the
introduction uh so this is the rise of
pele which is joint with claudio orlandi
and sophia jakobov
and in this paper uh we basically have a
single main technique which we use
throughout the paper in all of our
constructions
which is a way of doing a type of share
conversion in settings using kali
encryption
by a new method of solving the
distributed discrete log problem
and in the paper the two main
applications we consider of this uh
constructing homomorphic secret sharing
which is a kind of distributed analog of
homework encryption you could use for
secure two-party and multi-party
computation
as well as uh an application to
non-interactive generation of correlated
randomness used again in secure
multi-party computation
and with this correlated randomness a
special feature of our constructions
that we can do this was just a simple
non-interactive public key style setup
so i'm gonna start by diving straight
into the details of the core idea in
this distributed discrete log setting
uh so in previous works uh they mostly
worked with a prime order group g uh
with generator g
and the idea is that we have two parties
alice and bob
who have some group elements g0 and g1
which initially encodes some kind of
multiplicative secret sharing of message
x so this ratio of g1 over g0 gives us g
to the power of the message x
and the idea of solving distributed
discrete log is that we want a way of
converting these multiplicative shares
to give us additive shares of the
original message x over the integers so
these integers y zero y one which gives
us shares of x
and going back to this breakthrough
paper of boyle gabor and shai from 2016
they presented a way of doing this
which um
there's a special method of solving this
discrete log problem which has an
inverse polynomial probability of
correctness error
that's the main drawback of their
algorithm
and even though you can make this error
smaller to do that you have to work hard
computationally which means that in all
applications you end up with something
very expensive to make this work out
with small probability of error
so in our case we'll be looking at the
setting of pale encryption
uh where instead of a cyclic group we
have the group of integers mod n squared
under multiplication
where n is now an rsa modulus
and in this group the main thing we need
to know is that it has this special
element one plus n which generates a
subgroup where the discrete logarithm
problem is actually easy to solve and
this is what we exploit to get an
improved method of solving the
distributed discrete log
so as before alice and bob have inputs
g0 and g1 which are group elements so
now going to be in the large group g
and now the ratio g1 over g0 will encode
the message x but an exponent of one
plus n so it lies in this easy discrete
log sub group
and then we show that
if you have this setup there's actually
a very simple procedure for solving the
problem which is just to apply this
simple one-line computation to the group
elements
so i take my input g zero g one uh
divide by n over the integers for this
divide by uh the original input mod n
doing this all mod n squared and end up
with an integer uh which gives me an
additive secret sharing of the original
value x
we show that this gives you uh something
with a negligible probability of
correctness error and moreover it can
support exponentially large inputs x
whereas the previous um constructions
were all limited to polynomially bounded
x
so what do we do with this distributed
discrete log algorithm
so firstly we can use it to build
homomorphic secret sharing which as i
said is a distributed analog of homework
encryption so here we have two servers
um alice and bob
who will receive some secret shares in
some special secret sharing scheme of
the inputs x
such that these preserve privacy as long
as the servers don't collude
and then the homomorphic property means
that there is a local evaluation
procedure which the servers can apply to
the shares which homomorphically
evaluates some program p on the inputs
and this end up with shares of the
result we still hide the result until
they want to reconstruct and in our case
we'll be focusing on the setting where
the servers can reconstruct by simply
adding to that together their shares so
they get additive secret shares of the
program p applied to the inputs x
and our main result here is a
construction of hss for evaluating the
class of branching programs which you
can think of as logarithmic depth
circuits based on player encryption
and just as with the distributed
discrete log algorithm we obtain now
this negligible probability of
correctness error and exponentially
large plain text spaces which are things
we only previously knew how to do using
learning with errors
and i'll mention that there has been an
independent work uh at crypto this year
which obtained a similar result using
the downgrade europe crypto system which
is a generalization of
pelier okay and the second application i
want to talk about is generating
correlated randomness uh which is used
often in a pre-processing phase of
multi-party computation protocols
and this can be formalized as an object
called a pseudorandom correlation
function
which has a key generation algorithm
which outputs two correlated keys to
alice and bob
and then these keys define some function
which can be evaluated on a public input
of some nonce and then each evaluation
will give private samples alice and bob
the form of some strings r0 and r1 which
are some type of correlated randomness
so the examples we can think of
oblivious transfer correlations where
say bob gets two random strings s0 and
s1 and alice gets one of these sb for a
random bit b
and we also do something called vector
only which is like an arithmetic
generalization of oblivious transfer
with secret
shares and our main constructions here
are pseudo-random correlation functions
for vector ole based on pallet and ot
based on quadratic residuality both of
these have this nice feature of a public
key setup where instead of having some
trusted generation algorithm to generate
the keys we can actually replace this
with a simple public key infrastructure
and the advantage of this compared with
previous constructions is that we have
very simple constructions based on
standard classical assumptions
and very small private keys as well a
drawback compared with a previous
construction based on a variant of lpn
is that computationally it's quite slow
because we need to do exponentiations in
a pelier group
so i'll just quickly summarize the
results our main tool is this local
share conversion procedure based in
paleo groups which we use to build
homomorphic secret sharing with improved
properties and pseudorandom correlation
functions for generating correlated
randomness
which we can additionally build with
this public key setup
to generate non-interactively all of the
correlated randomness which alice and
bob need for their secure computation
so that's all i wanted to say
and if you want to learn more i hope you
can check out the video or watch read
the paper online
okay thank you um
got questions
no
maybe i can ask something maybe
quite difficult i don't know how would
you compare um this year
against the qr
so which one is more difficult for you
what's your
intuition
more difficult so so for homomorphic
secret sharing we have to use dcr we
cannot get the same from qr
so they give us different things and qr
naturally encrypts bits which we use for
oblivious transfer because it kind of
encodes the receiver's choice boat
so they give us different things
okay thank you
okay so
thanks again
[Applause]
so yeah we are now moving to io so we
have two talks
um so first one is um
in distinguishability obfuscation from
simple to state art problems
new assumption new techniques and
simplification
so this is by roman gay ayush chain
quaker lean and amit sahai and
ronald give the talk
hi thank you for the introduction
um
all right so first let me tell you what
is in distinguishability obfuscation
there's an efficient compiler that's
called the obfuscator
am i sharing
uh no you'll need to share your screen
let's start over
okay
all right uh thanks for the introduction
uh indistinguishability application from
simple to state heart problems new
assumptions new techniques and
simplification this is a joint work with
ayush chain rachel lin and amita hai
first let me recall what is
indistinguishability obfuscation
there is an efficient compiler
uh that's called the obtuse skater that
takes the program pi and transform it
into a functionally equivalent program
pi tilde
and if there is another program delta
which implements the same functionality
and has the same size
then it's computationally hard to
distinguish between an obfuscation of pi
and an obfuscation of delta
and this may seem perhaps a bit
artificial
but
this has been extremely versatile in
fact
uh together with minimal cryptographic
assumption io is known to imply
virtually all the known cryptographic
construction that are known
um
so this is a amazing unifying aspect of
io but there is more
it also has helped expand the landscape
of creativity by
allowing us to build new objects that
were
previously unachievable
so i've made some a list here
and in fact some of these constructions
ended up being built from standard
assumption later on
so
io is extremely versatile and extremely
powerful
therefore
it matters to build io from stable
grounds
and in particular we would have to have
probably secure construction from
computational hardness assumptions with
nice features
in particular this assumption should be
simple to understand by non-i o expert
which means they must have a succinct
description they should be falsifiable
instance independent that means for
example that if you do not want one
assumption per circuit that you're
obfuscating you just want actually a
constant number of assumptions
and in the work i'm presenting now
uh we build the first io from simple to
state hardness assumption so simple to
state assumptions are assumptions that
satisfies all these features
and this is without multi-linear maps
our work was a stepping stone to the
later uh celebrated results of
iujane rachelin and amit sahai
that gave the first io construction from
well studied assumption well well
founded the sediments like assumptions
that has a long history of study
um however so we give a construction
that's from simple to state assumption
but one of the assumption is new
namely
we use three assumptions the first one
is a standard lwe
learning with error assumption second
one is a standard assumption from
billionaire maps pairing
and the third one is new it's lw with
leakage
and i'll tell you more about that
in a second
but first let me mention that as is
typical for io we need all these
assumptions to be subexponentially
secure
so what is this new lw is leakage
assumption it's essentially the
combination the interaction of two long
studied assumptions the first one is lw
lwe with binary noise binary error and
the second one is the existence of
constant depth boolean prgs
more precisely
it says that if you have a bunch of
noisy linear
equations with binary noise
and you run a constant depth prg so the
random generator on
on the noise so the noise is a seed
then it should be computationally
indistinguishable from this same noisy
linear equation
and truly uniform
values
so
we take parameters for which
the learning with error with binary
noise is secure it's known to hold
and um we take a prg that we assume to
be secure and then we put them together
and in a sort of a circular flavor
assumption and we assume this also holds
i'm not going to give more details about
this assumption i will refer to the
paper if you are interested where we
give a survey of known attacks and we
also provide
new prg candidates
so this is our results
actually to build io we built a public
key
functional encryption for all functions
with sub-linear efficiency which is
known to employ io but what's
interesting is uh if you only care about
a public key fee which is interesting in
its own right then you only we only
require um polynomial hardness of the
underlying assumption so this is the
first time public key fee was built
directly from polynomial hardness
assumption
another advantage of our construction is
that it requires less
steps it's a more direct construction
than prior works
so conceptually simpler and also
more efficient
with that i'll just finish by mentioning
a few open problems
the first one is
to actually study more in depth this new
lw with leakage assumption
even though the latest work uh jls
removed actually the use of lw with ldk
and replaced it with learning parity
with noise
there's still some interest into
studying this assumption
because in fact many of the other
independent io construction
also use
some assumptions that are different but
also have this circular flavor or lw
with the cage flavor
and so i think it would be worthwhile to
study this assumption it could give some
insights to other construction as well
and finally one of the questions that i
think is important in the field is to
build io from long studied assumption
without pairing so from
post quantum assumption and without
circular security that would be a huge
step forward
all right so thank you
[Music]
okay some question on zoom oh there is
one
um so please i'd like to know if roman
gay saw the paper counter examples to
new circular secret assumption
underlying io by hopkins and others
and how it affects the assumption done
in his paper to construct io
would you comment on that
yeah sure
let me see the question i don't think it
affects this paper by the way i think
it's so about uh
this this construction i just presented
it does not require
oh yeah because i said there's a secular
favor no uh this attack this paper
mentioned does not affect um these
papers that i just presented
it affects other um
other papers no it doesn't apply
so it's a very high level comparison
that i was making there is a circular
flavor but it's not it's not the same
assumption
okay
more questions
no
so let's move to the last talk of this
session thank you very much
[Applause]
so next one will be online
[Music]
um
hi
okay so it's a candidate of escalation
via oblivious lwe sampling
by utter queen and daniel weeks and
danielle
i'm saying here so we'll give the talk
great can you see the screen
can you hear me
yes and yes perfect excellent thank you
great i'm daniel wicks and i'm going to
tell you about candidate obfuscation by
oblivious lw sampling this joint work
without a gui
so let me start with our results in a
nutshell we give a new candidate
construction of indistinguishable
obfuscation or io
it relies on lw style techniques but
unfortunately we don't know how to prove
security under the lw assumption on its
own
instead we formulate a new simple
indistinguishable based assumption
and we shall secure it under this new
assumption the assumption is simple it's
falsifiable
easy to state and it has a certain
circular security type flavor
uh overall because we rely on lw
techniques uh the scheme is plausibly
post quantum secure and the scheme is
conceptually simple
so uh let me start by telling you what
io is uh you already saw it in the last
talk but it's a way to take a program p
and convert it compile it into a new
program p tilde which is functional
equivalent on every input x p and p tell
that give you the same output
and the security says that b tilde
should hide all of the internal
implementation details of p in
particular if you have two different
programs p1 and p2 that are function
equivalent
then when you up your speed one or the
other
nobody can tell the difference so the
obfuscation p1 is computationally
distinguishable from the obfuscation of
p2
and a long series of works show that if
you have this kind of io then you can
use it to build all kinds of amazing
cryptographic primitives so the big
question is how do we build it
and there's been a lot of work on that i
don't have time to
give you much of a survey but instead
let me tell you about our approach
so our approach uh builds on a
a framework from uh by prokerskidal from
last year uh their framework was called
the split fully homomorphic encryption
split fhe framework and we give a small
variant of it that we call functional
encodings
and uh so we show that if you build
these function encodings that implies io
and then the question is how to
construct these uh functional codings
so uh functional encoding is a way of
taking a secret value x
and some public function f that has a
long output
and uh what we want to do is we want to
encode x in a way that reveals only the
output of the function only reveals f of
x but nothing else about x
and so we could do that easily by just
writing down f of x but the goal is to
do that where the size of the encoding
is much smaller than the output size of
the function
so that's where function coding is it's
relatively or we can rely on prior works
to show that function encoding is imply
io and then the
hard part is how do you build these
types of function encodings and we do
that by relying on
lw style assumptions and cryptosystems
uh more in more detail we rely on a
fully homomorphic encryption scheme
that's a small variant of the gentrisa
high waters fhe we call it the duo
gswfhe plus a new primitive that we call
oblivious lw sampling that essentially
allows you to create uh random lw
samples without knowing the underlying
secret so this is new primitive in our
work and we give a theorem we show that
with provable security we have lwe and
oblivious lw sampling then you get i o
in other words we reduce the problem of
building io to problem building
oblivious lw sampling and i think
there's something interesting here in
contrast to other generic approaches of
building io let's say from functional
encryption here oblivious lw sampling is
a simple standalone primitive that
doesn't talk about uh computation or
computation encrypted data or anything
like that at all
um so this is a theorem we give and then
the heuristic part of our construction
is constructing oblivious lw sampling
but again there's a standalone primitive
that does not involve channel
computation
so let me tell you a little bit more
about our approach for building
functional encodings
so we start with this uh gsw dual
gsw-free homework encryption scheme this
is a scheme that lets you encrypt the
secret value x and homomorphically
evaluate some function f to get a cipher
text that looks like this
so this is an
lw sample with respect to some public
matrix a
uh times an lw secret rf where rf comes
from the homomorphic the randomness of
the homomorphic computation plus some
error ef plus the output of the function
f of x times q over two so here the
output of the function f is m bits and
this uh you should think of as large
uh and so uh the homomorphic value
ciphertex is just an lw sample a times
rf plus ef
plus the function output times q over
two
and the nice thing about this is that i
can break open the ciphertext for you
and reveal the output f of x just by
giving you the short randomness r sub f
so this lets us uh this this
lets us uh reveal the output of a large
function with a small value
of course there's also the size of the
ciphertext that encrypts x which is
actually quite large but uh by doing
this for many different functions fi we
can amortize the size of the ciphertext
uh so that the overall opening of all of
these different functions is uh
reviewing all these different functions
is smaller than just writing down the
outputs
so the main problem with this approach
is that if i reveal r sub f this can
reveal more than just the function
output f of x and the solution is to
somehow re-randomize uh this ciphertext
c sub f by adding in a fresh lw sample
and then
essentially using the randomness s of
that lw sample to re-randomize r sub f
the problem is where do these fresh lw
samples come from and this is what we
saw via oblivious lw sample essential
way to use the crs to generate fresh lw
samples without knowing the secrets and
we give a formalization of this in the
paper
and we give a candidate construction
uh which on a high level once in summary
is that we uh create these lw samples by
homomorphically evaluating uh uh by
homomorphically generating a
pseudorandom lw sample using an
encrypted uh seat for pseudorandom
function
okay so uh that's why i wanted to tell
you about the construction i don't have
time to give you the assumption i want
to mention a few concurrent following
works so first there's works by game
pass and pracherskidal that gets similar
uh results using highla similar
high-level framework but they have
different abstractions implementations
and assumptions so it's worth looking at
all these works
there's also a follow-up paper that
someone asked about in the in the last
question for the last talk uh by hopkins
at all which shows that these
assumptions can be broken in their full
generality uh using some contrived
implementation of a prf so i think the
and uh the takeaway from that is you
need to be more careful about how you
instantiate them and there's a follow-up
work at tcc which gives a concrete
instantiation
of this scheme with a simplified prf and
results in a nice simple assumption
that's open to cryptanalysis so let me
uh and here thank you
thank you
question for daniel
last chance
oh there's one
zoom
um okay so
yeah i guess that's related to the
previous one so does this paper
construct are you directly or construct
x i o generalized on the theorem by lin
and others
to get iu from x i o
so uh uh at least for this time we go
through the x io framework we we first
get xio and then rely on the theorem of
lineardoll to go get io from xio
so thanks thanks again
so this is the end of today so end of
the session but before leaving so there
is an announcement by
peter by uh yeah regarding durham
session i guess