okay so this is joint work with michael
mayer and michael narig now i have a
habit of um really talking over time
when i do these pre-recorded talks so
i'm going to try to talk relatively
quickly
but you can slow down the the playback
speed if it's going too fast
so in this work
we're very interested in looking for
numbers like the two highlighted in the
middle of the screen
like most good problems in mathematics
or computational number theory
it's again one of those problems that's
quite easy to state and easy to
understand what the problem is but it
turns out it's
not as easy as you would hope to solve
the problem
so the reason we're looking for two
numbers like the the two in the middle
of the screen is that when we write
prime factorization both of these
numbers are very smooth
certainly with with uh in reference to
their neighbors relative to the numbers
that that are close by the largest prime
factor occurring in these two
consecutive integers is 47.
so the problem we're trying to solve is
to find two consecutive integers
whose product
is very very smooth with respect to some
fixed spoon this bound so you can see
that the surrounding numbers have uh
prime their largest prime factors are a
lot bigger than 47 but these two are
very very smooth uh relative to
the numbers that they're surrounded by
so the rest of the talk is
going to go like this so i'm first of
all going to motivate why we're
interested in the problem
um and then i'm going to talk about some
first attempts at trying to find
twin smooths before we move to the the
point of this work and and the
improvements that we found in this paper
which is the pte sieve
okay so why are we interested in this
problem
well some very recent constructions of
isogeny based public key protocols
are both reliant on finding
uh two consecutive smooth integers
in fact they're relying on a special
case of the problem where not only do we
find two consecutive smooth integers but
we find
these integers where their sum is a
prime okay so what these schemes rely on
is finding a prime of the form two m
plus one large prime to n plus one such
that m and n plus one
are both smooth uh and therefore p plus
or minus one which is two m and two n
plus two
are also both smooth
so what we're looking for to state the
problem concisely is we're looking for
two twin smooth numbers whose sum is a
prime
and if we find such an instance then we
can we can instantiate uh b side and ski
sine and perhaps some
other variants of these protocols
to be more efficient than
if we were to instantiate them over a
prime who's whose neighbors are not so
smooth
so really the efficiency of these
schemes is very very dependent on
the uh largest prime factor
appearing in p plus one or p minus one
now to just unpack that for a moment uh
recall that in srdh and psych
alice and bob set this
prime p to be a power of two times a
power of three minus one and that's
because alice computes two to the a
isogenes and bob computes three to the b
isogenys and for those isogenic
computations to be um
to be efficient
uh within the protocol
we want those
two factors the two to the a and the
three to the b
three to the power of b to divide p plus
one
but it turns out that
alice and bob don't both need to squeeze
their their isogeny degrees into p plus
one it turns out that they can actually
um split so that alice alice uses prime
factors of p plus one and bob unit uses
prime factors of p minus one
so if we take p plus one to be two times
m and p minus one to be two times n then
quite trivially the the gcd of m n must
be one the only common factor of p plus
one and p minus one can be
two
um so alice is going to compute m
isogenys and bob is going to compute n
isogenes and what we're looking for is
for m and n to be as smooth as possible
so ideally what we would have is that m
was 2 to the a just like before and n
was 3 to the b
just like before but unfortunately the
largest such prime
where m and n can both be of this form
is 17.
so the largest pair of
twins that are three smooth the largest
pair of consecutive integers that are
three smooth are eight and nine
there's no larger consecutive integers
that
uh
whose largest prime factor is is less
than three
uh and it turns out that their sum is
the prime 17. so that's our best
uh prime that sits between two three
smooth numbers
so given that 17 is the largest such
number that's sandwiched between a power
of 2 and a power of 3 or 2 times a power
of 2 and 2 times a power of 3. what we
want to do is to be able to bump up the
size of that prime to be
cryptographically sized so say
bigger than 200 bits
such that it's sandwiched between two
numbers whose prime factorization it's
not going to be prime powers for reasons
that i won't get into but whose
factorization contains only primes that
are that are up to some bound so in this
next stage i'm going to define what twin
smooths are and look at the first
attempts that were that were
made at trying to to find large
cryptographically sized ones
so let's just recall what the definition
of smoothness is so an integer is said
to be b smooth if it has no prime
factors larger than b so typically we
fix some smoothness bound big b
and we look for integers whose
prime factors are no no bigger than b
now two consecutive integers m and m
plus one
are called b smooth twins
if their product is b smooth so if each
of them is b smooth their product will
be b smooth and vice
versa uh
so that's what we're looking for we're
looking for numbers m and n plus one
that are both be smooth
now
i'll ignore the the um criteria of their
pr their sum being a prime for most of
the talk but it should be said that this
is a lot more rare for the types of
numbers we'll be looking for
um finding these consecutive smooths is
a lot more difficult than uh hoping that
their pro that their sum is a prime so
we're looking for ways that we can find
enough
enough of these uh twin smooth pairs at
a given size because once we find enough
of them then um heuristically we're
guaranteed that or or we should be
[Music]
we should have a very good probability
that their sum will be a prime um
certainly if they can they both contain
many small factors that are um and
they're co-prime to each other then that
rules out uh their sum having either of
those factors um and so actually this
their sun being a prime is is a little
more likely than a random a random
number of the same size
okay so for concreteness our goal is to
find this prime that is sandwiched
between two smooth integers
or equivalently as i said we're looking
for these two consecutive integers m and
m plus one
that are both smooth
and if we find enough of them we'll be
able to find such a pair whose sum is a
is a prime but for the
for for the remainder of the talk just
think that we're trying to find two
consecutive
smooth integers of a large cryptographic
size
now if we fix the smoothness bound and
look for
look for the largest
uh consecutive smooth integers with
respect to that smoothness bound that is
a problem that has a deterministic
solution it's just that finding
all such pairs and therefore finding the
largest such pair is it takes
exponential time so
to give some examples the largest three
smooth twins the largest consecutive
integers that are whose product is three
smooth is eight and nine it just so
happens that their sum is also prime as
we saw before the largest five
consecutive smooth twins are 80 and 81
it just so happens that their sum is
also a prime in general the largest
uh consecutive m smooth uh the b smooth
twins
um won't have a prime sum but if again
if we find all of them then one of the
largest ones will will have a have a
prime sum
uh and so here we've also listed the
largest 113 smooth twins
they have m
being around
74 bits
okay and then the largest 113 smooth
twins whose sum is a prime
is less than that uh less than that
example it's around 66 bits
and as i said uh and and i won't get
into the details here but to find
the largest b smooth twins in fact to
find all of the pairs of b smooth twins
um you have to solve two to the power of
pi b pell equations where pi b is the
number of primes up to b
so i think 113 there's uh
including 113 there's
30 30 primes up to 113 so finding that
largest 113 smooth twins required the
solution of
2 to the 30 pell equations that's not
really an easy task so going much higher
using this exhaustive method is is
becomes computationally infeasible quite
quickly and turns out that we can't um
these m's are not big enough to be
cryptographically secure remember we
want these m's to be at least 200 bits
in size so exhausting all of the b
smooth twins for a given smoothness
bound b turns out to be infeasible for
our purposes
now something that's kind of important
to understand this work is
smoothness probability so when we're
looking at numbers of a certain size
we want to know what the probability of
them being be smooth with respect to a
fixed smoothness boundary is and the way
that this uh these heuristics in this
theory is presented is by presenting the
smoothness bound
as the youth
root
of the number you're looking at so
the probability that an integer m
is b smooth where b is m to the power of
1 over u
is given by this row function this
dickman row function
and all of these heuristics rely on m
approaching infinity but for our
purposes
our numbers are close enough to infinity
that these heuristics are quite good
so suppose we take a random m of 256
bits
the probability that it is 2 to the 128
smooth so the probability that it has no
prime factors
bigger than 2 to the 128
is roughly 3 tenths so it's row of 2.
the probability that m is 2 to the 64
smooth so it contains no prime factors
that are more than a quarter of its bit
length
is
roughly 1 in 200
and you get the point that the
probability that the largest prime
factor
isn't
isn't bigger than one-eighth of its bit
length becomes very very small 3.2 by 10
to the negative eight and so on so we've
got this we've got this concrete way to
write down the probability that part of
a number that a given number a number of
a given size
is smooth with respect to a smoothness
bound so long as we write that
smoothness bound uh as as one over u
um now obviously if u is one the
probability is one because the
probability that m is m smooth is is one
but
as long as
the bigger u gets or the smaller that we
want the prime factors this probability
degrades uh exponentially
now this row function gives us a really
uh
easy way to analyze
methods that we
methods that we use to try to construct
or to try to find these these twin
smooth numbers
so on this slide i'm going to talk about
the three prior methods prior to this
work
that we use to to try to look for for
twin smooths
um and just for the sake of concreteness
we're going to assume that we're looking
for
256 bit numbers so m and m plus 1 are
close to 2 to the 256
and let's suppose our smoothness bound b
is 2 to the 16.
so
the
the easiest way to look for these
numbers now for the
as far as the whole slide goes
if you see a green number
that's a number that's um that we can
construct to be smooth okay and then the
red number is something that we hope to
be smooth
so in the first
example we're looking for we can easily
construct
uh m's that are smooth so we can just
take any any product of numbers that are
less than b
uh such that the product is is two to
the around two to the 256 and then what
we're hoping is that either m or m plus
m minus 1 or m plus 1 is is smooth
so the probability that a 256 bit number
is
um
2 to the 16 smooth
that would be the row function of
which is uh 2 to the minus 70. so our
chances of finding of constructing an m
that's smooth and then it's one of its
neighbors miraculously being smooth is
close to 2 to the minus 70. so it really
means that we'd have to try 2 to the 70
uh such such smooth numbers m until we
can expect to find
a smooth
a smooth pair a pair of twin smooths a
slightly better approach that gives us a
better probability is the extended gcd
approach so what we do there is we
choose two numbers a and b that are both
around half the bit length of m
and we use the extended euclidean
algorithm to
find coprime numbers s and t such that a
times s plus b times t is one
and then as long as we arrange the sines
properly then we get
the absolute value of a times s and the
absolute b value of b times t differ by
one
and then what we're hoping is that both
s and t were smooth
now the chances of two numbers that are
128 bits being 2 to the 16 smooth
is a lot better um it's two than minus
50 but it still means we'd have to
search over a lot of
a lot of a b pairs until we find an s
and t
that turn out to be 2 to the 16 smooth
so again the the intuition here is that
the smaller we chop up these numbers
um
rather than looking for one 256 bit
one 256 bit number that's that's smooth
it's it's a lot better to look for two
to the one two 128 bit numbers um that
are smooth and the intuition there is
uh it kind of rules out any factors that
are bigger than two to the 128 that
could have appeared in the first method
um
so to
now look at the third method is this
power method where we set m to be some
power of x
some small nth power in this case n
equals six
and then m minus one
is
x to the six minus one and we're
guaranteed that m minus one
factors
as x plus one times x minus one times
these two quadratic terms
so
these
they're setting the fir the larger
number to be a power of a power of x
and then uh looking at the
looking at the the
the smaller number as the power of x
minus one
you're guaranteed that these two things
factorizes as shown and then the the
hope is that these smaller pieces um
these smaller pieces
uh are smooth and the probability of
each of the smaller pieces being smooth
is again in this case a lot better than
uh the probability that a a random
number of the the large sizes is smooth
now prior to this paper the best
examples in the literature
uh were found using this third method um
so
here's a couple of examples with uh
n plus one being x to the power of six
and n minus one being the product of
those two linear terms in the two
quadratic terms
so in the first example uh alice
actually has
the the factorization of p plus one or m
plus one
uh is two to the sixth smooth or in this
case it's 53 smooth so her x is this
this value that's raised to the power of
six and then over on bob's side his uh
his val his
factorization that the largest prime
factor there is um less than two to the
20. so that occurs as one of the prime
factors of the the first quadratic term
x squared minus x plus one
um and then in a more balanced example a
slightly more balanced example the
second example
alice chose an x that was 2 to the 12th
move and over on bob's side he got a he
got a factorization of of x to the 6
minus 1 that was 2 to the 19 smooth
so roughly speaking i think two
b being close to two to the 19 was the
best
um in terms of numbers that were close
to 256 bits was the best kind of
smoothness bound that um
the the twin the twin smooth satisfied
prior to the prior to this work
okay so what do we do in this paper that
improves upon that that third method
well if you look closely at the at the
row function as applied to that third
method
the problem with it is these higher
degree terms these two quadratic terms
so if we were searching over x's to to
find x to the 6 and x to the 6 minus 1
being
roughly 256 bits we're searching for x's
that are around 2 to the 42
and in that case the probability of x
itself or x minus 1 or x plus 1 being b
smooth is far greater than the
probability of the quadratic terms being
b smooth
so for example with b is 2 to the 14 the
probability that a 42 bit number
is 2 to the 14 smooth that's the row
function of 3 which is roughly 1 in 20
or 0.0486
but the probability of a
of the quadratic term being smooth
is
the row of 6 which is
10 to the negative 5 or 2 times 10 to
the negative 5.
um
so the idea that we're that we're trying
to look at in this work is
can we find
uh m and m plus 1 that are both
polynomial functions ratio rational
polynomial functions where f of x and g
of x split completely into linear terms
so
if we're talking about degree in the
degree 2 case that's rather easy we can
take f x to be x squared and g of x to
be x squared minus one
and we've got a factorization of of both
f of x and g of x into linear terms but
what we really want is to find
uh
to find f of x and g of x with with
degrees
uh a fair bit larger than two
uh so that the the probability of these
these factors um
being uh
being smooth with respect to a fixed
smoothness bound becomes much greater
so what we're looking for here
is we're looking for split polynomials
in uh in the polynomial ring uh
whose coefficients are rational
with constant differences
so rather than differing by one we can
we can relax the requirement that the
polynomials differ by one and actually
tolerate constant differences
um so in this example this these two
degree four f of x and g of x functions
um they they differ by 180 so they
differ by a constant
but then what we can do
is we can search over
x
such that f of x and g of x are both 0
mod 180
therefore dividing f x and g of x at a
particular value of x
um by 180 you'll get two integers that
differ by one
okay so to to kind of give a high level
over overview of what we're doing here
we're not searching for
large numbers m such that m plus one is
smooth but rather we're going to search
for a lot smaller values of x
such that a bunch of these linear terms
that are that are much smaller because x
is much smaller are all smooth so the
the probability that in this case
uh
one 256 bit number is is b smooth will
be a lot less than the probability of
say seven or eight uh
uh
64-bit numbers being being b smooth
now it turns out that the main
difficulty in applying this approach to
find to find twin smooth integers
is in finding these polynomials f of x
and g of x that differ by a constant and
that that completely split over the
rationals
now after trying to construct them
ourselves for a while and running into
problems beyond degree uh degree three
and four
uh we dug around the literature and it
turns out that this problem is um
is
connected to what's called the prager
terry ascot problem
now this problem
the the ideal formulation of this
problem is to find
two disjoint multisets
a set of integers a1 through a n and b1
through bn
such that their uh their sum is the same
the sum of their squares is the same
and the sum of their all of their powers
up to the nth minus one powers is also
the same so these two sets can't contain
the same integer
uh but
they they need to have the same sum and
the same sum of squares and the same sum
of cubes and so on up to the n minus
month
uh powers all sum together
so that example the example of the two
polynomials on the previous slide
actually comes from
uh the solution to the the pte problem
where
the first set is 0 4 7 and 11 and the
second set is 1 2 9 10. and that's
because the the sum of the numbers in
these two sets is the same the sum of
their squares is the same and the sum of
their cubes is the same and it turns out
that that's as as much as you could hope
for um is the n n minus one powers of
all these uh these integers to be the
same
and it's rather straightforward to see
the connection between the solutions to
the pte problem and how they turn into
the into the two polynomials that we're
looking for in fact all we do is take
uh a linear function of who's whose
roots are all of the uh solution in the
solutions in the first set and a linear
function whose roots are all the
solutions in the second set
and it turns out that these will always
have a difference um
a constant difference when
viewed as polynomials over the rationals
now it turns out that finding solutions
to the pte problem is is rather
non-trivial but fortunately for our
purposes
a lot of this hard work had been done
for us already
um so there's a there's a fair few
methods out there that not only find um
not only find solutions but also allow
uh infinitely many solutions to be
generated from
a given solution to the to the pte
problem
so in particular when we were looking
for integers of around 256 bits in size
it turns out that the solutions with n
equals 6 was somewhat of a sweet spot
now that's not only because um the
number of solutions
uh
was plentiful it's also because the
power n being 6
is rather convenient so
we don't want n to be too large because
if n's too large it really shrinks the
search space
of our x's so in this case if n was 12
then we only get roughly 2 to the 22
values of x that we can search over for
smoothness
but if n is too small then the
probability of the the linear terms
being smooth with respect to a fixed
bound becomes a lot smaller so in this
case n equals 6 was right on the money
because then what we're looking for is
is 12
12 functions of linear functions of x
that are smooth with respect to a given
bound
and
n equals 6 means that we're searching
over x's being roughly 2 to the 43 in
size so we've got enough x's there to to
be able to sieve and look for for smooth
uh for those 12
linear terms to be smooth
just got really dark all of a sudden
anyway
i'm gonna go over this uh next bit
pretty quick because it's all kind of
standard stuff from the literature but
uh the first phase of our saving
algorithm um needs to identify all of
the smooth numbers in a given interval
so i'm going to give an example here
using the smoothness bound b equals 7.
we're going to sieve the 50 numbers from
4350 to 43.99 so the first thing we do
is in every place we we put a 1 we start
with a one
and then we start with all of the primes
up to b starting with two
and we look at all the multiples of two
and we multiply the the running uh the
running product underneath each number
by two then we do the multiples of four
multiples of two cubed which is eight
multiples of two to the four and we keep
doing multiples of
two until there's no multiple
in the interval the last one being 2 to
the 6 64
or 2 to the 7 128 rather
to d6 i should have said
and then there's no multiples of 2 to
the 9 in that interval so we're done
with 2.
we do the same thing for three
three squared
three q
three to the
four three
five three to the six three to the seven
multiples of five
we keep
going
[Music]
multiplying the the products underneath
each number by the
given multiple
and
until we're done so
with the multiples of seven
and then
once we've processed all of the primes
up to b we look at all the numbers in
that interval
and if any number
underneath its index is the same as the
number we know that that number is seven
smooth so in this case there's only two
numbers in the interval that are seven
smooth and they happen to be twin
smooths four three seven four and four
three seven five
so that we when we write out their
factorization of course we're guaranteed
that uh there's no primes bigger than
seven
so all that we need to do then is to
have one bit of information in each
index that corresponds to whether that
index was smooth or not whether that
number was smooth or not
um so we put two ones in the smooth
numbers and the rest of them were
non-smooth with respect to seven so
we've
sieved the whole interval and we've
marked
uh the smooth numbers with ones and left
the the non-smooth numbers as
zeros now i gave the naive version of
the the sieving but uh this book the
prime numbers book by crandall and
pomeranz gives a lot more optimizations
that are much better in practice so we
can replace
um
the numbers themselves with their
logarithms and that means we can uh
start with zeros all along and then we
can replace all of the multiple uh the
multipliers with additions we can use
approximations and we can skip the small
primes and do all sorts of uh
probabilistic versions of the sieving
that are much faster in practice
okay so now we come to phase two of the
the pt sieve so what i just described is
phase one that's the standard stuff
the the second phase is how we use
the pte solutions
uh to once we've sieved the interval we
we then check for ones that align with
our pte solutions
so now let's illustrate with a much
bigger example a kind of real real sized
example
um with b equals to the power of 15 and
the 50 numbers in this interval here so
suppose we've done step one with all the
primes from 2 3 5 7 all the way to 32
all the primes up to 2 to the 15. we've
sieved the interval exactly as i
described before
and at the end of the day we've
identified the smooth numbers in that
interval
and and marked those indexes with one
and the other indexes indices are marked
with with zero
now the output of
that step
is just a bit string of length 50 in
that case but of length the size of the
interval so once we've done phase one
we've processed the whole interval we've
got zeros for the non-smooth numbers and
one for the smooth numbers all we've got
is a bit strength who's a bit string
whose length is the length of the
interval
and then we move on to phase two which
is to check that bit string against our
pte solutions so in this case our pt
solution
was uh 0 3 5 11 13 16 in the first set
and the second set we've got some
repetition there 1 1 8 8 15 fifteen
so what that means is if we
move across this bit string with a uh
a window of length uh 17 from
the
the solutions from 0 through to 16.
um then we we shift this moving one at a
time
um until
all of those indices align with uh ones
that represent smooth numbers in the
interval
and in fact we don't have to shift by
one each time we can just move the arrow
above the zero to the very next one in
the in the bit string so we can
keep processing like that we start here
we see that not all of the arrows are
pointing to ones
we move to the next one we move the zero
to the next one
not all of the arrows there are pointing
to ones
we keep doing that
until
array we've got all of the arrows
pointing to ones and that means that
with this particular pte solution we've
found
two numbers
we've found a sorry in this case nine
numbers that are all smooth but when we
combine them according to those two
polynomials that correspond to our pte
solution
we're guaranteed that
we've got two uh integers that differ by
one that are both
be smooth
and so here they are we that corresponds
to this value of um this value of u here
um
and
in this case we also have that the sum
of the two twin smooths was a prime so
we've got alice with p plus 1 is 2 to
the 15 smooth and bob with p minus 1
also being 2 to the 15 smooth
so this is kind of the high level
summary of the results at least as far
as we'd be concerned within practice uh
we found a prime that was close to 256
bits
such that p plus or minus one were both
2 to the 15 smooth just like the one we
just saw we found one that was 384 bits
where that was sandwiched between two
numbers that are
2 to the 19 smooth and we found a 512
bit prime or prime close to 512 bits
where the uh p plus 1 and p minus 1 were
both 2 to the 28 smooth
there's of course a lot more in the
paper and i encourage you to take a look
at it
but
to finish up the future work we're
looking for for better methods of
finding twin smooths and of course at
any of those levels or at uh at
intermediate levels where we'd always be
interested in
any instances of smoother twins no
matter how they're found