hello my name is oharamon and i will be
presenting the paper three thread
generation attacks on the format
preserving encryption ff3 this paper was
made by myself or dunkelman nathan
keller ayal ronan and adishima let's
begin by defining ff3
ff3 is a format preserving encryption
specified by nist in 2016.
format preserving encryption can encrypt
any domain into itself unlike most block
ciphers which can only handle a specific
uh predetermined domain
for example we can encrypt credit card
numbers such that each each ciphertext
is also a confirming credit card number
this is useful mainly for adding
encryption to existing databases or
communication packets that require a
specific format
where the cipher text cannot have uh
cannot be of a different format than the
plain text
after ff3 was proven insecure by recent
attacks by dirac and vadine in 2017 a
new cipher ff31 was published that fixes
the uncovered vulnerabilities a recent
paper by bain presents an attack on ff31
however the attacks that we show in this
paper are relevant to the original ff3
and not to the newer ff3 one
so ff3 accepts plaintext of a domain mnn
along with a key k and a tweak t and
encrypts them to ciphertext in the same
domain the tweak acts as an iv value in
order to allow independent encryptions
of the same bank
for simplicity we will assume throughout
this presentation and also throughout
our paper that m is equal to
and we use n uh to express complexity um
however
these attacks can be relatively easy
gener easily generalized in order to
also
address cases where m is different from
n
the complexity of each attack will be
portrayed using data time and memory
requirements now the ff3 is generally
used on relatively small domains meaning
that heavy usage of time and memory is
practical
in that case we will prioritize
minimizing the data requirements meaning
the oracle queries
and a cost of additional data and sorry
at the cost of additional time and
memory
so let's begin by presenting previous
existing attacks against ff3 the purpose
of all of these attacks is to enable
encryption and decryption of any
plaintext and ciphertext under a surface
under a certain tweak the most trivial
way to do this is simply to query all
possible planning texts meaning the
entire domain of n squared and keep a
table of size n squared which holds the
ciphertext of all of these plain text
that allows us to then query the table
to encrypt or decrypt any plaintext that
we wish
the first attack that was an improvement
over this was an attack by dirac and
vadene in 2017
that improved the data requirements
meaning that we no longer need to query
the entire domain at a significant
increased time which
although it is uh and to the power of
five as we said earlier these times are
practical since uh ff3 works over low
domains
a second generation attack by hong
miller and true in 2019 uh preserves
this data and time memory requirements
while significantly reducing uh time uh
below and to the power of three
we give three attacks uh beyond these
existing attacks so the first attack is
a symmetric slide uh the symmetric slide
attack is based on the second generation
attack by hong kong it significantly
reduces the data complexity uh down up
to uh enter the power of 1.5 while also
improving the time and memory
complexities furthermore it also allows
trade-off between data and time if that
is required
the second attack is an isometric slide
it's based on the symmetric slide and is
also a further strict improvement over
the symmetric slide while also giving a
better time data trade-off
the third attack is a bit different uh
it's an application of an attack
previously shown by bm document in
keller in 2007 however that attack was
then considered impractical due to high
domain sizes since the attack requires
walking over nearly the entire domain
however
ff3 means that this attack is now
practical since ff3 and format
preserving encryptions in general have a
low domain size meaning that the attack
that was previously thought to be
theoretical is now practical
note that in this attack it is possible
uh to require more in the domain size uh
than the uh then n squared since we do
need to query several different tweaks
however we don't necessarily need to
query the exact plaintext or ciphertext
that we're trying to recover meaning
this attack is still better than the
trivial attack
all of our contributions we
experimentally verified simply by
simulating them many times over random
keys and tweaks we also got success
rates that are strictly better than the
second generation attack
as can be seen in the stable on the left
ha
on the left side you can see our
asymmetric slide and on the right side
you can see uh hong getau's a second
generation attack as you can see the
number of queries and time complexity
are significantly lower while the
success rate is higher
now that we've summarized the
contributions we can move on to show the
construction uh itself
uh so let's begin by the
uh cypher construction so f of three is
an eight round faisal construction from
anon to anon m the thing to note here is
that while most feistel constructions
use exclusive or in order to merge the
left and right hands uh ff3 uses
addition modulo
which is what that square notation means
that is uh due to the fact that uh the
domain that we're working on is not
necessarily a power of two making uh xor
unfeasible
the round function utilizes the tweak in
order to make each round distinct so as
i said earlier ff3 accepts two
parameters a secret key k and the tweak
t the tweak is divided into a left and
right half
into the left half and the right half
similarly to the state
so in order to calculate the round
function of around i we take the
corresponding tweak meaning the right
half if the round is even and the left
half if the round is odd
that is exclusive or to the num of the
round
the result of that xor is appended to
the input of the function and then all
of that together is encrypted with aes
with key k
then the result of that aes is truncated
as necessary in order to fit the state
the important thing to note here is that
the tweak is the thing that makes the
functions of each round distinct if the
tweak is identical in teardowns
then the functions
are also identical
so our attack has uh three parts
first we'll create a reduction from a
round ff3 to for round ff3
then we will break for around ff3 by
reconstructing the code books of each
individual round function using appear
using a subroutine that we will call prf
reconstruction
lastly we will simply combine the above
two steps in order to reconstruct the
codebooks of all eight rounds of ff3
in this presentation we only have time
to focus on the first strand meaning the
reduction to four rounds therefore the
second step we will simply assume uh
that we know the algorithm um that we
will call for the rest of the
presentation prf reconstruction and what
that does is simply accepts a number of
pairs um
plaintext and ciphertext pairs uh for
four round ff3 and returns their own
functions
okay so in order to create the reduction
from eight rounds to four rounds
we need slide cursors characteristic
which was presented by dirac and vodka
in 2017.
for that slight characteristic assume
that we can encrypt under any tweak we
wish
so we can abuse that scheme in order to
create a slide attack so for that we'll
need two tweaks one tweak uh which is
simply the tweak we are trying to attack
and the second week t prime um which is
equal equal to the first week where each
half is xored with four
let's see how encryption under each of
these tweaks looks like
so
if we encrypt under the original tweak
um then simply uh the tweak of each
round is x word with the number of the
rounds as we sign the definition of the
random functions
however if we look at an encryption
under the related tweak then rounds zero
through four our xor with four through
seven and rounds four through seven are
xored with zero through four
what that means is that the first half
of encryption under t is equal to the
second half of encryption under t prime
and vice versa
if we look at it a bit differently then
we can define uh these halves as
functions f and g such that uh
encryption under t is equal to
performing f and then g and encryption
under t prime is equal to performing g
and then f where note that both f and g
they're each f three with four rounds
so using this we can mount a slide
attack on ff3 where the purpose of the
slide attack is to find input output
pairs for f and 4g
in order to do so we will need something
called slip chains which was presented
by floria in 2002
still chains are iterative
encryptions meaning we choose a random
starting point x0 and iteratively
encrypted in order to create a chain
so here we can see encryption under uh t
we can also do the same thing for the
related tweak from a random starting
point y0
note that the functions that
the chains are both alternating
functions of f and g however we only
know um we do not know the intermediate
states between f and g
now note what happens if there exists
some offset t
for which f x zero is equal to y t
as shown here
in that case we can align the chains at
an offset of four rounds to each other
and we can see that since the functions
of g and f are now simply the same in
each chain
that means
that from here here on forward and also
backwards the values in both chains are
identical meaning that the intermediate
values of each chain are the values held
in the other chain
that gives us on one hand
a lot of values for f since f of x zero
is yt f x one is yt plus one and so
forth on the other hand that also gives
us values for g since g y t is x one g y
t plus one is x two and so forth
meaning that if we can locate two chains
and an offset where we can find a single
node where the intermediate value is
equal to the value of the other chain
we now have plaintext ciphertext players
4f and 4g
which then allow us to mount the
four-round prf reconstruction
so our goal is now to find such chains
which we call slit chains for a correct
offset
the problem with identifying the chains
is that it's difficult to do so without
knowing the intermediate values since we
do not know the encryption after four
rounds of f3
the naive solution is to not try to
figure out um what chains are slid or
not that means that for every single
possible offset between two chains we
simply try prf reconstruction on that
offset
if the reconstruction works
that means that we have succeeded we
have queried on a successful slide
and we're finished if it doesn't work we
can move on to the next slide
the problem with that is that this is
very expensive in time prf
reconstruction takes about uh n to the
power of 1.5 time uh for each query
meaning that if we try to query it for
each offset um
then we need to do the full process of
prf reconstruction a lot of times when
ideally we will only do it for a correct
offset therefore we can try to use a
distinguisher which was what hulangit
allude if we have a distinguisher for
400 ff3 then we can query
each offsets and only call prf
reconstruction on the correct offsets
that is since if the chains are slid
with offset t then the intermediate
values uh form planted ciphertext fields
before and ff3 therefore a distinguisher
will return true for those values
however if the chains are not split
chains under a certain offset then the
values are simply not correlated between
the two chains therefore a distinguisher
will return false that means that if we
can find the distinguisher that performs
better than prf reconstruction
then we can improve the attack
so huangit al used the distinguisher
that required uh enter the power of 1.5
pairs of plaintext
where each pair has a common right half
we used the same distinguisher that
holland getall used however we did
improved analysis that showed that it
only required o tilde of n piers
we can simulate such auto event pairs by
accepting only square root event
plaintext where all of those plaintexts
have a common right half therefore
defining all pairs between
each two of those plain text we can
create o tilde of n pairs
since the distinguisher can work in time
equal to the data that it accepts we now
have a distinguisher that works with
square root of n data and square root of
n time
sadly the exact workings of this
distinguish are outside the scope of
this presentation however if you are
interested they are presented uh in the
paper
um for this presentation we will use
this distinguisher as a black box um
only note that it does require square
root of event plaintext that all have a
common right hand
so using this distinguisher and the
solutions we can now set up our attacks
so all three of our attacks use similar
premises of creating chains and trying
to find slides between them however we
only have time to present one of those
attacks
so we've chosen to present the cycle
detection slide the third attack because
we believe it is the most interesting
um
so
how does the cycle structure attack work
so ff3 is a permutation meaning that its
graph is formed of cycles
this structure can be used to find sled
chains more easily
and that is as i said earlier a
theoretical attack presented by bm
duncan and keller in 2007
however as i said in the beginning of
the presentation before now this
attack was purely theoretical since it
requires unwalking over most of the
domain of any certain cipher therefore
it was impractical for any cipher with a
large domain due to format preserving
encryption having low domains that means
that this attack is now practical for
ff3 which gives it additional academic
value
so let's see how this attack works
consider a cyclic change
sorry consider a cyclic chain of size l
in the permutation graph defined by the
tweak t
now consider the intermediate values
meaning that if we look at the chain x0
x1 x2 then now we have the intermediate
values y0 y1 y2 and so forth
now consider the cycle defined by those
intermediate values that cycle has two
traits that we want the first trait is
that its length is exactly equal to the
length of the original cycle
the second is that um
as uh because it is formed of the
intermediate values because of the slide
characteristic of alternating forms of g
and on f
that means that that cycle is a cycle in
the permutation graph of the related
tweak meaning the tweak where each half
of the tweet is xored with four
since those two cycles are intermediate
hold the intermediate values of each
other that means that if we can find
those two cycles the first in the graph
of the original tweak and the second in
the graph of the related week then under
a certain offset those two cycles form
slid chains and then we can use them in
order to recover f and g
so in order for that we need to find a
cycle of sufficiently a cycle of
sufficient length and t and then find a
cycle of the exact same length
in t prime
so let's see how long our cycles need to
be so as we said earlier the
distinguisher needs a square root event
plaintext with a common right half in
order to work
that means that the minimum length of
the cycles needs to be n to the power of
1.5 in order for there to guarantee a
specific right half um where all of uh
in order to guarantee a specific right
half that has square root of plaintext
that i'll have that common right half
according to shep and lloyd from 1966
there is a high probability the cycle of
sufficient length exists and not only
that there is a high probability that a
cycle of that exact length is unique in
the permutation graph of the encryption
that means that if we can find two
cycles um that have the exact same
length one and t and one and t prime
with a very high probability they aren't
just random cycles that have the same
length they are the exact offset cycles
of intermediate values that we need
meaning that it's not a meaning that's
simply sufficient to find the cycle of
the exact same length in the related
tweak graph
the problem finding a cycle of a
specific lane is that it's costly in
data in order to do that you need to
walk over most
of the encryption graph of the related
tweak therefore that
takes n squared data and also n squared
time and memory in order to do so
now once we have found those two cycles
then we can now test all offsets between
the two cycles meaning that we look at
all plaintexts defined by all the
offsets
for example starting by x0 along with y0
then y1 then y2 and so forth
if a specific offset is accepted by the
distinguisher we can then use those
values in order to recover f and g and
first recover the full eight rounds of
ff3
so to go over the full algorithm start
to finish
first we find an input cycle of
sufficient length in the original graph
then we find an output cycle meaning a
cycle of the exact same length
under the related tweak
then we find all of the values in the
input cycle that we need for the
distinguisher meaning we find the most
common right hand value and keep uh
square root of n indices where it
appears and those will be the plaintext
that our distinguisher requires
then we go over all possible offsets
there will be enter the power of 1.5 of
them and test each and every one using
the distinguisher
if the distinguisher accepts a slide and
because of the uh the structure of the
cycles there is a
very high probability that it will
accept one of the slides we assume that
that slide is the correct one and then
we can call prf reconstruction on f and
on g
let's do some complexity analysis
the time requirement um there are n to
the power of 1.5 offsets and the
distinguisher requires square root of n
time to run therefore the time of
checking all of the offsets
is o tilde of n squared
which is also the time needed to find
the two cycles
and as we saw earlier the most heavy
data requirement is all of the queries
required to find the cycles
which is n squared
and that concludes our attack
now
beyond these three attacks that we have
we have some further more minor
contributions
uh which i will list here the first is
that we managed to improve the time
complexity of that pure rf
reconstruction um from n to the power of
five thirds which was what
which was what was used by huang get al
we improved that to enter the power of
three halves
we also added two related domain effects
which related the main effects mean that
we query under separate domains in order
to reconstruct
the encryption
the first is a generic attack on all
cycle walking format preserving
encryption schemes
and the section is a distinguishing
attack which is relevant for ff3 and
also for ff31 um where which are origin
which are three attacks that we
presented here uh don't work on ff3 one
since they fix um
the alter they fix
the slice characteristic slide
characteristic that was dependent on the
tweaks
we also have some several additional
minor results including
reduction of memory and some alternate
attack models
to conclude what we've done here
we presented three new attacks on ff3
where the symmetric and the asymmetric
attacks significantly reduced the data
complexity of previous attacks while
also improving time and data memory and
also allowing
time data
inside while also improving time and
memory complexity and also allowing a
time data trade-off as needed
we also
showed a new attack which is a practical
application of a previously theoretical
attack these findings show the general
potency of slide facts and why it's
important
to make round functions different from
one another and it also shows how
interesting theoretical results may
become practical in the future
thank you for watching