hi everyone i am italy chambi and i'm
going to talk about threshold garbage
circuits and adult secure computation
this is a joint work with people goyal
and rafael ostrowski
the private simultaneous model was
introduced in stock 1994 by feigetal
in this work the authors wanted to
consider a model that would allow the
parties to securely evaluate a function
with just one round of interaction
so we know that this is not possible in
general unless we put some restrictions
or we change the model and that's
exactly what the others did
and they consider a setting where there
are two types of entities
so the first is the evaluator
which wants to understand the output of
the function and then there are a set of
parties that are the only parties that
have inputs
a protocol in this setting has three
main algorithms
the first is the setup algorithm to
generate some correlated randomness
and we will denote the randomness that
each party
gets with
a red r
so after the setup phase each party has
his own correlated randomness
and
now
each party can create an encoding using
this randomness and using the input and
encoding of their input
for each for the part api we denote with
ci
after the encoding phase we go to the
online phase which is the phase where
the parties
actually provide their encodings to the
evaluator
the evaluator now has can use an
algorithm that we call
eval for evaluation
and running this algorithm on input the
randomness of zero r0 and
the encodings of the n parties he can
compute the output of the function f
so what we want here is that adversary
must not learn more than what can be
inferred by the output of the function
itself
very connected to this uh to this
setting is the notion of of cardboard
circuits using this notion it's easy to
realize a secure protocol in the model
we just described
just a quick recap on garbage circuits
so garbage circuits has a garbling
algorithm
that takes as input a description of a
function f
and returns
the
garbling of this function which we
denote with capital f
and a set of labels
two labels per wire so if we have
such a garbage circuit
uh and during the setup we will run the
garbling algorithm we can give uh to
to each party one
pair of
labels
in such a way that
when it comes to
do the encoding now each party can
select the label that
that he likes depending on what is
his input and send these labels to the
evaluator which he can later run the
evaluation algorithm of the verbal
circuit to compute the output of the
function
a stronger notion but very connected to
the one we just described is the notion
of an interactive multi-party
competition in addition to the to the
previous notion this allows the
evaluator to collude with a set of
parties
so what we uh require here is that uh
the evaluator should not learn more that
what what he can infer
from the residual function the result
function is the function that keeps uh
fixed the input of the honest parties
but um
where the
uh the input as lots of the functions
that correspond to
the uh corrupted slot can be
queried with with any value the
adversary uh likes
and the question another question is
whether the garbage circuit
instantiation is securing this setting
and as you can imagine the answer is no
because in this case
an evaluator a corrupted evaluator might
get multiple like two labels for the
same wire and this might in general
actually compromise it's the security of
the garbett circuit
and actually what uh being a little uh
shows that is that um
the notion of an interactive uh
multiverte competition implies in the
silica video fusekish
the work of berhamuda tal in crypto 2017
shows that this notion is
achievable relying just on one of the
functions
and
if the number of uh corrupted parties is
just
constant
moreover
they require the input of each party to
be just one bit
another interesting model is the doc
private simultaneous message model
in this model
uh we still have n parties during the
setup phase that receive all the
correlated randomness but the function
the evaluator wants to compute
is a k input function
indeed
we do not require here all the parties
to to participate in the online phase
but only a subset of parties
of sides k
so what we want here is again that well
we can
be honest evaluator can evaluate the
output of the function
and moreover that nothing more than that
without the function itself can be
computed in this notion only the
evaluator can be corrupted
also in this case
the garbage circuit based construction
does not help to achieve this notion
because
well unless we have at least one label
per wire we cannot run the evaluation
algorithm of the of the verb circuit
as our first contribution
we consider a new notion
that naturally combines the previous two
notions we have seen
so in this one we call that we call
threshold non-interactive mpc
not only we allow the evaluator to
uh collude with other parties but also
we do not require all the n parties to
be participating in the online phase
in particular
we denote with k again
the
input sides of the
function that you want to compute
and we require only key parties to be
participating in your line phase
the first thing we will do is to show
how to construct a scheme that satisfies
this notion
our construction is based on a standard
non-interactive mpc protocol and on a
new notion of a secret sharing that we
call position on secret sharing
the way we construct this tool
is
by relying on standard chaotic secret
sharing that we now revise
we have a special party alice in this
case that has a secret x now alice
she could uh run a sharing algorithm
thus obtaining uh and and values and
shares
distribute those among the end parties
and in such a way that the evaluator
only if he gets like k shares or more he
will be able to reconstruct the split of
alice
and if he receives less than k shares
then nothing is revealed about the input
values
in our new notion alice does not have
just one input but she has multiple
inputs
and the sharing algorithm as before
takes the secret or the secrets in this
case of alice together with her position
position 4 in this case and distributes
the shares among the end parties
the idea here is that
if k parties
if less than k parties participate uh
into this online phase let's say or if
the evaluator has less less than k
shares
as before nothing is revealed about any
of the input of alice
on the other hand if
k shares are provided to the evaluator
and we order those shares following the
ordering of the indices there
and the
share of alice
in position j
then only the secret x j is revealed to
the evaluator
let me give an example
so we have only 10 parties here and
let's say that
the evaluator only gets the contribution
from the second
the seventh and the eighth parties
together with
alice's share
so if we order the shares following the
uh following the uh indices
then the
cherubilis
occupies put the second position
and our definition says that only
the secret the second secret which is x2
ill is revealed to the evaluator
in this other scenario where
p1 does not speak does not participate
in the online phase
but
the party p5 p9 and p10 do participate
the shadow values is in the first
position this means that the evaluator
will get only the first
uh among the three the four secrets
okay in this other scenario instead
the evaluator will get only the third
secret and nothing more than that
so
the way
we construct a positional secret sharing
is the following so
the sharing algorithm
will do
something for each of the secret
of alice but in this
slide here i just want to give an
example of how the sharing algorithm
works
in the case
for the input x2 and for the simplified
scenario where the index of l is is two
so the sharing algorithm does the
following first of all it creates a
three out of three secret sharing thus
creating uh what we call the left share
um
center share and the right share
then for the left share we create a one
out of one secret sharing the same we do
for the
center share
and for the right share we create a one
out of two secret sharing okay we run a
similar process for x1 and x3
and we
arrange the output that we get in the
following way
so
the idea is
that
if for example
the evaluator gets the share s1 s2
and 1 of s3 or s4 that's what the star
stands for
then we have that
the capital s1 contains
the one out of one secret sharing of the
left share so we can reconstruct the
left share
alice contributes with the center share
which is the ping share
now no matter whether
the evaluator has s3 or s4
given that
it is possible to reconstruct uh the
right share with
uh
using a one out of two zip chaining well
we can basically reconstruct x2 because
we have
all the three shares
if for example we are in the situation
where
we have only s2 s3 and s4
it is easy to see that the information
that we have here are not sufficient to
reconstruct x2 because we have
missing
the
uh or to be precise we have no way to
reconstruct the left share here given
that
s1 is not in the hands of the evaluator
so for our construction
we use
the positional civic sharing scheme
i just mentioned and a standard
non-interactive secure multi-vertical
competition problem which let me remind
you
it's a a protocol that allows
um the parties to be colluding with the
we evaluator
so at a very high level uh our protocol
works in this way so assume for
simplicity that we have a function of
cardinality two
and that um only we have only three
parties okay so what will happen here is
that we have three parties but only two
of those will be participating in the
online phase
so the first thing we need to describe
is the setup
during the set setup
we create
an encoding for all the possible inputs
that the function f
could get
to be precise we have a function that
has two inputs and we know the team the
input of of of each part is just one bit
so for the first input of the function
we create an encoding of zero using the
randomness r1 of the interactive mpc
protocol
and then and an including of one using
the randomness l1 we do the same for the
sake of the input of the function
now i will not go into the detail of
these
by using our position on secret sharing
we can create a set of shares
that we distribute among
the parties so
and the idea is that
each party now depending on the input
can
decide which set of shares to send to
the evaluator
in this case the input of the first part
is zero and so he will send
the
the the set the the the set of the blue
shares let's say
uh whereas the third party which is the
only other party that will participate
to the online phase
um has one as his input so he will use
um
the red
set of shares
the idea here is that because of the
security of the positional secret
sharing scheme
the evaluator will be will be only able
to reconstruct an encoding of zero
for the first
input of the function f and an encoding
of one for the second input of the
function f we where the encodings are
with respect to the
uh non-interactive multiparty
competition problem
at this point the evaluator can just run
the evaluation algorithm and get
uh
and get the output of the function
so what happened in the case where the
third party for example is corrupted and
is colluding with the elevator well in
this case of course they can share
everything you can share the correlated
randomness so in this case the evaluator
well might be able to evaluate the
function by switching the second input
but but this is fine because we assume
that the underlying interactive secure
uh
multi-party competition protocol is
secured against this type of attacks
moreover we can prove that because of
the security of the positional secret
sharing scheme
the fact that
the
third party is sharing its randomness
everything he knows with the evaluator
does not leak anything about the
encodings
for the first um
input of the function
that is in this example
as long as the party p1 is honest the
blue party the left party here
we it is guaranteed that the encoding of
a one
that we denoted with the c11 is
protected
so the adversary in some sense he cannot
compute the output
of f on input one and one for example
for on input one and zero
as a second contribution of this work
we consider
um
the notion
of a kt secure dock private simultaneous
message
um so this notion
uh doesn't allow corruption of the uh
of parties other than the evaluator
but
uh it has the natural
relaxation that the number of parts that
could be aligned is not fixed so in the
previous example we had n parties and
only a subset of k parties might be
participating in the online phase
whereas in this notion any subset of
sites t can be participated
um so
unfortunately for genetic parameters of
tk and then this notion implies a
position in distinguishability of
foscation
and
what we do in this work is showing uh
that if
actually
um we are we want to compute our k input
function
and the number of parties that
participate in the online phase is k
plus c where c is some constant
uh then we can still get uh a secure
protocol
and in our construction um the input of
the parties are strings uh
that
compared to the previous construction we
were able only to achieve a protocol
securing the case where the input of the
parties are just a
single piece
another question is whether the previous
construction satisfies
already this notion whether there is
need to do some work so
to give an example
about how challenging is this task
consider the case where
we have again a k input function but now
k plus one parties might participate to
the online base
and in this case for example we have the
party from
p1 to pk plus 1 to be contributing with
their input
another evaluator can compute
can can can emulate the function on the
first k inputs
or in the
in the last
uh k inputs so by discarding the first
one by
um
we're doing the computation the last k
values
and now this is problematic because if
because the inputs might be such that
by doing this shift of one position in
the input that go
in the evaluation of the function
it may be that all the inputs now change
so in this example let's say that the
input of the parties can be described in
this way let's say that they are just
bit right we have one zero one zero one
no inverse second could be the output of
this function
but you can compute also the output of
the of this function where all
the input in all the positions like
uh have been uh switched
and
there is no way that we can argue
security in this setting by relying on a
non-interactive mpc protocol
that allows
um only the corruption of a
constant number of parties because here
it's like
all the parties have been corrupted and
so university can change the inputs in
all the positions of the function
so what we do in our work
is that we prove that our scheme
positional script sharing scheme enjoys
a stronger security notion
and we show that together with the
learning with our assumptions
we can
we can achieve
we can achieve this this notion where
again like we allow um k plus c parties
to be aligned where c is not known but
it must be constant and where the input
of all the parties is
um are
strings so in conclusion we have
introduced a new notion that allows both
corruptions of the parties and allows if
the evaluator evaluating a function
without having all the end parties being
online
and we provide a construction in the
secure adult private simultaneous
message model
for the case where the parties that can
be aligned is cardinality of the
function plus some constant and
uh
in this way we solve a problem that uh
was um left open in the work of being at
all
in europe
2017. so this construction although
relies on the learning with errors
assumption whereas the previous
construction of the threshold
non-interactive mpc
um just relies on longer functions
and with this uh
thank you very much