good afternoon everyone if you are
interested in learning about IOT
forensics you are in the right space so
good all right let's get started I am
loud and I am short so I'm gonna stand
over here rock out
alright so just so you know who I am
who's this person standing in front of
you my name is Jessica hi I have two
jobs from director of friends except
magnet forensics that means I work with
a product and development team and do a
lot of research to help ensure the
forensic goodness of the tools that we
put out and I also teach mobile device
forensics at George Mason University
where I did my MS and prior to them I
worked in as mr. Matt Mitchell described
in the keynote to the gummy square so
mostly as a contractor and then as a
professional doing digital forensics
investigations alright so I always was
told so I was in the Marine Corps forgot
to mention that and I was at least a
couple people you're gonna tell them and
tell them and told you but wrong with
you it's a good way to do this so we'll
do that so today we're gonna talk about
IOT I'm gonna give you kind of some
definition ease stuff of IOT it's the
boring stuff right then we're going to
talk about why we care about it then
we're actually going to get into the
categories where we find the data and
then we're going to dig deep into three
area we're gonna talk about a wearable
we're gonna talk about its marking
device and we're going to go ahead and
talk about some data that comes from
vehicles and then we'll wrap it up it's
a lot of stuff so get ready 140 slides
50 minutes ready let's go alright so we
like to start at the end what no because
I told you I was going to tell you what
I told you it's that the slide you might
see it again so first of all I ot is
imperative in your investigations why
because is now going to be a big part of
what we do you don't look at IOT you're
not going to get the full picture
because if it's ubiquitous you'll see in
a moment why without analyzing IOT we
won't know the full story and as we run
into more areas where you run into a
Christian because of the gentleman who
did the IOT security front are going to
cross that these devices are horrible as
far as security which means most
the data is easy to get databases clear
text and we love that so we're gonna
exploit that number and more and more
often
IOT devices are going to be our thoughts
back they're also coming to be a witness
they also an instance a bond that can
get a victory so we have to think about
IOT and all brandy Browns so what is the
AIA and what is the Internet of Things
as we say it well there are these
horrible definitions you can get in
places they tell you that it's all of
these physical devices that are
connected together in networks I
actually like this definition which is
nice and shortened to say a network of
Internet and that object people to
collect and exchange data using embedded
sensors the embedded part is important
but if you think about it this
definition actually goes back 34 years
to Peter T Lewis who was speaking to the
Congressional Black Caucus foundation
you know it's a promise and he stated
that the internet things or IOT is the
integration of people processes and
technology with connectable devices and
sensors to enable remote monitoring
status and insulation evaluation and
trends of such devices what I'm calling
the Internet of Things will be far
reaching and the whole reason I bring
that up to you it's holy crap somebody
in Congress actually knew what they were
talking about in terms of technology we
care by 2020
seven point six billion people on 50
billion devices sadden six point five
eight devices per person okay that means
it's not just your phone in your
computer anymore right if you look at
these estimates these an estimates range
all the way up to 75 billion devices by
2020 to one trillion by 2015 we did not
get that but you can see some of these
estimations are crazy they're all over
the place and by the way a few slides
are available because these ones are
full of work where are the technology
vendors what have they actually ship
what do we know exists 78 point 1
million wearables in 2015
78 point 1 million it's insane right 20
22 years from now we anticipate 5.1
connected devices
person so you will have five devices how
many of you in here have five devices
with you right now
I do you're gonna watch you've got a
laptop you've got a smartphone you got a
tablet
you got any reader wearing smart clothes
it's got it got knobs on the rim right
how many of you have a IOT device on you
right now I'd say that about 60% of the
room just put their hands up time
importances and we're a little bit more
of a techy group so we're more likely to
have these but we're also the most
security-conscious room so maybe we
should've made 45% of consumer in 2016
that they own dependence and 27% of
Smart Watch 12 four times smart clothing
man until I started doing this research
I didn't notice of such thing as smart
clothing my husband which is smart
clothing with clothes that watched
itself unfortunately it's not but it's
clothes it actually can give you
feedback a lot of things have to do with
heart rate and athletic performance clip
by 2020 more than half of businesses say
that they will have IT systems
incorporated in their business so this
is going into the enterprise
architecture if you'll like it or not
and so when we're talking about the
spending on these devices in terms of
what businesses are expecting 25 percent
of enterprise attacks but are estimated
to be relevant to a IOT devices
why because security sucks so if they're
going to be in the work space and the
security hasn't been worked out there's
a really really high risk factor there
we need to be aware of it and it's also
an issue in the home there's a variety
of reasons that people utilize these
vikas and it covers everything from
security and safety to resource
management such as your smart thermostat
the indoor convenience which is the one
I love etc and what happens now is they
also have to consider all of these
commercial applications because it's not
just your Smart Watch in your electric
speaker your Google home
it's a smart city in the crib it's the
logistics for shipping companies as
their shipping containers around the
world and then they can monitor that
flow
it's the smack city with the traffic
lights and their time based on how many
vehicles are coming up and forth am i
killing you I'm sound I am getting
corrected I'm joking I know you don't
need me to talk louder that's not
something I've ever been told before so
this is a first for me all right so as
IOT becomes more relevant the enterprise
is actually going to be the largest
target so just a mix in here how many of
you are actually working on Enterprise
Systems care about companies from
security okay a great deal of you how
many of you are looking at personal
consumer devices okay great so let's
talk about the different areas where we
can run into IOT devices because there
are some major categories and you might
not even think of everything that's
connected so the first category I like
to address just because it's the
scariest and I am not hacking any of
these for you guys because that would be
bad is biometric because biometrics can
include everything from heart monitors
to insulin pumps to bio chip
transponders on farm animals to actually
track your livestock there's actually
even some biometrics that are done on
clamps right
and is this actually used in
investigations yes this gentleman as it
turns out create committed arson on his
own house for insurance fraud his claim
was that he had actually dumped out once
the house caught on fire he packed a
bunch of suitcases really quickly and
then he broke a window and jumped out
the window
because he had all his important stuff
still well after analyzing the actual
heart monitor and his physician looking
at it they said there is no way that his
heart rate showed that level of exertion
that he packed all that stuff and jumped
out his heart rate did not was not
indicative of somebody who had been
caught by surprise by a fire and because
of his medical condition there was no
way that he could have possibly capped
all that stuff in that period of time so
that $400,000 claim out the window god
guy was committing fraud right all right
wearables now this is something we're
used to bolded that means I'm gonna talk
about it we're gonna go into some data
so you've got everything from your smart
watches like your pebble and your Apple
watch to your fitness gear and I swear
we're going to talk about some cases
with that too and look at some data then
we've got things that go you guys are
familiar with this this is your
entertainment system your connections to
your car these can be remote these can
be aftermarket it can also be your
automobiles built-in sensors that help
it Park the help itself Drive this can
also include things like drones this can
also include autopilot features on the
aircraft okay all of these things are
connected
that's scary the smart home which is
what people are becoming more and more
familiar with and one of the areas where
we're increasing rapidly in use can
include everything from home at speakers
like the Amazon echo which I'm going to
dig into the data with you guys and talk
about it from physical acquisition cloud
and app it's great to do Google home to
home automation where I tell my lights
to go on I I'm testing a lot of IOT
things I'm actually working on IOT
forensics book I currently have three
different vacuums on three different
speaker systems in my house my husband's
happy because the house is actually
clean the appliances like washer dryers
refrigerators in oven and then there's
the scary stuff it's the other category
right we've got things
helped firefighters in search and rescue
missions to be able to be identified and
found we have DNA analysis that's being
done and we have smart cities with these
grids it gets pretty scary and there's
more so where do you find the data now I
get to talk about data that's what I
like all right three primary sources for
data you're gonna find you're gonna find
data on the device itself
warning it's not much the data storage
on the device is small then you're gonna
find data any associated applications
this will be the mobile phone app that's
controlling the device and then you're
going to find data in the cloud the
clouds the big momma man the cloud is
where the data is that you want why do
we care about this because of the
artifacts because of what we're gonna
find it's residual let's go ahead and
start with these wearables so first
we're gonna talk about I'm gonna do one
in each category so we're gonna talk
about Fitbit and I'm chose Fitbit
actually for a reason because there's
some good cases but as you guys know
there have been around for about 11
years so they've been around for a while
they recently acquired pebble so that
was kind of interesting because I love
the hardware for pebble but they only
acquired the software and I've actually
done some pebble analysis as well as
2011 they actually were criticized for
their activity system settings sharing
too much information
they wouldn't fix them but one of the
interesting notes here you may see is
that some users were upset because they
were putting in their sexual activity as
physical activity for tracking and
monitoring their health and calories
burned in that information was made
public and available so what about when
we're using this investigation so I've
got two cases here that are interesting
so in this first case back in 2015 a
woman had said that she was staying at a
house a friend's house and that's while
she was sleeping someone came in and she
was raped and the house was trashed this
was actually a false claim and I think
it's important to talk about how data
can be used not only to find criminal
activity but to exonerate innocent
people because static can help in both
situations and from an exonerating
innocent people
she had accused someone of rape well she
said she was sleeping and someone came
in the actual Fitbit activity proved
that she was up and walking around and
she was actually trashing the house and
creating the scene
and then and up until the point where
she actually called an incident in
another side there is actually a murder
trial that went to trial last month so
this is super recent this was in
Wisconsin and what happened here was
this guy was accused of murder of this
woman and his claim was that the husband
had actually forced him at gunpoint
to kill her and bring her to the farm
and everything else he did the husband
claimed to be asleep and he was wearing
his Fitbit and his Fitbit actually told
the story that he was asleep and that he
had gotten up between 4:00 and 4:30 to
go use the restroom and actually you'll
see why it's only a 4:00 to 4:30 window
that I'm saying initially when we talk
about the data here in a second and that
was actually used in court - and the
first gentleman who was accused of
murder actually did get sentenced last
month for this and the other gentleman
got off and was exonerated because he
was actually sleeping at the time and
the Fitbit proved it and actually the
important thing about him getting up and
going to the bathroom was proof that he
was actually wearing it because it did
register the activity also the total
cumulative number of steps that he had
taken during the period of time while
the watch was being worn was not enough
for him to have traveled the distance
that was actually utilized in the
investigation so let's talk about some
data all right so the first thing you're
gonna get out of Fitbit and this is
actually looking at the application data
in this particular instance you're
actually going to get the full name
birthday and profile image now what you
might wonder about why do I really care
about this information is because it
gives some specific information about
how the person identifies themselves so
everything from their gender to their
height to their weight the walking
stride and running stride is actually
calculated both based off of those user
inputs but they can be utilized then -
that's how the steps are calculated you
they also can get their picture what
they self-identified with with their
picture now you also get that user ID in
the instance of the case I was just
referencing that happened Fitbit was
actually queried and they were served
with a warrant and they responded back
with data they gave a spreadsheet and
that spreadsheet action
they gave information that confirmed the
analysis from the app but additionally
actually gave things in a better
increment so the stride length is
calculated based on a gender and height
that the user enter so the steps and in
this instance I told you the steps were
utilize you'll see that the steps are
arranged in a fifteen minute increment
window so it's how many steps you took
within 15 minutes
and here you see so you get that start
time and end time this is why we know
that he went to the bathroom between
4:00 and 4:30 because there were steps
that were registered between 4 a.m. and
4:15 a.m. and then 4:15 a.m. and 4:30
a.m.
so how can this help just as we spoke to
this shows a level of activity and this
is actually what was used in both the
false rape case as well as presents lack
of movement during a crime is what
indicated that that gentleman who was
accused of a murder did not commit it
floors climbed this is interesting
because you get floors climbed but only
for an entire day so you don't actually
get this broken down into more precise
increments that's what it's based on but
it does indicate your overall activity
for a period of time over a day and you
can use this for pattern of life
analysis so heart rate now we already
learned how heart rate was used with a
pacemaker to register level of our
tivity but you can actually get periodic
heart rates and you get those in
5-minute increments so this can really
show the level of activity of somebody
as well as if they were exerting
themselves which can be helpful
especially if graphed over the period of
time of an incident so was there a spike
in a specific amount of time and I am
NOT a doctor so you would not want to
testify as to intent or what somebody
may or may not be doing but giving that
information to someone who can testify
to that is critical sleep is also
monitored by some of these but it's
actually kind of a gray area you see
that time awake time in bed time asleep
there's some debate about how those are
calculated and this doesn't pertain to
how much time you went to bed and stayed
in bed this pertains to more of looking
at things like sleep apnea so there's a
lot of debate as to what this data
actually means but it can be a useful
indicator in cases like the false rib
case because this actual data was news
that she was not sleeping and it can
play someone in their bed around a
specific time but remember there's some
questions regarding that data all right
now we're going to talk about my
favorite one the smart home so we're
gonna talk about what I like to call the
Amazon echo system get it echo system
all right
so the Alexa app actually was released
in 2014 but what's really interesting is
Amazon spent four years on this I will
preface this I did a lot of work with
Brian Moran on the research on Amazon of
Brian Mooar labs and we wound up finding
some vulnerabilities if you're
interested in this there's a reference
in the slides that tells you where we
talk about the vulnerabilities and we
did some reach back when they released a
new feature specifically the calling and
messaging feature this was particularly
scary to me because they spent four
years on this one
and they obviously did not spend four
years before releasing the Amazon echo
show which had a camera and calling and
dropping in and all kinds of other scary
stuff so the smart speaker is controlled
when you ever you say the wake word
Alexa whatever whichever one you set it
to there's three it's available US UK in
Germany
anybody wonder why it's not available in
Canada anybody know because it doesn't
speak French and Canadians have a rule
that you can't bring the product in it's
actually really interesting and it's
running fire OS so there I found it
really interesting because they actually
want to so now we've got some ones that
have cameras and video and they're great
in the kitchen for recipes but they're
really scary but what's really scary
about the smart speaker ecosystem is
you're not just limited to what Amazon
built there are these apps that you can
build
they're called skills in this universe
and you can see here that there were
over 7,000 in January 2017 guess who I
am asan gets people to build apps so
quickly
all right so I used to live in DC Metro
they actually house classes where they
teach you how to code apps and if you go
to the class and submit an app by the
end of the class you get a free echo and
they do this all over the place so
they're actually funding development of
new apps now if you're learning to write
the application and they say you don't
ever have to have written any code
before if you're learning to write the
application and you leave with an
application in under two hours how
secure do you think that app is exactly
right
and then I'm sure you've all heard about
this in London there was an ad that ran
that said Alexa get me a dollhouse and
hundreds of Alexa's queried the web and
began to order doll houses so they can
be pretty interesting but from a crime
perspective Amazon Alexa devices have
actually been used murders and I will
state that I've been requested to
provide information as to how to obtain
data from Amazon Alexis and at least for
police matters at least four so if
you're thinking that these things aren't
happening in crimes they are there was
actually a murder somebody died in a hot
tub and an Alexa was in the house and
there was reason to believe that the
Alexa had data of interest and so Amazon
was served a warrant and this is a
really important thing
Amazon refused to give over the data
okay
Fitbit gave over data we talked about
that so now it becomes even more
important to figure out how we can get
that data forensic ly if needed in cases
so we can get the data from three
different places and we're gonna get
different types of data we can go into
the hardware we can go into the mobile
app and we can go into the cloud alright
and what you guys don't know about me is
that I'm bi bi pending I used to be an
electrical engineer and I like hardware
attacks so I took these things apart for
fun and what you first get is you've got
a 4 gigabyte ein and ultra flash memory
on the tall echo the first device I took
apart and you can actually create an isp
pin out it's got these beautiful big
tests
points on it so you can go ahead and
solder directly to these and you can
pull the data without taking a chip off
score non-destructive methodology yes
all right
the echo dot mini the echo dot which is
a miniature one it's not called an echo
dot mini of the home it's called a mini
so excuse my vernacular that I actually
took apart two of these because there's
two different gens and they actually had
a different chip and there's no data
sheets on these chips which made this a
little bit more challenging I'm not
going to get exactly into that I assume
they were emmc as I went ahead took them
off look at the BGA figured it out then
once I took one off I went ahead and
wrote the pin out for this and this is a
little bit more of a pain you see how
they're all clustered together and small
and we've got our five pin so for those
of you who are not familiar with doing
ISPs you need your VC C voltage your V
CC Q your data in out your clock and
your command signals you solder to those
five points you connect it to a flasher
box you can pull data for gigs oh but
you need 40,000 Swire to connect to
those which is very very tiny it's like
hair wire I actually had to buy myself a
better soldering iron I was actually
stoked about it I love my job you see
now but I was able to easily pull that
data and what did I get
well I know a lot about what kind of
recordings Amazon's gonna have in the
future in what languages it's going to
support in the future wasn't much user
data there to be honest but I got what I
needed I got my Wi-Fi connections and I
got my registration information and see
that user ID string I know you can't see
it don't worry I've got bigger pictures
of what that user ID string looks like I
got first name full name and device name
and actually on one case that I helped a
PD with this was actually enough
information for them to do what they
needed to do it between those two fields
so that was actually pretty cool the
echo maintains 160 second recording the
last 60 second recording has been
through all the data so rule number one
if you go to a collection scene and you
believe that that Amazon may have been
critical in the investigation whatever
you do whatever you do do not say the
way quirt
do not say oh look there's an Amazon
echo it runs Alexa because now you just
said all three a quick words
so do not say yeah I'm a thot Alexa echo
because guess what the last recording is
going to be you and have fun explaining
that oh yeah it's fine it's not volatile
yeah this is this is a emmc chip an emmc
at the end of the day is an SD card and
emmc can actually put on an adapter that
you read through an SD card slot just
like and put through a write blocker if
you take it off the board
pretty cool stuff there there are
devices that have volatile memory this
is not one of them so let's talk about
the app okay Chuck so now we go to the
app the app goes ahead and gives you
user info remember I told you that
string is important see that customer ID
this is the mamma-jamma because this is
what we're gonna use to get cloud data I
told you I'm his home it's not going to
give you data so don't think that's
going to help you but at least now you
can tie it to a device and if there were
multiple accounts on that device I've
done testing with multiple accounts
you'll get those multiples now how this
is gonna help you you're gonna get the
basic user info that you might be able
to use for a search warrant or subpoena
but good luck eleska tasks now you can
parse all of this straight off the phone
these are all in sequel like databases
nice and easy it's going to give you all
of the requests that were made to a left
Alexa from here you can see things it
was asked right and you can set tasks
for specific time so you can see the
last time it was updated you can see
created times I love anything that gives
me timestamps
what you also see here is a resource URL
anybody notice anything in that resource
URL
that user ID pivots in there okay
this URL if you pop this into a web
browser guess what you popped that you
resource URL into a web browser you get
the actual recording but Shane that's
where they're stored there in the cloud
now you will have to put in the
credentials but I'm gonna teach you some
secrets so there you go you've got to
put in the credential going on how this
could help you
you've got great in photons hats hats
and you get the user dictated recording
now I will tell you these devices all
the smart speakers I've looked at they
are notoriously bad at recognizing some
voices some accents etc so they
sometimes mistake the word so if you are
using critical data that was something
that was spoken you may want to verify
with the recording yeah it keeps the
recording from the second awake word is
said it keeps the entire 60 seconds so
if someone breaks into your house please
say Alexa if you have one of these
devices in your home so you're gonna get
your audio tech same thing with the
Google home it will start recording when
you say the wake work we won't talk
about Linney's things start recording
when you don't say wake where it's
that's a whole another scary incident
that we're not gonna discuss um so you
can also get your audio activity and you
get a resource URL for that again you're
gonna get timestamps you're getting to
task types and you've got that link for
the cloud so you can pull that data down
cached audio how many audio recordings
are left on the device on the app how
many do you think a one so you get the
last sixty second recording it's also
sync there so if you don't have the
device and you only have the phone or
you can only get into the phone maybe
you don't have that's okay you're gonna
get the sixty second recording here here
is the path to it and boom you can play
it it's a sound it's an mp3 note starts
away if I lied there's a day that's a
WAV file because it doesn't actually
give you an extension so just export it
out call it a WAV file and you'll be
good and proof it'll play all right out
in the cloud so again Amazon has the
right to change it whenever they want
there is for each category there's a
certain number
of messages that are saved a certain
number of recordings it varies by
category most of them are a hundred or a
thousand they like these in numbers
I don't recall I have in my notes every
single category exactly how many but I
don't recall off the top of my head so
we did our testing what devices have
been running for two years so we had
plenty of data as well as new devices we
are breaking so if you go to account
data you will see that that string
remember that URL it's important right
now I'm going to tell you something that
I just discovered two weeks ago you do
not need the device already asked to
pull that string anymore Amazon did
something new in the web Amazon regular
application if you go onto your computer
and you log into your account your
personal account and you go to your
profile there is now a place to go look
up if you go to your profile anyone else
in the universe by first name last name
when you type in their first name last
name it brings you to a link with their
profile nobody has set up these profiles
unless they really link them to which
lists already you'll get a fake you know
like just like head that isn't anything
but guess what's in that URL bar that's
string so now you take that string even
if you don't have the device to pull any
of the stuff I told you here your cloud
data URLs go ahead you take that string
put it into any one of these replace
that string you will get all of the
calling and messaging so you will get
the full call outs that we used for the
calling a messaging service you look at
all of the contacts you will get all the
devices attached you will get the Wi-Fi
can fix I can go on and on when you pull
this data down you are going to get a
JSON file mark McKinnon thank you mark
McKinnon he went ahead and wrote
actually an autopsy plugin if any of you
Topsy it's an open source free forensics
tool and it'll go ahead and parcels so
you're welcome to use that parser we
also did a lot of work on Casa which is
one of the skills it can be used with
some Casa IOT devices it will parse the
stuff from those apps and stuff you get
from the cloud as well I mentioned there
were some major security flaws with
Amazon if you are really interested in
that stuff please go check it out this
is what you're going to get if you run
you're gonna get elect to index
card entries groups math data storage
accounts we basically pulled everything
and parse it if you want to know about
those vulnerabilities please check out
these presentations specifically the
fans one we went and depth on the
vulnerabilities that we found and
reported to Amazon and to Casa since
this is a security group I will let you
know that Casa or tp-link tp-link makes
a CAF app hapy link now has somebody
working in security and they were
fantastic and responsive they were
wonderful they actually now send me all
their devices ahead of time to beta test
which I love it's great more free
devices to go ahead and do forensics on
Amazon was also fantastic we notified
them of a coco vulnerabilities one they
had patched by 7:00 a.m. the next
morning after a 5 p.m. notification the
other one they did patch and update the
day that we gave our presentation they
knew that that was kind of their drop
that date on it and I mentioned this to
you for one other important reason is if
in your research you're coming across
vulnerabilities I'm not a vulnerability
researcher I'm a forensic ATAR I still
find vulnerabilities
please use responsible disclosure please
inform these organizations and give them
the opportunity to fix and correct their
issues and who knows you may spawn a
company who's got small IOT devices to
go ahead and actually hire somebody for
security and start addressing that in
their products oh they're completely
aware of the fact in that to them so I
actually met with their head of security
who's fantastic and to them that is a
not a security flaw because you still
need to put in the credentials you still
you need username and password I'm sorry
no you need user name and password to
get that data just like I said whenever
you put in any of those resource URLs
you need the username and password you
do need the users credentials so you do
need their username and password so that
is not a security flaw the other stuff
we found that was completely different
please feel free to check those things
out
things that go things that go alright so
we're gonna look at OnStar so for those
of you who aren't familiar with OnStar
um it's actually been on devices since
1996 that's quite some time
obviously it's part if they're I'm sorry
it's in Michigan and it's a subsidiary
of GM so this is on most new GM vehicles
in many instances you get it for the
first year for free it's available in
several countries United States Canada
China Mexico Europe all most of Europe
Brazil and Argentina so pretty big
global footprint there are some other
versions Opel star in Western Europe and
Chevy star in Latin America the data
that should be pulled from those are
similar in 2011 onstart said they had
more than six million customers that's a
lot of data points on vehicle data right
and they also have an aftermarket
product so it's not just Chevy's and GM
products it may have this it can be
anyone who installs installs the
aftermarket mirror which gives them
OnStar capabilities and there actually
has been some hacks into some OnStar
things and what's great is again a good
company who responded so in 2015
own star was introduced and that
actually allowed OnStar drivers cars to
be opened unlocked etc using a
man-in-the-middle and they can even
start the vehicle you can actually kill
someone like that right think about it
no no it's over the sim so so so any
device that uses own star actually has
an additional SIM card in it and it's a
separate sim that's being used to
transmit data so they actually pretty
quickly responded so July 30th own star
was publicized by August 11th General
Motors had released an update that went
out to every system and it patched it
and I want to bring up again that
companies do sometimes respond and I'm
only talking about the ones that respond
positively
alright so you're gonna get your account
information now this is critical because
you've got the account key and the
account number and that time that it was
set up but should get the VIN isn't it
nice to know the VIN if somebody's
vehicle just after getting their mobile
phone so now if you were stopped and
there is a reasonable cause and there is
a warrant and your phone is examined now
someone actually has the VIN of your
vehicle and if they say there's a police
department or a law enforcement agency
obviously they can go to the DMV and
find your car now that's kind of
interesting so again you can use that
account info the time stamps might be
relevant as to when you set it up but
the VIN is the key here because it's
going to provide you information about
something that might not be known hot
spots
oh great so how many of you use your
vehicles a hot spot well if you do the
password the hot spot and the creative
time in the last updated time along with
the fin because why not include the VIN
on every single piece of this data its
sarin every single one it's gonna be
there it is a unique number and it's
such a good unique number ah then you've
got OnStar remote link here so these
Wi-Fi hotspots now can provide location
related information this passwords might
have been used other places on the
password junkie I love them
recent location searches oh look now I
know where you searched I know the
actual destination address that you put
into your infotainment system boom there
it is and I know if it's sent you the
navigation route or not I don't know if
you drove it but I know at this point
that you got it so you've got
destination information you've got time
stamps you know where somebody wanted to
go this can help me with a pattern of
life especially if you're going to the
same place over and over and you know
what if you need nav it's probably not
your work or your house
unless you're trying to avoid traffic so
let's uh let's step back because we do
do traffic routing so remote commands so
what's great about remote commands is if
you interpret these commands yeah you
guys get it so you can get the requested
command as far as lock that lock door
send avert but those ones such as lock
door and start vehicle these can be
critical in examination you can also
tell when this command was sent by the
user versus when it was sent by the
system so it's time date stamp and the
events themselves can be very useful if
somebody says they did not get in their
vehicle that day they stayed at the
house all day and you have their vehicle
starting and them getting in own star
was patched it was probably them hey all
right
places of interest so you can actually
put in your places of interest places
you normally go or any of my Waterloo
friends in here yes look Waterloo
data-score alright so here are some
addresses in Waterloo you get the
addresses URL from the NAB you get the
actual latitude and longitude room Bob's
your uncle there you go
all right how can this help again this
is location information geo is golden
investigations gives you new places to
look it could provide insight on a
target wireless carrier information
remember how I told you that there's a
separate sim pretty answer guess what
here's its information and just because
of the way lives are in the u.s. you can
request this information from the
carrier so a PMP then can be requested
to actually provide the data of all of
the times that there was pinged out and
you'll get basically the equivalent of a
call data record which includes tower
information so you can potentially geo
locate where a vehicle have been at
specific time so there is basically so
there it is a subpoena target vehicle
diagnostics I can know if you need to
change your oil no that's not important
okay what what does matter is it's not
just the kind of Diagnostics you think
because it includes your trip domitor as
well as your odometer so you can
actually see
how long or how many miles have been on
a vehicle and it does give you the last
updated time so you are getting actual
information that relates to when a
vehicle was used so this can actually
potentially help you know how much the
vehicle was in use not anything super
critical but it might be helpful all
right vehicle info so this is actually
more than just the VIN it actually tells
you the vehicle make and model and gives
you the phone number and the account ID
for the user so this might be
interesting for actually going ahead and
identifying the vehicle even more
because now you don't just have a VIN if
you don't have records to do lookups you
can say oh I know now that it's a
Cadillac 85 it's a 2015 I can go ahead
and target those vehicles especially if
you're not a police department and
you're looking at the stuff so if you're
a private investigator doing some other
information but you can actually
correlate now a person to a vehicle any
questions so far oh yeah no I mean I
could go in pull my phone
change the data push it back to the
phone oh I'm sorry he asked if any of
that information with user modified and
it's not not from a user interface not
easily yes okay so the question is about
data that's coming from traditional
phone usage presumably call data records
being requested from the carriers and
that data being sometimes misrepresented
by attorneys in the court of law and are
there things we can do well I would say
that tower data in itself is less
reliable because there's actual codes
and influence and it depends what sector
and it's actually pretty complex to map
out called data record data so the real
answer is that somebody should have a
computer forensics examiner on the
defense
so that they can actually look at and
interpret that data correctly so as
somebody who works for it for if you're
working on the defense side you should
be advising or finding I can see the
forensics expert to look at that data if
that is the issue and the other point is
it's even if you don't do that that data
can be well you'd still need a computer
forensics expert but that data if they
do have applications like this on their
device or even if they don't because
there's tons of location today des that
comes off of phones in lots of different
apps anything from your weather app to
applications that serve you ads because
people know that ads are geofence now so
a lot of these applications on your
phone that allow other tools to serve up
ads will actually track your geolocation
and those things can be then used to
prove or disprove or corroborate us call
data record data
yes in the back take the sim out the
question was can you find a way to
disable send armed answer and there are
two ways don't pay your bill or pull up
a sim and I don't know it's not paying
your bill actually works I was joking
huh
so Wi-Fi will keep broadcasting but it
is a separate sim so if you pull that
separate sim you should you should be
okay so pull the separates so the point
that was just brought up this gentleman
does a lot of wardriving and he
mentioned the fact that he can sit in
intersection and get 300 cards wrap very
quickly that are broadcasting their
Wi-Fi MAC addresses absolutely
absolutely if you have multiple
locations you can then track where that
MAC address is being picked up again so
let's talk about some considerations
here typically less information is
stored on a device I have looked at lots
of physical devices pull the data from
them your actual locations where you're
going to find most of your data is
typically the cloud and the mobile
application itself oftentimes if you're
looking at the physical device and right
now I'm talking about considerations
with a physical device you are going to
need to either JTAG it is P it or take
the chip off how many people do I have
so a proficient in those here right zero
hands went up I am but I have an
electrical engineering background and
this is what I used to do for a living
great you can do JTAG and can you and
identify points sometimes it's a hard
skill depends on the chipset if you're
there's a lot of considerations and it's
expensive the equipment to do these
things are expensive and it's extensive
training so it's something to consider
when you're looking at the device so the
device itself it's not typically your
best target could be honest your best
target is not going to be the device and
what about non-consumer sources where
you might not have access we're talking
about if we're talking about a watch and
we're talking about something in your
vehicle that's fine
but if I'm talking about somebody's
pacemaker do you think I'm gonna do open
Church F surgery to go ahead and go
ahead and JTAG or ISP that device know
so sometimes it is just not feasible to
access the device what we're looking
about the application there's a lot of
things we have to consider one what's it
recently synced right that's one - is it
the actual device that's controlling it
three are there multiple devices that
are controlling it and then we run into
encryption a lot with mobile phones we
actually do not run into encryption
really with uh with needs as IOT smart
thinks by the way for those of you who
are concerned Amazon does encrypt all of
the network traffic I I did pcap all
this stuff and Brian actually
specifically P capped that but it is
encrypted so you can show a little bit
better about that but on actual mobile
devices if you don't have pin or
passcode you may be stopped for
encryption now there's plenty of
methodologies bootloader methodologies
custom recovery it's etc in the mobile
device forensics world that you can use
but on some devices you will be stopped
by encryption so it might not be a
viable source and the whole point is is
you need to look at the whole system and
thing cloud cloud is really interesting
because from a technical perspective for
most of these things pulling data from
the cloud is not difficult especially if
you've got the username and password and
let me tell you I love things like
Amazon where tells you to use your email
because usually I can get their Google
credentials and you guys can get
credential as a variety of ways right
you can ask the user and get consent you
can pull the credentials from another
device like their computer forensic
image you could fish them there's lots
of different ways that you could get
user credentials depending on what kind
of world you're working in but from a
legal perspective the laws are not there
yet for cloud there are more legal
challenges because there is no good
precedence right now for cloud then
there is technical challenges things you
might have to look into or em laughs
okay so agreements between countries as
to where if
data stored in a different country than
where you're doing the assessment from
this can be a very large pain because
depending on where the device is located
you may not be able to get that data at
all legally it also could be in the
country you are in you are not allowed
to get cloud data from a legal
perspective for law enforcement things
there are some countries where if you
recover the data and the device was
connected to the cloud and you recover
it from that scene at that time it's
fine but if you wait till you get back
to the lab you can't there are some
countries where it is completely legal
to pull cloud data they don't care and
then there are countries like in the US
where there is no precedent and some
jurisdictions are fine with it so if you
go to a law enforcement department and
let's say Massachusetts because of what
Circuit Court they fall under they're
probably going to be okay if their
search warrant spelled out pulling the
data from the cloud source to pull the
data
try to find an investigator in law
enforcement in California who's willing
to take that risk
they won't it's a different Circuit
Court so it's really interesting as I
talk to people about their ability to
pull this data from the cloud the first
thing I ask them when I'm advising them
on how to pull the data say do you
legally have access to pull from the
cloud and it's really really sticky
right now there's also two different
ways that you can pull data from the
clouds from devices and I know we were
speaking about Amazon data with the
cloud but there's two primary ways for
everything what is tokenized and one is
credentials when you use your phone to
authenticate something it doesn't always
ask you for your username and password
that is because there is a token on the
device a lot of times you can just
borrow that token and Relenza Kate
depending on the application some
applications require the token to
actually also have matching information
from the device you can fake that in a
VM or in an emulation for many devices
not perl but there's also a legal issue
with this
in some places using token credentials
it's considered impersonating the user
not impersonating the device so my big
statement here that I want you to
consider is just because you technically
can do something doesn't mean you can do
it because you might find yourself in a
whole host of hot water and you
definitely don't want to ruin something
because you touched fruit from the
poisonous tree right so there's also a
lot of different ways you can access
data so there's everything we were
talking about was just pulling data from
the cloud and there are even some
consumer things that allow you to pull
data from the cloud so everybody and
people here are familiar with Google and
the Google has a cloud are you guys
familiar with takeout takeout allows you
with your credentials to pull data from
your account you still have to parse and
figure out that data that's fine
is that forensic Lee sound will that
meet the needs of your investigation
maybe maybe not if they're potentially
more information that you can get
outside of takeout yes I will tell you
something really cool and actually
somebody who I who I know in forensics I
feel more out of Australia he actually
it's been doing some Google home
research and I've been chatting with him
about it and just recently takeout did
not used to pull the audio recordings
from Google home and it now is so it's
now storing those and then there's the
future and the things we need to worry
about right there was a hack where it's
Samsung when they first came out with
their Smart TVs running anybody know
what operating system Smart TVs by
Samsung were thrown Tizen they wrote
their own operating system oh no it's
okay it's an easy one it's got a regular
file system it looks very much like
Android that's fine and the Galaxy gear
2 and up for the smartwatches run Tizen
but the first one actually runs Android
there have been major botnet attacks
that have been used bringing in anything
from your refrigerator to your nanny cam
etc and everybody is familiar with this
but a hundred thousand everyday consumer
devices used in a botnet December 23rd
2013 and January 6 2014
so these go back a while and guess what
these flaws are not fixed most of these
exploits that were used start still
usable and while most homes are not
using the Internet of Things yet hackers
are prepared for it it is easy it is sad
I did want to talk about some
interesting things and actually it's
kind of you mentioned some of Sarah's
work earlier today Matt regarding IOT
toys as well as other types of devices
but this is I actually want to call I
like to put call-outs the companies that
are doing things right and I mentioned
that there were ones that weren't
helping so forensics bites on November
12th and I reached out to him after he
did that he actually reached out to the
makers of this cool little IOT dinosaur
and asked them how they would handle
forensic investigations and they vowed
that if they ever received information
from a law enforcement agency that they
would go over ahead and turn over the
records and actually the reason he
reached out and asked was because the
semaphore was actually pretty secure so
I thought that was great and I just want
to call out when I do see note that I'm
not calling out hundreds of companies
okay so cognitive is actually taking a
good stance on both forensics and
security and it's kind of that's a weird
thing right so I'm a forensics person
speaking at a security conference I just
want to address it sometimes there's a
little bit of differentiation right
because guess what when things are less
secure that's a win for me in my
analysis and in my investigations
right I think that there's a balance
that needs to be found and we're all
exploiting and looking at
vulnerabilities yes sure the it the
malware it did it not my pants story so
everybody everybody know with but not my
pants means so the question to repeat
the question for those who will be
watching the YouTube video of this was
do the vulnerabilities leave the opening
for somebody to say it wasn't me the
malware did it and for those of you who
are not so who are familiar with the
phrase not my pants this is when you get
a pat-down and they pull out some may be
a drug out of your pocket you say dude
these weren't my pants the reason I use
that correlation it's because many times
it's similar and the right thing for
Justice is to have a digital forensics
examiner on both the prosecution and the
defense that's the only way we get just
things the truth of it is in all things
is you typically don't want to rely on
just one data point to prove a case
right you want corroborating evidence
and so when you say the malware did it
my thought is that there is more than
one piece of evidence that's going to
pull you there so if I've got there's
also evidence of malware right so you
can actually look for that evidence as
well so yes people can go ahead and use
that excuse and five years ago that used
to hold up in court
and now forensics examiner's are smarter
and they use more corroborating evidence
and they actually do look for malware
that may have done what the person
claims and typically we're better in
that realm alright so in conclusion you
guys already know what's on this slide
right right so IOT is important because
there's a wealth of evidence you can
find it's gonna become a bigger part of
what we do in forensics without
analyzing the IOT data you're probably
gonna be missing part of the part of the
picture right I didn't put this on the
original one but that assists the data
system includes the device the
application and the cloud
in many instances you will need more
than one of them to get all of the
information and they're going to be our
suspect more often so I'd like to take a
moment to open up questions yes sure so
the question is if there are HIPPA
challenges to using this information and
how do you tie it in so in both of the
cases that I spoke about
they were cases that were being brought
up criminally and being looked at in
court so in those instances pH I is no
longer at issue because you have a
warrant and a subpoena signed off by a
judge it specifically speaking to US law
there are privacy violations if you just
start doing this stuff without proper
authority and consent you should not be
doing that that is illegal as far as
corporate analysis when we're talking
about Internet of Things you know how
many people are aware that a lot of
insurance companies now give deductions
for you he thinks physically fit and
will issue you a Fitbit and will give
you fifty dollars off your insurance so
here's a more interesting question
can that company who owns that device
look at that data I don't know that's a
good question for an attorney which I am
NOT it is it's a good question right
because it's and there's I could get
into a whole bunch of precedents and
different cases which would actually
make it all questionable because there's
cases on both sides of that from a
mobile phone perspective and I'm happy
to discuss that with you and send you
some of those citations afterwards as
far as corporate owned devices and if
there if there's still a reasonable
expectation of privacy for the most part
when you talk about your Fourth
Amendment applies only for the
government so there's a big difference
between if the company looks at the data
and they provided you to device
or if the company gives that data to the
government right so it's actually a
really interesting area and the answer
is my favorite forensics answer which is
it depends any other questions Oh
perfect yeah thank you
[Applause]