hello everybody hello yeah that's the
only time I'm gonna use that but I guess
we'll get started it's about 1 p.m. this
talk is gonna probably go along because
there's a lot to talk about and I really
hope that you all have interesting
questions for me at the end without
further ado let's get this started
so first of all who am i my name is
Chris I'm doing a talk on turning domain
data into domain intelligence I'm the
founder of DNS trace Pro which is
actually the project that does all of
this so I'm pretty much just talking
about my life for like two hours
I'm a third year RIT student in this
computing security department which I'm
very happy to be participating in it's
an awesome place awesome people shout
out to 4 professors in particular Robert
Olson Bill Stackpole Garrett our Karachi
Jonathan Weissman I don't think any of
y'all are in the building but can you
know thank you
acknowledgments I would applaud but
there are literally none of them here so
ok
so VA and I'm a big geek
I run snort on my own network I love
guacamole I'm a Dungeons & Dragons GM
and what little spare time I have and
I'm not really here presenting as an
expert and I want that to be
acknowledged from the outset at the end
we won't really have a
question-and-answer session so much as a
questions comments concerns and
corrections section I'm coming to you as
somebody who spent a lot of time working
with DNS and domain data you're free to
tell me I'm wrong about something and
we'll figure it out I have a notepad up
with me and a pad let's figure it out so
the contents of this talk are broken
down into seven little sections first of
all a quick refresher I know I'm sorry
second of all the reactive threat
intelligence problem really evaluating
what kind of security issues there are
with turning DNS into a secure service
for consumers and then we're going to
start trying to fix that problem of
course so we're going to look into
scraping and ingesting DNS data we're
going to look at anomalies and analysis
that we've found so far we're going to
then try to figure out if we can
chief proactive intelligence instead of
just reactive intelligence we'll talk
about that in section one technically
and then we'll talk a little bit about
limitations future improvements and then
open the floor up to discussion so this
is going to be a very domain centric
talk and yeah everybody hates DNS that's
okay
I do too I work with it all the time it
is not fun so just for the people that
might be new in the room please work
okay thank you so if you have a link you
have HTTP colon slash slash
www.facebook.com/hcmedvedikharkiv comm
which is a fully qualified domain name
and it's broken down into certain parts
facebook.com breaks down into three
distinct parts top-level domain or
suffix in this case com registerable
domain which is Facebook that's the one
that Facebook actually owns and then
subdomains that's the free domain space
that Facebook gets for owning
facebook.com I want going to tell you
DNS houses a lot of information it tells
your computer how to get to places using
ipv4 and ipv6 addresses it tells your
computer canonical names like where you
should actually be going instead of
going here
it tells you MX records for mail NS
records for name servers text records if
you really want to you can configure
geographic data to be served by the
domain system why I don't know but you
can and of course you can use a request
called aw or sorry any to try to get all
of this for a given fully qualified
domain name we'll talk about that later
and how does it work you make a request
to your dns this is assuming a recursive
query that's the two-year DNS which is
yeah a recursive query that's then
solved by iterative queries you send a
request out to your DNS your DNS goes to
the root DNS and you're like hey you
know this guy wants to go to
facebook.com how do we find com
and you know you get a reply saying this
is how you get sitcom your dns asks com
how to get to Facebook's name server
your dns then goes to Facebook's name
server and says how do I actually get
this person to WWF ace be calm and it's
a hierarchy this is a hierarchical
system and there's no point that any of
these DNS servers are obligated to
expose any more information than the
information that you specifically
requested they're not going to tell you
everything about Facebook or everything
about com it probably will tell you all
the top-level domains but we'll talk
about that later too but anyway it makes
this kind of close since there's this
hierarchy and nobody's obligated to tell
you anything that you haven't already
figured out something about for example
a fully qualified domain name it's hard
to get some data out and now we're going
to talk about how DNS security works for
the consumer for example if domain is
seen doing something bad like
distributing malware for example you
know what kind of security intelligence
do we have there to protect the end-user
and we have some real problems first of
all and let's consider for example that
let's realize for example that reactive
security is not great security and let's
consider a file-based antivirus file
signature based antivirus that is just
100% based on signatures malware author
generates some malware the antivirus
authors catch a copy of that malware
they analyze it they get a signature
they publish that signature to all other
users of their product in the meantime
the malware authors generated 5 10 50
more files with different signatures by
making small changes to code or making
morphic code so it's really really easy
for people to circumvent and it's purely
reactive so it's difficult and costly to
maintain for every new file that comes
in you have to develop a new signature
and you have to publish those and in
that time your users are getting
infected all over the place this is the
kind of stat or status that you know
malware was add in 2000 2005 it's not
great it's better than nothing don't get
me wrong but it's it's not great and
things did get better better for
anti-malware programs they got a lot
better we now have heuristic analysis
but do we have that for the domain space
here's a quote from Symantec
an IP address earns a negative
reputation when Symantec detects
suspicious activity such as spam or
viruses originating from that address
that sounds like purely reactive
security to me now when do you think
that this was published if you guessed
the last night the answer would have
been you know not surprising this is the
kind of status that a lot of security
companies are at when looking at the
domain space and trying to proactively
block threats at a network level here's
a little bit better if the IP address is
changed frequently and if the site has
an IP address that was hosting malicious
Continent content in the past it can
result in a poor web reputation now this
is from Cisco Talos and this is actually
a really great step forward because
they're starting to use heuristics so
they've noticed that malicious domains
tend to change IP addresses a lot more
frequently than non malicious domains do
now that is a good start and domain
safety heuristics are available and they
do help you can look at how recent the
registration was because some malware
authors tend to burn through a lot of
domains very very quickly you can look
for frequent address changes as Talos
does you can get estimates on popularity
if you have that kind of footprint on
the internet which of course this being
I am a college student we do not and
what can we do to improve this so
consider the following there exist
systems that are relational learning
systems these systems can predict
unforeseen or future relationships
between entities based on past
observations and you can see really good
examples of them down here they tend to
be directed or undirected graphs with a
very set structure and they are
typically very interconnected now we
can't really do this for malware malware
that has too many dimensions it can be
too many things you can't classify it as
easily as you can other data so malware
X does 50 different things and malware Y
might do 200 different things and just
classifying that much is going to be a
huge investment and then what are you
gonna get out of it you're not going to
get a huge amount unfortunately but
don't names
well domains have a very fixed structure
it's very very strongly ingrained into
the domain name system there are only a
certain number of things that a domain
can be it resolves to certain IPS
resolves to certain other domains it has
certain records of certain contents and
that's pretty much it so what if we try
to apply relational learning to the
domain space
well we're going to need a lot more than
just a you know say a list of some
domains you need to have a huge quantity
of parsed domain data you need to have
fully qualified domain names you need to
have subdomains you need to have pretty
much all TL DS you need to be getting
everything that those resolved to as
well because you have to build the
interconnected graphs and you're not
going to be able to connect
facebook.com/ to yahoo.com without a
little bit of an IP and some collect
this passively there are big
repositories of domain data for example
DNS DB that's run by Farsight we don't
have again the resources to do that
we can't establish a passive tap where
we get you know 2.7 billion data points
per day just by observing the kind of
DNS traffic that goes through the world
we have to acquire this kind of data
aggressively we have to perform the
queries we have to figure out what goes
where on our app and we need as much
threat intelligence as possible to go
with that it doesn't do you any good to
notice that yahoo.com and malware dot
are you go to the same place if you
don't realize that malware dot ru is
malicious you need to be able to figure
that out so you can see this information
into the relational intelligence systems
that we create and then of course you
need to make it responsive because it's
not very useful to have a graph database
that tends you know 30 minutes to render
a small graph with upwards of you know
like 500 but less than 1,000 nodes and
then you need real methods of analysis
you can't just say well this touches one
other malicious thing it's probably bad
you see a lot of stuff get flagged
you're going to have a lot of things
going to certain places for example if
you're looking at a hosting provider
there could be a ton of domains pointed
you know one IP and if one of those
domains is malicious and you
automatically flag everything else
you're going to have a huge false
positive so you need to figure out in a
quantifiable manner how you're going to
evaluate these graphs to generate real
intelligence that is not just okay well
it's getting somewhere near something
malicious so I'll put that
so let's get into it the first thing
that we need to do is acquire a list of
TL DS well you can go to da da da da an
org and get a list of all TLDs
congratulations that's the easiest part
of this entire talk
currently there are 1543 top-level
domains active this list is available by
HTTP and by FTP if you do so desire
great ok this wasn't really a challenge
now acquiring domains is going to be a
little bit harder so each top-level
domain has a zone file and that zone
file contains a list of all the domains
and also all of the name servers for
those domains and you can buy access to
zone files through certain providers for
about 300 dollars per year
which seems to be a reasonable price for
anybody who isn't a student and skin
broke and that's my ramen money so we're
not going to do that you could
alternatively request access to zone
files from those registrar's directly so
pretty much circumventing the middleman
that aggregates that zone data and going
straight to the register and being like
hey I'd like to see your dot-com zone
file please and a lot of them will say
yes that's fine as long as you're using
it for a real problem solving thing are
you doing valid research for your an
academic and a lot of them will say
great some of them won't such as Yahoo
Zappos etc which all are on their own
top-level domains and will not let me
touch them and if you wanted to do this
kind of thing in book you can go to I
can see zds which is the centralized
zone domain service zone data service my
apologies and you can actually bulk
request for I think it's 500 or more
zone files with like a single form now
we get into the real problems so we've
gone down the hierarchy from the root to
top-level domains to domains now we have
to figure out with all of those domains
how do we get those of the man
and I'll give you a hint they're not so
kindly you know regarding people
requesting access to their zone files
unfortunately that's just how it is for
a lot of companies Facebook doesn't see
the real value in exposing the
facebook.com zone file to me a
researcher even if it's for a good
purpose they like to keep stuff private
and that's fine so we're just going to
discover things that you know anyway now
there are certain things that are gonna
be out of scope I'm gonna just talk
about like how you could do this if you
wanted to and why we're not going to do
that and give you some examples of tools
that you could use there are going to be
other things that in scope that will
actually do demos of I have the demos
pre-recorded because I don't trust the
Wi-Fi so they're really nice gifts I
promise so first of all you could try to
brute force look up something you know
you go to facebook.com you point dig at
it and then you write a quick little
script to generate every possible
subdomain from A to Z zzzzzz absolutely
not that is a great way to have somebody
knocking on your door asking who the
legal resident is because you're being
served papers you know a good lawyer can
make this look like a denial of service
attack and if you tried to do it at
scale which we are going to try to do a
good lawyer actually a bad lawyer could
make it look like a denial or a
distributed denial of service attack you
don't want to do this and if this is the
first thing on your list to try shut
down y'know
take a breather get a monster you can
figure out a better method a good way of
doing this in normal engagements would
be to crawl a website if your domain
that you're investigating has a website
online anywhere that you can see you
might as well just go on there and
follow as many links as possible it's
fairly complex and resource intensive at
scale if you're rendering the entire
document but you know it's definitely a
possibility and you can do this with
skip fish web scarab etc there are a lot
of great options to do this and I do
recommend it for your own engagements
but not here and we could also do you
know looking things up in search engines
and
of DNS and again this is great for
real-life engagements I actually
strongly recommend this as a starting
point to just identify possible areas of
scope for any engagement that you might
be going into and you can use sub Lister
which is built into Kali for this it's
phenomenal just give it a domain and it
will find everything Google Yahoo Bing
passive DNS etc but this depends on
external services and those external
services are going to blacklist us if
all of a sudden we have a thousand
queries per second hitting them so
that's now let's start to evaluate what
might be in scope now brute force wasn't
a great idea but what if you did a
probabilistic lookup you know there are
certain domains and subdomains that tend
to show up more frequently than others
for example www or Mayo or things like
that
so if you were to perform lookups on
things that you suspect or more likely
to be present than not that could really
help cut down on the search space and
you can combine that with anything that
you've generated say a word list off the
website that you just scraped to cut
that down even further and you can
actually enumerate my site using some
software that I wrote for Robert Olsen's
class with 596 queries total just based
off rapid Evans forward DNS data set so
parse rapid7 down I actually provide
this in the github but you parse it down
to the most common subdomains you count
them you sort them by the frequency and
then you run through until you run out
and so here's that software you know
available here's that available software
running in default mode with the default
list
I'm just saying hey we're going to
enumerate this domain using a records
then you give it a couple seconds thanks
so please there we go and that's all of
the subdomains that were present for my
domain at the time enumerated and five
96 queries exactly takes about 10
seconds
it's a single-threaded program I wrote
it in like an hour you can write
something much better to get that time
much or much much farther down and
things will work out for a loophole for
you now you can also do reverse DNS
which is a simple little dig query just
the dash X and it's useful for ipv4
addresses pretty much for taking an ipv4
address you're saying hey domain name
services what is what domain goes here
but unfortunately that usually ends up
in ISP assigned address is not really
anything of use so you know the Digg
plush short for 1 to 1.7 3.6 2.2 ends up
with something dot cable dot telstra
cleared dotnet it doesn't tell us
anything so it's something that we're
not going to not use but it's not
something that's going to give us a huge
amount of data now let's talk for a
moment about DNS SEC DNS SEC is a set of
security extensions for DNS it provides
three main things origin authentication
so you know that the reply is coming
from a name server of authority it
provides data integrity so you know that
the reply that you're getting is
actually correct reply there's been no
errors in transit etc and you also get
authenticated denial of existence denial
of existence
well how does they make that work so
what they actually ended up doing for
denial of existence is they implemented
a record called n sec and n sec is
pretty much the next secure record which
in a lot of cases tends to be the next
record that exists so if you request
test example.com which clearly does not
exist the name server will reply that
the next secure record is WWE example
comm oh boy that's phenomenal and you
can see you can test things out right
here and if you look very closely you'll
see 164 in and SEC www.example.com and
you get exactly what the crews going to
look like and then you can just push for
that and then Krieg for the next thing
you know probably doesn't exist and
either you'll get a response and cool it
exists you don't get a response and you
understand the next secure record and
then you have the next target to
enumerate it's awesome and you can do
this with tools like n SEC 3 map which
for being a proof of concept tool has a
lot of really nice options this is
available on github it's not mine but
it's available on github and it's
awesome and we're going to per say yes
and sec to enumerate and would you look
at that there's all of the subdomains
for PayPal and oh that'll take I don't
know two more seconds one Mississippi
two Mississippi okay it's closer to
three but anyway with a mere six hundred
and eighty nine queries
we've now enumerated the entire sub
domain space of PayPal now to circle
back a little bit and just reiterate how
bad root for us is if you wanted to do
that just plain old naive brute force
that would have I believe the word was
Septon des Cillian I are there any
mathematicians in there it's like 10 to
the likes 55 it's ridiculous the amount
of queries that you would have to
perform and that is the query throughput
of Google ferb several millennia out
probably until the end of time it's a
lot of stuff so techniques like this can
really cut down on the resources
required to enumerate a domain in its
entirety
now some people very quickly noticed
that that was a bad idea
and so revised II NSX standard came out
that introduced the insect three record
and that improves privacy but doesn't
solve the problem completely
so pretty much instead of when you
request test example.com instead of
replying with WWE example comm is the
next secure record it says that there is
a secure record before this and past
this and it presents the hashed values
of those subdomains now that is
frustrating doing an DN n site three
look up on 0x0 potato de which clearly
does not exist but is secured with
insect three produces nothing of use I
mean if you can figure out just by
looking at that you know screenshot what
the next secure record is in plain text
you're a god and you should be
presenting not me but it's hatched and
these tend to be fairly short because WW
even if you're guessing every possible
character like possible combinations for
three characters on your local machine
is pretty low so what we do is we
enumerate the N SEC three secure domain
figuring out all of the you know there
is nothing between X hash and Y hash you
can and still enumerate all of those
hashes not the domains themselves but
the hashes and then what you can do is
you can throw that into hash cat if you
really wanted to and I did really want
to so I compiled OpenGL for my Xeon CPU
and I threw hash cat at it at the dot de
top-level domain zone file that I've
just enumerated I'm after a mere couple
seconds we're already up to 11%
discovered this is using a very very
naive mask it's not very useful it's not
very fast but with a little bit of
this could actually be a viable way of
enumerated domains especially if you
have per se several GPUs which the
system did not but that still wasn't
enough for some people so if you are
CloudFlare and by the way if there are
any CloudFlare guys in the audience
you're the bane of my existence
because they've implemented something
like this where instead of assuming that
the next secure record is going to be a
record that exists it will generate
records on the fly that are garbage
records and you'll see running through
this again we get nothing there's an
existing domain
ABCDEF what are these they're not mine
but you know CloudFlare says that this
stuff exists and all of a sudden
enumeration is no better than brute
force
great job CloudFlare whoops for me but
going through a recap here if you are an
engagement with somebody who has a DNS
SEC engage DNS SEC enabled site
enumerated you lose very little by
attempting an onset or an SEC three walk
worst case scenario you find out that
they've secured it with CloudFlare or
similar improve DNS SEC methods where
they return garbage and SEC responses
and you know oh well you've lost five
minutes of time but if it does work
you've suddenly enumerated their entire
domain space and that's phenomenal
and SEC five is on the way and SEC five
introduces certain improvements that
makes it such that people cannot do
walks whatsoever by default and you know
for my project sake hopefully it doesn't
reach mass adoption anytime soon because
I like being able to do in psyche loss
but another thing that you can do to
enumerate domains is of course a zone
transfer you can politely ask
the you know zone owner Facebook's
name server like hey can you please give
me the zone file and there are very few
reasons to have this enabled but some
people still do between 1 & 7 & 1 in 10
domains has a name server that will
actually allow you to perform a zone
transfer so all of a sudden you don't
just get you know a list of subdomains
though in this case it was very funny to
have a list of all the North Korean
domains as of September 2016 which is
phenomenal by the way one entire country
28 domains right but you can perform an
expert with very very little resource
investment and all of a sudden you get
everything in the zone so here we're
going to do a little test zone transfer
against zone transfer Emme which is a
great place to test your zone transfer
skills and we got everything we not only
get the domains subdomains we get a
records MX and a server everything
everything we could possibly want and we
are starting to get into the next stage
of the project which is not just sorry
not just fully qualified domain names
but actually getting domain data where
does this go and that's great but we're
really only halfway there now we have to
resolve the domain space so we have a
list of let's say a billion for example
1 billion fully qualified domain names
we've parsed them down into sub domains
in the domains into suffixes but we need
to actually figure out if there's any
more going on as well as trying to
figure out well where does this go what
a records what MX records what NS
records you know what are all of the
characteristics of this domain so we can
link it to other domains and the way
that we're going to go about this is
we're going to DIY it we're going to try
a zone transfer
we're going to try any queries which
again cloud filler people in the
audience you're the bane of my existence
because cloud fleur has deprecated the
Annie query also known as they've
stopped responding to them which
apparently if you're an Internet company
that's large enough means that you're
officially deprecating it so they are
not responding to any queries anymore
that's no longer a viable way of
enumerated any sort of data they just
reply with another garbage response
which is to be fair I I might be
complaining about cloud floor a lot I
understand the decisions that they've
made here and I understand that any
queries are really really useful for
example denial of service amplification
but you know it's frustrating for me as
somebody who would actually like to use
the any query instead of having to
enumerate you know option number three
iterating through every single desired
query type for every single fully
qualified domain name that we have in
the database but if that's what it comes
down to that's what it comes down to and
we're going to thread this because each
domain is independent and we're going to
geographically distribute it such that
we might be able to pick up on
interesting little things like miss
configurations or places that should
reply but aren't replying and things
like that and of course there is really
no excuse not to use the data that
others provide for example rapid sevens
sonar project they actually publish
several billion data points per week of
scans that they have performed off
Amazon AWS resolving all of the forward
DNS names that they know of looking into
a continuation of SSL observatory and
also looking into reverse DNS which is
something that we talked about
previously they do all of those queries
on a weekly basis why would we we could
just harvest it from them and they
permit non-malicious non-commercial use
now I'm using this for non malicious
purposes what you do with the service is
entirely up to you but we'll try to keep
it clean and then of course we have to
store everything so we're coming into
possession of several hundred gigabytes
of data every week how are you going to
store and organize that in a way that
you can actually query against it the
answer for us the scalable database
solutions we ended up after many trials
and errors with Percona 5.6 my sequel
drop-in variant with topo DB running as
a back-end which has actually scaled
fairly well to our solution unlike nodb
which pretty much folded after a certain
period of time
toku DB has well resisted all of the
challenges that we've thrown at it so I
do recommend it for large data projects
that you might be looking into a storage
method for and compression works wonders
this is all textual data you have no
reason to not use compression I know
you're like you've compressed a movie
once it didn't do anything this text
data it works awesome we use low
compression settings we get about 2/3
space savings it's awesome no impact on
performance time either great and if
you're querying against it index index
index index anything you're creating
against you should have an index because
otherwise if you're doing a full table
scan and you do not want to do a full
table scan on 1.3 billion rows of data
for example so let's get into the really
fun parts we have a lot of data let's
analyze it whoops I should have probably
deleted that oh well anyway so first of
all we have some interesting domain
errors that we've come across things
that we couldn't parse using our
internal tools and I'm not really sure
because I am NOT an authority but I'm
relatively confident that there is no
top-level domain called devil one five
two one nine four five nine three three
any Corrections no doesn't seem like a
registrable top-level domain and so you
come across interesting issues like that
again
dot a EO 152 no idea how this ends up
happening then we got into an
interesting one DC - WP prod - f5 if
anybody has any ideas as to what that is
I'd love to hear them the idea that came
closest to my mind when I was looking at
that was f5 big IP application
accelerators ok
I'm getting I'm getting some nods but ok
who knows and then we actually came up
against some very odd results that
actually really baffled me for a while
Nick thought LLC and Mac dot sport but
that seems like it should be valid and I
am says yes Diana says yes for LLC it
also says yes for sport these are TL DS
that exist nick is a fine domain name
that meets criteria right here very low
but it meets them but Mozilla's public
suffice suffix list says no and that's
actually a problem so we use Mozilla's
public suffix lists internally to figure
out what a registrable domain is because
if you take the naive approach of saying
like WWE facebook.com/ w w is the
subdomain facebook is the register bull
domain.com is the top-level domain well
we're just going to explode on the
periods and then take the last value and
that's the top-level domain that's the
suffix and then anything after that
directly is the registry bool domain
sounds great and then you hit a site
like dark net co uk if you apply the
same logic you're going to end up with
doc how is your registerable domain and
dark net as your sub domain so you
actually can't split them naively you
have to use a suffix list that will
allow you to separate things into what
is most likely and what is not most
likely a registrable domain based on
these suffixes that are currently
available the largest of which is the
Mozilla public suffix list it's
available for free you can find it on
github or public suffix level or things
like that and it's actually the list
that a lot of
rousers used to determine where users
where user could ease can be set because
you can set a cookie for your subdomain
or for your domain and if Mozilla's
public suffix list is having some
trouble figuring out what the
registrable domain is that should be the
maximum level that somebody can set a
cookie for all of a sudden you can set
super cookies that expand way beyond
what you should reasonably be able to
set data for and that's very bad
and I've actually poked the dragon and I
submitted a github issue and it's the
first github issue that I've ended up
submitting ever actually to any company
that is not me so the public suffix list
is actually missing a couple I am a
recognized top-level domains and I want
to figure out what's going on with that
they haven't responded yet find out
we've also seen some interesting invalid
types who I notice I'm running a long
time we're gonna burn through this so
we've noticed some interesting invalid
types for example a query type was
returned to us as a 104 - 100 - 169 I
can keep going it doesn't really seem
like a thing that exists when normally a
type for a DNS query is a or bought a or
C name who knows it returns some
interesting values that actually
returned a link to an ec2 instance and
then said that it was an a record
interesting and then we had DC - WP prod
- f5 I appear again and it appeared
talking about Khanum WS if any of you
want to investigate into that and tell
Kanab WS that they might have a f5 big
IP application accelerator that's acting
a little haywire you definitely could
let's look into stats so with the ipv4
address space the DNS a replies we
actually found a fairly significant use
of private IP space so this these are
private IP replies on public dns space
which is not necessarily good and you
honestly it was a very small percentage
of all of the replies that we got you
know hovering around 0.1% but that's
pretty huge when you consider that 0.1%
can be you know several million replies
that are exposing private IP mappings
to the public IPS or the public dns
space so there's actually a huge amount
of use of loopback the follower was 10.0
well 10.0.0.0 slash eight I met a couple
other notables that had a really good
amount of data being exposed so
definitely something to look into and
you hear a lot Google's touted you know
twenty percent of people visiting our
service are using ipv6
that's great null only about 1.1 percent
of domains that we knew about actually
resolved anywhere in the ipv6 space
everything else was ipv4 and that's a
holdover to how slow the DNS system is
with updates how slow people might be
moving their services over to ipv6
enabled servers data centers etc it is
what it is oh and it's an interesting
looking glass into the ipv4 to ipv6
transition we also got some interesting
cname mistakes just for reference if
you're putting HTTP into your canonical
name DNS record that's not how it works
unfortunately you have to keep things
within the DMS space only so you get
some interesting responses here we
actually saw a huge number that had a
cname that seemed to be some sort of
hash like the 6c a ofe etc responds
again oddities if any of you want access
to this data access to the database you
know you are free to do your own
research with this kind of stuff we also
get the occasional little keyboard smash
and it's at the bottom
FTF d DF DF DF great good job
an administrator got very bored and we
also get the occasional
little mishap where somebody forgets the
dot and dot com it happens and we
actually see that a lot of people point
their MX or NS records to localhost
which doesn't work out on the public
internet but that's the kind of stuff
that we see that amounted for nearly 1%
of em X + NS queries that we actually
got to apply to so very interesting
there it's probably a default on certain
systems which is why we see this level
so high but again if you want to receive
mail you probably need to set something
other than localhost so now we have a
huge amount of data what do we do with
this how are we going to work with this
we have to then map this together into
these great spanning graphs and how are
they even going to tell us stuff well
first of all we need to add threat
intelligence I talked about it a little
bit at the beginning and then you
probably forgot about it but by adding
more and more threat intelligence we can
really get a greater view into the
security of ganna space and we can get
better information about what clusters
of Deanna's information we should be
labeling our bad versus good and we
ingest as many feasts as possible we
ingest phishing feeds from open fish and
other sources like that domain
reputation feeds I mean just IP
reputation feeds we ingest the bogan
reference from teamsim Roo if theirs is
that even how I say it I don't know it's
awesome though
and we are considering heuristics like
the approach that Cisco Talos had
there's really no reason not to try to
evaluate heuristic data that we can get
for a domain
we're not going to be able to get our
hands on popularity data for a domain
but we might be able to figure out
things like when was it registered who
is it registered to you know what kind
of activity has it had like moving
around this kind of stuff can be used to
more accurately establish what is and is
not malicious and filter out both false
positives as well as false negatives and
we want to be able to tune this so we
checked the Intel's reputation like
itself for example we're more likely to
trust you know a fireEye threat source
than a you know wall-e 3k github io mi
kind of stuff and we also look at the
threat type and severity and we rate
both of those on a scale of one to five
and then for users who are eventually
generating lists with that we'll add a
user bias which is a multiplier so you
can say well I don't actually really
care about not going to the Pirate Bay
but I do definitely care about grandma
getting hit with an expert tip and with
all of that said we finally get to the
graphs with like five minutes remaining
here's the graphs so this is a map of a
hosting provider the redder nodes are
malicious
the yellower nodes are less malicious
we're actually going to zoom in a little
bit here so you can see that there are a
lot of malicious node it's pointing to
give an IPS with given C name and then
you notice one yellow node Adobe updated
table which is not flagged and that's
the kind of domain that we're looking
for this is the kind of proactive
intelligence that we want to generate we
want to be able to figure out Adobe
update dot top is malicious before
grandma goes to it and sometimes that's
going to be really hard you can generate
more graphs the very intricate they're
frustrating to work with and there are
times when you look at the graph and you
get a net just this absolute cluster of
information that's very very difficult
to interpret and we need to build a
machine that can interpret that
effectively and honestly we're still
working on because there
sometimes where the threat intelligence
that we get is not so great J max mine
comm probably shouldn't be read it's
used by some malware to figure out the
geolocation of a given target it's also
used by legitimate services to do the
same exact thing why is it blocked
who knows
and we need to be able to do this at
scale and reduce false positives this is
a WS by the way this is and this is a
subset of a WS I could only generate a
subset of a WS this is not all of a WS
because the graphing engine that I have
for this crashed so this is a subset of
a WS and this is a subset of github I oh
and we have to figure out you know there
are some red dots in here there's some
things that we definitely do need to
block but there are going to be others
that get caught in the crossfire if we
applying naive approaches so what we're
considering very strongly is frequency
you know what percentage of nodes
resolving to this IP are malicious and
that's a really great starting point for
us and it won't solve all the problems
and there's a lot to remove here
unfortunately the data is far from
complete we have about 2 million or
sorry we have 2 billion data points in
system right now but that's not enough
we're not covering enough of the domain
space we haven't enumerated all of the
possible subdomains we're not looking at
all of the possible data that we can
possibly get and it's the same problem
with our threat intelligence our sources
are good not great you know we're
working on a we have to work off three
intelligence we have to work off three
sources this is an academic project it's
not got the insight that fireEye has and
our response time due to that is
actually fairly slow of course the graph
engine needs work like I've just said
and it's really only useful as a
post-mortem investigation tool that's
not really what we want for it and
actually here's a distribution of where
we do our scanning from Sweden Canada
United States not that's not coverage
we're not covering the entire world and
we really need to this is needs to click
too and so we have a lot of stuff to
work on we need to talk to a lawyer I
need to talk to a lawyer I really need
to talk to a lawyer because Robert Olson
do I now see has shown up in the back hi
Rob Wilson there was a round of applause
waiting for you at the end it's half
yours it's half mine
we need to talk to a lawyer to figure
out can we actually use this data in a
way that it's useful because I am a lot
easier of a target for somebody to go
after then per se rapid7 rapid7 has
lawyers I do not so if somebody wanted
to say hey you're not allowed to do this
give me your money what am I gonna say
hey no I will see so we also need to
scale out cover more geographic areas
increase our query throughput we have
capped out at about 1,000 queries per
second which is pretty solid until you
consider the scale of the domain space
you know we need to ramp up those
numbers and you can help we're actually
releasing software that allows people to
use their systems as resolvers for our
system it'll take some of that extra
internet throughput that you have use it
to hit cloud floor DNS servers I've
talked to them about this they says it's
they say it's okay
you can hit CloudFlare get list from us
of things to resolve you some of those
resolved lists back cool we ingest more
data and more data we ingest the more of
an intelligent system we can create and
we need to implement certain things that
we talked about today such as n sec
walking and transfers going to implement
n psych walking in a way that doesn't
appear like it's a denial of service
attack I want to implement acts firs in
a way that you can actually parse them
because parsing domain data is actually
really frustrating and the end game of
this entire project as I have two
minutes to be and we want to make DNS
trace a proactive tool for geeks like me
like you like all of us here we want to
generate firewall configurations we want
to generate DNS block lists things that
you can toss at the pie hole that you
have sitting at home that you can block
threats before they actually reach your
network which could be awesome and most
of all we want to make this tool a
proactive tool for everyone we want to
make this protecting grandma for free if
we can hopefully we want to potentially
create browser extensions down the line
to identify malicious sites from an
independent source
we're not AVG you know it's just me and
we also want to create possibly a DNS
trace powered DNS
server like quad nine or such things
that provide a secure browsing
experience for people that can block
threats at the network level before they
get to Grandma because I don't know
about your grandma's but my grandma is
really bad at figuring out what a good
adult flash update is what a bad adobe
flash update is and if we can protect my
grandma we can protect yours too thank
you so much I wanted this to be an open
discussion we have 60 seconds left
really yeah all right awesome
Wow I thought your guess we're gonna cut
me off cool we have ten minutes please
discuss with me I've not slept I've very
receptive to questions comments concerns
criticisms issues general and really all
right yeah yeah yeah we have not what's
our PZ hmm oh sorry
have we interacted with DNS and our PZ
okay okay so that's the kind of stuff
that piehole would do okay simple I got
a better scale oh that's rad I am noting
that down that's why I have a like I
said at the beginning I have a pen and a
notepad are busy anybody else please now
I'm just standing up here you can ask me
how my day's been
stressful but it's okay now yes so newly
created like a DNS recency for example
it's so like looking at how recently
like something is mapped to a given IP
yeah yep so we actually condense all of
our data into the time that we have
first seen it and the time that we've
last seen it so actually it would be
very easy to implement that kind of
thing looking at the recency of well you
know what time is it right now and when
did we first see this result so yeah we
definitely could do we currently know
it's a great thing to do though so we
will definitely be getting on that yes
so yeah so SSL cert transparency so
rapid evans datasets actually do that so
rapid7 has it's a continuation of SSL
observatory that
yeah they provide all the SSL
certificates that they can find for I
think they do an ipv4 scan of all sites
exposing port 443 and then they pull
from that so yes we we do in just that
kind of data and it's awesome other
things or stuff my League of Legends
rank has plummeted because of this
nothing else all right well this is the
last slide thank you so much for coming
to my talk it means a lot to me
keep in touch I'm here all day I'm just
gonna be on the a tree I'm probably
buying things because I haven't acquired
stickers yet it's 2 p.m. so I'm getting
uncomfortable you can contact me by my
email Kris at Partridge Tech you can add
me on LinkedIn please that's a great
resume booster for me you can chat with
the Audion
I guess we'll just like create
repositories and then type into the
repositories and then submit pull
requests it works for me
or on Twitter but I never use Twitter so
good luck thank you so much you enjoy
the rest of besides
[Applause]
Thanks