[Music]
so you want to land a job in cyber
security but you look at the many many
areas of cyber security and you don't
know where to begin with
i'm don a current student studying
information security in this
presentation i will show you how i got
started things i did to help me to get
started with a career in cyber security
if you're new to infosec welcome i
wanted to share a little story of my own
how i got into cyber security
growing up i was this kid who likes to
poke around things and make use of
things creatively
in middle school i randomly browsed a
video that talks about ethical hacking
and i thought that was the coolest thing
in the world and i wanted to do that
so i browse the internet and people say
that in order to hack
you need to learn low level coding like
c programming
i learned how to code my first ever
program hello world nc
when the lying hello world exclamation
mark pops up on the command prompt i
feel like such an ethical hacker and i
feel like such a cool kid
and if you're thinking if the story is
going towards the direction of some
young genius hackers
i'm sorry i'm gonna let you be
disappointed so because of some
life-changing events i had to drop
i had to take home some family
responsibilities and had to drop
learning at the quahogy
fast forward to three years ago when i
just started college
i was still trying to figure out what i
wanted to do with my life and my family
really wants me to pursue a career in
law
but here's the thing so how american
school law school works is that you can
only earn your law degree after your
bachelor's
so i picked to have my undergrad degree
to business because i like people i like
talking to people
at the time i really enjoyed my first
business technology class
my professor mentioned that cyber
security is trending and in my major we
should check it out so i checked out my
school cyber security club and boom
this isn't the exact thing i wanted to
do
since middle school
i never knew that you could make a
career out of being a hacker
i have found my home and to be honest i
kind of regret not following through in
middle school with my passion
and i'm not letting myself regret it
again by dropping
as a result i started learning more
cyber security knowledge i got my
comptia security plus certification two
summers ago i also become more involved
in the cyber security club
on my in my university i became an
officer and i built the university of
women's cyber security chapter
currently i am a security advocate and i
go to a lot of conferences
and that helps shaping who i am and my
professional career which i will talk
about later
last year i tried for the first time
applying for cyber security internships
i found it really confusing because a
lot of job descriptions looks like the
following
an internship role that requires just a
lot
in-depth knowledge about networking
protocols
strong work experiences strong
experiences in scripting
and certification such as oscp cissp
which are definitely not interlocked
in particular cissp requires a candidate
to have at least
five years of security working
experiences and yet this role is for an
internship
there are many many examples like this
just getting into info just getting into
cyber security as a beginner i
definitely not did not have this many
experiences but i managed to have three
offers
so i don't want you to be scared away
because of the job qualifications
next i wanted to talk about a plan i
have for myself to land these offers
step number one is to get involved with
the community my tip of advice is to get
involved with the cyber security on
twitter and join discords and go to
conferences because that's the way that
you can get an understanding of which
certifications i should pursue next what
conference is everyone else going to and
what skills should i learn
step number two is to increase
face-to-face interactions
browsing twitter is a good way to get
information i like face to face because
you can get a small chat with a friendly
stranger while you're sitting next to
each other
and also with face to face is more real
to me because you're actually talking to
a person
you can do this step by going to
conferences meetups and hacker
associations
step number three is to apply and land a
job after we go to those conferences and
meet people it is show time for us to
apply follow up and land the job in
cyber security
and next i will explain in detail on
things how
that i did for those three steps
so there are many ways that we can get
involved with cyber security including
being active on twitter
at the first conference i went to
everyone was going by their hacker which
is their twitter handles and almost
everyone knows each other from twitter
and it's also a really good way to get
to know the most recent vulnerabilities
and cyber security professionals insight
into them which helps in terms of
interviews because they'll ask you
questions
um according to the most recent
vulnerabilities
i also liked playing capture the flag
competitions i played a couple of them
um and capture the flag competitions
also known as ctfs they're a jeopardy
style
gamified way of learning so what you do
is you solve a challenge you get a flag
you enter the flag and you get points
things with
ctf competitions is that
you can play it individually or you can
play it as a group
it's a really good way to learn cyber
security through going through a
hands-on way of learning
i i enjoy reading cyber security books
because they give you a general a really
in-depth knowledge on a particular topic
also studying certifications are a good
way because certifications give you
security knowledge in the theoretical
sometimes they give you a
practical knowledge in term depending on
which certification you are looking for
um one thing i wanted to know is that
for if you want to work in a large
company
um they use certifications to
differentiate their candidates
so in their their um hr screening resume
screening they'll look for specifically
which certifications
to differentiate um between candidates
to candidates so if you have this
certification it gives you a leg up
next one is connecting with cyber
security professionals on linkedin
i love this community and the
professionals in this community are
really really really helpful and so
friendly i would not hesitate to connect
with them on linkedin and ask your
questions away
i also listen to podcasts um usually
when i'm driving long distance where i'm
just driving in general if i wanted to
get my infosec news of the day i just go
ahead and listen to podcasts cast they
give me another perspective on what's
the most recent vulnerabilities
watching hands-on youtube videos also
really helped me because i get to see
from
another person's perspective of how they
did it versus um and how i should be
doing and if something goes wrong i just
google the the problem and boom it tells
me what to do and how i i knew that i
did it different from theirs
next i'll give you some examples on what
i used for resources
before i start with the resource slide i
just wanted to have a disclaimer that i
don't have any affiliation with any of
the recommended individuals or
organizations except for grim con those
are just examples or resources that i
use and i have found helpful
i know i mentioned twitter a lot of
cybersecurity on twitter but what is it
exactly you may wonder
so cybersecurity on twitter is not a
specific person or specific set of
people that you need to follow but it's
just
that
cyber security professionals are really
active
on twitter so you can follow anyone
who's you think it's in your expertise
and let's just by doing this by
following each other let's drop your
drop your twitter handle into the
discord chat and let's just follow each
other and um let's create this community
and um grimcon speakers are also really
good way to start following because
speakers we usually as speakers we
usually really like to give back to the
community and uh we're really um happy
and
into help helping each other um in in
this community
i really like um the tribe of hackers
series um for in terms of books
because the travel hacker series they
have three different books
security leaders red team and blue team
red team stands for the offensive side
of cyber security while blue team stands
for the defensive side of cyber security
this book has a collection of cyber
security professionals
recommendations advice in terms of if
you are new to cyber security what you
should be aware of so
just beginning with to begin with i read
that book and i found it tremendously
helpful for me
in terms of certifications
come to your security plus gives you a
really good foundation skills and
theoretical uh radical knowledge on
security
security that you need to know so it
kind of helped me pave the way and when
other people on twitter are talking
about oh this vulnerability is coming
from all kinds of they're using all
kinds of lingos and i can can kind of
sort of understand because of that
obtaining that certification
networking is also really important in
terms of cyber security and i recommend
cisco ccna um having a networking
foundation under your belt is
tremendously useful
podcasts i really enjoy listening to
document diaries
because and they go over like hacker
stories um in each series and i really
enjoy listening to them while i'm
driving
jack fransider is also really good um
storyteller
cyber outlier daily i listen to it to
get my influence that news of the day so
um just to
understanding more what's going on
what's happening in the secured security
world in the day
um and john hammond he does cyber
security ctf walkthroughs and i like
watching him when i'm stuck at a ctf
network chuck does
hands-on youtube videos hands-on
security videos
and black hill information security does
really good security educational videos
in terms of project to break it in
um i would recommend always do your
a home lab because you can't number one
you can practice it on your own in a
safe environment number two you can also
configure it on your own and becoming
your own syst admin get your experience
under the belt
for ctfs um there are three ctfs i
really enjoy playing
cyberstar pico ctf and national cyber
league those are really beginner
friendly ctfs um and there's our
gamified way of learning and
for pico ctf in particular um it's
established by it's developed by
carnegie mellon university and i will be
soon be um starting my master's in
carnegie mellon university so it'll be
really cool for me to look from a
developer perspective as opposed to a
player perspective
and for um blocks for my readers novi is
really good follow uh
novai does really cool
um
youtube videos and he writes a really
cool blog on
a set of instructions when what we
should
only what you can do
in terms of hacking too
so as a student i also got involved with
my school cyber security club which
introduced me to so many different
technical knowledge i learned about
networking so setting a home lab with
kali linux wi-fi hacking cryptography
web app pen testing password tracking i
also teamed up with other students who
are playing
to play regular jeopardy style ctfs and
social engineering competitions where we
were selected to compete internationally
and place top and osen open social
intelligence
we had guest speakers from hiring
companies to speak and hire us
i also helped building our community a w
of university chapter of women's cyber
security where we created the women's
cybersecurity group to be more like
community focused different from the
technical cyber security club
we had female guest speakers um and it
was really helpful for us to learn their
security journey and what their advice
is for a few future female cyber
security professionals
we also played ctfs together we hosted
coffee chats but mainly a sociable
aspect for students interested in cyber
security to get to know each other
now our women's cyber security group has
grown from three family members to more
than 30 students
and additionally for each university
there is usually its own stock and
hiring for
student workers stock stands for
security operations center and they're
really they're responsible for
monitoring and analyzing the
university's security posture and
incidents those positions normally don't
require any experiences and it's a good
way just to get your foot in the door
now conferences are my favorite
resources because the ability to make
one-on-one connections there are free
budget-friendly and more expensive
options some such as like local meetups
from hacker associations from where you
can meet local cyber security
professionals
some conferences are free and
educational such as grim con if you
enjoy those ones and want to try out
more options security b-sides are my
absolute favorite budget-friendly option
the first conference i would went to was
the local b-sides and was such a warm
community and everybody seemed to know
each other and welcomed newcomers when i
indicated that i was interested in
joining
if money is not an issue for you or if
you have the choice to go to a more
expensive conference i would definitely
recommend defcon rsa and black hat
defcon is one of the largest hacker
conventions in the world and coolest in
my opinion
i went to defcon 29 and it was an
absolute blast for me
they have villages such as biohacking
car hacking iot villages and where they
have workshops and labs that allows you
to hack into them legally my favorite
was the packet hacking village where the
famous wall sheep is
so defcon has this unwritten rule that
you want to secure your bluetooth and
wi-fi at a conference because otherwise
if you get hacked via those your name
and password will go on the wall of
sheep
yeah clear text and everybody will see
it
and also i wanted to share a good story
from defcon special shout out to elle so
i met out besides we kept in touch and
met up again at def con at the time i
went with my school to defcon we had
around 20 students when we met up again
she introduced it to us to even more
cyber security professionals in
different expertise
all the way ranging from network
security dfir
and threat intelligence to csos
and we started discussion group for us
students to ask them questions so it was
really cool for us because we started a
mini con in middle of the def con and we
attracted other conference participants
to join us slowly
in the end we had about 50 people in our
discussion group and we all enjoy the
session a lot el if you're still
watching thanks for the introduction
again
black hat unfortunately i have not been
that for myself
um but i've heard many good things about
it there are more uh there are more
expensive options and are more like
more like cyber security conferences for
the managers
next we're going to talk about how to
prepare for conferences usually for
conferences they will post a schedule
online several weeks in advance
they typically have several tracks
before i go to a conference i usually go
look up on the talks that i'm interested
in going to and mark them down in my
calendar on where the talk is when is
the talk and who is talking
when a conference is soon approaching i
connect with the speakers on twitter and
i usually say hey i saw you are talking
at this conference really look look
forward to hearing your talks
so this kind of helps me to leave a good
first impression with a speaker so when
i'm talking with
when i'm talking with them in person
later they already know who i am
and during the conference i usually just
go enjoy the conference experience
and talk with the people sitting next to
me to learn about more about what they
do
making friends in this field um because
cyber security is really small and the
friends that you make today may be your
co-workers the next day
i would also connect with them on
twitter linkedin see what their interest
areas are and find commonalities or ask
about them their areas of expertise
follow up with them see what conference
they're going to
now you have them in your network
another point i wanted to stress is to
leverage the brand that you have in
conference for more connections so for
me it was my university's name when i go
to a conference i wear my university
cyber security club officer polo because
it gives me authenticity and helps me
start with the conversations
when i went to defcon i had other
students recognize my polo and told me
that we played cctc together
and i also had recruiters coming up to
me because of that
after we finished step one and two it is
time for us to complete the last step
apply interview and land the job
applying is a game requires us to play
strategically
and i made a plan for myself when i
applied
i applied for 10 jobs a day
and in fact the more you apply the
higher chance you will get an interview
opportunity
but um as i applied to many jobs i kind
of got lost so i would go on google and
search and the same jobs i applied for
would show up again
so
i decided to make an excel sheet for
myself to keep track of the jobs i
applied for
contact i can follow up with whether i
heard back from them if i got an
interview
what's the interview state and time
it is now so much more efficient and
organized
i also wanted to emphasize on the
quality of applications
having connections in the community in
the company you apply for
allows us to get a higher chance of
getting an interview
that is why networking preparation is so
important
the next piece of advice i want to give
if you're a student is to not limit
yourself to your school's career
center connections
i used to only apply within my
universities network but i kept getting
rejections so i realized that i should
probably broaden my horizon and start
searching on google linkedin and even
twitter
that's how that's how i start to get
interview emails
the next one is for my ladies beat the
imposter syndrome
women don't really apply for the job
unless they fulfill the job requirements
a hundred percent while men apply when
they fulfill as 60
so i want to encourage my ladies to go
ahead and apply don't feel like you're
not qualified and don't let you reject
yourself
the last and most important one is to
stick to your plan and keep applying
until you find a job that you're
satisfied with
to prepare for interviews
it is more important for us to use it is
so important for us to use our osun
skills and on the company's culture
interviewer information if you have them
osun stands for open source intelligence
and overly getting prepared for the job
interview
and
never hurts this by
this means overly oh set your job
and you should also show your passion
from the ctfs that you played projects
that you've done relative experiences
that you have had whether if you had
worked experiences or not
a job can teach you the things that you
need to do but it can't teach you
passion
that's why hiring managers love to hire
passionate people
and to follow up i would also ask about
the timeline when you'll be hearing back
in how many interviews there will be so
that you can get an understanding of
when we should follow up
thank you notes this is to leave an
impression on the interviewer the
general rule of thumb is to send a thank
you note as soon as possible
but for holidays or fridays interviewers
are usually ready for the holidays or
the weekend
so sending a note on monday morning or
the next work work day would actually be
good
it is all about making an impression
the last lastly i just wanted to share
some additional resources
i don't have any affiliations with those
individuals but i found them super
helpful in terms of job hunting
um jason blanchard he does content and
community for black hills information
security and he has a youtube video on
how to hunt for jobs like a hacker
where he goes through he oceans the job
and
he teaches you how to do that
he also does twitch live stream on cyber
security job hunting so i would
definitely give him a um check him out
if you're looking for more of those
information
marcus j carey um he is one of the
authors for tribal hackers series and he
really supports the community and
supporting people applying for jobs
he has posts about job threads he asks
um hiring companies if they're hiring
for cyber security people and if they'll
ask them to
reply with the cyber security job links
and information
also indicating if the job is remote or
intere an entry level and do they have
any in internship positions
now whether you're new to
cyber security or if you're experienced
you belong here you belong to cyber
security
we are so happy you are here and i
wanted to give a special shout out to
yaga my mentor for your support
this is my first conference talk and
thank you and thank you everyone for
listening to my talk
now if you have any questions at all
please don't feel
don't hesitate to talk
i have posted my twitter and email in
the presentation
and thank you so much again for
listening
[Music]
you