[Music]
i'm going to hand it over to highs
though i do want to
uh heis i gotta read
your bio if you don't mind because this
is intense
okay
i normally don't just read things to
people but uh this is one of the most
intense bios i've ever read and i need
everybody to be well aware of what's in
here
heis gibson is a faculty member at the
harvard business school
most recently he was an academy
professor of systems engineering at the
united states military academy at west
point uh dr haisa o gibson graduated
with a bs in operations research from
the u.s military academy at west point
and he received his ms in operations
research from the naval post graduate
school
a masters in operations from the air
command and staff college and a doctor
of business administration in technology
and operations management from harvard
business school
he's a career military officer if you
couldn't tell uh who attained the rank
of colonel and is a master aviator a
master aviator
in the uh-60 blackhawk helicopter
who's been awarded the bronze star medal
he's led a large
led large and small teams globally most
recently as a battalion commander in the
historic 82nd airborne division
he also was a fellow at mit lincoln
laboratory engaged in strategic research
initiatives with the dod
and his his expertise is the
intersection of operational
effectiveness and human capital
development
and he has also worked with mid-size and
large transportation and distribution
organizations retailers finance energy
and tech startups on operational issues
and pathways to better leverage their
human capital in more effective ways
maximizing the intersection of
technology people
and processes holy cow highs
this is super impressive
i'm going to hand it over to you to tell
us about building agile tech tech
organizations
super excited take it away
that sounds way better i don't know who
you're talking about but that guy is uh
how are you
paid to write that you've got money well
spent
well well thank you very very much i
really appreciate it uh
and so
uh
well first off thanks to uh grim con for
inviting me to do
this keynote
really excited to engage this particular
audience uh
and also like look forward to sharing a
handful of things that hopefully you can
take away and leverage immediately
following this discussion but what i'd
like to first take you to
is
a place
uh back in 2000
and so in 2004 uh a younger
me was a company commander in
afghanistan in iraq uh we just spent
over a year uh
in combat
flying over baghdad supporting uh a 39
000 person organization
spread across baghdad
and we thought we were going home and so
we were we were relaxing
sitting down uh
folding up our aircraft getting ready to
leave
uh this place called uh iraq in order to
go home
but unfortunately
uh i got a call from a commit my
commander my boss who said hey
the decision has been made
that you and your team have to go back
to combat
have to go back to a place you've been
flying over primarily because
over the previous five to seven days
while we were gone
other aircraft had been shot down and
the decision was made that we were the
closest uh and were able to jump back in
to the fight and support
and help extend operations
not just in baghdad but further south
and so
me as a young
captain had to explain to my team this
group of gentlemen on the screen
that hey
you're not going home to see your family
i need you to get ready in 48 hours to
jump back on those iron horses and get
back in the fight
because our nation needs us right
now so it had nothing to do with the
technical expertise they were these were
all professionals these are all amazing
pilots amazing crew members who played
amazing maintainers and amazing
non-commissioned officers who could get
the mission done
it absolutely nothing to do with their
technical competence that i had to focus
on i had to focus on how do i influence
persuade
and inspire
these individuals to jump back into
the fire of a combat zone
this is very similar to what
all of you been engaging in over not
only the past two years but over the arc
of your careers but more intensely over
the last few years as we think about how
has covet
impacted you and your teams how is the
shutdown open shutdown reality
exposed vulnerabilities in your
processes
and it's not the technological expertise
that you need to worry about
it's mainly the soft skills they're
actually the hard skills
so
i want to describe further describe this
new normal that we're in and suggest
uh how systems thinking a different way
of
looking at these problems or challenges
flip it to more opportunities and then
also suggest eight ways to consider
leading the remote teams and and our new
normal in which we are operating as a
few key takeaways
so i think we all remember
uh this kind of arc
2019 everything's going great they were
honest very similar to the summer and
and
the what's happening you know as we're
in the middle of the pandemic
and then we all became very
connected to this visual
the spikes this reality of this thing
called
covet 19.
we've all we've always been exposed to
coronavirus but this became a pretty
nasty situation that
for the first time for all of us
completely shut down the markets and had
us tumble really quickly
and we we noticed that it didn't just
hurt uh our partners and allies in asia
but also on the continent and actually
shut the globe down it's like a really
bad sci-fi movie that we all have
experience
but as we come into
you know we're starting to see vaccines
um
folks are getting a shot and we think
we're good
everything's fantastic we're outside
we're engaged with each other we have
parties we're having gatherings we're
feeling good about ourselves
and then we've now all become very
connected
to this new variant omicron that's that
spreads faster
so now we almost have to take a lot of
the lessons that we've learned
and
re-imagine
uh and re-event how we're going to
operate with something that's even
that spreads even faster
but we don't want to shut down
and it completely changes our ideas of
what normal is this this term new normal
has been thrown around a lot over the
past couple years but i would argue that
it's really not a new normal it's just
become
our normal and we have to think about
how are we going to operate
and as we think about organizations that
emilia went to 100 remote some have said
they're going to remain remote
uh some try to bring people back these
are all the challenges in which we have
to deal with right now
because this has become
our normal with us engaging in this way
uh the world has now become even flatter
uh on the screens with little square
with uh squares and now we're trying to
be as productive as human possible
and even in that environment we have a
whole lot of folks who wish we could go
all the way back to 2019. we get back to
2019 back to the you know back to the
future we will be ecstatic
but we recognize now that maybe
this open office cubicle farm concept is
not going to come back anytime soon
so we're going to have to think about
the hybrid model how are we going to be
able to go in and out of this reality
effectively
as leaders
because again
similar to the combat zone it's not the
technical competence
that's the challenge it's our ability to
inspire persuade
others to want to engage
because
some of us can be in the office some of
us could be in this flat world but at
least from the organization that i spent
most of my adult life in the training
never stops we don't have that luxury
because we live in this vuca environment
and vuca
means volatile uncertain complex and
ambiguous
and so
if we think about
being in this kind of environment that
we're in it's very dynamic
there's things going on it's not linear
and we need
leaders
and teammates who are comfortable
being uncomfortable and are able to
consistently sustain the ability to
operate in this kind of environment
because the the world in which we
uh live in has a lot of kind of wicked
problems
the challenge is that sometimes our way
at approaching these problems is
sometimes a mismatch between what we
think is going to work
and what actually is going to work
so i like to suggest to you
maybe to take a a systems thinking
approach to this uh vuca world
and maybe change
your mental model and how you think
about
approaching the challenges that have
become uh ever present
in your reality
and so we think about this vuca world
this vulnerable certain complex and
bigger biggest environment
there's a real world reality
but a systems approach a way to think
about a systems approach is maybe
thinking about what are the distinctions
in the reality that we're operating what
are the systems that we have
what are the relationships and the
perspectives this is a system this is a
systems thinking framework there are
many this is one and this is taken from
my colleague at cornell derek cabrera at
the cabrera lab where
he's done extensive research on the dsrp
method because we have the real world
that has real boundaries
we throw things together
we create a bunch of systems
but sometimes you may forget the
interconnectedness of these systems and
they're in a massively complex way in
which you operate
and the dsrp allows us
to quickly
go in
figure out what those distinctions are
recognize that every large system can be
broken down into smaller groups because
it's easier to eat an elephant one bite
at a time
we can then distinguish those
relationships and recognize every
component every person
every division
has a perspective and you start to
understand
how to put yourself
in other shoes in order to attack and
smooth out challenges and problems
because this is the world that we're
living in uh it's challenging
there's cyber threats uh we're trying to
protect data
and so
we have the real world
but when we have that real world systems
you can approximate how it's going to be
you have some mental model
the world informs you and you're in a
constant loop
which means that you're
you have the real world you approximate
you leverage dsrp
to inform how you're going to
react to the world as it is
not
the world you wish it to
be because the reality is the training
must continue or in this case the way in
which you operate
must continue because
as we sit here
your organizations are being probed you
have folks trying to get after get the
data that that we have i mean although
technology integration has massively
made our lives easier it's for every new
technological
intervention
there's
five six hundreds of different branches
and sequels of challenges that we have
to engage in
and so
because training doesn't need to stop we
have to think about
how are we going to lead these remote
teams now this is something we've all
become very connected to over the past
two years if we think about most
organizations had less than 20 percent
of its uh population working in some
kind of remote uh status
and now even post pandemic that has gone
up to about 70 percent
and so when operating remote
environments
i would suggest that their teams and
they're leaders
and the scale is weighted towards the
leader
and so something that the leaders can do
is think about quickly
using a lead framework
how do we leverage the particular
platform there are many platforms go to
media and zoom
ms teams but what is the what is the
platform you're going to focus on and
ensure that all of your teams
are able to leverage in a meaningful way
and then how are you going to lean in as
a leader
leaning in means
leaning to the friction the friction of
what's really going on how do you really
measure productivity
how do you ensure your teammates are
doing okay what's going on behind the
screen that requires a frequency of
interactions to kind of get through the
friction and so you so leaders have to
engage
and by engaging you're able to adapt to
the environment and the seesaw effect of
we're going to all be fully remote we're
going to come in two to three days a
week we're gonna come in one day a week
we're gonna have this kind of cadence so
if you think about the way in which
you're adapting
are you adapting in a way that's almost
like whiplash to your teammates or are
you providing a level of predictability
that
enhances productivity
over time
and then
fundamental
for all leaders to be affected
is the ability to distill quickly
information and provide the important
points
in order to allow
your team
to operate effectively
because
no matter how much technology exists
no matter how buca the world is
when providing uh
when looking at surveys around what
makes effective or ineffective
organizations what makes effective or
ineffective
leaders it all comes back to
how does the leader communicate
and the way what the leader communicates
how does that leader make the team feel
and is it a psychologically safe
environment where everyone feels they
can speak up
are heard
is inclusive
uh and valued
and all of that is on the backs of
leaders no matter
what industry
we're operating in
and so
remote work requires far more managerial
engagement
and active engagement than when we're
just in the office and i think that's
that's something that we've all learned
over the past two years and i would
argue must be remembered
as we move through a sustained reality
of our current environment and as we
push through into the future because now
we're going to have a
second segment of the workforce that
really is very comfortable operating
remote
very comfortable operating in this
virtual world
and we have leaders who have to adapt to
being far more engaging
than prior to 2020.
and so i would suggest that you we think
about building agile
tech organizations it really just comes
back to some fundamentals
i suggest thinking about how do you love
the systems thinking approach
not very complex
just recognizing the world that you're
in
thinking through the mental model that
you have
the framework that you leverage in order
to be effective
and then
maybe think about leveraging lead
ensuring that the platform that you're
utilizing virtually and non-virtually or
hybrid is is the one that you need
leaning into the friction and not
running away from it
when you lean in your teams feel it when
you run away
your teams feel it and the reality is
people don't leave organizations
people leave people
and
think about how adaptive are you to the
environment you're in
do you feel comfortable in it are you
able to pivot when necessary i mean
those are some some
really self-reflections required to
really think about how adaptive you are
and how well do you distill
large values of information and plot the
important points and then share that
with your team
again communication is the key
to any organization to be effective for
any organization to scale
and in order to have an agile tech
organization
a lot is not necessarily the leader
who is the person on the keyboard who's
the person in the
the sock who is
when the breach happens is right there
at the keyboard
able to make a decision to influence the
reputational risk of the firm
then it's going to be based on the
information that that person has at the
time that the leaders at the time and
how much practice the team has had
across so
again communication
is imperative
i'd like to thank you all for your time
and attention i look real look forward
to any of your questions
you