[Music]
to both of you and hello everyone i hope
everyone's on discord i can actually
multitask i teach uh for sam so i can
like look down and see you all talking
so uh let's just start out by saying hey
how's everyone doing good morning good
afternoon good evening from wherever you
are where are you all
located
if uh if your opsec allows who's coming
from the furthest place
anyone from another country any
europeans out there
oh
look i see a few of you some some names
i recognize costa rica
australia i think australia won
california fantastic
awesome awesome awesome so yeah the
reason i uh mentioned discord is that
you can ask questions as i'm speaking to
you and i may see it and answer it
immediately or
if you uh are looking into the future i
might just have another slide that will
cover that so um
definitely
post that um any questions there and
again thank you for coming my name is
george or chias thank you for that uh
intro and thank you grim khan and
everyone behind the scenes there's like
a whole team
that's required to put a virtual
conference together so shout out to all
of them um and all the folks at grimm
that are making this happen all the
volunteers etc so appreciate that uh
i do not have all the creds uh of our
keynote speaker
uh but i do have some experience in the
commercial space um
i'm the chief technology office officer
already messing up
uh i'm the cto at scythe whatever that
stands for um and one of the co-creators
of the c2 matrix which is what we're
gonna cover
uh
here and i've done a few things i love
giving back to the community so speaking
at conferences especially free
conferences is awesome um
some of the things we've done is the
release the purple team exercise
framework that we will actually be going
through in our workshop later today so
um if you want to learn about purple
teaming and do some command and control
do some adversary emulation and then
detect it
with through detection engineering uh we
have a couple of psych folks uh
running through that chris peacock who
is our resident detective engineer and
elaine who runs support at site are all
gonna be there uh doing that so that's
at one
we'll cover some of that um prior to
psych i ran the offensive team at
citigroup so everything from
vulnerability assessment to pen testing
to red teaming that's kind of where i
really got into c2 stuff
um
also a sand certified instructor and
author of a red team course there
and a contributor to
some things you might have heard or seen
like mitre attack atomic red team cvss
version 3 and 3.1
and the google global financial markets
association built a framework there for
regulatory compliance so
that's a little bit about me feel free
to uh follow me there on twitter or
connect on linkedin i do uh love talking
to everyone and see how things are
evolving
and that's essentially what we're going
to talk about today is command and
control and how it has evolved
now for anyone uh that has not used or
knows what c2 is i'll give a little
intro just to bring everyone up to speed
uh some of you may have used c2 before
uh but essentially c2 stands for command
and control it's uh the ability to
communicate with a an asset in
a particular system in the cyber
security world uh generally you take
over a system you execute code in there
and you have to communicate with that
system to tell it what you want to do
um so by law i'm required to show at
least something about miter attack so
the miner attack tactics are here on the
top um
they have grown significantly but the
big one is command and control one of my
favorite ones um
and the thing about command and control
is that we all use this uh as johnny
said right before the talk is this is
important for red teamers blue teamers
really anyone needs to understand how
this happens uh because without
communication you don't have any control
which means you would have to build a
worm now do any of you recall
any recent worms that we've seen out
there
uh we can go back all the way to the
morris worm back in the 80s don't expect
many to uh recall that one but there
have been a lot since probably the newer
ones are things like not petya
and wannacry
and
um
stuxnet right all those
got out of control
right they were all they've all gone out
of control because there was no
um central c2 for them
and essentially they all got out and
that's how we know about them but other
than those most attacks have
some sort of communication channel again
this is taking over a system
and being able to uh communicate with so
our focus here is going to be on command
control frameworks but commanding
control as a channel is very simple over
on the left we have a target system they
might have gotten a phishing email they
were compromised some way somehow right
initial access is a matter of time
uh many many ways of doing that but once
you gain initial access you execute code
and
you
establish communication to your command
and control server which is over here on
the right this actually empire uh quick
question here on the expert track
channel do
any of you have experience have you
played with any c2s and so which ones
have you played with any c2s and if so
which ones uh and i see that uh message
going back to energy drinks with code
red yes code red was also a worm also
got out of control
um
cs which uh stands for cobalt strike
not crowd strike and covenant cool cool
cool
some at work and on my own so someone
developed something oh there we go
empire mythic posh
mostly from the rto course yeah
duct tape command and control never seen
that one that's an interesting one
um so yeah over here on the right you
can see um a year ago we hosted a the
user conference at site called unicon
because we love unicorns i don't know if
you've seen these guys they sell
unicorns
um and one of the things we did was i
capture the flag called know your
payload and our theory was a lot of
people know how to build payloads but
might not know everything that actually
happens in the background so
built a couple payloads put up a bunch
of c2 servers um in particular it was a
posh an empire and a site server
and we gave these payloads and i thought
are people actually going to run these
payloads in their environment and if you
look very closely we actually had 457
uh
payloads execu and connecting to this c2
server we had put up on digital ocean uh
it's the most i've seen on on empire
um they have a whole bunch of agents
connected so
um that's c2 it seems most of you all
know how c2 works so that's great we
will just continue on
um
where did c2 matrix come from all those
idea well back in july 2019 i was
writing um security 564 actually
rewriting it uh joe best was the
original uh author there i rewrote it
and i used empire um as the c2 we're
gonna use in the labs because for a two
day course you're going to teach someone
command and control and a lot of things
about red teaming you don't you can't
just spend the entire time on a c2
framework so we used empire as the main
c2 and it was mostly because it was the
most reliable and consistency too it
came out like in 2016
very
reliable and you need that in a class
environment i know john mentioned he
does some teaching and when you're
teaching a topic
and someone executes him follows the
direction you want to make sure
that it executes reliably and
consistently every time you don't want
to be troubleshooting a tool when you're
teaching a particular procedure a
particular ttp right so
back then empire was definitely the most
reliable and consistent built the class
around that turned the class in and then
july 31st occurs and
this happens uh
tweet from one of the maintainers of
um empire saying hey everyone knows and
knows how to detect power shell we're
not going to support uh empire anymore i
said all right cool so let's figure out
another c2 that we can use that's
actively maintained for the course i
started asking around
um
and i got a whole bunch of different ass
uh answers i actually went to sans
instructor chat
uh slack where you know ed scotus is on
there tim and dean john strand uh jeff
mcjunkin right ask all those folks hey
what c2 do you use and i got eight
different answers someone's like coming
in just like you all just did right oh
i've used covenant i've used a mythic or
i've used posh and mythic back then
wasn't really called mythic it was
called apfel uh etc
so
i'm like all right cool
let's figure out which one to use for my
class
then september uh right around derbycon
the last story become
rest in peace derbycon we will miss you
awesome awesome conference um had a
great time uh
remember
some parts of it thanks to a friend
carlos van germini who uh
took care of me after a few drinks um
before i broke my phone was was not a
good site but
i was there uh talking bryson and adam
machinshe about you know all these c2s
and which ones um they use and all that
and bryson was doing a talk uh where he
was trying to show caldera and if you
use caldera back in the day how there
was not very reliable or consistent
and we came up with this idea of just
you know why don't we evaluate these c2s
and track them so we started evaluating
these c2s and in november 2019 we
launched um the c2 matrix
and as any project goes you have to have
some goals because um you might get a
scope creep right so the goals were to
choose the best modern replacement for
empire one that's reliable consistent
user friendly and that meets the
requirements of a red team i was again
working at city at that time running the
red team there and we needed operational
security
right some encryption between a
system you compromised and your uh your
server
you needed multiple c2 channels so http
https dns etc
um
ability to build different payloads off
of your um
of your stagers so that you can execute
say in a microsoft word document or
execute the uh dlls and uh all these
other
low vast ways of executing right
and custom profiles you have to be able
to customize this because
a c2 is kind of obvious uh on the
network right especially when you use
some of these default profiles of
calling back like every five seconds or
every 10 seconds etc
um
so
other than that we wanted some other
things i worked at an enterprise
uh having a
proxy aware c2 was important many
enterprises have proxies going outbound
right you don't just allow access to the
internet in every way shape or form you
have to go through a proxy so
having a proxy aware payload was
important had to be able to pivot
internally because
c2 is only one tactic right of a minor
attack lateral movement is is generally
required and oh yeah we're running a red
team
there's no i in team so we needed a
multi-user c2 and of course something
that that was maintained so
we put together this evaluation lab
um essentially have windows and linux
servers as the attackers they were on
one side of a network uh all going
through a ppf sense uh firewall pfsense
is free easy to customize you can have
different segments you can send it um
and get like netflow data you can get
ids you can you get some visibility
there so all this i actually set up on
my laptop you don't need like extra
um
you don't need any extra hardware for
this you can do all this with vmware um
and then some victim systems a windows
one running wireshark running sysmon
linux system running tcp dom mac et
cetera and have some sort of visibility
to know what's actually happening
because we're gonna be downloading a
whole bunch of free stuff from the
internet and
do you trust everything you download
from the internet probably not right um
so we wanted visibility and see what's
really happening
um just looking here at some of the
questions um yes so empire python it was
python empire that was the original um
build of it so the server side was on
python and then it built
payloads in
powershell
um and that's why it came out as
powershell empire um it really was a
combination of a bunch of powershell
projects um all put together so the
authors like harm joy for instance was
one he has uh power supply and power
view and all those were all brought
together and empire and yes that's a
star wars reference um
do you want to note that empire today is
actually maintained uh by dc security so
they empire is alive and well it's now
only power shell um payloads now they do
have some c-sharp um and some other
payload types as well
um is atomic uh red team consider c2 no
atomic red team does not have command
and control atomic red team are atomic
tests tests that you grab
a
uh command and you execute it on a
particular system manually um it does
not have command and control
um let's see what other questions are
uh
[Music]
all right cool so
what features mattered and what were we
looking for well we want to know
where uh and how this server worked was
it a python server was the server-side
build
in
um
c-sharp and c etc
where were the stagers or the implants
built for so for example empire
originally was powershell implants now
we see a lot of c sharp
uh implants or stagers we wanted to see
the user interface if it was multi-user
that was very important
if it was a web
uh accessible if it was a gui if it was
a command line uh we actually added dark
mode as a joke but apparently a lot of
people care about dark mode um if
there's an api
and if we could build implants for
different operating systems because as a
red teamer you're gonna go attack um
you know window systems linux system mac
systems and depending on that you had to
choose your c2
and
communication channel this one was
pretty important all the different ways
of communicating um
with
your c2 and the typical one like 80
probably of the attacks we see today use
https right as a communication channel
http is generally allow outbound
everywhere sometimes it's through a
proxy um but that that's generally the
the most important one we see today
there's others there's tcp if you've
used metasploit right the reverse tcp
shells and all that
um
http 2 http 3 might not have visibility
in your organization they're newer
protocols as is dns over https some old
school ones etc
so all of this um was built in the
uh most used hacking tools so infosec
professionals as a whole use this one
particular tool more than anything else
um
it could be google sheets or microsoft
excel but essentially spreadsheets it's
the number one tool used by infosight
people i don't know if uh you all uh
spend a lot of time in excel or in uh or
in google sheets but you talk to other
people in the in the infosec industry
it's essentially the number one infosec
tool out there along with powerpoint um
so
you know those are the the top two um
so we built it like this as a way to to
see it um i'm gonna do a little demo of
that right now in a couple seconds um we
also launched a website to make this
prettier um
there's an ask the c2 matrix so you can
find out what c2 you wanted to use as
well as documentation so there's a how
to setting up these c2s there's a vm
there's a whole bunch of stuff um so let
me uh
go ahead and show that here real quick
pop open this uh c2 matrix
so here's the c2 matrix website the
matrix is the golden source it's a
google sheet page so if i click that and
load it up
um you can see the name of the c2
um so you can scroll down here and you
know we were talking about empire so
we'll use empire as a
as an example here it's a bsd3 license
meaning that you can use this right all
uh it's free there's no price there's a
github for it so you can access that um
there
here's a website by the way let me post
that over here on uh
on
our page
um
on discord so
you have the github where you can
download it the twitter if you want to
contact the the people that uh do it and
then who evaluated it and you could see
there's a whole bunch of people i have
evaluated uh c2s you can do this as well
i'll talk about contributions and all
that the version was three zero five
there's way later versions now
um there's a how-to for some of these so
you can actually click on this how-to
page and it tells you how to set up
empire some have videos some have
installs etc
um
it's available on the sans slingshot vm
and it's available on cali i actually
work with some of the folks uh offensive
security that released the kali um
distro so that you can get c2s on there
as well
and then here you can see the server the
server in this case was python and the
implants were created with powershell
it was multi-user with this thing called
starkiller
it has a gui it has dark mode it has an
api you can create implants for windows
linux and mac
communication uh mainly over http and
https
and then over here you see some of the
capabilities we looked at like the key
exchange so when you have a payload it
has a key hard-coded into it to
communicate with the c2 server for
operational security
um it doesn't allow for steganography
which is hiding things in images
is it proxy aware does that allow domain
fronting custom profiles
jitter working hours etc right so we've
been populating this um quite a bit
and
uh lots of things have changed so it's
kind of like the intro of the c2 matrix
if you've never um never seen this
before
um
so let me close out of this stuff and
get back on our presentation
um which is really the core of the talk
right is what has changed right what has
changed um since we started this project
well more c-tubes um back in november
2019 when this was released there was 30
c2s in the c2 matrix
last year in november 2020 uh there were
60 and this year around november i think
now we're up to 90.
88. so really big growth in uh c2s that
are available
um but
really
um
all of these
are not
c2s or c2 frameworks
so c2 is command and control a c2
framework is different than just command
and control a c2 framework is modular
allows you to build things in because
one thing's having the communication
channel the other thing is giving you
execution giving you the ability to do
lateral movement right all the features
that come in a c2 one thing is just
having a shell the other is having all
these different modules so we don't
currently distinguish between c2s and c2
frameworks they're just all listed there
um and then what we found out as well is
that writing a c2
does not equal maintaining ac2 so some
people will write a c2
put it on github
people use it
um and then it's never maintained
um so we've seen quite a bit of that but
again you can't complain about this
because you didn't pay for it right
um
so that that's become quite evident
we've added um is it actively maintained
and to be actively maintained it needs
to have been updated within the last
year so if it's been updated within the
last year we'll say it's actively
maintained
and of course there's a little debate
going on on twitter not sure if you all
are on twitter um or if you've been part
of this debate um and it's the offensive
security tool debate the ost debate um
essentially
one side of the
argument says that you shouldn't release
these tools for free because malicious
actors are using it while the other side
of the argument says do release this
tools because this is how
we learn and then we can defend better
so we're not going to go into that
debate it's been going on for a couple
years now uh but that's definitely still
going alive and well i see some of you
uh may have heard of it some you may not
but that's definitely has occurred
one of the cool things though that um i
want to give a shout out to and actually
uh hopefully get you all working on this
is sponsorwear so you have open source
stuff
that's built by developers and a lot of
times they build this on their free time
and then large organizations go and they
download these free open source tools
from github they look at the code they
use it and they get a bunch of value out
of them
and then something doesn't work and they
create a issue in uh github right they
don't create a pull request they create
an issue they say hey marcelo in this
example he's bite leader on uh twitter
um he has created a whole bunch of
awesome things um in particular and
related to this talk uh a c2 called
silent trinity though hey marcelo this
doesn't work man can you get this to
work come on come on come on it's like
marcelo's doing this for free you know
like
so he came out and he said look i'm
going to put some of these out as
sponsorware sponsor where it means that
you
can go on github or gitlab or a variety
of different um
platforms and essentially pay
them to support and there's different
ranges you can say hey you know i use a
lot of marcelo's tools my company should
probably pay him i don't know 300 a
month because we got a lot of value out
of this
um
or you can say you know i'm picking out
a pocket i can give him five bucks a
month right
and we've seen this kind of pick up on
the right here you see bc security did
this as well
and
um and a lot of others are kind of
starting to do that so we've seen that
growth uh for sure and not sure if you
all sponsor you contribute if you do
sponsor something what do you sponsor
let us know on get uh discord um
what what do you sponsor right
responders another one right not really
a c2 but definitely something a lot of
people have used in their enterprise and
probably did not help the developers
right so big fan of this model the other
model that we're seeing quite a bit is
commercialized c2s now full disclosure
i'm the cto at site we have uh we are on
this list so
uh do know that it was actually spun out
from grim so this is grim con so full
disclosure there before we we continue
on and talk about the commercial c2s but
this number has grown significantly it's
now 12
of the c2s on the c2 matrix are
commercial c2s
um some that we've seen are brute retell
this is by someone uh by dark vortex
also on twitter as paranoid ninja
created uh one of these uh cobalt strike
of course i think all of you have heard
of that um the big news since c2 matrix
started tracking all this is that they
were bought by help systems the makers
of core impact so we'll see what happens
there but joe vest is one of the folks
uh running now and working there uh
personal friends so
uh you you may have heard or used this
there's other companies that are like
consulting companies kind of like grim
uh creating site um
that
are doing this pivot labs phil haven
immunity has one called innuendo then
they were bought by
siteterra which was then spun out into
appgate etc um
nighthawk is is the new one in town this
one was just released this month um we
kind of knew this was coming these are
the folks from md set uh also a
consulting company out of the uk
um outflank another consulting company
and the netherlands um has a tool called
ost
uh that stands for offensive uh
or outflanked security tool
and
they have a stage one c2 then red code
labs has this one that i can't pronounce
um caldera the folks there
left and created one called
prelude
um
net spy another consulting company
bought renting toolkit uh scythe already
mentioned and then s2 security another
consulting company has one called voodoo
so essentially all these consulting
companies that do very
sophisticated and advanced red teaming
have built custom tools and then because
there's now a market to actually support
uh
a a c2 framework they are building this
up um over at the right a shout out to
elemental x2 um there was a little bit
of a twitter uh spat going on between
retell and nighthawk over which one was
better and then someone made a meme of
cobalt strike coming and bringing them
down and then someone put the c2 matrix
just running through them all because
you don't have to use just one c2 you
can actually use quite a bit so we'll
talk about that
um
a time check real quick uh just on the
expert track channel johnny uh what time
do i have to wrap up is that 12 30 or
someone just so i know i think i have 15
minutes but confirm that for me
so one of the things that we've seen is
specialization right in infosec you are
probably an example of specialization
right hands up if you were once the solo
security person in your organization at
one point
you were probably that um
so
if you were you've seen this uh kind of
evolve right now we have security
architects we have people that focus on
application security on network security
uh on security operations center
data uh digital forensics and instant
response cyber threat intel threat
hunting and offense right and office in
itself has changed when i started at
city like 12 years ago we were like six
or seven people doing everything offense
and then that um
started
you know spreading out we started doing
vulnerability assessment so running
vulnerability scans and then uh
prioritizing those vulnerabilities
validating them et cetera then pen
testing where you actually exploit
vulnerabilities and bug bounty where you
find vulnerabilities and vulnerability
research where you write all days kind
of like one of the things that grim does
right and then of course red teaming
which focuses on testing people process
and technology
and then within red teaming itself we
saw this evolve
my red team started i mentioned carlos
vendramini earlier on he is one of the
original red teamers uh over at city
still keep contact with him um
and
we went from hey we now have
you know seven or eight people on the
right team and while everyone kind of
knew how to do everything we started
specializing so we had developers
building custom
tooling and custom ways of custom
procedures custom tradecraft we had our
operators that were hands on keyboard
once initial access was obtained we had
people that specialized on initial
access and things like social
engineering oh carlos is on discord
there he goes he was one of the social
engineering uh folks way back when
um gaining access now i think his focus
is on cloud and whatnot but it was
really that specialization that allowed
us to be and show more value and really
where we've gone to now is that an
operator red team operator is not
necessarily a red team developer and tim
malcolm better uh who used to work over
at walmart and the red team there
when he wrote this blog post back in
2019 it's like three years ago if
anyone's keeping track of time nowadays
said the future of adversaries is
software development
and we're seeing that so one of the
things we're seeing is
training specialized in developing
command and control and implants here
are two these already passed but you can
keep your eye on them one was at eco
party
the premier latin american conference
it's like defcon of south america uh
it's in argentina uh there was a
workshop on that then uh
khan over in uh in europe did another
one uh shout out to joff and the wild
west hack folks and
they have a course called enterprise
attack emulation and c2 implant
development that one's coming up
and rasta mouse if uh someone actually
mentioned rfto on discord um
and this is
um a new course that uh that he put out
through zero point security so the same
c uh rto course um on c2 development and
c sharp so lots of specialization on
that uh and there i see kenny saying
operator is not the same as dev yes a
hundred percent we are seeing that right
and
attack infrastructure right those that
do attack infrastructure know how hard
this is this screenshot here is actually
taken from uh my friend mark smith uh he
runs out flank and um this actually is a
picture of red elk red elk is a red
teamers elastic instance um where you
can monitor all your red team um
infrastructure but you know just from
looking at this you can see over on the
right
you have multiple c2 servers in a single
red team operation and then you have a
bunch of redirectors
right and you use right up to track all
that and of course if you're doing blind
red teaming or stealth red teaming you
have a white cell or trusted agents uh
which is a more descriptive way of
calling them nowadays
and it's it's quite a bit right
so a lot of best practices we've learned
this year and i love some of the quotes
here uh hacking lz uh he is the cto at
it's justin uh elves over at trusted seg
i don't know what happened this time i
think uh cobalt strike had a
vulnerability or something and he wrote
it's 2021 don't expose those c servers
directly to the internet right use
redirectors and one of the most common
redirectors is domain fronting but
domain fronting is dead right it's
getting caught oh no never mind right
domain fronting's alive it actually
still works oh but microsoft might ban
your account yeah but it still works
right so uh domain fronting is it's
still one method it's a particular
technique under uh command and control
and now we're seeing serverless
functions being used for domain fronting
essentially using azure or lambda or
cloudflare worker cloud fair workers to
do your redirection from a purely
serverless uh method so there's a whole
bunch of this like that could be its own
talk um i post a lot about it at
howto.c2matrix.com
um other things we're seeing is
frameworks for c2s so in a particular
red team engagement you might actually
have not just multiple c2 servers but
multiple c2 frameworks running and these
folks out of argentina have this
framework called sutaka
that
uses the apis of the c2 so you can be in
one web app
and actually administer
your
implants from a variety of different c2s
all in that same window
uh so it's pretty cool very helpful from
a um
from a operations perspective
other sorry i'm going fast i see i have
like seven minutes left um other ones
that we see is abandoned this is to
build your uh your infrastructure
quickly because every
uh
exercise every red team you build
um
is
gonna have its own infrastructure so how
can you automate that build out of
buying domains doing redirectors having
visibility etc becomes a full-time job
um another cool one that i saw um is
havoc
this one uses aws and spins up um
using terraform your c2 so a lot of
focus on that as well so not only you
know the c2 side but all the
infrastructure required and why does it
require all of this because we're
getting better as an industry right
these c2s come out and we test them and
we see them and um
we improve making the red team's life
harder but if you make our life harder
that means we are improving
so um just based on the time here um
what's the road map we're going to
contin continue to evaluate the c2s we
want to map more to what the d2s can do
other than command and control what are
all these new features i see uh dom
uh just joined the discord there uh he's
one of the developers for nighthawk
which i mentioned earlier
awesome awesome stuff being built there
and really mapping to what you can do
afterwards right we're seeing a lot of
things like around edr events uh edr
evasion ndr evasion etc um so really
mapping that out and really lowering the
curve right like all of these tools or
at least most almost all of them right i
think 88 of them are free you can go on
github and test them so if anyone could
go on github and pull these down and
test them then you should too that's
really where we keep pushing for attack
detect and respond right you want to
attack yourself so that you can improve
your detection and be able to respond
before the impact actually happens
um with that said we have a new release
of the sand slingshot c2 matrix edition
so
this is a virtual machine that has
multiple c2s pre-installed
um the goal is to lower that learning
curve right if you've never set up or
never installed a c2 maybe you've never
used docker or something like that you
can get straight to testing comes with
covenant empire poetic merlin metasploit
mythic posh shadow silent trinity and
sliver already pre-installed you just
download the vm you uh run it in your
virtual machine and of course do not use
it for production testing this is
a lab environment
um
so with that please do get involved
contribute um literally you can just
ping us um like if you see a new c2 out
there that's not on the c2 matrix just
tag us tag c2 matrix tag me bryson or
adam
we have a feedback form um if there's
anything that's not accurate right c2s
change new features come out maybe we
said that a particular capability was
not an apartment c2 and now it is let us
know we do all this for free right so uh
uh definitely post those if you share a
blog post if you tested one of these c2s
right you just did a little how-to how
to run something let us know um and of
course if you evaluate any c2 uh we
would appreciate the whole line filled
out and um and have that information
there so i think uh i have like three
minutes left for questions so
apologize for that uh
mcs
didn't want to be that guy
excuse me
i don't think you're going to have time
for a whole lot of questions we might be
able to get one uh in before the next
speaker however if you want to answer
questions in the discord you're more
than welcome to
yo dawg i heard you like c2 so we built
a c2 that lets you c2 your c2s
yeah that's what it feels like there's
so many here
is a college degree required for open
source c2 no
um some are some are getting more and
more complex to install
um so
yeah that that's why we built the c2 the
the slingshot um is because they do get
a little tough to install and uh that is
not necessarily required to be an
operator so uh we put that out there
you do need a degree to be uh considered
to contribute to the repo though you're
gonna be vetted right
yeah
yeah so actually if you are so that's a
great question to contribute a c2 matrix
what i generally ask people is to just
share the entire line because the matrix
a lot of people are on it at like any
given time so i don't give right access
to a lot of people um there's a few like
if you contributed a few times and we
get know you right but you know someone
random coming off the internet that
we've never met before
does not get full right access to uh to
the c2 matrix now
why not
i thought this was open i thought this
was community
driven you know i thought it was open to
everything
yeah yeah
still some hot sex sorry yeah yeah uh
this is awesome
what a great thank you very much
yeah
um
yep we've uh uh we're running a little
short on time but uh like joyo said if
you want to throw additional questions
for jorge down in the discord jorge is
hanging out there and is happy to answer
every last one of them you have it's got
nothing but time i'm sure
well thank you all again uh happy
holidays thank you for doing this
on behalf of the the community thank you
for your time for real this it's hard to
run these um and keep them on schedule
so i'm going to shut up and talk to you
all on discord happy holidays
[Music]
you