[Music]
all right so um
this talk is shall we play a game my
name is uh is wolfgang gorlick
i'm an advisory cso for cisco secure
today before then i was a security
officer
i ran a couple of consulting companies
um i i did a uh apprenticeship program
for a while where we put a whole bunch
of cybersecurity people through through
the paces and got their careers started
and as a matter of fact
it was around the time doing that i mean
three four years ago now where i first
debuted this talk
and uh and i was like yeah you know
shall we play a game right like the the
quintessential war games
message right like the hacker one of the
first hacker movies that so many people
in my generation saw right where you got
like the modems and you're using the pay
phones and everything and uh and one of
the people was like you know that's it's
more edgy
than i'd expect from you wolf i'm like
edgy it's not edgy it's like shall we
shall we play the game like no no it's
really edgy like i i wouldn't think
you'd reference the the saw movies
and like the the saw movies they're like
yeah you know like do you want to play a
game
like what are you talking about i'm
talking about like a nice game of chess
like no no no we're like
tell me how much blood
will you give in order to survive
no
that's not it at all so
uh i do think that maybe millennials
roon ruined everything actually i think
more than that we need more like war
games and hacker movies like things that
are set in this time and not just reboot
to the matrix which is probably a whole
other conversation that we should really
have in discord
but uh what this topic is actually on is
a a idea a capability that i've been
doing for a very long time and it's
really been the crux of many of my
security programs back to when i was a
security officer in financial services
through a couple consulting firms
this idea of running security exercises
and so today i want to talk about how
and why to run security exercise how to
structure it um where to start if you
don't have ones and also i'm gonna end
up their time today
um talking about a maturity model okay
so if you've got something going on
where do you go next uh and if you're
just starting out how do you plot
a road map for doing security exercises
you know it's it kind of makes sense
right we all
have effectively two paths we're playing
when the chips are down we're really
playing the game of security now we're
doing the compliance things which are
incredibly important and needed um not
when we're doing the the operations
things which are again incredibly
important but when the chips are down
we've got two things going on we've got
the life cycle
of ir
and we got the life cycle of uh the
attacker and this is well known you know
we're gonna we're gonna do stuff in ir
we're gonna write a plan and i'm sure
it's a great plan i'm sure we haven't
handed it off to the junior analyst
we're gonna have some run books i'm sure
they're very accurate and have been
updated sometime
this century or at least this decade and
and then something's gonna happen we're
gonna identify the bad guys and we're
gonna crowd them and get them out of the
network meanwhile of course the
adversaries got their own sort of path
that they're taking from reconnaissance
and to breaking into the system to
achieving what their objectives are
fundamental problem of this of course is
the time delay now this is well known
it's been said for at least a decade
that takes months to years to detect
when an adversary is in our networks i
think the last figure i saw was around
six months i thought this is good six
months is bad but this is good it's much
better than it was i'm like it used to
be you know a year or more this is good
and then i was reading uh reading some
ransomware reports
and it occurred to me thanks to the
ransomware author uh the report author
by the way not the
ransomware code itself um that the
reason for that is
ransomware attacks are the majority of
attacks right now and of course they
want to be identified very quickly and
that's pulling that time frame down
so it takes months to detect we know
this it takes three months or more to
respond this isn't something we
ordinarily think about a talk about
why is that what happens there when
we're doing that response
i can tell you just from
conversations in the past couple months
what happens when you're doing that
response uh csos uh i'm talking to you
friends and peers cecil's want to
micromanage right the boards yelling at
us are the ceo's yelling at us i'm going
to get in there and i'm going to make
sure no you really shouldn't step away
from the keyboard trust me
trust me i know it feels good but we
need to step back so there's
micromanaging going on um there's lack
of coordination going we don't know what
the plan is paul the run book oh my
goodness this says we're running
semantic we haven't run semantics since
2015. i'm sure the run book has been
updated recently
but it probably hasn't
what else happens well this one was a
conversation i was just having
a couple weeks ago
where they're responding to an event and
they reload the entire environment
that's awesome they reload the entire
environment with the same vulnerable
version of software that they're running
that allowed the
attacker to get in the first place
that happens a number of things go wrong
because we don't necessarily have the
muscle built up to to necessarily go
ahead and eradicate so three months is
the the median figure there
meanwhile on the on the um
attacker side it's much different now
these numbers can vary uh
i was talking to a ciso a couple months
ago and he was telling me of an incident
that was literally minutes right they
uh did this attack that's very common
right now if you don't have thresholding
in your multi-factor they just kept
pushing a request and pushing a request
to someone to finally they accepted it
once that happened they got in their
email they threw up all the email rules
uh to
effectively backdoor uh outlook and then
sent in all the phishing emails and and
head shell in the environment in minutes
so obviously these numbers are averages
uh but reconnaissance it depends on how
long you're taking maybe a few months
depending on how you're scoping out in
the environment
initial breach a couple days escalating
privileges a couple days
hours usually moving laterally
and then depending on what the uh
objective is could be a couple minutes
after that or could be weeks after that
so if you line up this up with the the
you know time-based security right the
classic the time-based security
uh model
where we say security is where
prevention is time is greater than
detection plus recovery if you line all
that up it's pretty clear that we're in
a bad spot and we've been in a bad spot
for a very long time now we know this um
this is not news but there's so many
different ways to tackle this uh do we
add more people to it well maybe we've
got a town charger we don't um do we buy
more technology well maybe we got
budgeted we don't do we use a technology
that we have better well
probably should because most of the time
in my experience our security products
are maybe half used half the features
are enabled right they're not
necessarily widely deployed
but it really brings up a good argument
about what needs to happen
do we need more tech
do we need better processes do we need
more people
and so what i would argue what i'm
arguing in this talk and what i'm
presenting as a method in this talk
is what we really need to do is get
better at
formally exercising
those steps in ir
and formerly making sure that the
controls are enabled in our operational
and are working are there when we need
them and building up that muscle memory
well that's what i think we need to do
in order to get better at uh containing
and eradicating the adversary so what
does that look like where do we start if
we're gonna do that
well it fundamentally begins with a
story
you know the uh
the native american phrase
um is those who tell stories
uh rule the world
or at least rule the sock i think that
may be my version of it um those who
tell stories rule the sock that sounds
good
what where does a good story begin with
well it begins with a couple of things
certainly
breach of the week
if you and your team
have not done a threat model
um and possibly a tabletop
on log4j and say the last month
maybe maybe you should or at least do it
do that right now this is not a good
time but let's say
in the beginning of january that would
be a good time so whatever is in the
news is of course a a good example it's
a salient example
especially if it's at something
in an organization like ours right and
one of our peers um pen tests is is also
a good one hey a pen tester got in this
way this is what they did
let's talk through that and let's uh
let's go ahead and build out some
security exercises that way
um threat intelligence your ice acts
uh are a great one here's what's
happening
in
financial companies
just like ours here's what that looks
like we want to build out a
threat model and security exercise
around that
and of course we need to create a nice
clean feedback loop right if it happens
an instant response it probably should
be codified captured turned into an
exercise and repeated so the next time
that there's a fire we're not just
putting the fire with the other fire the
next time that there's a fire we're like
ah i remember this a few months ago we
went through this drill
so there's some good sources for these
stories now everyone's got a story right
everyone's got a way of saying this and
and there's some risks to these stories
so what what makes a good story the good
foundation for a security exercise i'd
argue it has three three things
it has a heart it's interesting it's
funny right there's a hero to that story
um and and it's the type of story that
makes you
want to hear it and makes you want to
tell it and that telling and retelling
is also a critical part of security
culture a little bit outside of this
conversation but if you've got good
stories that spread through your
organization oh
fantastic for security awareness much
better than please click through this
uh minute powerpoint and answer these
questions that you're going to brute
force english so it has a heart right it
has a heart uh it has a head it has some
facts we're not just saying oh yes
there's there's this really interesting
story that happened one day uh no we're
saying also did you know that um
this particular type of attack comprised
uh 37 of the attacks that were in the
verizon data breach report data set uh
for 2020 and so by adding a couple steps
we can circumvent that and oh by the way
again in that verizon data breach report
they found that if we increased it from
15 steps
or more
that the success that attack dropped in
half
it has a head it has some facts behind
it and then it has a point right all
right so now you capture the person's uh
attention hopefully they're enjoying the
story hopefully they're going to tell it
again
now you've stacked it up with some facts
it's grounded in reality and now you
have the ask here's what we want to do
we want you to enable this we want you
to change this we want you to join our
next drill that's what makes for a good
story
what makes for a bad story invariably is
fud
right those those are not the good
stories i've seen organizations have
attempted this
and uh
and it's
those
stories that go something like this
um there will be blood right this is
this is going to be terrible if this
happens the business will end and our
customers will never trust us again and
my god our stock money will market uh
valuation will fall through the floor
and people will will switch from owning
our stocks to buying bitcoin no no one
cares don't do that doesn't work
um and uh and they may get attention
initially but it's not backed by
facts and of course that's that's not
very reliable
it's need to be grounded in reality uh
one one
example
that i can give you is we did a security
exercise with the city uh when i was
running a red team a few years ago and
uh and we asked for and i thought this
was very reasonable
if i was johnny christmas i would have
gotten this approved
we asked for a grappling hook i thought
that was a reasonable request
if you're trying to break into a city
you would need a grappling hook
especially if you're anyway that was
apparently not backed up by any factual
data we couldn't demonstrate how often
times criminals are using these types of
uh these types of techniques so it has
to be grounded in reality
now when you're telling these stories
you're going to get some pushback and
that's not a bad thing
you can actually use the objections that
you get when you're telling these
stories as teachable moments
in one scenario i was i was doing a
early version of this with some
storytelling and talking through the
tactics and sort of level setting with a
security team the director was at the
head of the table
really smart lady her team was all in um
but you can tell she wasn't into it i
was referencing dave kennedy's uh talk
at the time i think it was a def con
talk uh if it may be a black hat someone
wants to correct me that's fine uh but
that he had shown how to like compromise
all the systems at once with system
center awesome talking he hits the
button he's got the lighter going and
all the shelves are pop so i was talking
through that and she's got her arms
crossed and she's pushing back from the
table
and finally she looks and she goes this
is all fine and good but no one's going
to know that we've got a system center
project going on
i'm like oh
yeah you're right no no one probably
would know that no no no
i'm like you know so the way you might
know that is the listeners common sense
uh or osn the way osn generally starts
until i'm on the projector so i throw
open a uh you know a browser and open up
google and so the way that
reconnaissance normally starts with some
google doors right some searches and so
maybe if someone searched with like your
company name and system center and so
you know i started walking through that
and and of course there's a job posting
for an engineer for system center um as
they were ramping up the system center
project they're trying to staff up uh
there are some you know help desk posts
and some forums
uh hey how does this work how does that
work
with the you know uh company's email
address um like i said when i do that
but the best one was the best one was so
remind you she was completely checked
out at this point the best one was
they had done a case study with
microsoft on system center
and so we catch at that point she puts
her hands with us pulls forward and
looks her dudes go see see this is why
we need to pay attention everyone now i
just want to demonstrate how easy it is
wolf please take us to the next steps it
was perfect so those objections those
objections themselves
are teachable moments
all right so now we've got a story
but now we need to know what the tactics
are
and for the longest time the tactics the
ttps were really what kept me up at
night right 10 years ago 15 years ago
building out exercises like this was
really the the ttps that were very
difficult for me to get my handle around
there's a lot of confusion around it
everyone had their own names for things
there wasn't a lot of commonality um
thankfully a lot of that is as
straightened out
so let's talk through how how we get
there
we start with that story
we do a tabletop
we build out the scenario right we got
the attack live cycle what does that
look like well for a data loss breach
here's how the attacker might move
through the network for going from
phishing to compromised data
here's what that might look like high
level
now behind the scenes for each one of
those labels we really want to get
specific tactics
that an adversary might execute
thankfully thankfully what's really been
a game changer in my opinion has been
the mitre attack framework in the past
few years which has really allowed us to
have a common set of language around
these tactics have a ability to delve
into what you can do to prevent detect
it
have uh have ability to get good data on
what's
regularly happening and whatnot
and then you use
as talked about earlier in in this track
right security's most used tool excel
there's probably a better way to do this
but i'd throw an excel
table lay out the stage layout the
tactics and have some descriptions
and that would break that story out into
a really good model and then we could
back that model up with some data again
how common are these tactics being
exploited who is exploiting them are
those threat actors threat actors that
are targeting our industry are those
threat actors that would want what we
have
and so on
from there one thing i want to caution
against
is is being too specific so i mentioned
system center and the system center
scenario
was really appropriate for an
organization that was going through a
system center implementation project
perfect spot on very timely
not so good for someone who's not using
system center so one of the things that
we did when we repeated those exercises
we raised it up a level right what is
what is your patch management what is
your configuration management software
what is your help desk use let's talk
about that if that was been compromised
similarly if you're talking about target
the the easy answer is okay we're going
to talk about hvac vendors getting
compromised but what we really need to
be talking about
is third-party vendors
equifax with the apache struts
vulnerability great example
because
should we be talking about apache struts
or should we be talking about what
happens
when there's an unknown zero-day
code in your environment
that's not your acid inventory how are
you identifying that how are you
protecting against that
i'd argue that later it's really
important
to bring these stories up a level
so they can be broad
now the the like marketing level
description that's right the the email
that you get would be like zero day
protection no
please no
i want to kill every single vendor who
tells me they've got zero day protection
that's not what i'm saying what i am
saying is
anyone who did a threat model and has
been running security exercises
on unpatched unknown
java vulnerabilities in their
environment
have had a leg up on the log for j
vulnerability doesn't mean they've got
zero day protection but what it does
mean is when the event happens if you've
been up a level anything that falls
under that category you've now been
prepared for
so that's how you start with your story
and your scenario now once we get that
down of course we need a tabletop but we
need to actually make sure that this
makes sense and what it looks like and
what we're going to do
the purpose for any tabletop is to share
out that story and scenario
educate participants on the ir life
cycle
because we forget
the human half life of memory is six
weeks
if you look at the forgetting curve it's
even more depressing than that i think
it's like 30 days
where you forget like half of everything
you hear
so the more frequently you can run
through this the better and also gaining
consensus on controls
you'd
be surprised or maybe not if you've done
things like this how often the
conversation goes like this uh security
team how would you detect this and they
go oh no problem we would turn to the
networking team that has networking
monitoring set up for the networking
modern teams like
we uh
on the last refresh two years ago we uh
didn't renew that licensing so no we
don't monitor any of those ports
security team's like wait i thought you
had full packet capture
we did three years ago but we haven't
recently um that's why we haven't had
any false positives that's a good thing
right
no
so gaining consensus on what controls
actually exist
is one of the benefits of the tabletop
of course getting everyone on the same
page for for future improvements
so here's where we're going to move from
tactics to controls and start going
through each tactic and listing out what
we can do
generally back to the beginning back to
time-based security i like to look at
prevent and detect right what can stop
this tactic what can detect it from uh
if it's occurring
as organizations mature
right if you've got a pretty mature
tabletop you can start looking at some
additional controls like disruption
deception is
really hot or at least was a couple
years ago
i think you should be really good at
prevent and detect before you even
consider deception but point is there's
additional things you can do
from there
once we've got our tactics
and our detect and prevent we can really
start getting a good handle
on defense and death
uh i am i am
generally a little bit annoyed at the
term defense and depth it's another one
of those things like zero day protection
that wrinkles me i don't think anyone
in 2021
anyone would say oh i don't have
defensiveness thank you for telling me
that i i knew i was missing something
all i needed was more layers of defense
i don't think anyone who's been
compromised uh by a ransomware attack
we'll go you know what if only we had a
couple more layers that probably would
have sold it the challenge with defense
and depth is it usually doesn't
measure depth against something right
it's not depth against a particular
tactic it's not depth against a
particular attack it's just general
depth which really translates into how
many products have you bought and
how deep is the stack of licensing
agreements on your desk
what i like about this approach is i can
get a real true defense and depth across
the scenario as we miss different
tactics if if a control fails if av is
evaded as we miss different
tactics we still have a series of depth
along that path to catch them
so we filled that out so what does that
look like in terms of
um
the overall process
well looks like something like this
we do the scenario threat modeling where
we do the attack stage and the tactic
tactic description and then we do the
tabletop where we fill in that control
and the control description if you were
to flip that around and kind of delve
deeper into that you can look at an
example here with credential access you
can see how we're tying this down to
multiple levels of prevention detection
you can also see again a really good
example of what i mean by
um you know a better level of defense
right balloon tower defenses the
balloons kind of move through their path
our ability to hit them and if we miss
okay we've got another monkey who's
going to be throwing a dart balloon
tower defense right
in this particular attack stage we've
got multi-factor we've got logging well
multi-factors bypass like that push
example i gave earlier we're going to
have additional stages where we can stop
the adversary
so there's a couple different things
here with the controls i want to
highlight one we do want to keep it high
level
i like to map it out to whatever control
framework the organization is running in
i've done iso
27 series i've done nist of course
cis is also popular so mopping it up to
a high-level guideline is pretty
important but as we know back to the
beds of death well all right our our
control set says we've got logging okay
great
do you log this our control set says we
have locking
do you log that our control
but do you no well
maybe not
we also want to make sure that we're
going low level and logging at a very
specific so
in the control keep it high level and
map to a framework in the description
keep it low level and specific what that
means is we can then map that low level
out
to whoever owns that
to
make sure it's done
to verify it um to audit it and so on
and from a high level we can of course
report that up to our audit committees
and into the c level
this also means from a stage perspective
we can use these coverage metrics for
prevention detection for each one of
these stages of the attack
all right so now what we have done right
we've got a story we've got a scenario
we've table top that okay we've talked
through the controls and we're good we
think we're good now what we need to do
is actually make sure that the controls
work which is where we get to
uh adversarial emulation uh or sometimes
red teaming or what have you
where we're gonna actually exercise
these controls so if you say we've got
80 authentication logging all right
we're going to attempt to log into a
disabled account and make sure
someone actually does something
it's actually a true story i it was one
of my controls
and i came in i had friday off i came in
on monday and my logs were just full my
scene was screaming my logs were full
turned to the guy i was on deck why did
you do anything
he's like well i i just figured it was
something you were screwing around with
like why would i screw around with a
disabled account it's like you're always
adding controls and alerts in this thing
i never know what's going on and sure
enough we had someone who had been
terminated who spent the entire weekend
trying to break into our network
so testing that and making sure someone
responds
similar to something like uh email
controls
right and exercising with it and i t
security to test each one of those
tactics
and determine control readiness ideally
you know in the beginning maybe it's a
manual process but ideally as you mature
that becomes an automated process a
scriptable process a repeatable process
the time and time again is verifying
those controls
and that's what really allows you to to
catch um any gaps in our understanding i
thought we had monitoring well we didn't
really know the licensing it also allows
us to catch any gaps that occurs from
like typical it operations
so i was doing this with a medical
provider
one of their strong controls was a very
well locked down
kiosk
kiosk in each
room so a patient facing kiosk there's
12 of them
and these kiosks had a
awesome certificate-based awesome great
not just mac address which you know
we can bypass pretty easily
but certificate-based awesome 12 of them
great so i said all right i sent my team
to go verify that because that was one
of their main controls against
preventing the type of a scenario where
we're mentioning first one fine second
one fine six one five seventh one fine
one out of those 12 did not have the
control in place
for whatever reason knack had been
disabled
moreover more concerning to me
was not only was it disabled
how it was also
not set to log
so
[Music]
we were able to plug in our attack
proceed and
blast through the rest of the scenario
and uh pretty quickly demonstrate some
real risk
so
kind of disconcerting when if you're the
cso or the security director leader
who's thinking i'm fine i've got an act
do you know do you really
because without exercising that defense
we really have
no assurance as to whether or not it
works we really don't and that's
something i think we forget all too
often
one additional comment i want to leave
here is we gotta create evidence when
we're testing these things out but not
incidents so it's very important that
when we're testing these things just
like a pen test
that we're very cautious about what we
exploit and what we pull on and what we
flip over um so we don't uh damage
anything
all right last section uh keeping score
metrics let's talk a little bit about
some numbers
um first off how often should you do
this we don't no there's no one knows
a lot a little no one knows
uh one thing that may be interesting
directionally is
cisco released the security outcomes uh
study volume two
about a month ago
and looked at these types of exercises
but for disaster recovery
so the question was um
how many exercises per month and that
includes tabletops that includes plan
reads that includes full polls the whole
nine hearts
how many exercises per month
would
generate
the highest degree of
uh confidence and uh you know
performance in the bcdr outcome
and they found that number is five right
organizations are doing five
exercises a month and again plan through
tabletop through actual technical
exercise were the ones that had the
highest reported uh numbers of
continuity and recovery success so in
that world five in my world when i was
security officer a few years ago we were
doing a monthly so somewhere between
five and one is where i would think we
would be
from a metrics perspective i think it's
more about just tracking the number held
and then slowly growing that up over
time
in each one of those tabletops looking
at the defense and depth numbers i
mentioned as well as the stage control
numbers i demonstrated those are really
good metrics for an individual tabletop
for a exercise itself again number of
exercises held control effectiveness if
you're batting like
fifty percent or sixty percent or even
seventy percent of your control is being
effective
um you've got a problem right we've got
a big disconnect between what we think
we have and what we really have
generally your control should be 90
percent or more effective if i think
i've got
12 stations with neck all 12 stations
should have neck
and then of course
if you've got your sock team watching
this how long does it take them to
detect and to respond that time metric
is is really critical as i mentioned
earlier to
running the whole ir process how quickly
can we identify
and jump on
the ir process pull down the right run
book and execute it
by doing multiple of these
we can begin to pull out common themes
we can begin to map them across
different exercises and start building
some really good plans for improvement
and by using controls that map up to a
higher level framework we can also
spot out uh you know any any hot spots
or areas where we need to jump on
and
level up
so in conclusion right shall we play a
game yes yes yes
but not this kind of game no fun
no fud
simply
um security exercises which arguably war
games was a little bit of flood
that led to a whole bunch of cyber
security laws but you get my point
security exercises
drills
finding ways to detect faster respond
faster by doing the actual scenarios
communicating them out getting people on
the same page
i mentioned at the beginning that would
give a maturity model so let me walk you
through what that looks like in the
beginning it's very ad hoc i've got a
story i'm going to tell it i'm going to
tell it and i want you know our team
meetings i'm going to tell it uh you
know our security awareness it's very ad
hoc
level two is taking that scenario making
it more formal laying in the the ttps
and and doing the tabletop level three
is taking that tabletop and tying those
tactics and controls out
to uh to make it very clear what is what
and making sure we've got good consensus
on that
level four is making sure those tactics
and controls are tied to frameworks and
are tracked in a unified fashion
consistently
and that we're doing exercises
and level five the most mature one
is where we are doing all that the table
tops the tactics the controls we got a
framework we got exercises but now we're
automating those
um we are uh in some cases some
organizations are also
pairing this level five pairing this
with chaos engineering where you also
have additional things happening to
test and verify the environment
and we're moving towards a continuous
improvement approach if you're looking
for a way to mature
this security capability which again i
would argue is really fundamental uh to
moving beyond just compliance i mean
beyond just check boxes really having a
strong ir capability
that that works when you need it
here's a maturity model you can follow
and of course behind the scenes of all
that
going ahead and keeping track of metrics
so that you can demonstrate success and
improve
that's it for me um i will pause for a
question i think i got a couple minutes
that qr code you can trust me you can
trust me it is my website or you can
type it in uh and there's my contact
information as well if you want to i'll
reach out for any questions that we
don't have a chance to get to today
[Music]
[Applause]
you