anyway so Artyom is first up
DNS security
and how to basically better manage those
so much give a warm round of applause
and welcome him and let's get moving
forward thank you very much good money
first of all let me say you say thank
you for showing up so early after
midnight social wasn't expecting so many
people coming up if I was you I wouldn't
be a bit so first of all a disclaimer
what were mainly going to talk about the
issues related to maintaining a DNA zone
in we are an authoritative DNS server
some issues are also kind of applicable
for recursive DNS server so we'll see
but the main focus is Dena zones and
authoritative service so let's start and
let's start with a bit of history so
back in the time of dinosaurs which was
like 80s the humanity was struggling for
a solution to civilization threatening
problem of name resolution on a
contemporary computers you can still
spot artifact from that distant past
which is called host file host file is
an essentially a mapping between an IP
address and what it's supposed to be a
handful of host names so if you want it
to like resolve first name you can just
read this file line my line until you've
found what they are looking for right
and correct mapping with an IP address
well it worked for for a while but the
issue is if your internet consists of a
large number of computers and I mean
really large like a thousand you easily
run into all sorts of troubles
maintaining and supporting
all those files in case and you network
services fired up
thus a network protocol was born a UDP
based at that moment with clients and
servers and stuff but the whole purpose
of this protocol was again simple and
really like to this intentionally wrong
see the code so it was just a simple
conversion from a stream which is a
hostname to a four byte integer which is
ipv4 address some other functionality
functionality was also built into the
protocol but except for few cases it was
all just required for the protocol
itself to run and main purpose initially
was like that then a bit less than 10
years ago World Wide Web appeared and
enterprises have started to a concrete
world wide web imposed new requirements
for DNS protocol and kept doing that new
applications like load balancing geo
balancing appeared and rather than
refined with more thorough approaches
like policy based a sand-based
balancing we'll discuss it a little bit
later
next enterprises wanted business
contingency in redundancy so they opted
for dns-based failover more and more
functionality was added we are extension
mechanisms like Adina so a client subnet
and more next ipv6 has arrived and a lot
of security stuff worse was being
started to be implemented in the DNS
protocol with DNS act day in CA and so
on so now there are such a lot of
features and opportunities built into a
DNS protocol so that if you are even not
using them currently you will start
doing it at some point in time or else
your competitors will do
and here is our problem how should an
Internet company Montee its genus
infrastructure well there are basically
two options either you can run it
yourself or you can outsource it to us
some kind of third-party provider with
each approach the Moke more question
state if you are doing it in-house then
you need some kind of a software server
product which will essentially do DNS
responses for you and if you are
outsourcing it you need to choose a
service provider because they're just
just the plenty of them available so
here is our problem statement let's
figure out starting with option 1 how do
we choose a software product at the
point where the overall requirements are
not still very clear the protocol is
changing the world is changing and
but-but-but I need to choose something a
naive approach would be a the service
software should be scalable in order to
handle all the Lord your marketing
department could bring to you be it
should be feature-rich in order to
handle our future suggestions and
possible requirements let's start this
way with cul ability back almost 5 years
ago we have carried out a complex
benchmarking for different DNS service
software releases there was
comprehensive list which is on the slide
of the products to test and they brought
some hardware decent at the moment for
that all the software was in vanilla
state without any third-party patches or
plugins our purpose was purely academic
in order to find out who runs better
code with better hash tables and stuff
so this way this is why we've mixed
authoritative service we've recursive
ones and for the authoritative thing
we've generated
300 zones for testing purposes and for
caching resolvers we've kept pretty much
the same amount of data in warm cache
we've done our benchmarks we've got our
results I'm referring to our previous 5
years old presentation for details here
is a link on the slide and when we've
shared that the question everyone kept
asking us was guess where's bind well
during preliminary testing a bind
appeared to show results so
disappointing most cases completely
indistinguishable from the x8 that we've
decided to skip benchmarking bind at all
however why here five years ago or four
years ago when we decided to repeat our
benchmark to see if anything has changed
in the world we've headed bind to that
here on this slide is the amount of
responses served as more and more
Curie's per second kept coming up up to
a number of to millions at the right
side of the slide by three different
servers namely bind not and NSD under
three different conditions the higher
the graph is on the right side the
better the results and ladies and
gentlemen here is mind regardless of
affinity and other configuration options
bind has failed to catch up pretty soon
at the stage there were about 400,000
queries per second on our hardware and
this is not only our observation just
for a sanity check here is another test
run by authors of DNS ever called not
note that the skill has changed some out
on the Y X there is now not the exact
amount of responses returned but the
percent percentage of successful
responses so the close the closer to
100% on the right side the better here
at a rate of 1 million Curie's per
second on a server dedicated for this
Veritas
bind fails to answer one third of
requests and this is when you have no
DNS SEC because when you turn it on the
results are a lot worse when mine starts
failing records almost from the very
beginning and at a rate of 1 million
queries it doesn't handle even even 1/2
of requests this is not good
bind is de facto a standard DNS software
right it's widely used on the internet
and it's a and it appears to have all
sorts of scalability problems yes of
course there are always our solutions
for scalability problems for example
like you can always lend a server farm
role roughly equal in size to a soccer
field fill it with back-end servers and
set up some reverse proxy in front of
the farm and that will pretty much do
for most of scalability problems for
example this way you can really do we
can check in user space or stuff but
when we're speaking of a simple task
like DNS this pretty much looks like an
overkill
ok next solution is to choose some other
product instead of bind but
bind is defector standard again and all
its competitors have much less customers
which raises all sorts of questions like
who maintains that what is his
motivation would they keep like backward
compatibility in case they get bored of
supporting their old code and decide to
rewrite all the stuff from scratch how
reliable is it is it scalable for all
the purposes or its authors are just
targeting there or a couple or a hand
and a handful of use cases
important or interesting for them how
will it be scalable under other
conditions how well is it supported is
what is the SLA for fixing bugs
getting bugs are authors aware of
contemporary security approaches well
what's with fixing vulnerabilities bug
bounty etc because you know if there are
no security advisories published for a
software product it doesn't mean its
authors are good at writing software it
might as well mean they are bad at
writing or at writing advisories and
again what features are on the product
roadmap so here with all this problem
issues we always tend to get back to our
requirements maybe they had just
excessive what is this feature set we
might want is it really big and how
scalable a good old DNS service should
be because in its core a genus lock up
is a quite simple thing here is the
Facebook page of our meeting I've heard
allotted it a few times and collected
traffic dams back in the time of
dinosaurs you can easily expect like 2
to 10 genus packets in the dump but
today we held off all sorts of subdomain
CDN some counters and stuff so an
average Facebook page makes about 50
genius queries to load which accounts
for a hundred of packets here but when
we are just counting packets it's still
one if they amount HTTP services
generated and each genus conversation is
brought a simple and straightforward
like you have a query which is 30 byte
long plus all plus all the headers then
you get an answer which is 45 bytes long
plus all the headers and that's pretty
much it so apparently DNS isn't rocket
science right well it's not when we are
talking about the type conversion thing
we've started with in theory there is no
difference between theory and practice
but in practice there is what if we want
more let's start with gia balancing it's
a widely used method as its appealing
right
to reduce the latency between network
clients and like web services by looking
at the IP source of a DNS query and
returning an answer with an IP address
which is as close to client as possible
in terms of geolocation say here's an
example let's say you have a customer is
in South Korea and you have two servers
set up you know one in Japan and they
are the one in California so you
probably want your customer to go
towards a Japanese server right
certainly there's no country data are
present in an IP packet so you should
use proprietary database from some
vendor here to map an IP address to in
geolocation however a reliability of
such databases for that particular TAC
is questionable to say the least
here is a simple example I've tripped
the demo on one Wenders website and
submitted Google Public DNS address
here's what's returned to the United
States sorry guys but for eight are in
custody they are not in United States
not in Europe not in Singapore they are
in each of those locations and another
funny thing by the way is that the
database not only returns the country it
also gives us GPS coordinates where's
that let's have a look well within the
middle of change there were how's the
water gentlemen so this is wrong
actually there's pretty much more to it
all those databases regardless of
whether I'm not blowing in magma max
mine here have this owner location
versus actual geographic location de
Lima what would you return
they are generally are generally
unreliable for anything except trough
statistics now this by over this a long
story by the way about those GPS
coordinates follow the last link on that
slide but the overall idea is the
database does know that the results
returned are in neck
right sometimes intentionally
intentionally inaccurate yet the
database API doesn't give us a clue to
that no warning no error this is just
one of the long list of issues I'm not
going in my Marc's mind again the all
those databases are all the same I've
tried a lot vendors for instance are
used to import data from regional
internet registries databases where the
information is of enact inaccurate or
outdated but probably the main issue
with gia balancing is that if you have a
server in Japan and a client a customer
in South Korea the traffic between them
doesn't necessarily go through Pacific
Ocean it could as well go all the way
through Atlantic because once again as
I've said before there's no country
dating an IP packet and there is no
geography on the internet that's just
network topology and as there are no
countries there are just autonomous
systems and their mutual relations with
that in mind some DNA separators
recently started offering more granule
granular approach to balancing here for
example is ns-one and their net net fans
filters which can be used to
subsequently refined answer policies for
different ace numbers and prefixes so in
case you're south korean users start
complaining about increased latency
which might be the case today because an
Olympic Games there and a lot of your
customers are probably there you can
simply add specific policies for
problematic Korean prefixes problem
solved
management has happened so gia balancing
and prefix targeting may be extremely
useful for some enterprises they issue
that of course as a matter of fact is
these all ads are great too
computational complexity of a DNS answer
next
dynamic configuration this is about how
you have to deploy changes in DNS
configuration here is an example of how
it was in Spotify like five years ago
there was some chat in an internal
messenger flooded with of topic as a
matter of fact and from time to time an
engineer in duty he shouted in this chat
Dinah's deploy this meant that he is now
going to deploy changes in their DNS
setup this desperate shout itself served
two purposes first everyone get notified
that some configuration changes are
ongoing so if anything goes wrong they
know where to seek revenge second it
served as a mutual exclusion a locking
mechanism of course this approach
allowed for all sorts of troubles and
Spotify guys are brilliant they are not
doing this anymore and neither should
you
DNS isn't a static configuration file
anymore this is essentially an API for
configuration management systems and
different applications
service provisioning statistics and
monitoring policy management all these
are tasks for this API an enterprise
will want this sooner or later
working with DNS all style with manual
deployment and human our thing is it
isn't a contemporary way to do that next
on our stage failover if you have two
like two servers in your DNS a record
and one of them goes down you want it to
be taken out of genus rotation for this
you need some kind of a monitoring tool
again which then reports to a genius API
we've discussed before there are issues
with DNS failover here's a graph of HTTP
requests towards a server which was
taken out of genus rotation a quarter
after 10:00 p.m. on the left of the
slide the TTL of DNS record was 120
seconds
as you can see 15 minutes ago
one third of traffic was still flowing
towards the server which was at that
moment meant supposed to be down for a
while only roughly an hour ago the
traffic finally stopped flowing and all
the square between the blue line is
customers who would have been lost for a
website in case of a real emergency
you can somehow fix that by reducing
your TTL time to live over the DNS
record for two lights that feel like 20
seconds but this way your traffic will
be easily six times it was before the
change next to the security as we've
discussed before you need to figure out
how the author of your genius software
handles vulnerabilities how often white
pages get released what's the policy of
security advisories etc another security
issue is DDoS first DNS is again once
again udp-based by but by design so it's
more exposed to volumetric attacks like
amplification and so on you need to use
some kind of effective line rate
challenges or handshakes to verify the
source IP address of queries not respond
to spoofed traffic for high level
attacks like water torture you need some
kind of analysis statistics and black
lists and again black lists are
ineffective without those challenges as
DNS traffic can easily be spoofed once
again to handle large attacks you'll
need an any casted Network for DNS it's
not an option or suggestion in 2018 it's
a must because DNS attacks are cheap
porn and tackle and completely
disastrous
they're also also other things like DNS
SEC DNS over HTTP and so on there are
almost almost 200 RFC is written
and related to DNS so now homegrown DNS
starts to look pretty much rocket
science so now what about service
providers there are plenty of them I've
outlined a few on the slide sorry for
not putting your favorite provider on
the list I have a slide only of that
size
however the question stands how do we
choose this way a service provider but
this way we have some good news a good
news is that apparently you don't need
to choose introducing SRT T which is a
smooth round trip time this is a
mechanisms built into resolver resolving
DNS service a lot of them and already
deployed in most small of his home
office and even enterprise networks
mostly accidentally by the way NS one
study suggests that though only like 50
percent of DNS resolvers on the internet
a habit those 50 percent of resolvers
actually account for up to 90 percent of
Internet traffic a subsidy is intended
to help running a lot of authoritative
name service simultaneously for a zone
benefiting from the combined coverage of
all of them if there are say two name
service for zone a subtlety enabled
server will query both and then use the
one which responds faster in order to
reduce latency for a DNS client here is
how it works I'm familiar with box plot
please raise your hands oh good
s'okay meat meat box plot a box plot is
a method for graphically depicting
groups of numerical data in our case
this will be the response times of DNA
is through their quartiles the bottom
and the top of the box are always the
first and third quartiles and the band
inside the box is always the second
quartile which is the medium at the ends
of the whiskers are always minimum and
maximum all of all the data or something
closely related to that here are stack
overflows DNS measurement in New Zealand
stackoverflow operated to dienes
operators at the time amazon route 53
and Google DNS apparently route 53 has a
point of presence somewhere close to New
Zealand and Google hasn't so if you
replace route 53 with Google you'll get
complaints from users due due to heavily
increased latency however what if you
don't replace but add Google in line
with route 53 will there be any
drawbacks for the DNS performance here
is the result in green as you can see a
combined solution performs much better
than Google
it's roughly equal to root 53 so adding
in even a heavily underperforming the
nest operator doesn't affect latency in
a bad way which what is more funny
the combined setup despite Google's
inefficiency in New Zealand performs
even better than route 53 alone so the
box plot is lower this is probably
because there's a couple of locations in
New Zealand where route 53 performs
really bad probably because of ice P
relations we discussed before in those
locations due to SRT Google takes over
so if you run two solutions
simultaneously you benefit from both
solutions in the most marvelous way so
here's how you can choose a genus
provider just pick a few the more you
have the better in might believe up to
406 will be just fine
this way in case by the way you are
paying them for the real traffic usage
it's easy to check down and replace the
underperforming ones because under those
under underperforming those who will
serve it's less traffic so those who are
painless
having multiple providers also helps
with operational issues and failures and
maintenance windows on behalf of your
providers of them being the dust or
anything else there's a mechanism built
into DNS for distributing zones but it's
to say the least
not that feature-rich compared to our
current requirements so you'd better
stick to providers with nice and
convenient API so now I hope that now
with all this in mind whether you are an
enterprise a network operator you'll be
able to build your DNS solution in a bad
way
questions
Oh
[Applause]