hi my name is Dan McGann oh okay forgot
mother they shot the microphone hi my
name is Dan Bogdanovich and I work for
Volta networks and we spent a lot of
time thinking about you know how to do
better in network management and service
orchestration because one of the things
is that I learned it's easy to build a
product but it's hard to manage the
network and integrate the new products
so we are hearing more and more about
Network automation you saw a few
presentations that talked a lot about
the benefits of that and it is what it
is but still according to some you know
information that the market research
organizations are providing is that 70%
still use manual CLI based network
configuration on the other hand if you
will start using the network automation
you can reduce you know some of your
errors by 50 percent and this is a
interesting stat because when I was
working in my previous employer
we had an SDK for the devices and they
loved writing specialized CLI
applications using the DES decay because
they were saying well we are just
exposing of the comments that we need in
order to provision the new things
so the key thing when you are doing is
about you need different data models and
the vendors will provide you a lot of
device models but for you the key things
as I believe are the service models
there is a plenty of data models but
very few service models and there is a
little bit more explanation about the
data model classification in the RFC 81
99 which says and how they are being
classified by the API is that you can
create essentially network device models
and then combine them into different
service model and these models both are
technical models you have your own
business models but
the technical service models are you
know pretty important because they can
simplify the provisioning of your server
you know of the services on on the
network and in this talk today I will be
talking more about the red layer and the
service models and why it makes it
easier to manage your network using the
service models a comparison to the car
is if you want to you know build a car
well you can build the engine from all
the devices or you can use the engine
and put the same engine in many
different car models so you can have you
know like the same 4-cylinder engine
across six different models and three
different brands and for the you know
for the car industry that is essentially
that speeds up their manufacturing
because they are saying oh we will be
putting up models together that will
satisfy our end customer form you know
from the common parts the networks are
they're managed today is mainly managed
you know as a collection of the devices
and what what we believe is that the
network automation it will be much more
easier to migrate from a device
management essentially to the network
service management that you can
essentially have a fixed network and
then overlaid with different services
that can each one can be easily
individually managed you know as well as
monitored the idea is that you will be
able in you know to directly change the
state of your network you know for each
you know indicate service you will not
do configuration management it will be I
have you know this is the configuration
just for this customer or actually just
the provisioning information just for
this customer which was translated into
the state and then you can manage this
state for that service in the idea with
the young data models is that you can
essentially load just those models and
those models will create a schema for
you and you can then drive the api's out
of that you know
out of that schema you can modify it
according to your business requirements
as well as well as you know to your you
know end-user requirements there are
tons of models out there but it's mainly
driven by vendors and some of them you
know are driven by you know the
operators so being you know getting more
input from the operators on the service
model development would be you know
really helpful and the idea is that the
more choices you have it will be easier
for you to achieve you know the final
goal because you using the tools you
know you're just loading a different
schema and with the different schemas
you can have you know different API that
are answering your requirements about
here use an example of an l2 VPN data
model so this is a fairly simplified
data model out of the whole
functionality that you can you know get
but this is sort of the minimum
information with which you can start
creating the l2 VPN services if you
would view it you know and develop and
deploy it on device level you will have
to put you know most of this information
in some of that you know can be system
generated but let's say and this is
usually how you do it today you are
entering the you know you're entering
the information in and you have to
specify if you would you know use a
network automation with topology
discovery when you have the topology
discovery you are getting your in your
neighbor peering informations and in
that case some of the information can be
retrieved from the network state so in
this you know example was just like oh
my neighbor I'm retrieving my neighbor
information in order to build up the
service and this is one of the most
frequent errors is is that verifying was
the IP address or some of the piranha
exactly typed in if you have the
topology you know already discovered and
you have it as the topology state you
can easily verify once you build your
network you know service schema if that
information is correct that you're
passing it in and once you verify it you
know once you verify that information
you can pass it and then with the high
confidence you know have the have the
result of the service creation you know
that you really wanted to achieve and in
short you know that will you know that
will build you have any questions would
be happy to answer
Ignis Bogdanovich winix two questions
one trivial and one heart talking about
your example of VPLS there might be
different flavours of how that is
implemented BGP one LDP one static when
if I am crazy enough evpn and similar
types trying to do one model which tries
to cover all of those options does it
really seem practical what about having
two layers of service models one which
is technology domain service model which
deals with abstraction above network
elements for example of a particular
flavor VPLS a VPN and provides a no
bound interface to what you describe as
later VPN service model so in my slide
here I was talking about the technical
service model and the technical service
model is giving you all those details
you know what you can do everything with
the l2 VPN now I have simplified it and
said that for my actual service that
without what I want to deploy in my case
this is you know the list of my model so
I am doing one model above that exactly
what you're mentioning is that you know
I have the technical part which gives me
the full flavor of it but I'm reducing
it to what I need and then what I'm
essentially then use it you know to
combine it is that instead of doing it
on a device by device model I'm looking
at another service like a topology and
making sure that my desired service
model is matched with my topology model
and then some you know the information
that is provided inside in the you know
in the provisioning information is
correct okay yeah the hard one who
should be developing these models the
technical models the technical service
models ideally would be led by the
operators and with the vendors you know
providing support
you know how to plug in certain device
models into it so I you know there are
some initiatives out there already like
open config but they are mainly focused
on the abstracted device models and the
idea is how we could move that up using
those device models to create services
okay thank you
I know I'm Benoit and I will be speaking
with my ITF up Siri Adam and to answer
agnostic on question it's it's a fact it
must be done by operators the to Express
we discussed the last two days at the
ITF the l2 VPN and VPN were done by
operators we don't want you have the
vendors to just expose all the knobs
there now since those should be done by
operators I would like to understand
from the people here if there is some
value to have a kind of standard way of
having like those service models and
then which ones right because we we've
been having like two very unique one a
two VPN at Rypien but I have people also
telling I would like to have this
service you know security related very
simple a very simple policy and I'm
wondering it makes sense to try to
entice those because by the time we do
the service have been evolving right
that's one issue the second issue is
that I'm hearing some people telling ya
it should be nice you have those service
models somewhere but when I speak to
some operators they are not going to
share their model right so in the end
I'm wondering it's a tough situation
right it's also why we we put this young
catalogue there where people could just
even push their service model they want
to but the operators don't do it so you
know I want to get some feedback from
the room here just a short one so the
whole point with the data models when
you have them and you you can get schema
driven API is that you can write their
different business logic how to you know
create the end service but you don't
have to create you know every single
time the folk
figuration you already can create the
right abstractions that you need to
deploy that service and then with and
then you can assure that service will be
correctly deployed with the increase in
automation because you are verifying
that in verifying that information with
other services that are running in your
network and making sure you know that
you're passing the right information so
there you shouldn't try to come you
should not try to convince me that
having model is guilty right we we know
that okay now what about the feedback
from the room if there is like interest
to get more stylized service model or
not and then which ones just into north
networks
so the among their semantic health
question to this you could build a model
service models that represents what your
network is doing and this is what our
config is doing or you could take a
model and try to represent business
logic as coming from all SS BSS layer
and just to are somewhat difficult to
combine so finding right mix I believe
would define the success of service
models and really need feedback from
operators I mean we know what vendors
are doing we know how to map today's
also VPN configuration to your model 30
minutes work however applying business
logic to service model it's much more
complicated think and we'll need help
here in a TIA
[Applause]