yeah so we're welcome we're gonna go
back kind of to the topic of the first
talk but kind of zoom out a little bit
so if you were really digging into the
yang models and things that are on the
slides earlier you can probably go to
sleep now for those of you had no idea
what was going on this talk is for you
so this concept the API is in UCLA I
think if you're paying attention to new
trends in networking
you've probably heard some variation of
this statement and I kind of wanna
unpack it a little bit and look at what
that means right so we're really
starting simplistically we're really
talking about two different interfaces
right the command-line interface which
is set up specifically for people to
interact with machines and the
application programming interface which
is set up specifically for programs to
talk to programs I think that's
important as we work through this and
really when we're talking about API is
in networking anyway there's kind of
three that I think you need to pay
attention to
so there's net comp there's rest and
there's rest comp so we'll look at those
each here really quickly that confident
network configuration protocol it's
defined in RFC 6241 and as it says in
the RC it provides mechanisms to install
manipulate and delete the configuration
of network devices so this is what we
typically call crud right create read
update and delete so doing configuration
actions against devices it says it's
through a remote procedure call so
basically there's a client-server
interaction where the client is the
script or application or controller
that's going to be sending our PCs
requests to the server which is in this
case a router or a switch or something
like that
it's transport protocol agnostic but SSH
is required to be supported and that's
what's typically used and then all the
data that you're shipping between
devices and the scripts or applications
you're running are encoded in XML so
that's the basics about networks a
couple things that are interesting there
it does have the idea of a configuration
lock and when you combine that with the
two-way communication between
client/server you end up being able to
do atomic changes across the network
what I mean is if configuration change
fails on one device you can essentially
roll back the whole change across all of
the devices that you were trying to
change pretty handy also it defines this
idea of state data which allows for kind
of the other direction of information or
they kind of look at if you're looking
at item ation or Sdn or any of those
things you're really trying to do two
things right trying to put information
into the network by configuration and
you're trying to get information out of
the network through telemetry and the
state data defines those kind of events
and things you can pull out so you can
get telemetry like data from your
device's through the same API which can
be either an addition to or in support
of configuration changes right so again
going back to that atomic change you can
actually verify the changes were made
and have the effect you wanted them to
have so then the next API or and talk
about is our type of referee is rest so
rest stands for represent all state
transfer it is defined in a PhD
dissertation by Roy Thomas fielding
called architectural styles in the
design of network based software
architectures just because it's fun to
read poetry on stage at nanog what is
life it is the flash of a firefly in the
night there's the breath of a buffalo
buffalo in the wintertime is a little
shout out which runs across the grass
and loses itself in the sunset so this
is actually the beginning of the paper
if you read it but I think actually the
second code is actually more interesting
um where he talks about the fact that he
says one day when we have learned the
timeless way again we shall feel the
same about our towns I think this kind
of reads into potentially not just city
design but products application design
maybe we should take a timeless approach
and look at that beam it's kind of a
side version that's in the beginning of
the paper address the paper explains
well basically how rest works which is
essentially just the way the web works
so rest is essentially using HTTP all
the things like get put post delete
instead of interacting with a website
you evidentially interacting with a
router or a switch or firewall or
whatever else so you can get information
in and out
then when you combine the two right so
rest comp is essentially net comp
over HTTP so instead of using SSH you're
not using HTTP so from the RC 80/40
that's an HTTP based protocol that
provides a programmatic interface for
accessing data defined in yang using the
data store concepts defined in the
network configuration protocol in Netcom
so again it's a restful implementation
of net comp a couple of things that are
different from or added to I guess in
ingress comp versus net comp is you can
actually use JSON instead of XML which a
lot of people find easier to read and
fun it also defines an event stream
which again kind of enhances potentially
the telemetry ability so you can
actually subscribe to a stream of event
notifications through the API to get
constant information from the devices so
kind of a push model versus a poll so
potentially right replacing SNMP with an
API that you're using for configuration
as well as telemetry pretty cool so
devices can support Netcom things
support rest comp or they can support
both and a lot to both so it's not an
either/or choice necessarily but
definitely something to look at when
you're getting new devices do they
support these protocols if you want to
work down the programmatic interface to
your network so yang is not an API it is
defined in RFC 7950 it's a data modeling
language so essentially right if we put
these kind of all together yang is the
data model which is the template for
formatting your data then you can use
either net comp or rest comp to encode
that data with XML or JSON to send it to
or receive it from a network device over
SSH or HTTP that's kind of the whole
package of over talking about th IP is
in the configuration so the original
vision was is the API have a new CLI and
I think as we've hopefully seen right
APR 3 2016 2 Matt has been interacting
with the devices through an 8
I think one of the back to the very
first slide I had which is this idea
that API is are really for software
defective software whereas CL eyes are
still there for for people to talk to
machines and so yes APR 2 stay but so is
the CLI so I think in situations where
you're doing intense troubleshooting
those kind of things I think for a long
time anyway maybe not always but there
will still be a seal either but I think
routine day-to-day more and more you're
gonna be using an API and some kind of
software to interact with your devices
rather than directly logging into each
machine especially as we scale so
obviously those of you run really big
network is probably already completely
doing this you have in for many years
maybe even just back to like expect
scripts and those kind of things now
there's actually an API to do this so
the answer is no it's not the new CLI
but yes it kind of is I have a YouTube
channel with a bunch of videos of talks
from nanog from right from a bunch of
other conferences with a bunch of stuff
about automation how to big native the
details of actually how to implement all
of this if you want as well as just you
know digging through the archives
themselves with that we have a couple
minutes if anybody has a question
otherwise we'll get to the closing thank
you
[Applause]