there we go
another ddos research talk here
researcher with Arbor networks if you
don't know Arbor we do DDoS mitigation
products and services and this is the
story of a strange - DDoS attack that we
saw we were unable to explain and how we
did some research to get to the bottom
of it
if you've already jumped to the
conclusion that it has to do with IOT
and SSDP you'd be correct that looks
strange but so before we begin you kind
of have to understand how SSDP works so
if you're on a laptop and you want to
print a document well nobody has a
parallel port on their laptop anymore
nobody wants to type the IP address of a
printer into their settings because it's
2018 you just you just expect printers
to appear so this protocol called SSTP
which stands for the simple service
discovery protocol will help your laptop
discover services that are on your local
network so when you go to print your
laptop will send a request for any
devices on your local network that have
services to announce themselves and the
way it does this is it sends a UDP
packet to a well-known multicast address
on UDP port 1900 and pretty much every
single service discovery packet looks
the exact same it's got this em search
it kind of looks like HTTP even though
it's running over UDP but it's really
not so anyway so your laptop sends this
discovery packet to the network and for
every possible are sorry for every
service that's available on your network
you'll get a response back and the
response will be from sorry the response
will be a unicast packet that is from
the IP address of the printer or
whatever and the source port will be
1900 and it will reply to your ephemeral
port that you sent the search on and the
response is also UDP and it looks like
HTTP even though it's really not so the
important fields here are it shows you a
location which is a an actual tcp-based
URL that if your laptop will go to it
will list all the services available
it'll be able to interact with a via
soap which is not really germane to this
conversation but one of the fields that
I didn't include here but it's kind of
weird is that a lot of these
implementations will respond with a user
agent which is coming from the response
not from the client which is kind of
weird but we'll get into what that is in
a minute
so a long time ago years ago attackers
figured out that they can abuse this
this protocol
so most SSDP implementations will send
one packet that contains a description
of each unique service available so if I
send one M search packet to a printer
and the printer is you know it's a fax
machine it's a scanner it's a printer I
might get any number of response packets
so in other words sending one packet
results in you know anywhere up to a
dozen response packets so attackers
figure this out very quickly if they
send an M search packet to a unicast
address which could be anywhere on the
internet it can illicit you know a dozen
response packets and if they set the
source IP address to a IP address of a
target they would like to launch a
denial service attack on that they could
flood their network essentially with
response packets so that's all very
straightforward mitigating this attack
is also pretty straightforward at
several of your network points you could
just filter out UDP packets that have a
source port of 1900 and the attack will
be mitigated so that's all fine and
dandy but one attack we noticed was very
strange so this attack started off as a
normal SSDP attack and the victim just
filter source port 1900 UDP at their
network boundaries and then something
strange happened the attack shifted and
they were still getting flooded with
SSDP response packets but they were from
ephemeral source ports and destination
ports so if you look on the right there
and Wireshark you can see that those are
pretty much just random ports and that
bypasses any
sort of port filtering you might have in
place because it's essentially two
random source but random port UDP
packets flooding your network and
they're clearly SSTP their sstp
responses and of course to mitigate this
requires a little more lower level
inspection you have to look at the
contents of the packet to see that it's
a UDP packet that has an HTTP response
then you drop those packets but we
weren't really sure why this was
happening it was really strange so as is
very fashionable these days we decided
to figure this out by scanning the
entire Internet so as a proxy for a
random port a random ephemeral source
port we used a static port of 1901
it doesn't have to be 1901 we just used
one static port and the reason we did
that was so that we could record the
responses that come back to that port
and literally all we did was just send
the EM search packet to every address on
the Internet recorded the responses and
tried to figure out what was happening
here so of all of our responses I
divided them into two different buckets
the behaving and the misbehaving so the
behaving group I would get responses
that were destined for a sort that had a
source port of 1900 and the misbehaving
responses were of source ports something
other than 1900 and what was immediately
striking is that there are way more
misbehaving sstp implementations on the
internet than there are behaving so
that's really strange so what's going on
here so in addition I recorded the first
service response from every single
response that I got oh I forgot to
mention two we got like I think it was 5
million responses so basically 0.14
percent of the Internet has all this
sitting SSDP implementation on it which
thought that was interesting
but anyway remember how I said in the
response packets sometimes the user
agent asset which is strange because
it's a HTTP response
and not a request but one thing that
really stood out was that in the
behaving responses there was
overwhelmingly no user agent installed
on the misbehaving it was overwhelmingly
this red Sonic user agent in the packet
so doing some creative googling we found
this open source project called lib you
P and P which is reused by everybody
pretty much 56% of the internet
apparently it actually hard codes this
this red Sonic user agent into it and
we're gonna release a paper that talks a
little more in depth about some of the
other aspects that we found because it's
not just the the red Sonic user agent
that pointed us to lib UPnP but that was
by far most damning piece of evidence so
this open source library is used in all
sorts of CP IOT devices it's used in DVR
as it's used in webcams it's uses in
lots of different stuff so two minutes
left so just to summarize the library
code that exists in these IOT devices
sometimes these devices are really hard
to update so even if we did fix this
which I'm not even sure would be
considered a bug it's just some sort of
strange behavior but even if we did fix
it
this code is gonna live on these devices
for a long time just given a large
install base but the more important
point I think is that the attackers are
aware of this behavior and they will use
they will shift their tactics if one
attack isn't working they will focus
their attack on this more random source
port and of course the block these
attacks requires much deeper packet
inspection so require you to look at UDP
packet all UDP packets to see if they
have an HTTP response that looks
something like SSDP
and if you do that and drop those
packets it will mitigate the attack and
that's pretty much it we have one minute
left if there's any questions
job Snider's NTT communications it's not
per se a question but a follow-up to
your recommendation
NTT just rate limits SSDP traffic to 1%
of the ports capacity and this very
greatly reduces the fallout from those
packets and I would recommend my
partners and competitors and customers
to just do the same
we should not CSS to be traffic on the
global Internet so exactly it should be
on the local network and put it in the
trash a few exactly thank you thank you
all right cool thank you
[Applause]