our job our next speaker is job's
Snyder's he's going to talk about
using Aaron Whois data in BGP prefix
filters hi I'm I'm joke thank you for
having me here I would like to cover
with you a particular project that we've
been doing in the last few months to
make it easier for customers to signal
to us NTT but also to iook sprout server
operators and other stakeholders what
the intentions are of certain IP blocks
in terms of routing traditionally we use
what is called an IRR and an IR is
internet routing registry and it's
basically a database where you can
publish statements about this IP block
should be originated by this ASM and
this is a common source of data publicly
accessible and the nice thing about it
being public is that other people can
verify how it works what what data is
there and consume the data in their own
prefix filters if we zoom in on the
actual contents of IRR we have the route
object which is essentially the Atem of
of this concept and I've highlighted
with the bold letters the two elements
of the route object that matter all the
other attributes are discarded and not
considered by prefix filter generators
there's the prefix itself and the ASM
that is allowed to originate the prefix
if we zoom in under the hood how that
data is transformed into actual BGP
prefix filters what happens is certain
queries are sent to an IRR daemon in
this instance the command is exclamation
mark G it's very intuitive and the demon
will return you a list of prefixes that
can be originated by the ASM for which
he did a reverse lookup so so far so
good
now in October 2017 I worked together
with the Calgary
infinite exchange to migrate them from
unfiltered route servers to filter out
servers the interesting discovery was
said after we convert it from insecure
to secure there were still 7,000 or so
prefixes that were rejected by the
filters and we dug into why are these
prefixes rejected cyst is an IRS issue
is is there perhaps any way that we can
do a validation step to pump up the
number of valid prefixes and this is
where we came across the Aaron Whois
data source I recalled from long ago
that in the Aaron Whois database which
should not be confused with the Aaron
IRR database they are separate you can
document an origin is so with the
Calgary internet exchange data set and
the data from Aaron Whois database we
saw if there was anything that could be
unified or leveraged and it turned out
that from those seven thousand or so
invalid prefixes we could validate an
additional 1700 prefixes using this
Aaron Whois database so to us that meant
a 23% production in invalid routes so
what is this Aaron who is fing if you go
to the Aaron website and you log in with
your my Aaron online or whatever
accounts and you you go down to where
you can manage your inept blocks there's
a field called origin AAS and for each
allocation that you received or is
managed by Aaron you can specify one or
more origin a SMS and the beauty of this
data source is that it's a four tative
because only the owner of an IP block
can actually modify this information and
this places the data source on
a higher level of furtiveness compared
to the IRR where essentially anyone can
do anything and we saw this data
actually reflected in the BGP routing
tables if you if you take the Whois data
dump convert it into something your
routers can use you end up with roughly
90,000 let's call it route objects and
20% of those are a one-to-one match with
what we saw in the BGP tables and for an
a routing data source that's a pretty
high score so the mechanics of using the
Arin Whois database are a little bit
clunky at the moment I'm hoping that in
the coming months this process will be
slightly more elegant but what we do is
and we I mean NL nach we download a 3.5
gigabyte XML file that contains all of
Aaron Whois data and then we massage
that data through a pipeline and only
look at objects where there is an actual
specification of the origin ASM then
that reduced data set is converted into
IRR formats that's shipped off to an IRR
daemon and then the daemon is signaled
hey load this new data base and that
makes it accessible for our tool chain
the reason we did it this way is that
entity would not have to update any of
its tool chain regarding the prefix
filter generation and that's always
attractive so the endgame in this regard
is that customers have a choice they can
either register an IR route object or
they can specify an errand who is what
the origin ASM is and this should make
it slightly easier for us to to motivate
people to indicate what their intentions
are an example could be viewed here if
you issue
this commands on your terminal you'll
get back what looks like an IRR route
object but in a sense is a reflection of
what is originally Aaron who is data
from the XML file the format thing is
not entirely ideal this is what happens
when you produce PDFs on OpenBSD
handsome
so in this route object in the remarks
we describe what the actual source is
there's a link to the Aaron who is
website where you can see the same data
reflected and changed dates reflects
when the original record was created in
the Aaron database I've also loaded this
data set into IRR Explorer dot NL not
net you can see on the screen there is
various data sources there's what we see
in BGP there is apparently for the
Aaron dot net IP address also a route
object in the level free IRR database
they might want to check that out
there's a route object in the Aaron
database and that's the second last
column we see that there also is
representation in the Aaron Whois
database so this is an attempt to make
it slightly easier to debug this type of
data there are currently two methods to
obtain the data you can either use what
I generate but I will not claim that
that is actually an authoritative data
dump because you just have to trust me
on my blue eyes that I correctly did
this so the recommended way to obtain
this type of data is to sign the Aaron
bulk who is agreements which is a fairly
standard agreement that says don't use
this for marketing don't use it in your
commercial products you sign the
agreements you get an API key and then
you can access the XML file and then you
can throw the XML file for your own
pipeline and plug it into your
provisioning system
so I will stress again just go directly
to the source but if you just want a toy
around and look at what might be
available it might be of use to you then
of course the JSON dump that I provides
can be inspected that's the end of my
slide deck I see two people running to
the microphone okay if the beard can go
first well okay well okay the one with
longer beard too short too short remarks
kind of this morning I heard that the
semantics of that field are not defined
that is something that actually should
be fixed the other thing is of course
also Aaron should provide what you are
doing in transformation and kind of if
there are any problems in understanding
how to do this right I am offering my
services of of consultation for free
thank you so I I asked Aaron for this
type of data dump and it's on the
roadmap but the timeline you know I'm
very patient so I was like come on I'll
just do it myself and we can get a proof
of concept running and go with this but
I understand that it's on Aaron's
roadmap to make this data available
directly without the need for this
approach buku coal miner net tipic back
on slide three you'd said there are only
two elements that are uniquely
identified that you that are used by
filter generators I know of at least one
other providers filter gen that cares
about source and you can specify the
order of the source and and what I see
here is you're creating a synthetic
database that is just another source so
that's awesome thank you
you raise some interesting points I I
may have oversimplified a little bit
here but sources are relevant in some
contexts okay thank you for your time
thank you Joe
[Applause]