uh welcome to my besides the dublin 2022
talk uh charge my car for free forever
uh first of all don't do it it's a crime
let's get that out of the way
uh a short intro for me
i'm vaguely stickers i'm greek i work as
a senior penetration api tester at
pandas partners
i have a couple of startups that i'm
advising
to secure themselves and to build
better and more secure apis
my research interests are mainly api for
iot and web application security for the
past
year
close to a year i have been developing a
machine learning tool to spot
api flows and low hanging api issues low
hanging fruits on api issues
you can hear my dodgy accent you might
have heard my dodgy accent on the telly
on a couple of programs
usually i'm not a bad guy
and please follow me on twitter at
evistika's twitter handle
so our talk today is going to be about
electric vehicles there are two distinct
categories of electric vehicles one is
teslas and the other is everything else
if you ever met a tesla owner he would
never stop talking about his ev and how
he's saving the world but that's a talk
for another time
the car industry is trying to switch to
electric vehicles and chargers
the uk government and the eu in general
is planning to ban selling petrol and
diesel cars by 2030
and
currently
there are
more or less three and a half million
electric vehicles in the world and
that's a slightly out of date 28 percent
serve in january 2022 of the car sold
where ev vehicles
and we are moving to the actual uh
theme uh subject of the talk which is
evie charger it's a booming market
it's there's a lot of competition there
are smart devices with rush to market
the common issues anyone who has worked
in a startup knows that there are to
market is
implementation
really badly they are implementing stuff
really badly uh it it will keep growing
to the millions of devices because the
plan says that it's going to be one or
two chargers per household right now
from a market analysis there are 18
startups in the field in addition to the
big players like pretty much every huge
company like abb the vw and anyone else
is developing their own
charger and
notice the smart there's the high
opponent's law that says whenever an
appliance is described as smart it's
vulnerable and we're going to see that
it is most of the chargers that we
looked at were one way or another
vulnerable
the ev charger categories are the home
chargers that are installed in our home
they are connected to the land networks
and are usually slower less power
usually 7 to 20 kilowatts
for for power
and the public chargers who are
installed on the public roadside they're
really fast and really high power some
go up to
400 kilowatts per hour
they're interconnected with an protocol
named ocpi we're going to see later what
that means
and the accounts for them can work
globally on all the chargers through
ocpi
random code
the ev fleet in 2020 consumed over 80
terabytes per hour of electricity that's
one percent of current electricity total
and the projection for 2030 is it's
going to be 10 fold 860 terabytes per
hour which is going to be 10
of the current electricity total we're
going to see how this is going to be
used on the
end of this presentation
the cloud-based attacks
is what we're going to look in here now
we are not going to have that black
magic which is called hardware hacking
if you are expecting hardware hacking
from me
i'm going to disappoint you
there's a saying
on api security learn that authorization
is not equal with authentication or api
resources after you so
most of the things that we're going to
see in here they
test that you were authenticated but
never test that you were able or you
should allow you should be allowed to
access that device
generic api testing
all attack has attacks in the stock as i
said are
based are
remotely we didn't have i didn't have to
have any physical access to there
from most of the research i was based in
greece the charters were based somewhere
in back hampshire i had someone pressed
power on and that's all that i needed
they were either mobile or web based
most of them are really really low
hanging fruit you're gonna see on the
following slides and you're gonna
be surprised on how badly they were
implemented the apis
all of them are logic flows
you should not test for injection on any
platform because that's breaking the cma
that's a crime
and the most unfortunate part is that
if something is platform based you're
not getting a cv unfortunately you can
control million of devices but no cv is
going to be assigned to you
what we're going to see we're going to
see api's missive authentication api is
checking for authentication and other
authorization
we're going to see an api that let me uh
upgrade myself to a super admin
and an api that linked everything
because i knew a static key which was
just the compiled application
the fancier stuff is that we're going to
see a charger who was using a
third-party api that was not only
connecting controlling chargers but also
bathtubs
and a lot of other devices into tenths
of millions
api research 101 i have to
warn you first
if i was on piktok i would play the red
alert
the
red crime
sound
most of those issues you have to be
extra careful you should never ever
interact with a device that you don't
own if by mistake you end up being an
admin and yeah you can be an admin by
mistake you have to
notify the vendor immediately
on the following slides you're going to
see some
text which is read this means the cma in
the uk was broken and we had to alert
the
vendor immediately
and
all you know don't do crime please i'm
not encouraging anyone to do crime in
here
let's also
set the goals of what we would say was a
successful research the bare minimum was
control a device
started stop it
and make it things that you shouldn't do
the pii leak is also a bare minimum so
we would want to see who owns a charger
and where the charger is
the medium level goal is to flash a
firmware i'm not going to
to build the firmware there are people
who help me build the firmware so we you
could either break the device or pivot
to the network and the home run is
getting platform admin on everything
unfortunately this was done more than
once
the first category as we said is the
home-based chargers
i was planning to do
a new charger because that presentation
was also done in
in besides london but unfortunately i
disclosed in early january 2022
they responded in 50 days they asked for
more time and as this is a platform
admin if i was disclosing it right now i
would be
bringing a zero day and giving platform
i mean that would be really bad
i have two and a half thousand
installations they're us-based and
probably going to be disclosed i hope in
april but i cannot really know when it's
going to be disclosed
then the other thing is the russia
incident first of all i have an alibi i
didn't do it
it was not a hack i don't know if you
see there are evie charging stations
that were
showing in their screens that putting
putin is
something i'm not going to say the word
it was not a hack it was an ukrainian
company that
tricked that did the back end they had
full ownage of
of the back end so they disabled all the
charges in m11 from saint petersburg to
moscow and dvd vehicles couldn't charge
so they made that travel
impossible now on the actual hacks
first one is the project tv slash either
last sentence and grow watts last
a lot of other names
i had the 2000 installation last year in
the uk
the growbot cloud had a lot of
devices in their cloud not only chargers
photovoltaic
also bathtubs
iot
and cs iot which all of them could be
bound
it was also
approved by the department of transport
and the growth and senzan
are china-based companies and as anyone
who has done research for iot for
chinese iot they were quite slow in
responding
[Music]
they
as you can see in here they were fully
lacking authentication on any call they
just checked on the first call that you
knew the username and password and then
they didn't even check for decision so
you could just say
that you are that charger and you could
control that charger full stop if they
were consecutive
numbers so you could
do anything for all the chargers you
could
you could have full functionality
intended functionality you could lock
and unlock the device
you could firmware update it there was
no signature check so you could have
access to the internal network you could
backdoor it pivot into the internal
network obviously you could take all the
personal identifier
information
you could broke the device and you could
take platform admin which it's in red so
it's a bridge of the cma
now the disclosure went as you would
expect as a train wreck they didn't
respond for weeks they only responded
when i had the bbc
i had the bbc itself
sent
the query they eventually fixed it after
a failed first attempt which they didn't
fix anything they just said that they
fixed and we tested they their fix is a
really strange fix they have a stateless
login which means
they check the login and then they don't
check decision or anything so they
somehow keep decision in your ip on the
server i didn't truly test it because i
didn't want to find anything else
i would grade them
really really bad
the second charger is evbox it's one of
the
biggest companies they have close to 200
000 charging points throughout the world
they're based in amsterdam
they are department of transport
approved and they were acquired by nce
from an undisclosed number of money
their api was surprisingly good but
they had no obvious reasons but
i'm going to challenge you can you see
the issue in here because my machine
learning actually found it
when you are putting something you are
also putting the roles and then it says
account admin and account owner so if
you change the account document to admin
antenna admin you can see on the right
side
that you had the full platform admin for
yourself
so
you had total compromisation of
everything that's with red you could
also control the server you could
control
everything so you were actually the
tenant admin there obviously pii lik
uh you had all the admin functionality
in the world so you could delete you
could stop you could
create new charges you could do
everything the platform admin is of cma
so they responded in two hours which is
a really refreshing they fixed
everything in 24 hours they double
checked the in 48 hours that everything
was fixed
this was an excellent response
i can say that the api's api falls
happen i would give them the gold medal
because they were really good in
everything and
they missed something yeah
we took platform admin but
things happen as we saw in the keynote
it's how you handle them that makes you
a good company or a bad
cyber security wise company
third one is wallbox they have around
100 000 users they are based in
barcelona
they are raising for 300 million usd and
after they are merged
with
an acquisition corp that i don't know
and
they had a second level either as you
might seen here
you could add when you were adding a
user to your charger you were passing
the id
the first and the second is not ids that
i should own so i could
make
me an admin on every charger
there were four different instances of
this in the api
we could have a total control over all
charges we could lock and unlock there
was no way to firmware update
with our own
firmware there was a pii leakage and
we didn't take any platform admin so we
did the minimum of every one of all the
others
they responded the next day they fixed
it in a couple of days unfortunately
when we were engaged because we were
doing a new
check we found something else
quite similar so they didn't fix the
root cause they fixed just the instance
that was found
they wanted to engage so that we could
provide them with services
but they wanted me to
to sign an mba i'm not doing that so all
in all not great
not terrible they tried but
okay
fourth one is the eo charger or eohab
it was the first charger that was
installed in the uk they are based in
london their department of plasma of
transport approved as you can see the
department of transport randomly
approved pretty much anyone it had a lot
of teething problems they have 15 000
users on my estimation
now it was just a raspberry pi you could
just take the sd card and take
everything there's no bootloader
security
i had the recovery we could recover the
full source code which is two python
scripts hard-coded credentials
everywhere full documentation so that
you didn't even have to understand what
it's doing they had everything in there
and
you could do anything you could decrypt
everything you could make a botnet
uh total control over the devices you
could mimic the server the communication
i think they have ticked all the boxes
so they responded in timely fashion they
worked hard into reworking everything
they changed from python to go i think
or
i don't remember the word but their new
and improved eomini is again a raspberry
pi by with just an sd card so they
thrive i i can tell that they tried but
at least
they failed again
uh
for raspberry p
in iot
it's a valid prototyping device not a
good idea to put it on
production
you can easily extract everything
it's easily rootable and there is no
secure bootloader you can see the three
boxes that were
raspberry
based you have in your mini wall box and
hypervolt all of them could be rooted
and
some findings were as you saw in there
the public chargers we only have one i
only have one in there
it's charge point it's one of the three
biggest
charger
networks in the world they have around
points which means
close to half a million chargers
um they went public in 2021 they're a
huge company
and as you can see they had the publicly
exposed unauthenticated graphql endpoint
that could get everything from every
charger and control it
potentially leaking
their full schema no authentication so
you could get a lot of things now
again
don't do crime
if i pulled the schema which
as you can see in the next slide they
said that they would be okay i would
have gotten about 20 gigabytes of data
with everything and i would have done
one of the
a really big crime never ever interact
with the device you don't own
if you mistakenly do it
notify the vendor immediately and try
not to commit crimes so
chargepoint they responded in an hour
they fixed it on the same day they had
an excellent response they acknowledged
that there was an issue in there and
they said that yeah even if you pulled
it you would be happy not to answer not
to
go after you but this is not something
that you should assume that is going to
happen for all every company so i also
get the gold medal
now the potential issues on the public
charger is on the ocpi
the open charge point protocol is an
application protocol for communicating
it's like
roaming they are also naming roaming so
you create
an account in
chargepoint and you can also do it on
chargeboard or another company that are
all cpi connected this is in the uk and
the us
the connection between providers and
manufacturer
means that
if you find a vulnerability in
one
[Music]
vendor you you have found a
vulnerability everywhere
you could obviously
pii lick everything
and much like the mobile network it's
called roaming
the issue of throw cpi is you could
steal energy and have someone else pay
for it because
obviously you could lick the pii you
could deny service to legitimate users
because you could close the charger
while they're charging but it gets way
way worse
now the
even worse potential issues are based on
a really good job that i'm trying to
pronounce his name william westerhoff
did at his master thesis there is an
attack based on photovoltaic
vulnerabilities that can potentially
destabilize the power grid by
manipulating photovoltaic installations
we are going to take a slightly
different approach in here
so instead of doing
the
the power grids are interconnected in
europe i don't know how familiar with
you are with that but when greece has a
huge energy
demand the import power from bulgaria
when bulgaria has uh demands the import
from greece so they're interconnected
and if you could
for a reason
we're going to see later
demand a lot of power you could bring
down a lot of
places potentially a full country
so on the whole scenario you should go
there to the link and read it it has a
lot of math that i cannot really
understand i'm not a math guy instead of
limiting the pv power but yeah let's
keep that with a star because on another
talk we're going to talk about the pv
power and
a lot of photovoltaic issues that are
going to be announced later
instead of doing that let's maximize the
need for power keep the mind of 80
terawatts per hour and 800 terabytes per
hour think that 80
80 100 watts per hour is how much
belgium is consuming right now so
if you turned on off and done again you
would have a huge spike
on the demand of power
like
as i said the the belgium
having a new belgium
evolve from anywhere else and bring down
the whole
power grid
this is
the home chargers are usually used
during the night and
for this to work you you have to have a
car uh on the charger so you cannot tell
the charger now you need the
power you have to have something
connected with so that it will request
the power
i think that's all
any questions
so
thanks very much for a great talk
on the api
um
the how
how is it possible for you to find the
public api
endpoints um
uh of uh
offenders
you mean the charge point the the the
the actual the actual api
that they connected to
you you're talking about the charge
point issue or for the home charges
because all the home chargers we i used
the
mobile applications for the charge point
the mobile application was sending some
log to that graphql and then when i went
and browsed the graphql i showed that
every charge has a mobile app associated
and you have to download the i've used
the app and that's yes okay and that's
how you export everything
thank you
thanks very much for the talk i wanted
to ask what's the best way for
individuals at home with their own
charging stations to protect themselves
cost-effective
uh
well
first of all you should isolate any iot
that you have and not connected to your
public to your actual network you should
segment your network so that it cannot
pivot
as you saw
make having updating your firmware
wouldn't touch this kind of
vulnerabilities
try to use
devices that are from companies that
seem to know how security works
so no no name chinese iot
and i don't know if prey works for you
pray that nobody sees you but
it's it's one of those things that will
happen eventually unfortunately i think
any other questions
thank you
[Applause]
you