okay we're live hi everybody
i am
this guy stuart mcmurray i am a lead
engineer
on klarna the payment company's
ever-growing security offensive security
team
contesting red teaming that kind of
things
also just a gold fashion
neckbeard unix nerd um these slides
should be tweeted now onto twitter so
feel free to grab twitter if you want
copy the slides
also welcome worth mentioning that i'm
not affiliated with any company
organization or cartel or
anything of the sort which does
defensive type things that we'll be
talking about so this is my own my own
opinions um and even more so it's not
the opinions necessarily of my employer
past present future
and so on um also
typical disclaimer please like don't
hack things if you're not allowed to
um if you do my name is george
washington keep that in mind when
somebody asks
so back to the talk um quick deal they
are of the talk uh
we have this problem that we don't
really know if defensive tools work
until the tools are tested
um
point number two is you have to figure
out how like who knows um vendors are
probably not the best to ask and in fact
in my opinion they're like the worst
people to ask is i don't know they're
selling something um and and the whole
thesis behind the talk is the best
people to ask for the blue teamers to to
figure out if their tools are working um
and point three it's you know doing the
testing itself is actually quite fun and
it's pretty easy and it's an enjoyable
thing to do and that's sort of what
we'll be talking about
so over the next 40 odd minutes um we'll
go we'll talk about sort of the idea
behind this talk uh and then
it's a little weird to say yeah blue
teamers should doing security testing
it's kind of like the opposite to what
they normally do
then we'll look at sort of my red ish
approach to a blue
problem
and how to test things and we'll take a
quick case study
that i was originally going to like use
a tool i've
gone against so to speak uh we won't do
that because that wouldn't be very nice
so the idea behind the talk is we have
this problem um every every large
organization with the network needs some
sort of security tooling in place we
need the ability to find bad guys stock
bad guys make reactions so on and so
forth
we have to figure out though if they
actually work and it turns out a lot of
blue teams that i've talked to don't
really know they're like yeah we know
what it should do we know it has done we
don't know if in the future it will keep
doing um also these tools are
ridiculously expensive so like
um back before i moved over this way of
course the us had a car and it would not
occur to me to make like a massive
purchase that's like multiple times my
income
uh without test driving and i i feel the
same way about security tools like you
know multi-million dollars or euros of
tooling um you probably should test it
before you buy it there is a counter
argument to that
and that is that it's somebody else's
budget really like you know it shouldn't
be on the budget of the organization
buying the thing to figure out if the
thing works like do dev work basically
for the vendor
so here's the solution
let's just see if this thing that we may
be hoping to buy or may have bought
already is actually worth the money
we'll just dig in and find out if it
works
um
in the interest of a 40-minute talk
scope it down though um so when i talk
about a thing a defensive tool i really
am talking about like a single defensive
thing i'm talking about an edr
box appliance agent what have you a
network traffic analysis thing a
firewall thing maybe even like a dns
server that's configured to be
particularly hacker unfriendly
um the same principles apply to what you
know in the modern world you get oh it's
a cyber analytics a defense platform is
using ai and ml and threat intelligence
and all that stuff it's same thing
applies
um tweaked a little of course and and
every so often you'll find yourself or
find a situation where it's not just
like hey i'm testing a thing it's like
hey we've hired this this other team to
you know defend a part of the network
sort of an mssp type thing
it works more or less the same um
with some
minor adjustments and and we're going to
again scope it down to one question to
answer and the question is does it work
which in real life something turns
sometimes turns into like okay does it
just work enough um which actually
realize in real life often turns into
like okay does this thing do anything
um and then sort of as a side quest we
like to also answer and just how hard is
it to get past it i mean like you know
most most of these tools are not uh
particularly impossible to bypass so
that's that and that's that's just a fun
bit anyways so it's like
kind of your reward for doing all the
work um and then the question is when
you would do this and hopefully you're
doing this pre-purchase hopefully you
know somebody is like hey we need a new
edr product for whatever reason
um let's let's
get a bunch of trials and test them and
see what happens i've done that it's
it's enjoyable for sure and it's it's
really helpful to see like hey the
vendor you know we're being exactly
forthcoming for this one and this one
works better um probably more often it's
post purchase it's like hey we have this
tool maybe you hired a red team or maybe
you set up a new red team or whatever
and you can see like oh
you know just doesn't actually do what
it says um and and i say red team it's
actually probably better for the blue
teams
um the other time i've seen it is post
compromise like bad thing happened bad
thing was done to the company really it
doesn't just happen and the company's
like all right we missed that one
what else are we going to miss or what
else can we catch at least to know where
to fix things a bit better
which gets us then to the who's going to
do it um
the thesis behind this whole talk is
that i think the blue teamers are the
best not just like because i have other
things i want to do but blue teamers in
general are the best suited to do this
testing
um start from the other end like who is
not good
managers stock managers sizzos that kind
some of them are awesome um i have to
work for one some of them
you know they have different priorities
they're more concerned with kpis closing
tickets what not uh sometimes they're a
little less technical than would be
expedient to know exactly how their
tools they're meant to have work
um
the other obvious answer is usually the
red team the fantaster so on and so
forth uh quick pull of the audience
who's on the blue side of things
so about
a third maybe how many blue tumors
cringed when i was like hey yeah we'll
just get the red teamers to test the
tools
one one is honest in the crowd all right
so um
we have one person who's honest anyways
but yeah um that having been said ask us
for planning ask us for like you know
hey how else could you get through this
how else could you would you attack this
what you know what other tricks you have
up your sleeve um besides we also don't
really always know the entire defensive
scope of the company or the organization
as it turns as it may be
um
and then then the other you know and
actually probably the most often asked
if the thing works is whoever's selling
it
you're like oh can you map this to
whatever framework or matrix or whatnot
and they'll have a nice list for you of
test cases they've done and um there's
the benefit that it's free hopefully uh
it should be anyways there's the
downside that um
you know i have cat pictures and that's
a cool cat picture
so that that's who you wouldn't ask um
who you would ask or the blue team
uh ask them because they they know
all that or hopefully know anyways all
the defenses that are there they know
probably the gaps i
i used to work with a fellow who went
from blue to red and um actually it's
running the red team i think the
organization i was at now and um we hit
this amazing thing you would just rock
into a company we were working with and
you just go to their sock and be like
hey it was a sock analyst how do i hack
you
and they'd be like oh dude all you gotta
do is like use this creds there and jump
to the system so yeah the blue team
knows um and they'll know
they've used these tools every day so
they're you know pretty pretty set even
just from that point of view um
more importantly blue knows the
environment that you're operating in
they know that hey that you know we
block whatever out we've got high cmp
outbound say so no we don't need to
worry about that even though the vendors
may be iffy on that um they know some
things are definitely possible like man
we know that who is gets out happened
once we know who is gets out all you
have to do is ssh over who is and it
works
um and they know you know where they may
have a little less visibility which is
what's kind of testing is good um and
they also know like hey we don't just
need like one trick to win
on the red side and certainly i would
never do this um but some red teamers
anyways are like hey i used https and it
won hey i used https and i got out of
your network again hey by the way hd
yeah so it's you know you get a broader
scope of things um
and so from that no it's missing
uh the red side does know that too
a few more side benefits you get from
this um when i've done this in the past
working red blue you know the whole
chain of people uh communication gets a
little weird
so you know you find yourself like i
think oh i need to test this you know
one set of activities one set of
behaviors and the blue team you know
analyst or whatnot i'm working with
stock analyst is like not quite and then
he goes talk to his it's like whoa
wrong operating system something along
those lines
um
also get a sort of more honest look at
what needs improvement especially if
you're hiring a external team to do this
uh they like repeat business and if if
your report that you hand a client is
like yo everything's broken
it's it's really hard to say and please
hire us again it happens but not that i
would ever do this again
um cheaper of course and i've also found
when i've worked sort of on the purplish
not like in the modern sense of purple
team you're just like hey you see this
kind of thing hey you know come come
look at this cool thing i'm doing um i
find that oftentimes especially like
junior soccer analysts and it guys
really love like the learning like oh
how you do this one trick and such i'm
usually smaller scoped
so that is sort of a thesis the why
behind it um
here is sort of an approach my own
approach to testing these sorts of
things
for a bit of context
mostly when i'm thinking you know tool
bypass i'm i'm really thinking about two
things i have to get past and thinking
about
um automated tools so like something
making an alert and i'm thinking about
whoever's doing the triage tier one sock
something along those lines um sort of a
counter example i know young lad who he
had a file on his desktop i think
lol.pie
and because he just thought it was funny
and uh sock was like oh my god what are
you doing you know deconfliction
happened and he's like i don't know what
he was doing but he's like not playing
league of legends because the soccer
stock because you know the one the sock
was like oh my gosh file names are
credible we'll believe this so you know
flip that on his head like hey if i just
rename a file and it works
then it works so you know that's kind of
like thought number one is okay just it
just has to work enough um somebody
asked me yesterday like how do you pack
linux binaries and i'm like
why and the answer is because nothing
looks so
uh upx i guess but
yeah so that's the kind of thing um and
then so that
you know dependency to figure that out
is okay what what can i get away with to
get to that point uh so i need to know
what's not blocked uh because if
something's blocked
but not caught because i also need to
know it's not cod something's blocked
and not caught it's like well let's try
again okay you know respond go again
likewise if something's caught but not
blocked
well it still works i mean i'll get a
socket manager mad at me probably but um
that's kind of par for the course with
red teaming so that's kind of the two
things when we're formulating these
tests we're talking about to think what
what can we do to avoid getting blocked
what can you do to avoid getting caught
um and then it's always good to keep in
the back of your mind what else can you
get away with uh
you know it's it's sort of the red team
mentality um
context from the red side but like hey
not not just like yeah i won yeah i got
ceos you know dropped a report on the
ceo's desktop or something but like what
else can i do
um
this all turns into like fooling the
system at five ish places um sometimes
on the sensing side so uh network
traffic analysis you know it's sniffing
taking pcap and whatnot it can't be
doing that for everything so i'll just
like turn things off um
i know of
three different tools that don't look at
icp so okay i can fool the sensing
because it's not sensing icp processing
so um if something is taking a stream of
events data whatever has to like turn
that from some raw sensor output to
something useful
um
so if i can break it there i that that's
another win another way to break a tool
which is then informs these test cases
we're gonna be talking about later
um good example of that we had something
a tool i was going against it was
parsing http
sure um so i put at the beginning of my
ssh stream like an http request header
just like the one line get something
something and then just ssh after that
and then likewise from the server i just
put like an http 200 okay and then like
ssh after that and and that poor tool
then it was not expecting gigs and gigs
of http requests and response
simultaneously
that broke um
likewise decisioning is the next sort of
step in this
i hate to call it a chain it's overused
but chain uh if you can break the
decision if you can say you know hey you
you sensed this thing on the wire you
looked at it but you decided it's
probably not that bad then that's a win
too
um i don't have a canned example off the
top of my head but you know that is like
fooling it where it's like yeah it looks
okay
um
alerting as well so every so often i'll
do something
that you know what else can i get away
with i'll do like something like that
and i'll usually say to the stock guys
hey dudes do you uh do you see that
and
there is a tool without naming names of
course that you know they'll say yeah it
made an alert i was like cool
would you have seen that and you know
most of the time yes but every once in a
blue moon it's like well the tool was
like nah it's not that not that awesome
it's not that important so if you can
break it there and then of course the
response is the other one um
you know if you know even if you're like
oh my gosh the sky is falling but you
don't actually kill the whatever needs
to be killed
well i still win
cool so back to this this uh rambly
philosophy step one what what are we
actually meant to do what is this tool
really meant to do um and sometimes it's
not obvious if you if you get one of
these uh enterprise grade cloud native
ai ml low calorie intel driven makes
your t in the morning thing does not
tell you what it's actually supposed to
do it tells you that like some some
ceo's gonna buy it
but um so you have to sort of sometimes
really dig and figure out okay what does
this thing actually do and sometimes
it's just as simple as like regex
um sometimes it's as simple as like
matching domain names
uh sometimes it's complicated neural
nets are involved and whatever else and
then also how it does it so if you can
figure out what source of data it gets
in
um that much you know the closer you get
to like truth for lack of a better word
the closer you get to uh figuring out
how things work oh boy my timer just
locked itself
there we go
uh so like the network tool i was
talking about it it used a packet socket
or something snapped snarfs traffic and
pcapped it and did some math over that
um the linux edr thing that actually did
catch me once and it just it parsed on
it d output i was like oh so i just have
to stay out of audit d no problem
um things like that
and so where do we find this well
poker on the ui um which is something
that blue teamers are way better at
doing than red teamers um
speaking only for myself i poke around
like edr ai uis and i'm like
i could do doing other things
uh false positives as well so if if the
tool whatever it is says hey this is a
bad thing like the ll.pi like oh my god
he's running a forbidden game okay we
know it's looking for games let's see if
let's let's validate that let's try
another game let's try something
pretending to be a game so on and so
forth
um in a similar situation i found out it
was like mac app like dot app directory
things that was just a name matchy thing
um spotify was not allowed by technical
policy but allowed by like hr policy um
and it turned out splattified that app
worked really good uh and i had music
and the sock was
not happy
uh documentation also um documentation
can be misleading by the way but you
know just like if it says hey turn this
thing on to catch this thing but there
is it can't be misleading there is a
tool out there i i um my name is not on
it and hopefully it never will be but
there is a like bug report in that the
documentation says it blocks x and
allows y
and it actually allows x and blocks y so
yeah keep it take it for what it's worth
um previous incidents as well if you had
a thing that happened and it did not get
caught you're like maybe that should get
caught or you had a thing that happened
and i mean it's an incidence you somehow
you had happened um that's a good way of
saying hey this you get caught um
so a call i had once and by call like i
was doing something it sounds like what
are you doing and i was like hey yos
made up yes credits don't you and i was
like no they're like yeah you do it's
you're coming from the wrong network for
those creds okay so i know that whatever
tool that was i don't know what tool it
is because don't tell me but whatever
tool that was i know like it catches aws
creds from a weird place that's good
it's good um less good sources that
still may give you good information
about what our tool does uh the sales
pitch itself um if especially if you get
like a sales engineer that will give you
good information
um
and also false negatives if if you have
a team that does a thing and you're like
they're like hey you catch this and
they're like no
uh yeah take that um and then let's take
these you know what's this tool meant to
do and compile it into sort of a list of
use cases um this can be all the way
from really specific things like i would
like to match dns names that are longer
than 18 characters and catch dns
tunneling just to like i want x-fil
blocked
and then we should also ask what should
this tool do what we like this tool do
especially if we're looking for a
replacement for a tool
um if it's something like hey we have
this thing it's not working all that
good let's find another thing
you know kind of a wish list um
it does happen and i've i've seen this
before vendors are just like oh yeah
that would be a good thing to block um
so like i mentioned the 18 character dns
thing it was a friend of mine was going
against a dns something and
the client specifically said hey could
you could you do dns tunneling we want
to see how this looks in our tools and i
just happened to have some code to hand
him and i handed it to him and that the
blue guys came back and were like you
didn't do dns tunneling and he's like
well i did and they're like well your
domain names were too short so okay
lesson learned for them maybe we
we shortened the like length of domain
names just because the vendor was like
oh yeah i guess i guess you can't like
tunnel out with three character sub
domains
um regulatory requirements as well
especially if you work in like pci dss
fintechy type things um
finding credit card numbers is always
like you know if something can identify
credit card numbers and three cpv
numbers and whatnot that's that's an
excellent ask it's next to impossible
but it's a good thing to think about um
et cetera uh trade magazines i find come
from above usually um
did this thing and i was like hey i
found a power strip several jobs ago i
found a power strip on you know let you
know loose
uh i could log in and like shut down a
server rack and they're like cool story
bro
and then like six months later uh some
trademark or some sizzle magazine or
whatever had like oh my god you can get
hacked by iot
um
just happen to have a report
ready for that it's had a funny date on
it but you know all right so we kind of
have our like wish list high level wish
list of use cases um in the terminology
use case test case it's everybody's
going to use different terms that's cool
um so let's then come up with kind of a
list of test cases more technical like
things we can put on the wire it's it's
a good idea to keep these small
like a pass fail or a like a severity of
alert or something
um
it's also a good idea to keep it part of
like notionally part of some larger
scenario part of something that's uh
either like a cool hack that happened um
so when electronic arts lost
something like source code and it came
out it was a slack cookie that was owned
uh team came to me and was like hey
could you show us talk to us about slack
cookies neat little demo and some
learnings happened and some fixes
happened it was good um but like the the
the test if you wanted to call it that
was just like can i put this slack
cookie in a browser oh yeah of course um
i could anyways
so
you know make it make it part of a
larger scenario that gives you a bit of
impact uh gives you a bit of credibility
and makes it easier for the people who
are reading these like results to kind
of figure out oh yeah this is this is
actually useful
um you can also take it just like from
knowledge of how things could happen
like i said the guy i knew was just like
hey sock how do we own you and they're
like yeah sure so that sort of like
chain of events and they knew like okay
we should probably worry about this then
there's like little bit like oh yeah
this one little thing it does actually
work and
you know helpful tests um and then
sometimes you know bad things are done
uh and you know you can take your tests
and go on that there was an organization
um i heard of and it was had some crypto
minor stuff and some
you know comms out and uh the question
was like hey can we test like just the
comms that were similar to what happened
and i could see that actually um until
we did and we just i mean it was http
requests in a loop there's nothing big
but it was a useful thing um and a thing
and a question like hey just do our
tools that are supposed to catch c2
actually catch this um those years ago i
have no idea if they did or not also
when you're putting together these test
cases keep as few confounding factors
around as possible um
a because it's good science uh but b
more importantly it's it's like 100
chance somebody's going to say something
to the tune of well yeah it worked when
you did it but you know you you had a an
easier answer you know it worked when
you did it but like a real bad guy so
the less of that the better
um
also when you have a stopwatch make sure
it stays on
cool so then then as you're coming up
with these test cases it's good to
figure out like where to start it's
really tempting to be like i'm just
going to do a whole hack from beginning
to end um sales dudes love that if you
ever gonna sell a product like having a
scenario and scenario like
uh is is a very valued thing
that's not what we're doing here we're
just testing like does this thing work
so a better idea is just start start
right before the thing that your testing
is supposed to come into play
uh so if you're gonna say hey does this
thing catch some execution okay just ssh
in star dp in just something drop it to
the desktop double click see if it works
um
it does work if you're going to look at
something that blocks c2 you start with
code execution ssh and drop your thing
don't worry about whether that gets
caught just see like hey does you know
my http out to
something weird get caught
um it is it is highly likely that at
some point
when you're doing this you're like yeah
we assumed access to whatever someone
will come back and say yeah but if
somebody has access to whatever we have
bigger problems um
you've done two things there yes that's
what the tools for and then you've also
identified sort of a bigger problem in
the organization as like the security
mindset
um so anyways once you have this list of
test cases like single testable things
make a list you know so you have a list
of use cases test cases
and then last things try and get caught
like do it um
which is uh very situationally dependent
it's very like
way outside the scope of the talk how to
like test all the things
but essentially it's hacking light it's
all like the fun bits of hacking without
like the setting up infrastructure and
really boring stuff you'll need some
sort of hacker tools
hacker tools i the vast majority of the
hacker tools i use involve ssh and like
cat and grip
um but you'll need something to test it
especially if you're on the network side
of things a great place to find this is
search results favorite search engine
um
some search engines are less great about
getting things on the first page but the
second page is some forget the fella's
name i'll never remember but he says you
know the one thing i'm worried about
blue team one thing i'm worried about is
like a monkey armed with github i think
is what he said so yes google proof see
if the uh
not supposed to name things apologies
yeah see if it's google proof um
for and postpoit host endpoint based
things um the gtfo bins and the lol bins
projects are great sources they'll just
give you a list of like commands you can
run to do bad things
um
by the way if you're interviewing
somebody and you're like ah find the one
command that does weird things and you
let like open internet ability totally
go to the website
um
more more you know to that point also
roll your own like if there's nothing
out there that tests the exact use case
you want that's cool um it's it's always
surprising to me like how like eight
lines of python were discovered five
years later
um or how like you know really like
terribly written implants work um
there's this one that was uh iranian
malware i think it was dns tunneling
and um like i i re-implemented it as
best i could from reporting
i took it to a client site was like hey
let's test and see you know this kind of
thing and it like broke immediately
because like they were blocking the ip
address
scheme type thing that this tool used
i'm like how did this actually work i i
wrote the thing i think during a meeting
because i was bored that day uh so yeah
to take it it's totally there's the
argument like hey is this realistic yeah
i could do whatever it works
um
as you're doing this think about impact
you don't necessarily have to like drop
something it works and then you know get
domain admin but it it does make a
better story when you can say hey this
thing happened um
it's good you know like hey this you
know whatever we did made an alert so
it's obviously bad or we hope it is
anyways that's a start but some human
visible-ish something is better if you
can you know make the test such that
somebody sees something add yourself to
an ldap group um
i know a fellow and that's like he just
gets bored and and he ends up in ldap
groups
and and then we end up with things to
fix um
less and less these days which is quite
nice
uh
and the more the more real you make
these tests the more real you execute
the tests uh the more credible it is and
by this i mostly mean where you're doing
them
so
user endpoints i mean don't just like go
up to somebody and say hey can i hack
you please um but you know something
configured reasonably similarly it's not
great to say like oh yeah we just got
domain admin but the box didn't have the
normal set of defensive tools on it
because you know there's the question
like would that have blocked it um prod
network as well uh
with care um
if you don't have care i get this
message one day and and i
i got the message after i figured out
how to reconnect to the network and uh
the message was
our ceo would really like you to stop
breaking the wi-fi
so
test and fraud
carefully
on the blue side another benefit is you
you know how things look in security
tools nothing's looking defensive tools
so you don't have to worry about like
false positives i mean you're going to
hopefully have them but you also have
hopefully a much better idea than red
side does how things are laid out and
how to not break things
anyway so you have all this you know
test cases and list updated listed with
results
uh so now let's take a few minutes and
look at sort of a kind of real-ish case
study and like i said in the beginning
originally i was gonna you know think of
something i've gone against tested and
be like all right here just change the
names to protect the innocent
um that wouldn't be very kind so let's
not do that
instead the tool we're going to go
against is kind of a
kind of a mishmash of several other
real-life things all of the all of what
we're going to talk about has happened
just not in one tool
recap what we'll do in the case study um
we're going to work out what this tool
is meant to do and also what we'd like
it to do we'll figure out some test
cases and then
and we won't actually do it but
notionally get caught
also please note when you're doing this
there's no need for this all to be this
formal like it can totally just be like
you know got some time in one day and
write it i i don't know how many times
i've sat in meetings that i wasn't
really part of like i was there because
i don't know they wanted somebody with
long hair and a beard
and i was like i'll just write this
thing and then like a month later i'm
like let's use this thing and see what
happens
so every situation of course is
different
so here's our super duper effective tool
which is really not one tool but it's a
network-based bad guy catcher and maybe
bad guy sometimes blocker um and and in
the sales pitch again notional they were
like this thing catches c2 this thing
catches x-fil this thing catches lateral
movement so on
um and and what we've sort of figured
out is it catches
everything and it's meant to block
obviously bad like high confidence
malicious activity
um
totally not a contrived example that
works for a 40-minute talk
okay so step one let's figure out what
what this tool is meant to do
so from the vendor's description we know
it catches c2x fill lateral movement
cool
we need a little more to go on than that
though so we know from previous alerts
notional alerts that dns tunneling gets
caught okay that's something we can go
on
we know from a friend that you know high
volume ssh is bad and that a tool like
this that catches x-fil can reasonably
be assumed to catch high volume ssh
true story actually a lot i know
network admin went to him security guy
and it's like hey why does our network
traffic go like this
and he said
that doesn't happen our network traffic
doesn't go like this and
and it goes like this if you scp out the
entire company's code base as it turns
out
uh then it goes like this really fast
so does somebody's paycheck um
likewise the thing i alluded to earlier
uh we know that you know again somebody
else uh
quite a bit ago was compromise
cryptocurrency
dropper persistent steel was a cron job
and uh all it did was curl in a crown
job that reached out to whatever so
we'll assume that that's probably
something that should get caught that's
well within the scope of this tool
um on the catch side on the block side
from the vendor description we know it's
high confidence malicious activity
that's great uh what does that mean
so let's poke into the documentation ssh
tunnels are meant to be blocked and
there is a tool that does this um
and it's like hey we will not allow ssh
tunnels to be made your only
point-to-point shell type things
sure that's cool um and then we just
like take a first page of search results
like high confidence malicious activity
or just known malware and see what's
there so you'll get some pretty old
stuff that hopefully is caught you'll
get some maybe modern stuff that
hopefully is caught there are a few
tools out there that um
without naming names that are really
really common to see in the wild
uh if you can convince somebody to spend
a couple thousand bucks for a license
that would be an excellent test case for
almost everything
um and then we'll say from a previous
job another true story we'll just comms
to a malicious ip um
we were using this network scanner tool
and uh
and the guy who was not actually on our
team who was using the tool from our
infrastructure for his own purposes like
work purposes not that kind of own
purposes
uh
scott called him and was like hey dude
um what you got against russia
he's supposed to be like 10. network
right like internal he's like
cool dudes i guess and uh turns out
there was a bug in the tool but one of
the defensive systems was like one of
the defensive tools was like hey yeah
coms to known c2 address comes to
like some ip that is known to
harbor bad things
nowadays
everyone this was before everything went
to cloud um it's a little less high
fidelity but we'll just assume for the
sake of a case study
in 10 minutes that uh that's a thing and
then sort of like stretch goals like hey
what else what else can we get this to
catch so let's ask the red team
um there is a red teamer that at least
one will say try icmp i know at least
three tools that block it
add that to the list um another person
to ask is the people who deal with
regulators like hey if you know if we
could
use defensive tools to help with
regulatory oddity things then it's a
conversation i've had before what what
would it be
um and the answer i got being working
for fintech is credit card numbers like
yeah cool if if you know that happens
sure
so we have a list of use cases like i
said make a list here's our list uh we
will go against dns tunneling high
volume ssh periodic http requests on the
catching side we'll try and test ssh
tunneling known malware google search
engine results and some malicious ip on
the blocking side and we'll just throw
some icmp tool at it and maybe some fake
but you know past one check credit card
numbers
see what
happens that then turns into a bunch of
test cases
which look something like this
um
do i have a little pointer thing
no
sometimes google gives you pointers and
sometimes it doesn't it's my yeah the
crystal's visible yeah so we'll just
lump them sort of into three things that
are our imaginary tools meant to do it's
meant to catch c2 protocols we'll have a
bunch of test cases meant to catch well
known malware bunch of test cases meant
to catch x fill bunch of test cases um
i will not read these all out i promise
i would like to point out a couple that
are sort of interesting um
it doesn't have to be
elegant necessarily uh this is actually
a way to get dns on twitter um
you can't actually get dns feel this way
we're testing a network thing it doesn't
really matter that you know the
likelihood of finding something like
that in your logs is low
um
what wrote something similar to this and
like the guy next to me was like hugging
his tummy and rocking back and forth and
uh and at that point i realized pearl is
an awesome language to write things in
uh because
i can't yeah i would have trouble
reading that somebody looking at that by
catching it the same thing gives me
another hour
um
and then similar on the the simple side
here's that curl and loop i was talking
about
that's girl in a loop that's all that is
so that works um
and and it can be really simple or you
can go complicated or so uh we were
talking about you know first search
first page of i literally typed in like
dns tunneling entered and this there is
a tool i changed the name um but there's
a tool written in ruby that i've used
before it's a pretty good tool
um yeah throw on there see if it works
that kind of thing
um
anything else of note
no
so also also worth mentioning it doesn't
have to be exactly faithful so this was
scpus the high volume ssh thing um scp
on the wire is going to look like ssh
because it's tunnel over ssh right so
that that is sort of that
a few tips that i've gotten just learned
over the years when you're going to do
this use long format options in syntax
so
things like curl here um i probably
should just use hyphen hyphen silent
there much like down here form uh that
way when you're reading it and more
importantly when you hand this
spreadsheet something somebody's gonna
ask for the spreadsheet and the
spreadsheet to somebody with like red
boxes everywhere or whatever it'll be a
lot more obvious what it is
um speaking of the spreadsheet make a
copy uh
it has happened in the past
years ago that i had this nice
spreadsheet color coded and all sorts of
good notes and whatnot and
and we were handing it to somebody i
forget who and it it turns out that my
spreadsheet changed and things that i
was like hey this is important for
whoever it was to know
were deemed not as important uh by
probably a sales guy
uh so yeah copy your spreadsheet you
might need it i i did not and then i had
to go like reconstruct it um
also make sure your tools are fairly
easy to use there's
without getting any details there's a
tool set that i wrote to do this sort of
thing uh that is still in use at an
organization that i have not been a part
of for a few years now
um but you know i i turned it into a
just sort of like a a draggy double
clicky thing that worked pretty good
um
keeping logs is also important pcap is
good as a log uh and i've had many
people say hey can you give me the p cap
for that
i am not entirely sure what somebody's
going to do with 100 gig of ssh p cap
but somebody will ask um and likewise
just logs of like what you're doing uh
screen recordings are also not a bad
thing um
that when i was talking about the icmp
thing the vendor was like hey can you
send us a screen recording of you
abusing icmp and i did and i hit up
arrow and enter and it was like done
it happened
um and then last last but not least uh
and it will happen come prepared with
answers to the hand wavy like no that
could never happen there are no droids
here move along uh you'll find yourself
in these meetings where like you'll
start the meeting and you'll be like
yeah so i tested
i don't know just to pull one of these
things out yeah we wrote a tool to do
icmp tunneling we were you know had some
time we wrote it
and uh
you know it worked and then somebody
would be like yeah but you know you can
sit and write tools the bad guy class
we're worried we're not really worried
about the you know fsb or something
we're worried about like you know our
lower level hackers they're not gonna be
able to write their tools only focus on
like known malware
um and then you'll sit in the meeting
and and you'll be like yeah so we also
did this thing where we um
you know we use curl and loop like you
know kind of the lower level guys you're
talking about and and somebody will
invariably tell you yeah but you know
we're looking at more sophisticated
adversaries it's true story i mean these
things happen all the time in meetings
um and and you're sitting there thinking
like all right either i'm a wizard or
i'm a knucklehead i don't know which i
am
and then sometimes you can be
mathematical and possibilities and i've
been there too um i was i was working
with a group of mathematicians who were
using math uh that that is not sort of
math i understand to catch bad guys and
like take various data points and and
turn that into a score basically and one
of them one of them was convinced that i
think it was like a one minute beacon
interval or something was not a
malicious beacon interval
i had a shell with a one minute beacon
interval at that point but
you know these things happen uh so yeah
be prepared to be you know you'll have
all sorts of um sort of resolution of
cognitive dissonance things um
they happen or you know to be
mathematically impossible
all right quick recap so um
tools it's really hard to know if they
actually work when you're using them
before you just test them um and even if
you test them you'll only know if they
work for what you've tested but it's
still quite a bit better than probably
um
i think blue teamers sort of the thesis
of the talk uh the best people to test
are blue teamers you have the most
knowledge
um you have the most uh skin in the game
really so you know you're the best and
then when you do the testing itself
figure out what the tool should do
uh come up with some test cases and do
it
uh thank you for watching uh happy to
take questions if there are any
and again that will link you to the
slides which makes you all the fun stuff
none
it's like pub is open now
oh
all right non-drinker there
well thank you for the amazing talk was
very interesting just
you let me think in
it is true that the red red team can
help
but you you know also
when you are testing that the tool
because at the end that is the message
you you gave us that you we need to test
in order to check that the tool actually
work we need to think
like the attacker so
so in a way we need to think like like
the red red team is thinking you're just
curious what what do you
think i have a slide for you okay yeah
so things i'm thinking with regards to
one tool these are the things on my on
my brain on my mind
um
you know mostly i'm thinking
i have to full tier one or whatever i
was automated whatever the first step
that makes the decision because if
whatever the first step that makes that
decision uh decisioning right here um
whatever that is if that's like yeah
it's cool then
yeah that's cool
so uh that's that's the first thing and
then figure out what
what i can do that won't get blocked
maybe it blends in maybe there's just no
capability against it and things i do
that won't just not get blocked but
won't get caught
they're not i mean there's subtle
differences there so that's kind of
in one half of a slide sort of the
mentality there
yeah um but happy to talk to you
afterwards much longer conversation if
you'd like yeah good question though
um any other questions
all right cool thank you very much