so uh very good morning to all let's
begin with the first talk of the day
um this talk is going to be more about
security of cellular networks and modems
which are present in your smartphones
your cars your iot devices drones and
what not my name is amit viteka i'm a
cyber security master student at
national college of ireland i have a two
plus years of experience as security
researcher
into hacking electric vehicle iot
devices embedded devices my most focus
is on security of cellular networks i
have worked on security of gsm lte
5g somewhat
and
most of my time i spend reverse
engineering and exploiting embedded and
iot devices
i'm also interested of something i mean
i have a special interest in awkward
science too
okay so what's this talk going to be
about first things first we'll be
looking at an overview of 4g lte network
to just get a basic understanding of how
cellular networks work
then we'll try to fit in how does modern
play
important role
into communicating with cellular
networks and then we'll be talking about
security features in the cellular modems
we'll also be looking at the case study
of what of different vulnerabilities
that i had reported
and then we'll talk about machine
mitigation techniques that can be
used by different vendors
okay
so this is what a basic 4g network looks
like the ue is basically user equipment
we call it this a smartphone this could
be a smartphone this could be your car
which
is connected to a 4g network let's say
tesla
or it could be an iot device it could be
a drone which is connected to a cellular
network the enb which is basically the
cellular tower also known as evolved
node base
this is your cellphone tower through
which to which your smartphone
communicates
this tower is connected to
the mme mme basically stands for mobile
management entity this is where all the
security stuff happens
all of your uh encryption keys are
stored here everything and the enb talks
to the mme directly these are mostly
connected to fiber optics and various
means all of your ip packets are routed
through s gateway
okay so most of whatever you're browsing
let's say you're browsing facebook
everything all of the data flows from s
gateway
and the job of the pdm gateway or the p
gateway is to allocate you ip as soon as
you turn on your smartphone and your
data so pdm plays a very important role
in all this all of these things work
interconnected with each other
right from your smartphone to your pdm
gateway that is how your data flows and
then you are able to browse the internet
so now the question arises where do
cellular models fit in and why do we
need them
so
just like there are rfcs for various
community various protocols so for web
and tcp and stuff
there's a consortium called idu
international telecom union and it has a
different
sister
groups i would say
one of them is 3gb so 3gpp is
responsible for laying out technical
specifications of how the network should
be
architected how the architecture of the
network should be how they should be
deployed and how it should work
so specifically when it comes to your
smartphone vendors your routers your
electric vehicles and whatnot
they have to follow this specification
to design the modem chip and a firmware
running on top of this chip which is
basically an rtos with different
different tasks
it makes sure that all the 80 commands
which are being executed are being
translated into different
um
basically commands and being sent to the
nearby cell phone tower over rf means
this chips are
mainly available in your mostly found i
would say in your smartphones in your
routers and even your electric cars
drones and whatnot so our talk will be
focusing mostly on based on this chip as
i said a baseband firmware and cellular
modem contains 3gb specs and it is
implemented in from an rtos also
sometimes it has been found it is
available in the form of embedded linux
or open source linux systems
so these are some of the security
features that are being you know are
given by various vendors
uh what today i'll be talking mostly is
about quechtel quechtel is one of the
biggest
vendors in modern space and telecom
space and they use qualcomm's
architecture called as hexagon
hexagon has a very different
architecture a very different
instruction set
reverse engineering hexagon chip is very
difficult because they are not arm based
they have a very different way of
working and executing so there are four
protection techniques that are given by
this different different vendors
one of them is jamming detection so if
let's say you're traveling somewhere and
you lose connectivity to your cellular
network basically your phone is offline
right you cannot call anyone you cannot
use the internet or do anything
now this is in the case when you're
roaming let's say there is some white
noise or disturbance present in an rx
spectrum
this causes the smartphone to get jammed
and there is jamming detection in these
chips specifically when they are used in
electric cars and drones and stuff in
smartphone
apple does provide protection from
jamming but i'm not aware about with
other vendors like samsung and
oppo or something like that
the second
protection technique or mechanism in
this provide are this vendors provide a
pseudo based station attack direction
which is basically deploying a fake gsm
or ld network and forcing your
smartphone or your device
to connect to this cellular fake
cellular network
so again depends on different different
smartphone vendors some of them provide
protection some of them don't
then there is a private apn attack so
mostly in electric cars and drones what
you would find is that
apns used are very different from the
aps that you find in your smartphones or
your iot devices they are not just that
you create an apn go to your settings
open as create an api and type in the
name of your api and save it and your
data starts flowing through their
network that's not how it works
usually they have a user password
mechanism but when i have what when i've
been tested couple of uh evs
uh in last two years i haven't found any
of the security mechanisms being induced
and this is something has been advised
by a lot of modern manufacturers and
it's even present into 3gb specs that a
username password combination should be
used to authenticate
let's say a car or field of cars to a
cellular network and the last thing we
will be talking about is an 80 command
one ability attack
so this is basically a hardware and a
firmware based attack in which if you
reverse engineer the modem you find
serial communication ports let's say uh
universal synchronous real-time
communication serial wire interface swi
and once you get access to this you
access the internal firmware or your
time try to dump the firmware you
reverse engineer the firmware figure out
what 80 commands are being there and
then you try to manipulate the city
commands
so these are some of the protection
techniques
are provided by vendors against these
various attacks so one by one we'll be
seeing
how we can bypass this technique even if
the protection mechanisms are available
and
what measures should different different
oems take when it comes to protecting
the devices from attacks specifically to
modems and
cellular networks
okay so how is this going to be done
what is the lab setup and everything so
most of this stuff that i'll be talking
about will be done in an isolated
environment you can consider a faraday's
case something like that or a room which
is isolated from external networks we'll
be using a software defined radio so all
of those who don't know what's a
software defined radio
it's a radio which is in which you can
listen to any frequency or you can
transmit any frequency
and stuff
so we'll be using usrpb200 for deploying
our 4g network which will act as a
pseudo based station
i will be using hack rf everybody knows
hacker what is hacker it's pretty famous
uh it will use it for i will be using it
for jamming the network
gps proofing this mostly has been used
when it comes to spoofing your apps like
uber and all this stuff where you try to
manipulate the destination that you're
trying to reach and sometimes just get
away with it at zero cost you can get a
ride and later on we'll see how a usb
total converter can be used to just talk
to the modem over uh swi interface
so let's begin
so to bypass the jamming detection the
first thing is that we need to figure
out at what frequency
is your smartphone or your target device
communicating with a nearby cellular
network
so this is something this is called
something called as ear fcn eu absolute
radio frequency channel number this is
specified in the 3gbp specifications
uh you have to do some reconnaissance
you need to run uh your
hack rf or usrp uh with
your custom gnu radio script and start
listening to various gsm frequencies if
you stay in area so let's say in india
we use basically use frequencies on a
gsm of 900 megahertz
and that is where every region or every
state in india has been allocated a
specific ar fcn and then you have to
just look it up and try yeah oh is your
device listening at this here fca
uh i have tested this and over a
smartphone and even some other ot
devices
also the target device uh which was kind
of a telematics unit or using jamming
attack i was completely able to
disconnect it from the legitimate
circular network and in further attacks
uh we'll see how we can use jamming
attack to force a device to disconnect
from a legitimate network and connect it
to a fake network and then get all the
data traffic flowing
so this is an erfs calculator that you
can find on screenwave so let's say
after reconnaissance you find out the
frequency your frequency is 2 1 4 this
is where you see a huge bike using a
software defined radio you just go to
this here i've seen calculator type in
the frequency and you will get the afc
number or let's say you figure out in
your fcn number and just click on the
frequency thing this is available on
it's an online tool you get to know the
uplink and downlink so 2114.20 and 1924
or 20 these are the frequencies which
are
basically being used by your device to
communicate to the nearby cellular
network
what you need to do next is to jam the
downlink frequency
that's the tricky part
so this is the script that i had been
using
now this software over here on the left
side uh which shows some blocks
interconnected and everything this is
gnu radio gna radio is an open source uh
software based on python
and python and c plus plus
you can use this to generate different
waveforms and you can transmit and
receive data over the air and a lot of
stuff especially if you're a
communication student this is a tool you
should be playing with a lot
using a cheap rtl sdr
after jamming on the right side as you
can see there's a symbol that's a
semicircle symbol which shows that
the frequency has been jammed and some
of the other
other slides you can just slide it to
various frequencies and increase the rf
transmission power to lower or increase
the power of jamming
remember do not jam too much as this
could cause the device to be completely
disconnected and go into a very
different state where it will not even
try to connect to any other cellular
network and just remain idle this is
some this is a kind of a security
mechanism being provided by a lot of
vendors especially some of the very
great israeli vendors i've seen this
they're doing it's a very great security
mechanism and
it's a very nice way to you know detect
oh someone's trying to hack your device
over cellular network you know just sit
there don't do anything let's quit let
the hacker do his thing we wait for half
an hour 45 minutes nothing happens then
we again try to go and try to connect to
the legitimate network
that's the way it works
okay now this was the first attack now
this jamming attack that i described
we'll be using this to deploy our
pseudo base station attack why would i
do this
thing is
as soon as you power on your device your
smartphone your iot device or even you
start your car
it knows what frequencies are nearby
being used by your cellular company
because this data has been is being
transmitted by your telecom operator to
your device and it's resides as a cache
into your
modem
so it directly will go to go and try to
connect to those frequencies
through jamming we force it to
disconnect through those frequencies
once you understand what those
frequencies or what those ear f sense
where
and then at the same frequency or
frequency just a different offset we
deploy our fake network
with
uh all the fields like uh mcc mnc mg
team z so what are these fields
uh mcc stands for mobile country code so
when you're sniffing you can come to
know what is your mobile country cover
then mnc is your network code so mnc is
unique for each and every telecom
operator let's say vodafone has a
different mnc and then three has a
different terms and somewhat mg is your
user's unique identity over cellular
network it stands for international
mobile subscriber identity so let's say
you are coming you're going from ireland
to u.s and
let's say you're on vodafone so how do
they recognize for you're from ireland
or you're from norway or you're from
india or india so mg is your unique
identifier it helps you recognize oh
this guy is coming from here we need to
provide him roaming services we need to
provide him data packs data services and
so
when you're in your home country so
let's say i'm currently a subscriber of
some telecom operator here in ireland so
i have been assigned something called as
timzy so tmz helps me helps the telecom
operators to locate
whether i am going from dublin to car
to call away where am i exactly
your telecom operator has every or log
of whatever you are doing where you are
roaming what services you're using so
timzy comes into the play when you're in
your home network or you're roaming in
your own country or let's say european
union mg is global
wherever you go they know that you have
gone there you are there for so much
time because the telecom operators over
there they send data back to the
your main operator and they are always
talking to each other using ss7 or
different protocols
okay
so we deploy of cellul uh pseudo fake
cellular network using open source
deploy deployments like srs lte for 4g
network
this is a very famous or i would say of
one of the best deployments of available
right now for 4g networks and open bps
open bts is
old it's now deprecated the main there's
no more maintenance going on but it's
still one of the best choice you can
also go for osmocom it's an amazing 2g
implementation if you have a software
defined radio
in case of 4g now comes a big trick the
big hurdle in 4g networks in 4g we have
something called as private keys these
private keys are basically used for
mutual authentication
in gsm in 2g and 2g networks what used
to be that let's say you are a
subscriber of a certain certain telecom
operator and you try to go into your
settings try to connect to a different
operator
there was no mutual authentication you
could actually fool different operators
to connect your device to the network in
4g this is not possible in 4g you have
to share something like hashes of your
private key to your telecom operator
then that hash goes into the management
entity and those hashes accompanied oh
this has is present in my database this
guy belongs to my network let's give him
access if this does not happen you won't
be allowed to use any of the services
and
in in such situations so let's say you
are using a commercial
mobile operator sim card these sim cards
are not going to get connected to your
fake network because you don't have the
private keys of those sim cards right so
what do you do
well gsm does not use mutual
authentication right we just force the
device to switch back to gsm and tell it
no 4g network is available here please
switch back to gsm it falls back to gsm
on gsm there is no mutual authentication
the device connects to your fake network
and starts sending data all the way
or you can use a programmable sim card
cismo com is one of the best windows to
do this
and after this off after analyzing all
these stakes and you have you are done
with your entire setup then you start
jamming and you jam you keep on jamming
you're jamming until and there's a
device connects to your fake network and
then it starts throwing the data
so this is my test bed that i had used a
laptop for with wireshark and my 4g
network deployment a smartphone for test
purposes
this smartphone was basically used this
smartphone and the target device
connects to the usrp so that's the usrp
which runs your 4g network the
smartphone on the target device uh
connects to your network the smartphone
the reason why i use a smartphone
alongside with my target device is
because on smartphone you can see
different statistics of how what data
rate is being coming on and you know
what other characteristics of your
pseudo network are able to be variable
you are able to see because if you try
to do the same over let's say an iot
device or electric car you won't be able
to see all these things a smartphone
rooted smartphone with some amazing apps
uh
can give you a lot of information about
this
so this is what you get once you start
sniffing and once you deploy it and
the
what whatever messages you get so over
here as you can see the one which is
highlighted rrc connection setup
complete attach request pdm connectivity
request so these are some some of the
initial steps that needs to be done in
order to you know
uh
identify a device and connect just like
we have tcp handshake there are some
handstands that need to be done in
cellular networks after which the
identity is confirmed and then your
granted request as you can see below
yeah
so authentication response security mode
command and then cipher message begins
this happens in very later stage
encryption begins at a very lateness
before that whatever data whatever basic
communication happens it's all in plain
text this was a big flaw in 4g using
this flaw
you can easily study oh at what
frequency is a cellular network running
what is the base station id how you can
even track users how many users are
connected use or to the specific
cellular network or that specific
cellular power which is nearby in your
vicinity those are very sophisticated
attacks and you need a lot of great
radios to carry out such research
so at below uh sorry
below you can see
here mcc says return india or the reason
why i have uh you know masked this
information because this is all very
crucial information and
anyone can use this information to
deploy the fake network
so that's the reason why i have masked i
don't want to get into any legal
troubles
mcc is india india has its own code i
have done this i had carried out this
research work uh in pune a city based
out in maharashtra of india
then you have an mnc so mnc what is what
tells the network or which network are
you in that's what it is and then it
also tells the state so where it says
maharashtra so it's a state in india
then you have mma group id so remember i
said mme is the one who manages all of
your authentication and integrity and
cryptography stuff once you know your
mme group id
you can track users oh this user belongs
to this group id his encrypted key
resides over there
and if you are able to break in
physically
mme you can get access to the private
keys don't do that
then you have mme code and then you have
timzy so these are some of the very
crucial inform and this is all available
in plain text you just need a rtl
uh
rtl sdr and bioshock just need to pipe
it to irish and wire would dissect this
things for you
so once you get all this information and
you study all of these messages one by
one one by one
now what attacks can you conduct using
all of this information downgrade
attacks as i told you because in 4g it's
very difficult to force a device to get
connected to your 4g network because of
the hindrance of the private key not
available you just downgraded you just
tell the device you know hey right now
over here in this vicinity there's no 4g
network running please go back to gsm
and the device will be sure if there's
no 4g available and go back to gsm but
uh gsm has one issue there's not enough
bandwidth over gprs and edge network
that's a big issue
so the second thing is using the list of
nearby area of cns or arfcs i was able
to perform a redirection attack this is
one of the most biggest flaw in 4g this
was revealed and it has been fixed in 5g
networks now
so the thing is using your pseudo base
station network you can tell a device if
he is trying to connect to your network
that you are not allowed to connect to
me but yes i can give you access to my
gsm network and tell him the frequency
of my gsm network the smart the device
goes and connect to your gsm network
this is a huge flaw it should not happen
i mean you're tracking you're tricking
anyone you're taking users to connect to
a cellular fake cellular network
and this has been fixed now in 5g
specifications
then once the target device ue is good
is getting uh it's connected to your
pseudo network you can obtain all the ip
packets whatever data has been flowing
back into the internet and your device
and everything
using this you can use gps spoofing if
you know how to do that let's not get
into that that's not the topic right now
sms proofing you can even manipulate the
80 commands once you have access to the
hardware let's say in next uh slides
will come to know how we can combine all
of these attacks and create a very big
supply chain attack and compromise the
device completely
okay this is something that is the data
you will find in your fake network once
that device gets connected and has been
fooled okay so i have masked the ip
addresses where it's connected to
over here you can see gps log vehicle
info sensitive credentials blah blah
blah
this all is a malform package it's a
packet data this goes to the cloud
the ips are hard coded of the cloud into
the device's firmware
you are just sitting in middle it's a
magnetometer attack a device getting
talking to the cloud you're sitting in
middle you're watching observing all the
data okay now let's say over here there
is lighter to the longitude you do a gps
spoofing attack on the device you see
the change in nitrogen longitude here
now if this was in case of an electric
vehicle let's say you have a app which
shows where your car is right now it
shows uh
uh it might show where you're connected
to and later on it will change your
location you won't be able to figure out
private apn attack so as i said apn
settings are present in your smartphones
uh these are pre-configured if you have
a smartphone in electric vehicles and
all these things
uh it needs to be configured so when you
buy a vehicle and all these are
pre-configured by your
manufacturers
this is how if you are using a 4g
network this is how you would set up a
uh
apn so first you go to your settings of
cellular network scan for the network in
this case the name is 90155 this was the
name given to the network set up
a private apn so srs lte tells you to
set up a private api so that your data
flows to the network very easily
once you create this you just put to
under to put the name name is srslt
that's it nothing else see your username
and password combination is given but we
don't need to use it
okay and this is in the case of
smartphones in cars and iot devices you
need to have this combination otherwise
security is compromised
and this is the bandwidth i was getting
on the
after it was connected to my network
and the final vulnerability that we will
be talking about is 80 command so uh
cellular communication relies heavily on
the baseband modem or the so-called
basement processors in the smartphones
and they are responsible for all the
cellular communication that happens
baseband modems are nothing but they are
where they are they execute 80 commands
and make sure they are communicating
through your antennas to the nearby
cell phone tower
i was able to successfully been able to
sniff the baseband communication from
the target device and analyze the live
communication between the device and the
smartphone i was able to acquire a sms
and call information i'll just show it
how it was
yeah so this is how the attack is
carried down this is a usb to ttl
converter
uh this is used to connect to the
interface or swi or ui interface of this
device and on your terminal or laptop
you get to
so you you get all the information
if you want to know more about this just
go to smoke they have explained great in
depth
once you are set you have set up all
these things i have used tool called qc
super so this is basically a python
script which
once your hardware setup is complete it
interfaces your laptop and your target
device and make sure the communication
is happening between them synchronously
and then you can see and then you have
to just pipe this data wireshark live
and decrypt the traffic
so you have to pipe all this data to
wireshark
this is some this is this is how you
start getting the data from your
smartphone
uh baseband
yeah
this was the thing so this sms's are
usually encrypted in this case i was
able to get you can see here
zero four six zero one four is the otp
for transaction of this this this otp is
added for 15 minutes from the request
please do not share with anyone
well you just shared with me so
i know what the otp is and we were able
to use this otp to
make another device subscribe to the
service and
i mean a huge blog and why are we able
to see this in plain text because we are
logging everything from baseband
remember sms is coming from your
cellular tower to your smartphone from
your smartphone it's going to your
processor processor is decrypting it we
are reading those decrypted messages
no need of encryption you don't deal
with encryption at the hardware layer
everything has been done for you from
the application your kernel and
everything you are reading directly from
the chip
okay what are the mitigations so along
with jamming detection i i feel that
vendor should also provide driving
prevention mechanisms
for pseudo base station attack it is
advised to use a two two factor
authentication
and for private api attack it is better
to whitelist necessary ip and request
made by any other ips so there's only
specific ip addresses the device will
talk to also one can ask the telecom
operator to provide username password
combo for a pin configuration this will
improve your security and in case of 80
comma vulnerability it's better to
disable serial communication ports or
pin outs and execution of system level
commands or serial imports because
sometimes modems give direct access to
their linux interface and you can just
execute linux commands and make system
changes
questions
[Music]
yeah
yeah does
sorry does the phone not then just step
to another frequency it tries to so in
that case you have to keep on jamming
that's what i said you have to keep on
jamming and jamming and jamming at some
point it just stops looking for it and
then once you know what is the frequency
the smartphone is likely to connect to
after jamming multiple frequencies you
just deploy your fake network at that
frequency it tries to go back to that
and it's connected to your network you
don't need to do anything else that's
how you fool the modem
anything else any other questions
okay
okay okay sure
so thanks thanks a lot