we're going awesome thank you
bye now you know my name is Charlie this
is my first time in NOLA con I'm having
a great time so far a special shout-out
to all of y'all that think you're at the
ransomware talk they're too polite to
leave I don't actually have any films
for you today this title is stolen from
a classic episode of The Simpsons that
featured a bunch of loosely related
short stories and that's what I have for
you tonight is sort of a meta talk about
my experiences as a speaker and all the
all the rejected ideas I haven't had a
chance to present before so some of
these ideas have been rejected by CFP
review boards others were rejected by me
but projection is something that happens
to everyone and it's nothing to stress
about if you need convincing
check out this excellent blog post by
Jake Williams
alright I've been going to hacker
conferences for more than 10 years and
my favorite part of the conference
experience is hearing other people's
summaries of what they seen
I'm not picky I like to hear everybody's
conference Cliff's Notes but it's
especially awesome when a friend
condenses the day's worth the
presentations and bar conversations into
the few minutes of stuff that I really
wanted to hear I feel like that's the
closest I'm going to get to that matrix
I know kung-fu sensation so I'm super
excited tonight to be delivering a bunch
of talks in TL DR for my wife is a web
designer and a couple years ago a few
years ago she was I was helping her move
stuff to a new server she had been
pretty diligent about patching her old
lamp server it was running several web
applications that were installed outside
of the OS package manager and weren't
getting updated luckily for her none of
these vulnerable vhosts we're still in
DNS these were all domains she had
previously moved or let expire the web
applications were still exploitable they
just weren't easy to enumerate so I
started to take a look at what it would
how to identify these orphan v hosts at
a large scale
this tool from Sai Barris does der
buster style brute forcing a V hosts the
tool from portcullis takes a different
approach looking at the server cert for
subjects alternative names and searching
the server IP against several websites
including Bing but neither these tools
are particularly well-suited for
large-scale scanning I think a robust
solution we based on historical DNS data
but understandably the the free options
for this are limited I think the best a
lot is probably DNS trails comm but even
they suggest that you contact them
before doing bulk lookups I thought
about this problem for a while but then
ultimately just sort of lost interest
before building a tool so it's sort of
anti-climatic but that's the two minute
summary
so these check out these links if you're
interested in these sort of
configuration issues this slide these
slides are on my website you'll see the
link at the end of the presentation on
to the next talk in 2014 I gave a talk
with my friend Mike Larsen about tor
traffic analysis the TLDR here was that
the Tor protocol is similar enough to
HTTPS that some simple JavaScript can
generate traffic that'll fool the rules
of IDs and IPS sensors they're trying to
identify tor traffic so later that
summer after this talk I was still
running a bunch of tor nodes when I saw
this tweet so cool this is the same
problem that we were just talking about
where the the web servers the host
configuration is acting as sort of an
accidental security layer but if people
really are exposing hidden services to
the Internet this way there's even
simpler tests we can try we could just
enumerate SSH in services collect the
public key fingerprints and then scan
the internet for them so I thought it
would be a cool project something that I
could do and then John Mather Lee blows
up my spot and puts all of that DNS
fingerprint information in showed in so
he did all the hard work all I could do
was tweet the idea and move on to
something else if you're skeptical the
Dan's approach would have worked in 2015
the cthulhu found that there really are
web servers set up this way as a show
shown here via Apache mod status if
you're interested in the sort of
research definitely check out Sarah
Jamie Lewis's awesome onion scan project
my favorite tour my favorite or story of
2016 was this the pinion bug and firefox
from the tor browser this was initially
discovered by the Tor fork guy but it
was just sort of dismissed as him being
an angry jerk
ryan duff really saved the day here and
found the route and identified the root
cause and got the bug killed so I've
been that guy is anybody else here been
that guy been the angry jerk please
don't be that person
for most of us in our careers our
ability to build rapport and persuade
people be just as important as our
technical skills for we're just keeping
going all right for a long time I've
want to give a talk on security career
advice there's just one problem
I'm not very successful I wouldn't
listen to me but who I would listen to
is 2 Chainz
I love hip-hop and 2 Chainz is super
successful so let's see what he has to
say if you have a job and your last
paycheck tin and bounce your
organization is live to fight another
day
cynicism is part of the hacker mindset
so pessimism doesn't need to be things
are getting better on lots of security
frauds keeping up to date is a challenge
we all share for years I follow a ton of
security people on Twitter and follow
more than a thousand blogs and listened
to six to eight hours a week of security
podcasts when I'm not listening to
hip-hop nation and the vast majority of
useful stuffs I've learned through these
channels I've also seen come through our
net sack so props to these folks this is
a great resource as well as those mods
tweeted even the CIA reads our net sack
this is from the vault 7li it's a link
to a net sect discussion about UAC
bypass on grey hat hacker
in a few months some of you may be at
the the black hat business hall hearing
all the latest product pitches this year
promise to be just like last year except
machine learning that's been added to
everything okay so this doesn't sound
too bad
everybody sim does some stats the most
frequently seen the least frequently
seen or what else can we do
counting seems like a good place to
start I'm going to show a couple of
samples with Splunk that you should be
able to do this with any modern sim this
is a simple indicator from Chris Gates
excellent purple team talk a random 16
character workstation name from
Metasploit SMB choir so here's that
search these next two searches require
this app this Splunk app we can
calculate entropy - defined random ish
to find random ish data you're looking
at domain names or we can calculate
levenshtein distance to find similar
strings here looking for domain similar
to google.com or we can calculate the
average time between connections to
identify beaconing but statistical
analysis is going to identify anomalies
and not incidents I have high hopes for
machine learning solutions but most
organizations aren't going to find value
in investigating every statistical
anomaly security architectures and
control frameworks are great resources
to identify where you are and where you
want to go but unfortunately seems like
all the options from the NIST
cybersecurity framework to 20 critical
security controls require big bucks to
implement years ago when you Nature had
advocated for building similar resources
for people living below the security
poverty line and as far as I can tell
the first the person making the most
progress on this front is Taylor Swift
Taylor's website features security
information written for IT professionals
and the security community definitely
needs more outreach like
so I'm not suggesting just clarify I'm
not suggesting that you're going to
solve the world security problems with a
blog post but I am suggesting that more
than just the hacker community can
benefit from your expertise in 2011 I
gave this choose your own adventure
style talk at besides Las Vegas and
hacker con I don't know if you can tell
from this gift but that's Dave Kennedy
he seems like a really nice guy but if
you look closely he's stealing my wallet
the TLDR there was that I didn't think
most companies were ready were mature
enough for penetration testing and now
more than five years later I still feel
the same way and props to Adrian for
recording this he's a real asset to our
community he's been doing this for years
and it's amazing that these videos are
out there he's probably sitting right
over there so clap a little bit louder
so he can hear you on the other side of
the wall
thanks Adrian thank you
so the dirty secret of the penetration
testing business is that a lot of the
lessons learned from these penetration
tests there are essentially the same and
you don't need to pay for a test to
learn them for example there's this
report from Victorian labs and this
other one from rapid7 and the primary
lesson that most organizations haven't
learned is about protecting credentials
so this guidance from Microsoft is
pretty simple
they suggest you just organize your
system administration activities and in
a way that your admin creds are
unnecessarily exposed so this isn't
technically difficult or censored to
implement but does require changes in
system administration behavior an
organization should at least invest some
resources and protecting credentials
before paying for a pen test a word of
warning if you are a networked person
looking at this picture you may think
that this is about network segmentation
it's actually not it's about how and
where admin credentials are used on your
network so if you're not familiar with
these sort of escalation paths
definitely check out bloodhound it was
an open source tool released
last year DEFCON and was updated just
this week but even if you choose to
adopt this tiered administration model
you're probably going to fuck it up and
here are some of the ways like here are
some of the problems that you're likely
to encounter
starting with essentially anyone that
has read access to NTDs zip file on a
domain controller is de facto domain
admin and if you run virtualized domain
controllers this may include the people
that manage the virtualization or shared
storage layers so those users need to be
treated as tier 0 users and if you've
delegated group policy management to
members of the group policy creators
owners group and then link their GPOs to
tier 0 assets then they also need to be
treated as tier 0 users here's another
layer of delegation to keep an eye on
this script will show you things like
who can reset the passwords on your
critical accounts and this is part of
the functionality that was just added to
bloodhound 1.3 this tool doesn't get
enough love Mykel graph emitters vs
internals PowerShell module will parse
your entity F stats it and can show you
things like which accounts share the
same password so this is valuable
because if you have admin ik admins with
accounts and multiple tiers any security
benefit of having separate accounts is
lost if they share the same password if
you require smart cards for logon you
might not think that the password issues
apply to you but users can still change
they're still change their password and
the hash never expires so to work around
this you can toggle a smart card logon
require it off then on and you'll have
to rely on this workaround until both
the domain and forest functional level
are updated to Server 2016 yeah that
might be a while in some places another
thing you may want to look at it that
you want to take a close look at is all
of the agents running on your tier 0
assets including your endpoint security
software but a good place to start is
with the patch management client the
role-based access
then each of these tools needs to match
the cheered administration model for it
to be effective all right so I still
believe in the value of pen testing I
just don't think it's for everybody I
like to hear your ideas about getting
the most value out of a test
feel free to yell them out or I'll be
around for the rest the weekend come
chat in conclusion keep doing your thing
submit to the next CF PUC and don't
worry about getting rejected I can't
wait to see your talk that was it thank
you
[Applause]