all right thank you all right yeah thank
you for coming out in all the time
survivors the party was what was great
last night you guys go see that you see
you see fuzzy and dual core play I said
that was really fun I'm really glad to
see that and so I know what it was like
last night and I'm glad to see you all
here I'm also glad to be here and want
to go through a series of what I call
parlor trick hacks they're basically a
collection of attacks and compromises
that I've seen many people do I have a
slide at the end that kind of show you
who I took most of these attacks from
but I wanted to put together a narrative
a story of how some very bad decisions
and pour'd configuration options that I
see some some organizations do how you
can kind of string these things together
to basically steal all the things and so
so the tactics that I've put together
here are not terribly sophisticated but
they are they are effective they work
and they do actually get you from
nothing all the way to domain admin and
stealing Active Directory so what I'm
going to go through here doesn't use a
lot of the Suites and the tools that we
use but the reason that I did that is
because I wanted to be able to show ways
to do these compromises and be able to
describe it to some of the businesses
that I talk to because if I can show of
native Windows tools that can lead to
some pretty terrible things that gets
their attention and it lets them think
maybe there are things we could do
better so that's what this whole series
is about and to kind of set the stage
we're going to start out where we have
to get into an environment and then look
around and then actually do the
compromising and take all the step and
we're going to do this basically with
three different machines right we're
going to start out trying to get into a
workstation we're going to compromising
that then we're going to take that
workstation and jump over to a member
server and compromise that and once we
get from there we're going to jump over
to the domain controller and then take
everything all right so they want to see
what it looks like let's start up me I'm
Shanna Fritz I'm a Solutions Architect
at the company called concurrency
and I'm actually really fortunate to
work at a company like that because they
actually sponsor to have me come out and
do these kinds of talks so I know after
talking with a lot of you that a lot of
you are on vacation and personal time
and this is actually my job so I'm
really fortunate to work in a company
that gives me the opportunities to
participate in these kinds of events
where I also work with our customers on
making improvements in security so my
background is quite varied
I work in eleven structure and mobility
but today I'm working with customers on
making improvements in their security
decision at the end of the presentation
we also can have my email address with a
special subject line that you can get
the deck so if you want to you don't
have to like rush through and take a
bunch of notes but what I'm basically
going to be doing is doing the attack
showing your slide on things you can do
to mitigate it and then going back into
the attack threat so that at the end you
can get the deck just by email and me so
again to kind of set the stage we're
going to start out with them is the
story of somebody losing their laptop
right somebody might have gotten mugged
maybe they left it on you know some
transit or maybe they went to a bar and
when they get up to go to the bathroom
they come back in the laptops gone right
so the laptop is gone what might that
mean if we you know think about in many
cases it might just be that someone
wants the hardware right they're going
to take it format it use it for their
own purposes but if we wanted to do
something more nefarious what might that
look like
so we jump over here let's assume this
is the laptop obviously if we're doing
demos I want to be able to roll back
snapshots and stuff so this were David's
laptop you know some of the things that
we can find out right away is that you
know where this laptop is from right you
can just pretty easily look over here
and see like oh this is from this tech
ready organization and with that
information I can start looking around
figure out who is tech ready where where
they located
but maybe I'm targeting this
organization and that's exactly why I
took this laptop so I might already know
some information like that about them
but I want to get some things off of
this machine
well I knew obviously is username and
password I'm actually going to really
need is username right because it's
already logged in I just need to type in
get in but I don't know its password I
don't know it's pin I don't have
finger I don't have his face so I can't
do any of those hello gestures to log
into the machine but if I still wanted
to get in the box
easiest thing to really do is just
reboot the machine and on rebooting
we're just going to boot off of like the
Windows setup CD alright so I just take
the set of CD that I download from the
demo site or TechNet and boot the thing
up not some hacker tool or anything like
that just the ISO and then of course it
runs Windows PE and windows PE if you do
any kind of disk in the gene you know
that you can use this for running a
variety of tool but one of them you
really just hold shift and hit up 10 and
you get a command prompt and at the
command prompt we can open up notepad
and inside a notepad you can go to file
and open and then we can just start
browsing around the file system alright
so we can come in here and see that you
know I've got a I've got a USB Drive
attached to this computer but we also
have this C Drive so we can go ahead and
double click on that we can see under
users there's David's profile here so we
can look in here go to his documents and
we go and change the file types to
everything we can go ahead and just copy
this file go to the USB Drive guru and
paste it and then what hue I just stole
some stuff not super convenient to do
one file at a time but I can write I can
copy stuff off of the drive so I wanted
to get more things I actually want to
get into this computer that's a little
bit more useful is to go to the C Drive
thanks and then we can go into the
Windows System it's just 32 and then
there's that file in here called set HC
dot exe and we can copy the cmd.exe
right over the settings even exe and say
yes I want to overwrite that and then of
course we just close this out close this
out say yes we want to reboot and then
when we reboot this time we're not going
to boot from the ISO we're just gonna
let windows load like normal and who's
no set I see
assume somebody knows ring yes that HD
is sticky keys right so sticky keys is
that accessibility option that allows us
to do things like press the control or
the shift key and it actually holds it
for us so we can hit the other buttons
but if we use sticky keys you hit it 1 2
3 4 5 hitting the shift key and now I
get the command prompt on the lock
screen and if you say Who am I we can
look in here and see that not only am i
running set hchc right here but I'm also
running a system all right so just
replacing a file rebooting the computer
and using sticky keys now I can get a
system level command prompt at the lock
screen now I can invoke actions as the
computer I don't have to do much else I
am the machine now but I still want to
get into the computer so I can interact
with it right
with with fancy gooeys because GUI is
our fun right
so instead what we're going to do is run
comp MGMT MSc and this will load the the
computer management console and in the
Commuter to management console now we
can go into users and groups and we see
there is actually a local admin account
on this machine which is pretty bad
decision but I could right click and
change this password and get into the
machine but I'm going to hold on to that
one leave that one as is for now and
instead I'm actually going to right
click create a new user and give them a
fancy name and we'll give them a
password and we'll make sure it doesn't
expire so that I can use it without you
know being cumbersome with that and then
add this user to the administrator's
account our group and then we can close
this go ahead and close that log in as a
different user to the local machine set
that account and login so now I'm able
to get into the computer right I have my
own account I'm a local admin and I can
use it just like their regular and way
you would with a user on the machine I
don't have to do any kind of remote
command and control I'm actually just on
the Box locally so
a question I get after that usually is
well what do you do to stop that right
so we'll jump back to the deck and we'll
revisit this a couple of times but what
would you do to stop that
good Locker exactly yeah if we can
encrypt the hard drive then you can't
interact with the file system outside of
the context of running Windows right so
that would have prevented me from being
able to replace the sticky keys with
command I'd exe and it would have made
it so that I couldn't have gone to
create my own account so just encrypting
the drive would have gone a long way and
did Locker being built into Windows or
something you can literally just turn on
if you right-click on the C Drive enable
BitLocker and you're good to go
as an enterprise though you need to
manage it so if you wanted to maybe do
some passive an audit so you can show
that you actually are encrypting their
systems you can use em BAM which is the
Microsoft BitLocker administration and
monitoring tool it has an on-prem server
that the agents you deploy report back
and tell whether or not the devices are
actually compliant with the policy for
encryption and can also invoke the
encryption if you use group policies you
can only say what to do when it turns on
you can't actually turn it on with the
policy so you have to use an agent for
that and that's what ambam does also if
you've heard of Azure Active Directory
join azure ad join you can have Windows
10 machines join Azure Active Directory
not Windows Active Directory but a sure
ad and if those machines are instant go
capable which means that you know they
have connected standby enabled they will
automatically turn on BitLocker so
there's nothing you have to do you
literally join the directory and it
turns itself on so for some monitoring
if we wanted to see some activity that
to know like what's happening on the
machines we can use Windows Defender ATP
as anyone heard of that defender ATP not
just Defender 680 P so defender ATP is a
new thing for Windows 10 if you're
running the Windows 10 enterprise and
you have the e 5 SKU which comes with a
variety of licensing bundles the B 5 SKU
gives you defender ATP which is a new
cloud service that allows you to see
actions and activities happening on the
workstation not just like defender where
it will do signature based detection of
files of binaries but activities
happening on the machine things
happening in memory network connectivity
and
process working all that kind of stuff
so just to show what that looks like we
can jump over here and this is the
Windows Defender dashboard and in here
we can see kind of the heads-up of all
the alerts in the warnings and things
and in my demo environment I do a
variety of these demos so we can see a
couple of things that have popped up so
for example the sticky keys hijack right
if you replace that file it can say hey
this doesn't look like that HD dot exe
it is running something else but it can
also detect that the file itself has
been replaced and what it looks like so
here is the set HC we can see that it
then ran the MMC and Who am I alright so
those are the those are the things that
I did and it saw that it can report on
and give you a warning estate ticking
keys isn't supposed to be doing that
really like you need to do something
about it but it can also detect a bunch
of a series of other things for example
if we jump back here quick we can also
see like it's a suspiciously named
hacking tool which happens to be mini
caps and we can see things like the
right-to-left override you seen that the
character that allows you to take the
letters and shift them from left to
right instead of right to left so you
can make it actually look like a jpg for
example so that bar this case I'm
actually doing a PDF we're using the
sticky keys hide there and not sticky
keys but the left-to-right override it
actually looks like the extensions then
switched and if you have extensions
turned off you only see dot PDF you
don't see the dot exh them a variety of
things that can be detected in here but
once you come in and you do some
investigations we can see things like
let's say this sticky keys hijack that
we just did you can see over here that
this is the machine that this activity
had taken place on so now I can say well
who's been logged onto this machine who
do I need to contact and you know do
some some actions with and say oh well
this is David's computer and the
helpdesk is logged into this machine and
there's also this hax or account that's
not in the computer so maybe that's not
so good but if I decide that all of
these other alerts that have come up on
this machine now mean that I need to do
something like take an action on this
computer
I can actually click here and do one of
two things one is this investigation
package it'll basically collect some
files and log data and tell me some more
information that's on the machine so I
can investigate what went on with the
computer but I can also isolate the
machine which basically instructs it to
shields up the firewall and prevent it
from talking to anything except for the
defender ATP service so that's a pretty
handy tool now I can shut the Machine
off the network contact the user and say
hey bring in your brick we need to pave
this machine and give you a new setup so
that's that's the fender 8qp it's a
pretty neat service that it gives us a
lot of protections and actions that as a
blue team you don't really have a lot of
solutions for that right now so let's
jump back over to our workstation and
now that I'm logged into this computer
as my hacks or account I want to start
taking some stuff so usually what that
means is basically what we had done on
the the setup CD so we'll go into the C
Drive we'll take a look at maybe David's
profile in this case now it tells me how
you don't have permissions to access his
files but I'm a local admin now so I can
just take permissions before I wasn't
operating in the context of the
operating system so I have no they
didn't really care about permissions at
that point but now that I've taken
permissions or given myself access I can
come in here I can copy all of these
files off of this Documents and then I
can go over to my USB Drive and I can
steal all the steps so we'll go over
here USB and paste it okay now what's
what else has gone on here like in this
case you happens to be using onedrive
for business and with onedrive for
business you syncs all this stuff
offline just like with you know Google
Drive or Dropbox or whatever so we can
come in here and here's a pretty bad
habit that a lot of organizations
actually still view where they're
creating password files because they
have a lot to manage so using password
managers would be a really good
alternative here because now I can log
in and check out a bank I can check out
a timesheet and I can read his personal
email I can do all kinds of stuff with
his passwords also use them to try and
log into other systems that maybe are
he's doing password reuse but let's go
ahead and take that his picture
and kind of taxes take this and paste it
over here
another one that's really interesting
the grab is right over here in app data
and under local Microsoft Outlook and
under outlook we can take this which is
data outlook cashed in box so now we can
read all of his mail and there's all
kinds of stuff to search in their inbox
right like if this person was recently
on boarded I might be able to find out
how do you get into the building how do
you get on the VPN how do you get on the
Wi-Fi it might all just be in a Xena
because well that's how people find that
stuff out right so now that I have a
copy of his inbox I can also figure out
who he has good relationships with as
bad relationships maybe who his
customers are contacts and all that
stuff I can use for other for expanding
like phishing campaigns for example so
now that we have all of these things but
what kind of tactics can we use to
prevent this from being the problem well
if we were to use BitLocker BitLocker
would also have stopped us from being
able to copy files off of the machine so
if we did like the set up CD and use the
tool to copy things off of it we
wouldn't necessarily have to have made
ourselves a local account to get into
the machine to do this so BitLocker
might have prevented that but if you had
like a remote shell on this machine and
you were running in the context of David
you would have had access to these files
and could have copied them just as
easily so in that case we might need to
encrypt the files themselves not just
the file system and if we're using
something like Azure RMS we can we can
do either selective encryption of
content that we deem to be sensitive and
the nice thing about azure RMS is that
if you're using Azure Active Directory
there is no real change to user behavior
here they don't have to like enter a key
or some other kind of way of decrypting
the content they just open the content
in office and because they're logged
into office with their azure ad account
it can automatically check out the
decryption key and interact with the
files so azure RMS is a really good
option that's actually called azure
information protection now it's the
azure arm the RMS name doesn't really
ring very well as a lot of places
because RMS
is always traditionally a pain in the
butt to deploy as your RMS you basically
enable it and then you use it there
isn't much else to deploy so it's really
it's really useful now also new for
Windows 10 is what's called Windows
Information protection or with Windows
Information protections users as your
RMS under the covers so instead of
needing to take the APM the SDKs and
develop your applications to be RMS
enlightened we can actually just as an
organization declare certain
applications to be enterprise apps and
an enterprise app then can be a can have
an RMS policy applied so any files that
it interacts with becomes encrypted and
decrypted transparently so we can say
WordPad is an enterprise app and when
you open up a text document in our RTF
it will encrypt that file transparently
at the US there is actually an article
posted two days ago on the TechNet blog
that covers with if you want to know
more about that okay so now that we've
gotten into the machine we've stolen
some files off of it we want to take our
next step and find a way off of the
machine so let's take a look at how to
find the corporate network now because
I'm doing demos on a VM it's actually
hard to attach a wireless network
adapter to a VM despite my efforts but
what we so I got this other machine that
I'm logged in here as a local admin same
hacks or account the main join and this
machine I used another domain account to
connect to other wireless networks and
when you connect the other networks you
can tell it to remember or connect
automatically and when you do that the
machine saves a list of the networks
you've attached to so we click over here
to network settings and then we can go
to manage known networks and then we can
see this list of networks that this
computer has connected to what's nice
for us is that these network these are
saved so that any user that logs in the
machine can use them again later so I'm
logged in as a local account I did not
connect to these networks someone else
did and now I can reuse them because
they've been saved in the machine now
because I'm a local admin I can interact
with things as the machine but I can
also scoop these network settings out of
here
so if I would do that let's open up
command prompt and at the command prompt
I'm going to go over to the desktop and
we're just going to use net SH for this
so you just do net SH W lamb export
profile and the key should be clear and
then this generates a couple of XML
files and then we can go ahead and take
a look at what's in here and we can see
not only the SSID of the network that
that we're going to connect to but it
also shows hey this is wpa2 and here is
the passphrase so you can go ahead and
use that to login to the network so now
I know the rest ID and the clear text
password to go ahead and connect I could
check my own devices I could also take
these XML files and re-import them
that's actually the intent behind this
is if I'm an administrator of an
organization I could pre configure the
wireless network settings and just run
the import of this XML file and I don't
have to like block or user through that
you know that annoying process of
connecting to a wireless network
this will also export the certificates
if you're using certificate based Wi-Fi
and I'm not totally sure the last time I
did this somebody said you could
actually get the private keys of the
search that you're using to I have a
test of that yet so I'm really
interested to know if that's actually
the case I know me kneecaps has ways of
doing that but if you're using that Sh I
don't think you actually get the private
keys so what can we do to prevent this
well first that is a function of a local
administrator so if you have local admin
you can do this so preventing users from
having local admins a good one if you
have a remote shell on a machine and the
users not local admin you couldn't run
that SH to dump this out of hearing but
if they are a local admin and I'm
remotely connected to the guys machine
then you could use this to get their
Wireless passwords and then go to their
offices connect to the Wi-Fi from the
parking lot or from the bathrooms or
somewhere and they get on their network
because you know the credential and if
you wanted to use certificate based
Wi-Fi to deploy it you can use group
policies to config
are those things as well as MDM so if
you're using something like in tune to
manage Windows 10 you can actually
configure the wireless networks and
certificates so you can have group
policy to automatically enroll
automatically renew and set up the
wireless networks all with policies so
it's actually not as not as tough as
sometimes it seems to be ok so now we're
kind of at the point where we have gone
through we've compromised the Machine
and now it's time to kind of look around
and figure out where can we go from here
so let's assume that we just did the
wireless we've got the SSID network and
maybe we looked a mop on wiggle net or
we just know where this company is or we
found their address on their website and
we drove to their office we're sitting
in the parking lot and we connect to the
wireless network what kind of things can
we can we find so back here on our on
our workstation we minimize these things
here one of the tools that I usually use
just in troubleshooting and I used to do
a lot of direct access deployments so a
tool that I always used with an Apsara
and I'll test give a reason I'll test
its active directory tool so we can just
open up a command prompt here I always
say so we'll open up a command prompt
little Agee and at the the command
prompt we'll just run an old test let me
make this a little bit bigger so you can
see it so we'll go to keep up and 20
should be good ok so if we do an old
test /dc list of a colon
this will actually query the active
directory to give me a list of domain
controllers now since I'm running as a
local account I don't have permissions
to do a query against active directory I
don't have read permission but it does
still tell me the name of the primary
domain controller right so if that's all
I wanted that would be really useful but
I want to get some more information
because then I'll test usually tells me
more about all of the DCs and
sites in Active Directory so what we can
do is use the computer right because
since I'm a local admin I can invoke
actions as a system but if I try sticky
keys it will give me a command prompt
but it actually is still owes running in
the context of my local account not
running as system right now so I want to
be systems well in order to do that
we're going to go use a tool to do some
elevation of privileges and thanks to
our friend mark russinovich he gave us
PS exec so here's PS exec we'll go ahead
and copy this right over here to the C
Drive I'm going to make a new folder
over here called tools and then tools
we're going to paste that we'll come
back over to my command prompt go to
tools and here's my PS exec so around PS
exec we'll run a system interactive do
not wait for cmd.exe and what this does
is well first prompt you to accept the
EULA so yes we'll do that and then when
I run Who am I you can see we're back to
running a system right so local admins
have the abilities to invoke these
actions and become system now that I'm
system I can do my query again so let's
go ahead and do an L test /dc list and
then this time it gives me the whole
list of things in active directories now
I can see where other domain controllers
are I can see names of sites and it
gives me some insight to the topology of
the network and relationships between
them right so just a real quick and
dirty way to get a dump of all the DC
now I want to go after the primary
domain controller because why not let's
just go for broke and get the biggest
one and since we already know the name
of that we know DC 3 is ultimately going
to be our target now that we we know
that there's some other things that we
can we can ask active directories so
let's make this a little bit bigger
again and change here and also extend
that cool
so now what I can do is basically just
get a list of all of the users in the
domain so there's a net user
/ domain and so this will actually just
dump all of the Active Directory
accounts and I can take a look at any
users in here and start inferring things
like naming conventions I can get an
idea of who's in there maybe figure out
through you know social networking and I
can find out well maybe whose account is
what their actual name is but I can also
see things like the the groups that are
in there with the same kind of command
so instead of net users I just do net
group domain so this will dump all of
the groups and Active Directory and then
with that I can start looking around see
what what kinds of products and services
maybe they use because you know naming
conventions we like to name things to
the products that we use so we can see
that they use Remote Desktop Services
they have some some level of MFA in
tunes and plays hyper-v exchange and so
we can start using that as a way to
decide well what kinds of products might
be out there that we can maybe
compromise and get in we can also be
more specific so we can say net group
domain admins in the domain and this
will actually give me the list of all of
the domain administrators that are out
here and because I know that these
accounts are doing admins these are
probably the ones I'm going to target
right I want to find out know where
these accounts are being used and see if
I can get the credentials Philips
accounts well we can also see that with
the naming conventions the a - probably
means humans and administrators and s -
probably mean service accounts and what
do we know about service accounts and
their passwords they never change right
nobody changes passwords for servers
accounts because it's a hassle so those
are probably going to be our our Golden
Tickets those are the ones that we
really want to get and if we look at
like this we can see that they have
sequel we have this app service we also
have you know vmm and some other ones if
we can find those accounts somewhere
that's going to be the ultimate thing
right we can get what we want with those
counts so now what we need to do is find
some computers that we can attach to
there are some things we can do like
nslookup to try and do a zone transfer
and dump all of the DNS but that's kind
of loud and usually doesn't work because
the main controllers out as of 2008 and
up
reject that kind of a query so instead
we can just return to our friend top
management and GMT MSC comp mg and PM SC
and again I'm still running this from
the context of the system so now I can
actually do queries against Active
Directory with this account so let's go
into groups and pick any group I usually
use domain admins because it's funny and
then if we go and do an advanced search
we can change the object type here to
just show me computers and if we do find
now in this list now we can actually see
dumping out of active directories
listing of all of the computers in the
domain so I can start doing the same
sort of list and start go out there and
say well where where are these machines
are they online does it using the
product that I know I can compromise and
in this case I actually have app server
and if humans do what humans do app
server and app service are probably
related to each other so if I can get on
app service I can probably or the app
server I can probably use the app
service account right so let's if we
target that machine we need to figure
out how can we get on that box so in
order to administer that machine if I
was an admitted that stopped so if I can
RDP to the machine with credentials I
can probably find out where the service
account is so kind of connecting the
dots a little bit here on some
assumptions but it's not uncommon right
this is a very common practice and it's
actually pretty pretty likely to work so
what what do I know right now I know
where their primary domain controller is
I know a service account
I know a server I have access to the
network and I also know that they're
already in the habit of using a local
administrator account on their machines
if they're doing that they're probably
using it on their servers too right so
if we remember over here I have in the
top management window under users I have
this local admin account now if they're
reusing this account to I
use it to get into appserver right so
since I'm local admin on this machine
the credential for this account is saved
and if I use another tool like me me
cats I can dump those credentials so
let's go ahead and get that credential
we come back over here to our set of
tools we have these files for me me cats
and if I try and copy this and paste it
over here to the C Drive defender pops
up and says ha ha ha
got you well alright let's go back into
defender I'm a local admin so I can go
to my my protection settings and I can
say turn off real time protection yes I
really mean that and then say try again
and it'll paste that file that I want
and haha I did it so now if I go to my
tools directory and sader now I have
Nene cats now if we look at this
Muni cats script basically all I'm doing
is I'm running mini cats using the debug
privileges and then I'm going to dump
the LSA database right so just to so I
want protected make professor we're
going to go ahead and do me me catch you
I got a paste my files again go back
over here go to tools unique at Caffe I
did this last time too and that's trying
to just be quick and paste up there no
and now I can run it so now that will go
through a dumps the Sam database of the
local admin account and in here if we go
ahead and copy it we can go edit and
mark we have our local admins password
hash we can copy that and we're going to
use our hacking tool the internet and
we're going to go to crack de Guiche and
dotnet and
they have this neat little text box to
paste it into and we're going to type in
this I'm a human challenge and en TOS jg
e OT last time I did this the text came
up had but in the name so so in this
case the password that they're using
pretty bad right because it's in the
database I just look it up I don't have
to crack it I don't so reverse it I want
to use you know John the Ripper or hash
cat or anything I can just look it up
and that's also not a terribly uncommon
practice so it's not very hard to undo
this so if you are using these accounts
you should at the very least use a much
better password but the real solution to
this is to frankly not use those local
accounts that are spread around your
organization alright if you do have
local accounts we lapse with talks about
that at other sessions this week where
you can use the local administrator
password solution to roll the passwords
on these accounts but they're usually
for like the named administrator account
if you're using group policy or your
imaging process to create an account
that's local admin this is going to be a
problem and you should just stop doing
ok other things that we can do is seems
like device card right if we're using
device card we can actually make
application whitelist and prevent us
from using some of the tools that we had
used and then we couldn't do things like
dumping the the crunches off of the
machines but you saw I was using in
Windows 10 right this was eaten in the
insider preview so this is the latest
build that was released just the other
day so it's not an issue with with the
build or version of Windows that's
actually just how Windows works so you
know don't use those account as far as
monitoring goes we can use something
called advanced threat analytics or ata
advanced threat analytics will actually
let us see activities happening in
Active Directory so when we were doing
some of the reconnaissance to find who's
in the directory you know dump a list of
users don't ballistic groups as well as
other things like pass the hash and
testicle and take a skeleton key like
those kinds of activities we were
interacting with Active Directory we can
monitor and detect those things with ata
so if we jump back over here real quick
I can show you
what that looks like so this is the
dashboard for advanced threat analytics
and inside of ata we can see that this
was doing a successful enumeration of
all the users and groups right so I can
start getting alerts to say somebody's
poking around in Active Directory doing
things that is not normal for a user to
do and then start taking actions I can
go click on this machine and I can see
who's logged into the machine what other
services they've touched and talked to
who else has been on the computer one
thing you'll notice is that the acts or
account does not show up in this list
because the acts or account is local to
the machine it's not Active Directory
but I do still see the actions of the
computer talking to Active Directory so
so that's just a real quick overview of
ata so if we go back over here to our
workstation now that we have this
incredible local administrator password
we want to use our lateral movement tool
remote desktop to jump over to our app
server so if we want to go to app server
and we want to log into app server using
the local admin account and the password
that we just scraped out of the website
and because they're using the same
practice of creating the local
administrator account on a workstation
and on the server I can now use that
credential to jump on to a member server
and remember I'm sitting in a car in the
parking lot on the Wi-Fi so there's an
awful lot of bad stuff that's going on
in decisions here to make this work so
if we take a look real quick on the you
know what do we do about this well you
know laps would help if we were using
different passwords at very least I
couldn't have just used the same
credential to jump in another one is the
firewall many organizations still are
disabling the Windows Firewall because
they want to paying a remote desktop to
a server that's incredibly lazy and
terrible or should not be done then I
scold them every time I see it but they
do it because they've always done it
that way and if they continue to do it
that way they're going to they're going
to be hurtin so they need to stop but
one of the things we can do with group
policy is we can limit the source IPS
right so we can
use jump boxes just the group policy if
we don't have the ability to physically
segment our networks which honestly is
what should be done you can start at the
very least by saying the only way you
can RDP is you come from this IPS and
everybody has to go to one box we're
more monitoring and tools can be put in
place for controlling access and then
you can only use that to get to the
other machines just by configuring a
group policy we can also say that you
cannot RDP with a local account right
you can say this local account cannot be
used remotely so even if they did have
the same password and they could RDP to
the machine the machine would say nope
you're not local admin or you are a
local admin not an Active Directory
account and you can't RDP to the machine
so there's a variety of things we can do
just to stop just to stop that okay so
we're on the machine now it's time to
level up a little bit let's take a look
at this computer and on the server
sometimes what we'll do is we'll take a
look at what's on the machine right
check out what roles are installed what
products are installed see if there's
some kind of compromises or things that
we want to take off of the machine but
really the easiest thing is if we look
on services now we'll do updates later
we do services inside of services we can
see any kind of processes that are set
to run and in this case I do have a
service that's running my domain
administrator accounts down here so you
know lucky me this machine that I could
log into the local admin account can
also see that this domain administrator
account is being used as a service well
if you think about how this service is
being used the machine when it reboots
has to be able to use the credentials to
run the service under that account and
that means that the password is saved on
the machine so it can use it to
authenticate right well since I'm a
local admin I can do things as a system
and if the system can get out the
password I can get at the password
alright so if we want to do that we're
going to use another tool and this time
we're going to go to the C Drive I'm
going to make another tools folder we'll
go back to the laptop and on the USB
Drive in the tools directory I have this
tool called CQ secrets number from
security atomy
so the security Atome team did this blog
about service accounts and on their
website you can go and download this
tool and it's right here when it's got a
nice password on it so you know you
can't just use it without knowing what
you got but we can use this tool just go
ahead and copy this and we're going to
take PS exec as well because we have to
run this as a system so in the tools
directory we'll paste these two things
we'll go ahead and open up a command
prompt again and we'll go to our tools
directory or run PS exec with a system
interactive game you have eight cmd.exe
and in our system right if I say Who am
I we can see that I'm running a system
now I can run the CQ secrets number tool
and then it tells us how this works it
says you just need to tell me what
service you want right so that's right
over here so tell me the name of the
service so we'll go into our our
management console we'll copy the name
of our service out of there and then
we're going to run the CQ secrets bumper
service equals the service name and then
it dumps out the password for us so we
can go ahead and mark this we'll
highlight the text and then we're going
to take that text over to our other
hacker tool notepad and we're going to
replace all of the dots with nothing and
then we'll remove our line breaks close
it and then we've got our password so
this is actually the password for that
service account so of all the bad
decisions and practices that we've seen
this set up so far they're actually
using a pretty good password here but it
turns out that doesn't matter
because it's just saved in the registry
and I can scoop it right out so we'll
copy this password and now we want to
jump into actually let's jump to the
deck for a second and say what can we do
about this right so
that's sailors night these are all the
things that we can do here if we're
looking at activities that are happening
on this machine you know we can use the
group policies so that we can prevent
access with these local accounts right
so you can't RDP in with the local
administrator account we want to stop
using some of these tools we can use
things like device guard grants so we
can't run that process and then we can
also do some monitoring with things like
sis mods so as much as we might beat up
on using tools IPS executive to get the
system system on can give us a lot of
logging and monitoring and if you've
seen Swift on Security's blog or Twitter
feed the XML file for configuration
that's out there even mark russinovich
us and yeah that's a that's a good model
to follow so you can deploy system on to
see you know process for working and
other activities and then harvest those
logs so that you can see what's
happening in the environment ok so now
we've gone and through the workstation
it's time to finish our movement and get
onto the domain controller so at this
point we have quite a bit of information
right we know about the active directory
we know about a domain administrator
account
we know that domain administrators
password and we also know that we want
to get onto the PDC so if we use Remote
Desktop we can go to dc-3 and now in
dc-3 we do want to log into the domain
with our app service account with our
nice password and now I can get on the
DC so so far like I haven't even really
used any hacking tools right I mean I
use PS exec and CQ Secrets dumper but
like I'm just using stuff that's built
into Windows because there's a lot of
really bad decisions on how this stuff
has been set up so I made my way all the
way from a workstation that I have no
credentials or access to and I'm sitting
on the DC now so now that I'm in the DC
we want to take active directory right
so we can do that with another Windows
tool we don't have to use any other kind
of hacking stuff for that so what I did
is a wrote a script or
quick just because I don't like typing
in front of people this is it'll go
Honda DC will open up a notepad and
paste our script over here and then
we'll open up a command prompt now in
active directory it's just a database
right so the files that we want are
right here under the NTDs folder and
what I really want is a Santi IDs dip
file of course but because it's a
running domain controller the file is
locked right it's in process because
it's being queried by authentications of
users so just copying the file isn't
really going to going to work for me
plus there's a system file that I need
that has basically the secrets that let
me see the inside of this database so I
need those two files and they're both
locks so what we'll do is we'll just use
volume Shadow Copy because the volume
Shadow Copy lets us copy files that are
locked by a process and it's just built
into windows so if we go over here open
up our command prompt and in here we're
going to go ahead and create ourselves a
directory I actually don't know why I
decided to call it tone instead of tools
this time but whatever and then what
we'll do is use volume Shadow Copy to
create a shadow of the C Drive and later
we'll also do the F Drive where the
other file is but when you do this it
spits out this line that tells me the
name of the partition that it just made
so in this case it's 7 right I've done
this a couple times so so the volume
Shadow Copy number 7 so in my script I
need to change this right here to a 7
when I make the next one it's just
increments so it's going to be 8 so what
i'm doing here is literally just a copy
command I'm literally just copying the
file from the from the Shadow Copy
volume to the C Drive and then I'm going
to remove that volume Shadow Copy just
so I can you know clean up the tracks
and then I'll come over here and do the
other volume as well so because I'll do
copying of at the other file also to the
same folder and clean up the mess so if
we come over to our C Drive in this poem
directory
I have now the NTDs dead end system
files and to exfiltrate that will use
another hack tool windows and create us
a zip file on the desktop and it will
then give me all of the things that I've
been looking for which is all of the
users accounts their password hashes
groups and anything else that I want to
get out of Active Directory and I'll
just come over here and paste it on to
my thumb drive so I just got everything
I wanted right I finally I made it to
the domain I stole Active Directory and
I was in and out now everything I did
super super loud right I was using tools
that leave trails and tracks all over
the place but nobody is looking right so
that's why it works because there's
nothing being done to track and monitor
and alert on it now of course I did put
some things in here to show some alerts
and stuff but if nobody's watching those
alert cues I just went in and out of
there in less than an hour so what can
we do about that well for one well if we
can stop access to the domain controller
that's going to help a lot right if you
can't touch the DC you can't still think
one of the reasons that I showed that
notepad trick is if I can get physical
access to a DC you can boot off of
another media and literally just copy
the two files you need because they're
not going to be in use right so the
whole thing could have been done if the
machine was a DC instead of the laptop
so like branch offices with a DC under
desk or a terrible idea
but we can also use group policy to do
things like prevent access to domain
controllers unless you're a domain admin
or prevent the use of a domain admin
account on machine that's not a domain
controller we can also just restrict
access to the physical machines okay so
in the in the whole tak line that we
went through right we went through and
we stole all this stuff and if we kind
of take a glance back at this to
understand you know what can we do about
it just wanted to put together a slide
they kind of put it all in one so we did
the sticky keys hijack and I have
another demo that actually uses the
phishing macro if you want the deck I
actually
show you a link in that so you can see
that too and then the things that we can
do to stop it right encryption is a big
part of this first step is protecting
the asset from compromise we can also
take the part where we're doing a lot of
the recon and lateral movement stuff
where we're actually doing most in
monitoring and in protection and then
for Active Directory the only one I
showed was NTDs that's it but there's a
lot of other really really fun things
you can do to a domain controller to
actually get access to it and protecting
that comes down to preventing access to
it and Group Policy isolation and things
like device parent of events are in
schools are learning one of the things
that we do with our customers is we try
to align some of the solutions and ways
of solving these problems with the NIST
CSF so sometimes this is goes a long way
to talk with businesses about what you
can do specifically right these
particular things address this column of
activity and the CSF a lot of
organizations need those kinds of
references to to be able to take some
actions and narrow scope of effect and
engagements down and so just another
slide of all the the people that most of
this stuff came from I assume most of
you have heard of or seen these people
before but they have so much more out
there a lot of the things that I went
through I learned from these guys so
very very inspirational I really
appreciate the things that they put out
there and if you want to learn more
check these guys out and if you want the
deck go ahead and shoot me an email with
that subject line it'll automatically
reply it's not going to like a spam list
or something that's literally just
coming to me and I'll reply with the
deck of all the things that you've seen
so far and if you have any questions I'm
happy to answer them now yeah service
counts you know who you think and to
just oh that service account to expire
yeah yeah that comes up on audits and
whether or not your service counts
change that's business partner actually
hands on what must be also yes success
service account if they don't want to
really man
I mean I watch them high-profile we're
setting all service yeah well are you
are asking what you can do about service
accounts that not change so there's
there's a variety of things you can do
one of them using group managed service
accounts so if you're using a group
managed service account they've managed
the servers in the environment manage
the password of service accounts much
like they manage their own passwords so
the more you can use group managed
service accounts the better
I must have glanced glossed over that
part I think I skip this slide or
something but yeah group managed service
account is something that's new for
Server 2012 and 2012 r2 so that you can
use a GMS a instead of what is really
just a user account right so that's one
thing if you can't use a GMS a then
there are products and tools you can use
like psychotic has a tool that will roll
passwords and service accounts for you
psychotic like psychotic but a th and
there's a couple other products like
that too they will actually
programmatically roll and change those
those passwords for you
yeah P but so anyway I hope that you
guys liked it and if you had any
questions or if you have other examples
I would love to hear them because I like
to tell these kinds of stories so thank
you very much and I'll see you later
[Applause]
[Music]