okay so so pre-brief intro of Who I am I
am the CTO of Defense storm we are at
cloud cybersecurity company the sim in
the clouds you send all your events to
us you can alert and search do all that
kind of stuff on them gave a cool talk
last year at mooc on called boss paths
it's kind of a cool phishing attack
against LastPass they got all of your
credentials including your two-factor
stole your so all your all of your data
it was a really really cool phishing
attack and then last year gherkin I did
how to implement crypto poorly I
basically found maybe 20 or so examples
completely hand rolled crypto like not
even using AES or md5 like making up
their own stuff
finding where companies were actually
using it and then kind of my adventure
and trying to get them to not do that
which was not super successful but here
I'm talking about software service today
so software is a service
basically everybody uses software
service nowadays it's basically becoming
the predominant model of software
delivery all these companies help stop
snapchat Gmail Google all these are
different examples of software servers
you don't buy software anymore you buy
the software service you don't run the
computers anymore you buy the whole
thing
it's a huge market it's over a hundred
billion dollars a year in revenue now
and its projected to keep growing this
is an absolutely enormous market from a
value value perspective and security
people need to know you know what to
what to do to test it some motivation
from D DiNozzo V I really like this
tweet in ten years will be three major
operating systems Amazon Web Services
Google compute measure and kind of a
very different way of thinking about
computing right it's what we're no
longer thinking Windows Mac Linux we're
thinking how do I do this on AWS maybe
lambdas or Google's bigquery another bit
of motivation is there was a executive
order I think last week basically
mandating the federal government to move
clouds and cloud gov so even even the
federal government is moving to the
cloud and to kind of
SAP software development with 18f and
that kind of stuff so my gold friends
talk is to explain how SAP software is
made and why that's useful for security
people to know and vice versa if you're
a software person why like what you're
going to be doing wrong this is kind of
a really huge broad topic so this is an
introduction isn't going to be a deep
dive in any particular area because I'm
going specifically for breath over them
okay I like to start my talks to the
conclusion so my conclusion is that
access to a developer's laptop is
basically equal access to everything you
can get access to them you're in if you
have access to the build server you also
have access to everything because now
you can back to where everything filled
that kind of stuff if you have access to
the artifact server well now you can
upload back doored artifacts and still
get you know access everything that says
to the configuration management server
give access everything because you can
control how nodes are provisioned if you
have access to no sequel database you
please give access everything because
now you have all the data or the docker
container configuration or the cloud API
really access to anything is access to
everything this is a really kind of
unfortunate state of affairs so why are
sass companies different why is it not
just exactly the same as every other
company so sass come is a fast iterative
development process they usually take
you know hours to days deploy new
software instead of weeks months or
quarters or years lots lots of
automation developers like to pride
themselves and like oh I didn't have to
click many buttons to get out it was all
that tested and deployed automatic
monitors let me know when it stops
working engineers are very very
empowered usually they have access to
production they like to do lots of stuff
they provision new nodes they do lots of
crazy things they have very powerful
tools to do so
and these new powerful tools well
they're great you know they're also they
can be used by attackers to create great
purposes and this isn't really specific
to SAS companies but there's something
everywhere else is really a lack of
security culture a lot of engineers
don't know of what exactly they need to
do to secure their software sometimes
they'll go to DEFCON and then can take
the wrong impressions away I've seen
that a lot and they don't really
understand the kind of risk benefit
trade-offs
so all those differences also correspond
to weaknesses so the fast iterative
development process really it would need
you need linchpin servers right you need
like you know git server and your
Jenkins server and your chest server you
need all these specific servers that are
very very crucial to your SAS
deployments even though there's lots of
automation there's not usually a lot of
security monitoring really advanced
startup some tasks companies good
security monitoring that's definitely
not the norm really there's no security
strategy you're planning those powerful
tools can be used for evil and there's
really little to no budget for security
maybe they'll get you know great log or
elasticsearch monitoring their logs and
that's it so how does fast companies
work so step one the engineer needs to
write code they're going to take the
products back they're going to write the
code they're going to make it do what
they want to do engineer is going to
commit to code usually to get subversion
they're going to push it somewhere and
the continuous integration jenkins
travis circle CI something is going to
build the code and run the tests even if
you're using python or something them
technically has to be built it's
probably gonna be packaged something and
there something is going to run the
tests there's going to be automatically
deployed to dev which is usually the
name of your development environment
sometimes there's a lot of other
different names so jenkins going to
deploy it to dev and then you might have
a staging or QA environment sometimes
that's automatic based on tests and then
deploying to production is usually
manual although some really advanced
companies like Facebook or something
have that completely automated as long
as it passed all the tests it goes out
but how does how does just this part
work so let's dive in just here for a
second so this is Jenkins I'm sure a lot
of you seen jackets before you can start
up new projects on here get them
building get them tested very easily it
sports basically every programming
language and it's most used by Java
because that's kind of its bread and
butter but you can do anything with
Jenkins so how does Jenkins work build
is triggered either it's polling or a
web hook something like that source code
is downloaded source code compiled tests
are run software's package
and then it's uploaded to the artifact
server so now let's go through some of
these steps so here is an example of how
to like break in if if you're kind of
thinking of a SAS company is a separate
sort of entity we want to run our code
on Jenkins right because I said with a
lynchpin server and if we run our code
in the Jenkins we can backdoor
everything of the build back to
everything that it builds we have access
to basically of dev staging production
we win as attackers one thing I noticed
is that basically anyone can submit pull
requests on public github projects some
people use Jenkins for their public you
know projects so I was wondering if we
submit pull requests will it just run
our code right if I just submitted tests
will it run our code and actually I
found this tweet yes it will so actually
there are people out there that have
that make pull requests that literally
just replace all the tests with Bitcoin
mining code and now they have Jenkins or
whatever running Bitcoin mining code
trying to get you know bitcoins mined
and this works
apparently this works this works on
several different continuous integration
servers and it's usually where it's set
up to automatically build and run tests
the most popular github pull request
builder though has a one caveat in here
it when a new pour request is opened it
will actually post a comment in there
saying can one of the admins verify this
batch right which seems reasonable so
that you could be admin can check and
make sure that all the code hasn't been
replaced by some kind of Bitcoin mining
code right so I was saying about this
because this is you know as an attacker
now I can't add my pick coin mining code
or take over the Jenkins right so I
tried it out this is my pull request and
I noticed that after the difference
between my pull request where I wrote
ABC and where the bots replied can when
they added and verified batch I notice
it was five minutes high medicine really
suspicious to me it seemed like polling
and that's exactly how it works so this
how it works every five minutes it's
going to pull all open pull requests
it's going to find every open one check
to see if either the author's
whitelisted like you know I trust James
or whatever
- right not Bitcoin mining code or if
the pull request is accepted the admin
said yes you should run the test so I am
going to merge this if not post a
comment and if so build the pull request
and run the test so we want to get to
step five right so five is where we want
to get to because we want to run our
test but we don't want to have the admin
looking at our malicious code so how do
we do this we're going to post it an
oculus pull request that requires
running the test maybe we're eFax with
code something right it requires running
tests the bot will post can the admin
verify presumably the admin will say
test this please write because
everything's good but then within five
minutes I have five whole minutes now I
can force push a new malicious commit
this is how you force push you just get
commit amend you overwrite your all the
one you just push you force bullshit and
this is important because if you don't
do this you just add a new commit it
github is going to send a message out to
people saying hey a new commit was added
and you want to avoid this email because
you're trying to trick the admin and if
you do this like like I just did so on
the admin write test this please and
Jenkins ran ran my test here
but what did it run so I actually this
is the thing I force pushed I actually
added you know just the string I'm going
to print out the string hacked like
obviously you could put some more
malicious code in there and on my
drinkin we can see it's building my pull
request right here and it actually ran
my hacked version and the admin had
approved the one without this so because
of this the admin had basically allowed
the running of malicious code and if you
look around this is a very popular pull
request plug-in lots of people use it
and has this kind of inherent race
condition built in so what do you do if
you do get challenging two different
ways you might get shell on Jenkins what
you do so the best thing about this is
you can read or write any file Jenkins
controls it has no segmentations know
like chroot or anything like that it
basically if you get access to Jenkins
you can read and write as a Jenkins user
so what can you do they can take that
XML file is
is a file that controls the
configuration of Jenkins you can add
your own plugins you can do that kind of
stuff the credentials that XML that's a
really fun file that's where all of the
like secret like ooofff tokens for
github or username passwords for
artifactory or something like that will
live you'll you might even have ssh
username and password in there m2 that's
if you're a Java developer that's where
all your libraries are so you can
actually back to our libraries that when
the code is built using done and - all
that stuff is going to be taking them
there secrets is where you get basically
the keys to decrypt the credentials file
and the workspace down there that's
actually where all the code lives if you
want to actually backdoor the code
itself it's all there so if you want a
backdoor jars
this is the way I do it so the victims
out my class this is going to be the
main class for whatever the victim is
this works with like spring boot or
anything in Java and you don't actually
need the actual class you can just
basically make a dummy class that has
that exact signature and all you need is
this class file as you compile it
obviously you're not going to print out
have to do something more interesting
you're going to have a Terp retriever
shell or something cool in there and
it's very easy to add to the jar file so
all you need to do is tell Java that you
have a new main class at my path is
called hack done hacked and what you
need to do is you first need to add the
your jar to sorry your class to the
victim jar that's what the first jar
line does and then you need to add your
manifest file to victim jar and then
once you do that your main file is going
to run before there's and then you're
going to call theirs and then that is
backdoor very very simple very
straightforward way this isn't like
super advanced but it's very effective
it's very easy to do by backdooring
Jenkins it's very easy to setup maven or
something to automatically choose for
you and if you want to decrypt any
Jenkins secrets pretty straightforward
to do you just login to Jenkins flash
script
and it has a script council and all you
need to do is print line Hudson's I
utility courtesy gripped pop in The
Seeker right here and it will spit out
the plain text supporter ever it is you
just take that credential son XML file
and you can just put in various secrets
in there and will just print them out
you know OAuth tokens this way you get
SSH keys artifactory username password
all that stuff in there there's loads
more you can do with this one talk I
really liked was Jonathan Claudius's
talk attacking cloud services source
code has lots of neat ideas and they're
about other things you can do his is
more focused on Ruby but it's basically
applicable to any any language so what
happened to build after it's built
uploaded to an artifact server and
what's the artifact servers basically
just fancy web server that holds
versions of software artifacts version 1
version 2 version 3 usually you can't
delete them or overwrite them which make
sense unless its development version
which going to be continuously updated
your continuous integration is going to
keep uploading to this and your
deployment software whatever that is is
going to download from the artifact
server some examples of this is sono
type nexus chief j frog's art factory or
even a docker registry counts as an
artifact server and all of these the
Nexus and artifactory are Java based but
they support basically any programming
language so if you can upload to the
artifact server maybe you've stolen the
credentials out of the consul's dot xml
you can upload back to our versions of
code directly you don't have to do the
whole maven automatic backdooring
you can just use curl to upload to them
very simple just upload file specify the
path and you have a release there this
is easiest to do on development versions
not tagged versions tagged versions you
can overwrite
so it's all versions can deployment so
after we've committed code built the
code we need to get the code on machines
that are gonna be running usually in the
cloud how do we do this there's two main
ways people do this nowadays some kind
of Linux container like dr. core OS this
is a virtualized OS and the job you know
most people note how it's not the same
thing as the VirtualBox in VMware
different type of virtualization usually
all the dependencies are included since
you have like
see libraries you need or specific Java
version or specific Python libraries all
that will be built into your docker
image and usually your Jenkins will
build the entire image and this is
really nice because your developers can
put on their laptops and run the exact
same things they're running in
production without any problems the
other way I've seen people do it is
configuration management software chef
or puppet ansible salt any of these
things they're actually very very
effective at deploying software to nodes
and production and the other thing
people use is custom scripts batch
scripts downloading things mark factory
putting in particular places so let's
talk about all these so containers I try
to find a list of all the different
containers and technologies and most of
these I didn't know about dr kubernetes
core OS mezzos are can keep adamak Dave
retainer Rancher shipyard there was
about 20 more I didn't have on here it's
crazy it really makes me want to kill
myself and I like containers and all
this stuff I think they're really cool
and there's just so much stuff out there
just happening so fast it's really hard
to keep up with and that that's if
you're somebody who's kind of into this
if you're kind of new to this there's
actually really funny a blog post called
The Illustrated children's guide to
kubernetes it's kind of fun it's a
really good like a little lightweight
introduction to this I like pointing
people to this because I get kick out of
kit imagining kids are eating coding
about them so containers so there's
security trade-offs
one thing about containers is it's
really easy to patch an update
it fits microservices really well which
we'll talk about in a bit it's easy to
automate building and deployment of them
there's actually really really great
tools for building docker images
nowadays and keeping them up to date
building your things into them in
deploying one surprising thing and that
especially a lot of developers don't
know this is that they're not a security
barrier I've actually only met one
developer at a developer conference like
not at a security conference because
itself is like go to security
conferences usually know a little bit
more about security I've only met one of
the developer conference that actually
knew that docker was not a security
barrier so it's really not well known
even though that's a pretty standard
thing the doctor says we'll talk about
that more in a little bit
and the biggest danger is that all these
tools is that they're pretty new so even
as a security person you might not be
aware of the security trade-offs you're
making let's talk about those things so
here's an example
so kubernetes automates deployments and
containers so you might have an SSH
Bastion host right because you want all
of your at Sage to go into one machines
you can check it and do two factor and
log and do all the great stuff you want
to do because you're a security person
and you might not realize that
kubernetes actually can bypass SSH
directly and this is a cool feature it
has you just do coups ETL exec you
specify the pod name or the container
name and you do slash pin match now you
have a bash shell and this actually
tunnels over a 443 to the kubernetes
master and you if you've done all of you
all this work to set up SSH and set up
your logging and to factor all the stuff
so carefully you just didn't realize
that by running kubernetes now there's
kind of a side door into your
architecture and this isn't a bug this
is absolutely a feature it's super
convenient and developers love it but
you have to be you know careful with
this this I got this from a really cool
talk at sector crash course and
kubernetes and security by matt
johansson really interesting if you're
interested in kubernetes
another thing easy dr root shell this
isn't like a super advanced but this is
something that some people don't know
about if the user is in the docker group
they can basically run containers of
that to do and they have access to route
essentially because of how docker works
so this first command is going to start
a docker container they going up one to
image and it's going to map the users
home directory to /h Docs it's going to
copy a bash shell in the docker
container to /h docks which the same
thing as the user's home directory
called slash root shell and then it's
going to set you ID that root shell okay
so then outside of the docker image on
the host it's going to you know we're
looking at the root shell and it's owned
by root on the host and it's at UID so
even though you know in the doctor image
you were root and outside the docker
image you were also root so when you run
that root shell using high speed of
honor set UID you can get a root shell
and this is not a bug this is absolutely
a feature doctor
and they will not fix this and this
trips you go up all the time because
they're like oh you know I have doctor
it's like stay true something I'll run
all my applications is rude this happens
so like Dockers are the cool for
security in some aspects and it has some
kind of pitfalls another one other
things I found was I just decided to
look on showdown for just what I could
find for docker I found a port a nur on
the Internet if you put this kind of
stuff on the internet you've ever owned
yourself because I all these you can
just login to directly from your port
Aynor here I can start stop anything I
want this is obviously a huge problem
and part of the problem with this is
that they don't come built-in with
authentication zall network off that's a
very very common thing with all these
new tools it's like Oh lock it down and
but then people like but I want to
access it from home or my VPN and they
mess it up and they accidentally put it
on the Internet
that's another one this is kubernetes
and actually found the jenkins password
just right away and they were obviously
running jenkins in a doctor i could log
into it directly which I didn't do that
would be illegal but you could do is all
in here in it actually all the docker
images also on the internet which is
that that was weird
usually that doesn't happen but so you
might also see this where people
accidentally put this kind of stuff
directly on the Internet
okay so config management is the other
major wage deploy software and maybe
configure your docker hosts so your
software might depend on ntpd running
and the time being correct maybe a
recent Linux kernel version imagemagick
installed hopefully not maybe you want
to ask the question are all of your
nodes up-to-date like are they all the
current patches they all these specific
packages installed configuration
management answers all of these
questions one thing that I really like
about it is it also gives you a way to
peer review changes to your
infrastructure because all of your
configuration management can be
described in files which would be
checking to get and then somebody can
review your changes which is really nice
so chef is a very popular one it's not
the only one
to what I know best but basically all
these apply to any old concepts apply to
any major figuration management chef is
cool because it treats an infrastructure
is code and you describe what not how so
like basically every programming
language describes how to do something
but chef does it kind of the other way
it says okay well this directory should
exist that op slash application you can
fig that's going to be like fig
directory it's owned by service and this
mode make sure you create it and create
any directories of you know recursively
and what's nice about this is it's ident
so if you keep doing it over and over
and over it doesn't make new directories
as you try to adjust checks at the
directory exists directory is like the
most simple example but you can make
very very complicated resources like
this is my move my entire application
and then you can describe in Ruby code
exactly how that works nice is the
command line tool interacts with chef
chef is very kind of cutesy it has
cookbooks and recipes and knives it's
kind of annoying actually
so in chef's knife RB this is tells you
where the chef server is if you could
access your developers machine this is
going to tell you where their chef
server is and this is their key to talk
to chefs or any both of these you just
put them in that directory knife will
use them and now you can talk to their
chef server so you have access to their
chef server and now you want a list of
every node in every environment this can
be very useful for you used to knife
nodes list it will print out every
single node with helpful names and
descriptions you want to see em install
packages for every machine you just
search the quoted asterisk is basically
just all you can specify environments or
you can segment that up a little bit and
the - a packages tells it I want to see
all the packages I want see which its
come over not in the excursion which
like imagemagick installed a lot kind of
sublet which versions over that cell
kernel version is different you kernel
release and secrets basically this - L
is basically says give me all the
attributes that the every node has and
I'm just going to correct for maybe
password but you can just look through
all of this and find maybe useful bits
of information
you're not supposed to put secrets in
this not a best practice for chef's
developing people do this all the time
when you put passwords secrets in here
so you have selkies and all this from
the chef server you can find even more
data where you're supposed to put things
as difficult data bags so like you
chef's we store our data bit our pub key
search in our data bags and you would
show them like this you can run
arbitrary SSH commands like with salts
or ansible but this isn't going to be
super useful for you because you need SH
off and if you have SSH off as an
attacker usually you have everything you
need already and you don't need to use
chef but this is just kind of for
completeness susceptance usually like
using nice and staged so we went back to
our chefs it's pretty it's pretty simple
the first thing you want to do is you
want to find a recipe the most use
because you want to back to or
everything right you want to get your
stuff everywhere
so all this is going to do is just find
the most common recipe that's used so on
my system zishe was the first which
obviously makes sense because it was the
shell and every machine Walter shell we
also have to do on our machine slack so
we're going to download the cookbook for
zishe and we're just going to add our
backdoor to the default recipe I'll show
you what that backdoor is in a minute
and as soon as we do that all you have
to do is upload it you don't have to do
git commit or anything if you have
access to this you can actually talk to
the chef server directly which is really
nice you don't have to bother leaving
trail of like commit messages or
anything and the backdoor that you know
I wrote for this is just very very
simple it's just it's run this bash
download this F staged script and just
execute it and this is very simple you
could write a really nice one that was I
didn't and all that kind of fun DevOps e
stuff but it's just very simple and then
every single node that wants to install
zishe is now going to run this every
time it run one thing I want to talk
about is micro services because this is
a kind of defining feature of SAS
company
they're really small services that do a
few things they're kind of like a unique
philosophy applied to services so
instead of making a huge program that
does everything you make a tool like cut
switch just cut strings up or something
like that usually they're centered
around some kind of business area like
if you have a to do part of your app you
have a to-do list service right like an
Gmail Gmail it to do a little thing and
that's probably some micro service
somewhere they usually communicate
exclusively via API there's no shared
memory or anything nothing like that
usually it's rest which is over HTTP and
JSON but sometimes you see some kind of
queuing system like RabbitMQ and Dundas
to ask that sort of thing why do we use
them why do developers like them that's
developed in time I don't have to
consider this huge codebase I can
consider a much smaller codebase when
I'm making my changes it's easy to
separate your code logically my codes to
do this has nothing to do with my code
that says email different keep them far
apart it's very easy to monitor and
services can remain partially up during
disruptions this is why you might see
like on Gmail where calendar is not
working but certain aspects of like
maybe Google Drive is working it's very
easy to test and release automatically
much easier to test in relief I'm just
going to change this one small aspect of
my codes of my entire company's entire
code base so if we had a to this
application here's our user it's going
to download the front-end maybe angular
react or something it's going to hit the
off load balancer talk to some kind of
login off service who's going to talk to
its database and then once it's logged
in and hit some login cookie or
something like that it's going to now
talk to the actual micro service to do
to talk to one or more to do services
and it needs to talk to the auth service
to make sure that it's logged in because
now the to do service can't it doesn't
know who's logged in right - that needs
to talk to something else so it talks
about service hey is this a valid cookie
or something then it needs to talk to
suited to date to do database kind of a
tongue twister
to make sure like you know to add new
to-do items it might talk to a queue for
some reason I don't know to do batch
processing and question is might start
asking yourself is like how is this
authenticate how is it service to
services authenticated if their rate
limiting is their input validation and
one thing I like to do is like is there
sequel injection all the way like kind
of the back end there a lot of people do
sequel injection kind of question
response but there's actually a lot of
batch processing a lot of these SAS
applications very very common and sequel
injections actually tend to crop up you
know everywhere and a place if not very
well tested is like after after being in
queue or something I really like to draw
a line here just based on like being a
developer stuff to the left is usually
pretty good we don't mess that up as
quite as much like you know load
balancers we're pretty familiar with we
know how to secure them and everything
but then if you have access anything on
the right-hand side that's where we've
messed up that's where we've cut corners
and everything we have not if you have
access to our to do box we haven't
really considered what that means as a
defender so how do you figure out what
the API is this is this is pretty
straightforward
every nose burp suite you know you're
going to have offset example coms a
login you might have something as
verbose as the to do the service
production example comm and this is very
instructive because now you know that
they embed the environment in their URLs
so it might have dev or staging or QA in
their URLs you can just flip that out
and try to enumerate their different
environments one thing that I like burp
suite does this automatically but a lot
of programmers actually might not know
about it is you can use the web
application description language or the
wisdom this is what it looks like and
like I said burp or something like that
we'll try to find this automatically but
sometimes when I point this out to
developers they don't know that they're
actually advertising every single thing
that your application can do at every
path so in this example this is some XML
to describe to get getting a to-do item
at slash we have to do and in
practice is the ID there could be some
kind of ID its string you can see pram
ID string and then our methods going to
get we're going to return application
JSON this just tells you how to interact
with it but as an attacker this is super
useful information because you know
exactly what you need to put in to do
this and if you try to like fuzz or
something outside of this it's going to
be not as fruitful if you're doing it
within the bounds of this because like
Jersey and that kind of stuff is pretty
well tested and the application code is
use your little less well tested and
usually this is just that slash
application dot wdl
for java but there's also WSDL and
there's tons of these different ones and
those programs programmers don't know
they're there let's talk about some
weaknesses like how is this
authenticated one thing is interactions
between micro-services tend to get
pretty complicated and this is a pretty
good argument against microservices at
some level because if you have ten
different things they're all talking to
each other it can get pretty complicated
both from security perspective and from
just a normal programming perspective
because now you have to say like okay
what happens with service eh talks to B
and then B is down so it's trying to do
this Matt it's pretty complicated
something that I see a lot of people get
wrong it's service the service off so
that means like how does the task
service need to talk to the email
service to link tasks email the most
common unfortunately just network level
off if you can talk to the service
you're allowed in this is super super
common and if you get access to any of
their network you can talk to it as
basically anything you want usually you
know any create read update delete
operations you can do the next most
common is shared key custom off so you
might have everything over HTTP and
you're going to add just some header
like X company off equal to some string
and you're like oh that over HTTP I'm
safe
no no network attacker can get in but
because it's shared key if you had
access to one of them you like to solve
them and it's only really slightly
marginally better next when I see is
passed through credentials actually like
this one it's pretty simple for people
to do and you don't need to do some kind
of complicated thing it's basically you
just act on the
half of user so you are like task
service and you have the cookie and
you're gonna be like I'm going to
pretend to be the user and I'm going to
talk to this back-end
thing you have to you do have to worry
about server-side like redirections and
that kind of stuff you have to make sure
the user can't specify who is talking to
but I like that do the question huh
course yes cross-origin cross-origin
requests this isn't a big deal when
you're talking service to service
because that browser but yeah people do
mess up course quite a bit I see that a
loss where they just allow everything in
and they basically broken their browsers
built-in security it's up at the cloud
real quick cloud what's the cloud
everybody knows the cloud is a nice talk
about with cloud is access keys so one
of the best parts about AWS and Azure is
it as extremely fine grained permission
but ops and dev teams sometimes just
give themselves wide Commission's I'm
the CTO my company I deserve to have
access to everything I'll just give
myself whatever and it's just sitting on
my machine and it gives access to
everything I have it's pretty common
parade of us they usually live in done
AWS credentials using AWS CLI but really
sometimes they're committed to source
control and then reverted because people
forget that get vert is not the same
thing as removing commits it just was an
inverse commit so I'd like to use the
command like this just search for AWS
keys
this one actually there's this is not
the official regex to use for eight of
us keys it's the one I use though they
actually have you just do any uppercase
letter a number but 20 of them I've
never seen one that hasn't started with
a and I get a lot of false positives
when just do that because you know just
20 uppercase letters numbers it's a lot
of things like you know and empty five
hashes that kind of stuff
one of the best parts about the cloud is
logs so here is AWS cloud trail so we
have a bunch of logs here like Andrew at
the bottom stops an instance of an eric
logged into the console and then
you started an infant's very very useful
to have these logs and you gotta put
these in some kind of sim some
monitoring grade logs and like that but
you can disrupt logging obviously the
most brute-force way to do this is just
to delete the whole entire thing this is
like the most loud angry thing you could
do just delete all of the cloud trail
configuration to stop the next thing you
do is just tell it to stop it'll keep
all configuration but it won't continue
logging anymore this one is really
clever if you update the cloud trail
basically to say you instead of acting
globally you act in this one region this
actually restricts tons of API calls
from being logs because the api's are
global for instance like s3 is global
everything interacting with it is global
so there's no region so this stops any
logging associated with that but you get
some logs so if you have a lot you're a
learning system that's like if I don't
have any log send me an email that you
will still get some logs pretty clever
you can also just do things like
removing the bucket which is going to
silently start failing logging because
s3 cloud rousing start storing all the
logs in the bucket there's no bucket
there you can't store the logs this one
made me laugh and s3 lifecycle the rules
of the legal logs after one second which
you're probably not fast enough to get
to get the logs and this was pretty
clever
encrypt the logs the key the company
doesn't have the logs are in f3 they're
there but you can't read them because
the you didn't configure it encrypted
and they just change your kms key and
now it's something else I got all these
ideas for this blog post by Daniel
grizzle AK really clever and there's
tons more here so the lesson here is if
you're a defender you have to look for
every single one of these different ways
your log and can be disrupted but not
only just are you not getting any logs
but like partial degradation and that
kind of stuff
AWS remote access tool it's like how do
you persist your compromised native us
if you've gotten access keys or
something how do you keep it
if AWS is operating system like dang of
geumsan so he was saying
if you just use a user with credentials
those users or credentials are often
audited if you have any company of any
scale one of the main things is that
they all say okay well let's print out a
list of all the users and they're going
to be like who's this person that that
that happens in basically every company
even even pretty minor companies do that
if you start an easy-to instance and
just you know use that that cost some
money so what you do so I think lambdas
are the best tool here if you don't know
what a lambda is basically it's server
lives computing which some people kind
of get missed by because it's like well
there is a server there it's just you're
not running it so you upload code you
don't run Linux any more users upload
code here's my code run the code when
API is hit it's kind of at the moment
it's underutilized some kind of people
are trying to build entire business
around it but it's not super common yet
the most important things it's freakier
eligible so it does not if you use a
very small amount of it it does not cost
the company money it will not show up on
their billing report so when the CFO is
looking at it he doesn't see what is
this lambda thing and then since the
developer also look at it you can assign
a role to the lambda and roles are nice
because they don't have access keys you
just say this lambda can do this it can
upload things to be a three bucket or
something like that and roles are less
often audited than users right because
roles are a means to an end and not
you're never gonna look login with a
role to that machine and the last thing
we're going to do is we're in deploy in
a region that they don't use AWS has
like 20 regions if you ever use AWS the
way to look through different regions is
to go into the upright click the region
thing and then manually switch your
region to looking for for instance if
you want to look for this remote access
tool in your account via the VD UI you
would have to first go in your region
click and then go to the next one you
click and for the next one click and
you'd have to do that 20 times via API
you do that pretty pretty quickly but if
you don't know to do that you wouldn't
be doing code demo code coming soon
I'll nearly done with it you can issue
commands remotely which is cool it
messes blog via the
helped the update cloud trail one where
it disables global logging just during
its own operation and because it
disables multi-region stuff and it's
deployed in the region that you are not
in it tends not to have any logs
associated with it and so the price for
using it is basically don't cost the
company money the thing that companies
pay attention to the most is their
spending and usually CFOs asking a lot
of questions exactly why did our s3
usage go up that kind of stuff and you
get research which events are generated
this is still kind of a new field
advanced for blue team you got a
restricted direct developer access which
engineers tend to bristle at a little
bit but you can sell it to them by
telling them actually we're going to
automate everything instead of you
logging in and typing on servers is a
bad idea we're going to automate
everything and tell person to get behind
that and even if you're taking access
away from them they tend to like it
because they like automation continuous
integration despite the kind of cool
thing we did earlier is actually a great
boon to security because you're
constantly testing your software and you
can include in your steps like an s2
scan or code hinting that kind of stuff
peer review is really really great peer
reviewing 100% your codes and I highly
recommend choosing your NewTek carefully
a lot of people get tripped up by new
tools these new DevOps tools there's
actually some people we're talking on
flak about this kind of nice key secret
sharing program called vault but the way
vault works is when you add your secrets
to it you have to specify them on the
command line you have to say and just
evolved and my secret password on the
command line and well it's writing on
the command line it goes in your bash
history and you have access to your
machine now you have access to all of
that even though you don't have the
secret vault password so after your bash
history contains a complete plaintext of
everything in the vault and they
specifically say we're not going to fix
that that is outside the scope of our
project six six bash which is crazy
but you know as a security person the
company you have to be like okay well
how are my developers using vault or
all of these tools it's daunting then
obviously of the extra self what
happened this is compromised
so like linchpin servers what happens is
my continuous integration servers
compromised how do how do we do that how
we protect against that your chef server
the artifact server your bastion hose
and these are these are very very
challenging somebody gets access to your
chef server I don't have a lot of super
great advice but that planning that out
is that is better than nothing
so yeah how do you how do you detect
that that's a key thing there cloud
specific don't use root account use
roles not access keys access key you
basically don't have to use anymore
unless you're using band line tools
recommend moving away from that roles
are great so if you are deploying
anything into AWS or Google two are the
same thing as your has a very similar
thing you can just give that ec2
instance a role which lets it do things
because then access keep can't be stolen
obviously used to if they always watch
it alert on your logs all of the
including all the disrupting ones and
segments your network using groups this
is something that ops people tend to be
like to want to do they want to make a
software-defined network that is cool
the database only allowed to talk to
this no something like that and you know
you're I am regularly make sure that
there's no back to work user and they're
what to alert on obviously new access
keys just like any system new provision
users roles and groups which is pretty
uncommon new instances we we alerted on
this but it's super noisy I don't know
exactly what to do to make this less
noisy we start up at least ten a day and
we shut it went down I don't really have
any great ideas for this because
attackers would do this but we do this
too so anybody is any really good ideas
for that I've been thinking about trying
to like model like what types we use
what availability zones but obviously
stuff like suspicious console log in and
disruption of logging all the different
ones we talked about there's tons
there's tons more here and it's really
not a great list of best practices yet
for what to alert on like
from Google computer as your AWS and I'd
love to say bring any resources about
that that's it
any questions yes it's it's it's very
similar
well basically Google compute and as
you're an AWS for the stuff I was
talking about are basically comparable
they they all have the idea of roles and
access keys and obviously wanna protect
your expertise not use them use roles
all the support to si and that kind of
stuff all of them have a similar type
logging thing although I'm most familiar
with AWS which is why it talks about
here yep yeah till to lock down any of
us yeah so the question was are there
any open source tools or anything to
lock down and secure a tip us there's a
few for-profit companies to do that
which you know because a lot of money
there are a few able us has something
called trusted advisor built-in it's not
great and they actually charge you a bit
of money for it and it basically says oh
you don't have to eff a setup which is
mildly useful there are a few I'm
blanking on the name of one of them but
the problem is that and why there's
for-profit companies that do this rather
than open source is it's a ton of work
to figure out all of the different
possible use cases for AWS and to
recommend secure configuration and that
there was one project but I'm blanking
on the name of that exact project right
now but it is kind of it's very nascent
it's it's very early in this whole thing
so I don't know if anybody happens to
know great
yes so it's good yeah
cloud checker what was that one dome 9
there's a few for-profit companies like
evident io and there's a ton of them out
there to do this yep cool any other
questions
alright thanks everybody
[Applause]