oh alright does everyone else ready I'm
ready
it goes good alright so this talk is
going past the wire leveraging social
engineering and physical security
assessments just to kind of get a quick
survey of the room raise your hands with
your blue team okay couple red team
raise your hand all right cool so my
goal here is if your blue team you kind
of see some tips and things that I do
when I'm going out performing these
assessments and hopefully can going to
give you some ideas of things to look
out for excuse me
if your red team maybe get understanding
some things I do that if you're not
doing you can incorporate or kind of
just see the way someone else does it so
just a quick about me slide my name is
Stephanie and I also go by snow I'm from
Salt Lake City Utah and I've lived there
for about three years now
I won the black badge for the social
engineering capture-the-flag at DEFCON a
few years ago and in my free time I like
to do special effects makeup and go to
theme parks and play booking my company
is snow offensive we primarily focus on
offensive security services physical
security is one of the big ones that
we're doing right now I actually have JC
in the back he's one of Mya my team
members he just did three physical
security assessments in three different
countries in the last two weeks so he
yeah he's been busy he got in at 4 a.m.
so he's still awake which is
surprisingly good but yeah we focus a
lot on physical security so this talk I
chose to do this talk kind of out of a
pet peeve when I started talking to
other pen testers I noticed that when
they say they do physical security
assessment what they're doing is they're
going out getting on-site and plugging
in a box to network and leaving that's
it
they're not testing the actual physical
security of the building they're not
testing the employees and really what
the client is left with
at the end of the day is a pen test
report if that's what you want I could
ship you a laptop and do everything
remotely so I really think physical
security should be focused on the
building and the employees all right so
for the agenda I'm going to be going
over OSINT so you might hear it called
Ostend OSI it's open source intelligence
it's going out finding things online
through open sources like Google social
media even things like blogs and forum
may be talking about pretext development
things that you should keep in mind
recon so actually going out before you
perform the assessment and what to look
for the actual attacks I do when I'm on
site and then wrap it up with training
so I'm doing open source intelligence
I'm typically looking at three domains
I'm looking for employees the reason why
I'm doing that is because it's who I
want to impersonate so I want to make
sure I blend into the environment I want
to see their trappings and what I mean
by that is their dress code if they have
badges do they all wear them at the hip
on a clip do they wear it off a lanyard
if they have lanyards does everyone
bring their own in or is it a company
lanyard anything like that that really
gives us much detail so I don't stand
out I blend in well I look at the
company location I try to see if they
have access control systems in place
let's see if they've guards cameras
nearby restaurants which I'm going to
give the story's about floor plans and
also my calendar and then if I'm not
pretending to be an employee and
typically pretending to be a vendor so
just like employees I'm trying to see
what specific vendors they're using if I
can get the names of the company maybe
contact names do they have uniforms do
they wear badges try to make things like
business cards anything that makes me
look legit
so social media is typically the first
stop I do when I'm doing open Facebook
is one of them a lot of people don't
know this but you can actually put
queries into Facebook so one of the ones
I use a lot is people who work at my
target company and I'll pull up a list
of everyone who says they work for this
company I like to focus on new people
and in turn typically because they
haven't had the best training they're
the ones that are most likely to put out
company sensitive or information online
so let's take this girl for an example
so the first couple pictures she posted
to her Facebook account the first
picture of trappings you kind of see
what everyone's wearing I know how I
would want to blend into the environment
the second one more my favorite picture
she put out there it's actually a shot
looking into the building this is really
cool because if I were to show up of the
building I know exactly what it looks
like I don't have to walk and kind of
look around it makes me stand out I'll
know okay I'm probably go ahead up right
those stairs I'm not going to you know
look for any building Maps anything like
that in the first picture she tagged a
handful of people that we're in the
picture so I kind of used that and I
went to look through their pictures
where I found the next two ones and it's
really cool to see in this one in the
RFID one you can see the thick hid
clamshell badges in you but the other
one you see another badge a picture
badge so it's important to know that
some companies will have two different
style badges so the more information you
can find during the ascent the better a
lot of companies have anti tailgating
policies which are really cool but it's
dependent on two things the first thing
is that the employees actually follow
this procedure they actually will check
the badge behind them like the one here
on Google and then the second thing is
they will actually inspect the badge
does anyone here work at Google no one
does anybody know what's cool about this
Google badge no one this whole badge is
actually a hologram the whole thing so
that's something you can't really
hell during osa it might just look like
a crappy badge but it's really special
and that's something you can't find
during oh soon something you have to see
in sight so excuse me so it's really
important to pay attention things like
that I have a client who was based out
of downtown LA and I was performing a
physical security assessment for them
and during the opening phase I found a
lot of employees who had badges online
which is perfect for me I use my badge
printer made out a copy look legit
shut up on site everyone the badges were
they wore them at the hip we're all
turned around so you could just see the
white which was really odd to me but I
just turned mine around so you could see
the light back of the badge and it
worked fine and so later I asked my
clients you know why why is that bad
this turn around he explained that he
knew that they had a lot of employees
posting pictures on social media and
instead of telling the employees not to
do that or have some kind of policy he
just told them to all turn it around
which made my job a lot easier because I
just needed a white badge and I was in
all right for claims are really cool so
if the target company is like a shared
building multi-tenant a lot of times if
different floors in the building are for
rent they might be on loosen it and this
is something I use a lot and as an
example of it so they'll have actual
floor plans it is important to know that
only the structure of the poor planners
legit so things like the elevator shafts
and the stairway stairway well and the
bathrooms are going to be there but
different clients can come in and
remodel add walls add building or at a
cubicle things like that but knowing
once I get off the elevator if I go left
there's a bathroom right there that can
help me especially someone's kind of
suspicious right there I could just duck
into the bathroom really fast they also
have descriptions which is really
helpful so I know that this building had
24 by 7 security they had cameras and
card key entry system
not only that they also said who else
was in the building so if I wanted to
show up on site and maybe ask the
receptionist to print off my resume I
can just say I'm having an interview
with one of these other companies and it
looks like I should be there and I know
who's in the building some companies
have calendars online whether it's like
this one for example with the hospital
so they'll have things where people can
sign up and take different trainings
different classes things like that or
they might have internal calendars so
hot dog Tuesday's or whatever seems like
this is really helpful for hospitals
that they have a diabetes class on
Tuesday at 7:00 and so I just signed up
for it online told them I was there
because okay go to second floor nobody
lost me there nobody cared they just let
me go and I was free to get past
security and really have access to
everything all this 74 watering holes so
cool thing on Google you could type in
your target address and you hit nearby
and it gives you a list of different
restaurant excuse me
Saturday nearby I like to go to these
different places for a handful of
reasons I like to do it during recon to
try to capture cards with my badge
cloner
and the second reason is I like to
overhear small talk so I can hear you
know current office drama one time I
heard that the CSO was at a conference
so I was able to use that my to my
advantage go to the receptionist explain
that hey I know
vod's out of town I just need to leave
these documents on a desk
she knew I knew Bob and that he was out
of town and she let me in so really just
trying to hear as much information over
small talk alright I have a video now we
don't have sound it's a minute and 30
second clip so I'm going to ask you guys
what you see afterwards on this video
Oh
[Music]
Thank You Microsoft so this is one of
the things like to look on YouTube for
HR recruiting clip life of interns so
question for you guys just y'all amount
what were some of the things that you
saw in that video sorry
dress code badges sorry a lot of windows
yeah anything else yeah that's it stump
look I got at all yeah standardized
system yep everyone has seen devices so
I pulled out some stills from the video
so I'm going to go over what I found
close-up of the badge very clear very
easy to replicate you see that she is
using a company lanyard but throughout
the video you see that's not always the
case but again close up of the badge
that's not going to be hard to
impersonate someone else mention this
one axis control system at the front
what do you guys see in this one
reception yet you get a view into the
front there's also a camera anything
different about this one kinda hard to
see his badge off pants not only that
it's a different color so that's
important to note depending on who
you're impersonating if you're
impersonating an employee to know what
the different colors mean this one's
just kind of fun you know they have a
KVM rather than a crash cart - nice easy
access otherwise it's one crack me up
there a window shop but they're using
Chrome kind of funny but yeah you get a
look into what they're using their
calendars all that
stuff so again going back to YouTube
lots of information you can find
typically though it's more for bigger
businesses small medium businesses you
won't see as many recruiting videos or
intern videos but you can get a lot of
information just like employees I try to
find vendors here's are just a quick
google dork that I use when I'm looking
for vendors once actually find them I
see what their dress code are sometimes
they'll have things like if they work
certain hours the more information the
better idea can do to impersonate them
alright pretexting pretext is who you're
pretending to be when you go on site
it's your backstory it's why you're
there really what you're going after
some more work you put into your pretext
typically the more confident you'll feel
so the biggest thing with great X do not
impersonate law enforcement doctors or
lawyers totally illegal do not do it
some states have different laws about
people you can and can't impersonate if
you're kind of in a hurry situation
contact a lawyer from that state just to
be sure but those are very important to
know
scope of addiction sometimes we will
have clients who say ok you could be
anyone external vendors non vendors
whoever not but you just can't be
pretend to be anyone internal so working
out stuff like that ahead of time with
your client just to make sure everyone's
on the same page and actually document
your pre tech proud pretext reuse I'm
going to get into a story about that
next about how it burned me in the past
and then appearance once you figure out
who you want to be make sure you look
legit you know what to wear
transportation a janitor is not going to
show up in a car service I mean if
you're pretending to be someone high up
in the company shirt if you're
pretending to be some type of a janitor
company or someone like that
send the extra money and get a really
cool decal or even a magnet one go out
and write to you all then and you look
so much more legit badges and business
cards
even if you can't find the online most
of times people don't know their vendors
business card but that adds so much more
credibility if you have things like that
clipboard and documents I'll get into
with the story as well but a clipboard
is one of my favorite things to have it
just adds so much more credibility to
wire there people think we've cooked if
you have a clipboard you know you're
doing you're writing things down I don't
know why but it's worked very well for
me using so this kind of story is
twofold the first one is pretext reused
I had a client based out of the Midwest
and they had 16 locations they wanted me
to go to in like 14 days so it was a lot
but this client also limited my pretext
to only one thing I had the same story
for every location we went to it worked
amazing for the first 5 location we're
on the fifth one you could tell she was
kind of suspicious like this doesn't
really make sense and I haven't verified
who you are while you're here but she
still gave me everything I asked for but
she called ahead to the sixth location
and kind of said hey this person is
coming on site I don't know if it's
legit you might want to check out before
you probably let her on site because you
know you're you're next on her list so
as they're talking in this group calling
her IT manager trying to verify who I am
and if I should be there I show up on
site she asked me just to take a seat in
the lobby and so I did ten minutes later
her into place officers come around the
corner I don't even have the chance to
blame myself for who I was
so that's how password reuse can burn
you but the other thing with that is I
had a get out of jail free card right I
the one page thing I should be there and
points of contacts the points were kind
of confused one cop thought it was
awesome he's like there's no way you do
this for a living
the other ones like yeah you're full of
shit so the one who didn't believe me
you know he's looking over this letter
like this is stupid like I don't
understand this he didn't read it all so
that's why I am a big believer that you
get out jail free
argh it should say in monopoly like most
the time people don't understand it so
now what I do is actually carry the
whole scope or start that statement of
work and to make sure that the scope has
everything laid out very clear that way
it's easier for people to understand so
past three years of bed and get out jail
free card doesn't always work with
pretexting it's important to be flexible
I know building a really good pretext I
mean coughing is awesome but sometimes
things don't always go to plan I had a
client who had just built their European
headquarters in Amsterdam and I went out
there to test their new facility and
when I got on site I was really cocky I
was I was going to have my pretext ready
I was just kind of doing recon really
fast like oh can we get in do my goals
get out I get there and everything I
wanted to do for my paycheck didn't make
sense
it was a pain in the butt they had so
much more security than I thought they
did so I had to kind of go back to my
hotel and reevaluate everything I knew
the pretext I was going to use there was
no way it was going to work so I ended
up changing it to I said that I was from
there America location and that was an
investment investment relations manager
and I was explaining how there are new
potential investors in the area they
wanted to do meeting at the location
kind of get a feel for the location ask
them question but before I had people
come out I wanted to go and be familiar
with the location so knowing that money
was on the line of course they lent me
and they gave me a tour of the location
I went on to say these ancestors have
been burned in the past and they want to
make sure that the physical security of
the building was good so what's your
issues he showed me all the issues how
he currently had and how he plans on
changing it which is able to use to my
advantage and get in later that night
but it was password or pretext it's
important to to be flexible it's good to
have a really good concrete prefix but
sometimes they don't work out depending
on the situation
all right reconnaissance it is very
helpful when you can't find a lot of
information during ascent and sometimes
it's important to do a full day of recon
I like to do in the daytime when
everyone's there and also at night time
when people are gone should to kind of
get a well observation of the
environment when during recon I
typically look in three areas the first
one is the perimeter I'll do a walk
around see if I can find things like
different entrances
is there an employee entrance only that
maybe badge protected that could still
be open 24/7 or is there just like
public entrances that have certain
building operating time because if I
know that building closes at 8:00 I want
to try to sneak in at 7:55 and hide
somewhere until the doors actually lock
so leave them inside I look for things
like access control systems loading dock
and it's really beneficial for actually
getting a delivery a lot of times they
leave that unlock and I'm able to flip
right in depending on the client in the
building sometimes I'm able to do
interior recon something like a hospital
where you can just go in and out if it's
like a suite in a really big building
it's going to be a lot harder to do that
but if you can't do interior and
interior recon like fun to do and then
nearby cafes during Austin I try to make
a list of the ones I want to visit in
all actually go visit them bring my
badge reader try to capture cards and
listen to small talk excuse me yes yeah
oh I'm good things so attack risk chart
so now I'm going to be going into the
things actually doing I'm on site so I
talked about Oh sant pretext and recon
so these are things coming up then they
actually do when I go on side I try to
label everything low medium high low of
something if I get caught I can talk my
way out of or just walk away from medium
is kind of risky maybe I'm asking
employee something and they're getting
suspicious
high is like if I get caught my cover's
blown but something like picking a lock
in some a box and I'm just standing
there right so that's why I break
everything out
tailgating a piggybacking does anyone
know the difference difference between
tailgating piggybacking no there's a
difference a lot of people don't know
that they use the term interchangeably
yep so tailgating is or piggybacking is
they yeah they're aware right so there
is a difference in just really fun to
see a lot of people just use both terms
and don't know that there is a
difference so this is something that I
do when I'm on site I actually had a
client who knew that I was flying her I
was piggybacking her right and you could
tell she was suspicious but she didn't
know what to say and that's a benefit of
social engineering people are so nice
they're so friendly and even if they are
suspicious like they don't know how to
stop you or correct you like they don't
know what words to say so she saw me she
let me and just kind of look but didn't
same thing so I went and I did my first
pass got through handful of gold when I
came back later in the day I was talking
to the receptionist having her open up
the USB for me and right behind I saw a
glass door to the conference center so
lady that saw me with suspicious was
saying they're talking with security
giving them a full description of me as
I'm standing right there like 20 feet
away from them so I got out as fast as I
could but but again people are
suspicious and they don't always know to
say anything document management
something I do this is more of when set
is an in scope so I'll look for
sensitive documents maybe PII my clients
patients or clients information and
alternative pictures of them a lot of
times we were body cams but still
sometimes having a clean shot clear shot
is helpful and then these are the places
I look for them excuse me
a lot of times people are lazing they
leave things on printers so it's pretty
cool to kind of scour that area and see
what you can find
yeah the other pay rains yeah that's a
good one
my favorite is when shred phones are on
wheels so JC and I were doing a physical
a handful months back and it was really
convenient cause it's on live I just
dragged it into one of the offices he
was able to pick the lock I just locked
the door and blem do sing well I did
other things so just kind of convenient
elicitation which is talking to people
trying to get information out of them I
try to either get information from them
verbally or ask them to perform a task
for me so the favorite thing is can you
please open up my UC and print a file
whether it's directions or resume
something like that and then I will ask
them Kurt actually asked some things
about their physical building or company
sensitive information and kind of going
into that I do a lot of physical penta
or a physical security assessment at
hospitals my favorite prey text as I'm a
HIPAA no one wants to tell apart or know
where to go away like they want to give
you everything you asked for
so when I do this I have my badge my
business cards is Who I am pertaining to
be I have my clipboard I actually have a
legit form with real HIPAA questions
seemed like I felt a physical scary
where our cameras in place things like
that so I actually don't have to go look
around I'm asking people okay where do
you keep your Eph I if you have to
destroy it what do you do one of the
times I ask them if you have to destroy
it what you do she's like oh we just
take it down to IT tricks your hard
drive on it she's like yeah I actually
have to go take this down oh let me hope
that helped you with that so I got a
whole a whole thing but again having
forms having questions
this is excellent pretext if you're
working with a hospital
RFID cloning this is something that we
use a lot excuse me
we use Proxmire or Fiddler's and then
they also use out now if anyone's
familiar with Bishop Fox tastic anyone
good handful of you so we we have
something very similar we have it some
really cool upgrades
we have a Bluetooth module which I think
their new one might have but but it's
really cool because the second we
capture card it goes right to our phone
we get we get to see it so it's really
instant feedback another cool thing is
we added a vibration motor from like an
old cell phone so when I take up carts
to kind of get just the buzz so no we
got it
excuse me um tips for this get as many
cards as you can during recon capture as
many so you could write as many try them
later it's different people have
different levels of access so maybe you
might be able to get in through the
front door with a standard code some
employees still can't get further into
the building so having as many options
is important and then if you have these
cards make sure you keep them away from
your reader or you'll be like me walking
down the hall no way around and
wondering why my Kriegers going off
because it's reading my card
but yeah RFID cloning is something big
that we do Laughton that really helps us
get further on site
you must be dropped where do you not put
USBs
are you doing USB Drive anyone I heard
something no parking lot everyone that
says that you do USB drop save they put
them in parking lot set it's such a bad
mistake what if your clients patients or
their clients give it our land scope
know so it's important to put them at
places that employees only are at so I
like to leave them like actually on
someone's desk if I will bring like
white envelopes and if I'm walking by an
office I'll see the name on the office
I'll write their name on it and I'm
naming it something really fun that
people want to see I think Hayden
mentioned something about payroll but if
you name the file on the USB something
juicy like this like everyone's going to
want to do that oh well my do are USC's
we have a file that looks like a PDF
that's really executable and it just
calls in and checks into our server so
it's proof that they're opening it right
when they open it they get this error so
they're like oh it's not working
try another computer so it's really fun
to see the same USB go from computer the
computer like people trying to open it
and once they do open it we get this
really cool feedback every time just
kind of showing us it was open what a
specific POC opened all I could stuff
all right Network port security ID all
kind of talked about the beginning how a
lot of companies like to just go in to
plug in a box and leave I'm not saying
not do that I'm just saying it shouldn't
be the focus of your test you still
should try to see if you can gain
network access right so when I do that I
just do like a quick networks piece we
just can't use me and a lot of times I
get away with it in conference rooms so
have computers or even their phone lines
things where I can just get onto the
network with a lot of people don't lock
their conference room doors so that's my
favorite place to get onto the network
non-destructive entry I'm not gonna
spend a lot of time here just because
there's a lot of cool videos TV actually
recently did one for a sans webcast I
believe it was talking about lots of
cool stuff but these are all things I
typically have in my bag I do have
clients that don't want me to use non
struck the venturi just because they're
scared that it's going to break but I
always have a some picks on me some shin
airbag is really fun some latch tool I
don't know if anybody seen those but
those are really cool to crash bar under
the door tool drive what mm-hmm
but doing um webcasts actually has
nothing videos of him using them so I
don't like to pick locks on site but I
will the biggest reason is my very first
physical deck that's all I thought
people do is just going to pick every
lock they can find and of course I got
caught because I was a dumbass and I
learned my lesson but it's the only time
I pick locks is if the risk is worth it
so when I was at a hospital they had a
couple of conference rooms like in our
basement and one of the signs on the
basement conference room door said
financial audit in progress please do
not touch papers
and you look in their New Jersey papers
and I wanted this paper so bad so nobody
was around so in that moment it made
sense to pick the lock and to get in and
get all those papers which are really
cool all right Seth is my absolute
favorite thing to do during physical
this is the most tangible thing that you
can get I like to take laptops that's
probably one of my favorites a lot of
times people don't secure them to their
to their desk phones files building keys
and if you take badges that's pretty
cool too because you all have to
actually do the work to clone them you
actually have a badge but it's very
important to know not leave the building
with this stuff the last thing you want
to do is to leave a bunch of your
clients laptops in your car for some
reason your car gets jacked right that's
not good so before I even go on site I
work out with my client a drop-off
location so if I do take stuff where
does he want me to leave them at his
site so I'm not taking them with me
after-hours access um it's important to
go in thank you I have kids does anyone
see the lego movie yeah you got ready
button everything it's important to test
in a daytime and the nighttime just
because you know you're testing a
different group of people some buildings
they just won't have any people at night
so you want to make sure they're
security guards are paying attention so
I like to go back at night well is too
and then if I do get on my Uganda gotta
be more careful because Cara's not Kim
whereas Madhuri and whatnot but but
again I'll do my same goals I do in the
daytime I just try to do them at night
all right going into my risk chart so I
typically do at least five visits when
I'm doing a physical security assessment
the first two are recon so I'll go in
the daytime and I'll go in the evening
and then when I do my other three visits
that's what I'm actually trying to do my
tax so it seems that I just went over
I'll start with my lows because I don't
want to get caught right away so I'll
try to tailgate piggyback
see what information is going around
document intimate and I'll drop us these
around so those are all things if I get
caught doing that I can talk my way out
of I'm not too worried
medium is my next visit so I'll try to
actually get onto the network talk to
employees get information from them and
actually print out the badge and you try
to use the badge to gain entry and then
my last visit is I'm doing the risky
stuff so if I get caught doing the stuff
my cover's blown it doesn't make sense
to start with the high because then you
can't go back later and then another
important thing to note is this is kind
of talking to one person going out and
doing the physical security assessment
we try to have at least two that way if
someone's covered does get blown we have
a backup person so we can kind of keep
assessing the situation if for some
reason we do have one person on site
like JC was one person in the last
couple we do have comms we use you know
once he goes under those recliners I can
leave me to do recon the kind of trick
thing gives us an overview and tells us
went back that way we know where
everyone is at all time and on some tips
and trick bathrooms are your friends so
I was able to get on-site at one of my
client locations right before they
closed and there's only a handful of
employees left but I wanted them all to
leave because I was trying to get into a
specific office and I know there's some
employees surrounding it so I just went
and hung out in the bathroom for like 45
minutes which kind of got boring but I
just go on Twitter she posted but it
worked once everyone left there was no
one around all I had to do is hang out
for a little bit right so bathrooms are
your friend I kind of talked about this
a little bit get out of jail free card
again should stay in the Napoles it's
gimmicky it's corny it's not going to
work I don't know if you guys have ever
heard of another of other security
companies saying they do the fake
Gentile jail free card cuz anyone heard
that so I've heard of consultants
actually making a fake one and like
putting out like Oh
Poynter contacts our fake name to
actually test I think it caught test the
security guard to see if they're going
to calm verify which kind of sounds cool
until they call and they're like I don't
know who this person is or this doesn't
make sense
oh no no here's the real one why are
they going to trust you now you're just
burning their trust and it doesn't make
sense
so what we like to do is we just print
out the whole statement of work and we
make sure in the statement of work the
scope is very specific it lists out
everything we're going to do if we're
going to do after-hours access you want
to put that down the last thing you want
is show up at like midnight and give a
security guard a heart attack but that's
not in scope right that you're going to
be there during those hour so the more
detail in that document and if you do
get caught they know exactly what you're
doing it makes more sense out of order
so we have a bunch of outer order signs
that we just print out and keep with us
whenever we go on-site and we'll bring
in like fake like trash bin put them
right next to a shredder and tape out of
order right over there shredder so a lot
of times they'll put their important
documents and that and we can go and
collect the only go back at night that's
pretty fun bill coffee so we have a
handful of fake resumes to that we keep
and we spill coffee and make it look
dirty so when we go to the reception set
we explain we have an interview and we
actually have the coffee so or the the
resume well that looks all dirty so hey
I just need your fresh copy of my resume
do you mind printing it out and they
always say yeah they always feel bad for
you they want to help all right
so that's kind of all the attacks and
some tips and tricks kind of going into
training teachable moments is one of my
favorite ways to train employees against
a physical attack but what its kind of
tricky because if you are doing multiple
sites and and you run into a point in a
situation you can't say it right away
you kind of have to wait and go back but
that makes sense you don't want to kind
of blow your cover so what I like to do
is I like to do my assessment and I'll
go back the next day and find those
employees and talk with
so that is one of the biggest ways
people learn and then on-site security
awareness training
I am completely against computer-based
training say it's so boring it's
distracting nobody pays attention half
the time it's like a cartoon on YouTube
and they're not relevant so what we like
to do is actually have security
awareness training done on-site so we'll
do all of our assessments and we like to
wrap them into the tree
so not just like watch out for
tailgaters no here's a video of your
actual building and us tailgating in it
makes it much more realistic and opens
their eyes a lot more all right and then
recap so we talk about different things
that I look for before I go on-site
pretty text development about vendors
excuse me
making sure you have the dress code you
feel confident custard or protectress
isn't always necessarily good recon the
different areas I like to do recon on
what I look for and then the handful of
texts again not just going out and
plugging in something to network and
leaving and saying he did a physical pen
test that's I mean you're just going to
be left with the pen test report that's
not physical security assessment and
then wrapping it off with training and
sorry guys I talk fast and I have a cost
so it's a really bad combination but I
really appreciate you guys being here if
you would like a copy of my slide deck
please feel free to email me my contact
informations up here but thank you guys
for coming I appreciate it I think I
have time for some questions I also have
some business cards up here as well but
if anyone has questions yes
chances question was if I go in like for
example after hours and I get burned and
the security guard catches me do I
continue with the test or do I kind of
stop after he verifies me that's your
question right it kind of depends on the
client sometimes I'll have clients say
once you get caught stop you're done if
they don't really say and he does catch
me that definitely goes in my report you
know this person caught me at this time
and I'll still try to continue on and
I'll just document at that point we'll
be more of if I don't get caught here's
what I would find but a lot of that goes
into prior scoping with the client so
that's a good question thank you yep yep
right great question so the question was
with statements written scoping how do I
worked out ahead of time with clients to
make sure it all goes into that document
before we even send over the statement
of work we have questionnaires that we
build out so I'll have every sir every
attack that we can do in a description
and then I'll have the client check yes
I want that or no I don't so what I take
that information that's kind of what
builds our scope or our rules of
engagement does answer your question
would that's true yeah no that does and
we'll have like places like if there is
off limit areas or or if it's the whole
building in general but if we get more
into red teaming then we'll have you
know a bigger broader scope but it's not
specific so it kind of lets us have a
lot more wiggle room any other question
yes
that's hard the question was how do you
justify to a client if you get caught
continue testing pretty much I'm out
there I'm spending my time I mean if
they want to see what other information
I can find then it makes sense for them
just just from a
in point of view right just what else
could I do yep exactly
and I have had I have had clients that
if I get burned they'll say okay well or
what was this or if I did get burned
they'll let us come out and do it again
with another person but but yeah
justifying it it's hard and depends on
the client - yes is there any advantage
the security staffing though I would say
no as little people can know about this
the better because that makes it more
realistic really other than my point of
contact I would love it if nobody knew
about it that way they're getting real
responses and you can kind of see who
talks to who and see what their
communication flow any other question
all right cool good thank you so much
for coming I appreciate it
[Applause]