okay saw what happens is this is a
two-step process first we measure the
blank
and we can store the profile for later
replication in a database
in the computer and Dan we can tell it
to me all the blank there's about five
different
size is a blanks to basically do any key
and Saul a little milling head comes out
and it laterally Mills the blank arm
most profiles can be copied and lesser
square-cut profiles as shown on the
right hand side
it won't do squares and it won't do
protrusions
now the cool thing about this machine is
bad it already you can take a change key
now think about this in the master key
environment when you can't get the
blanks this is the problem with this
machine
if you have access to the machine and
you have access to a change key
but not a blankie this machine will
replicate the change key and change it
into a blank key so you have no
access problems for the blank keys this
is why this home after king issue has
become so critical
and again here's what the blanks look
like
and here's what the cut keys look like
and what it does is it actually samples
and approximates the words in the lock
so it doesn't
absolutely precisely represent the key
now what's really cool about this
machine I've been working with the
manufacture in Germany
there's now software out for this
machine
that you can take a photograph have a
key way
you gotta love science okay
saw we take we take a picture out the
keyway
imported into Adobe Photoshop size it
imported and the easy entry and what you
do I don't know if you can see
a little bit you actually draw the
keyway
you draw out the way you want it to be
and then you stored in a database and
you replicate the keyway and
then used now you have a blankie that
fits the lock
now you may have some special
requirements let's talk about our
friends at Schley
now this is the database how you store
the profile then you can modify you can
make it thinner you can make it thicker
you can shop pieces of you can add
pieces you can change sectional key ways
in high security environment you can do
whatever you want so here's our friend
mister everest
this is an original everest profile
and you can see how the undercut would
prevent a standard blank from
entering mackey way which is it's very
clever design and patented
an if you're not able to have that
undercut you are getting into that key
way
now commerce the the modified profile
and as you can see
what I did was I drew around the
undercut
so this is now not a slag avarice blank
this is one little open this lock and
then my friend can Pearson at Peterson
manufacturing that makes the lock picks
he made a little p.m. inserts in the
lock
and raises the check PN so it's very
clever
saw imp so that that's basically the
machine
I they have a website easy entry .de if
you want more information on
impression ng notes as I said I
you can open are as I found with a
ballpoint pen
I the the locks for the computers
thank God nobody steals computers today
or
or that wouldn't have much effect this
is a formal impression system that's
made by John fall as I mention
and basically you stick an aluminum foil
carrier into the lock
and in 30 seconds a search Lake I 923
see which Matt talked about
its open and by the way the two books
that Matt talked about
arm written by Hobbs and then there's
another one written by George price
and a are to manipulation are all in the
city
okay I and this is what the carrot for
oil carrier looks like after its
impression
very clever and you can actually decode
that for carrier
and come up with the code number for the
key
this is another method have opening for
oil aluminum foil with the temple keys
I like berries gonna show you an
alternate over now to mark
I'm and if we have time at the end we'll
talk about and work a little more
thank you
either my name's mark sidon
and I do physical security for a living
break into things
always when authorized are usually a
require written permission so I'm not
going to repeat
stuff that these other fine people have
said I'll try to skip over
have way too many slides because I was
invited on the yesterday
I'd like to step back a bit though and
look at the bigger picture here
which is not focusing on locks but
focusing on the system issues
locks are just one component which fit
in
into a gestalt which most manufactures
Tony mother
understand the users who install also
don't bother to understand the context
in in which the lock or the things
around
are installed so this fits in a much
bigger context
a physical security I am which
has been getting smaller and smaller
since 911
am hands a number of
features emerge in the enterprise
environment the business environment
have been reducing physical security
specifically for example
reliance on external parties outsourcing
and offshore development that means
you're depending on all the and
colocation sites
this means you're depending on all these
external people to do the security for
you
rather than doing it yourself I'm even
in the enterprise if you work in a
business you'll discover there's
fragmented responsibility and authority
between sysadmins networking and legal
and facilities
and often their multiple sites editor
their different people in different
locations
they have responsibility for stuff and
there's a lot of gaps between these
competing on parties so stuff or just
fall into the cracks
there's very little budget for mediation
older facilities problems with older
facilities like locks that were
installed thirty-five years ago
om mostly the risk management mindset is
insurance oriented
you know where we stand to lose had we
buy insurance to
pass for lost covers for the loss
another problem is that the the
facilities people who have lotsa
functional power
they have this keyring which can open
anything have very little status
so they might be in a queue instead in a
locked office
moreover they have very little
training in how to make buying decisions
so
the vendors selling snake or products
that don't work very well
meanwhile almost no solutions are open
source it's really hard to evaluate
what the vendor product or unless you're
somebody like Tobias
are you guys book an ace
see I'm employees cell other problem is
man has pointed out that the strongly
believe in security through obscurity
their common cop outs rationalizations
excuses are that's not my job
it's my vendors problem i'm concerned. a
plausible threat
we just have to do a little bit better
than locks and keys we have to raise the
bar just a few inches
so they'll go to our neighbors in a
campus or a building
there's a lot lot a legacy to deal with
for example partial hi
walls unsealing raised floor
wiring rooms in the wrong places like in
the hallways why run through public
areas
doors that were installed thirty years
ago locks that arms installed
now at least you can ask yourself in the
physical security world
is there a perimeter you can ask that in
the network in context anymore
cause a wireless then there are in the
physical security world they're also
these back doors and I don't mean
the physical back toward plant where the
people got site smoke
that is one of them there's also the
Knox box
it's this this little box that sits on
the side of your building and has the
keys inside it
and there's a single key that although
firefighters
and police officers have that opens at
Knox
Knox box and they take out the curing
which opens the inside
so if they need to get in case of
emergency
they had thats what you call in computer
science a single point of failure
the Knox box is usually protected by a
medico camp
another physical security problem in
campuses are buildings
is the local operating networks that is
the building control
is on a network itself usually runs on
power lines or some other kind of
network in often these things are
connected with the enterprise network
sometimes these things also controlled
doors marks
multi-tenant buildings are special
problem because they have shared
infrastructure
and there's a lowest common denominator
factor the comes in because the weakest
10 and security policy
probably is your key factors security
policy
if they let anybody in anybody can walk
up to your front door
soco location facilities are one of my
favorites I'm often higher to test
the security colas and these are like 80
communities
except when the motorcycle gangs in down
the street
you lost all your security your co
tenants weakest visitor inventor policy
puts you at risk
so let's get out components now there
are things like doors
which are made of what are they single
or double doors where the hinges
sometimes are on the outside sometimes
you can just take in japan's of the
doors
than their locks part near the ends this
is in
a PowerPoint wonderfulness all these
guys talk about locks
a few amusing problems with blocks are
that the best-selling tubular locks late
have deadlock urs which are rendered
ineffective by the biggest selling
electric strikes
these are often install together and the
deadlock or just slips into the gap
behind the electric strike so you can
just
push back the bolt the deadlock it
doesn't work
I frequently see exposed electric strike
wiring
outside the protected area magnetic
strikes which are those things with the
big magnets
not on a trip to power and its
little realized that adhesive tape on
the magnetic strike
were you know any kind of coding reduces
the holding strength dramatically
according to an interest you block man
had to mathematics laughed at a map
next now so key blocks
are often installed even on doors
controlled by badge access control
so you have a parallel weaker system by
which you can get through
and often nobody knows who has the key
to the key blocks
on the magnetic on the
on the doors controlled by the badge
access system so
I won't talk about any of these lock
cylinder issues cuz everybody else has
except for interchangeable core Saunders
interchangeable course owners have a
special key call the control key
which you can use to remove the core and
replace it with the different core
in other words Ricky the lock how
quickly the problem is that the control
key is
often even more universal that any
master key
there's one control key for the whole
system and you can make control key with
one
instanceof a lock 1 comment on mark's
I A description out master up systems
that
avoid the master key vulnerability the
mat described
is that you can still take apart any
instanceof
any of these locks and figure out what
the cyber combination is
so mean it leaves a trace there's a hold
story some
lock is to Spears maybe a padlock is
walked off
but you still only need one lakh to
reverse engineer the entire system
mark let me just by let me just make one
comment
that's true if one side bar code is used
in the whole system
that is not true as I sad
if there's multiple side bar codes that
medical an awesome I have the capability
of development for generating
which no other system does if you take a
target lock
with a different side bar code and what
you're going after you are gone open
okay that's the problem thank you the
real problem with physical ox is that
revocation
rights is unacceptably difficult and
expensive I want I learned to pick locks
a calm university in the nineteen
sixties so that
work for the radio station there and we
wanted to report on kids getting
beat up by cops on campus and we didn't
want to get beaten up for church ask
ourselves
so I make keys to the tunnels under the
campus in the
the building so we the radio station
could report on what's going on
went back for my twenty-fifth cops are
you going on in other words you.re
terrorist that's running I was a
terrorist but now I was like Les
Miserables grandpa
terrace cell
when I went back for my twenty-fifth
reunion guess what my tunnel keys and my
friend turkeys the building's
still worked twenty-five years later
so this is just a demonstration that
revocation a bright too seldom
if ever done because it's enormously
expensive so what we use instead
we use computer access batch systems so
this computer nerd
database involved I could hear you
saying 0
its wired somehow to microcomputer based
panels local caches
access rights and these things used to
be connected on local wiring point to
point wiring
but now they've networked it all how the
network did they put these
Lantronix terminal controllers in front
of it the use
bogus proprietary protocols they seldom
use mutual authentication
on the counter parties in any
transaction so you can do man millet
accident sniffing attacks
and these are the things that open the
doors that control the doors
if they're on your enterprise network
your baby basically lost the game
the manufactures leavin back doors for
the installers and the maintainers and
maybe others
and they don't document any the only way
you could find his back doors is by
researcher
and then there are these cards which
light %um procs carts
an early example of RFID tags they have
a short number
which is sent by RF to the reader and
these can be read remotely by an
attacker while you're in the elevators
and we can walk up to you
with the battery powered reader in re
the card in your wallet maybe if you
have to it would be difficult
but you only have one card in your
wallet they can read them some these are
feel programmable see can generate your
own cards
the low card numbers have problems and
brute force attacks are possible
although I don't know a brute forcing
machine yet are these more secure than
keyes
me so here's a case study that I did
with March and had a financial
institution where
we decided it would be fun to break into
the badging system
which would gain as access to everything
else I won't
name the vendor on the tape arm
but the system was running SCO UNIX on a
PC with
basically all the services turned on
serial wiring to cart stations
root password was published in the user
manual R 00 T
when we call tech support and said why
did you publisher and password they said
you want to change that you know that
could create
big service problems for for us we can
support you
dialup modems which they also
recommended always be left on
so of course I logged on his route and
start poking around
it was listening for TCP connections and
21 ports
the sources on the machine it was open
source but not because they believed in
open source it was for their convenience
so they could compile in features and so
I was looking at if def check waihee
if TF US House
I was starting to get alarmed
other if tests included LDS Church
GE King of Prussia which I think makes
nuclear gadget search engines or
something
University Washington corning US Senate
here is a Southern California Yale
University Medical Center
and five airports by name all the
British Airports
and their customers included 50 airports
prisons all the state
correctional institutions in
pennsylvania I was visualizing musical
cells
at midnight we'll just open all the cell
doors and see what happens
so looking at the database schema was
really instructive because the system
has this concept the passkey magic word
you type that the car terminal and it
conveys ferries privileges it's like a
password but without a log
in all these things are in a database
table lightly obfuscated
so of course we extracted the passwords
and we noticed there was a special pass
keys a magic function up-to-date
which conveyed system manager privilege
to anyone who knew how to
computed secret just type in this number
and boom you were
the superuser this was not document
so person attacked her could do anything
including musical cells
create stealth badges alter code I'll
you know disable the locking mechanism
remove /url to log records
there are general problems with sensors
& alarms
which I don't have time to talk about on
par equal won't have time to dem
won't talk about video video has its
pluses and minuses
particularly may discover this when the
PN have your ATM card
is sniffed by someone who was installed
a surreptitious video camera pointed at
the keyboard
and has put an overlay card reader on
the on the ATM
I'll just talk about this caucasian case
study I was hired to
test security a at a big coehlo up
one run by publicly held company with
faults the call the vaults
cages and cabinets on a raised floor but
the raised floor
was the plan for the cool air which
would flow through the race for
go through vents in the vault go up into
the ceiling
so basically this was just an enclosed
area within open floor
an open ceiling
naturally you could go over the ceiling
or under the floor
but they said we have we are passive
infrared sensors
were protected by motion sensors
intervals so I decided to test
I submarine under the floor popped up
waved at the motion sensor
twenty minutes later nothing happened
so I walked out the door and I wave to
the camera
put up a sign saying bust me
nothing happened I walked out the door
with a PC
matter how to get in the first place I
walked in the back door and the bosnian
because I had a legitimate looking batch
which I had forged
so its it of course what you find out
is that the motion sensor is for their
conveniences it's a request to exit
sensor
it shuts the switch on the door that
enables you to leave without setting off
the alarm
if you force the door on the way in it
would set off the alarm
but if you're walking out no alarm
so they didn't ask himself the question
how could somebody getting the space
with nobody n church there's been nobody
in the space for 48 hours but sadly
there's movement in the space
is not normal well no because they have
no integration between the
motion-sensing
and the access control in the alarm the
role disintegrated systems
identity I'll just leave you with one
thought X thought question
which is the last bullet here is it
better for your call I'll
to accept your driver's license 40 issue
you their own credential
containing a shared secret or check your
face in a database
in my claim is that private credentials
are much better these days because
anybody can make drivers license
like this guy who forged
the identity this is Abraham a dollar
who pled guilty
to some to some number large number of
councils
forging the identities of 211 at the
fortune 400 richest people
a few years ago the USGA are also
has been doing experiments on front
driver's licenses they determined
that if you fill out this form which
s/he questions like are you a fugitive
from justice
are you subject to court order
restraining you from
harassing stalking or threatening or
have you ever been adjudicated mentally
defective
if you answer these questions yes well
the
then you can't get it but if you answer
them all know and you have a driver's
license or have something that looks
like a valid driver's license
with which you can make using stuff on
eBay you can buy stuff like this
in the five states with minimum brady
law enforcement the reason why
years they look up your driver's license
in a database
and if they don't get hit that must be a
good guy
they don't look up the driver's license
to determine if it's valid they look it
up to determine if it has the name of a
known criminal
what's wrong with this picture here just
two more scary devices which will
underscore why physical security is
important they're keystroke staffers
you can buy them frontera under 100
dollars out catalogs on the Internet
and the store about half a megabyte a
key strokes
this is why passwords are completely
obsolete technology people should not
use them
for high value transactions
on I'm Way at a time very
okay
okay then
last 30 minutes
I'm going to do some demos and then
hopefully some people can ask questions
as well the
s many people have you know I'm Germano
the Dutch
for group 2 which is filled with 3 O's
stands for the open organization of luck
because
and we kiddingly say that the 30 stand
for you have to practice
over and over and over again to become
any good at lockpicking
which really is true I mean at this
moment I'm
very very busy with my business which is
the crib the phone
that's where I spend most of my time
I'm the signing a secure phone which
looks like this it's it's an open
or or the source code is available of
this phone we tried to make a iphone
that isn't typeable and a secure as
possible by publishing the source and is
really takes up a lot of my time so
a.m. unfortunately I've not be involved
in lockpicking
for the last two years as much as I
would like to unfortunately
a lot of people from Germany and even
some from France have
help me collect some nice tricks for you
to show
and actually to follow up of what I did
two years ago
the video did I did two years ago with
Michael sitting over there
a.m. exist
is still available online it's being
downloaded the lots its its downloadable
for free
if you go to website if you go to our
website www
tool .nl with 3 O's tooo held up to now
you'll find the link to the free
download of
all the things that we did last year
and that included the electoral pick
that included the formal dimple
impression
that included a lot of things until now
focus
to some other things that we've been up
to one other things is that
we're being recognized more and more as
a serious party is a serious player
by the look industry for instance we
have found a severe
very extreme severe a vulnerability in
in a lock
that I will demonstrate now a.m. I
promised the guys that
made the locked in the manufacture date
II would put a little table for their
brand name because
how because there are still a few
a small number of these locks around but
what actually happened is that
from somebody came into the
to the tools sport evening and said well
you know here's this
denies lock and tears to key and
all this of course works in operates
a.m.
but he found that if you insert a blank
key
and you turn it into you put it into
block you put pressure on it
you take it out but to leave to tippin
weekly the little bit its open now
this this happened at a evening that
mister tobias was
at was worse visiting Austin doing a
lecture on March 2 keying
and you know we'll look at look at each
other and he said well you know there's
just a a lucky combination of beans
and a it's it's a one thing go but then
we thought about it some more and we
discovered that it actually was a
vulnerability
that to apply to all the locks to
complete series of locks ever made in
the Serie
a and and we figured out what happens a
the the factory dads manufactures these
locks actually
din manufacture all of it they only did
a part of it what happened is that they
bought the locks
from a cheaper manufacture and when they
got the looks they were completely
assembled but they were filled with all
the a combination
beings three so the the bins would be
all at the same length
3 3333 and they would have a blankie
that looks like
that that's got a little bit deeper a.m.
that would be a whole line
of lady sitting there with a pink it am
they would insure turkey the in they
wouldn't hurt the blank with 23
turn the plug a 180 degrees
remove the blog a.m. rekey
the pins with a new combination for
inches 157
53 a.m. and put it back in now
so far there is no vulnerability but
what happened is that the factory that
sold the locks
used bins the the pinch of a diameter of
2.2 millimeters
and they replaced the low pins
with bins of 2.0 millimeters which means
that they are actually more thin so the
the pins that that the key Duchess are
more thin
than the bins that are on top of it so
if you turn it a little bit if you put a
little
tension on it a.m. the gap that normally
is 2.3 millimeters
goes to 2.0 millimeters and the pin
that's two point three millimeters
cannot fall down anymore
so a I i phone to factory and I said
well you know you have a serious problem
and eight couldn't believe it they said
well you know it it cannot be that with
a blank
everybody can open these key within
two seconds without any training and and
remember no physical evidence is is
there i mean when I pick a lock
I make scratches in the lock and if you
sent a pic block to a forensic
laboratory which the German sport
troopers got some experience with the
the German forensic laboratory are stiff
they could pick some locks
and examen demand and they could
actually quite detailed explain
this locus picked with an electric big
this is done by hand isn't been picked
at all
but with this technique nobody would
ever find out so somebody could
rub your complete house and the you know
you really have tough luck because
there's nobody who can prove
that you didn't lose a key or problems
like that
so did that gave us quite some credit to
the industry especially since
we came to them you know we could have
gone to the 8 o'clock news or
whatever I make a big fuss out a bit but
we didn't do that
we tried to be the good guys this is
such a serious vulnerability
that you know we we we tried to
and and they immediately close to
factory and the
it took them three days in a weekend to
think
what was the best strategy and a got all
the locks back from the shop
and that's a crime you know david now
its
they did they handled it well I
okay then about the lockpicking itself
from I could explain how lockpicking
works don't know if there's a need for
that time many people would like me to
explain in detail
why lockpicking as possible and in
howard's can be done because
it's been told many many times before
and I will be downstairs at the second
floor
between 2&5 as a leader three hours
teaching everybody wants to to pick
locks
as mark sets a.m. we have
designed a special its already a
collector's item
a special picture normally the pic sets
that people carry
a.m. you know our extremely helpful with
all sorts of impressive looking
tools but the thing is for look picking
you only needs
actually one tool or two well you always
need a pensioner
and something called the finger or or
the lifter and
the this a specific one we made as got
to
different dance and this will open if
you spend enough time practicing
this will help you open I'm I don't dare
to say exactly how many percent but I
would say
eighty percent of the of the locks
around you without any problem
as long as you practice because the
tools don't open the locks
you do you open the lock 'em
okay so if you want to learn to pick
locks just come downstairs between 2&5
tomorrow morning there's going to be a
lockpick championship will put a nice
a reward on that will put a nice prize
on the
mmm okay water I'm not exactly sure
about the time yet
so okay we got fifteen minutes
okay well I brought a whole lot of
things to demonstrate
but since we're running little bit out
of time
I we're going to bump key the bump key
as mark already explained is a is a key
that is cuts
to its lowest position sometimes it even
got a little bit below its lowest
position a
and what it what happens is that if you
insert it into the lock
if you insert it into the lock
of course it will not turn because the
pins are not in the right position
what do you do if you take out one click
so you remove it a little bit and then
you hit it
I I'm not sure if I'm can do this on
camera
demonstration effect
open okay
now I was first shown this technique was
first shown to me
a actually with a key in the lock in in
Germany by some of my good friends at
the
those for trying to this property a and
and that their
the they become really good at it and
the nice thing about this technique
is that it can be used on locks like
this one a.m.
I'm not sure if you can see
but the keyway of this locket and Eva
lockers extremely narrow
it's almost impossible to even get a
tool in
because is Ward its all over the place
is going six ek
it's really extremely difficult a but
luckily
with the bump key you know it's no
problem at all or at least
takes a few blows to to open it if it
blows in
to turn that's open so just takes a
little
a little practice the 22 to do it and as
I told you I didn't have much time to
practice
a mmm now Mike my good friend all a
pretty decent from Germany
explain to me that this could also be
done with the dimple keys
with the high secure a locks
so but he also found that if you pull
back one
full notch a.m. that it doesn't work
well so what he does is
he cuts to quiche or he cuts the cuts
in the key a a little bit more to the
tip of the key
to I am and and and this will give you
more space
a and teammates with some
with a hot glue stick from from a glue
gun
he made a what he calls a buffer and
what happens issue
inserted in the locked and you have a
little bit of play
but you cannot push it in you
cannot push it in too deep you can only
put it in a little while to a little bit
and I'll see if I can open this one
making tension
table
okay to open
now but but this is what I mean with a
if it wasn't with the help from from my
friends have Germany and France
I wouldn't be able to show you all
districts because I really don't have
that much time to really go into you
know
nights and nights of playing with all
these things a.m.
I i hope to do it the better a better
repair job
maybe next time a some trick from France
them
the mmm their is a
breed Garlock and debris Carlo kisses
special
that the key itself has got a.m.
two rows of pins next to each other
I don't know if you can see it but it's
it's a very sophisticated system
and of course you will probably never
see every car look because she's French
and the yup but but in in in but but but
but in france
a you know this is really a very
expensive high security lock
and to pick it it's it's almost
virtually impossible because of these
two rows of pins and it's very difficult
but my good friend gmail somebody a.m.
he East thinking a lot about a look
security
any thought well it must be possible to
make some sort of impression ink system
and this is Mark already put out with to
its
a formal tape you can make some
impression existence but with this look
that seems not to work so what he did
was used
packaging material this this phone me
like stuff
and he made a blank which
is made out of two parts: actually I'm
this is it uncut so you can move
departure and he
sticks in this packaging material and
it's really amazing but it really works
at least I hope it does now
hmm
demonstration effect kicking in
nomogram okay
gonna removed from the camera
yes okay so while you doing I have a
quick question
what kinda block do you have on your
door
okay the the reason the
what what was also my daytime job is
the making sure the physical security of
the space around the crib the phone area
I mean we were making secure phones do
to keep the bad guys out but these bad
guys have almost unlimited resources
so the thing is II need to be at the
the state-of-the-art level of making
sure that nobody enters our building
without without them compromising our
computers or decisions that we work on
a.m. summer going to tell you I
okay so funny its ok hun
its stunning but I can tell you that
the love computer securities is involved
it's not only a mechanical system we use
I can tell a little bit it's funny I am
know if you want to
if you wanna harass us with questions
please you up at the microphone
arm in the Senate where William few
minutes left but
want to yell at us with with questions
or
just say harassing comment 2011 real
good a
secure lock system uses by %uh blood
a.m.
its it it works with discs
and I did open a couple of this clocks
the
last time from from others but this is
actually much more sophisticated it's
got a double
locking bar and if I was to recommend
locks it would probably be
medico m3 a South feet then and
apply systems because these are really
the high secure
systems okay
if you have a question yeah question
about the %uh pumpkin method
does our government jordy it locks yeah
its it works on on
amazingly amount of blocks the only
thing is
you needs time to practice you really
you know if you think you can open any
luck with three strikes with the first
time you try it
you're wrong but if you practice with
its
you can open large amount of locks did
it works the same assess big on it
elevates the bins up
and it's it's a timing matter as well so
you need to strike
weights a fraction of a second and then
turn if you turn be
at the moment the the two-strike you not
gonna open it its
it's really a timing matter it is really
something and other
he likes it better that is tend to work
on our to the style the locker
wise as I said the the medicos
a suffi- 10 dispersed luck with the
sidebar
and %ah blood completely resistance
against it it works on a bright idea
blocks
but some padlocks works on door locks
had worked on them
amazing amount of books thank you
welcome my friend Mike
their home first of British Gas
but the the one thing that I think
mister tobias a festering
don't you don't even really touched on
the
the fact that locks are one of the
weakest links in all security networking
country the drywall go over the walls
are under as he said I am
in just that in the general feeling that
now
considering that when we talk about
this like a terrible with this year not
like a terrible weakness there
as a whole security wide thing you
really feel the lock is that important
to the scary jane yes it is yes
it still is a point of attack everyone
one advantage is that from the attackers
pointed you attack the lock you up
leave very little forensic evidence so
one property in the lockers was punching
a hole through the drywall
is that you don't discover the attack
until much later
on am so know that's why one reason the
locks are important to study in
themselves but absolutely true abusers
as part of a larger system
and if you're concerned with securing
something you have to look at everything
you really want defense in depth which
means locks alarms
video everything the key distribution is
often a problem
if you can find the facilities guys left
the key in the coffee cup
well and then you impression then you
have forever entry
so it's not the lock that's the problem
it's the way the keys are stored
a
want the questions I have focuses more
on the
kinda fight some the automotive cars
where you had the
the microchip embedded within the key
system now
as far as the additional then regarding
liked numbers are there something else
needed to
activate the chip so that lock turns
bunch of different kinds of those
some of them are really unsophisticated
on the earlier ones that
that computer chip turned out to just be
a resistor and with with with fifteen or
sixteen different values
actually that was pretty out pretty it's
a pretty good system that still out
there
was it easy and it works but some have
charged response these days
so they really transponders with RFID
child responses very sophisticated
solve the problem is you can tell what
it is by the way why do you wanna steal
cars
actually something about a friend of
mine who have misplaced want this keys
and since I about orkut British Treasury
heil 500 bucks for a place to keep from
GM mami
yeah well
I'm not sure why you wanted to pride
those good people GM
their five hundred dollars replacement I
we have a couple minutes
self please actually
in addition to his that's the Texas
Instruments terrorist system
that they're using challenge response
based are ideas actually
to ask you about that last question
because I have to be out of your
fortune speed pass system uses the exact
same technology
have any view going into any sort of
analysis up this you can look at a
farmer's list
interesting people there is there's
recently been a thread
on easy pass pass pass how it works it's
basically a very simple are
I have the equipment to read them down
in my room right now again I have the
equipment to read them down in my room
right now i cant send me an e-mail
largess
ok I'll a good point let each take a
parting one-sentence parting shot
are just a between we have to be out
here right now
okay well thank you very much and I hope
to see you at the second floor between
two and five today
and tomorrow thank you very much